Today, I want to talk about the
relationship between risk and law.
And I want to do this in the context
of the history of agriculture and
regulating pesticides
during the 20th century.
And also I want to have you
considered the idea of, of risk.
And I'm a reminded, uh, as
I think about this of Tsla,
it's line only those who will risk going
too far can possibly find out how far
one can go.
So many believe that environmentalists
are in the business of trying to
absolutely minimize risk
as opposed to balance, uh,
the threat of loss or danger
or against other opportunities.
And others argue that without risk
in life things will be pretty boring.
It's traveling through Europe.
Last summer on a lecture tour and I saw
this village sitting on the top of a
cliff and I wondered to myself about the
village and I wondered how they chose
to build so close to the edge and what
kind of thinking was in their minds.
And I could imagine that this used to be
an a number of fields where they graze
cattle and sheep and they probably
worried about losing cattle.
And sheep across the cliff.
Then as it grew into a little village,
I can imagine them worried about
their children playing near the edge.
So much of environmental law is about
thinking about the buffer zone or the
safety factor that you would
want to use to offer sufficient,
sufficient protection
against significant damage.
So
the idea of risk and understanding risk
is really a fundamental aspect of human
logic and instinct.
Within law,
it tends to become defined
as probability of loss.
Probability of damage, uh, might be an
endangered species. It might be, uh,
air quality.
It could be human health,
and it's often expressed in both
quantitative and qualitative terms.
So particularly over the past 30 years,
the field of quantitative risk
assessment has grown in importance, uh,
to try to understand what happens
to chemicals or to species, uh,
what kinds of pathways
they travel, uh, what,
what kinds of problems might occur
from a chemical release and chemical
movement. And increasingly, uh,
it's more sophisticated mathematically
and more difficult to understand the
different sources of uncertainty that
are embedded in these estimates of risk.
You may have heard of,
of the idea of a unacceptable risk
level for cancer or some or some other
undesirable outcome as being one in
a million or the government used that
standard on many occasions, a one
in a million excess risk. Well,
to put that into perspective, you might
think about the h one n one infection.
So what was the actual morbidity rate,
uh, over the past year?
Uh, for h one n one? Well,
it turns out that you would first think
about the number of people in the United
States know,
say roughly 300 million people and you'd
want to know what the incidence rate
was and the illness and those.
Now I was looking at them last night
on the Centers for Disease Control and
prevention website.
Their estimate is that between
30 and 45 or 50 million people,
uh,
carried the virus and had
some adverse effect from it.
And then I was looking at the statistics
for mortality and between 15 and 20,000
people, uh, might be, uh,
how are or were killed by the illness.
Why the uncertainty associated with
the estimate? Well, uh, it's a,
it's an illness that, uh, uh, can harvest,
so to speak in epidemiological terms,
uh,
the more susceptible those that
have serious background illnesses.
So the expression of risk for morbidity,
which means illness would be
roughly let's say a 30 million
out of a 300 million, uh,
which is really quite striking.
You know, there are few illnesses that
uh, uh, have that have that rate. So,
you know, roughly a one in 10 risk.
And I mentioned when I started this,
a brief aside, uh, that a one in a million
risk is often thought of as acceptable.
The distinction between
environmental risks, uh,
that are not biologically based or or
generated by pathogens like h one n one
and chemical risks is often that a,
there was a clear causal relationship
between exposure and an understanding of
the source of the illness and also
what might be done to manage it more
effectively, such as
the vaccine. By the way,
the vaccine that was produced
and distributed this year,
it was really pretty remarkable,
was extremely effective. And the,
the incidents rate was projected to be
far higher than it actually turned out.
So this concern over
quantitative risk assessment,
trying to understand who's most
vulnerable, who is going to, uh, uh,
basically sustain the, the, the most
serious effects this preoccupies,
uh, the environmental protection agency,
the food and Drug Administration,
when they're thinking about allowing a
new drug to be added to the marketplace.
Uh, and really the decision
is all about balancing, uh,
trying to think through what the quality
of the evidence evidence is and should
the danger's be balanced
against the benefits.
And this standard for balancing
has shifted dramatically
over the 20th century.
So that, uh, the lecture of
the day really, we'll trace
the evolution of law, uh,
and demonstrate how it's shifted
from 1906 to the present.
And I want you to think about how it
really reflects changing science, uh,
as well as changing human values so
that as the science gets a stronger,
we understand the relationship between
an exposure and an adverse outcome. Uh,
and oftentimes the government will
intervene by setting a new law or a new
regulation.
So the back in 1906,
uh, the food drug and or the, uh, um, uh,
jump ahead here,
but pure food and drug act of 1906 was
passed after Upton Sinclair published the
jungle. The describe the filthy
slaughtering conditions in, in Chicago.
The two or food and drug act
was passed in 1906 as well.
And at four bayed foreign
in Interstate Commerce,
adulterated or fraudulently
labeled, uh, food and drugs.
So products could now be sees
and condemned and offending
persons could be fine
or jail, uh, and fresh, canned or frozen
food shipped in interstate commerce.
It must be pure and wholesome.
That was the new standard back in 1906.
So basically the idea of adulteration,
uh,
and the idea of fraudulent
labeling became important.
So the very first attempts to try
to control a risk in society, uh,
related to food and agriculture,
a really concentrated on
the idea of labeling a,
the idea of,
of making sure that the product inside
the package was what it claimed to be.
On that it had an effectiveness
that, uh, was also claimed.
And then it wasn't a
excessively dangerous.
They really worried about farmers buying,
uh, pesticides, I suppose at pesticides.
And then basically, uh, uh,
having the container filled
with sugar or flour. Uh,
how would they know the difference?
Uh, there were many cases of,
of fraudulent manufacturing
practices early in the,
in the 20th century before this
law was put into, into place.
Another critical statute that built on
this was the insecticide act of 1910.
Uh, that similarly PR prohibited, uh,
uh, fraudulently labeled pesticides, uh,
and set standards for purity.
Uh,
so the idea of ingredient labeling was
added to the insecticide act and it was
designed to protect farmers from
dangerous and impotent pesticides.
You jump forward,
you find that the federal food,
drug and cosmetic act of
1938 is important. And it
became the, uh, it can't,
became the home for pesticide
regulation for, for many years, uh,
until, uh, uh, Epa took over
that responsibility in 1970.
And the food and Drug Administration
was authorized to set in 1938, uh,
limits for Chemicals and food.
So the recognition that if you
sprayed a field of corn and a,
you harvested the corn, uh, and then
you, you sold it in the supermarket,
that it might still carry residues.
This was beginning to be well
recognized back in the 1930s.
The criteria used to set the tolerances,
uh, was really quite interesting.
At that time.
It wasn't a health based criteria,
wasn't an environmentally based criterion.
It was how much residue and
should be allowed to, to uh, uh,
remain on the food product if the chemical
is sprayed in the field and a dose
that's effective to get the job done.
In other words, to kill the pest.
So that's kind of interesting.
So it was really a standard that was
set to make sure that the residues would
not cause the food to be pulled out
of the marketplace because they were
adulterated.
So they were really designed to protect
the farmer and the economic value of the
crop rather than the health of the
population or the environmental quality.
The Miller amendment of 1954 required
tolerances for all pesticides if they
might remain as food residues.
And then the Delaney amendment in 1958
became infamous because it set a zero
risk standard, uh, a tolerance
for carcinogens in food.
So the,
the exact language is that if a,
a pesticide or other food additive is
carcinogenic in laboratory animals or in
humans, and it was the
first time in law that, uh,
using evidence from laboratory animals
was considered to be sufficient in order
to ban the use of a chemical,
then it could not be used in a way that
would cause the residue to be present in
the food supply.
Now you can imagine that these chemicals
were applied to too many different
crops. And, uh, I mentioned
to you that that Ddt, uh,
in my last lecture was applied so
heavily to so many different foods, uh,
300 different food crops had
tolerances by the mid 1950s.
But the government's ability to detect
these chemicals is really important to
this story.
So if you use insensitive detection
technology and other words supposing that
you're,
you're a chemical detection equipment
is only capable of finding residues at
the, uh, uh, part per 100,000,
level 10 to the minus fifth, uh,
or even part per million level,
and the chemical is there, but it's there
at the high part per billion level, uh,
the chemical test is going
to come back negative.
It's going to come back as a non-detect.
So gradually you see this, uh,
a very interesting evolution
in the concept of purity,
in what constitutes a safe and pure
environment that's very much driven by the
sensitivity of the detection equipment.
So during the century, as the,
as the detection equipment became more
and more sensitive, now for some dioxins,
we can detect those down to
the part per quadrillion level.
In many chemicals are present and
food of the a part per trillion level.
It's got people thinking about, well, what
does that mean? What's that mean to, to,
to uh, uh, their potential
to influence human health.
So back in the forties and 50s,
the detection technology
was really quite limited.
And also the sampling was quite limited
so that there really weren't sampling
that many foods.
And you can imagine that the,
the scale of the problem this prince
presents today given the international
character of our food supply.
And I asked this question with
respect to several commodities. Uh,
first I started with apples and wondered
how many times the government tested
apples for,
for pesticides.
And then I looked at a bananas and for
bananas for a chemical that was, uh,
when I looked about eight years ago,
one of the most heavily used
insecticides on bananas. Uh, you know,
grown in the tropics. The
government was looking at, uh,
uh,
about a 15 to 18 samples of
bananas a for this compound.
Uh, when, uh,
I then was able to calculate that several
trillion individual bananas had been
imported into the nation
during that year. So, you know,
one needs to think about, uh, uh,
what standards are in place in
different parts of the world, uh,
where that food is likely to go, uh,
keeping records of imports, statistics,
and then think about what
kind of a sampling design
would be necessary in order
to find these residues,
uh, in a way that, uh,
might eventually lead
to health protection.
So the Delaney amendment that was really
quite striking. It was, uh, adopted,
uh, really, uh, uh,
with great support in Congress in part
because of the u s fascination with
cancer and also cancer management.
So this grew in part because of the
nuclear weapons testing euro. Uh,
but it is curious that, uh,
within the European nations,
the regulatory approach to environmental
quality has not been as concerned with
cancer.
It's been more concerned with a
neurological decline and also reproductive
health.
Uh,
so race is really interesting questions
about why the preoccupation in the
United States with cancer. So the first
seriously health protective statute, uh,
that, uh, we can find
an environment of law.
It has to do with food and
it has to do with pesticides.
And it's contained in this
Delaney amendment. By the way,
this amendment applies to
all food additives in the
food additive could be in a
defined, also as a coloring agent,
like the salmon calling I spoke of.
It could be defined as a
packaging material migrant. Uh,
it could be a flavoring agent as well.
Uh, so that the standard is very clear.
If it induces cancer in animals or in
humans, uh, then it is not allowed.
Curiously,
there's a clause within the statute
that applies only to pesticides,
uh, that are defined as food
additives if they concentrate.
And you remember the story I told you
the other day about, uh, taking a,
a grape and extracting all the
water out of it, or taking a, uh,
corn and extracting the oil out of it
and having to be thoughtful about what
that really might mean for, for
chemical residues. So if you,
if you are concerned about oil extraction,
uh,
you need to think about lipophilicity.
So if you've got a chemical such as a
chlorinated carbon that is likely to bind
onto, to fats of, of one form or another,
extracting the oil out will likely
also concentrate the chemical residue.
So if you look in the code of federal
regulations, it's very curious.
You can go over to the law library and
pull out the code of federal regulations
on pesticides.
It's actually a good,
it'd be a good assignment for
a teaching fellows to, to, uh,
disseminate a go look at the code of
federal regulations for pesticide residues
in food. And you'll see a 40 CFR, uh,
one 35,
and you go to the appendix and the
appendix is several hundred pages long of
individual pesticide food combinations.
So I was quite struck by this, uh, uh,
several years ago and I added all of
these up and it turns out that there are
about 10,000 different
pesticide food combinations.
And if you look carefully at these
combinations, uh, that set limits for Ben,
the Millon Bananas or, or, uh,
say chlorpyrifos and, and, uh, uh,
apples or DDT and milk, uh,
that standard is still in place.
By the way, it's kind of interesting,
even though DDT was banned,
as I said the other day and in the 1970s,
but if you look carefully,
you'll see that you get a different
residue limit allowed for fresh corn or a
fresh apples or fresh soybeans than
you do for the process product.
And it's basically because of this
concentration factor. So water extraction,
you know,
making raisins out of grapes,
making wine out of grapes
or making oils out of, uh,
different kinds of grains
can have this effect.
The Federal Insecticide fungicide and
rodenticide act in 1947 was the, uh,
central, uh, statute that was,
was passed and it really set the stage
for the u s department of Agriculture's
authority to issue licenses
or registrations. So,
and as I mentioned earlier,
the idea of registering a pesticide or
allowing it to be used for a certain crop,
uh, this, these registrations
were given out one after another,
after another,
a decade after decade.
So that by 1960 there were 50,000
different pesticide registrations, uh,
that had been issued.
And by 1970,
there were nearly 70,000
pesticide registrations.
And registration has given for a
specific chemical use and it may be also
assigned for a specific package.
So the,
you may have chemical x,
uh,
and that has one registration and then
it may be sold also with chemical why or
chemical y and Z.
And they would have different
registrations assigned to
them and they might have
different registrations assigned
for different kinds of uses.
So that these are not just used
on, on food commodities. Uh,
where else might they be used?
Well, you know, think about it, uh,
many of many of the buildings at Yale
or sprayed by pesticides indoors, uh,
so that type of use often had to have a
separate registration sprayed in subway,
sprayed in vehicles,
added to materials such as plastics
that are components of cars or that,
uh, uh, uh, are components of urethanes
for example, that coat the wood here.
So that plastics,
uh,
have carried biocides into our
environment in a whole set of ways.
And the government had to keep track of
where these chemicals were going and had
to license each of these distinctive uses.
So the,
the fifth Pfiffer of 1947,
I was important because it defined
these chemicals as economic poisons a
implying yes, they're poisonous, uh,
but they also carry an economic benefit
so that, uh, we need to look at this and,
uh, using a utilitarian
balancing standard. Uh,
so that risk benefit balancing
became the phrase, uh, that,
that guided us department, the Department
of Agriculture to crank out these,
these registrations.
It also extended the right regulations,
not just to insecticides,
but two herbicides and rodenticides.
And right now in terms of volume
of chemical released in the world,
you find that herbicides are the
most heavily, uh, type of pesticide.
So there are pesticides or insecticides,
herbicides,
rodenticides designed to
kill a rats or mice, ah,
Sliema sides that are applied to kill
slime and algae on the side of nuclear
power plant cooling, cooling towers. Uh,
there are nearly a hundred different
chemicals. Uh, any swimmers in the,
in the room? Well, probably a
few are former swimmers. Uh,
well there they're nearly a hundred
different pesticides that have been
registered for use in swimming pools,
uh, to kill a variety of viruses,
bacteria, uh, as well as, as
molds and other pathogens.
And if you think about that, uh, uh,
carefully and you think about the relative
risk that is associated with using
those chemicals as
opposed to not using them,
it's probably a really good choice
given the illnesses that could,
could live in that environment.
So that this statute, uh, was,
was the first to really break down these
different categories of biocides and
really assigned different regulatory
responsibility nor authority was given to
the Department of Agriculture.
However,
to remove hazardous chemicals from the
marketplace so that they always found
that the benefits outweighed the risk.
There are no instances that I can point
to a that the Department of Agriculture,
uh, either abandoned chemical or
found that the risk was too serious.
They may have adjusted the
allowable use rates or,
or the type type of environment it could
be released to or the type of crop, uh,
but, uh, no product bans.
And think about this.
The government gave the Congress,
gave the Department of Agriculture
the Authority to manage this program,
to implement the program.
Now is that a good idea?
What's the Department of
Agriculture is basic role? Well,
it's really to promote economic
production of a variety of different
agricultural commodities and they really
also do not have and have not had much
expertise in environmental science to
know what happened to the chemicals once
they were released or two to think
carefully about the health effects.
Uh, so the medical expertise it within
the Department of Agriculture, uh,
throughout their period of jurisdiction,
which ended in 1970 when the environmental
protection agency was formed,
uh,
was a period when they really had very
little expertise in environmental science
or in medical science,
which is really fundamental to the way
that we're thinking about regulating
pesticides today.
The fifth for amendments in 1964 came
after Rachel Carson's book, Silent Spring,
uh, raised the alarm and caused, uh,
the population to be quite
upset about pesticide residues,
particularly their effect on wildlife,
uh, but also growing recognition that,
that these chemicals could build in the
human body and also the food and Drug
Administration's admission,
uh, that, that, uh,
they had found pesticides in human
breast milk as early as 1952.
The public wasn't a warned about this.
Uh,
and basically if you find a chemical,
regardless of what it is,
you find it in a another
species of mammals, breast milk,
you can presume that it's likely to
get into human breast milk as well.
So Rachel Carson silent spring
turned out to be a real watershed,
not just legally for pesticides because
it really increased the sense of
susceptibility to biocides
or the economic poisons. Uh,
but it really met with quite a
bit of resistance in Congress. Uh,
again, this was the end of the
nuclear weapons testing, uh, in the,
in the atmosphere.
And it was also a period of great
unrest in the United States. The, the,
the origin of the civil rights movement,
uh,
maybe a trace to this period,
the civil rights act of 1964
a recall that also we were,
we're getting more deeply embedded in
the war in Vietnam at that point in time.
And Environmental Ism was, uh, growing
up, uh, uh, creeping up on the agenda. Uh,
but it was really quite an
interesting period. Congress
Hower was preoccupied, uh,
other than making some minor revisions
to the statute that included adding these
words, caution, warning and hazard
depending upon the relative toxicity.
This didn't really help very much because
of public confusion about what those
phrases meant. And the Department
of Agriculture Secretary,
I was given the authority finally to
remove pesticides from the market, uh,
based upon a finding of
imminent hazard to the public.
Now EPA was created in 1970 a and it
was given the responsibility to manage
pesticides and it was
consolidated from other agencies,
some 15 or 16 different sub units of
different agencies were pulled together to
create,
to create EPA back in 1970,
including the department of Agriculture
that had formerly had the pesticide, uh,
management responsibility. So you can
imagine, you know, an entire, uh, uh,
sub bureaucracies picking up and
moving their materials to EPA and a,
the stories from some of the early
administrators about how they did this and
what the effect was, or a really quite
striking. Uh, they described that, uh,
the Department of Agriculture had
kept files on individual chemicals.
They were completely disorganized.
I'll often just handwritten, uh,
often with no environmental science data,
often no testing of,
of chemical presence in,
in a different commodities that it had
been a license license to be used on.
And, uh, some chemicals
had no data at all.
So Epa was in this situation of becoming
immediately responsible for 70,000
different pesticide registrations.
Uh,
the public was quite concerned about
these residues getting into their bodies
and into the environment and
the wildlife effects. Uh,
so they felt a lot of heat
and increasingly environmental
laws had these, uh,
citizen's suit provisions.
So Epa was getting sued in the early
1970s and they got sued on, on a,
a variety of compounds such as
DDT and Aldrin, the Dieldrin.
And they were forced to go back and look
at the data that they had available.
And they found that they really had very
little data to justify many of these
registrations,
but the law was set up that forced them
to look at at a this problem chemical at
a time.
So if you've got 70,000
different chemicals and the
law requires that you look
at them one at a time and you've got a
staff that doesn't have the basic data in
place, this basically put the
regulatory process in deep freeze.
So how would you manage
that if you are responsible?
Well,
Congress thought about this and they
allocated more and more money to the
Environmental Protection Agency and EPA
became much more aggressive and started
banning chemicals.
They ban DDT first and then Aldrin
and then Dieldrin haptic floor,
and then Cordain. All of these
were the coronated hydrocarbons.
The fifth for amendments in 1975 gave
the secretary of Agriculture Authority to
be notified a pending cancellations,
uh,
which meant that he was given a voice,
to oppose cancellations. Uh, but, uh,
the environmental protection agency,
he really became the, the
stewards for, for, uh,
a human health and environmental quality
so that the secretary of ag agriculture,
his voice was diminishing in the 1970s.
Uh,
Congress also recognize that boy,
you know,
EPA is not making much progress
on this sea of chemicals,
so they better do something about it.
They mandated that each chemical had to
be reviewed within a nine year deadline.
Well,
EPA was not able to accomplish that.
So the 70s and the eighties and
nineties are all great examples, uh,
of what I call the rule of 20,
uh, that each chemical, uh,
might get some attention every 20 years.
But what does that mean?
You can think about the fact that a
new chemicals are being added to the
marketplace. A new registrations
are being issued. Uh,
the data aren't lousy and a EPA is taking
20 years to review a single chemical.
Uh, that doesn't make sense.
The science is evolving at a,
at a lightening pace on where the
chemicals are in the environment, uh,
or what the health effects are or what
the effects on different species are.
And Epa is like this,
uh,
ship is a frozen, it's, it's icebound, uh,
unable to move with the speed that,
that it really need me to, to, well,
this was recognized by the National
Academy of Sciences in to two publications
that I had a chance to work on a one
regulating pesticides and food. Uh,
that really critique the Delaney paradox.
And, uh, a bunch of us thought that, uh,
the zero risk standard is it had
been interpreted by the food and Drug
Administration.
A really did not make much sense.
A FDA had had interpreted zero
risk to mean a little bit of risk.
So a de minimis is the
phrase that, uh, uh, it used.
And De minimis means a trivial amount of
risk and they define that generally as
a one in a million risk
threshold. So that, uh,
this was a, a, a curious experience
for me because it was my first, uh,
uh, exploration of the human
diet and its variability.
So I started pouring through
food intake surveys, uh,
which is the reason that I asked a section
on Monday night to keep track of just
one day of your own diet. You
know, think about that. Uh, uh,
what foods do you eat as a way of thinking
about how patterns in your diet might
lead to predictable patterns of,
of your exposure to residues that
had been allowed by government.
So in this case, uh, we were looking only
at that subset of chemicals, uh, that, uh,
had some evidence of carcinogenicity so
that these chemicals induce cancer in
animals or we're known to
induce cancer cancer in humans.
And when we were thinking particularly
about how cancer risk might add up across
the chemicals, so a hundred different
chemicals, uh, that are, are,
are cancer inducing and
laboratory experiments,
how would you deal with that
issue of risk additives? It would,
would it be possible that, uh, uh,
there may be a negative effect on risk
if you had to chemical exposures at the
same time?
Well,
scientists have found some cases where
that actually occurred where a lower risk
chemical is able to bind onto a site
in a cell and prevent a higher risk
chemical from doing the same thing.
In other cases,
there's a synergistic relationship
so that, uh, the, the,
the risk is not just additive,
uh,
but if you're exposed to chemical
a and then chemical B, Oh,
you've got a higher risk of,
of getting cancer.
So working with a bunch of specialists
and cancer as well as specialists in and
residue chemistry and exposure, uh,
analysis. We came up with, uh, uh,
uh, not to, uh,
complimentary picture of the way that
EPA had regulated carcinogens in the food
and recommended also that,
uh,
they pay much more attention
to the individual diet, uh,
that the Diet, uh, was the,
uh,
likely to be the key root of exposure
to a variety of different chemicals.
The second book flowed from the first by
the National Academy of Sciences called
Pesticides in the diets
of infants and children.
And at this focused on of
finding inside the red book, uh,
the finding that there's
a lot of variability out
there in the diets that, uh,
people eat, that that is quite
predictable. So if you're Italian,
you're likely to eat more tomato
products. Uh, if you're Latino,
you're likely to eat more corn
products. Uh, if you are, uh, uh,
an African African American from the
southern part of the United States, uh,
people generally eat more greens.
Uh, if you are living in California,
you're going to eat more fresh produce
than you would if you live in the
northeast. Uh, it's a,
it's cost does not go up the way
that it does in the northeast.
So diet vary by season. I had
varied by region of the country. Uh,
it varies by age. Uh, and it also
varies quite a bit by ethnicity.
So if you don't understand these
differences and dietary patterns,
you really don't have much hope of,
of understanding the variability in the
chemical matrix that these individual
diets might convey into your body.
So it also presents a really kind of
an interesting idea that you could use
cropping patterns is a way of predicting
which chemicals make their way into
certain environments. So if, if, uh,
you were looking at the effect of corn
on environmental quality in the United
States corn production,
you'd want to know where is it planted
predominantly in the Midwestern part of
the u s uh, Ground Zero is,
is, uh, uh, pretty much, uh,
Iowa through Ohio and
Pennsylvania. And, uh, if,
if you map out the pattern of
chemical use, you'll see that, uh,
herbicides are applied
much more intensely, uh,
in this area than in other
parts of the nation. Uh,
and that explains why herbicide residues
are detectable in the water supplies of
a nearly 30 million people in
the United States and also in,
in a human tissues.
So that this understanding of dietary
diversity turned out to be extremely
important,
uh,
because it had been completely neglected
by environmental law and the diversity
in patterns of exposure in
environmental law is something that, um,
uh, I became curious about and wondered
about whether or not you'd find the same
thing relative to a drinking water.
Would you find the same issue
relative to air quality? Uh,
are there pockets of high exposure out
there in the population that could be
predictable,
that would make environmental law and
regulation able to focus in a way that was
more effective? And the answer is yes. Uh,
so as we look across cases over the
next, uh, next couple of a weeks,
we'll see the same pattern emerging that
once you understand variability in the,
in the Diet, in other words,
once you focus in and you,
you look for, uh, you know,
pockets of a high exposure,
high a consumption of corn or hike
consumption of a certain cluster of foods,
or you look at a certain
populations such as athletes, uh,
that have a higher respiration rate,
then then nonathletes to, uh, that, uh,
that because of that higher respiration
rate, they're going to absorb more,
more chemicals that are present
in the, in the air. So, uh,
across a whole array of different kinds
of environmental problems that are
managed by law, there's basically, uh,
there had been a neglect of
this issue of variability.
So how do you take a body of law such
as the body that I just described to you
for a, these chemicals and transform
it to be more sensitive, uh,
to the reality of these patterns
of chemical use and exposure.
So what I'm painting here is a picture
of what I think of is fractured a science
and fractured law so that
the legal authority from
pesticides is now broken into
three different bureaus,
the environmental protection agency that
is responsible for tolerance setting,
but also toxicity testing.
The Food and drug administration is
responsible for detecting residues in the
food supply.
And the Department of Agriculture is
responsible for the enforcement of these
statutes in meat and poultry and also
for the assessment of economic benefits
associated with producing
the nation's food supply.
So you've got these different agencies
with different legal mandates and they
tend not to talk to one another.
So that the a in Great Britain,
they've created a new food
safety organization that, uh,
is really quite a distinctive as a model.
They had the same fractured pattern of
bureaucratic control and Great Britain.
And, uh, they decided that that,
uh, they would consolidate,
that they'd centralize the
authority in one group. And it's,
it's very curious because by doing that,
uh,
it is allowed conservative
administrations, uh,
to slow down regulation and to become
less environmentally protective, uh,
much more quickly than if the authority
is, is diffused among different agencies.
So this is a very interesting
kind of a problem.
The primary authority for tolerance
setting was taken away from the Department
of Agriculture,
just like the authority for regulating
nuclear power was taken away from the
Atomic Energy Commission. So the nuclear
regulatory commission was created.
So you don't,
you don't want the producer and the
protector of the public interest to be
sitting inside the same organization.
That's really the key principle
for those
of you that I haven't stunned to death,
uh, enough with this lecture so far. Uh,
if you want to know more about
pesticide science and history in law,
I published this book, uh, about 10
years ago and this really details the,
the description of how we discovered
that kids were more exposed to many
different pesticides and
adults, uh, that, uh, uh, uh,
was eventually adopted into the Food Crop
Quality Protection Act passed in 1996.
So this law was designed to,
to deal with this problem of,
of risk being not equally distributed
in society and it included a new general
safety standard.
It did away with the risk
benefit balancing standard
and it said, okay, instead,
uh,
EPA must make its choices based upon the
phrase reasonable certainty of no harm.
It's kind of interesting. If you were, if
you were given the assignment to, to uh,
uh, include a decision standard in a
statute that was health protective, uh,
what would you choose?
Would you choose a balancing standard?
Probably not a,
would you choose the Delaney clause model,
which is a zero risk
standard? You might, uh,
would you choose a standard such as
this reasonable certainty of no harm?
While you can imagine that this is
hammered out politically, uh, in,
in Congress with great interest on the
part of chemical companies and also, uh,
uh,
food manufacturers to try to understand
what its implications might be for them,
it also requires a finding of safety.
This had not been part
of the law until 1996.
So we pay must now find that uh,
uh, chemicals are safe for children.
This is really quite new and striking.
Uh,
and it requires a 10 fold additional
safety factor to account for uncertainty
and the data that they have as they
set their limits so that this idea of a
buffer zone,
if you think the risk is x,
then you have to allow x over what,
uh,
in order to set your standard
for exposure. While is it, uh,
do you want a 10 fold safety factor?
Uh,
do you want to a hundred
fold a thousand fold? Well,
the tradition had been to use
a hundred fold safety factor.
So if you think that this is what it is,
you account for your,
your absence of knowledge or
your ignorance by dividing
the allowable level by a
hundred. And in this case, Congress
said, that's not good enough.
You have to divide it by an additional
10 to account for the uncertainty about
the distributional patterns
and also the issue of,
of some groups being more susceptible
to these chemicals than, than others.
It also required that the
agency for the first time, uh,
needed to consider how people might
be exposed to the same chemical, uh,
not just from, from a food, uh, or, uh,
different crops, uh, but
food, drinking water, uh,
and other kinds of environments.
So the same chemical might be sprayed on
the fruits and vegetables and it might
get into dairy cattle,
uh,
but it also might be sprayed in your
apartment building or also might be a used
as an algaecide in a, in a
swimming pool. Uh, so that, uh,
formerly EPA had just kind of given up
licenses as USDA had to these different
allowable uses and not thought about
the fact that to somebody is a basically
walk through their daily life.
Uh,
it could be exposed to
the same chemical across,
across these environmental compartments,
so to speak.
So the idea of aggregate risk is new
and it's an attempt to think about the
complexity of the way that these
compounds can move through a environments.
The idea of cumulative risk is also knew,
uh,
the government had to consider
the idea that, uh, you know,
a group of chemicals might act the same
way in the human body and the risk might
be at least additive if not a synergistic.
So for the first time in 1996, EPA had
to review all of his tolerances to,
to think about this
issue of cumulative risk.
And the pace of review was also sped
up so that all chemicals that, uh, had,
had licensed had to be reviewed by 2006,
uh, that was accomplished. You know,
we're quite remarkably,
uh, but, uh, the, uh,
the critique I could give you a
of the quality of the review is,
is a different matter.
Uh, and finally, uh,
Congress directed the agency not to
give equal attention to every pesticide,
but to come through or to develop
some sort of a strategy to,
to concentrate and focus on chemicals
that it thought a would be the most risky.
So how would you do that?
How would you define the most risky
chemicals while you try to find those that
had the highest a dose response rate?
In other words,
they seem like they were the most potent,
are the most toxic,
but you also probably want to concentrate
on chemicals that were persistent
chemicals that got into
different environmental
compartments or chemicals that
were used in, in, uh, food or, or
environments that people freak.
Frequent foods that people eat a lot
of, or environments that, uh, uh, we're,
we're highly frequented such
as schools or, or, uh, uh,
such as, uh, uh, occupational
settings or, or, or homes. Uh,
so that the idea of strategic attention
to the most toxic chemicals is an
important concept. So,
uh, what's happened here,
as you think back across history,
you've got kind of a sequence of
changing regulatory priorities.
And you might ask yourself, well, why
is that? So the first attempt backed in,
in 2019 Oh six,
was to protect the economy of farmers
against fraudulent labeling. Uh,
then the obligation, uh, became
to protect food and a crap uses.
So set limits for levels of revenue
in different kinds of foods.
Uh,
then wildlife,
wildlife remedies became extremely
important as people worry about, uh,
how chemicals were causing decline
in species that, uh, were really, uh,
much loved in the United
States, particularly large
raptors, a bald eagles, uh,
the national symbol or the Golden Eagle,
uh,
the Peregrine Falcon ospreys that,
now you can see coming back along
the shoreline here in Connecticut.
If you take the train from new
haven up to Boston, for example,
and look out over the salt marshes,
you'll see these polls, uh,
sitting in the middle of the salt marshes
with Osprey's ospreys came very close
to extinction because of the chemical
DDT that was building up and it's,
it's body and causing its
egg shells to thin. Uh,
so it's reproductive success declined.
Soil contamination became important,
uh, as instances where chemical had
been used in the field one year and had
persisted in that field.
Uh,
another tenant farmer comes along the
next year and plants a different crop.
That crop is not permitted to
have that chemical used on it,
but it absorbed the chemical
up through, uh, its roots,
uh, and becomes adulterated.
So that failure to think about soil
contamination was causing some foods to
become adulterated in ways that were
not predictable and drinking water
contamination has come late to the
attention of the environmental protection
agency. Why would that be? You know,
if you think about water as one of the
most consumed foods in the human diet,
why wouldn't the government have
paid more attention to water? Also,
think about indoor environments.
Uh,
I've come to believe that all of
the attention given to food, uh,
is really probably misplaced a relative
to exposures that occur in indoor
environments so that in many situations
today people can be in rooms,
uh, when they are sprayed
by a licensed applicator.
So they exposures that occur
after that, uh, often are far,
far higher than the exposures that
come from food borne residues.
The idea that the susceptible need,
need attention.
This is new and environmental law has
of 1996 and new areas that deserve
additional attention that, that, uh,
I think are extremely important is
the use of these chemicals as they're
impregnated into a variety of consumer
products. So, you know, if you're,
if you're hiking long distances,
you may want a pesticide impregnated
into the fabric that you buy if you don't
have an opportunity to, to
wash your clothes. Uh, but
what, what does that mean? Uh,
there are whole new array of products
in the marketplace now that carry these
residues,
uh,
for obvious functions
such as is durability,
keeping them from degrading pesticides
are added to paints, for example,
to keep the bacteria in
paint from breaking it down
and shipping and causing you
to have to, uh, to, uh,
you know, repaint in,
in a short period of time so that the
functional side of these chemicals used in
consumer products is
pretty well understood. Uh,
but the longterm implications for
environmental quality and human health,
really or not.
So the underlying problems here include
the human inability to sense chemical
risk.
You know,
we basically don't know
where these chemicals are in
our environment because we
can't see them. We can't taste them.
Uh, we can't feel them. We have to,
we have to imply where
they are, uh, by, uh,
by proxy a thinking about,
Gee, you know, I live near,
I'm living on a track of
land and I've got a, well,
and this used to be a farmland. Maybe
I had a test my drinking water, uh,
or I'm living next to a field that is
plant that is planted with a crop that's
routinely sprayed by a plane that
flies over. Maybe the drift is,
is getting into my, uh,
into my environment.
So that thinking about where these things
are in the environment really demands
a certain level of background
literacy and knowledge, uh,
that often is not present. The underlying
problem of lack of sensitivity to,
to susceptibility is really important.
Uh, who's susceptible? Well, the,
the very youngest are,
uh,
remember that all of these concentrations
are measured how they're expressed per
unit of your body weight.
So when in life, uh,
does a human had the lowest body
weight in utero first trimester.
So if the concentration in
the mom is the same, uh,
moving across the placenta
as the concentration in
the fetus and you get to an
exposure estimate by taking
that concentration and
dividing it by body weight
and the mom's body weight might be 160
pounds and the fetus is body weight might
be a quarter of a pound. I'm
sorry. Sorry Laura. About this,
you get the idea.
The same concentration in the environment
affects the fetus much more than it
would, uh, the average adult.
So this has really transformed the way
that a government regulators have begun
to think about chemical management.
We've had poor monitoring
of chemical release. Uh,
we have thought much more about chemical
persistence and environmental fate
having learned from strontium
90 and the DDT story. Uh,
and we've under misunderstood
variability in human exposure. Still,
we're not putting monitors
on individual people,
although increasingly the government
is, is uh, uh, monitoring human tissue,
taking blood and urine, uh, and hair
samples to try to figure out, you know,
what the, what the Matrix
or chemicals might be that,
that an individual is exposed to.
So looking not just by a
sampling in the marketplace, uh,
but looking at this pattern by
taking human tissue samples,
this is a whole new wave that's giving
people the opportunity literally to go to
a doctor and say, I want to be measured
for this entire array of chemicals.
So it may cost you a couple thousand
dollars to go through that process.
But increasingly people are doing this,
trying to make some sense out of the way
that they feel their medical condition
and a environmental quality,
single chemical exposure is
still the focus of government.
No company wants it's chemical
to be compared to another
company. When, uh, when,
uh, uh, they're making
a regulatory choice, uh,
toxicity testing is incomplete and a
variety of areas, uh, especially, uh,
relative to the immune system. And,
you know, the rise in allergies that a,
we're experiencing a severe allergies.
Uh,
more people are walking around with
Epi pens today because of, of, uh, uh,
worries about anaphylaxis
than ever before.
Something is happening to the human
immune system. It's not clear why,
but many of the chemicals that are
released such as some pesticides, uh,
do influence the human immune system.
That's one example of an area of human
health that has been neglected by,
by the government. Uh, also
the Endocrin, uh, affects are,
are quite, uh, uh,
misunderstood the, the, uh, uh,
behavior of these chemicals as human
hormones that we'll speak about a bit next
week. Uh, also failure of
labeling as a management strategy.
Labeling is still the dominant approach
that EPA takes to try to inform the
public,
to educate the public how they might be
able to use these economic poisons a in
a safe way.
But you need to think about whether or
not that's really a potentially effective
way of controlling these kinds of risks.
And we're also misunderstanding, uh,
trends in human illness.
Uh, W for example, uh,
we had no asthma registry in
Connecticut until I'm not 2003,
so we couldn't figure out
whether or not, uh, uh,
people that lived in areas that had
higher levels of air pollution, uh,
were more likely to have asthma.
So the absence of surveillance
of health conditions, uh,
makes it impossible to correlate
these exposures to health outcomes.
And finally, a variance and
human capacity to manage risk.
There's a real environmental justice
here that needs to be paid attention to,
that there are many members of society
that do not have the capacity, uh,
to get the education necessary
to self manage risk. Uh, so that,
uh, some people, uh, simply
are more reliant on government
standard setting than,
than other people are. So these are
all underlying problems of law. Uh,
and all of them are pretty
well exemplified by this
history of pesticide, uh,
uh, uh, management. Okay.
That's it for today. And, uh,
we'll come back on Tuesday,
have a great weekend.