Everybody to the h three podcasts,
we were formally known as the h three
experience,
but I have to say after meditating this
weekend,
I believe we are now the age three
transsexual.
Welcome to the correct opinion.
This is the Tuesday episode where we
talk about current events and basically
everything you're going to hear here is
the correct opinion.
You need another one of those.
This is no longer an experience.
My friend did it work then.
Now I guess we missed to hit it one more
time.
Let's turn it off that weekend guys.
Today's episode is sponsored by honey
and I want to plead you all guys,
please everyone who watches on Youtube,
head on over to itunes,
spotify,
Google podcast,
play whatever the heck they're doing and
subscribe to us there so you can get us
in your car and your commune.
Wherever the heck you are,
where you don't get access to videos.
Listen to us on the podcasting APP.
Let's get those numbers up because we
are transcending the genre and the
experience itself,
so slammed those subscribe buttons and
do your boy a solid.
This Friday.
We've got tim height are coming up.
What,
what?
Excited about that?
So don't miss that.
Or we were on.
Um,
yeah,
last night.
Yeah,
we were on killed.
Tony killed.
Tony is the number one they love saying.
Yeah,
that's true.
Number one,
live podcast,
light world,
but it's alive in front of a live
audience and they do it every Monday
night at the comedy store.
They tour a lot too,
but they were gracious enough to have us
on the show and it was a blast.
So those guys are awesome.
I can't wait to have them in here.
Life Kill Tony.
Check it out.
We were on their,
their,
their show,
but obviously don't click away because
we're just getting started.
I'm most importantly,
we need to talk about Papa John.
Yeah,
let's let us by.
John is having a meltdown.
Papa John's spent a little too much time
on the pizza.
I'm saying I liked my pizza a little
overcooked,
but this pizza is.
This pizza's a little too overcooked.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
I'm check this out.
So Papa John,
as you guys all know,
they're late.
Great.
Papa John,
who was outed from Papa John,
there's a whole,
there's like a whole kind of paradoxical
situation going on with Papa Johns.
Papa John is trying to kick Papa John
Out,
but how can papa John Be Papa John
Without Papa John?
So Papa John the company is trying to
kick out Papa John the person the
Shatner,
but they are proper.
John just change your name at that
point.
Your Papa John Pizza.
You can't separate the pizza from the
man so they're trying to distance
themselves from here as much as possible
like his face is all over.
So they removed his face from the
branding that was white.
That's what was the final Straw for papa
himself.
He's like,
you cannot take my face off that Pi box.
No,
because basically my face looks like a
pizza pie.
I've spent so much time near a pizza
oven and it's basically a preview of
what's going to be like when you open
it,
but they're saying we can't be dependent
on one person,
especially this person.
So he made.
This is.
I love this story.
This is just so he made a website,
papa himself called.
Hey Papa John Dot com.
I am Papa John like a Spartagen
[inaudible].
You know that although I am Papa John,
he,
he acts like it's a social movement
where like everyone fucking cares so
much about Papa John.
I am Papa John.
We,
you,
you shall not silence us.
We are,
we are,
we are pizza.
So let me read you some of the excerpts.
You know how long the actual their
website.
When you order a pizza you can choose
the toppings and then in like phones,
like always.
Oh yeah,
I know finance.
Who is here still on this website?
You can still order a pizza from Papa
John's dot com.
I'm here.
You guys.
Let me read.
This is the,
the his homepage.
So let me read it.
An excerpt here for,
for you all here.
I built Papa John's from the ground up
and remain its largest shareholder.
I love my company,
its employees,
its franchisees.
Customers don't love you anymore.
The board wants to silence me.
This is my website and my way to talk to
you.
Save Papa John's dot com.
As I said in a recent letter,
I miss you all very much.
How the fuck you get claimed them?
You're just.
You're a pizza CEO.
I missed you guys all you fat,
butter,
loving sauced,
gluttonous.
Sons of bitches I love.
Sometimes I'm at home and I imagined
suck in the butter garlic sauce off your
fingers.
I miss it that much.
I miss you very much more than words can
express sometime that day though more
than words can express sometimes garlic
sauce because sometimes I rub garlic,
salt,
peanuts and use it as a lubricant.
It reminds me of how much I love you.
Better Times.
Papa John's is our life's work and we
will all get this together somehow.
Some way.
I can only imagine how difficult this
entire situation is on.
You know,
he goes from I to we,
I feel it.
Papa John's and then he's like,
is our life's work?
We will all get through this imagined
papa John's saying to just some fucking
guy,
the orders pizza from there at once a
week.
I can only imagine how difficult this
entire situation is on you.
I feel like you run this to you,
right?
I think he wrote it to himself.
I'm very sorry that you all have to go
through this.
Just know that
I still finger my wife with butter.
Garlic sauce though is listening.
Ethan and Beau don't even get me started
about that.
Kid Ain't right.
I can only imagine how hard this has
been on boat.
We pack his lunch with butter,
garlic sauce every day,
and this,
this part is real.
Know that in every minute of every day
you're in my thoughts and my prayers.
Who exactly drama queen included in this
website or links to recent press
releases,
news articles and recipes to my world.
Famous garlic sauce,
which also doubles as a really good sex
lubricant to remind you of the better
times.
Signed.
Sincerely,
pop up.
Butter,
garlic,
salt shatner.
Oh,
he also wrote,
we are getting the truth out there.
Garlic,
my bar,
my butter garlic sauce was invented as I
tried to make my own sex lubricant.
My wife tasted it accidentally and said,
hey,
pretty good.
That was emotional.
Beautiful Journey.
A roller coaster.
And um,
except for the sex stuff that is all
written,
that was very dramatic,
Papa.
I mean,
I don't know in his mind he really sees
this as a big pizza war when people are
picking sides there.
He has a lot of support.
I mean there's people demonstrating
outside the White House right now,
Free Papa
and his mind.
And it's fine.
It's a,
it really is a war right now.
But when Papa John's and Papa Johns,
Papa Johns exist without Papa John.
No,
just like when the civil war happened,
a country divided cannot stand as the
Abraham Lincoln famously said.
And I feel that Papa John is kind of a
pizza civil rights leader in his own
right when the Cold War.
This isn't a hot or this is a hot oven.
A cheesy on other than about.
Oh,
this is just his life story.
Um,
new.
He's actually got all the legal papers
because he's suing Papa John.
It's like,
dude,
y'all started a war with a fucking.
Make sure you could finish it.
He's got feed some money.
Anyway,
I just loved his little cover letter.
So pop.
I wish you all the best in your fight.
There's a standing invitation for Papa
to complete his case on our show.
We had previously reached out and better
times,
and I have to say papa passed.
He said,
I got Peyton manning throwing pizzas
into the American living rooms of
everywhere.
Now all the sudden.
Who would you have left?
Papa?
Who Do you have left?
Me.
That's who it's time to.
Come on this show.
Bring the butter garlic sauce because
we're going to have a good old fashion.
Reach around soggy pizza.
Anyone know what that is?
Soggy,
soggy pizza when the pizza got saggy.
Or is this like a metaphor for something
else?
Is it Swiss?
Papa knows I'm Alex Jones is in the news
again,
but this time you may not expect why
this,
this story just cracked me up.
I had to talk about this.
All right,
now Alex Jones.
Uh,
you know and love him.
You guys.
I'm sorry.
I think our stream just got pulled down.
Why?
No,
I'm just kidding.
You going to ask you.
I felt for them.
I let him go look.
So stupid.
I was going to make a joke like that.
Dan,
come on.
You guys need to coordinate the jokes
here.
Well,
he gives me.
Well I am,
I am somewhat hesitant to mention the
boogie man's name.
Alex Jones.
J A J.
um,
so he,
you know,
Mr.
turn the frogs gay was doing a
advertisement during his show recently.
Let me show you the video that he was
watching and,
and tell me if you catch something in
this video because it's fried.
It's brief,
but the um,
the internet super,
super sleuths did find it.
So watch closely.
No,
I heard about it from family and then
George Dorian and others that I had to
get involved.
Info wars?
Yes.
At infowars.com
to go look all of this up.
Oh,
did you catch it?
No.
How does he talk?
How does that guide that end of the day?
Talk to her.
Um,
I like that is,
he's all jacked up advertising in
nutrition when it's.
Sorry,
it's the Alex Jones voice.
Fuck my throat up.
Or was he doing an ad for skincare?
I love it.
He's so funny,
man.
He thought he puts on so many hats,
like he'll,
he'll advertise anything and all of a
sudden he's doing info wars.
Yes.
It's like a Martha Stewart brand.
If it was.
Yes.
Get your skincare products over here at.
Well.
Anyway,
so what was that George?
Nora and others that I had to get
involved.
Info wars.
Yes.
There's no space in that informs
cash.com
to go look all of the
looks like flesh.
So he's showing all of his open tab
browsing and.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
So the Internet super sleuth went to
work crunching the numbers.
A touring the frogs gay.
And what came up will shock you.
Here it is.
The title of the video in question was
naughty t babe Marissa minks.
Relieved of caulk.
Hunger by stuck.
Can I open?
Can I show this?
Let me see if I can show an image of
this.
Um,
yeah.
I can't show the porn.
You know,
that,
that thing.
But it's basically,
I mean really all you need is that
title.
Let me read that for you again,
if I can.
Knotty.
T Babe stands for trans.
So grill,
penis,
for those who are not initiated,
she's naughty.
Tba.
Marissa minks.
Relieved of caulk.
Hunger by Stud.
That's how that is A.
I don't even understand half of the
sentence.
I'm really.
What do you want me to break down?
Naughty teabag.
She's a naughty girl with a big old
thick presumably.
Okay.
She and then her name is Marissa and
beings and she has.
She has an insatiable hunger.
She is so thirsty for COC.
She's so hungry.
She's relieved.
She's fine.
She has this insatiable hunger for coc,
but yet.
But what's this done?
I feel like I know that.
I want to make sure that if the guy that
fucks.
Okay,
think it goes back to a horse.
It's a horse though,
but it's like that guy's a fucking stud.
So this girl with this insatiable hunger
for coc has finally after all of her
searching on the earth for this one
study that could relieve for thirst for
coc,
she was relieved of Caulk,
hunger by Stud.
So that's pretty interesting.
I'm not one to judge,
you know,
watch whatever you want.
But it is Alex Jones and he did have a
video titled Naughty Tba Marie Main
Relieved,
relieved of caulk hunger.
I love the Alex Jones was watching that.
He hasn't addressed it by the way.
Oh,
I mean how,
what do say yes,
she was relieved of our hunger.
To be fair,
he may,
he may have addressed it,
but I hunted really hard and that this
is such outstanding news that if you,
if you google anything related to this,
all you're going to find his articles
about,
you know,
this insatiable tb.
The interesting thing about Alex Jones
watching a transport is that heat,
one of his strikes that he got before
the closure of his gentle was four.
He called Trans people mentally ill.
Oh,
that's nice because like you maybe
mentally ill,
but I'm,
I mean that doesn't mean I can't beat
off to it.
Does that make him mentally ill if he
likes it?
I guess it does.
By calling.
Maybe would have said.
Couldn't make him say that.
I just love.
This is so funny.
So funny man.
I'm so relieved of caulk hunger.
Next time you see Alex Jones,
just remember that by
hmm.
Nice little story.
Great little story which we had Alex
Jones to call him and tell us about
[inaudible] 90 day fiance.
Love this show.
We've talked about a lot about the show.
Ninety Ninety Day fiance.
Yeah.
And Fisa and George the a gold digger
Isa.
So this store,
this,
this show is just a goldmine.
Ninety day fiance eats well here.
I thought this show was like an old
show,
but it's still going.
Oh Man.
I mean it may have been around for,
I don't know.
How long has it been around?
Just looks like it's from the night is.
Yeah.
But it's still going.
I got to set dvr to record this show
because it seems like got to be one of
the more entertaining shows on TV.
Um,
so this lady has married,
I believe in African and she is an
Africa visiting the family now.
The family,
one of their native dishes is snails and
she's very hesitant to eat the snails,
which makes sense to me,
but be respectful in their face of your
fiance's family and you meet the snails
and you enjoy them.
Right.
Okay.
She's,
you know,
she doesn't seem to be someone who has a
problem eating food,
so she doesn't seem necessarily that she
should have a problem putting it down.
But
yeah,
it looks good.
It looks cooked up.
I mean
got a little nice like tomato sauce in
there.
Little creamy.
Okay.
So native dish.
Just a central person except for being
respectful to his mom for every meal.
I'm going to taste.
She out there,
but God,
I'm terrified right now.
It's very quiet.
It's a quiet predestined is I'm a boost
in it as much as possible.
So cell phone quality.
If she takes a little bite and going
okay with it,
he ripped off and sent her mouth and a
kiss me,
her fiance,
me and get it out of my mouth.
Oh,
they're watching by the way,
you're not slipping up.
So what are you doing?
They saw that.
Yeah.
So she basically said to her fiance,
kiss me and let me spit it into your
mouth so that I don't have to chew it
anymore.
That's not paying respect to anyone.
I mean,
that's horrifying thing to witness.
Just handed out on your plate and say,
hey man,
hey for me.
Hey,
come here.
Pretend to kiss me.
I'll spit in your mouth.
Nobody will know.
They're all like,
they're all like cameras staring right
at you.
And it was like three cameras watching.
Hey,
let's get.
Let's get another one of that day.
Let's get a slow mo if we can put it in
the slower.
The speed here.
No,
no,
no.
Yeah man.
Let's see.
Let's get a close look.
Guess me.
She's like,
damn,
I only don't.
She's like,
I only fuck with butter.
Garlic sauce.
Say Papa.
Say Papa John Dot Com.
This white American.
This takes on a whole new vibe here.
Coaster comes to past and that is a
romantic kiss
I've ever seen.
One sucks
right out of her mouth.
Any fucking choose it to that God damn
mvp.
That guy just saved the day.
Thank you Michael.
And he's like,
man,
the things I do for a green card,
these relationships on these shows are
really all about getting a green card.
I don't think any of these relationships
were genuine.
So it's really what's so interesting
about this show is like,
what is this one person is willing to
take?
Right?
It's like one eligible datable person
matched up with one completely
undateable person and then you kind of
just see how much that one datable
person can do indoor for a green card.
And I think that guy in this moment
reached his limit it did it.
No.
Yeah,
he did it.
Hmm.
Am Very special stuff.
Guys.
Want shows on fire today.
Are you saying that you wouldn't suck a
snail out of [inaudible] mouth?
I suck.
Garlic butter sauce out of your mouth.
In fact,
I think I have in fact.
Isla.
No,
you are.
You sure did you know that I for me,
I'm going to go there to shows on fire
today.
We are killing it.
All I'm saying is that next time you
order Papa John Pizza,
Save Papa John Dot Com.
Try replacing.
Yeah.
You're a sex lube with butter,
garlic sauce and see if that doesn't get
you somewhere new.
Nice.
This is one of your advisors.
I read it on Safe Papa John Dot com.
It's under tabs of tech of techniques
and strategies.
Nearing my asshole.
This is what we all came for a lot of
debate over last week about wiping
techniques about how best to approach
the Asshole,
how best to clean it,
how best to manicure it.
I received an email from somebody that
said they near their asshole and that it
changed their life for the better.
I was so intrigued because it was so
insane.
So preposterous.
I have an idea that,
um,
I thought I had to try it out.
I'm Ila says,
why do I keep saying messing on
strangers,
but you're getting messages from
strangers on discord.
I wrote to Dan,
but yeah.
Well now I'm intrigued and you're
getting bombed by strangers on discord.
I just keep saying all kinds of
notifications on my cell.
I'm isla.
I'm talking about narrowing my asshole.
Can you please focus?
So I was trying to distract myself from
the onset.
What the fuck they found you?
Who found her?
I don't know.
These are just like,
we're just in a private channel,
which was does.
I don't know who's Raz sneaking in.
Oh No.
Our private discourse getting
infiltrated.
But we are talking about narrowing my
asshole.
So if everyone could please focus
almost.
Sorry.
So anyway,
I was about,
I was going to near my asshole because
it just seems so insane.
I was like,
for the sake of the show,
let's do it.
Yeah.
But the other side of me was like,
this is kind of really weird,
insane thing to do.
And you could burn your skin.
Yeah.
And the asshole is pretty sensitive,
right?
Apparently from what I understand.
But then I also,
I had a feeling that this guy was
fucking with me.
He seemed genuine,
but I can see someone be like,
I'm gonna get Ethan and narrows asshole
knowing full well that would ruin my
life.
So another great fan emailed me and was
like,
dude,
do not near your app.
And here is why.
And he sent me this craigslist story
that was so funny.
I had to read it to you because I had to
share it with you guys.
So for now this story alone put my
narrow,
my asshole on.
Hold on,
hold on.
I'm still open to it.
Frankly.
We got the product at home.
Yeah,
I have the PR.
I got three.
I don't know why an Amazon.
They made me buy three bottles.
Looks like on this fucking weird guy.
It's just like I have an apocalypse,
a stash of narrowing my asshole.
Look,
the world may be ending,
but my asshole is going to be clean.
One of them was called involves bomb.
Oh yeah.
I wanted to say in my pursuit of the
sensitive nature that would've burned my
asshole.
I found a product called balls bomb
that's made for applying to your balls.
Balls.
Bomb Guy.
Got a bike,
some balls bond.
So I don't know.
I've got balls bomb.
Yeah.
And I was thinking of just getting it,
just seeing what happens.
But you guys,
you guys read this and tell me.
I don't know.
This spooked me most.
Most definitely.
And it rang so true.
Let me zoom in on this.
So this was from craigslist,
it's called a warning,
don't shave that hair.
I've recently made a mistake in my life
and I offer my story to you that you may
learn from my air.
It all started as many things to do with
me having trouble shitting.
Did you write this?
No,
Dan,
I think we need some kind of music.
What kind of,
what kind of stories I want to play when
you play sad violin?
Let me,
let me try and find some.
Uh,
no.
I was not constipated.
This was not a regularity problem,
but a matter of technique.
It seems my ass hair had grown to such a
length that my tiny grope Grogan's we're
constantly getting tied up and the
jungle between my ass cheeks.
It led so much frustration with me
knowing that I still had something to
drop but not able to shake.
The tenacious turned loose from its butt
hair dwelling eventually would have to
do two things,
either reached down with some paper and
try to pinch off the lingering low,
which required careful precision to
avoid smearing the creature over my
rear.
Especially since I had no way of seeing
what I was doing or just go for broke,
start wiping and hope that I can remove
all the leftover fecal matter before the
toilet reached.
It's can't be flushed threshold.
I was contemplating this problem.
This is very long.
Yeah.
Can you cut through the paraphrase here?
Let me paraphrase.
So Yada,
Yada,
Yada.
He did the deed.
Now I have great respect for anal hair
like everything in this world God
created.
It has.
It's all my purpose and existence.
It was only after I had removed it that
I started to learn how much I had been
taking it for granted.
For one,
it provides friction.
I learned that this next day when I
walked out into the sun,
the headed for class.
After climbing two flights of stairs and
starting to sweat,
I started to notice something
unpleasant.
The sweat was accumulating in my crap
and what's causing the unpleasant
sensation of Mike to ask Jake sliding
past each other with every step.
I thought about going to the bathroom
and starting the wipe it off,
but I had to go to class.
I thought eventually it would drive.
Unfortunately it did dry,
but only after mingling with the
microscopic shit molecules lingering
around my ground starfish.
Yes.
When I stood up after your class,
my ass chiefs were stuck together and a
slimy sticky shit sweat combination.
As that made my way back to the dorm.
It started to itch God did it itch.
I felt like a swarm of ants was making
its way up and down my craft fighting to
keep from jamming my hand down there and
scratching away.
I rushed back to the dorm.
Unfortunately again,
this excretion caused me to sweat.
And when I,
uh,
when I finally reached my room,
my cheeks were sliding back and forth
against each other like a pair of Horny
cane toads.
I quickly dropped my pants and attempted
to drive my ass by sticking it in front
of a fan and spreading my cheeks.
As I pulled the two mounds of flesh
apart,
a horrible stench burst free and filled
the room.
Every dog within four blocks started the
house.
I had the worst of it as the ripe aroma,
a festering shit and sweat went into the
fan.
And my face,
I thought to keep from heaving as I sat
there fighting,
vomit in my ass cheeks,
bread and tripping with the concentrated
aroma of my body odor mixed with the
tangy smell of my own shit blowing right
into my face.
I only had one thought.
I will be like this until my hair grows
back.
For weeks later on trying to deal as
best I could,
wiping my asset every opportunity I
discovered another wonderful use for
this ass hair ventilation.
I attempted to launch a fart only to get
it stuck between my ass cheeks.
Apparently with no hair.
The two pink twins kind of get vacuumed,
sealed together.
And the result was a frustrating fart
that slid up and down between my cheeks,
like a last durable as if there wasn't
enough.
I am known during further torture as
anyone who has ever shaved anything
knows when hair is growing,
it becomes stubble.
I imagine your ass having the texture of
a Brillo pad.
Well that is what I'm dealing with now
is a hellish torture.
And there are times when I just look out
the window and contemplate why I
shouldn't just jump out and get it all
over with rather than indoor.
This agony.
Friends,
do not shave your ass here.
Wow.
But see,
see it.
Thank.
Thank you.
Um,
thank you for that anecdote.
But what I think about is,
um,
I love the lawyer was almost vomiting.
Yeah,
I definitely get that.
Like,
but he shaved.
Okay.
I'm narrowing.
Narrowing is like shaving the stubble.
I won't deal with the stub a while.
It will grow back.
So basically once you narrow your
asshole,
you're stuck in a vicious cycle because
once that stubble grows in and you're,
I can only imagine your asshole itching
with every step.
You're back in there narrowing.
You're stuck in the net or stuck in a
loop.
Yeah,
I'm going to be doomed to a hairless
asshole forever.
Or I'm gonna have to like take two weeks
off that you can burn yourself.
Right?
And I keep telling you because I saw
him,
but he was so entertaining to be like,
okay guys,
I narrowed my asshole.
I feel like.
But then I also don't want to be the guy
that narrowed his asshole.
You know what if I bought albums,
my asshole.
It's the same thing.
I do fear of the shit and sweat of
ocean.
The potential of vomit.
God wouldn't be so great to hear you
talk about the smell of my shit and
swimming.
Yeah.
Because you'll be there.
I'll not be there.
You're going to leave me out.
He wasn't going to leave like damn I
did.
It was doing it for you man.
I was not asking for this.
Well,
I'm still intrigued,
but the guy definitely spooked me
straight.
I do want to tell you that the pole that
you did on twitter.
Oh yeah,
there hasn't been an update with the
numbers.
So let's open the pool actually.
So I was so interested in this debate
we've been having with,
with,
from the front or from the back because
again,
as I said,
there's two worlds of wipers and they
don't even know that they exist.
And I felt like an outcast my whole life
for lifting up my balls and reaching
under there.
Right.
And so I said,
I go to the HD podcasts on twitter,
the HD podcasts,
and I asked our loyal fans,
how do you wipe your ass from the front
or from the back?
And it may surprise you,
but we have a lot of the,
a lot of results here.
First of all,
66,534
people participated.
So thank you.
I feel like this is an actual legitimate
census of the American public life.
This is for men only because women only
have one option.
They're supposed to wipe away from the
badge.
And um,
I do love the top comment here.
I don't think men wipe him.
And he said,
well,
I don't know who the fuck she's been
with,
but uh,
she's had a foul.
She said some foul relationships.
Maybe she dated that guy.
We were just reading really every time
I've been with a guy just smells like
ass and sweat.
Um,
so last time it was 60 slash 40 and now
it's 60 1:39.
I feel like it's been brigaded by the
front labors.
But anyway,
39 percent wiped from the front.
Those are like minded brethren who
lifted their balls and prove and you
know,
perform a scoop from the front.
It's really a scoop.
The way I do it.
It is.
It's a scoop and scoop.
It's a skilled scoop.
Is this group that I've been developing
for a long time.
You lift the balls,
you scoop your clean baby,
you scoop the shit out.
This is a smear.
I don't know.
This is.
You can't give it back,
but 61 percent a traditional white
maybe.
But I like scoot.
You want to scoop out when you're
dealing with a bowl,
you want to be scooping out.
You can't wipe the whole.
You scoop out of a hole.
Am I right?
Thirty one percent.
Thirty nine percent of you know exactly
what I'm talking about.
Sixty one percent of you wiped from the
back and that's pretty and I have to say
I'm kind of surprised by how many of
them are out there like me that white
from the front.
That's pretty.
I mean that's really close to 50
percent.
That's a,
that's a 10 percent variance we're
talking about.
So speak up front.
Wipers don't leave me in the trenches
scoop and grenades out of my ass.
Okay.
Help me represent to the world that we
are out there.
We are strong,
we are people and we have rights.
We are pumper John and go to [inaudible]
dot com and use butter.
Garlic.
I've heard that butter garlic sauce is
so powerful.
It actually can act like Nair and
burning the hair right off.
Just again.
I'm going to try plain butter.
Garlic sauce,
my asshole tonight.
See if that works.
Um,
so I thought that was an interesting
scientific experiment.
We should do more poles because I feel
like we're actually making an important
contribution to science here.
Good.
We are really.
I feel like we're doing important things
here.
This is way more than the experience.
We have transcendent experience.
Podcasts.
Moment of silence and clarity.
We'll be right back after this break
with Logan Paul,
verse Ksi.
Stay tuned.
Okay.
Deal like free money because that.
Oh,
thank you.
You wasn't expecting a response.
Now that I know you like free money,
would you like to hear about honey?
Because that's what it does.
Is it an extension for your browser that
browses the website,
the whole Internet for the perfect
coupon for whatever you're shopping for?
Oh,
I'm on Amazon trying to buy dog food.
Oh honey,
boom coupon.
Whoa.
Just save me money like an old man
clipping coupons by the fireplace every
evening for you for free.
Honey.
That should be their slogan.
An old man clipping coupons for you as
you browse.
Don't believe me.
The Lincoln,
the description,
join [inaudible] dot com slash h three
has saved people collectively over
$102,000
in the past couple of months.
That's an average saving of $25 per
person.
You also maybe thinking the honey
doesn't work at sites that I shop at.
Well,
the truth is,
honey works on over 30,000
sites including Amazon,
Ebay,
new egg razor,
Walmart,
and more so much more.
Pretty much everywhere that I've
shopped.
Honey,
he's like,
I love.
I love using it on Amazon.
Even shows you like the price history of
a product and if it's like the lowest
now or not.
The big question is how was honey free?
What's the catch?
There's no catch your depths hunting
gets a small commission from sites.
Every time they clip a coupon for you,
so it's always free.
There's no catch.
It's easy to install.
It takes a couple of clicks and then
you're going to be off to the races
saving cash.
Give it a shot.
It's free and it literally takes 10
seconds to install.
So use the link in the description.
Join honey.com/h
three.
Try it out.
It takes two clicks in two seconds.
I guarantee you're going to love it and
you're going to say,
Dang it,
Ethan.
Thank you for joining honey.com/h
three.
Welcome back everybody.
I'm out of breath from running to the
bathroom.
Isla is not back yet.
Did we?
Where are we at a screen or was the
comeback?
Slick and perfect.
Then we did have to go to the screen for
about five seconds.
I had just gone to the screen as you
open the door.
We went to a screen.
Oh No,
not at this day would come now.
Here you come in quiet because you
turned it down.
Oh,
okay.
Damn.
We gotta we gotta get out of this
office,
this office we're in so fucking small.
You've got to run to the bathroom.
We're looking for new office.
Five second slate screen.
Oh my God.
We just got.
We just got demoted to experience.
Oh,
we were transcendent,
but we just got back down from
enlightenment.
Back to the experience and too harsh.
Okay.
Well let's get right onto the main
story.
Logan Paul,
Verse Ksi.
Everybody is talking about Logan Paul,
Verse Ksi,
the boxing match.
Isla,
who do you think?
One?
I already know what happened because you
think one.
I'm a cylon.
It was a tie.
Okay.
Suspicious.
I'll show you guys.
Let's go over some stats.
Okay.
I find this stuff really interesting.
Before I kind of talked about Logan,
Paul Brest,
Ksi,
the boxing match.
You guys have all heard of it.
I kind of got to give credit to these
guys because even if you hate them both,
it's just irresistible.
Irresistible.
You got attack about it.
You gotTa love it.
I mean really it's pretty cool and,
and it was pretty slick.
I have to,
I honestly have to give them credit.
They,
they masterminded this crazy thing.
They saw that this arena,
they have eight.
How many?
800 paperview viewers.
That's right.
I got it.
I got to give him it up,
man.
I'll pay off.
It was definitely pretty exciting.
I'm like,
on the day of like everyone was talking
about it.
Pretty cool.
Definitely some great memorable moments
in there that I'd like to share with you
guys.
But on the whole I just want to say I'm
not going to sit there and hate.
Okay.
I want to say I got to give these guys
some credit where it's due.
Yeah,
definitely taking this whole online
youtube experience to,
to a new level.
Um,
so general admission tickets started at.
I,
I'm,
I want to break this down because
they've always said this fight is bigger
than mayweather verse make rigor.
And I've heard a lot of people say that.
I understand that because that is such a
ridiculous.
I've heard them say,
and I've heard other people reporting on
it being like I heard,
um,
I've heard it in really reputable places
have been,
like they had more views than they are.
Press conference had more views,
more hype.
So I do want to break it down.
I want to compare.
I want you,
I want to show what,
what's going on here.
I mean Logan Paul,
Verse Ksi,
that's,
you can't really get more hype online
than that.
It's like Max hype.
I mean,
what,
what could you put together that's
better than that shoe?
Nice for Joey Salads.
Would you guys watch for as Joey Salads?
I would be scared to put shoe and sent
Britain niche audience that thing.
Somehow I don't see that point.
Eight hundred thousand page views to
shoe.
Nice Wood.
Fucking eat his opponent.
I want to see that.
I mean don't.
The only real option to get more than
them would be something like a pod by
pod.
Like Ryan's toy review
beat the shit out of a 12 year old.
Oh yeah,
I'd watch that.
Um,
so here's,
here's some stats for you guys.
Okay?
A general admission ticket started at
$39 with the highest price.
Going to 600 average was probably like
50 bucks a.
They sold out the arena,
right?
Dan?
I,
I think they sold out what they were
offering.
I think the arena actually sits 20,000
and they only have 15,000
available for something,
so they sold 15,000
live attendee.
Take.
Why you smiling?
You though.
Are you laughing?
Just looking at our notes.
Oh,
we've got funny notes.
it's just our notes are funny.
Heads up people with keep defining
story.
We did.
What did we skip?
But we could go back to it later and bed
a couple of.
Oh well hang on.
This is so related to everything we were
talking about,
but now it's confusing.
Get to it later.
Oh Man.
This young couple was using nair on
their assholes.
I'm Ksi.
So they sold 50,000
live attendees.
They took him about $2 million at the
box office.
That's okay.
I mean,
who am I?
That's great.
That's amazing.
Okay.
Eight hundred thousand youtube streams.
That's incredible.
That is incredible.
It was $10 per a paper review,
so that's about 10 million bucks in
revenue.
And um,
what do you.
What'd you write here?
Oh,
keep in mind 1 million plus.
Oh yeah.
Over a million people were watching
illegally on twitch,
which is pretty funny.
I saw a picture of twitch staff was in
the illegal room,
like for twitch staff for watching.
They made this a press release,
like we were trying as hard as we could
to remove.
So that is crazy revenue,
but you gotta also remember those
probably such crazy costs and sane cost
in putting it together and say,
let me put it this way.
We were considering doing a show at the
ace theater,
which we never did,
but the cost of paying the venue alone
was like close to 50 percent of the
take.
And this was a crazy event.
Huge.
Yeah.
I was kind of like really professional.
$10,000,000
may sound like a lot,
but considering how many people were
involved and the.
And I mean Logan,
Paul and Ksi are super rich.
So getting $2,000,000
for a single payday sounds good.
But the scope of what it was,
I was like,
hmm.
It doesn't seem like that much money.
When you think about mayweather and
Mcgregor Mayweather got paid like
$300,000,000
alone,
right?
Dan Was it 300 million?
Yeah,
that's what I.
I don't think there's actually.
Oh,
here.
Official figure.
It's speculated.
300.
So mayweather made $300.
Million and Mcgregor get made a $100.
Like how the fuck was that big of a
difference of money?
It's huge.
I was like,
what?
That's so much more.
That was really.
So I.
If I had the guests,
I don't know if they had sponsors and so
I guess that Ksi and Logan Paul each
made like,
I don't even know that they each made $5
million.
I don't think there was that much money
involved.
No,
no way.
Because the Logan.
Paul definitely made a good amount.
They're fine,
they're fine.
They made.
They made enough money to buy a house
with cash.
But it was.
Dave made something cool,
man.
GotTa give it up.
So here I want to do them so much time
to organize the whole thing.
Well,
the training's not really amazing work.
It's like,
no,
it's insane.
The training,
the promotion,
they were like this whole narrative.
They were sewing.
I mean,
well I think the peripheral hype was
really beneficial for them to like all
their videos and everything.
We're getting way more views than usual.
So it's like,
it's kind of this next level of logging
where you're creating like this crazy,
like real draw.
I mean,
it was extremely orchestrated.
These guys are best friends.
They're fucking loving it.
They're straight up butter,
garlic,
saucing each other reaching around.
Double Hand Job Right now.
Straight up.
Satisfying.
They're insatiable hunger before they're
fine if they what narrowed.
Oh yeah,
Bro.
You know that Ksi narrowed his asshole
and Logan Paul ate that ass clean by
insatiable,
insatiable hunger.
That is the best state.
I love the title.
What was the title of that?
Uh,
uh,
what was the title of that video?
Because I feel like I can't forget.
I mean,
scroll up you guys,
we're gonna,
we're gonna rewind here.
A relieved of caulk hunger.
So they were relieved of their cock
hunger for each other.
It's like when you teach a language
where like teaching you how to use this
sentence,
I feel like that that's,
that phrase has got to live in infamy on
relieved of caulk hunger.
Um,
so I think like not only was it about
their payday from this single fight,
but everything around it was so hyped
and so big that it was greatly to the
benefit.
Are you being.
Did we say,
well we're an actual results for people
don't know.
I'm getting there.
So mayweather versus macgregor just for
comparison.
Four point 4 million paper view buyers.
That's insane.
That is insane.
Especially when you consider that the
purchase price of that was $100.
That equals 440 million.
It wasn't St.
everybody was glued to the whole Vegas
was about.
Defy actually was really weird.
We were playing blackjack and the hard
rock and,
and,
and it was a weird,
weird thing where only certain hotels
had the license to play it even though
you can just buy it.
I find that so weird.
We could go play and watch it on all the
therapies and found out.
So then,
um,
Austin's bodyguard had his brother,
he had his cell phone on the living room
table,
live streaming on instagram,
on Instagram,
his TV,
and so we were watching a livestream of
instagram,
of a,
of a recording of a TV and then random
livestream ended up having like 10,000
viewers by the time.
Then when we found out that it wasn't a
whole team,
there were thousands of people doing
that.
Yeah,
it's kind of hard to take it down.
But like there was a huge crowd behind
us to just to watch on this little
iphone because you couldn't find it
anywhere.
Well anyway,
that's 440 and I just a,
I looked it up again that four point $4
million.
That's just domestic,
that's just us paper.
So overseas it's probably another
million.
So that's the live tickets generated $55
What the fuck were they charging people?
I think ringside tickets were probably
thousands of dollars.
Tens of thousands.
Probably total estimate.
They brought in $600.
Million to do that as close to a billion
dollars from one five crazy.
So Mayweather,
as we said,
got $300,
million mcgregor paid 100 million.
I was just really curious because it was
like why?
I mean like four point four verse 800 is
a big difference,
but I mean having a million live viewers
is pretty significant,
but I guess at 10,
$10 makes a big difference.
Well anyway,
just a little comparison there.
They were very far from,
from the most popular,
but again,
to their credit that's a huge event.
We're talking about like the biggest
live event of all time.
So I just thought it was interesting to
compare those two events.
Now let's talk about that fight itself.
Shall We?
Uh,
J dot Paul,
one in the fifth round out of six via a
technical knockout.
They ended it.
But you know what,
even though Jake Paul did,
when it seems that the most entertaining
and talked about moment of the night was
this image of Jake Paul with a bloody
nose.
So shout out to comedy shorts Gamer.
He looked dazed and confused.
Hmm.
That's going to be a lot of people's
twitter profiles on like a lot of
avatars.
Well,
I don't,
I don't want to take too much pride and
the guy,
he's fine by the way.
Yeah,
he's one,
he's fine.
It's just pretty,
pretty great.
I guess.
I don't know.
So that was apparently,
that was the highlight of the night,
which it doesn't say much.
Here's a video of Jake Paul being
punched in the face 40 times.
They've been super strict on the copper
itself.
So I guess this one is editorial enough.
So here you go.
How many times was Jake Paul punched in
the face?
People really hate Jake Paul.
They're like,
yes,
right.
Lots of people allowing them to kids.
I feel like anyway,
it wasn't than just telling us 30.
Just it is now at Lingq.
Who knows how many million?
10 million a lot,
man.
I got to say he's,
he's more likable than Logan.
Right?
I agree.
I mean,
he,
when he was a guest on our,
on our show,
he was,
I,
he came out looking much better and I
think everyone had a sense of
appreciation for him,
you know,
that said,
let's watch him get back for and said,
let us,
watch him get punched in the face.
Definitely landings from solid punches.
A veggie definitely land.
It's installed punches now as I've heard
it is jake.
Paul was significantly larger,
taller,
longer,
right.
There was not really a fair match up by,
by uh,
definitely.
Apparently Jake Paul was
forced to slouch down because at the
height difference in the size difference
was so great.
But Hey,
shout out to a dog for getting 40.
Slamming good solid punches to the
fucking dome.
Not Bad.
How's that?
It was this,
I don't know,
some guy should I say.
Dang.
Good.
Thank you too.
Thank you to dank again.
Take a good you.
Yeah.
Um,
this was pretty funny.
Tell honestly,
post fight interview with Jake.
This just shows you this rivalry.
I,
I've always said and suspect that Jake
and logan actually hate each other.
Deep,
deep hatred of each other and this kind
of proves like,
here's Jake's big moment,
by the way,
since when did,
when did jake.
He's got a kid.
They call them little jake.
Paul.
He doesn't have a kid,
right?
What A.
No.
So here he's doing his post fight
interview and his love and belonging and
he's enjoying his victory and his
brother.
That's what the fuck.
I want to know what did what,
what do you.
When the boxing match,
you get a kid and that kid's going to be
such a piece of shit when it grows up.
I just googled it.
I guess this is a meme.
There's a whole bunch of Little Jake
Paul or mini Jake Paul.
They call them,
but who is he kidnapped?
I guess it was a bunch of pictures of
guy.
This kid looks like me.
I'll take him.
It does look like.
Yeah,
I'm sure the related.
But when did you shit out a child?
There's no way to Ken,
you know what this kid is?
He's like,
um,
he's like from these Greek mythological
stories where it's like your first born
is four toll to surpass you and
subscribers and jake tries to like
prevent it from happening,
but the kid ends up bigger and then he
also fucks Jake's wife,
his mom.
Just like the Greek mythology.
I'm trying to make it interesting.
No,
oedipus anyone to own.
Not connecting too old for this
audience.
That's my what?
I'm.
So anyway,
he's enjoying the limelight.
He's having a lot of fun.
Logan Paul comes in and steals the
steals the thunder and it's a blast to
watch.
Listen,
joy,
Jake,
Paul,
Little Jake.
What's up man?
What do you think that kid's going to be
doing at 18 years?
Hello?
It was a very cute kid and nobody knows.
Could be anything you want to.
Yeah.
You could be anything.
It could be the president,
right?
It could be an astronaut.
He's going to be great.
He's going to be raised really well by a
punch of well adjusted people,
their dad for Napa.
Really good role model.
It's just a meme
that is a superstar and tonight you made
it yourself as well.
You're wearing that WBC amateur strap.
It was hard quite.
He was trying to care about.
Jake is really trying to care about
jake.
He's really wants to care about him.
It seemed like maybe this going to be an
easy fight for the condition.
What was the toughest part of it?
I think for me personally,
I got tired.
I don't know.
I watch logan.
You don't care about what Jake,
but watch logan in the back.
The the hardest thing.
Knowledges that there's an interview.
You see that he looks back like three
times.
You see that?
Let me go back so you can.
Everyone acknowledged that and so in
that moment he goes,
you know what?
I'm going to fucking end this interview.
Like you can see the gears moving in his
head,
Washington.
He looks back my first fight maybe,
but I'm pushing through the fuck.
Fuck.
All the attention is not on me.
Look back so many times.
Okay,
now watch what happens.
Now.
I was surprised by how much heart that
you had.
A much,
much respect to him for support.
One of you in this room who's not paying
attention to me.
Please turn the cameras towards me and
all the interviews and all conversations
that are about me.
And please everybody focus.
Yes.
There is no fucking way.
Did with the second time.
You're right.
Jake is so much more enjoyable.
Yeah.
And in that interview he was being very
gracious in victory and everything and
just,
you know,
if you see the,
I don't know if we're going to watch the
logan one,
but Logan's like,
I fucking won that.
I think this is bullshit.
We're not gonna watch it.
Yeah,
it just.
Jake is definitely necessary.
We need to give that look of Logan.
Do I know?
Triple check.
You literally did a triple check and he
shut down the interview.
So.
Great.
That moment is just beautiful.
This is by Jake's new March dog shop R
and B,
O dot.
I don't know what this is,
but uh,
does that make it okay?
I get new merge.
Would that mean is march my March?
I'm Logan Paul.
Merge to someone to say merchant might
be a maverick Dotcom.
I come visit you said you got tired,
you got.
That's about all you need to see from
that.
And that was great,
but I'm telling you that brotherly
rivalries thick as foss.
And let me tell you that sauce is thick
as it gets.
Okay?
Delicious.
Creamy,
insatiable hunger.
Relieved of insatiable butter sauce.
Hunkered down.
Anyway,
this shit's fucking gold.
I love it.
Um,
what else we got?
Okay,
well guys,
listen,
we've talked about Jake and Logan,
Paul and Ksi and dig and we've talked
about at all.
Hats off to them.
But the fact of the matter is that the
real fight is the one that we're all
waiting for.
Frank invasion verse Ethan Bradbury.
Now,
now there is a prelude to this.
Um.
Oh,
I didn't say it was a tie by the way.
The fight was a tie between Logan and k
center,
which for if you don't know,
is extremely rare.
One of the rarest outcomes for a boxing
match extra.
Almost unheard of.
So a lot of people are saying that the
outcome was rig to help hype up their
second match and to that I say,
do you really think they would do that?
And the answer is yes,
absolutely not.
Well that is an interesting claim
because as far as I could tell that
would be a pretty serious crime,
um,
to fix a large sporting event like this.
But again,
you know.
Yeah.
Would they do this?
Yes,
definitely.
Yes.
I personally found the outcome pretty
disappointed.
I would've been more excited if somebody
wants because then there's an underdog
story going into the next fight,
but then that kind of makes it more real
because they also want like the better
story.
Well I think they thought the tie was
the better store.
You'd think so.
Yeah.
Does that mean the all the bookies one,
like what kind of bullshit is that?
Like how many people bet on a tie the
book,
is that like.
Sorry.
Hmm.
Pretty Shady.
I agree.
It's pretty shady.
Um,
are people going to be justice hype for
the second fight?
I actually don't think so because in,
in there,
first of all it's a tie.
I think everyone's disappointed by that
frankly.
I think everyone's kind of over it.
And then the logan and ksi both made
videos being like,
it was a great fight.
I respect him so much and this whole
facade of being like,
I'm going to eat your children or
whatever.
That's the Mike Tyson.
Classical economics to your children.
Praise be to Allah.
Like Tyson.
Nobody can fucking sell a fight like
Mike Tyson,
he wants said to an opponent,
I'm going to eat your children.
Praise be to Allah.
I mean,
shit,
I don't know how I'm better you sell
fight.
And then that,
um,
so back to.
And I don't think that the second one's
going to be as high because I think the,
you know,
I think the illusion is busted that they
hate each other.
But anyway,
I'll be there.
I'm going to be there and I'll tell you
what.
I want to send Joey Salads on a live
report.
I want him to live stream it.
We haven't asked you that way.
Yeah,
he's,
I think he's got to do meal,
so anyway,
so that,
that same day prank invasion tweets at
me,
me and either we're in Santa Cruz
enjoying ourselves having a great
vacation and this honestly just made it
even better for me.
I had a blast with this.
He goes,
by the way,
for full disclosure,
I was on the phone with frank invasion
now on the phone,
but I was tweeting with him in dms and I
was like,
Hey,
do you want to do a know your main,
we'd all love to,
to talk to you and do a segment with you
because I mean you're been a consistent
part of the show for so long and we
caught him.
He's becoming,
starting to become self aware.
I feel like with his recent kissing
pranks and then he.
And then we agreed that we would do it
and he ghosted out on us,
which is fine.
But then a couple days later he tweeted
this at me.
I challenged h three h three productions
to a fight.
If I lose,
I delete my youtube channel and give him
$100,000.
Well,
first of all,
Chris,
if you delete your youtube channel,
what the fuck am I going to talk about?
You think I want you to arrange your
youtube channel.
I'm going to throw the fight on purpose,
man.
We got to lose that gem.
That's the.
Come on.
That's history,
man.
That's.
So I,
I proposed to him.
How about a quick game for a quick kiss
instead,
which is,
you know,
something I've been proposing to him for
a long time.
I want him to come in here and
challenge.
I gave you approval to him.
Hmm?
What if he got my number?
Is that.
Can I get your number?
I was like,
fuck you got any butter?
Butter,
garlic sauce.
I have A.
I have an insatiable thirst for calc.
I keep forgetting what the exact
phrases.
So anyway,
this turn into a whole thing.
Ken Bone stuck up for me.
God bless Ken bone.
He said,
I volunteer to serve as tribute in your
place.
My Papa.
Bless my efforts in the battle to come.
Ken Bone was prank invasion.
I thought that would be interesting.
But he said and prank invasion.
Not to be outdone tweeted,
how about you ask Isla client about my
kissing prowess shall tell you all about
all you need to know.
Now quit reflecting.
Are you going to fight me or run scared,
Bro.
You look like you disappeared for a year
and you were in prison and you've been
lifting weights that whole time.
Like the last video you made.
I was scared.
I was like,
this guy was in prison for a year.
Like you looked jacked,
bro.
You Look Patrice Wilson jacked.
Do you think I'm insane?
Do you think that's my skill that would
get in a ring with you and fight you?
Why don't you fight Patrice Wilson did.
I mean he,
he's veins were like surgeon.
It's like,
what did you do to be in prison for the
past two years to be that Jack?
Because he disappeared to.
I always love when we get into this
Kinda fuse or whatever the word is.
They always try to.
Yeah,
I know.
Take a stab at me cause it's like,
oh,
you're married.
I'm going to go after your wife.
Did it work?
No.
Well,
Isla,
I'm asking you now as you directed me.
What about Chris's pray kissing prowess.
What about it?
Quit deflecting.
Are you going to fight me or run scared?
You fucking dumb ass.
You're gonna.
Fight me like everybody.
Like if you challenge me to a fight on
twitter,
I am duty.
I'm like honor bound Sarah,
I challenge you to a duel.
No Bro.
Actually fucking work.
I actually do shit everyday.
I'm not training in prison to fucking
kill someone.
And then he continues all these
youtubers afraid to take me on in the
ring.
Look at that face.
And then of course is a changed his
profile description too.
I am the best kisser in the world.
Hmm.
Another step into being the main.
Yeah,
the main,
the main verse.
Kinda like to self aware at that point.
So what I was really hoping for now that
prank of Adrian has kind of entered this
world of boxing.
I would love so much to put together the
first ever h,
three podcast,
h three transcendent experience,
special fight night.
And I will put up a $100,000,
100,000
dollars to the winner of prank invasion
verse.
I don't know who you guys think is the
best matchup.
Joey Salads shoe.
Nice.
Ethan Bradbury.
Maybe what we can do a poll on our,
um,
itchy podcast handle.
But we will organize event and put up
100,000
freaking dollars to the winner.
I will referee it.
Okay.
I will be there.
We will judge it.
It's going to be an incredible night.
Prank invasion.
Put your money where your mouth is.
I'm putting up $100,000
for you to fight Joey Salads.
I wonder what people think.
We should do a poll or something.
Yeah,
we should definitely do a poll.
But that would be a fricken blessed man.
I,
we have to do this.
We have to.
So that's what I was thinking.
What do you guys think?
Because that sounds like a fun time or
what?
Be like a fight outside of Mcdonald's.
Dan?
Yeah.
Throw up a poll.
Let's get a live count on it.
Um,
no.
I want to rent a venue.
I want to publicize it and wants to be a
big deal,
not a big deal,
just like an episode.
It's like an episode of the podcast.
Hopefully I get sponsors that help me
pay those,
pay the price.
Did the winner gets a kiss from,
um,
maybe we can get that Papa John's
sponsorship that I've always been
looking after.
Um,
do you want to talk about this Chinese
people's story before we move on to the
shoe?
Nice story
and what kind of move on to.
Nice.
I love this story.
I guess maybe we can talk about it next
week.
So good.
Apparently a Chinese company,
a Chinese couple.
Apparently sex education is so poor in
China that a couple was trying to
conceive for four years and they were
having anal sex the whole time.
I don't know.
That's possible.
So they were trying to conceive and then
it wasn't working and they went to see a
doctor and the lady said every time they
have sex it's usually painful.
So she was like,
let me examine you.
Like why is it painful for four years?
And then if it turns out they
mistakenly.
I've been having anal intercourse.
Lou gave the couple a sex education
handbook and within months the woman
became pregnant to show their
appreciation.
They sent the doctor a live hand and 100
eggs as a gift.
You know,
you think of humans as these really
smart,
evolved creatures,
but when you go out to the rural rural
parts of the world without medicine or
doctors or technology available were
fucking each other's in the ass trying
to make ourselves pregnant.
Huh?
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Right.
The guy is just like,
yeah,
that's how,
that's how you get pregnant.
That blows my mind.
The two human beings can have anal sex
trying to get pregnant.
Like when you're that disconnected from
technology that that's how that can go
down.
I'm rally that is pretty rare to be so
lacking of knowledge,
but it's not uncommon.
And um,
like sexual education and there is not
really sensing enough yet.
Yeah.
The big takeaway that was interesting
for me is that in rural China,
apparently sex education is.
So I'm all,
I can't vote on it.
That's disappointing.
I opened the thread,
the pole,
just just show me the damn results out.
Apparently sex education in China is so
poor that people are out there having,
you know,
shooting loads in each other to
buttholes trying to shoot out a baby
literally.
So now is the story.
So anyway.
Okay,
we got that out of the way.
Great.
Let's move on a little shoe and I says a
fucking lunatic.
And other nodes we mentioned.
Should I,
so briefly in our last episode so
briefly and in fact I want to show you
the video so you can see how brief it
was,
just so that you can understand the
reaction he had,
how insane it is.
Okay.
I'm shoe.
Nice.
Oh,
he's a legend.
He eats you yoder and chases alcohol.
So he made,
he made a asm art eating chips video.
He just never showed it by the way.
So that was,
you know,
very light mentioned.
And we went into the comments section,
um,
boy strap up because this is a wild
fucking ride.
My dudes.
So apparently shooting ice has like 20
different accounts and he switches
between them.
I don't know if he thinks that we don't
know that it's him because they all have
his name in the title or maybe he
switched into other accounts to upvote
himself,
but this is a wild ride shoe.
Nice.
First comments.
Thank God bro,
for another mention.
Wish I could be the hundredth podcast.
I'll behave.
Love you guys.
Then he replies to himself.
Thank you.
Didn't log out of the right one.
Then he logs into shoe.
Nice.
Youtube.
Thank you.
Then shoe and ice youtube videos.
Let's do this shoe and inspirational
quote of the day.
Shoe and ice loves isla and wishes she
would forgive him if you guys don't know
he had called you a
Jewish whore or something.
Start something sweet like that.
And then boom and ice.
Ghost hunting was shoe.
Nice.
Let's do this at which is the same
comment left by shoe.
Nice youtube videos and sit down.
She and I believe it.
Exclamation.
I believe Ethan is willing to forgive
shoe.
Nice bye.
Ha Ha,
ha ha.
Wish Ethan would pin this.
He continues shoe.
Nice.
Deleted videos to CSU nights would be
legendary.
The real issue.
Nice deleted videos.
Wish upon a star,
Bro.
Wish.
Wish upon a star,
Bro Shoe.
Nice is not dead shoe.
Nice.
The mental sad man.
Never duplicated.
Give this a thumbs up.
Everyone shoe.
Nice exposed.
I will come to Cali,
bro.
Let me know this.
Are you fucking mind blowing that it's
taken to do [inaudible]?
Like are you mind blown yet?
Did He created all those channels?
Your thing,
every comment or you think he already
had?
I think he already had them shoot and I
says,
well known for having multiple channels
and I'm constantly erasing videos and
using other accounts.
As I was saying,
he had an Asm,
our video channel for a moment,
so not surprised that he has all these
accounts.
I am shocked and awed,
frankly the scope of this operation and
I will continue just for the sake of
posterity.
A shoe.
Nice revival.
She I says in revival mode,
a shooting winning channels and I says,
always went it,
shoot.
Nice deleted video x nine.
Said Yep,
continue a few.
Nice is nice shoe.
Nice is nice.
Actually.
Shoe.
Nice impersonation and parodies.
Mind over matter.
I'm not sure what's the relevance of
that one.
That should have been from the shoe.
Nice inspirational quotes,
right?
Go to mixed up.
She wanted to get your shit together,
man.
You've got to keep your identities
organized.
Shoe.
Nice.
Redemption.
Time shoe.
Nice deleted videos.
Let's do this shoe.
X Twenty eight top comment.
Youtube Hall of shame to burt.
Cool.
Shoe nights wouldn't be legend.
Interview Shoe.
Nice.
Classic videos.
Isla can make me eat whatever she wants
or surprise me with Luggabeast what lab?
Oh,
okay.
Right.
Me.
I don't know.
Um,
we're almost done here guys.
So bear with us.
This report shoe.
Nice storm chasing.
A podcast.
Storm is brewing shoe.
Nice.
Loves La Beast.
We shoot a nice trailer.
Trash jokes.
Uh,
yeah.
Shoe.
Nice deleted videos.
Xx Six.
Mind over matter.
I feel like he's giving himself a prep
talk because he's on like the 20th
account.
A nice war hero deleted videos anyone
knows.
She.
Nice is a war veteran.
Like Isla Shoe.
Nice impersonations.
Yep.
Shoe.
Nice free shout outs.
Thank you.
Shoe.
Nice back.
The original back to finally close it up
with a thank you for replying to that
was so fucking nuts and you know what's
even crazier when I saw that,
I was like,
you know what,
if we're talking about whack pack,
Howard Stern,
whack pack that we want to build our own
shoe and ice is the beetle juice,
and so we would try every.
I've tweeted at him,
I emailed him and this fucking psycho
that spent five hours.
We're applying 100 times.
I can't get ahold of them.
I have no way of getting a hold of him.
So shoe.
Nice.
I've said your name three times in a
spin in a circle.
Shoo.
Not Summon,
disappeared back into the comments.
Give us a way to contact you.
I want you to be part of this show shoe
and I just.
I think you have what it takes to be the
first official member of the h three
goof gang gang gangs.
Pretty good or bad?
Yeah.
We're out here on the fly.
People Hae a little update.
This poll is neck and neck going back
and forth.
Ethan Bradbury and Joey Salads both
hovering around 42 percent.
Julia was a head a little bit,
but now Ethan,
let me take you this.
Who Do you think would put up the best
fight?
Because let me tell you guys.
Chris from Pre-eq invasion went away for
some kind of sexual crime and he is
jacked,
so who would give up the best fight?
Ethan?
Ethan has a madness.
He's got the fighting spirit for sure,
but I think joey,
I think joey would.
Who would you say is winning right now?
Are Neck and neck.
It really is not kidding.
It keeps going back.
It's actually tied right now.
Nobody cares about shoe.
Nice,
right?
He's down at 16 and would actually.
And I'm not saying this as a joke,
I'm saying literally would kill him.
Think that he would die.
She and I in the ring.
I'm joey salads or Ethan Bradbury.
Who would offer a better fight.
Are you texting during our show you'll.
I just voted.
Okay.
Who'd you vote for?
I can't say it because not everyone.
That's true.
That's good.
I want to keep it anonymous.
You have a preference because I'm asking
you.
Well,
you don't want to say it.
I honestly can't say which one I prefer.
I think they're both great candidates.
Got To vote to see the results.
So I think joey might be a little taller
and a little heavier,
so I think that he might offer the best
challenge to.
Right now it's at Ethan Bradbury.
Forty two percent.
Really?
It's 43.
Oh good.
I caught,
I think joey cells would be a better
candidate and I think joey salads is
more up for anything.
So Shana I'm calling out shoe.
Nice.
Versus just want to contact you?
Um,
yeah.
Joey Salads and prank invasion.
If you're watching this,
that gotland has been tossed for the h
three Trans sensel transcend.
Transcend.
Joel didn't say thank you.
I'm calling out Joey Salads.
Prank invasion,
Bradford,
all three of them in the ring together.
Referral rumble.
Let us transcend together.
Thank you.
Good spiritual sometimes on the show.
We've got a couple more things to cover
here folks.
We've got this story.
Just makes me rock hard.
Let me pull this up.
I don't know if this is too graphic,
this photo actually on the main page.
I'm probably not.
Do you want to look at this time
article?
Do you want it to look peek at this and
tell me if you think it's too graphic,
but it's fine.
I saw it really little touch.
Maybe not.
I don't want to show it here.
This one I could show.
I'll show this.
I just won't move up so that.
I don't know if that helps you at all or
not really.
First North American sex doll,
brothel opens and Toronto actually here
I can click on that.
Picture it and Laura.
I got this.
So what does that mean?
A brothel instead of having human sex
dolls.
That sound bad set of having humans you
can have sex with.
They have sex dolls.
Realistic sex dolls.
We have a photo of the adults,
don't we?
Dan?
Yeah.
Where are they?
The dogs.
I've got it.
You got to go.
So if you're wondering,
what I'm talking about here is some of
the choices are adult.
So you have a choice of ana who was
busty as who can play and see huge,
very busty,
romantic and spontaneous.
I don't not sure how a doll is
spontaneous.
I mean,
I think a doll is pretty much the
opposite of spontaneous,
if that's possible.
As predictable as it get.
Erica,
who's a young,
was gorgeous and sweet.
You've got harper,
the perfect girl.
Next door.
You've got jasmine exotic faced angel.
That just means she's black.
Exotic paste angel.
Okay guys,
a scarlet the absolute American dream.
Yes.
Nothing more American than butter.
Garlic.
So are we eating John Snyder?
What?
Nope.
And Yuki submissive.
I think all dogs are by definition
submissive.
They literally cannot help but be
submissive,
innocent.
Not when I'm done with her.
And playful.
So this is some.
This is some wild shit.
You guys that we're talking about here.
So you choose what you want to fuck
with.
Now their rate and membership thing
cracked me up.
Okay.
And I was like,
you could probably fund a real
prostitute for this price.
So for half an hour you get one doll for
80 bucks and two dolls.
What do you need to dolls?
They're not living.
Imagine taking the boat.
They're lifeless heads and like how to
buy your own dog.
I think those real ones actually are
like thousands.
Yeah.
Do you really need a real one at that
point?
It's like Ian said,
uh,
he,
when he was researching at 4,000
really start and really I didn't ask you
[inaudible] wasn't part of our research
dollars.
I love that.
You can have a threesome with these
things in 180.
No discount.
That's just double the price.
I know I could double the price.
There's a discount.
You can get them for a half hour.
One,
two,
three or four hours.
They have a grand opening in like a $10
off.
Nothing.
What I'm saying,
man,
give me a discount.
Grand opening.
Twenty five percent off the price.
Now guys,
you can use your imagination and
understand that fucking the same fake
doll as many men before you gets a
little strange.
I guess it's true of women,
but there are biological creatures.
They shower,
they walk around,
you know?
Yeah.
I'll know that fake vagina is going to
get blasted out after like a thousand
times.
Right.
But I guess you get the mileage out of
it after that.
I mean,
dude,
the human body is regenerative as the
very beautiful ability of rejuvenating
itself and healing itself.
But this is not a.
and that is going to get the last it out
wide tongue me after probably 100 times.
So I guess that's how the prices sweet,
innocent Yuki is going to get blasted
out anyway.
Yeah,
I guess they,
they,
they calculate that based on the mileage
they expect to get right now.
Here's a great little twist on this.
Um,
the,
the prostitution association is fighting
back because they're afraid this is
going to cut into their market.
Um,
I w I wonder how much it is for real
prostitute.
I'd like to see that.
Their rate card,
it's probably more $80
for half an hour.
And do you have any information on that?
Are you asking Ian specifically calls?
He said so on your own.
I think 80 would be quite cheap.
I think that would be like a blow job or
something.
I don't think that would be the full
Monte,
right?
So you save a couple bucks and you fuck
a doll that had punched his Dick's had
been in.
I wonder if they have insatiable hunger
for coc.
So,
um,
the,
the people who own the dol said,
uh,
the doll that could grow will be ready
and waiting in your room.
We do encourage the use of condoms just
because we don't want people to.
Well,
there's still a chance of getting a
sexual disease.
Can you like you like that?
He gave him a fuck up a lifeless doll,
not a condom these days.
Just sanitize the gauges,
clean it,
man.
I am not.
When they don't want the responsibility.
You've seen that room.
I trucked often for the sperm test.
Imagine,
imagine it's that.
And then you fuck this doll that other
guys.
All bunch of dudes have had their way
with,
excuse me.
And then so the prostitution
association,
the Association of sex professionals
strikes back.
They set quote the sex affection of a
person cannot be provided by a doll.
You would say that they are different
and compatible services.
They do not communicate.
They do not listen to you or Koresh you.
They do not come for you or look at you.
They do not give you their opinion or
drink.
I didn't ask for your opinion.
Sorry.
They do not give you their opinion or
drink a glass of champagne with you.
Champagne.
Alright,
sorry.
Whoa.
I didn't ask for A.
I didn't getting all jacked up on.
They do not give.
Thank you Dan.
They do not give you their opinion or
drink a glass of champagne with you.
One of the members also said it's
another strategy of the patriarchy that
presents us as objects without rights.
Are souls a privilege of the wealthy
class.
That's funny because in a way isn't any
better for a woman more accessible like
to let men do whatever they want.
We to an object instead of a person.
Well,
I think that their perspective is that
it's female empowerment in that you.
You're not telling a woman what she can
or cannot do with their body because
like prostitution is outlawed a lot of
places and there's a lot of women that
do want to make their living that way
and they say,
Hey,
don't tell me what to do with my body,
and that's right,
that's true,
but to throw these sweet,
innocent submissive dollars under the
bus is just low at the level below.
They also added,
do you realize that you're fucking adult
where didn't add added up and that's
really gross and you have to use a
condom with that anyway because you can
get some dudes on your deck.
That was their best counterpoint.
I was like,
wow,
that's interesting.
They had a video showing how the build
though those dollars and it looked like
graphic west orange.
It was basically a direct parody of
westworld hits in the fucking vagina and
that like you guys all watched
westworld.
It's like this really epic building of a
clone accepted this.
It's like we're like,
Teddy's get bolted on.
The ask comes up and like some guys
dangling with like layby on a fake
vagina.
It's like,
that's crazy.
You saw that clip,
right?
He was dangling it.
Damn Turkey neck.
The westworld songs playing high
shredder
shredder would fuck the hell out of a
doggy sex doll.
So horny all the time.
And sometimes we take shutter the dog
park and he,
he's a little Romeo man.
He fucks any trouble maker.
We have to,
we have to strap him up because he just
fucking everyone at everything.
Oh,
he's eating.
Give you.
Let me give you guys a.
I plan better boys shredder.
Eat some,
eat some food.
I'll take it a dog park to fuck a small
update real quick.
We're up to 3000 votes on the pole and
joey is pulling ahead.
Oh,
interesting.
Is that 45 percent to Ethan?
Bradbury's 40.
So Jan,
can you reach out?
Um,
now.
So you said that I feel like I can
reveal my vote.
Was it was,
it was Ethan Bradbury.
What's important to that?
Just because it was so crazy.
He has the wild eyes such as what are
you talking about?
Blackie Wacko.
Every man rumble.
Fuck the rules.
Like a free for all.
I think that's what we got to do.
We can try to blow up like a serious
event now.
I would love to see a four man rumble.
Nice.
He would fucking kill them all.
He'd be so psycho psycho.
So anyway,
Dan,
get a ahold.
Can you get ahold of I'm joey,
Ethan and Prank invasion and see if any
of them are actually interested.
100,000
bucks.
I'm putting the price up.
It's very generous of you.
I see what you're right.
I pray that we can get sponsors because
that's a lot of fucking cheddar cheese.
If we.
God
there's some sponsors out there that
they'll do it for 5,000.
I changed the price.
5,000.
Could we negotiable.
There's gotta be some sterile shares and
the follows.
So tell him there's some minute for
them.
We just haven't decided yet.
No,
we just got Paul Harris.
Got Them.
Um,
how long have you been going?
Because I have a couple more stories.
You get to hour and a half.
Okay.
Let's through John Mccain and American
hero.
What better to follow up our story on
fucking dolls blasted open two for the
price of $1.
Just kidding.
There's no discounts.
John Mccain,
American here.
A great segue.
John Mccain.
Now,
as you guys probably heard who recently
passed,
um,
I think we had recently discussed John
Mccain for this,
what I consider and what I cherish as
one of the classiest moments in American
history,
recent American history.
Because as you know,
the country is so politically divided.
It bothers me.
It bothers most people frankly.
I mean there's a lot of people did drink
the Koolaid on either side and it's
really cut.
Like who watches CNN everyday and who
watches Fox News every day.
That's your team line.
Okay.
Now John Mccain was a conservative
through and through.
He was a Fox News man and the people,
a lot of people that,
that Bruno didn't like Obama.
There was a lot of weird conspiracy
theories about him.
One of which perpetrated,
by the way,
of our current president,
which is probably the dumbest.
I mean,
there's a lot of things to say about
trump.
I'm not going to get into it,
but accusing Obama of not being an
American citizen and is probably the
dumbest and the most insidious,
flat out insane lie I've ever heard of
in my life.
All right,
so a lot of the people bought into that
and one of the women at the rally,
a lot of it's happened several times
actually a couple of times where they
say who Obama is.
An Arab obviously implying a lot more.
Not implying that Arabs can't be good
people,
but John Mccain read between the lines
being you'll see for yourself,
but basically this one,
the classiest moment in my opinion in
recent American history where he went
against the grain.
He risked his own ass.
He's in,
you know,
a town hall meeting with these people
that are thirsty,
bloodthirsty,
and he just fucking stopped him in his
tracks.
He said no,
and he knew even gets booed.
They fucking turned on him for actually
standing up for his values and,
and,
and speaking some,
some sanity and the part that really
pisses me off.
Well,
let me show you the clip,
but actually now that this fucking class
act and true American hero has passed
on,
you know,
the people
on the left who I politically are
supposed to be my political allies
because I am very left.
I'm a very liberal person.
Say that all the time are eviscerating
John Mccain for this clip to people that
he's reaching out to across the bridge.
Yes,
because.
Well,
Lemme let's watch the video.
Yeah,
I mean it's just so sad and it's so
fucking sad.
Let me play you this.
Frankly,
we're,
we're scared.
We're scared of an Obama presidency.
First of all,
I want to be present United States and
obviously I do not want central Obama to
be,
but I have to tell you,
I have to tell you,
he is a decent person and a person that
you do not have to be scared as the
United States.
Now I hear them turn on him and I just
now look,
if I didn't think I wouldn't be one heck
of a lot better president,
I wouldn't be running.
Okay,
and that's the point.
That's excellent.
Can hear the crowds turn on him when he
there to insinuate he's a decent guy.
You don't have to be scared of.
I mean,
how messed up is our country that,
that simple insinuation,
he is not the antichrist.
You don't have to be scared of him.
He,
he's a good person.
I can't believe he said that.
You know?
Yeah.
The second part is the part that people
are outraged about.
To the point.
I'm going to ask you a question.
I don't know.
This lady is fucking right.
Yeah.
Look at her hair,
man.
This lady's.
She's Got Fox and he was pumping through
our veins.
These fellows don't run.
No.
Really her.
These colors don't run at all.
Well even I can't trust Obama.
I had read about him and he's not.
He's not.
He's a,
he's an Arab.
He is not.
No,
no,
no ma'am.
She's like,
What do I say?
Tell me what to think.
Tell me what the thing.
No,
he's a decent family man.
Citizen that I just happened to have
disagreements with on fundamental issues
and that's what this campaign is all
about.
He's not okay.
He was just saying stuff with this like,
don't even go there with those arguments
as nonsense.
Exactly,
and so here's the kind of tweet that
I've been seeing online.
I'm going to show you one example of
many people,
many of supposedly enlightened people.
Okay,
look at this.
Fucking stop with the story about how
John Mccain shut down a race,
set a rally by saying Barack Obama was
an Arab,
but a decent family man as citizen.
You can be Arab and an American citizen.
You can be Arab and a decent family
person.
These are not opposed.
The story perpetuate racism,
Bro.
You perpetuate racism.
You're perpetuating this great divide
and you are willfully.
I mean,
you either didn't watch the same clip I
did.
I mean,
dude,
that's not what he said.
Like he's the,
the what's,
what really makes me sad as he's
reaching out to these people,
he's putting his ass on the line to
cross to make a bridge of,
of class and dignity that doesn't seem
to be alive,
left honestly anymore.
Politics and say,
you know what it was saying,
it's a good men like if I'm going to
lose and he's going to be the president,
you guys don't have to worry,
we disagree,
but you'll have a good guy.
This,
this is so sad to me.
It's great and people are,
are politicizing this,
trying to be submerged in when,
when his intention and the purpose of
what he did was the exact opposite of
what they're trying to say after his
death.
She said he's an Arab,
but her insinuation was so much more
that,
and he said,
what he's saying is,
no,
he's not an Arab.
He's saying,
no ma'am,
don't even go there.
Wherever it is that you're trying to
say.
Yeah.
Also,
he's going off the cuff.
It's a live event.
He's,
yeah,
he's in the hole with all these people
ready to turn on him.
He's making a risk.
They're like,
well,
actually I just want to clarify that.
Um,
Arabs can be good people.
He is not an era,
but Arabs can be good people.
It's like,
dude,
he shut her down.
I don't know.
I'm so.
I'm so sick of fucking people like this
dude.
He could look at this other tweet.
Someone responds to him.
The same guy says,
I hope.
I hope you actually take to heart the
idea of reading tweets without your own
tweet,
from the hip assumptions getting the
way.
I clearly said the story was racist.
This is the guy,
by the way.
I don't want to show them.
I'm not talking about the guy,
whatever,
but I'm just like,
man,
this dude.
It's not even about him.
I've seen this sentiment echoed a lot
and I just think it's,
it's a fucking shame.
Like we should be honoring this like a
really courageous moment of,
of.
I thought it was really nice of him when
I saw it courageous and rest in peace to
John Mccain,
the last honest vestige of class.
And how can a guy like that even be
classy when the people he's trying to
reach out to our viscera rating because
it's never enough.
I don't know,
man.
That made me really sad.
But I think John Mckinsey and awesome
dude.
And,
uh,
he said,
he said in his final statement that he
just wants to remember it as someone
that served his country.
So he definitely will be remembered as
that.
Hmm Rep
and the words feel Tony from last night.
All right,
let's move it on to this footage I have
to share with you guys is one of the
most intense and insane things I've ever
freaking seen in my life.
Um,
you guys probably heard,
we covered a lot of the fires last year
that were ravaging Ventura and Santa
Barbara.
There was a fire and nor cal or.
Yeah,
I think it was in north cal that was
even bigger than last year.
Gen savaging and destroying the state.
So on continues.
So this father and son were out hiking
and it was all clear.
It was all good and they saw smoke in
the distance and didn't think anything
of it because it was pretty far away.
But the winds picked up and this fire
started spreading super fast and all of
a sudden they're like,
we got get out.
We should,
we should get outta here.
And so here is their attempt to escape
this forest.
They were just on a hike.
And this video is just,
I mean,
it's one of the craziest things I've
ever seen,
um,
to 70 year old dad and a son.
And that jeep escaping the forest.
Do I go here in a minute?
I think we can drive through this.
So for those of you that can't see,
they're driving down a narrow forced
path and fires raging pretty much on all
sides of them.
Really intense forest fire is insane.
Trees falling over.
Slow down.
It was like a movie.
Yeah.
It doesn't feel real.
So they got,
they think they're out.
The fires Kinda cleared without the dad
said we're out.
And then they turn a corner and it's
like the craziest hellscape I can
imagine.
Just fire everywhere.
Fires raging over the road or
driving through it.
Literally driving through fire.
Can't see.
Just go easy.
Now the car is heating up.
It's going to explode.
Jesus.
God,
help us.
Carry on so we can see Joe's one.
If a tree falls on us,
please go out and help us get.
Nope,
stop.
Stop you gotta get out of here.
So they reached
a log in the road that was,
that was covering the road.
It was on fire and it stops.
There were just like the craziest
cliffhanger of all.
Can't write it.
Even in the movies that much of a
cliffhanger.
You know what I've got?
I know how the story ends.
I'm gonna.
Read it to you guys there.
Okay.
Does that shredder there?
Um,
I find it interesting because that guy
who's driving is like forties and the
data is 70.
And like in this life threatening
situation,
how they like to evolve kind of back to
like a little child.
Yeah.
So these fucking lunatics,
they kick it into reverse and backed up
through that real road,
back through there in reverse and made
it out.
That's so crazy.
An excerpt of them explaining what
happened.
That's when things went bad to worse.
That tree ravaged by the intense fire
had fallen down across the road,
blocking their escape route.
I saw that and I thought we were going
to die.
Justin said,
I thought we were trapped.
There was no way we could turn around on
the road with his father's guidance just
in kick the car into reverse and drove
the vehicle all the way back to the
trail head at the end of the road.
At times.
Justin said he was going as fast as 40
miles per hour was absolutely insane.
I don't know how I was able to keep the
car on the road.
He said,
but somehow a few prayers in a higher
power.
We stayed on the road once they were
back at the trail head,
which was safe from the fire for the
time being.
They walked down towards a nearby
cabinets.
You if anyone could help them.
That's when they saw a small boat
floating on Lake Mcdonald with two
people aboard.
We flagged them down and they came over
and grabbed us and we got onto the boat.
Justin said 10 minutes later we were on
the water and we saw the whole part of
the lecture where we had been standing.
Just go up in flames.
Crazy.
Don.
Unbelievable.
Gape is like,
I was just.
I was mind blown and I watched it.
I'm so happy that they didn't know I had
to.
When you first showed me the video,
I was like,
you gotta tell me that they made it
because the thing is that you can't like
appreciate is how hot it must've been.
And driving like this road to drive in
reverse.
It's got unbelievable.
Jesus definitely took the wheel.
His words.
Anyway,
I just to share that little incredible
thing I saw with you guys.
Um,
we've got California law makers,
past bill to erase old poc convictions.
The state a district,
uh,
the doj with the fuck is that department
of Justice that bless it out.
He's calmed down.
Sorry.
It's my fault.
A Department of Justice estimates that
almost 220,000
cases are eligible for a ratio or
reduction.
They better pass that you cannot make it
legal and then be like,
oh,
everyone rotting in prison.
Each shit too bad.
Imagine being in prison for 10 years for
pot.
And then they make it legal and they're
like,
okay,
you can come out now.
It's like,
fuck anyone who's in jail for president
in this supposed land of freedom.
Can you imagine like,
I mean anyone could go to jail for
having marijuana.
It's in your light,
like a bright young mind getting wasted
in prison.
I fucking our law,
our prison system is the most,
I think barbaric thing about this
country almost really by far and so man,
everyone,
every one of those 2:20
people should be handed a joint two
hundred and twenty thousand two hundred
twenty thousand people should be handed
a fat blunt,
100,000
dollars,
hundred thousand dollars because it's a
lot of people.
They deserve more box in my thing and
I'll put up a prize,
but they should all be offered a fat
blunt and a sincere apology from the
state of California.
I mean that is just a goddamn crying
shame.
It's unbelievable.
I don't think any.
I think that drugs should be legal.
I think all drugs should be illegal.
Personally,
I don't think what good does it do?
Society locking somebody with a drug
issue up in prison.
I'll tell what good it does.
Society,
it creates a system of slavery,
of Free Labor.
Hm.
In prison.
Yeah,
and it makes a bunch of people that are
privately owned prisons.
A bunch of money.
So sick.
It's.
It shouldn't be private.
That's that.
I know something as prison.
Yeah.
You want to monetize a locking people up
almost as sick as privatizing healthcare
almost.
Oh Man,
you're dying of cancer.
Well,
if you can't,
I mean the treatments of million bucks.
Do you have a million bucks?
I guess you're just gonna have to die
then.
Oh,
you're the richest country of all time.
Well,
go to prison.
They have a great health care.
You just don't get paid.
You're basically a slave,
but we will.
I wonder if you get cancer treatment in
prison probably.
Hmm.
That's a good question.
I think you do.
I think.
I think that that is true.
Yeah.
I think you get hooks on somehow the
conditions in prison or I guess you have
to make a choice between freedom and
dying of cancer.
Hmm.
They love that.
And finally I'm Ethan.
You're such a socialist.
Fuck you.
Not a.
So I'm a capitalist.
Socialist.
Okay.
Let's be realistic.
I'm not talking about communism.
Look at Scandinavia.
I love how people always like,
socialism doesn't work,
idiot.
How are you going to pay for it?
Let's go space force.
Let's give rich people fucking
$10,000,000,000,000
tax cut.
How are you going to pay for healthcare,
healthcare?
Everyone else in the word sound like you
sound like a socialist.
Isla Israel.
Configure it on Israel.
Where did they ever agree on anything?
They don't agree about anything and they
all care about money and somehow they
all figured it out and you.
Everyone has healthcare and it's pretty
much free Scandinavia.
They always say socialism doesn't work.
Scandinavia
for university,
free healthcare.
Utopia.
Everyone's happy.
Great quality of life.
They're not okay.
Yeah,
it's a capitalistic country.
I'm not talking about communism.
You fucking idiot.
Be Realistic with what I'm saying.
Just don't want to go bankrupt over
getting sick.
You sound like a 30 socialistic scumbag.
Now.
Can I lock you up and give you some
cancer treatment in exchange for your
life?
Get a little political here for a
minute.
We just found out it's been one year
since our lawsuit ended and I can't
believe it's not been longer.
I cannot believe kind of explains when I
look back that our lawsuit is ended only
one year ago explains how fucked up I've
been mentally.
We've moved twice in that time.
We were in this gut wrenching lawsuit.
Your Dad has been sick this whole time
and I've just been like,
it's such a mental fuck this whole time
and like you,
it's hard to look from the outside,
but like damn,
it's been a crazy.
It's been a crazy time.
It's been a crazy year.
I've heard a lot of people say that 2017
was the worst year.
Seems like a New Year's.
Everyone's always like,
this is going to be my year.
No,
it's not guaranteed.
It's not.
Anyway,
I thought this was cute or alert.
Our attorney that did most of the work
on our case.
He sent me this picture of his office.
He's got this t shirt hung on the wall
of his office,
the matter of law shirt
that we made that one and I was like,
man,
that's cool.
That's really cool.
It's a trophy as he put it.
I appreciated that and I thank you guys
all for hanging around.
It's been a tough year for us and uh,
you guys hanging around and Karen about
what we're talking about and what we're
going through.
It sure means a lot to us.
Not Been My best over this past year.
I would say that I don't think so.
I felt like it.
What is your best anyway?
I felt like Shit,
you know,
I made a jacket that says I feel like
shit.
It's no secret there.
A lot of people related.
What do we do about that?
Why we all feel like shit.
What are we going to do about that?
That was great.
Dan was at you maybe?
Yes.
One last update on the pool.
I think we've got a clear winner with
Joey Salads at 44 percent.
1,000
votes in
going on buddy.
So
reach out to them.
Would you?
Dan?
Will do.
Okay,
let's set this up.
I'm excited guys.
Fuck you.
Fuck all the pranksters would want to.
Well,
we can have like a tournament bracket.
It's like a prankster and turned them
into whole bracket.
Man.
I don't give a shit,
I kinda liked the idea of like
untrained.
Just get in there and throw some
punches.
I don't mean to make.
No one is allowed to train.
Yeah,
no big deal.
We're just going to let the rain come.
Shoot and ice is the Guardian.
He's the boss.
She and I still going to eat a stick of
deodorant before he takes you on guys.
Thank you for watching.
This has been another correct opinion
zone h three Tuesday episode.
Hope you are enjoying these Tuesday
episodes.
I have no plan on stopping because a lot
of people don't know what to think about
things and if you need to know what to
think,
how to feel my friends,
it's Tuesday.
We are fully enlightened and when you're
in the correct opinion,
his own you cannot be wrong.
Friday is Tim.
Hi Decker.
The comedy,
a legend,
a pioneer.
God legend.
I would say God,
I'm both nervous and excited to make his
acquaintance because as many of you
know,
he is a.
I have said that he is the sole reason
I've made comedy.
Yeah,
I think most of our listeners know that,
so I think everyone is probably feeling
you're like dread site man.
Um,
why can't I just be like,
why can't I just
be happily excited?
I feel like that's normal to be like,
I'm going to meet one of my heroes.
I don't know.
Why do I have to offer?
You're actually excited about stuff like
positively excited.
Why do I have to suffer?
It's a good thing.
Either jumped out at me.
He's like,
are we done yet?
Yeah,
we're done.
Thank you everyone.
We'll see you on Friday.
I love Ya.
Go Watch killed Tony.
We did.
That was a lot of fun.
It's on youtube.
Just type killed Tony World.
We did it.
I was great.
Great show.
And you can degrade.
I didn't say a word that starts shtick.
I was really nervous though.
I was fucking so nervous again.
Why do I have to suffer?
I was excited to be there.
I love their show.
I liked them.
So why do I have to suffer?
Hmm.
That's a question for another time.
Why we transcend,
we think deeply
experience.
We shall see you on Friday on the h
three podcasts,
enlightenment
show.
Thank you for watching.
Thanks for watching.