Welcome everybody to the premiere
experience and the podcasting world,
the age three podcast experience.
All other experiences are lesser to our
own.
This is the premier experience.
Today's episode is sponsored by stitch
fix meant dimmable and empty empty
movement.
I am Ethan Klein.
You're a grand wizard host of
loneliness.
Last week I was the wizard of
Isla was supposed to be back this week.
She had to delay her return by another
10 days or so.
So I've taken on the title of grant
wizard of Loneliness,
um,
not to do with the Klu Klux Klan,
by the way,
just my loneliness.
Uh,
I will talk more about Ella's extended
trip.
It is quite a sad and unfortunate,
so I will save that for the end of the
show.
Uh,
and I'm not going to lie to you guys.
I'm not wearing underwear today.
He has been gone for three weeks.
I've never been away from her for this
long.
She's finally coming back on Wednesday.
Ila,
please come home.
I come almost completely.
I'm out of underwear.
I have no underwear,
dude.
I just came out of the bathroom.
There's pissed dribbling down my leg
onto my pants.
You know what I'm talking about?
That's why you wear underwear,
right?
That's the whole point is that it
catches your pis.
I don't have that protection anymore.
Ila,
please,
I need you.
With that being said,
let's get right into it.
So,
uh,
I got a really exciting announcement.
Um,
announcing a new game we've got here.
Know your meme.
Um,
we're going to be taking calls today and
one very lucky color is going to chance
to win a brand new slam and hot Samsung
Galaxy s nine plus.
What's the value of that,
Dan?
It's like around a thousand dollars.
Now we personally,
my favorite phone on the market,
and if you can call in and guests three
out of five answers about Joey Salads,
you're going to win a brand new phone.
Here's the number.
If you guys think you have what it takes
to know your meme with Joey Salads,
call (818) 214-8504.
We will be taking that one lucky color
after the break.
Very,
very excited about that.
And true.
We want true salad heads.
By the way,
if you're not a true sal ahead,
we'll know and Ian will hang the f up on
you quick.
Okay,
so don't be wasting his time.
Okay.
Loving the sound board.
By the way,
this one is dedicated to you,
but before I,
I've got a lot I want to talk about
today.
Okay.
Lucy to daddy o five and so many more
goofs and gaffs along the way.
But I really like as we did last time I
was in here,
the trenches by myself.
You start off with a great video video
of the day.
Does that have a,
does that work?
I feel like it a better,
the better title.
I was thinking video of bliss.
It's a bit over the top,
isn't it?
Video of bliss.
I'm a think on it,
but I actually had two that I thought
were so great.
I wanted to watch it at the top of you.
This one I got to tell you,
you're gonna,
you're gonna love this.
I can't,
I,
I'm such a skeptic.
I feel like part of me thinks this is
fake,
but I have to believe in my soul and
heart that it's real.
Um,
here we go.
Thank you.
This crawfish caught the fucking penny.
Oh,
show that again.
I was crazy.
I got to see that again.
Yeah.
Ethnic guys,
just like,
I mean,
how do you react when you throw a penny?
Had a crawfish and it catches it and its
claw.
How do you react?
That's pretty much the only way.
Okay.
But then the,
it begs the question,
why was he filming to begin with?
Right.
Yeah.
That's a good point.
Why are you filming a crawfish on a
bathroom floor and then throwing a pen
yet?
Like what,
in what world is this something that you
film that makes me suspicious yet again,
I've come full circle.
That being said,
I dunno.
I feel like it's real.
It fucking looks real.
But I,
but why are you,
why,
why we need,
we need a,
the captain.
We need the cabin back.
Yeah.
When the captain disillusion,
don't worry.
Okay.
But like,
why would someone filmed this?
I mean,
what,
Oh,
it's from instagram.
Yeah.
Everything.
There's fake.
Anyway,
I love it regardless.
And then there's one other one that I
had to share with you guys.
This is one of my favorite videos to
come from the Internet.
And these past weeks,
this guy went to city hall and gave an
impassioned speech.
Not about,
you know,
traffic or politics or whatever city
ordiance taxables shit you would here at
city council.
No,
this man came with something much more
important and pressing.
He came asking that massage therapists
be able to jerk you off.
Sometimes you got to go with you.
Sometimes you have to go to city hall to
get to fight for your rights.
Why can't a massage therapist touch my
dick if I pay an extra 20 bucks?
20 bucks is that,
that's probably a good deal.
It's probably more than that.
Anyway,
here.
Yeah.
Anyway,
this guy obviously says it better than I
ever could.
So with that,
yeah,
here you go.
It seems quiet,
Dan.
Let's go here.
We let things go.
It's a little different than are you?
Why is it different,
Dan?
Uh,
you know what?
You're right.
Why is it different?
Hell we let ask doctors,
finger men basically finger men all day.
Not Basically,
literally,
literally finger means assholes all day.
This guy's a hero,
dude,
don't question him.
Rolling.
I love the his,
the crotch of his argument is what's
worse.
I got to go back.
Is that really what he argued?
He's like,
it's more nasty for the practicality,
so let just let him jerk him off.
Right?
He's saying,
what's the difference you're already
getting in the folds.
Why not just touch his dick along the
way?
Compelling argument.
I'd like to see a counterpoint made to
that.
Right,
right.
Amen,
brother.
What a Patriot and go get one,
right?
Wow.
Okay.
Not a full circle right there.
Amen,
brother.
That guy's definitely a comedian,
right?
He's got the socks and sandals.
That would truly be a happy ending for
everyone.
Fuck
Amen,
brother Dan,
if you are,
have you ever had gotten a massage,
like a,
like a full body Swedish massage?
Dan?
I have not.
Seriously.
Yeah,
never done it.
I was going to ask if like I've gotten a
couple of times,
but I just fucking applause.
Sound effect.
I was going to ask if it's ever moved
when you were getting a massage?
Uh,
I mean,
I can't say in a professional setting.
you know,
obviously in private that's a different,
that's a different tale altogether.
But no,
it's,
it's too weird.
I don't know.
I have like,
I have a weird hang ups about it.
Sometimes it moves.
Sure.
I mean it's a natural,
what are you going to do?
Can you do anyway?
God bless to this guy,
Ian,
has it ever moved for you?
Have you ever had a massage and he's off
headset right now.
He's starting to screen calls.
All right,
let's just say that he has no,
okay.
Um,
yeah,
so anyway,
I salute this Patriot and I'm all about
it.
All right.
But that being said,
let's get,
let's get into the main event here.
Boosie too.
I feel like it's like a repeat almost of
last week when we talked about Connie
cannacon just trying to decode and
explain what's happening.
So Fusi,
Fusi,
tube,
if you guys don't know who he is,
he's a,
he,
he can has a prankster and he faked a
lot of pranks.
He almost,
he invented almost like the moral,
the righteous fake prank where it was
like,
uh,
what,
what was the example you gave me Dan,
where he had one word.
Oh yeah.
He's like,
he sends in the street and he's yelling
at people for not having like they're a
seat belt on or something.
I don't know.
Just like he's always got to have like a
moral twist on it.
He kind of invented that whole thing.
So anyway,
he fell off.
I'm pretty sure he's,
he's been having a lot of mental issues
and it seems like he's in a full blown
manic state right now.
I mean,
he,
let's start here.
Let's start from the top here.
He says with 2 million viewers,
drake is going to grace the stage of my
concert.
He's only got 2000 likes.
That seems like a far way off.
2 million views.
Um,
anyway,
he keeps saying that Drake's going to be
at a show.
Drake's going to be at a show.
He's never,
he never talked to drake.
He's ever known drake.
He's,
he sells out the Greek a free show and
he says Drake's going to be there and
obviously drink never shows up.
But basically what ensues is a lot of
insanity,
a lot of confusion and a very little
crowd.
Um,
and him stalking drake,
which is probably the best,
I mean the best,
the most entertaining and concerning
thing to come out of this whole thing.
Um,
this video pretty much sums it all up
for me.
Let me throw this up here for you.
This,
this video really has it all.
It's got stocking.
It's got a Jeroma.
Let's hear it quiet.
Dan,
can you turn it up?
Yep.
Gotcha.
Do to the people.
And by the way,
he's taken this clip from someone else's
show and upload.
This is a video on his channel right
now.
So to put it in frame here
building,
this is when it gets really good.
So I think he probably spent about a
hundred thousand dollars reserving the
Greek.
And I will say to his credit,
I mean I don't want to compare it to
Taneka cause with Tana did was basically
sell supposedly free tickets and didn't
even give on the event or refund people
his was free.
So at least there's,
there's the a big separation to be made
there.
I mean,
he's not scamming people,
he's just misleading people,
but it's a free show.
But what's really fascinating,
it's just his clear mental decline here.
Um,
watch this.
I want to go over a little bit on that
as hard.
Right.
Is He,
is he,
I mean I can't tell if he's just like
cracked out.
Yeah.
Our features on a manic rant.
Yeah,
it,
it seems very manic.
Yeah.
It seems very mannequin and isn't he?
He publicly has a history of that.
Does he not he,
he has.
Yeah.
He's bipolar,
he said.
Right.
So I just,
yeah,
I dunno.
I think people give food seat.
Well,
let,
let's,
let's keep watching.
Let's get the whole frame of reference
here.
Oh
whoa.
I love that he included that.
I Dunno who it was.
I don't even know if it was a police
officer could have just been normal guy
who's just like,
fuck this idiot,
give back of your car.
He goes from being like a total bad ass
to being like,
oh,
I'm sorry dude.
Sorry about that.
But he leaves it in,
which I find curious.
You clearly could have edited that out.
He finished his statement,
but he got an I,
and I hate to say this,
but he got cooked a little bit by
whoever was on the street.
You know what I mean?
When he left that in,
find the interesting,
um,
now this is when it get texts are really
dark twist.
I mean,
first of all,
dude,
if there's a setting for any video,
okay,
talking to a celebrity,
this is him.
I mean,
look at,
look at this frame.
He's,
I mean,
dude,
this is straight out of like a horror
movie.
Like are you in my basement right now?
Fusi?
I listen what he says.
He's got the dongles hanging out.
Okay.
Those downloads are not a good look for
anybody,
by the way,
let alone a celebrity stalker.
But let's watch.
Cool.
You've acknowledged stopped there.
I literally look and I'm acting like a
crazy person right now because I'm
outside of the house.
You're at stop there dude.
You just,
you just summarized it.
Okay.
But he knows that it's not actually
crazy even though it is.
All right.
Don't ask me how I found it.
I've got ways,
creepy,
creepy ways.
You're probably wondering how did I find
you?
You're probably wondering to yourself
rent now,
how did I find you and do I need to call
the police and get a restraining order?
Do I need to have my body gourds,
body guards,
escort and mount?
You're probably wondering,
don't worry about that.
Don't worry.
I I,
it's interesting how we on one hand
acknowledges all this,
how creepy he's been.
Right?
And on the other hand,
fully committed.
It's why it seems so manic is it doesn't
seem,
yeah.
Does it seem like he's intoxicated or on
drugs or anything?
He's very clear headed about it.
It's just nuts.
Well,
symptoms of of Manic episode,
I mean here,
let's read it off.
Abnormally upbeat,
jumpy or wired bill.
Increased activity,
energy or agitation.
Boom.
Exaggerated self sense of wellbeing and
self confidence.
Yes.
Unusually talkative racing thoughts.
Distractability I mean,
yeah,
Yup,
Yup.
I started the line I never thought of.
That is one old person.
It's an extra little layer of creepy
that he keeps playing that God's plan
loop.
This is like such a creepy stalker video
of like a weird fan food.
If fusi ends up killing track,
I'll be like 10% surprised God's plan.
Baby.
You might be thinking to yourself,
he's like over him.
Drink sleeping in his,
he's like covering over him.
You might think this is a little strange
streak.
Okay,
but this is God's plan for me to murder
you right now.
In fact,
if you look down,
you'll notice is already a knife in your
stomach.
I mean,
you know what he does.
Meanwhile,
he's got on his phone,
God's plan looping God's plan.
God's plan.
Damn.
Damn he is [inaudible].
He's going to come down to earth and cut
and like,
I dunno,
I dunno how long manic episodes last,
but he's going to be like,
Oh,
I dunno.
Fusi.
He's interesting guy.
Like,
I don't know if I feel bad for him in a
way because it's like he's such a
strange situation with him because he
has a fan base.
Like when you're,
when you're having a manic episode,
I'd having delusions of grandeur,
the fact that he actually has a fan base
and people encouraging him.
Right.
That makes it all so much more fucked
up.
So much worse.
He's just enables his delusions.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Okay.
Can you imagine how to see having a 32nd
conversation that's never happened.
I promise that this event is going to be
huge,
but I need you for it to be huge.
It's like,
yeah,
fucking obviously he doesn't need you
though.
Unfortunately.
When it goes one way,
I'm like,
listen guys,
I'm putting on the hugest show of the
year.
All I need is Tupac and Biggie to return
from the grave and cohosted with me and
it's going to be the biggest concert
ever put on
sick,
sick hype,
Bro.
How long did it take you to make that
and premiere?
Oh,
oh hey.
Now my video can get copyrighted.
Dang.
You just fucked me up.
Thanks for the thanks to see your
fucking,
all of our monetization it up now.
Now I got beef with you.
Um,
where's my mouse?
So he uploaded on this channel.
I mean it's still up of him.
Literally.
Here's a,
this always trips me out when I can see
myself.
Um,
it's still up of him publicly stocking a
celebrity on his channel,
which just shows you how unaware he use
of,
of how strange is his behaviors.
Um,
so that's,
that's where,
that's kind of where it began.
He's no withdrawn from,
from the Internet,
right?
I Dunno.
He's retreated back into,
into his cave.
Yeah.
I don't know.
He is,
he,
he posted a distract on rice gum,
which I find strange,
like out of,
okay.
Clearly acting's not working out for
your dog.
That was a pretty corny read a clear,
clearly acting,
uh,
not working out for me.
I feel like I just acted that out better
than him when I was trying to act that
can I?
Okay.
Damn.
That was really counted on the phone.
Wow.
Crazy.
So anyway,
it's just,
it's really just another youtube hip hop
did it.
You got to seen a thousand of these rap
video.
But what I found fascinating about this
was the vision board.
I'm here,
let me play for a second just so you can
kind of
put into perspective what he hoped for
this song.
So rice,
gum distract.
So anyway,
you get that.
Yeah,
I mean you really get the idea.
That's all I need to see.
So his vision for this rice come
distract is number one song on billboard
hot 100 can you imagine the country
banking tour,
race gum,
Distrac the region of 50 million views
and under three months.
Well,
in what fucking planet to rice come
distract bro.
Like if you want it to actually make an
accessible song,
why would you just write it about
anything else?
Club banger on radio in the entire world
at least once a day.
Manifest your dreams.
Just as I did,
man.
I swear to God,
I'm,
I feel like I'm entering the mind of men
reading this.
Help each other,
achieve each other's dream.
Kill your ego.
Oof.
You got a long way to go there,
buddy.
Okay,
so I don't know.
I thought that was pretty cute.
Pretty cute.
Pretty interesting.
Well guys,
I mean we can get it there.
We got to get this on top.
Billboard number one.
I'm sure it's really close.
It's climbing.
It's climbing first.
God,
I really need the yellow pack.
I need Isla back,
dude.
Next week.
Thanks a week.
Maybe Wednesday.
No fucking underwear.
I always joke about people getting shit
stains.
I was like,
who gets shit stands?
I'm in pants was shit and piss inside of
it.
I'll show you if you don't believe me.
There's little shit streaks.
I've got SMEGMA building up on my penis.
I didn't have for skin.
Eva changes my diaper and cleans my
Dick.
Telling you Ila,
please come back.
Ah,
where was I event?
Yada,
Yada Yada.
He holds the event at the Greek.
A free show.
How many seats is a Greek cab?
Like 10,000
new.
Quite.
What does this video training,
whatever Greek holds?
Uh,
I believe around six or 7,000.
Okay.
Pretty big show.
So this,
this is my favorite thing to cut.
So this is the show.
It's happening.
Fusi hasn't even showed up,
but this,
this is the fucking crowd.
I mean,
what does that like 20 people there at
the stage and this Dj man,
God bless his soul.
Crushing it.
Huh?
Look at the employees.
They're like,
what is this like these guys?
Are you still like ushering like huge
solo out events?
What the fuck is this?
I swear to God,
you must,
I mean,
getting the Greek,
we were going to spend 25,000
just to rent out the ace,
which is a 2000 seat theater.
That was 25,000
this on all this shit.
I'd say at least a hundred thousand he
spent on this.
Yeah.
And I mean the Greek is,
it's an iconic venue.
It's very,
very much in demand.
Yeah.
It's not cheap.
Wow.
On a weekend too.
Oh yeah.
On a weekend.
Damn.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a pretty penny right there.
It's trying to hype up the crowd.
Well,
I don't know,
man.
You're mixing doesn't sound that good.
I love that.
Even the Djs in on this illusion,
delusion.
What if drake just walked on stage right
now to the hundred of you huddled around
the stage,
he'd be so mad.
No Dude,
it's because you and not drink.
Killing it.
Crushing it.
Damn.
That's a,
that is a coal to crowd my dudes.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
That's the vibe there.
There's basically nobody there.
Um,
and then someone calls it cause it's,
he's livestreaming it.
It's got like 60,000
views.
He said he was going to get 2 million.
Jake was going to come out.
There's like a thousand people there,
60,000
people watching online.
That's kind of a lot to be honest.
But I think most people are watching
just for the beautiful train wreck that
they knew what was going to be and
somebody called a bomb threat,
which is just like Jerry on top.
I mean it's like I'm not surprised.
I'm not surprised.
There are conspiracy theories and I have
to say they're compelling cause you
always have to ask yourself who benefits
the most from this crime bomb threats
called could totally be anyone on the
Internet.
I mean that is a,
it's a juicy mean,
but if Fusi called the bomb threat,
he wasn't at the venue yet.
He was waiting to see how big it got.
If drake would just,
I don't know what he thinks happened.
If like drake would just like
materialize.
He's like 2 million,
I'm here.
But if he called it in himself,
I wonder if he was able to get a refund
to be like,
Oh man,
the show never happened or oh,
I don't have to be embarrassed because
drake never showed up.
You know what I'm saying?
He kind of benefited the most from that
bomb threat,
which is why it's a compelling
conspiracy theory.
And I'm not saying that.
How dare you say,
I would never say or implicate or say
and make any statement like that as an
opinion.
You know what I'm saying?
There is a thought experiment merely
asking questions.
Been through enough lawsuits
won by the way.
And that's plenty.
That's plenty there.
There is some sense in it,
you know?
I mean he benefit,
he really,
he did.
Frankly,
I can see him benefiting from that bond.
But like you said,
I mean,
you know,
people get swatted all the time.
Deal.
Really.
It could be somebody else just,
just as silly.
Yup.
Easily.
Whoever it was,
by the way,
fuck that person.
And I hope they get caught.
If it does end up being food soup,
wouldn't that be like the greatest twice
in this epic saga ever?
Am I explaining this?
If people understanding,
is this making sense?
Who gives a fuck?
It's also stupid.
There's just another thing of like
youtube has just devolved into such
like,
why is he famous?
You know what I mean?
Like Youtube is,
youtube has turned into this like engine
for creating fame for people who should
never had even a taste of fame.
Okay.
The most Fusi should have ever been
famous for his stocking drake.
Yeah,
like there's so many people and when you
give fame and like cause fame,
it has,
it has a lot of power and frankly a lot
of responsibility that comes with it.
And when you give it to somebody like
that and many others on youtube,
it's like you're given a bazooka to a
monkey.
Fusi should not be famous man.
Okay,
so many other people.
The cons,
Tana should not be famous.
My God,
Tana should be working at Wendy's
specifically.
Wendy,
she does the other fast foods for some
reason don't ring true to me.
She should be serving up Wendy's.
Okay,
and yet here she is,
you know?
Well she might be serving on burgers in
prison.
Pretty soon somebody's got to cook them.
You think they get burgers and prison?
Maybe?
I think they probably do.
That was pretty dope.
Prison doesn't sound that bad after all.
Sounds Nice.
I don't know.
This is why I'm like,
I feel like I don't,
I don't like,
I love the podcast because I really feel
like we're doing our own thing,
but I just feel like you tuber is
becoming and youtube itself is just
like,
what is this?
It's like always the same shit.
Like this is fucking stupid.
I might have been talking about this.
I got to finish this story though.
It's reality show,
you know it's the same I guess.
Right?
But it's almost,
I mean maybe it's not worse.
I don't know.
I guess you're right.
It is the same impulse,
but people look at Kim Kardashian.
I mean I guess a lot of people look to
them as a role model.
I guess it's the same kind of thing.
I don't know.
Not that I know.
So then basically the bomb threat shuts
this whole bitch down and he shows up,
gets on his,
gets on a car or the uber driver who was
fired by the way after this.
So good.
He's like,
I'll give you,
he said,
this isn't the video,
but I'm not going to bother showing it
too cause it's like,
come on,
give me a fucking break.
But he says,
I'll give you $50,000
if you let me stand on your car and
deliver a monologue to everybody.
And he's like,
okay.
You know,
so it goes on the car,
he makes them hit a blunt,
he gets fired obviously.
And then food,
see sharing their text messages of the
Uber drive being like,
dude,
I got fired.
I really need this job.
I need the money.
And he's like,
talk to my accountant.
My accountant's going to hook you up.
Whatever.
I can't tell if that's flab or six back.
He's got a rolled up though.
Why does he have it rolled up?
What does,
and you're already wearing a wife
beater.
It's the most breathable shirt you can
possibly wear.
So it's like,
it makes it look like he's wearing a
sports bra.
Does it got some nice teddy's but like
some support,
right?
I can't tell what's flab or arts muscle,
but he's rolled up.
Just take it off.
I mean take off the fucking shirt.
At that point you're,
you've gone 70% of the way training bra.
You've got a training bra and for some
luscious breasts you've been grilling.
Um,
it sounds weird to say a training bra
and luscious breasts.
Yeah.
Next to each other.
You know what I mean?
Was like 10 years apart.
Okay,
let's move on.
I love that line.
It's really not a great insult.
Heating up my,
you're heating up your breakfast.
Well anyway,
let's watch this shit.
Um,
you know,
don't want to drag this out too much by
the way.
His event is called like a hate dies.
Love wins or whatever.
Rise arrived.
He just gets on this car and he's
fucking talking shit to everybody.
Fuck you.
Well,
to be fair,
there's a lot of love sprinkled in
there,
seemingly at random to you.
Little Love,
a little hate.
No.
He should call his vent a little love.
A little,
hey,
that would have been accurate.
I would have accepted that is a more
accurate,
I'm going to throw a convention called a
little love.
A little,
hey,
it's a balanced meal.
Anyway,
this,
this is an image of a man on the,
on the verge of a complete,
you know,
this reminds me of,
you remember the coney guy?
Oh,
the county guy.
He came the biggest meme on the
Internet,
right?
And then he was jerking off at the
corner some corner in San Diego.
He was like the most important guy and
then he was jerking off and public Fusi
as a couple,
as a couple stressful days away from
full blown masturbating in public.
I mean,
I wouldn't be at all surprised if he
whipped out his dick right now on that
car.
He's just sharing the love now.
That's what I call love arriving.
Give me three seconds by loves about to
arrive,
baby.
Anyway,
you get the fucking idea.
It gives a shit.
Yeah.
Uh,
anyway,
I really,
for me,
ah,
he's,
he's having a mental break.
There's really no question about it.
Definitely he's,
he,
he is bipolar and he said that.
So the do needs help.
He needs intervention man.
He needs someone who loves him and cares
about him to step in and be like,
dude,
let's wrap this up before you'd get your
dick out in public because there's no
going back once you go that far.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
The top of this week when we heard about
all of this and then I started
investigating it,
I was laughing my ass off.
I thought it was hilarious and the more
I watched the laughter was fading,
I was like,
oh,
this is,
this is actually kind of sad.
This,
this event is called the,
the laughter dies and the concern
around,
yeah.
All right,
let's take a quick break.
We got,
we're going to come back with know your
meme featuring Joey Salads.
I am so excited to play this game.
We've got to all prepared.
Joey himself has a recorded answers so
you are not going to want to miss this
guys.
See you soon.
It's hard enough to dress myself.
Let's be honest,
especially with egon,
it's impossible.
Talk about going to a store,
buying stuff,
making decisions.
It's,
it's unfathomable.
That's why stitch fix is changing the
game.
So convenient.
Stitch fix is an online site.
You Go,
you tell them your style,
your preferences,
your budget,
and they have a stylist that we'll pick
out clothing for you based on your
preferences and send it to you,
tailored for you.
You don't have to go to the store.
You don't have to pick anything out.
You don't have to worry about it.
You got people with taste to do that for
you.
And let's be frank.
Most of us,
most of us guys,
we can't dress ourselves.
We are completely helpless.
I'm gonna be frank with you guys right
now.
I am not wearing underwear because isla
has been gone for three weeks and I
haven't done laundry.
I'm just saying,
not all of us have egos and for the rest
of us that stitch fix,
they've reinvented how we buy clothes.
You just answer a few questions on size,
preference,
budget,
boom.
You're going silas springs into action
hand selecting five brand new clothing
items just for you.
The styling fee is only 20 bucks,
which is applied as a credit towards
anything you keep.
And since it is based on your
preference,
it,
you're still in control.
It's not your mom taking over here.
Okay,
why don't your items arrive?
You try them on.
And here's the best part.
You only pay for what you keep.
So really they're sending you clothes to
try on and if you like it,
you keep it and you buy it.
And if you don't,
you send it back.
Come on guys.
It doesn't get any better than that.
So get your fix whenever you want.
Or sign up to receive scheduled
shipments.
The choice is yours.
So my dude's head on over to stitch
fix.com/h
three to get started right now.
Keep all five items in your box and
you'll get 25% off your entire purchase.
That stitch fix.com/h
three stitch fix.com/h
three it's convenient.
It is gonna make you look and feel like
1 trillion bucks and you got nothing to
lose because you can return it if you
don't like it.
Thank you.
Stitch fix.
Very excited about our new sponsor meant
mobile,
which is changing the game on cellular
phone plans.
Now,
let me give you a little anecdote.
When I was in Israel and me and either
were really broke,
barely getting by,
there was companies who was doing like
these guys did and it's saved our ass.
What these guys offer is basically an
exit from these normal giants like at t
and t and verizon and everyone else,
because these guys will cut your
wireless bill down to 15 bucks a month
instead of and sort of what,
50 to a hundred bucks.
I mean mobile,
it's so fricking expensive.
It should be $15 a month and these guys
are going to get you there.
Meant mobile is proving to millions of
Americans that getting your wireless
bill doesn't have to be the worst day of
the month.
They make it so easy to cut the wireless
bill down to just 15 use your own phone
with any meant mobile plant.
You can keep your old number along with
all of your existing contracts and you
choose between two five or 10 gigabyte,
four g lte plants.
There's no,
you don't have to pay for an unlimited
data plan that you're never going to
use.
Every plant comes with unlimited talk
and text so you can safely and cheaply
annoy all your friends and loved ones.
I hope my mom doesn't get this plan and
get it cause she calls me a lot.
Just one of those jokes and if you're
not 100% satisfied meant mobile has you
covered with their seven day money back
guarantee outfox your old wireless bill
and start saving with meant mobile.
Listen guys,
15 bucks you,
it's,
it's the same shit.
It's in this day and age is not like,
oh can you hear me now?
It's the same shit.
Everyone's got good reception,
15 bucks a month.
I'm telling you this shit is going to
change everything for you to get your
new wireless plan for just $15 a month
plus free shipping on your Mint Mobile
Sim card.
Go to meant mobile.com/hd
that's meant mobile.com/h
three cut your wireless bill to 15 bucks
a month and get free shipping on your
men Mobile Sim card meant mobile.com/h
three and the empty movement watches are
the greatest watches on the market and
the cheapest price.
How do they do that?
They cut out the middle man and do it
themselves.
Don't take my word for it.
Take it from the almost 2 million people
that have bought watches and 160
countries and they continue to
revolutionize the market.
Check this out.
They come from being crowdfunded kids
working out of a living room.
The past year.
They not only introduced a ton of new
watch collections for both men and women
and also expanded into sunglasses and
fashion forward bracelets for her.
Uh,
they keep making new new products.
They'll get.
This is their new one right here.
This is the revolver.
Uh,
I gotta tell you I like it.
I want,
I want one of these.
Look at this black one dude's slick as
hell.
It's like,
what the fuck is up now?
Haters.
That's what I would,
that's what it says to me.
And this is what I frankly like this.
Okay?
It's a watch.
It tells the time and it looks good.
It's not blowing up my wrist.
Isla always sending me nudes.
Gimme a break.
You know what I mean?
It's a watch.
That's what it does.
It looks good.
So movement watches start at just $95 at
a department store.
You're looking at four to 500 to 5,000
a million dollars in department stores.
But these guys,
95 bucks,
a classic design quality construction
styled minimalist.
Again,
don't take it from me.
Take it from the 2 million people that
are wearing this right now and getting
tons of people touching their dick.
Probably tons of that.
So get 15% because the watch looks so
good.
They're just like,
Oh shit,
let me grab your deck.
Not in a sexual assault way,
just like,
oh my God.
It's like you want it and then they
touch it.
It's not like a crime.
Get 15% off today with free shipping and
free returns by going to mvmt.com/h
three c y n vmt keeps growing.
Check out there expanding collection.
Go to mvmt.com/
[inaudible] and join the flippin
movement.
Welcome back everyone to the experience.
What am I missing us so much?
God,
I wish it wasn't shit my fucking diaper
right now.
You know what?
I feel like,
I feel like Bo and Neil is my papa.
I should tell you got,
we were goofing around on twitter a
little bit that drake was going to be
here where that's unreal.
He,
I've just,
I have to stalk him a little bit later.
I have somebody,
I have a bunch of goons stalking him
right now,
so if we can get up to 100,000
live viewers on the stream right now.
I don't know what we're at,
but drake will,
as I understand it from Fusi,
he will basically materialize until the
podcast studio.
So yeah,
tell everybody to tune in because I
told,
I'm really excited for love to arrive.
I should tell you guys,
by the way,
that Fusi reached out to me yesterday.
I almost had him on the show today.
I almost had him on,
he reached out to me and said something
like,
only you can cut through the bullshit.
Yeah.
If you ever want me on.
I was like,
I said he'd save himself for you.
He said that.
Oh,
it was like his virginity.
I mean,
you want to,
should we find out?
Let's see.
I wonder if he's into giving happy
endings,
which is every Americans God given,
right?
You should take all of this manic energy
he has and go join that guy at the city
council meeting and all that manic
energy and put it into rubbing my dick.
Anyway,
he,
he contacted me and I almost had him on,
but I was like,
I don't know.
I learned my miss my,
I feel like with Isla gone,
I got to play it straight.
I get into trouble when needless gone.
She's back home dealing with some really
heavy duty stuff.
I gotta go do it straight.
I wanted to talk about what's going on
with Ila.
So I was like,
I don't,
I don't want that cirque is coming to
here and,
and,
and like,
I don't really care that much if I'm
being honest.
You know what I mean?
I couldn't tell.
I mean,
what's there to say?
What's there to say?
The guy's insane.
He's in the lunatic,
right?
There's not really anything more to
break down in that,
you know.
All right,
let's go.
Let's get on with it.
No,
your main guys.
All right,
here we go.
Here we go.
I'm excited.
You guys are gonna love this.
I've really,
we've,
we've put effort.
Okay,
so here we go.
Welcome everybody to know your meme.
The first episode featuring Joey Salads.
Do you know your meme?
Let's find out what our first caller,
Dan.
The music seems to loud.
Uh,
okay.
I mean,
it sounds good on the stream,
but I'll pull you down.
Let's take our first call.
Laura.
Laura,
you're on the air.
How are Ya Laura?
Keep it together.
We're playing a game here.
All right.
Are you ready to play and know your
meme?
All right.
Here we go.
Question number one.
All right,
let me turn this music off.
It's a bit money.
Joey's most embarrassing or recorded
act.
Is it a his dick pics leaked online,
be paying in his own mouth or c being
caught race baiting.
Fake Pranks.
Go ahead.
What do you think a,
B or c take you?
But I don't know.
Are we going off like what you
personally think or whatever?
This is based on his own answer.
I think
peeing in his own mouth is that final
answer.
Yeah.
All right.
Hit us with it.
Dan.
What is his answer?
Gonna to be mean now.
Ooh,
good.
Damn cold.
It really good.
Try.
Really,
really good try.
I would have guessed peeing in his
mouth.
That's embarrassing for most people,
but sadly,
joey is a host to many embarrassing
moments and you were very close.
So w based,
by the way,
you need three points.
We've got five questions,
so all hope is not lost.
Okay.
You're good.
You got,
we're moving on to number two.
Okay.
What does Joey Salads like most about
Donald Trump?
Is it a his policies be his swagger or
see his hate for Hillary Clinton?
Take your time.
Well,
it's tough getting the mine of Joey
Salad.
Enter the mind of madness.
Swagger.
Is that your final answer?
Okay.
You're go ahead and roll it.
That's right.
Swagger,
correct.
All right.
Joe,
you to you explaining too long?
Yeah,
we got it.
We got it.
Yes,
that is correct.
His attitude,
his swagger.
You have,
you have successfully gotten the mind of
salad and you're doing great.
You've got one point.
You need two more.
We've got three more questions.
Okay.
How are you feeling?
Feeling confident.
You're holding it down.
You're doing great.
Here we go.
Question three.
What percentage of Joey Salads pranks
are fake?
A 50 50 b.
They're all fake or C,
they're all real.
Enter the mind of salad.
Take your time.
A,
b.
They're all fake.
It's a debt.
That's a very definite answer.
It's all answering.
Take.
Keep.
Take a moment and think about it.
Can you sense hands,
man?
This is not,
you have 10 seconds on the clock.
A,
B or c 50 50 your final answer.
Is it 50 50 Dan?
MMM.
Mine
Salad.
Congratulations.
Laura,
you are just one correct answer away
from this brand new galaxy s nine plus.
Do you need this phone?
Will you cherish and enjoy this phone
call with you,
you guys?
Oh yeah.
That's okay.
Good answer.
It's a really good answer.
All right.
There's two more left.
You only need one and he's one,
right?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
We got this.
Okay.
What is Joey Salads?
Real last name.
Is it a salad?
Tino sell.
Ateneo.
Sorry,
sal.
A Tainio be salad or see salad.
Dino,
take your time.
That's a tricky one.
Salad.
Tineo Salad or salad?
Dino,
enter the mind of salad.
What does your heart say that the final
answer to the mind?
Meditate.
You have one more chance so don't
stress,
but we are running low on the clock.
What is your answer?
Salad.
Dino.
Is it salad?
Dan.
Ah,
Ooh.
Do we have any winning music?
Dan,
who's been winning music?
I guess it's a little too emotional
salad,
dino.
That is three.
Correct.
Congratulations.
You're a winner.
We've got one bonus question if,
and let's just say it.
Let's do this.
Okay.
Because I,
I,
you know,
we've got these answers from joe or
they're all terrific.
So let's do this.
If you get this wrong,
you lose the phone.
No,
I'm kidding.
I wouldn't do that to you.
But let's just play.
Let's just play it for fun,
right?
If you get this right,
we're going to include some swag,
some extra swag.
You're going to love crazy shit,
dude.
Basically Drake's going to show up to
your house.
Are you,
I don't know if he'll do anything you
want literally talked about it.
So that's what I'm offering you is.
Yeah.
I don't know if you're any of that,
but that's what's on the table.
Uh,
what,
no,
no.
He's coming with much more than singing.
Okay.
So this really nothing on this table,
but I love the tension.
So let's,
let's mount it.
Joey's,
what is Joey Salads?
Favorite type of salad dressing.
Is it a ranch?
Be Italian or C does he hate salad
itself and a stunning,
you're confident.
I really feel it.
You said that one of your podcast.
Hmm.
A true fan.
A true listener.
I like you very much Laura.
And I'm glad we're giving you this phone
cause she,
I
the say Dan,
what is the answer?
Yes,
you are the ultimate winner.
Laura correcting know your meme coming
through.
What?
That's four points out of five.
This brand new Samsung Galaxy s my plus
is yours and drake is going to come.
He's going to sing for you and so much
more and that's my personal guarantee.
You Dan,
how do we keep her on the line?
Can,
can we pass her over to Ian to get her
details?
Yes,
we will stay on the line and we'll,
we'll go down the line.
Laura,
thank you for the f being the first one
or of know your meme.
Everyone give a round of applause.
That was a lot of fun.
Thank you.
You very much and God bless you.
God bless.
All right.
I think that one pretty well.
Hey I,
that was a lot of fun.
We were worried that people wouldn't be,
you know,
up to snuff on the Laura Joey Trivia.
She entered the mine of salad four out
of five was stressful when she missed
the first one,
which is kind of exciting.
Yeah,
yeah,
no that there was ups and downs,
you know.
Oh my God,
we got to do more on gutters.
I want to do one with like a Ethan
Bradbury and Mo [inaudible].
Yeah,
I've got to think who else would be
really good at this.
But that was,
that was a blast.
We do the Bradbury's we could do,
we could do Mister Antonio Brown berry
farms forever.
Uh,
guys,
I want to look back and memorial today
Gaddy a five as you all know,
was the great and wonderful Youtuber who
filmed himself abusing both physically
and verbally,
his children for the amusement of
everyone on youtube.
And if I can continue my thesis of
youtubers being garbage,
they shouldn't be famous.
He was really the main exhibit there.
Here you have a man,
like if we can pull up just an image so
that you all know kind of what I'm
talking about here.
You have a man white trash as as,
as humanly possible.
Who has found fame and fortune on
youtube?
Daddy of five.
I mean,
give it up.
I mean there's nowhere else in the
planet where a man like this,
ladies and gentlemen,
a man like this could ever find fame.
Look at that.
Um,
he,
he and his wife who won't say much,
but man,
she is something him and his wife were
abusing their kids actually have quite a
fan base.
Half a million subscribers,
hundreds of thousands of views on every
video.
And there was one that really crossed
the line.
The police got involved.
They actually,
they're convicted for child neglect.
Um,
he had some kids from a previous
marriage,
right?
They were removed.
Yes.
Right.
And he was convicted from for child
neglect and it's first channel we'll
shut down.
But being the intuit,
the,
I won't say the industrious,
the ingenuity [inaudible] the
[inaudible] daddy oh five rebranded
himself.
He returned triumphantly to youtube
under the flag of family of five.
Beautiful.
He's back.
He's been back at it for several months
until recently.
His name came up again.
And I'm sad to say after posting another
video of abusing his poor son,
who I'm sure,
and I hate to say this about,
his son is probably going to shoot up a
school in five years and I don't enjoy
saying that,
but I would,
I mean,
I keep an eye on that kid and I
appreciate it.
I mean,
I know that I've been through a lot and
I love that kid.
He's a sweet guy,
but when you make your kid dressed like
this,
that's kid's name is cody.
This kids is the fucking,
they just bullying on this poor kid.
And he's like,
man,
that's crazy.
They make him wear glasses with like a
look at this shit.
They make them wear these glasses and
it's got like the tail.
So he can't drop him,
but it's like really tight around his
head.
And you cannot wear sunglasses,
protectors and not get your ass beat all
the time.
You guys know what I'm talking about.
Why the fuck bro?
Why the fuck is the god of cringe
blowing up Google images?
Talk about someone's who's challenged
should be erased.
This guy's sitting naked in the fucking
google images.
I'm trying to run a show here.
He got me the god of crunch.
He got you.
He fucking got booming.
How was he so high in the ranking for
daddy or five?
I don't get that.
Anyway,
he's back.
It came up again and Youtube finally has
said,
daddy have five more like daddy of
having a channel.
Wow.
Fucking roasted crickets on that one.
Um,
so I thought we would look back and
cherish the moments we had together.
So,
um,
this is from him,
one of his new channels actually.
And I thought you guys might enjoy this.
Once again,
cody is the subject of his ridicule.
The title of the video.
This is a re upload dad destroys son,
Nintendo ds and well,
I don't know about you,
but that's pretty much the title of a
loving family.
Five overheard long.
Absolutely wants to enjoy it.
Okay.
Only on Youtube.
Can you enjoy actual child abuse?
Yeah,
one of the many fine tastes available
here among many others.
MMM.
So it's like an episode of police,
except nobody's arresting him
by the way.
His crime,
his crime is that he just keeps taking
his dad's d s and playing it.
This kid,
nothing better to do in his life.
What a wants to play his dad's d s when
he's not using it.
Fucking piece of shit that need nerd
needs to go down and guess who's going
to be the one to do it?
His Dad.
Okay.
What's posted?
Like what is,
this is just like screeching going on in
the background fucking war zone in
hundreds of thousands of views.
This is good.
Shit is good shit.
Dan.
Bad Fat cat,
his wife.
Something like the fucking wicked witch
about it.
Way I thought was like unlike,
I mean listen to this piece of work.
Okay,
what are you cooking kids?
She's got a crazy wise man.
I gotta tell you,
if you could make the most white trash
hick ass hillbilly fucks in Sim,
they wouldn't compete with family of
five.
Can You Imagine Your Dad's screaming at
you like that?
So fun.
You know everyone in his school is
watching this dude.
Sometimes you got to teach a kid a
lesson.
The worst part is like,
oh,
that's somehow they did that.
He's putting on a good show.
Damn,
this guy must have the emotional
maturity of like a real 12 year.
I mean,
he's bullying magic.
Bowling your own kids.
Like not like being rough with them or
tough with them.
Actually bullying your own child and
then,
and then sitting down at a computer with
that footage,
editing,
editing it.
Well,
Dan,
I have to tell you,
you're going to appreciate where this
goes because his editing comes into play
and a really terrific way.
It's an accent,
you know?
Great.
Um,
the best editing is usually invisible.
You know,
this video is,
is,
is marinated finally.
All right.
Okay.
Someone
save this poor child.
He looks like a murder.
He looks they're fine.
Yeah.
Yay.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Yay.
I imagine that's your dad.
I feel like he's putting it on for the
video too,
but he can't tell the difference.
The kids certainly can,
you know.
No.
Same to them.
Yeah.
He's thinking right now.
This is good drama.
We're getting some good shit right now.
I've squeezed some good trauma out of
these kids right now.
Teach him a lesson.
Teach that little piece of shit.
Nice.
You got,
I'm good man.
Really good.
He gets good.
It gets really good.
There's a scene that one will tie a
great scene.
He goes to a,
there's a scene where it goes to the
garage and starts hitting it with a
mouse.
Notice his brother flank,
jump kicking him in the head with no
intervention from his parents.
He goes to the garage with a mallet and
starts smashing it.
Where's that?
Well regarded this.
This is when it gets really good.
Dan,
this is what I was referring to.
I hope you enjoyed this editing feet.
Wow.
I really wonder why it's so poorly
adjusted to the world.
Yeah.
I don't,
I don't know,
man.
I just thought if I had a kid and beat
the shit out of him and yelled at him
all the time and destroyed,
it's stuff he grow up to be a good kid.
I mean,
I worked for him,
right?
Yeah.
He to I turned out great.
Okay.
He edited end,
sad fucking music.
Cherish this.
When I heard that,
I was like,
no fucking way.
Put that in.
He's got way.
It's not for him.
It's not for cody,
it's for the dad.
The Dad's heart is broken.
I see.
But Watch,
you'll see.
He lays it down.
Right.
We've seen enough,
cody.
It's about you.
Now Watch,
he's suffering.
Being a dad of five is tough.
Sometimes you have to discipline your
kids for the greater good because
they're liars and they're thieves.
By no fault of your own.
Life's tough and you need sad music to
help the audience understand how
stressful
life is.
Okay?
And you got to act really sad and upset.
Wow.
Very consciously putting a vlog camera
at.
Make sure the framings Nice.
Let's,
let's forget that too.
Is selfie camera work there though to
bill?
He's good.
He's a pro.
But I have to say,
let's,
let's definitely forget that he's
holding up vlog camera on one hand,
pointed at his face while having a
breakdown and the other hand,
damn,
that music has really gut wrenching.
Yeah.
And I feel so bad for so sympathetic.
I feel so bad for this.
Daddy.
Oh five he's for Lauren.
Oh,
he doesn't care about the camera
anymore.
Isn't care fade to black.
He died.
Okay.
Listen,
is torture room now.
If you thought he was a Shitty Guy,
listen,
where is he?
Oh,
I see.
I had to do it.
It really hurts him and upsets him that
he had to do that.
No,
you got it anyway.
Fucking good.
Riddens you fucking fuck that.
Fuck that guy.
God Damn,
this is okay.
Again,
this guy's famous on youtube.
This guy has made a healthy living on
youtube.
And I get,
I don't know what my point is because
there's plenty of legit people on
Youtube too.
But um,
well and,
and he's gone.
Now what?
I don't understand.
Why was he allowed back?
Yeah.
I don't know.
He is his family of five channel after
being a convicted child.
Neglect or was allowed to continue.
I Dunno.
I Dunno,
but they just shut it down finally.
So I,
who knows,
who knows?
I mean,
I guess better late than never,
but shit.
So give it up to Daddy.
A five rest in peace.
I fear for that.
When he loses his livelihood.
I fear for what will become of that
family speaking frankly point.
Well we're at the bottom of the show and
I had mentioned at the top of the show
that I'm healers eludes dealing with
some stuff back home and I didn't want
to talk about it cause it's really
heavy.
But I do want to talk about it right now
is that I'm Ella's dad passed away
about,
I guess it was probably like three or
four days ago now.
So it's crazy.
It's so crazy.
Like she went there for two weeks.
She planned to go there for two weeks
and when she went there he was,
it wasn't fun.
He was terminally ill but I mean nobody
expected that he was going to die during
her stay there.
Like he,
he picked her up from the airport.
It's just,
I dunno,
it's been,
it's been really a wild ride for her.
I mean,
she knew her dad was like terminally
ill,
but like the day she arrived they were
giving them radiation treatment because
his lung cancer spread to his brain and
the doctors like we really need to kill
this tumor with radiation.
The chance of success is really high and
it takes eight weeks for it to work.
So an a week after that he fucking
passed away.
Okay.
Which is so crazy man.
Like
I dunno,
she's been,
she's been going through a lot and I do
want to say about Ilos Dad.
I have talked about them on this podcast
a couple of times.
Um,
some wonderful moments I will say fondly
now
because they were always kind of like
not taking very seriously.
The first great one being that he told
me,
he said,
[inaudible] don't ever let ethan come in
this house if he's coming over here with
socks and sandals.
That was my move back then.
I was wearing not just like sliders but
flip flops.
The one with the string in the middle.
So I was wearing a white sock all the
way up and the string like shoving the
socket.
It was not a good luck.
And frankly I understand it's
embarrassing.
This is my son in law.
I thought it was funny,
but he was serious and frankly he's a,
he's an old school guy.
He's all about respect and integrity.
But I didn't wear sandals to the house
again and frankly I don't do that
anymore because it is pretty insane way
to walk around the world.
Okay.
So I can,
I can and retrospect appreciate it
that that was a changing point for me.
Straighten you out.
The next great moment yo can on moment
was um,
God,
we've told the story but it's like back
in the day when we first started
youtube,
there was this one video called shake
that Dick and it was so obscene.
One,
I can't watch,
it's so vulgar and like our videos
weren't particularly vulgar,
but this is the one for some reason,
the one that he actually saw and it was
a parody of shake that ass.
And it was,
are lots of closeups of me wearing like
basketball shorts without underwear
shaking.
My Dick was disgusting and obscene.
It's legit.
One of the funniest videos ever.
And he saw,
that's the one he had to see and he
says,
Isla,
if you guys keep making videos like
this,
I will.
I'm going to disown Ethan from being my
son in law.
And once again,
I see,
I get it.
You know,
I didn't know why that had to be the
one,
but that's the one.
But that's these a guy that was all
about,
he's old school,
he's all about respect and integrity and
upholding the family name.
But I have to say
he was,
he was always good to me.
I mean when I,
when we moved to Israel for America,
he's like a really old school dude.
He let me move in with them.
He had never met me before and he let me
come and stay with them and sleep in
their house and he always treated me
well and he always welcomed me and he
fed me and he gave me a chance to,
to be there and work there and make it
work with Ila.
And he definitely could have been like
weird guy coming saying my house.
I mean that's,
that was a huge stretch for him.
But it definitely,
me definitely gave us a chance that that
made it all work.
But it's,
there was something that Ella told me
that was like really I guess
heartbreaking in a way.
Not Really,
but nice is that,
you know,
he from that moment where he was like,
we're saw shake that Dick at the
funeral.
Every,
all of his friends and family were
telling you that.
Oh God
he was,
he was telling all of the friends and
family how proud he was of her and us in
particular of of what we've accomplished
since then.
And they were saying like he was always
bragging about you guys sharing your
videos on facebook,
talking about you and with everybody.
And we unfriended him after the,
the chick,
that Dick thing.
Cause we were like,
all right,
we can't,
you can't be seeing these.
Well we didn't even know that every time
we posted a podcast or a video or a post
or whatever he was re he was sharing it
on his own facebook page too.
His family is all school,
traditional conservative family.
This was like the last picture they took
to get together.
Like right when you went in the hospital
was like a week left and he's got a big
ass
fucking smile on his face
and he's rocking that teddy fresh.
Yeah.
And he is basically one week from death.
I mean he's in pain all the time and
like,
I dunno,
just the fact that he mustered that big
smile for Ila,
rocking that teddy fresh.
I mean he was,
he was a great one and it was a true
supporter and he really enabled us to,
to thrive and succeed in Israel.
I know I got thinking about like,
I've been thinking a lot about just this
whole concept of like saying goodbye.
It's like we're always,
it's like,
it's so hard,
but like we're not ready.
We're not trained at all.
Like we don't ever think about death or
like how to say goodbye to loved ones or
even for us to say goodbye.
We don't confront death.
It's always like swept under the rug.
Um,
and my band mate and my really good
friend,
Isaac's mom also passed away suddenly
earlier this year.
So we made a little song that we
dedicated to Ella's dad and Isaac's mom.
So that's the end of the show.
I hope you guys enjoy this song.
Thanks for watching.
Three one can say hello.
Everyone know who's to say hello to
leave you with is to say,
uh,
I'll see you on the,
this,
uh,
no.
Please swirl bell to go.
Nobody,
you know,
nobody,
oh to say,
uh,
I'll see you on the,
the uh
hm.
Everybody know,
everyone knows today is just the day.
Okay.
Blank.
Yeah.
Taught me how to say no.
Didn't teach me how to say,
uh,
yeah.
By is just the stone.
Wow.
No Bro Stones.
Everyone.
No.
Zero one stone to see you when to say
good.
Uh,
laid across the know.
Everybody know I see you when I closed
my,
uh,
nobody knows nobody.
No.
Jane what?
Faye,
you know,
I'll walk along the road
cheese and very bad.
Everyone knows
today is just the blanket of time.
You've taught me how to say no.
Teach me how to say good,
good
bye.
Good
by just a pal
style.