Welcome everybody to the h three podcast
lie.
Today's episode is sponsored by hinge
and hymns.
Thinking for them.
Today's guest is Tim Heidecker,
the triple threat.
I would even say musician,
actor,
comedian,
and my humble opinion,
one of the most influential comedians of
our generation.
Can I say that?
Yes.
The most.
I would say one of the most.
Okay.
I can't think of a more influential one
off the top of my head in my life,
but I can definitely tell you on my part
that I wouldn't be in comedy today,
I think if it wasn't for your
[inaudible].
So we're going to get some fears.
Thank you to that.
Um,
check out temps,
live tour on cinema,
live checkout,
Tim Howard,
Ecker and Greg Turking 10 live.
Go to Tim heidecker.com/events
for dates and tickets.
All right,
well thanks for having me.
Very grateful and very honored to have
you.
And yeah,
I know it's always tough.
It's tough to get through that.
What'd you think about that intro?
Was it too much?
It was very a sarcastic,
I assume not.
And start counting to get off.
Yeah.
Okay,
good.
Sure.
Fuck.
Already.
Fucking with me.
I'm trying to put you at ease.
You don't want this to be uncomfortable.
I want this to be a positive experience
for you.
Most.
Most important.
Okay,
thank you.
Well that's,
I'm glad to hear that because I have to
admit that I was nervous.
I mean,
you shoot,
yes,
I was nervous,
but I'll tell you why because I wasn't
sure which Tim I was going to get.
I know.
You know what I mean?
They're real tim or the,
uh,
interview Tim,
the interview Tim that kind of makes
like a parody of we'll see how it goes,
but I feel like
good,
I'm in a different place right now,
really.
Um,
but I,
uh,
I've,
we have some mutual friends and,
uh,
and I've,
you know,
I,
I'm,
I'm interested to talk to you in a,
uh,
open and frank manner without any kind
of aggression.
Well,
that's not necessarily confusion,
but you said you're in a different
place.
Does that mean,
well,
I mean,
I guess I've done a fair amount of the
kind of Kauffman s uncomfortable,
right.
Interviews,
which are fun sometimes and funny,
sometimes results in funny content.
Absolutely content.
I've enjoyed Washington.
So I feel like I've done that.
I've done enough of that.
Where to keep doing it sometimes becomes
redundant and not as much fun.
And uh,
and now that,
that,
that maybe I've made enough stuff that
there is interesting things to talk
about.
Maybe it's an interesting experience to
watch me talk about things in more of a
sincere fashion.
Is it,
is it harder for you to be,
is it easier in a way to do interviews
under that Kauffman ass kind of?
No,
it's um,
it's actually a little easier to do it
this way because I'm not worried about
being in a,
in a bit the whole time.
But we'll see.
I mean,
we'll talk it out,
see how this goes.
I think I have a propensity to be
amusing without being confrontational.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
but now we're like very,
it's funny that we're analyzing the
style of interview.
We haven't really talked at all.
No.
Yeah,
just a little,
I guess we should start before play all
that.
Now that we got that out of the way.
Um,
let,
let me,
let me ask you,
thanks for the coffee.
Yup.
God bless.
How is it?
And it's very good.
Cool.
Good balance.
Did they,
oh,
it's black.
So it's kind of hard to mess up.
When did you start drinking black
coffee?
Was that right away or did you,
were you cream first grade?
Wow.
Yeah.
You were sipping coffee at first?
No,
I would try it.
I mean that's a very boring question to
start off.
Well,
you were getting our feet in the,
uh,
we're tipping our code hair.
You know,
you are good.
Yeah.
Who has the braveness?
The ass.
I think I did.
It was boring,
but I did drink coffee in high school.
It's a diner level,
you know,
going and cream and the sugar.
Yeah.
And then,
um,
excuse me.
And then,
uh,
I stopped for a long time after a very,
like anxiety.
Like I drank a lot of coffee.
Um,
I just remember drinking a lot of iced
coffee.
One at a movie,
right.
A friend of mine and got the full panic
caffeine,
the panic,
like over caffeinated panic,
uh,
cocaine feeling and then stopped for a
long time.
But then like,
you know,
the past,
I would say 15 years.
I drink coffee in the morning,
but to get even to get even more in the
weeds and boring,
uh,
first of all this an event tonight.
So I usually can't drink coffee after
the afternoon,
you know,
after lunch.
Sure.
But now the judge tonight,
so I'm just going to,
I'm going to let myself have some coffee
so I could talk very fast during this
interview and we can get through it,
right?
Sure.
And I could be full of brain fires off.
What do you have going on tonight?
I'm doing a musical performance for
Kevin Mcdonald's podcast goes live.
I don't know anything about,
so that sounds gives in the hole.
I do know that show,
but I don't know them on a,
on a name basis.
Yeah.
Are you going to be drinking more
coffee?
No.
No,
this is the last car you got to come
down now.
Okay,
let me,
I,
okay.
I do want to ask you,
so I feel like myself and many of my
contemporaries are,
are so equally influenced by your work.
How old are you?
I could turn into a co interview cause I
don't know very much about absolutely.
You know,
a little bit,
but I don't know the background.
Yeah,
sure.
So if I,
if I apologize cause probably knows
this,
it's redundant for them now.
It's all,
it's all good.
So I might just be curious because I
thought my own show please,
please ask away.
That is totally fine.
But I am,
I'm 32 by 33.
Oh
yeah.
Right.
So we're about 10 years apart.
I'm 42 so I would say,
well basically people who were in
college at the time that Tim and Eric,
awesome show,
great job.
You know,
cause that's when I discovered you guys
and for me,
I remembered the end.
I think a lot of people do remember the
exact moment when they saw your show.
Almost like a on nine 11 almost in a
weird,
it's like wow.
It was that it,
yeah,
it was that formative.
Wow.
So tell me about that.
Um,
I was in college,
three m playing world of warcraft in a
little shithole apartment by myself and
uh,
I just was,
had adult swim on,
it was like some anime and then on came
tim and Eric,
not tom goes to the mayor.
No,
I can't see Allen came.
Awesome show.
And it was just the editing,
the colors,
the sketches,
the surrealism.
Where you a fan of where your comedy fan
before that?
Yes.
You like,
what?
Like what would you have been?
Well,
a,
I will,
I love,
and I love Seinfeld.
It'd be frank.
I love Seinfeld.
That's always been my favorite.
I love comedy,
but I wasn't so much,
you know,
and deep right.
But I'll tell you when I saw that and I
was like mind blown because I didn't
know that you could kind of be funny in
that way and it was done in a way that I
was like accessible to me in a way.
It seems like you could maybe do it.
Yeah.
And it was Seinfeld didn't feel I can
never do that.
I can never ever do that feels so far
away.
Although do you notice now if you watch
it on Hulu,
it,
it feels like,
it feels like a set now.
It feels like you're way they stretched
it or the way they've made.
Like I think the problem is that all of
our tvs are so good that you can see the
truth.
I'm walking down that street.
You're like,
all right.
But anyway,
you like Seinfeld,
you fan.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's great.
I could watch that every night.
Yeah,
it's probably crazy.
So good.
Um,
so basically when I saw that I knew in a
way that I was like,
Oh man,
I would love to work in company.
All of a sudden that crystallizes video
game.
And you did like,
yeah,
I put down the video game and I told all
my friends about it too.
I will say I was,
I was here.
I was your Messenger.
I was,
I was uh,
always call me is they say I was such a
fan.
You guys,
all my friends hated it.
No,
all my friends loved it.
Everyone.
I would always find that where people
were like little backhand.
My,
yeah.
It's like,
I need to say that you liked it.
Leave it there.
I love to tell me like these backhanded
things like I loved your show,
but my boyfriend,
he gay too.
That's funny.
Okay.
I don't,
I don't need to know those staff.
That is true.
I get my,
uh,
my friend's a huge fan of,
yeah.
Yeah.
Tell me about you come on and buy those
times.
That was the time when we met and I was
in Israel.
Anything was here and um,
we were talking over skype like every
day and he would always try to send me
your guys's sketches.
It wouldn't work in Israel and we will
always like,
I want to see it.
I want to see what you're talking about.
It like he couldn't stop talking about
it.
It was forbidden fruit.
And I think we downloaded a bunch of
them.
I apologize for that.
I believe they were pirated,
but I was spreading the word.
You don't care a bit.
Torrenting everything.
Um,
at that time that was,
yes,
that was the pirate rotted Israel.
And I remember sitting down in your
sister and being like,
you got to wash this Brownie mountain
shit.
And she,
she liked it.
Everyone was loving it.
So I'm not one of those guys,
but I had to wait till the question is,
is that that first of all,
you probably hear that a lot from people
that you have influenced their comedy.
Do you,
how do you accept that level of praise?
I mean,
do you accept that?
Do you,
uh,
do you know what I mean?
Not really.
I mean,
not first of all.
I think when,
when we talk about our work,
um,
I,
it is,
it is not just me,
it's just,
it's Eric,
it's John's Krystal.
It's Doug Loosen,
hop.
It's the whole,
it's a collective of people that made
that what it was.
Um,
so I,
I'm okay.
It's not,
I don't,
I'm not too,
uh,
you know,
narcissistic about it that I'm,
so this is all me.
I'm a part of it.
Um,
but yeah,
we admit we,
uh,
so much of that period was making stuff.
It's in such an insular way in such a,
uh,
for ourselves that whether people dug it
or not was kind of not as important to
us.
Right.
And we prided ourself on that,
that we were not doing anything for
fans.
We were not fan friendly.
Um,
not that we,
I mean we,
we,
we were very nice to our fans I think.
And um,
but we weren't trying to please anyone
but ourselves.
So,
um,
I ended,
it's cool to have because I had that I
had,
um,
the kids in the hall,
we were talking before the show that I
like something like the kids in the
hall,
right.
We're totally a influential to me and
like,
you know,
Saturday night live and all those,
and then you get to meet those people
sometimes in life and you get to share
that with them.
And it's nice.
It's definitely nice.
I appreciate it.
I'm glad that those people are out
there.
I'm glad you're,
you know,
it usually results in kind of decent
people too.
Interesting.
I think so.
But I,
I think it's interesting what you said
about that you guys were making it for
yourself cause I definitely think that
shows the,
almost didn't care about how accessible
it was.
The anyone that wasn't like initiated or
I don't know how to say,
but it's definitely part of what was
special about it to what they can.
A sense that it was very much your own,
just really your guys,
his own thing.
Yeah.
We had our,
a strong,
a sense of what we thought was funny and
we felt like we were delivering to each
other that,
you know,
we were making ourselves laugh and,
and the,
the stakes were so low.
I mean we were on in the middle of the
night and we were given very little
money relatively to make something.
Right.
And uh,
so it just seemed like we were most of
the time learning on the,
on the job and making stuff.
And if you use,
especially in the first season you see
stuff that was shot like in the hallways
and like out in front of the office.
That was all like probably a lot of that
was like making a first pass at
something and it not working and then
going like,
well,
let's just go outside and shoot
something,
you know?
So we were given just tremendous,
a kind of freedom to experiment and
figure it out.
What time did originally air on adult
swim?
It's like 1230 or something like that.
1215 maybe.
It was like really fun to tell your
parents that you have a,
I'm on TV at 1215 on something called
adult swim,
which is what we feel all the time
wasn't,
it really was a couple of years.
Yeah.
I had been around for a few years,
but no,
nobody,
nobody still knows what I mean.
Yeah.
It's like,
well rick and I saw your show on comedy
central.
Like,
oh,
they don't even do it on their network.
They saw it.
Yeah.
And then it's still like people,
the funny thing this year has been,
um,
this free real estate
meme.
Oh,
we wanted to ask you about that.
That happened.
I don't know.
I mean,
it comes out of nowhere,
right?
It comes out of the reddit Internet.
Yeah.
And it doesn't count.
It doesn't have any
connection to the work really to the
original piece or to who I am or
anything.
And so I had this little part and the
ant man movie and people on the internet
or like,
Hey,
did you know the guy from the free real
estate,
these names?
And No,
I didn't,
didn't know.
It's like,
that's so fun.
And people get mad about that.
And so it's a weird thing.
And this happened to Eric with the
universe thing and you know,
it's like,
it's chill.
Um,
how does that mean?
How does that feel almost to be like,
it's like appreciating a piece without
knowing the origin.
Does that bother you at all?
Um,
it does a little bit.
I think it certainly does,
but the also there's a resignation to
not having any control over that.
So it's become yours,
you know,
it's whatever kind of cool too on the
other.
Yeah,
it's fine.
I mean,
I saw a fucking free real estate mural
somewhere.
I loved that sketch.
I mean,
and like I remember writing it
and like it being such a simple stupid
idea knowing that you didn't have to do
very much to make it work.
I want to ask you about that specific
sketch because I'm,
I always wonder like where,
where's your guys' minds when you over
high?
I mean we just get super,
are you serious?
No,
I feel like that's always the
assumption.
I didn't assume that.
I didn't think you can't be that
creative when you're no,
not like that.
No,
I don't remember specifically that idea
of where you're headed with that.
It's really probably comes down to it's
free real estate.
Let's do a commercial where were real,
you know,
probably seeing a uh,
late,
I'm carney,
some real estate commercial and yeah,
making that little turn and then knowing
that we could just go in front of a
green screen for a half hour.
Right.
And we would give it to our boys and
they would turn it into,
as Doug would say,
we give them,
you know,
give him some shit to shine.
Is that what it feels like?
Sometimes because I feel like our style
is similar years off saving it's Meyer
from you.
But a lot of times we'll go just fuck
around in front of a camera and then
it's like I have no idea if that was any
good or not,
but I'm going to sit and edit it for a
thousand years.
That'll work out.
Hopefully.
Yeah.
I think there we've gotten more
efficient without I think and are also
our style or interest in what we want to
make has changed a little bit.
So there's some stuff we've done that's
more conceived and thought out and
planned and then that becomes pretty
much what you intended.
Bedtime stories.
Yeah.
It was just like holy planned out.
It's like not that different than the
script and great things happen in the
edit but um,
but then yeah,
there are certain,
lots of great moments from awesome show
that we're just like,
I dunno fucking put on some crazy wig
and you know,
March around and we'll figure something
out a little,
a few of those moments for sure.
Um,
Bob,
I,
there's this story,
I'm not going to make you tell it cause
I,
I'm sure you've told us so many times
about how you guys met Bob [inaudible]
and Kirk and you kind of had,
what'd you call it?
Your break?
I mean,
absolutely.
Yeah,
it was your brain.
It was our big break out.
Just to paraphrase,
uh,
you and Eric,
when it college scent search for Bob
owed and Kirk's address,
send him a vhs with some of your
sketches or was it tom goes to mirror on
the vhs?
Yes.
Well,
the first little short film Tom goes to
the mayor.
Okay.
Matt and voice and an invoice.
The DVD or the DVD if,
to me it changed from vhs to DVD in this
world that you're ehs.
Oh really?
As we shipped it out.
But Bob loved the,
he called you guys up and since then he
kind of mentored you and get your foot
in the door.
Yes.
So I'm curious now that story is
somewhat famous.
I would say apocryphal.
Is that the word?
Uh,
Dan,
can we get a yes,
we're good stuff of legend.
Do you guys get a bunch of Shit in the
mail?
We get a bunch of better call Saul Saul
Swag.
Yeah,
I was there people who hear that story
and they're like,
you know what a little bit,
yeah.
It is a encouraged and,
and certainly through social media,
twitter and facebook,
there's more,
it's easier to get.
It's very easy to get in touch with
Maths v they're easier to get in touch
with.
Yeah.
And every once in a while there's
something that we see or,
and we also are in the business of
making stuff.
Uh,
our production company makes stuff.
So we are actually kind of on the talent
scout.
Have you,
have you ever found talent
and a similar way that Bob found?
Do you guys oh well,
Vic Berger is a big one,
right.
And Love Dick.
And um,
I was telling you earlier the story with
him where he was,
uh,
making fan videos for on cinema and
sending them in and they're like these
music videos he's made that are really
good songs and funny videos just using
our footage from the show.
And He,
uh,
so he,
we were just amused by that and we
contacted him and had him make some
other stuff.
And that set amount of course I think
gave them a little confidence.
It's like all you need is that one
little like one little boost.
No,
it's so true.
And now,
I mean,
today's today as you were touching on,
it's like so easy to kind of get ahold
of people.
Yeah.
It's interesting that if you ever like
determined and you're make something
good.
Yeah,
you can get,
you can get I to see it.
You can,
but they're getting,
making something good is,
I think the hard part's the,
uh,
the barrier.
Most people are a reductive of other
people's work or they're not ready yet
or they don't have the resources.
They're not good enough for us or they,
I dunno.
It's just,
I think it's,
it's good.
I think that there's still a small,
uh,
you know,
it's not a ton of overly,
incredibly talented new voices still
like going to be a small one kid out of
a hundred that's got like this new look
at something.
But,
but there's plenty of funny people.
There's plenty of,
yeah.
You know,
definitely good filmmakers and stuff.
Uh,
speaking of Bob and he's gone on to like
this incredible success.
Has it been crazy to watch because,
yeah,
because that's formation from a comedian
to dramatic actors,
but really something.
Yeah.
I mean when we were,
he was in a transition period I think in
his life when we met him because he had
come out of doing a couple of pilots
that didn't go,
he was directing a couple of movies and
I think he was not really sure what he
was going to be doing for them.
And he was helping us and he was helping
a bunch of other people get started in
the business and,
and,
and yeah.
So I think the,
he was a,
I don't know.
I mean he's,
he's got a good attitude about it.
I know that.
I know.
He's like,
just happy to have the,
have cool work.
You know,
it gets to do cool work.
He's incredible.
I feel that people don't even remember
that he was a comedian at this point
because he's so the breaking bad guy.
It's all right.
But it's all on me lives because I was
listening to a Dana carvey was on Howard
Stern.
It was a replay,
but I was listening to it and he was
talking about Odin Kirk writing these
iconic Saturday night live sketches back
in the Dana carvey years cause he was,
I didn't even know he was involved in
the Odin Kirk and smuggle and Conan
O'brien.
We're all writing like this Saturday
night live
sketch that that got me into comedy.
He was there.
So like he's had these incredible,
you know,
several lives in this business.
Are you,
is that something that kind of appeals
to you?
Because I know you just got cast and the
new Jordan peele movie,
which is awesome,
super excited about you.
Is that something that you can see
yourself kind of doing is making a
switch in a way to a dramatic actor,
which by the way they,
I think you're awesome actor.
I love everything.
Dot.
Yeah.
I mean,
I've been lucky to dip into that world
now.
Uh,
every,
you know,
a cup.
I weirdly a look at my cmdb page and I
noticed this thing where I've been in
two movies a year for the past several
years.
Right.
And it's like a neat,
uh,
kind of thing to try to keep doing it,
you know,
like if I keep doing this and they're
like,
I'm going to start racking them up,
you know,
like I'll stop making movies.
So,
um,
I've,
this is the first big,
I would say,
big movie where like,
you can tell your aunt,
although,
you know,
bridesmaids was a big movie that I'm in
for a minute.
But you're,
are you a main or you're not allowed to
talk about you talk too much about it
because we're shooting right now.
We're actually shooting.
Right.
How about the,
can I you,
this is part of the,
yeah,
I didn't sign any big,
this is my big,
it is the first one where like,
they announce you.
There's like a,
there's a thing.
It's like,
you know,
um,
and everyone's excited.
Everyone's excited that this,
that what's his next move is going to be
in that whole thing is neat.
But it's a great,
it's a great project to be involved in.
Exactly what is the main and,
but then I'm in the middle of it and
it's so great cause it's just like
anything else I do really.
It's um,
you know,
every,
the,
the production people are great.
The cast members or everyone's nice,
everyone's like warm and,
and collaborative and you know,
Jordan's interested in what I think and
cold and you just feel like welcome and
that's relaxing and that's kind of like
a nice environment.
While I am super excited to see what
comes of that.
Yeah,
me too.
Do you audition for that role?
How did you get the wrong?
No,
I didn't,
I'm curious.
I had a friend write me and like,
he was like,
how the fuck are you doing?
Because he's also an actor and he's
like,
what are you,
why didn't,
I didn't even know about this part.
Like am I,
and I'm like,
no,
I just,
I just got asked to do it because Jordan
was interested in you playing this role.
I,
me and mine,
but just writing and that's got to feel
good.
Yeah,
it does.
Pretty amazing.
But you know,
I know him a little bit from the world
of comedy and stuff,
so I'm not,
and he was such a big fan of the comedy,
the movie,
the comedy that um,
it was one of those movies that when it
came out again
was a thing that half the people hated.
And you know,
if you look at the reviews of that
movie,
it's like an they're angry,
reviewed and um,
we felt rick and I felt just like beaten
up by the whole thing and uh,
like very proud of it.
But,
but also like furious that,
that,
that these people weren't getting what
rick was trying to do and all this
stuff.
But what happens is like that movie,
people like your age and younger fuck
fucking like love that movie.
And it meant a lot to them.
And somebody like Jordan is like,
that's one of my favorite movies of your
or of a,
maybe not,
it's his favorite movie,
but he thinks of me through that movie.
And so I'm very grateful for that.
You know?
Are you tired of being like loved and
hated?
That's kind of been like the defining
characteristic of like your career.
I mean,
it's always a good,
I've always said that
for years that like if you're not
pissing somebody off,
you're probably not doing something
interesting.
Do you have to pay them off all the
time?
I don't try to know.
You don't mind?
I might have in the past probably by
like,
I mean as a,
as a result of your work of people being
like so frustrated,
they don't understand it.
It's like,
do you ever fantasize about making this
be,
would you like to just spill out?
Everybody loved this.
Yeah.
I mean,
not sure,
but,
uh,
that's just not in my car really heavy.
I mean,
I know,
I would tell you like it never happened
up until,
you know,
the first from Tom goes to the mayor.
When that came out,
Eric and I were very excited.
We made our TV show.
We thought it was pretty good and we
went on the message boards
and it was just like,
fuck you really,
these guys have aids,
you know that these guys are f word.
It's adult swim forum.
Where like the message,
I didn't know there was such a tough
crowd.
Oh my God.
It was like,
it was a,
and it was just like a flood.
There was like one after the other.
And that was when we learned that this
is a cruel business.
Um,
I mean like,
I know,
but,
but are macho side was like,
good,
fuck them.
Fuck that.
Yeah,
we're,
we're pissing you off.
And then we kind of embrace that a
little bit,
but it still hurts.
It does hurt cause you just want to be
like,
we made this and make you laugh and to
make us laugh.
I'll say if you don't like it,
I mean just,
you know,
here's why you care about,
I mean,
there's plenty of things I don't like.
I don't,
that doesn't make me laugh.
I've never like rage.
It doesn't make me go on the message
board and say like,
I hate the king of Queens or whatever.
Do you,
are you at the point or do you know,
like,
I'm just wondering like,
do you feel like those kind of comments
don't get to anymore when you get into
stuff with people
now become,
and that's why I've kind of,
I try to get off the,
the social media was telling you I'm
taking twitter breaks and personal.
Yeah.
Um,
I do take it personally.
I've been honest about that.
They do take it personally and then I'm
in,
there was a cycle now of people who are
like,
I used to be your biggest fan and now
you suck.
And that's like,
that's,
I don't know if that's worse or
well,
how does that feel?
I mean like genuinely,
how do you feel when people tell you
that?
Um,
it depends.
Like,
if it's something that's,
that I know is a little risky that I'm
doing that's a little s self,
a little personal or something.
Especially my music,
you know,
I put out my music analytical.
Yeah.
And the and which obviously has a
tendency to people that are,
that get upset about it.
Yeah.
But you know,
it's all personal taste.
And I know the music I make is not the,
it's not popular music anyways.
You know,
it's like a kind of music I love,
but it's not,
so people are like,
this sucks,
then I get it.
But I also doesn't,
you never want to hear it.
You don't want to hear that.
Rather not hear it.
And the easiest thing to do is just to
not repeat it.
Yeah.
That's what I've done.
I've been very public about how I,
it wasn't even like that I wanted to,
I needed to stop engaging in reading and
comments.
And I've,
and it's funny to say,
but I've seen,
it's been a process for me to unstick
myself because I've been trying to not
do it for like a year.
I'd say in the past couple months I've
been successfully really boris like
completely.
But like in between that process I would
read comments of like,
and this should just really upset me.
Like,
uh,
what do you guys think about h three?
Not Reading comments anymore.
It's like,
well it's not doing him any good.
And it's like,
I dunno,
it's funny.
[inaudible] man can read probably 20
positive things.
The cortisone car.
I said,
why is that?
Why is that?
I know that too.
And it really disturbs me.
Yeah.
I don't know 20 people or like changed
my life.
I was going to go and heal my son.
I've gotten that idiot.
Nothing.
Oh wait.
I do have the funniest
often the funniest fans,
like especially the cinema crowd.
I love you.
Um,
they're,
they're fucking hilarious and they
contribute to sort of the,
the jokes and the story in a way that's
like,
I would want to hang out with a lot of
those people,
you know,
so I don't want to,
it's,
it's uh,
it would be too bad to totally,
I know,
I know Michael Jackson and lock myself
up.
Yeah.
Cause I also tried to completely not
read anything and I started to feel
really like disconnected from
everything,
which also doesn't feel right.
The large human being is you can meet or
it'd be be around.
I mean my,
I try to,
Oh,
I'm not on the Internet.
I'm actually playing with my daughter
more.
Somehow I'd be like,
oh,
that worked out nicely.
You know,
I'll have the guys filters some comments
to me,
but I just feel like it's not a bad idea
is you get like a digest only the good
stuff and it's like somebody says like,
oh you dive aids.
I think you have aids and you're awful
person and downs.
Like this guy didn't,
didn't like the video.
I'm like,
okay.
Right,
right.
You know,
you give you sweet 13 years old.
And when I was 10 years old,
not all of them,
but I know I used to do terrible.
And this was when the Internet was just
beginning aol chat room.
I would,
I'll tell you the worst thing I ever did
tell me I went into this soap opera chat
room.
Hmm.
Okay.
Like back in those days,
you'd have like chat rooms but with,
with topics and AOL and I created a
persona that was like a mom and I
started typing like,
um,
my baby,
my baby's choking,
my baby's choking.
And they were like,
get off,
get help,
you know,
call the ambulance.
I'm like,
what should,
what do I do?
She's turning blue and this.
And the joke to us was like,
why would I be typing this?
You know,
that's the worst thing you've done.
Huh?
I mean,
gear sweet.
Probably more blocked out praying,
but I think you'd do strike on a good
point is that like sometimes I read
them,
I'll,
I'll brush over 2080 it's that like me
and I'll be like,
oh,
that guy dislikes me.
But the thing you don't know about that
guy because it's the fucking internet
and a could be a 10 year old.
It can be a 10 year old where it could
be the same guy 10 times with 10
different accounts.
Right.
Anyways,
let's stop talking about this because
it's,
I can't imagine.
Well,
it's relatable to most people listen
because when you want to go back talking
about coffee.
No,
I'm just saying like if you're a guy out
there with 10 followers who wants to
make stuff,
he's like,
I'd be so happy to have people hate my
work if they would actually.
Does.
The grass is always greener at any way.
We are at a perfect time for a break,
but we've got a ton of more questions
coming up.
Guys.
Do not go away.
We will be right back after this short
commercial break.
Thank you.
To hinge for sponsoring this episode.
Hinge is a dating app that promotes
healthy relationships of all kinds.
It's a dating app for people looking for
a real relationship with a partner.
Now I'm a married man,
so I was browsing hinge with Dan and I
got to say,
compared to what I've seen of other
dating apps,
it's better.
Okay.
Just straight up.
There's more information.
It's a less superficial and there's a
perfect balance between seeing,
okay,
look,
I met you.
Gotta be attracted to the person.
That's important,
but you want to know a little bit more
about,
or they cute.
What are they into?
What kind of hobbies do they have?
All this stuff is perfectly presented
there before you give them that
proverbial swipe and to oblivion.
Okay?
Now,
why should you believe me?
That hinges better and offered to
healthy relationships.
How about this fact?
80% of hinge dates are rated four or
five stars by real users.
That means that people go on hinge
dates.
Real love,
real connections guys,
go download it@hinge.co
download hinge and the APP store guys,
it's all about wholesomeness.
Stay hinged to find love.
Find meaning.
It's free for Christ sakes.
So just get on there.
Give it a shot.
You food the troopers out there.
I want you to be happy,
okay?
That's why I want you to use hinge.co
take you to hinge.
Do you hear the sound?
That's the clock.
It's taking for the hairs on your head.
You Bald Sob,
right?
66% of men lose their hair by age 35 my
question to you,
what are you going to do about it?
Okay.
Here's the thing.
It's easier to keep the hair.
You have them to replace it and once
you've ordered last tick tock the sweat
dripping down your forehead,
yet you'll vault son of a gun.
It's a hairline.
Slowly starting to move backwards.
Any bald spots they making me read?
This is something really mean.
I'm just,
I'm going with it,
but it's true guys,
because I will tell you from a year from
now,
is it going to be usual business as
usual up there or are you going to be a
bald fucking George Castanza ass looking
motherfucker.
Okay,
I love George,
but he's insecure.
He's bald and he,
okay,
that's not the point.
Do you want a bald spot or do you want
to do something about it?
You can stop the ticking.
Thank you.
Do you want your headlight to recede or
do you want to do something about it
first?
Why do you guys turned to weird
solutions or do nothing when they could
turn to medicine and science?
Introducing for hymns.com
a one stop shop for hair loss,
skincare,
sexual wellness for men.
Hey Man,
I five take care of your bodies,
boys.
Here's the deal.
Thanks to science baldness is can be
optional.
Hims connects you with real doctors and
medical grade solutions to treat your
hair loss.
We got well known generic equivalents to
name brand prescriptions,
to help you keep the hair on your head.
Okay?
These are prescription solutions backed
by science.
There's no way to grow,
no awkward in person doctor visits.
You're going to save hours by going to
four hymns.com
it's so frickin easy.
Answer.
A few quick questions.
Doctors will review and prescribe you
products are shipped directly to your
door.
Here's the call to action,
so listen to f up order.
Now my listeners get a trial of for
fruit of hymns,
not for free,
for $5.
Scratch that and put $5 instead today,
right now,
while supplies last,
that's four hymns and dotcom slash h.
Three you get a month trial for just $5.
This would have cost $100 if you went to
the doctor of pharmacy and it'd be
humiliating.
Now you do it online.
No problem.
No trouble,
baby.
Go to Ford,
[inaudible] dot com slash atria that's f
o,
r h,
I m s.com/h
three four hymns.com/free.
We're back with a great tim.
I notes we might occur and,
well,
what I want to say is go on over to Tim
heidecker.com/events
to crush the site.
Don't blow it up guys.
Get some tickets to my decker and Greg
Turkin 10 art cinema,
live experience,
live,
live.
It's an experience.
It really is basically an off Broadway
show.
There's a head on over.
Um,
we,
we were just talking about on cinema.
Yes.
Which is such a,
it's been such a wild ride.
And then,
yeah,
my question with aunt cinema enough for
you guys that don't know,
started as a movie review,
it's still is essentially broke,
but it was this two couple of guys doing
films,
but he's been a lot of twists,
a lot of turns.
Yeah.
A couple of tribulations.
Was it always your intention from the
beginning that it would have this kind
of story arc to it?
Kinda just as it went?
No.
The story there is,
um,
greg and I were both on the comedy,
the movie,
the comedy that we talked about earlier
and as you do with movies,
uh,
you have a lot of downtime.
Um,
there was this feeling that summer of
there being kind of a overabundance of
podcasts,
medians,
just the mark Marin thing had been kind
of blowing up and there was just this
like to greg and I at least,
it felt like there was too many voices,
po piping in about garbage,
you know.
And uh,
so we had the just idly out of,
we had this idea of doing this movie
review thing and we did it on my phone.
So like the first five episodes of the
podcast are these three minute,
like,
let's talk about ghostbusters.
And then like,
not really knowing much about Ross
busters and it was just kind of,
but we,
yeah,
we started doing longer versions of
that.
And in that setting,
when we're back in La and my studio,
we'd developed kind of a couple of
personas that started developing there.
And then,
yeah,
I think we realized that these guys had
a,
that we could tell stories through these
episodes that could be talked about.
You didn't have to actually see happen.
You know,
you could just say what kind of what we
did off camera be talking about them.
And you could almost create these,
this,
these,
this drama that you didn't have to
actually shoot.
We're actually produce,
um,
became like a radio play.
And,
um,
and it just kind of naturally happened
just to probably fill,
because we didn't want to just make it
this one joke of a guys who probably
haven't seen the movies giving good
reviews.
Um,
so yeah,
it became kind of after a couple of,
I think we,
we saw what the potential of these two
characters and it could,
it could go anywhere.
And it's been the,
I think,
the most fun,
um,
creatively stimulating project for me.
Yeah.
Wow.
Just because it,
uh,
it's such a fun character to be,
and it's a,
and,
and Greg really is,
I think,
the funniest person in the world really.
He's a great foil.
I mean you guys,
and uh,
so,
and it exists on this,
in this a form that like it can exist on
twitter.
It can exist,
um,
in the show itself.
Law,
it can be this,
this soap opera.
It's like we've gotten to make a soap
opera that can go forever.
And that's true.
And that's uh,
that,
that is very liberating.
And um,
you know,
lot actors can die and come back as
well.
The culmination of course they have of
the recent,
yeah.
Arc being the trial for murder or those
20 vanquis parcels.
Yeah,
that was incredible.
That really wasn't,
I've never seen anything.
I've genuinely never seen anything like
that.
I know,
and I hate like being like,
so boy,
so kind of boastful of my own stuff.
Sure.
But somebody has to,
I know I am,
but,
and again,
it goes back to the thing I was saying
earlier with awesome show.
It's this collaborative thing that I'm
so proud of,
Eric [inaudible],
Nicola who directs it and writes with us
and Greg and our producer Andrew and
these people that make that possible.
Um,
so I feel like it's my job to come out
and help you got up.
But it does feel like we put that out.
We put,
we made that and I've heard it from
people like you and we feel it.
We're like,
this is what,
there's nothing else like just,
and the concept alone of seeing you're
saying in a court room and playing it
like straight straight.
But then people like Boden,
Kirk who is always sort of checking in
with me and I'm checking in with him
about stuff,
you know,
he wrote me just being like,
this is like the best thing I've seen
you do.
And for in a long time that,
that Ma that's exciting to me cause I'm
like,
yes,
I feel that way too.
Uh,
but it's also a thing where it's like,
it doesn't get,
it doesn't get treated like anything
else either because it's not,
you know,
I don't care about awards or anything,
but like it isn't a TV show.
It's this thing that,
that people end up watching on youtube
as it's five hours folks.
So it's like,
it's like it's a thing that you have to
commit to,
but I don't know.
We're extremely proud of it and want to
do more things like that.
Cause we're like,
oh this is the fun about other,
had other people have said like what a
great environment to do comedy and just
as a trial where,
you know,
you,
you just set up in the,
it was so fun to make because we just
did it in a courtroom.
Uh,
that was unused.
It was like,
you know,
it'll real courtroom that had been I
guess abandoned or something.
But um,
but we just said,
you know,
like this year he set up at five cameras
and then just did this play every day
for like three days.
Unless you guys plan it out.
It was planned out.
Yeah.
It was pretty planned out.
Um,
but not,
I would say not written,
not dialogue written between he got
planned.
Yeah.
Cause we had,
we had cast people that knew not to give
too much away,
but we,
we cast people that knew how to behave
in that environment and let them,
and by the end of the couple of days,
I mean,
everybody was like,
this is so fun because we're,
we're,
we're just,
we're playing.
It's playing.
You're playing.
Yeah.
And,
um,
if there was an outtakes version of
that,
you'd see much,
lots of like crying,
laughing,
lots of,
yeah.
Lots of like what a read them
deal with.
Do you have think about like how do we,
how do we,
this is so good and I'm so proud of it.
How do we get more people to watch this?
I,
yeah,
I mean it's very,
it's always,
especially with on cinema,
it's been this sort of frustrating.
Um,
it's not for everyone,
but the people that love it,
I'm really care about it and,
um,
support it in different ways and,
and feel like it's the greatest thing.
So I'm happy for that.
I wish it was,
you know,
millions of viewers,
but it's,
it's,
I understand that it's a,
uh,
it's a contentious dry,
um,
watching bad people watching of
negative.
It's not,
it's like a,
it's a kind of comedy that's like that,
that kind of buy all this kind of grow
like not gross but just kind of like
creates uncomfortable experiences and
that's been our whole career in various
forms.
So I understand that some people maybe
have enough shit going on in their real
life that they don't have the luxury of
just like relaxing to that kind of humor
that you guys have always had that
fascination with like an end and you see
it in the other shows that you guys
produce as well.
That absolutely made yeah.
As a real focus on like discomfort,
cringe for lack of a better word.
You know,
what is that?
I,
I mean I don't know it,
it comes probably from the kind of
comedy we liked.
Some of it,
some of it like,
you know,
Albert Brooks,
like Albert Brooks is a lost in America
movie,
which I think is maybe my favorite
comedy film is every scene is that kind
of scene that makes your stomach kind of
hurt.
It's tenses you up.
It's like,
oh no,
don't,
I don't go there.
Don't say that.
Um,
so some of that,
there's some of that.
Um,
most of it's probably though just create
in awesome show at least like creating
absurd situations that,
um,
go dark for very,
not very logical reasons are real
realistic reasons,
but yeah,
I don't know.
It,
it's,
there's something,
I think it's also like a,
a,
a fundamental comedy construct of
failing is funny of,
of some of failure.
Um,
like slapstick comedy is,
is violence and you know,
somebody slipping on a banana peel or
falling down stairs is essentially them
failing somewhere out,
you know?
And so we're doing it on more of like a
emotional level sometimes it's just,
nothing's funny about like people things
going well.
I don't think I like to see an attempt
at that,
but I feel it.
Yeah.
I mean there,
there was kind of comedy that's like
people being clever and smart and that
and witty and quick and that's a
different kind of comedy that I didn't,
I'm not that.
I Love Big Bang if,
yeah.
Quippy and cute.
Well,
let me ask you about absolutely because
I'm a huge fan of everything you guys
produce.
I mean,
predominantly you guys have two huge
shows right now that I think a lot of
people are talking about,
which is the Eric Andre show.
Nathan for you.
I want to ask you questions about the
shows,
but how are you involved like personally
in the planning conception of these?
Not,
not very much at all.
Really.
No.
Were pretty removed.
Our Pr,
our producing partner,
Dave kneebone,
uh,
you know,
we started,
he,
he's a little more involved than we are,
but we,
we essentially started the company in
this second season of Tom goes to the
mayor because we had terrible
experiences with another production
company.
Um,
and really saw that there wasn't much to
it.
You just needed to kind of like hire a
manager,
you know,
and get somebody to manage that kind of
that side of the books.
So we started that just to produce our
own stuff.
And then,
um,
after awesome show wrapped,
we won,
we,
Eric and I needed to take some time
because we wanted to make a movie and we
needed to kind of write the movie and,
and think about it and develop it.
And w another show came in that was
looking for a producer and that was the
John Benjamin has a van show.
And that,
uh,
that for our,
from our perspective,
it was,
we could keep all of our talented people
working while we went off and did
something that didn't require their
services for a few months.
So it kind of created a gap and then it
just became,
you know,
holistically out of that.
Like I know Nathan Nathan actually was
on that,
the Jon Benjamin show.
And so he got to know dave or producer
and he pitched his show to us and you
know,
just try it,
let's go wrong.
So I,
it's,
there's some maybe a let down,
but we just,
we do what we offer with the company is,
is the opportunity that we had,
which is sort of creative freedom and
nobody telling you nobody budding in
with their ideas and notes everything
that you guys practice doesn't have a
quality till it.
Yes.
I mean it's a lot of the similar,
it's a lot of same blood,
same editors is that a group of talented
people at work and a lot of them started
with awesome show and came out of,
I mean most of the people that are
editing and directing have come out of
the,
most of the people have edited and
directed the shows that you probably
like our had worked on awesome show
basically or check it out or you know,
something like that.
I mean,
if it's funny you look at,
we didn't produce the new Sasha Baron
Cohen show,
but I,
yeah.
But if you look at the credits of that,
there's like four guys,
Nathan,
buddy,
Eric,
Nicola who directs all the awesome,
all of a on cinema and decker,
um,
and was,
and also worked on new.
These are your employees.
They w they have been at points.
Yeah.
Um,
there'll be freelancers mostly,
but,
um,
just,
you know,
it's like a small group of guys,
mostly guys,
um,
come editors and producers and writers.
You make like an editorial decision,
like on a pitch.
Like if Nathan's like,
Hey,
I've got this concept.
I don't,
you don't know.
No,
I mean nothing to do with it.
Oh,
what shell,
what's,
you know,
what,
how does absolutely decide what it wants
to produce?
Oh,
we don't decide.
I mean,
we,
we don't have that,
that luxury.
Uh,
we have people,
I mean,
people now we do a little bit,
but we take,
people come in,
pitch us ideas.
Uh,
we sometimes have,
you know,
were developed.
There are certain things or like Nathan
show is really what Nathan wants to do
and it's his vision and you already know
him and we know him and we,
and then you've involved a network like
comedy central who has their say.
So the last thing they want is us.
I mean,
of the conversations I've had with
Nathan about his show have been like,
um,
some,
some stuff having to do with like
promotion and marketing where he wanted
my advice on certain that side of it
sort of like how to handle the war,
getting whatever,
you know,
what the network wants me to do this,
what do you think?
And then watching some rough cuts,
giving maybe a couple of thoughts that
aren't certainly aren't required.
Yeah,
I mean,
so,
um,
no we're just just saying we're glad to
have our names attached,
but you know,
I want environment.
I think our,
our office creates a,
just like a good environment for those
kinds of people to feel creative.
Yeah.
I wonder if you're not giving yourself
enough credit in this situation.
I swear to God,
let me ask you this then in that case.
Well at any rate,
love him.
Thank you.
And keep doing.
You're doing what's,
what's the story behind this?
I've always wondered what the hell is
going on.
Well,
that's my dad.
I see the resemble.
How do you not know that common
knowledge?
It's sort of common knowledge for the
people.
Probably all.
Yeah.
Oh,
there's all sorts of stuff.
Let's close up.
So that's your dad.
That's home movies from the that day,
which was 1989 whatever it was.
I was in Florida and I was going around
with the video camera asking my family
to describe this vacation in three
words.
That was pretty quick,
switch hats,
a little bit high or something.
He said,
absolutely.
And then when Eric and I were just
starting making videos,
I had recently gotten all these video
tapes transferred or something and we
were looking through them.
I was looking through them and there
were a few moments where I was like,
this is great gold right now.
And one of them was that,
one was my poor sister at a recital
singing some song from fiddler on the
roof and her like pho.
Totally fucking up a second verse.
And we didn't use that for anything.
But um,
yeah,
that's it.
And then that just became pretty early
on our slate and it has not changed.
That gets a little,
he likes it.
He takes it.
I think he gets a little residual check
as he getting a little,
a little,
but I think it might be format.
There was a sketch,
we did an awesome show.
It was my funeral and it was when I was
dead and I had this great bloated face
and uh,
we had my dad and mom make a like a
video eulogy for me.
That's really funny.
Oh that was your actual pants?
Yeah,
it's still getting a little,
I think he gets a little,
a couple of cents out of that.
That's finally allowing.
It looks fine to me cause he,
he did this the most sort of insincere
like,
oh well we wish you the best and take it
easy,
you know,
take care and we'll,
you'll be missed.
And just like really insincere though.
Funny.
Tell me how,
how was your relationship with your dad?
You got a lot of dad jokes,
dad jokes in your content,
which I'm a big fan of,
you know about that debt.
Want to meet that dad?
Yeah.
It was mutual with Eric and I,
we both had this sort of a,
we love our dads.
Um,
we could,
I think we have a good relationship with
our dads have a better relationship with
his dad.
Um,
no,
but um,
I think we've just always,
it's been a funny,
it's kind of weird cause it's now kind
of like a common understanding comedy,
comedy concept of Dad.
The jokes,
you know,
you see that like once something gets
into like the world of like Levi's jeans
or you know,
stuff,
it's like,
yeah,
it's fully matured into its own.
But for us it was just something,
there's something awkward about the
relationship and adult man has with his
dad and he's like,
it's,
it can be,
it can be awkward.
It can be just like,
well now we're just two adult men were
in,
have different tastes.
And I dunno,
it was just something as me now being a
dad,
I get it too.
It's like,
um,
you feel a little unnecessary.
Oh,
little holiday.
Your kids,
you can't be on my category three and
no.
Uh,
for,
uh,
no,
she just turned my daughter Amelia just
turned five yesterday and I have had a
little birthday.
Just kidding.
And then I have a son who's about to
turn two.
And Toby,
what a wonderful,
I mean,
how was it,
how was a fatherhood?
It's great gains,
cheer game.
Mesic changed your sense of comedy of
what's funny and kind of giving you a
nail.
Not really.
Same Old,
same old.
I know I'm,
when Amelia was born,
if you look at the third or third season
of check it out,
there's diaper,
there's a diaper joke.
And that's,
I think one of the funniest things to
ever,
but it's right out of the experience of
being,
having diapers in my life.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It's,
it's brule changing a grown an adult
man's diaper and pissed on.
Um,
I want to go back.
I got this,
you'll have this video,
the cat film festival.
I want to ask you some questions about
it.
So this was,
if I can pop this,
oh my God,
look at this little,
a little long way.
So it looked like a monk.
A little funk.
Yeah,
I look at it obviously cut my own hair
or something.
So deviant cut the brow seems very heavy
and yeah,
it was well lit.
It's clearly well lit.
Um,
this was this the first,
what's the history on this video?
Cause I'm not quite sure it was the
final,
uh,
project that UN,
no,
we had been out of college by this
point.
I was living in New York,
uh,
with my girlfriend that was our bedroom
and we an eric would come up from philly
and I would go back to philly and we'd
make stuff sort of recreationally for
fun.
Back in the days when it was fun to make
stuff,
no one was paying attention.
There was no chat rooms and there was no
message boards.
Um,
but we did I think have this idea to
actually do this cat film festival.
It was,
we're coming out of like the
Philadelphia art world a little bit like
I'm out of college.
It was a lot of like trying to like a
lot of festivals and pr and projects and
sort of like arts events.
I think we were kind of into but also
kind of aware of it being silly and kind
of pretentious.
So I think there was this original idea
to actually do a cat film festival,
which happened years ago.
I mean it really did happen that we had
anything to do with it.
Well,
I'll play this if you don't mind.
Okay.
That's a man of it.
Those who have not seen it,
professor,
this is what,
2001 or something stupid or no,
2000 of school program.
We put it up later.
This is tim high.
Decker's interesting in me is like
welcomes Tim and Eric.
You guys already.
It was right there at the very rear.
This,
this is the proposal for the cat fills
their subs to when you,
when you see like these little videos
like this,
is there kind of a golden city,
its golden days kind of vibe.
Do you ever feel like that to mental?
I don't have any sentiment in my heart
that no.
That's a good for you.
Like no,
it's cool.
It's a I fun.
I've fondness for it.
Film Festival visitable.
You got you.
You get,
yeah.
And this was all eric like look at me.
I really did have that picture of me on
the wall with my girlfriend and the
other side.
And I was like ironic,
you know,
it was like silly,
but Eric always tells a story that
Zamboni or that picture of the girl,
the ice skating,
he says that that was in there cause
eric would make um,
like wedding videos and stuff.
Uh,
and,
and like film people's recitals for
money and that,
that shot was in,
it was a mistake when he was a genuine,
that he says it was thick and that I saw
that and said,
don't,
that's the way claims,
that's the case.
Now.
I don't know about that.
He's,
he likes to shower me with,
well why?
But I thought,
I know why.
I thought for sure that was a school
project.
So that kind of messes up my whole line
of questioning here.
Five we did another one,
but we did one that was about lobsters
and film and being better.
It is,
but it's worth,
but go ahead.
I mean it's probably applicable.
It's not really,
um,
let me hear it and not really.
All right,
well we've got it.
Let's see.
Uh,
what's the story behind this video?
Check off that one.
Uh,
what kind of grades did you get?
Well,
a's,
a's always.
Did your peers enjoy it?
Did they understand it?
Well,
we did make a video.
You can look it up.
It's called,
oh,
it's called cat film festival.
No,
it's called lobsters and film would
probably get you there.
But if we're not seeing that,
I think that one we made for our senior
project,
it was like mid,
mid semester senior project.
Similar and yeah,
it was a little more rough.
It was a little rougher.
Not quite there yet,
but that one I'm angered our fellow
classmate.
Really.
And what and what a fashion.
Well,
we were kind of dicks about it.
We were given a assignment to make.
So we had a full year of,
of a film class
that the culmination was making a film,
making a short film.
Now they needed a way to grade US
halfway through to for that first
semester or whatever.
So they gave this assignment that we had
to do a presentation for the class about
some aspect of filmmaking,
uh,
art direction or editing or
cinematography.
And Eric and I were just so into the
idea of making this film and we thought,
well,
this is what we're here for is to do
this film.
By the way,
my films awful.
My real film is awful.
Very serious.
So embarrassed to show you first joined
film school,
you were trying to be a serious
filmmaker.
There was this period of like,
comedy wasn't a real thing.
It wasn't seemed unattainable.
Yeah.
And it wasn't something you should just
always a funny guy.
Be like,
Hey,
I'm a funny guy.
Oh,
he's a funny guy.
Hilarious guy.
Very fine on what's a yes,
but I'm,
I'm going to make size area flicks,
but I'll be,
I'll be like woody allen in the mid
seventies you know,
I'll be September.
What do out terriers.
I loved Woody Allen and that's why I
kind of,
I mean I think I wanted to go in that,
that sort of direction of making my own
stuff and being funny in that,
was there a point during college where
you're like,
this is kind of all these people and the
people I'm around,
this isn't what this is isn't connecting
with me.
Yeah,
a little bit.
I mean at Temple University they were
very socially,
uh,
in India they're interested in,
in sort of political,
social justice,
the kind of storytelling,
filmmaking and comedy was not considered
something that you could do that with,
which is really stupid.
It's almost like the do that more than
anything is the perfect breeding ground
for your style.
Yeah.
So,
and there were also like technically not
capable of,
of,
you know,
they didn't do it.
We hadn't entered into like the final
cut pro era of where everyone could just
load up a bunch of footage.
We still were doing like a weird video
toaster slash cutting film.
So it was,
we're in a weird place where we couldn't
really make anything that great.
You know how you guys pass?
You got to the finish that story.
It was in the middle of the semester.
Instead of doing a presentation on the
art direction in front of the students,
uh,
we made this absurd film that was me
with my presentation was that there are
lobsters in film and then I could show
you examples is adults.
It sounds almost like a conspiracy
theory.
It was just like a meaningless waste of
time and interviewed some professors
about it.
And then Eric's was like that vhs is
better than film and we just made these
stupid like you,
you know,
you could look it up.
But,
and then what we thought was really
clever,
it was,
we shot the presentation in the same
lecture hall as where we were.
Everyone else was giving the thing.
So when we played it in
the room,
we were in the room,
it was playing,
we were in the room that it was being
played in.
So,
um,
and then it had this musical interlude
of us like dancing and it was just like
very primordial,
but they were pissed off.
We got an a because the professor had
thought it was funny.
The students felt like we,
they're pissed that we got away with
really not doing the assignment.
You know,
they're just angry because they didn't
think about it and none of them are
doing anything.
You don't hear their names.
They're not two films a year,
not the thought buddy jokes are
beginning of making videos.
Kind of started at my school too.
I studied art and video art class.
Then I ended up doing like our early
videos and show them in class as,
as like my assignment,
which was also kind of kind of like what
you're describing because in art
everyone was also very serious and huck
high emotion and talking in classes and
I was just never very,
I was never very visually uh,
adept.
And so you'd take those classes in my,
my go to move would be to like make
something intentionally bad,
just to be like,
well,
this is my art,
you know?
But it's also like,
I really don't know how to do that
stuff.
You're shielding yourself in a way of
like criticism.
Yeah.
But it's,
funnily enough,
Ila had these video art classes in
college and I mean,
I was just emulating you guys as much as
I could because that's all I knew.
That was funny.
And we just made,
like the first one would ne was this
fetal called chocolate,
where I was like grotesquely naked.
I mean,
it was wearing underwear and just bring
my buying chocolate.
I think we must have just horrified,
horrified everybody.
Well,
there's a lot of that out.
Certainly in college is a lot of just
like,
I'm crazy.
What can I tell you?
Uh,
my favorite anecdote of Ella's a college
years,
one of her best friends and credit to
her for thinking of this idea shirt,
her final video,
we should put a camera on the toilet and
filmed herself taking a poop at that
professor's comment,
which,
which sticks with me to this day.
One of the best things I've ever heard
his note to her was,
was simply this.
Maybe next time,
less hair.
Oh,
that's horrifying.
So that was what we were up against.
So by,
by contrast,
I think that it probably wasn't,
that wasn't that discussed right?
I would love to never see that.
Yeah.
Let me ask you again,
did you ever have any director disputes
during the making of pigment with Tommy?
Uh,
yeah.
Um,
that was,
I dunno how much to tell you about that,
but,
um,
well why'd you say that?
Or is there some things that you,
you don't like to talk about it.
Why is that?
No,
I,
I think there's a little nice to have a
little mystery,
but I think we
brought him in and um,
and made him the director of that direct
us and then we,
cause we really wanted to be around him
to watch how he worked.
That's really why we brought deserve
that.
You know,
you guys were kind of ahead of the game
and the timing wise up because now he's
kind of a superstar.
He was last year and now it's,
I don't know,
it's just,
it's probably,
that's probably it,
right?
I mean that's not going to,
yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
I dunno.
We were trying to get him on the potty
and he,
I mean he keep blew us off twice.
Really?
He lost her number.
Oh,
well he was a big,
not the most satisfying experience.
I,
I suspected I suspected that and go how
I want it to go.
No,
I mean there was definitely the was so
room vibe in La,
you know,
when we got here back in 2003 so I don't
feel like we were,
we were in that maybe second wave of
people that were,
because when we went to the screenings,
it was sold out and,
but all the way back then.
So yeah,
it was fun.
And then I remember going,
the last time I went,
which is also several years ago,
it was,
it had like a,
it took a mean turn.
Maybe it was just the night I was there,
but it just felt like people were
laughing at that woman who was like,
you know,
kind of implying that she had gotten fat
and it was just,
it had this kind of nastiness to it in
the audience.
It's kind of mob mentality.
That claim was like,
hm.
I don't know if I liked it.
Yeah.
I don't know about this,
but it might've just been the night.
Yeah.
Tough,
tough audience crowd,
but did you guys ever kind of,
I mean,
and the editing bay does well I guess
you don't want to talk about,
no,
go ahead.
What about him?
Did he ever give his opinion when you
guys putting it together?
Like how did he like the piece after I
came out,
you know,
I don't know.
I didn't talk.
Go about,
uh,
one of a kind.
Yeah,
he is.
We've met with them several times after
working with them about doing something
together and it never,
it would always get weird and um,
you know,
we wanted,
he did this thing,
the neighbors,
just,
you ever see the neighbors?
Yeah,
that was,
we have one off the wall.
We were like,
well,
we'd love to help you produce that.
And he'd be like,
great,
maybe you can get me,
you know,
the right editors and the right people.
Like he wanted to do it for like,
I understand that idea,
but it is about it.
Because what made that so special was
we're like,
we will literally just find you the
money and then you make it and whatever
it is you'd give it to us and we will
hand it to the network.
Like we don't want to have any,
we want to like,
like uh,
like disturbing a tribe in the Amazon.
I don't want to have any influence.
I don't want to try to like replicate
what you do,
but I also don't want to assist you to
make it better.
But I also understand his desire to
like,
why can't I,
why can't we just have the best people
working on this?
But then it just becomes like anything
else,
the trig.
So we,
it's just like,
it became too complicated.
Yeah.
I can imagine.
That's kind of his style.
But like working with people like
Tommy's like their bread and butter of,
of,
of what you guys did an awesome show.
Yeah.
Do you guys ever,
I mean for all for,
I've heard this while to story.
Tell me if this is something you guys
did.
You guys used to do.
Put people through uncomfortable
situations.
They get a good performer react
performance for example,
is it true that you will put people on
cranes up in the sky,
the green screen,
they get a ride to get?
Well No,
it'd be,
I actually opposite.
I was up in the crane with the actor on
green and there's just a couple people
we do that with,
which is to create a,
uh,
just the Doug [inaudible] who's one of
the announcers on check it out and he's
one of the,
he's like the sports guy and he's a real
straight guys,
a real like serious kind of a normal
guy.
But when,
when we,
we just have the system where when we're
shooting him,
we tried to create just like distraction
so we can get a moment of him being
like,
what was that?
And those get harder and harder to do.
The more they get more elaborate.
And just so they culminated in me with
one of those cranes,
one of those like [inaudible] where you
change the light bulb just being like
operating where those go.
Yeah.
And we just want to create this chaos
and,
and an uncomfortable environment that,
that gives just that little spark in
their eye.
Like,
I might,
something's gonna fall on me.
Just one that moment.
Yeah.
Um,
and we've done that.
We probably took it too far,
too far.
I'm very intrigued by that.
Uh,
you know,
we would just like,
there's certain people where we would
just,
uh,
we'd maybe kinda gotten sick of them and
gotten tired of,
uh,
they had done something a little bit
maybe to deserve it,
but,
um,
we would just like amuse ourselves by
like sending in a entree,
like sending an appetizers while we were
shooting and,
you know,
yelling at the crew,
like,
get Outta here,
you know?
And they're like,
but he said he was like creating these
little plays that really were just for
us in a year.
Um,
and but nothing ever.
nothing ever that we felt like bad about
it.
It would always end.
It always ended them feeling good and
like wanting to work with us again.
That's the ticket.
I mean,
you walk a thin line because the people
that act frequently,
I don't know if they know whether or not
they're right on the joke or not,
but I think the real kicker,
we have kind of the same effect.
We work with people like that too.
Is it?
They want it,
they want to come back.
They want to be a part it,
yeah,
no.
Yeah.
I mean we've had a few people that
weren't happy with the way things went
and we feel bad about that,
you know?
But,
but for the most part,
uh,
there is,
first of all,
we're never,
we're never presenting things,
uh,
w with false pretenses.
We're not saying it's something that,
it isn't always like this is a comedy
show.
It's,
uh,
but you know,
there's certain tricks that we do to get
what you say is a little pr little
reality out of the situation.
Yeah.
You know,
I feel is fairly benign,
but,
you know,
not the most honorable,
honorable way to behave,
which is fine.
You can be a little,
you can be a level dishonorable
sometimes.
Um,
how do you find these bizarre people?
Just craigslist.
People are,
I mean,
do you have techniques?
What do you,
what do you find these folks?
Uh,
well we'd like to say,
uh,
there's a couple of services that people
sign up for to become actors and then
forget that they've,
you know,
it was like three years ago,
you go for the old ones,
we'd go over like the bottom of the
pile.
Like,
Oh yeah,
I remember doing that,
but do you want me?
And so some of those people and then
frankly,
yeah,
it's,
we built,
sometimes there'll be like an extra that
we,
that ha we'd had like working background
and we'd be like,
who's that?
Right.
Bring him up.
Um,
yeah,
there was a guy in,
in check it out that we call Brown,
his name is Brown.
And he was a background guy and he was
just walking behind rule and he had a
brown a sweatshirt on.
It's why we call him brown and we're,
we just saw him and we're like,
that guy,
have him keep walking behind brule.
Just like create a line and just,
and have him look at rural and,
and we were,
it was one of those things we're just
zooming in like,
oh,
that's fucking weird.
And they were like,
you stick around,
we have worked for you.
Hey,
you're recognizing.
So kind of special quality.
Yeah.
Just a look.
It's a weird,
weird vibe where,
you know,
yeah,
a little on edge.
Um,
that's usually it.
It's,
we get plenty of people sent,
you know,
who are like,
their headshots or wearing a bow tie and
they've got glasses and then they're
like,
you know,
I'm the wacky guy.
And like it's a special thing.
Usually it's like a normal person that,
that feels like they don't belong in
this,
in this world.
Have you ever had had a bad reaction
with some of these people because they
are a little lacking.
Some of them are little and seem like a
little wackier than others.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
whacked by a Wacky,
I dunno what that,
uh,
there's people that you're like,
yeah,
like,
Ooh,
this,
I don't want to keep this guy.
I'm going to not give them my cell
phone.
We're not going to hang out after the
shoot.
Um,
but yeah,
I mean it's usually pretty good vibes.
Everybody you've ever heard of this,
uh,
this phenomenon,
I always hear this now it's like you
hear people,
it,
it's like a tim and
Eric Sketch,
you know?
Yeah.
Have you heard of the subreddit?
It's called.
I'm not knocking him.
And what do you think about that?
I love that place.
Cool.
Yeah.
I don't go there often,
but sometimes I see stuff there and it's
like,
yeah,
that's,
I mean it's,
that's where are a lot of our stuff
comes from.
We don't look there,
but we under,
that's the world that we would look at
and I've got one video.
Cool is my favorite.
That actually was one of our first big
videos was making an edit this video,
I don't know if you've seen this,
have you seen this?
I don't think so.
I think you'll love it.
This guy's such a leg,
30 seconds.
I mean it's so powerful.
I'm telling you this is cool.
So while this guy just,
he just kept it cause it's such an old
video,
but it's just the guy from a documentary
a,
he's a ice cream taste tester by
professional
gold.
He's think I have seen,
this is what we do is take a small
amount of right off the top.
It doesn't take much.
That's the warmest part right here.
I'm going to invert the spoon,
hold 9,000
tastes,
but doug would just loop that part
having pure vanilla or sweeteners,
that's a 10
so actually you know what I want to do,
if I can just indulge myself so I get
here for Christ's sake.
The first big video we made was it edit
kind of a Doug Dj dug a little remix.
Yeah.
Just show you a picture I just sent to
vic.
That is like a pretty good example of
how we work in real time.
Mm hmm.
12 million views on this sick little
baby man.
That's crazy.
Oh that was when w I'm ready.
Are you ready to watch this?
I'll look at the picture.
Oh that's very quick.
And maybe you can show your crowd,
but yeah,
we can show them.
I just was watching a little bit of the
John Mccain funeral the other day,
like the procession and you know it was
just on the news and they just,
you see this guy off to the side and
it's the kind of thing I just capture
and send to.
Who is that guy?
Matt?
Matt,
can you see that?
Let's get,
let's find out who is.
This is a,
it's probably somebody well known.
He's standing right by the car.
Buy The car,
look at this guy.
But like that's a great special call.
It's like the world is full of the Tim
and Eric.
It's all around us.
You are,
but you guys,
you're,
you named it,
right?
You like put a name to this strange?
I guess so.
No.
So here,
this is my,
this was my big break.
Okay.
This is 27 seconds.
It's quick.
Quicker than the original.
Yeah.
Cover all thousand taste bud area
warming up,
driving up,
talking to him.
That cream pure vanilla.
Yup.
That's a 10
that I mean for for 11 that's 11 million
views.
While 12,
if,
do you know if you want to round did jay
well,
good for you.
That was my,
Nathan was learning how to edit.
Like that was the first video I edited
possibly by myself and then come on.
Hey,
well good for you.
I mean it's great.
Thank you.
You've found something original and um,
you know,
you found the rhythm of that that made
you laugh and you,
thank you.
You sure?
Now we see the original,
we almost do that editing,
right?
Yeah,
that's right.
It was so simple.
What's going on?
Why's Papa John's so funny because we've
also been John's,
I became fascinated by papa John and
then almost separately.
I didn't realize that you guys were
doing pop that on gags.
We did it lie papa John.
I,
yeah,
I don't remember.
It's just so benign and lame and,
well,
what year company Papa?
Kind of funny.
Just right out the gate.
I can't remember what our,
well,
we started doing live shows,
sort of.
Um,
not,
we didn't naturally come out of doing
live.
You're not like standups.
Uh,
so we were like,
oh,
we've got to do a live show,
you know,
where are we going to do,
and one of that was one of the ideas was
that we'd sort of like throw a pizza out
in the field.
This is basically what gallagher used to
do.
You know,
isn't that complicated?
But yeah,
I don't remember.
It was just like the,
the world of the khaki pants and the
bad,
I mean it comes out of that,
which we did with the Shrek videos too,
which is like a blatant,
uh,
like self promotion for somebody else.
Just sort of like proud of companies.
This is a corporate kind of like no,
uh,
no shame kind of vibe that we'd see in,
in life.
You know,
at like a super bowl or something.
Like Papa John's presents,
you know,
Whitney Houston,
the whole stadium after Papa Papa is no
longer in the house.
I've been hearing about it.
They C oh is called Steven Steven pop.
Steven.
No Papa Steve.
Not Love.
Why always think like,
why can't,
why do companies have to keep existing
forever?
Like camp,
things just end.
Can't they just tell it all it all off
now they've all doe way.
He tried giving away a pizza and empire.
These things don't mean think,
think companies come and go.
Right.
I'll pop it.
He was built to last I think sauces or
butter sauce.
Yeah.
That's pretty good skill.
It's ridiculous.
Also,
I've got a couple more,
I mean we're,
we're pretty much done here,
but I've got some videos that I'd love
to show you if you got some time.
Okay.
They my videos now.
Oh,
okay.
Well Alex Jones,
I've seen you goofing on him.
You have a great impression.
Yep.
It takes me a little bit to get into it.
Yeah.
Happy to be here.
He's also been,
um,
in a little bit of a goofball.
He got band a little bit of a Goof,
but then I'll tell you why.
I'll tell you why they're doing it.
Because the powers that we have,
the influence that we have,
the ability to reach the people out
there scares,
scares them too.
Yeah.
That is too good.
Well,
here I've got a little soundbite here.
Destroy the child.
That's my little soundboard.
It,
uh,
in fact he got banned.
But then the,
I mean that,
you know,
that was a thing that happened.
But then,
and first of all,
let me just preface this because I
don't,
there's nothing wrong with being trans
and that's not the point of what I'm
about to tell you.
Transient or,
or transgender close to them are
perfectly acceptable.
But he is someone who has said that
being a transgender person is a mental
illness.
And have you seen in the news that he
was actually found to be a jerk in his
toolbox to transport?
Oh,
oh,
I didn't know.
No,
let me thank you.
The of this chick,
well,
he's kind of,
I want to say,
I don't want to say ruins,
but I feel like being banned,
he had this huge thing.
He was banned off everywhere and
everyone was like,
it was this great social issue where
like freedom of speech and he was like
riding that.
But like a couple of days later,
I think he's a meme.
I think he's a meme now.
Well,
he's been to meet people.
There's people that support him.
But I feel like he's been turned off the
video before you,
have you seen the video where the,
the fan of his Milo and him or sitting
at a diner and this fan comes up to him
and he's,
the guy looks like he's on meth like
this.
Tweaker you're like living in a trailer
somewhere and like he just looks like
he's got that thing in his eye that he
believes everything Alex Jones says.
And he's like,
uh,
you know,
I've been following you for years.
And he's all like,
yeah.
And I was,
you could see Alex Jones just like
cringy.
Oh,
I haven't,
yeah,
I've got some,
I got some time to send you.
I've got this footage you need.
And you could see them like getting up
and leaving and you're like family.
No,
but Alex Jones is going to be haunted by
these people and it's nice to get a dose
of like,
Hey,
these are your people.
People suck.
Well,
so Alex Jones,
by the way,
he's selling beauty products called Info
wars.
Yes.
For Women.
Well,
it's for skincare for men because I
mean,
he is an Alpha male.
He's very alpha as as it gets.
He's so alpha that when he watches porn,
even the chicks dicks.
Wow.
Let me see this.
So how do we not a joke.
This is real.
This is real is a heart attack.
And this is fresh news.
This is today.
It's a cup from him I bought a week ago.
Yeah.
Well I mean,
I mean you know twitter.
So who knows?
I wouldn't know.
Yeah,
no,
as far as I'm aware that hasn't happened
but close.
Okay.
Let's see.
Let's do this in mind
products.
But these are so good.
Great skin cream.
Aloe Vera.
There's no spatial.com.
So here we go.
Here's the moment you can stop,
right?
So,
uh,
hey baby.
Okay.
Now obviously it was a brief encounter.
Now what was it that we saw?
Dan,
can you tell me what was the title?
Cause I don't want to pull up and show
anything.
I'm not supposed to see.
It was something of like,
um,
Dan,
tell me what was the exact title,
if you could play,
you need to hear because it's really
true cause it was um,
insatiable cock.
Hunger is a,
and I need a,
I need a direct,
let me,
let me Google it real quick man.
He's like,
he's got some,
some uh,
you know,
he used to be satisfied somehow.
Self satisfaction.
Well,
I mean watching pornography is fine,
but yeah,
no,
I understand.
You can't be,
you're watching people are mentally sick
and then beaten your fucking dirty ass.
Alex Jones.
Me.
No,
that's good.
That's good.
Okay.
That's so funny that now we can just see
everything I'm doing and my can't
opening windows.
Who and who knows what's what people saw
on my phone.
You gave me that phone.
I will.
Yeah,
I showed him the naughty Tba Marissa
minx relieved of cock hunger by Stud.
So that's,
that's what it said on the screen real
briefly is that uh,
trends,
well naughty t girl to girl relieved of
cock hunger.
So confusing is a clear like found the
video.
They saw the title Naughty Tieger.
Okay.
And people found that video and it was a
very graphic,
I was doing research,
I was finding out what's going on in
nursing world.
Well actually we don't even need to
imagine he is the reaction because we've
got it.
Good
development upset about this thing.
Look a little like Wilson,
that cut guy,
you know the wheel Sasso from Fox.
I mean from mad tv yet it'll come.
You could look up.
We'll come and get us to,
well let's look up for,
and don't realize it until just now,
but well Sasso done that right?
We've got another SNA.
Oh yeah,
it does look like they're on.
Um,
what was that name of that Vm at TV.
So,
so here we go.
So caller asked him going to get and
everyone on the Internet was just
talking about how he was caught watching
porn.
I'm going to address something.
Here we go.
Okay.
That was neck and neck.
So people don't get upset about this.
They can win.
Yeah.
Um,
and also,
um,
what about the Trans Porn on your phone?
Out of her,
you were going to talk about that?
Say that again.
Sorry.
Articles about that.
It's ridiculous.
I was like looking up,
some reporter popped up porn on my
phone,
everybody's had porn,
popular phones hundreds of times in the
studio.
And then like something pops up like,
oh my God,
I looked at,
it wasn't the news blurted out cause
there was nothing there.
They blurt it to then say something was
there,
he went to it.
But some porn menu,
I probably had porn men use pop up 500
times in the line.
By the way,
I've seen it was a four chan detective
kind of live and die by the pepe the
frog.
Right.
And so I've seen the detective work and
there is no doubt that this guy was
looking to relieve his insatiable
coffee.
Determined it wasn't some pop up and it
was most definitely,
yeah,
I've seen it.
I've seen the detective work.
Okay.
There's insatiable hunger.
China gets to something,
right?
That's the end.
It's the nihilism that that if they live
to eat just as much pleasure,
it's just about getting whoever's no
law,
no alliances or ounces for you guys.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
No,
I'm the fortune freaks.
Yeah,
no,
they got one.
They your own.
Yeah,
but I'll finish it cause he's squirming
and it's really fun.
The one who loves,
I appreciate your call.
I mean it's insane.
People,
people that look at porn and people that
lie about it.
I wasn't looking at porn on my phone.
There's people who watch porn are people
who lie about it and I wasn't.
Looking at a bar is a great little piece
of Alex Jones and we do it on my call
and show called.
It's a,
by the way,
that's the other thing.
Want to plug office hours,
office hours.
It's my little podcast Collin's show.
What's the funnel page?
A real tim.
Hi Decker.
But you're telling me I should do it
here on Youtube,
I believe.
I truly believe you can subscribe to the
podcast usual podcast ways.
Yeah,
but he's got a great one.
I use the sample of the time it seemed
good
or or or or
that is that edit or was he really just
trying to get a stop?
He did a few like or times dick really
gets Alex.
Man,
you good?
I don't
take phones on here that I look at porn
on of porn on exclusively in the shower.
They have a Ziploc bag.
Weird.
Non Camera's already going.
Like he used to be that bad,
like androids.
It's so great and it reminds me so much
of the tech crews,
you know?
I thought he was going to say it was an
end in
Turner,
so yeah,
he didn't even know.
Didn't even go that far.
Right.
Everyone can watch whatever they want,
but don't think about it and,
right,
exactly.
Exactly.
Well that's about,
I mean we're going to end on that note.
Yeah.
Is there anything else that we should
discuss?
No,
I think it's been lively.
Lovely chat.
Thank you.
Well,
I enjoyed it.
First of all,
guys,
please once again,
head on over to Tim heidecker.com/events
let's party party.
Let's a great show.
No pizza's going to be thrown out at
that show.
Bring your own pizza.
Oh No.
Yeah,
the on cinema show.
You're going to get a some dkr also.
I'm doing the adult swim festival.
I should be booked that.
I think that'll be fun.
You want to go there with Justin,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Um,
and then,
uh,
office hours when I have the time and
see me in Jordan peals new movie,
March,
2009.
Well that's not [inaudible] release
already.
And that is where you get on it.
You're still filming or just you're not
even start?
No,
we're in the middle.
In the middle.
Is that the real time consuming?
Uh,
for him?
It is not for you.
Uh,
no.
I'm,
I'm kind of in and out throughout the
next few months.
It's,
it's,
it's lovely though,
just when you w w when you,
uh,
can do something where you're not
responsible for that element of it,
which is unusual for us to just kind of
be happy,
you know,
not worry about,
oh,
we're running a little late here.
How are we going to get this?
You don't have to worry about any of
that.
You just show up.
Just show up,
do your best.
Uh,
say God bless you said a lot of
memorizing lines and some,
but not much.
And it's very,
you know,
he's not super specific,
it's like say what?
Say what?
How you would say that's good because
I'm,
that's the one thing I'm not good at is
memorizing lines.
I'm afraid I could never do that.
I think it's a discipline.
Right?
And it's to get better at it.
It's like you can train your brain to do
that better,
but I'm not,
I'm still very,
very like,
what do I see?
Oh,
it was in a better call Saul,
the last episode there was a,
that gail character.
Do you watch the show caught up except
for the new APP?
Oh,
well,
you know gail characters from breaking
bad.
That's the guy that business is now.
Yeah.
Well he does this thing where he's like
singing all these,
these,
uh,
chemical compounds to a walkman
millennium and he's doing it like
perfectly.
And I'm watching that going like,
I would never be able to do that pretty,
it would be like,
it would be like a week of shooting and
like you could edit something together
and it was such a short scene,
like the dedication and rehearsing just
for that brief.
And I bet you nobody thinks about that.
But yeah,
I did have this sinking feeling like I
would never be able to do that.
And what else can't I do?
What if I get something like that?
Oh,
you said you're a big ass while I'm Tim.
I appreciate you so much.
Coming out of,
I mean we're a needless to say,
but I'll say it again.
Huge,
huge fans and I'm very grateful for
everything you do and I'm glad this was,
I think this was a positive experience
for you.
It was very good.
I feel I'm old.
I was there.
There you go.
Oh,
it was lovely.
Good time.
Coffee.
Yeah.
I'll never watch it or listen to it.
No,
I won't even go to mean.
Like I said,
I hope I didn't hurt anybody's feelings.
I hope I didn't reveal too much.
I didn't ruin,
I won't read the Common Vic.
Maybe he's watched me feel good to make.
Are you out there?
You're great.
Thank you.
With one of these,
by the way,
your boy some sick stuff.
All right,
well thank you so much.
We love [inaudible].
Yeah,
I'll be there and not in a heartbeat
here.
All right guys,
guys,
thank you so much for why instincts is
to be the one wrapping it up.
I'm such a natural home.
Please.
We Have Adam Carolla on next week.
If you want to wrap it up for us,
ladies and gentlemen,
you,
I'll do it.
I'll do it going folks,
you're in for a real treat.
We've got one of the greats,
Adam Carolla coming up next week,
right here on the h three podcasts.
It's going to be a lot of fun talking to
Adam about all the things that he's got
going on in his career.
Is it on a Thursday?
Damn,
I think it's an unknown.
No,
it is Thursday actually.
Oh,
we'll get back to you on showtime.
I mean,
all right,
let's wrap it up guys.
Thank you for,
we will be here on Tuesday as we always
are,
always in the past two weeks and we
shall have really the very best.
So thank you all for watching and have a
great weekend and a happy Labor Day.
Let's celebrate those labors,
the Labor that right you doing a
barbecue for Labor Day.
Uh,
my daughter's birthday party.
Any petting a,
what's going on?
Are you planning?
You've got petting animals.
We're having a halloween themed birthday
party.
Oh,
that's cute.
Yeah.
I'm dressing up.
Where's the Frankenstein?
Well,
they pictured that online.
No,
maybe if it,
if it looks good.
My audience.
Yeah.
Oh Shit.
That's him.
All right,
let's adios.
Thanks guys.