Welcome one and all to the h three
podcast experience experience now.
Yeah,
I like it to echo stone.
It would be cool if you,
I don't know if that's an effect or if
you guys could just do that with your
voice.
It'd be way cooler.
We can't get to hit us,
Dan.
So you want to hit us with an
experienced sailor eight to say hd
podcast.
Oh,
she does that.
So it's only you got so already.
It's an ego thing he's gotten,
I haven't,
I don't have it and now it's gone.
Anyway guys,
welcome to the experience.
Uh,
today's sponsors are expressed vpn and
honey,
and today's guest is the great and
hilarious comedian and an actor,
Chris Delea.
Yes.
Who hosts and extremely funny podcasts
you should all be watching called.
Congratulations with Chris.
Delete with me with you know,
guests.
Uh,
you guys can check them out.
He's got you.
Got You.
I was talking about you can.
Cool.
He's got,
it's like I'm gonna bring him out.
He's got the fall of the leader tour
tickets are available now@chrisdelea.com
slash tour tour.
Also,
if you have Netflix,
any of not washes to hilarious specials
magnifier and,
and cordial,
then what the fuck are you doing with
your life?
We can curse here.
Okay.
I hope you have a full life.
If you haven't seen them,
I hope you have a full life in it
because you've been so busy.
You've been,
yeah,
that's the only acceptable excuse.
And I'm like,
all right,
cool.
Yeah.
You know,
but if not,
then hey,
maybe I'm just not your type,
but maybe I look like a guy.
Try it at least.
Yeah,
true.
Already have netflix.
Everybody has,
you know,
he's talking about this recently
fucking,
I think they almost have 200 million
people on Netflix now.
So it's like over half the country.
So I did.
I know.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
So I did like a year and a half ago,
they had a party for 100 million
subscribers.
It was half a year ago.
No,
a year.
Like a year and a half ago.
Oh my God.
They're growing fast and,
and they were like,
they,
they hit up my manager and they were
like,
does Chris want to perform for the
party?
And it was like,
no,
it's going to be a fucking train wreck.
But I was like,
yeah,
I'm not gonna say it.
No.
Well,
what's your hesitation you're performing
to just the Netflix?
It was like,
Hey,
uh,
well,
yeah,
and friends and people that were invited
to the party.
It's a special event,
but it's just like,
it's just,
I knew just anytime as a comedian,
people are like,
you want to perform it,
this thing that's not in a comedy club.
Right.
You're like,
okay,
I'm not going to be right.
It's not going to be amazing,
you know?
But so,
uh,
so I was like,
well,
I don't want to say no to them and I
love Netflix.
So,
and I worked for them,
so I was like,
yeah,
I'll fucking do it,
you know?
And we made it fun.
It was fun.
It was me and three other comedians
cannot remember who one of the other
comedians were.
That's how it was a crazy,
but it was,
it was,
it was fun.
We made it fun.
It was like in this room off to the side
where other bands were playing too.
So he like,
you heard you were,
he had this crazy,
it was like I would have to do it.
That knows how to party.
I know they go,
oh,
it was huge.
It was huge.
And um,
we were doing,
it was like,
it brought me back to the open mic days
when I was doing,
I'm like,
I will play bowling alleys.
It doesn't sound,
I mean dude,
you play by play.
I played bowling alleys where like you
would compete with people who were
bowling in between pins.
You'll try to time like the punch line
in between like after they are right
before they,
it would go with the kids.
Is that the worst show you've ever done
in a bowling alley?
No.
Uh,
no.
What's,
what happened?
The worst show I ever did.
I talk about it and incorrigible is
when,
uh,
well the worst kind of like show coming
up that I did was we're a lady rushed
the stage and it was because she was
heckling me and,
uh,
I said to her,
she had like this really like wild hair
that was like really up and out and I,
and I called her Blanca after she was
like,
you know,
three fighter.
Yeah,
of course.
I don't know if,
and she,
I was like,
I don't even know what she's going to
know what this means.
And I did.
And she knew what it meant.
She was very,
so she ran right up and grabbed the
microphone and hit my face,
like pushed it into my face and I was
like,
Oh God,
I gotta say of all of the insults that
would cause someone to attack you,
the street fighter reference pretty
special one.
It's a good one.
And it just kind of proved my point
because I'd be like,
I feel like that's kind of what Blanca
would've done.
Like Shit.
Yeah.
You some of those sparks.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like eating my,
what was that one where he ate the guy's
head.
Right.
Of course.
Hey,
whatever.
If he would've done that.
Yeah.
Well,
you,
we,
I realized we've been podcasting for
about the same really because you,
this is what episode is the [inaudible]
70 [inaudible] 71 71 I think I'm up to
74.
So yeah,
it's been like three weeks or three week
difference.
I'm curious,
how is podcasting like affected your
stand up in a way?
Kind of,
it's been really,
actually,
it's been really interesting because I,
you know,
I,
I started a podcast after I had a
following.
Right,
right.
And what would you guys did too?
And so,
um,
and uh,
and I did,
so I was like,
look,
I'm just going to do this and see how
long it lasts.
You know,
everyone's got a part.
I felt like,
you know,
I really found out through other
comedians that if you don't have a
podcast and you already have a fan base,
you're leaving money on the table.
So beyond that,
it's just a great way to connect.
But I didn't think of it that way until
I started doing it.
I was like,
you know,
I wanna,
I wanna make money more money and fuck
it,
you know?
And then,
uh,
and then I realized once I started doing
it,
how much,
like,
I mean,
in a much smaller way,
for me at least,
it's like,
you know,
it's like a TV,
like the TV show,
the when,
when people are watching a TV show and
they're like,
oh,
I've got to wait til next week to watch
the next TV,
which we,
a lot of people binge watch now,
but when I was a kid,
that's how people used to watch TV and
now people feel connected and they wait
for the,
you know,
they feel like they know me more and
they do because,
uh,
um,
I'm,
you know,
me or a version of me on that comedy,
the comedy podcasts.
Yeah.
Uh,
and um,
but yeah,
it really like,
makes them feel like they know you.
And that's kind of a double edge sword.
Sometimes you like it,
sometimes you don't,
but,
but um,
but it,
it,
it as,
as I might have my opener when he says
you guys listened to,
uh,
congratulations before it brings me up.
Um,
the chairs are just gotten bigger and
bigger,
bigger throughout the whole,
throughout the past year.
Yeah.
It's really crazy.
Your podcast is different than ours and
that you're just,
it's you and you're talking,
I mean,
how was that experience from going from
standup to just like talking into a
camera and nobody's there cause you do
shows you act a lot,
right?
But was that a different skill to learn
or did it kind of translate?
I,
you know what,
it's,
it's like standup in the way that like
stand up to me is a version of making.
Like when I'm at a diner with my
friends,
late night,
I'm sometimes like,
you know,
doing jokes,
we're,
I mean we're always joking around,
messing around,
but like sometimes I'm just fucking with
them and we're just making jokes and
we're doing bits or whatever.
I always felt like before I did stand
up,
I was like,
if I could get to be onstage and treat
the audience like they're the other
people in the diner,
then I'll be able to do,
I know I'll be able to do it because I,
I,
I literally would do that every day of
my life.
I,
I love,
I'm obsessed with truck trying to maybe
have a laugh and like trying to and
think of what w what do I think is
funny,
what's funny about this situation.
And so for podcasting it was the same
thing except that except like when I'm
in my house and I'm with my dogs,
like I'll catch myself just like talking
about things for no reason.
Like I'm a fucking insane person.
And then,
and then I'm like,
oh well maybe I'll say that on my end,
my end,
my show or my act or whatever.
But then when I started to do the
podcasts,
I was like,
oh,
this is just that.
This is just like me talking out loud in
my house.
And I kind of do that anyway.
I don't do it for a full hour,
like an insane person,
but like that's how I come up with
material.
I just start like talking to my house
and I think all that's funny.
This is material born from your podcast
ever.
Does it only start and the podcast and
then goes to the day it has for sure.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
Well,
it also helps me like creatively because
I don't like sit down and like right at
the computer,
my act,
so like,
um,
well,
yeah,
because when you do your act as it very
much rehearsed for me,
I'll go up with an idea that I have and
all.
When you do man on fire,
which is like,
yeah,
yeah.
Well that's,
that's the act that I've been kind of
honing.
Right.
Okay.
But you all,
but yeah.
But all of those bits came from and to
me going on stage thinking like,
oh,
it's funny when guys work out,
I'll go on stage and start talking about
it.
Wow.
That's a wild way to approach it.
To kind of just go up there and be like,
all right,
let's see what's happening.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think,
I think though,
like so much of it is about,
like,
that's what I say,
if I go back,
going back to like being in a diner with
my friends,
I'm so comfortable with them,
they're my friends.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
And I think through years and years of
practicing through thousands and
thousands of shows,
yeah.
I'm able to get into that headspace on
stage.
Do you know?
That's awesome.
So I,
and I love it.
I love doing it.
And it's,
you know,
there's an old saying like,
it's not what you say,
it's how you say it or,
uh,
and,
and uh,
you know,
I think it is if you're that confident.
And I mean,
like there's guys who,
my buddy Brian calendar,
it goes on stage.
He talks about horse shit for an hour
and it's hilarious.
Yeah.
And it's not true,
but he acts like it is,
and it's,
it's,
you know.
Yeah.
So it's,
those guys are the,
I mean,
you know,
guys like that.
It's about how you say it.
That's cool.
I think that's a cool way to,
to just hone the skill just to get up in
the fucking gauntlet and yeah.
And get it down.
And it's a onetime dude.
One time I was on a plane.
I shit you not mad if somebody told me
this.
I wouldn't have,
I wouldn't believe that,
but it happened to me on,
I know it happened to me.
And it's true because I know that
because I witnessed it.
This almost sounds like a lie.
Yeah,
I know.
You know what reaffirmed that part of it
is because I have to,
I have to convince myself it actually
how,
okay.
It's not nobody shit on the plane or
anything like that,
but it's like,
so I'm,
we're going to Montreal,
which is a big festival in Montreal just
for laughs.
I'm doing it again this year,
but I went and,
uh,
the,
they fly us up there and whenever you
fly up there,
since it's,
uh,
stand up festival,
it's comedy festival.
There's always like nine comedians on
your flight,
right?
She's sitting there with Sebastian
Thompson,
Gora,
Bill Burr,
whoever the fuck you and you see,
oh hey,
Chelsea handler.
Oh Hey.
You know,
so Adam Carolla sitting behind me.
I know,
I know Adam,
you know,
say hey,
he sits behind me and he doesn't know
there's another comedian behind me and I
meet him and Adam didn't know him.
So Adam Corolla is sitting next to this
other comedian.
This is the two seats and I'm in front
of them and the flight tomorrow from Las
Vegas,
six hours.
Okay.
And Adam Carolla,
I'm,
I'm telling you,
did not stop talking to that kid for
longer than no exaggeration,
30 seconds.
Now you are watching this with like more
of a curiosity.
In the beginning I was like,
and I know Adam and I love Adam and he's
great at those pockets all the time and
he's fucking hilarious.
And I was like,
what is this guy going to fucking take a
break?
Dude,
he,
he didn't,
he didn't take a break.
He didn't take away.
The other kid didn't talk.
It was just like,
yeah,
the whole thing.
And that first hour I was like,
man,
he's been talking for an hour and a half
ago.
And I was like,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna stay listening because I have
to.
I have to find out when he takes a
break.
Right.
I have to like see how long and he
didn't do land,
he landed and I was like this
motherfucker.
And was he talking to off the plane?
It kept going and he never stopped.
He never stopped the kid,
the new kid who,
who,
who was on the road,
I don't even know who that was.
Did you catch a glance in his eyes?
No.
No,
not while it was going on.
I mean maybe,
maybe I did.
I don't,
was anything interesting?
Yeah,
no,
every,
it was all interesting.
Adam Corolla is so good at that and he
was talking about stuff and I was like,
man,
this guys,
it's like he had thought about
everything already that ever happened.
And he's like,
if you say,
if the guy's like,
yeah,
cute tips.
It's like,
well,
you know,
thinking about,
the guy's just amazing at it.
So,
so when you're in that comfortable space
where you can just say it like Corolla
didn't even need that kid to be sitting
there.
And it was interesting if you just
talked for six hours,
I could be like,
all right,
I would listen to this.
He's a conduit of comedy.
It's always challenge them.
So you know,
and I'm not saying I'm as good as that,
but I,
I,
you know,
to get into that comfortable space to
where you can just talk,
which is what we do as comedians.
So I feel like it was a version of that
and I just had to work through a few
episodes and then I kind of,
I think figured it out after like the
third episode,
I was like,
oh I can do,
I really expected to do about three or
four episodes and then just chalk it up
as a,
as a loss.
But well guys,
check it out like 74 now.
So we'll keep going.
God bless.
I'm gonna listen.
So I want,
I know you've probably talked about this
so many times,
but we've talked about on the podcast
and Logan Paul hit me with that Echo.
Logan Paul.
All right.
We Ms.
Logan.
Paul got it.
Let me see.
We got that.
He's,
he's something we've talked about a lot.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I saw you got to sell and what you
talked about it and it's like,
I feel like that exchange really showed
what a fucking dumb ass he is.
Or maybe even just like how damaged he
is from the whole suicide forest.
Yeah.
I want to go over it with,
yeah.
Yeah.
If you don't mind,
I'm happy to,
yeah.
I want to go over this and I want to get
your thoughts on some of these twitter
exchanges.
Okay.
Well first of all,
I'm curious your initial interaction.
Yeah.
When he said it's important that you
want,
no,
it's not right now.
How did,
how did Logan Paul come on your radar to
begin with because you are following,
you are ready.
W did,
I don't know if I was fall.
I may have been following him,
but I think actually I just maybe saw it
because he's so,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
So I probably just responded to it.
Maybe I follow him,
I don't know.
But um,
uh,
so I just write no,
it wasn't because because of the suicide
forest and how everywhere that will,
that will,
yeah,
that was just bad.
But uh,
and so I just wrote no,
it wasn't because like this fucking shot
him dead body in the forest.
This is important.
My,
no,
it wasn't.
So yeah,
it's less I was trolling them and more
that I was just reacting off of that.
Right.
Yeah.
Um,
and I just thought I didn't think
anything of it.
I just,
yeah,
it's,
and then,
but when he responded,
and let me pull this up actually,
because this was like damn dog really
fucking tried to make this work.
The tsunami of fried laughing analogies.
Oh Shit.
Like what'd you think when you saw that
wave of yellow and blue?
I was really confused because I thought
it was a fake.
I was like,
this is not him.
But then I saw the check,
I was like,
okay.
So I guess that is,
and then I thought that's so many,
uh,
emojis so fucking amused.
Yeah.
Like that's laughing for a long time.
That's like,
it's not funny anymore.
That's like after the first two rows
it's getting a little sad.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
After two rows you're like,
oh shit man.
Maybe he's just mentally imbalanced
because that's why he thought it was
okay to shoot somebody.
Be like,
all right,
well at least that.
Um,
and then when he said,
and then I read it wrong,
I first read it,
I'm laughing because I know why your
comedy career took a dive and not,
not,
I didn't read.
I'm laughing cause now I know why you're
coming here.
So I thought she knew something I didn't
know.
And I was like,
does this guy,
what did I do that I don't know.
That's bad.
Right.
That's so much about me.
Like I'm like,
did I just something like my head is
like,
because it's such a stupid comment,
you almost want to believe that.
It's like,
oh my God,
does he actually know that there's
something else,
right?
Like,
yeah.
Like did he see me literally her first
response then?
No,
it's not.
What,
so not like deserving of anything more
than just,
yeah.
Or just like at fuck off or whatever the
fuck.
But personally like,
like that response also.
What is it in your response that you
know,
educated him till now,
what,
like why your comedy career took a dive?
Like there wasn't that much information
encoded in your initial response.
Right?
Yeah,
that's true.
Now I know.
Now I know because I wasn't really
trying to make a joke.
I was just like saying something that's,
I guess like in comedy,
like you'd say what he did was
fundamentally flawed.
Right.
But another thing that's fundamentally,
and I was listening to Bert Kreischer
talk about this too.
Uh,
and,
and this sounds defensive and this is
why I have not said this until now in my
comedy career has not taken a dive,
right?
Like every year it's been more and more
clearly a wounded child.
But what Bert was saying,
and he's right,
there needs to be some kind of truth in
your burn or roast or whatever you want
to it.
So
I was like,
oh,
oh.
And so I read all that and then I read
it correctly cause like I'm laughing
cause I knew why I now I know why you're
coming to her.
It's like,
oh yeah,
he's trying to act like I was trying to
make a joke and whatever.
Yeah.
So then I kind of,
I honestly went right to feeling badly,
right?
Because I was like,
oh well you kind of realize you're
dealing with the child really well,
he's 24 though.
Right?
But intellectually like how can you
write that and not have the intellect of
a much younger person?
That's true.
But even further than that,
here's,
here's the thing,
like if you're going to write to
somebody who I write to people,
oh dude,
this is fun for me.
Right?
I like to fucking clap back and shit
like that to me.
I'm bored.
And people are like,
what do you take it personally?
I don't,
it's just fun.
I like doing it.
My whole thing is if you say something
to me and you got your 14 followers and
you think nobody's gonna see it,
dude,
I can't wait.
I want to imagine the look on your face
when I read the heat.
Load it up,
dude.
You,
this is your game play.
I love that philosophy.
So fun.
People don't appreciate the shit that
you get when you're online.
Like,
oh Jesus Christ.
And I love the thought when you do that,
then again,
I'm mad at you.
Like you should have known better than
to put them on blast.
Yeah.
And it's like,
dude,
but this is like,
oh,
oh hey,
this is the internet.
Welcome to the fucking Internet.
When you sign up for twitter,
isn't that what,
what you dream happen that somebody who
gives you attention,
like that's why you're here.
It is.
You would just browse twitter.
You don't even need an account.
Yeah,
exactly.
So,
so then I kind of felt bad cause I was
like,
damn,
I'm going to,
I knew exactly what to say.
I was like,
Oh,
I'm going to say what I said.
Right.
It's cozy.
He basically say yo for a coat.
And I was like,
oh,
maybe I should,
maybe I should leave it alone.
But I,
I can't leave it alone because he kind
of took it to the next level.
Maybe if there was one row of class.
But then I was like,
all right,
fuck it.
I'm just going to do it.
I did it.
And I was like,
that's what you write.
Well here,
let's have a look.
At least in my career dies.
You can film it and put it on Youtube.
I love that.
When you quote tweet him,
you can't even see.
I actually thought maybe that's why he
did that.
I don't think.
No,
I don't think so either.
No Way.
You wouldn't see the response or tweeted
how fucking great.
Um,
that was such a slam dunk.
Yeah.
I mean,
and look at the likes and likes on that
one.
It's like everyone,
not everyone just started.
All right.
So he should have been like,
you know,
well played.
I'm going to go on a shoot day,
but now he should have known.
I was going to say something like that.
But,
but here's the other thing too,
like if you're,
you're doing to somebody who's going to
write back to you who does this for a
living.
Yeah.
Like,
it's not,
you're not doing it to Jerry Seinfeld.
There's going to be like,
who's that kid?
Oh,
pairs to do this.
I'm just going to come right back to you
and,
and this is what I do.
So like,
anyway,
I did that.
Let's see what's next?
And then he just kept going.
Not going to lie.
This single tweet is funnier than your
entire Netflix special,
which actually it has a lot of looking
back,
right?
Yeah.
Yes.
And that was the last is at least
tactically breaking this down.
If I were a Dork,
technically this is it.
This is,
uh,
this is,
you know,
it makes sense.
It's falling compared to that.
But he,
he admits he saw my entire Netflix
special.
He must not have hated it at that.
And in a way,
in a way,
it's really a sincere compliment because
he's like,
go your Netflix special enough to watch
the whole thing and this tweet was he?
Yeah.
I love everything you do.
Especially they came out 10 months ago.
That was great,
but now you're even,
you've topped yourself.
So I'm a huge fan.
I almost let it go because I was like,
because of that,
because I was like,
all right,
I'm a compliment,
but you can't.
I couldn't cause I thought of this and I
was like,
thanks.
How does it feel to have your name
finally attached to something you don't
understand?
Oh good.
Oh Man.
And I'm on my phone like,
Oh God,
this is fucking hilarious.
I can't wait and I'm having fun because
come on,
come on.
Eh.
And then so this is something that logan
and his peers do a lot.
They do the whole thing of like,
oh,
the 38 year old,
it's like dog,
I don't get that.
Oh,
well,
first of all,
I'm 38 I'm not,
I'm not 60 yeah,
but,
but that aside,
I don't understand the whole,
your old,
you don't get it thing because everyone
gets to be old.
I,
that's my favorite image is that logan
is not that young.
At the same time,
you've got to hit in behind.
This guy's like,
I'm just a kid for so long.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's like doc,
I'm 38.
Yeah,
it was a kid.
But the thing is I love to imagine Logan
Paul at 38 and he is going to be
completely without hair.
He is going to,
it's going to be a beautiful thing.
I want to check in when he's 38 then
it'd be like talk,
you can't talk to anybody anymore cause
you're a 38 year old man.
Yeah.
Remember what you said.
The thing I know I have it on my
calendar like 12 years.
I don't know that,
that's not a very good argument.
Uh,
cause who fucking cares but also by its
merit,
there's nothing really insulting about
it.
It just shows how immature he is.
It's like you're 38 I should,
I don't,
what do I care about?
Anything you think also imagine,
imagine referring to yourself as is
shunned it really kind of a rock bottom
thing.
Like,
like that's how he sees himself is kind
of almost like a,
oh imagine being like,
yeah,
cause you know,
cause like I'm a,
I'm a shank.
That's like you're who I want to be a
team.
Hey who are we fighting against?
Because we're both on the same team
here.
Your we're,
we're both fighting you.
Yeah.
It's like you can see the meeting with
the Spiderman in the spiderman where
they're looking at each other.
That's what the fuck he's doing right
now.
Well,
it's funny you didn't say shun flogger
introduced.
That also is like blaming you for our
hearing with him over at twitter when he
was the one to make it into this whole
thing.
Has this been broken down?
This many layers?
I haven't done it yet.
So funny that he used like an like,
I dunno,
I dunno what's worse.
He's just shit.
A Schengen blog or being the 38 oldest
fuck.
You're like basically over Canadian
arguing with and the insinuation,
the,
the crux of this is that anybody who
interacts with the shun vlogger.
Yeah,
no,
he's like,
you're arguing with the shunt blogger
over twitter who are on twitter.
Yeah.
Who does that?
He's so self deprivation that prep
Kayden in the worst way.
Let's keep going.
Right?
Yeah.
Ask Your fans to have their moms read
out loud to them.
See what they think.
I didn't want to make fun of how
youngest fans were,
but I felt like that because they
brought up the age too.
It was coming of age.
It really,
and I bought it.
I was like,
this is a good enough to me.
this is funny enough to bring that up.
I just didn't want to be like stupid.
You know?
They're just young.
No.
And,
and the truth is,
if you ever do look up like fan meetup
photos,
like yeah,
it's pretty shocking.
Yeah.
Can you guys look a pregnant lady?
You'd be like,
Oh,
you're a fan.
No,
my baby and definitely button.
Then it doesn't stop.
No,
but here's the thing.
He,
I think,
and this may not be right,
but I think he wanted to have the last
word,
but he didn't want me to see it.
So then I was even old people roasting
me.
So I was like,
I think I actually responded to this.
I'm not sure.
Well I'm,
I'm not sure what the,
the significance of the greater than
symbol is in this situation.
You know,
old people greater than greatest thing
on planet earth and I don't understand
the significance a,
I'll try that.
Well,
at any rate,
I love that.
He,
that's such a good observation.
That's definitely what happened.
Yeah,
I think so.
Yeah.
And you know,
he had like his whole think tank.
Well cause he rolls with a possum.
Hello Gang.
Like to think that um,
but when they were all side the suicide
forest,
but they only come up with those insults
because my friend,
they're all the best gang.
Yeah.
I had other ones too that were so
brutal,
but I just,
do you remember any?
No,
I don't.
I,
I took a,
I was,
I had brutal one.
I was going to go,
like,
I didn't bring anybody else but him into
it.
I was going,
I could have,
you know what I mean?
But I was just like,
Nah,
I can't do that.
Well,
you did it tastefully.
How about this?
You're my son.
Tag Your fucking Daddy.
I'm your fucking dad.
This this way.
I was like,
at least I'm now I'm getting silly or
I'm like,
all right.
You know what I mean?
Like I just want to do it in my head.
Like maybe this kid,
I don't know him.
Maybe he's,
maybe he's literally like,
Oh man,
I'm having fun.
Making fun of the comedian.
No,
no,
no.
I don't know.
In a way it's almost like the suicide
forest all over again.
But you're the one filming the dead body
and it does it continue?
Oh yeah.
Logan go,
oh I forgot about this whole exchange is
really,
really similar to your life.
As time passes,
your jokes get less and less funny.
Sorry Dad.
Yeah,
that's that one actually.
And the likes are,
are,
are getting,
but also as time passes,
jokes do get less and less funny cause
because you just by the nature of it,
as,
as time passes,
memories become less depressed.
As you get older,
you're 38 to,
you don't remember anything probably.
Uh,
and I don't know.
I think there might have been in it that
are just so legendary.
Yeah.
This is one of the best things.
Let me tell you something,
man.
Thanks.
But I,
first of all,
thank you.
Second of all,
I walked around,
I walked around and people were like,
it was like I did the fucking tonight
show in 1987.
People were like that.
It speaks to how much and how much they,
how much they cared about that thing you
did in the suicide for us.
Like I get,
I listen.
You know,
I get that.
What I said was,
you know,
somewhat funny,
but that,
that isn't why it got so many retweets.
It got so many retweets because they
felt emotional about the stuff that he
did.
Cause it was a beautiful,
perfect storm.
Sadly for new media is usually and
mainstream media only when something
awful happens and Logan that suicide
force and was just so fucking,
yeah,
I mean this was a beautiful,
this was just a perfect battle between
good and evil.
It played out on twitter and this new
age and I,
and something occurred to me as I read
the his fine,
I'll tweet them and did this whole,
uh,
this whole suicide forest part too.
This was the one,
this was the brain trust final act.
This was what they all thought about and
we're like,
that's the one.
Oh right Chris,
this whole exchange really something
cause he's had a set,
he dramatically,
you know,
space it out.
This was,
this,
was it this,
this was their joke.
This was the coup de Gras.
Well,
did they get,
yeah,
sorry.
Yeah,
I forgot about it.
Hey,
the jokes.
You're just all right.
We are going to take a short break.
We'll be right back with the great and
hilarious Chris Delea.
If you go anywhere,
well I guess that's your prerogative,
but I urge you to stay.
See you soon.
Thank you.
To Express Vpn for sponsoring this
episode.
Guys,
if you are not using a vpn and this day
and age,
you're literally insane.
You've got facebook,
you've got twitter,
you've got Google,
you've got all these tech giants peaking
up your skirt,
skirt.
You've,
yes,
they're seeing the goods and they're not
paying for it.
You've got the,
you've got your own ISP,
right?
They know everything you're doing.
The VPN hide your activity and keeps you
anonymous and let's be frank,
the weird shit that you're doing on the
internet,
if that ever came out,
your life would be ruined and it just
takes one rogue guy with a vpn to be
like,
oh,
look what Ethan's been up to when it be
shipped through.
Exactly.
I don't want you to know and I don't
ever want you to know,
and that's the power of the vpn at Max.
All your activity.
It could you anonymous as the Internet
should be,
that keeps you safe and it keeps all
these other boys from picking up your
skirt without buying you dinner,
pound it.
Here's another thing.
If you're in a public space and you're
not using a vpn,
you are literally getting hacked by
everybody there.
You go into a starbucks,
there's 50 people there,
you know there's at least one guy
stealing people's credit card
information and bank statements and all
of your private information.
Without a VPN,
you are subject to people literally
stealing your data and public spaces.
If you're not using a vpn and today's
age,
you are literally nuts.
The best one is expressed vpn.
It's fast.
It's the world's leader in security.
They keep your activity private and
anonymous.
They are great for streaming with their
blazing,
blazing fast speeds and it costs less
than seven bucks a month.
Give me a fricking break.
I'd say that's a great price to pay for
a little on amenity.
That's what the Internet is all about,
so every time you use it in and out
without express Vpn,
you are putting sensitive data at risk.
Take your Internet privacy back right
now and find out how you can get three
months free.
Go to xpress vpn.com/h
street.
That's e x p r e s s vpn.com/h
hd for three months free with a one year
package fidget.
Visit Express vpn.com/age
three to learn more.
This is so important,
you guys don't let it get out about the
Hentai you've been watching.
Thank you,
honey.
If you are not using honey,
then you are literally burning money,
right Ila.
It's true.
Honey is as good as it sounds,
sweet as honey.
It's the honeypot.
Folks.
Just put your hand in and get some of
that sweet honey.
Honey is an app you went to solid.
It's two clicks on the browser you're
using.
You shopped the web like you usually do.
What this does is it checks for coupons
you ever,
you have neurotic like we are and you
just,
you're like,
oh,
I'm buying shoes.
Let me just see if this store has
coupons on there because sometimes you
find the qb gets 50% off.
Honey does that for you while you shop.
Not only do they save you money,
they save you life.
If you're like me because I'm neurotic
to the point,
I'll spend 30 minutes looking for a
coupon.
You know what I mean?
And then I'll go,
it's like,
man,
I saved 20 bucks and I spent 30 minutes
on my life.
I'm not sure it was worth it.
Honey saves you both automatically with
two fricking clicks.
Look here,
I was shopping for shoes.
Swear to God.
Got a couple pairs.
Honey pops in at the checkout and it's
like,
I found coupons.
Click here to apply it.
Boom,
look at this $53 save without even
thinking about it.
I was skeptical at first of honey.
I was like,
oh,
what's the deal with this?
It fricking works and I love it and I
wouldn't browse without it anymore.
Also does shit like on Amazon,
it compares previous prices and sellers
like the best price.
Yeah.
It tells you if this is like the best
price it's ever been.
If you should stick around,
if you should hold it or if you should
slam,
and that's the honeypot.
Folks.
When hunter has got your back,
you will never overpay for anything on
Amazon ever again.
They're going to save you money.
You're going to be praising to the Lord
Jesus.
Honey,
how could I ever done it without you?
It's two clicks.
It's free.
There's no reason not to add,
honey.
Get the sweetness.
Get it in your mouth.
You're going to get the honey.
You're going to be like,
oh my God,
it's a little sticky.
It's a little wild,
but it tastes so f and good and it's
free.
You're basically going to be winning the
fricking pool after you plug this baby
in,
so go add it right fricking.
Now join honey.com/h
three that's join honey.com/age
three it's free.
It takes two clicks.
You have nothing to lose.
Give it a shot or my name isn't Pooh
bear.
Pretty cut that part down.
We are back with Chris Delea.
What's the fucking thing
with Lacroix?
I right?
Yeah,
I,
yeah,
and I know,
I know the day that I learned about
Lacroix and I,
and it's weird that I'm telling you this
now because you brought this up,
he,
so you guys brought up that you didn't
know that you didn't realize
I was on an episode of workaholics and
before I kind of had telfer a fan that
go right.
Yeah.
Great workaholics episode ever sing the
praises.
It was our favorite episode and out APP.
Wow.
Thanks.
That's so it's,
and that,
that's,
that's the long thanks.
Anyway,
at any rate,
it was the first season of the,
of the show and uh,
while I was shooting that as tofor,
that was when I learned,
uh,
when you had your first check was like,
man,
Lacroix is fucking awesome boy.
Shit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I was like,
what is it?
Shit.
And I was like,
just fucking soda is really good.
It is better than,
here's what I,
here's my thing about Lacroix.
They,
and this is not an ad.
No,
this is not an addict,
but everybody fucking knows what Lacroix
is.
It's like Google.
It's just like,
it's the Google of nodal advertising,
but everyone knows,
hey fuck it is,
why is it that people act as if Lacroix
invented soda water?
You could buy soda water.
Yes.
That little flavor.
Always.
When I was,
when I came out of everything that they
offered you a sip of Cherry flavored
soda.
Whoa.
What it is.
Cause it's,
what is it like French and it's got a
French name,
but I heard that Americans are like,
Ooh,
I'm a Dan.
Tom Tell us that.
It's not just saying it's a girl like
the crew or some bullshit.
I don't know.
And he was getting upset because it was
like,
you guys are the guys who we named it.
He was saying they want it to be called
like Lacroix,
like the French way.
But he's like,
but you guys are not French.
So it's like,
oh fuck is a this,
I don't know.
Yeah.
It surprised me.
I was like,
Oh shit,
you just to speak French.
He's like,
no,
but I'm,
I know all about drinks.
I think what they did is like,
it's an American brand.
Kids were not drinking soda.
Water was the beverage of,
of all of your dad.
I always hated it.
Yeah,
me too.
Me Too.
And I think it was a perfect timing of
people being like,
maybe I don't want to drink 50 grams of
sugar,
but I want something more exciting than
water from the garbers.
Yeah.
Before I was born,
this can't believe this isn't an ad,
but especially,
well,
let me just say to you,
pull this out.
It's fucking soda water.
You can buy a 99 cent Ralph Brute
Brands,
soda water through the same shit.
Not the same.
But here's the thing.
I don't,
I drink sparkling water.
Um,
I don't like it as bright as,
um,
I don't like it as much as club soda.
I like clubs,
sort of better soda.
Oh,
I didn't know there was a distinction.
I'm holding it like this.
Like,
okay,
they need to pay me now I'm going to put
it down.
Club soda has,
has larger bubble.
It feels like it.
Like,
like whenever,
like I'm in a restaurant,
I'm like,
Can I get club soda?
And they're like,
you want Pellegrino?
I'm like,
no.
Do you have it from the gun that I
fucking better.
Yeah,
exactly.
So did I fucking stutter?
I've heard,
you know,
I've,
I've hung out with friends who are like,
Ooh,
I know the difference between,
yeah,
I prefer Pellegrino because it has
tighter bubbles.
Oh yeah,
it does.
Huh?
For the carbonation is less intense.
Yes.
Is that the difference?
It's like fine.
And the club is like,
if you chug it,
you'll fuck your throat up thing.
That's why I love that shit.
A little burn.
I love it.
Nice.
Because when I got,
when I cut out soda,
I was like 31 and my mom,
I did,
uh,
I was actually doing some kind of a joke
with my family and I lifted my shirt up
as it afforded the joke and my mom was
like,
you gained some weight?
And I was like,
no.
I thought I had been one 75 my whole
life.
And uh,
once 75.
Yeah,
you're tall guy.
That's pretty well,
but this was when I was 31.
And so I was like,
no.
She's like,
I have a scale up there.
Why don't you weigh yourself.
And I was one 95 and I almost passed out
and I was like,
Oh my God,
I'm 20 pounds heavier.
I didn't check but this long.
And uh,
but I'm tall.
So like it had been down,
you know,
and uh,
and I stopped drinking soda.
I started drinking diet at first.
I,
and I fucking hate diet soda.
All of you get used to it.
I like it now.
I never got used to tell him.
I was like,
dude,
this is,
I,
it's,
it tastes horrible to be,
at first it tastes like,
you know,
poison really.
[inaudible] it is.
Yeah.
When I'm presented with the choice of do
I want the original or do I want the,
basically it's do I want to be fat or
don't want to die of cancer or diabetes
or cancer.
It's literally the what you're choosing.
And so,
so I,
I,
he's great.
I was like,
diabetes never tasted so good.
at least I'll look good.
Hold life even though it will be
shorter.
And,
and that is basically,
if I'm ever run for mayor,
that's what I'm going to use as my
platform.
Do you know what I mean?
Like live a shorter life,
but look good the whole time.
And as Mary you're plugging in diet
beverages if they pay me.
And so,
um,
so I,
I,
I stopped drinking diets.
I was like a fuck this diet.
This sucks too.
Right?
And so,
and then I would watch like the
documentary is about how I was like,
you're dying.
You take your diet and selfish because
your family will cry.
And uh,
and so I started,
I was like,
fuck this.
And I started drinking just water and I
was like,
I can't just drink.
Fuck.
What am I [inaudible] here we're human
beings.
We crave.
Yeah.
This is why we're on this earth.
We invented things better than water.
Come on,
dude.
That's like saying I'm not gonna live in
a house.
I'm just going to go camping.
I'm going to live in a fucking cave.
That's all I had to get the fuck outta
here.
We made walls,
we've got toasters,
the microwaves.
Let's do all of those motherfuckers.
So now,
so now I'm like,
all right,
I'm not going to just drink water.
And then I was like,
let's see what this fucking lacroixs up.
Right.
See what's up.
And I did it and it was the PR.
I waited enough time to where I didn't
have the soda and I was like,
oh,
this has the bubbles.
But also it's not just water,
little flavor,
a little flavor if you want that flavor
to,
by the way,
what?
What's the flavor that I drink?
Where does it come from?
I don't know.
Is that Sweden?
Yeah.
I don't know what I mean.
But I also drink the regular blue
lacroix.
I'll just drink regular soda water.
Just straight up the water that's safe
because we know what the bubble,
but like feel like taste.
They're like,
eh.
I mean,
think about how,
this is kind of weird,
right?
They're like,
here's a mango flavored soda water.
Yeah,
there's just no mango.
And you look at the fucking things in
zero.
Oh Romaine will.
But if you eat a mango,
it's not zero across silos where they'll
know it's bullshit.
I'm just saying maybe just,
I'm glad this isn't an ad cause you're
bullshit for doing there.
I was from Wisconsin.
From Wisconsin.
Yeah.
You can't trust people from Wisconsin.
Little Croydon.
The may well be getting millions people
cancer.
True.
We wouldn't know now.
It just came up 10 fucking years lying
down in 10 years.
It'll be like,
yeah.
It turns out that Luke Roy is the new
smoking in,
in,
in 30 years.
I'm going to be like on a hospital bed
just like I shouldn't have drank all
that look cry.
I should've stuck with Ivan coke cans.
Sugar was organic.
Damn it.
We understood what it was.
At least now that can take the cancer
out.
They can take the sugar cancer out.
That can't take the Lacrosse.
We haven't gotten there.
He's not fast enough.
Um,
well guys,
if your drink lacroix responsibility and
be aware of that,
you know,
you could be cost.
It could cost a new disease that we
didn't even have yet.
That's the thing about disease.
It's just going to keep it,
we're going to figure stuff out and then
not,
not align.
Poppy common.
I'm also going to run for mayor at that
path guide.
A killer platform.
Literally.
Yeah.
Literally you're all going to die.
You might as well have me be your
maximum.
So on twitter,
well clearly,
you know you got into it with Logan,
but you're very,
you have a good time on twitter.
Let's say you have a trend where you,
if people talk some smack,
yeah.
You'll retweet them and blast into the
world.
Yeah.
But I'm curious,
does twitter comments ever like actually
get to you?
Because sometimes you know,
and my case,
yeah.
Sometimes you know it's a,
it's a lot.
Yeah.
Like do they ever make me feel bad?
Like it's about a performance or a stand
up or whatever.
Like Hey,
I don't,
I didn't like what you did if more than
if it's a genuine thing and not just
like,
oh,
you know,
you select a piece of shit or whatever.
But if it's like,
I don't know though.
I mean,
maybe I can't say it never affects me,
but like,
you know,
a person,
but like I just,
I kinda,
the Internet is just like,
you have to adopt the fact that it's
just Narnia and it doesn't exist or
you're going to go fucking crazy.
Yeah.
You know?
Um,
and my brother also told me someone,
I was a kid when I was coming up when I
was growing up and he's younger than me,
but,
uh,
we,
we were talking about girls and I was
talking about how I,
I,
I hated when a girl didn't like me and I
liked her,
like,
and I was like,
why does that bother me so much?
Not Fair.
Yeah.
It sucks.
I want,
I like to rejection,
you know?
And my brother said,
well,
what do you think everybody's going to
like you?
And I know that so,
so simple.
But that time,
for some reason it clicked like that,
that isn't possible.
So I was like,
Eh,
and it made it a lot easier.
So now I'm telling you that was like a
switch.
And I know it's so simple and I'm not an
idiot.
I didn't do that already.
Yeah.
Just like it was like a perfect time.
Perfect way that he said it and it was
just like,
yeah,
I guess fuck it.
You know,
plus stand up when you're onstage
telling 400 people that joke and it
bombs,
right.
You tend to learn to not care about.
Is that the worst thing bombing on stage
to this day?
Are you,
does that happen still when you're
laying on it?
Once you have any sort of fan base,
it's,
it becomes tougher to bomb because
people just going to be a generous,
more generous and they give you the
benefit of the doubt.
I always say this though.
Um,
you're not truly bombing.
A comedian doesn't truly bomb on unless
the comedian feels bad about bombing
because if you're on stage,
it's all about the state of mind.
If I'm bombing,
like if,
if people aren't laughing and I'm like,
I fucking fuck you guys.
It doesn't matter.
This is funny.
You don't feel bad for the guy.
You're like,
oh,
he's just having an off night.
But if I'm on stage,
I'm bombing and he freaking all African.
I'm just like,
all right,
well,
uh,
anyway,
yeah.
Then you're like,
oh,
this guy.
Right.
So being on the stage is so much about
that confidence,
which I,
I do,
I don't know if we've talked about this
on air off air,
but we were talking about it before,
uh,
maybe 20 minutes ago.
But yeah.
Um,
yeah,
it's about,
it's how you say it is it,
but it's still tough though sometimes
if,
uh,
like if I get heck,
I get heckled a bunch and if,
if I get heckled and,
and I dig a hole because I'm like
telling some guy off and then I tried to
get back into it.
It's tougher and snap back.
It happened the other night actually.
Um,
what'd he say?
No,
you know what I get sometimes I hate
this Wu's like woo,
like mid Joe.
Yeah.
Like Woo.
Like you're not at the fucking mets
game,
like laughing,
don't laugh.
But if I'm like,
if I'm like,
hey,
so I was at verizon and someone's like,
Woo,
like you don't fucking,
or like I've mentioned the other night,
I was like,
yeah,
I said something about El Paso and
somebody was like,
Woo El Paso.
And I'm like,
I'm not being a guy who does that.
I imagine being a guy who is like,
oh dude,
that guy just said where I'm from.
And then having to be like,
oh fuck yeah,
that's,
imagine being a guy who does that.
And for real lots of guys do that.
That's fucking,
to me,
that's,
I'd rather be a guy who like thought my
own shit was his meal at least then I
don't fit in and know that around.
It's like,
oh that guy.
But to be one of those Douche bag guys,
that's like,
he said,
fucking Austin,
Woo,
you suck.
And you're also in this society.
I wonder if he thinks he's helping you.
He's just like they do.
Yeah,
they 100% though.
Cause then I roast them and then they're
like mid to show better.
Right.
No Man,
I'm hilarious.
Thank God I fucking just fixed it so
everyone's going to be worn at your
show,
dude.
I hate,
but it's like,
it's like,
it's like going to the fucking,
it's like going to Ikea and,
and,
and uh,
that,
that guy fucking up the show and be
fixing it and thinking that he did it is
like,
it's like going to Ikea and walking in
with the furniture and then breaking it
and going and then being like,
it broke.
You're like,
all right,
well you broke it.
You fucked it up.
I've heard you go on rants like this.
Similar.
I heard you ranting recently about uh,
listening parties.
Yeah,
dude,
I heard you're going on about what is a
new thing?
This wasn't a thing like a couple of
years ago.
All of a sudden,
this is how lost we are,
man.
Dude.
Okay,
so you made a,
you made an album.
We can hear it anywhere.
Do you know that?
You know that?
Okay,
so why are we a flying to Wyoming if
you're not going to be doing it live?
We're just going to be around a fire and
Kitkat he's going to be there.
Eat My dick.
There's no fucking way.
There's no fucking,
what makes you so angry that I'm
intrigued,
dude,
there's no way cause you weren't
invited.
Now that somebody said that on twitter
and I was like,
Bro,
you don't know me.
If Kanye West fucking knock on my door
and said,
hey man,
you want to come to my listening party,
I go like this.
Hey Man,
no,
I will wait for this fucking spotify
thing to drop.
What is it that listening to music with
a bunch of people in a room,
it makes you go so fucking nuts because
you know why?
Because,
because,
because here's why.
Because 80 and that's a fucking small.
It might be more,
80% of the people are just there because
it's a thing that's not because they
really want to hear them.
Because if you just really wanted to
hear the album,
you'd just hear the fucking album,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
You wouldn't cop a flight to Wyoming.
All right,
so,
so that's really what it is.
And that's w.
W w I have this thing on my podcast
where I talk about that's what a fucking
Kuta
is,
man.
And a Kuta is short for Barracuda and
Barracuda is if,
if you're wearing jewelry and you and
you fish and to get a barracuda and you
pull it Barracuda,
the Barracuda will attack you because it
sees jewelry and it's just like high
jewelry.
Got To have it.
That's what,
that's what you are.
If you're going to Coachella,
that's what you're doing.
Cause you're like,
oh,
it's a thing.
Let's go do what you want.
I have never been to either coachella or
they're listening so it's just fine.
But last night I felt that,
oh my God,
no,
every,
everybody has a little bit of Kuta in
them.
Right?
You got to hear about our last night.
You need a little,
you need a little little lacroix and
your life.
You get out,
you need a simple look,
you have to do.
And I get it and,
and to me,
my life is all about fighting that as
best I can right now.
That's a valeant.
That's a valeant work.
Dude.
I have a code man.
Do you know,
let me ask you this,
but what about your,
about your shoes?
What about my shoes?
They're not the belly.
Fuck do cheer was I?
No,
I got the,
I was,
I want to know is,
do you think that's a little,
because it's the funniest,
well wait,
those are cognacs.
Yeah.
So you won't go to his listening party
feel where his fucking,
cause if we can go anywhere that ship
from right here,
I got them on stock X.
I love shoes.
I might,
I'm might in it and that way you can
say,
but I buy,
I buy the shoes that I really genuinely
like.
And are those coffee?
You're very,
yeah.
Connie white shoes are fucking,
you know,
our,
our intern has fake yeezys on,
he's in deep.
You've got the whole,
you know the onion night from game of
thrones.
You Watch that show?
No,
I watched like three seasons and the
smuggler,
he knows all the like back channels.
Yeah.
He could open a fake easy store.
That's the guy.
Uh,
and he should,
the guy who has the brothel,
no,
not him.
The onion night.
He's the modeler.
I Dunno.
Yeah,
I saw the whole thing.
Anyway.
I saw a guy at the gym the other day
that had on this was hilarious.
He had on fake yeezys you could tell.
Well the reason that on the side it
literally said Kanye.
I was like,
dude,
special edition or what not even how it,
this is not even what they look like.
You know,
you can go on Amazon cause I was just so
intrigued because,
well apparently what?
It's hooked up.
I'm sorry,
Ian's probably feeling so bad cause he's
in so deep,
but I,
I'm just so intrigued.
Yeah.
Oh Man.
Poor man dude.
Why I out of them?
I'm still intrigued because he finds
like there's hookups.
Yeah.
So in China you've got the people that
make the,
the real yeezys and those same mother
fuckers,
what the fuck would a little tiny
difference.
So they don't get sued and then they
sell them to people like on the Silk
Road.
Right.
So there's in betweens and they sell to
America and they're not
that cheap.
You get those for like 100 bucks.
Like,
how much can I ask?
How many of those shoes you're going to
get?
Well,
it depends on what the market is like
what are those run?
Yeah.
So these,
okay,
so here's the interesting about it sells
out,
right?
And then you're getting my name out.
They were like,
I dunno,
200 or something reasonable.
Sure.
And when they came out,
they shut up and I want it to get them,
but they were like 700 bucks and I was
like,
I'm not the ham.
They went up to a thousand and I was
like,
I got to get them going.
So I paid for them.
I paid for him a thousand or a thousand
dollars.
That's the most,
by the way,
I've ever paid for shoes.
And then the next like month they
rereleased nother,
like 400 bucks.
But that's the game though,
man.
I did the same.
Kind of did the same thing with the
supreme bag.
Oh,
you were in a supreme,
well we feel we have a street clothing
brand and supreme as much of a meme as
they are and how ridiculous has gotten,
yeah,
it does make awesome shit.
Yeah.
No,
that's kind of the shame of it is that
it's gotten it.
Same with Gucci.
Like I love Gucci and everything they
do,
but it's like Logan Paul for example,
is always wearing Gucci.
If I was new to you,
I would prohibit sale people like him,
but we can't.
Right?
Like how are you going to stop that?
That's funny.
I dude,
death threats,
right.
Investigators of jared,
let them get it,
get this stuff and said now he's got to
burn the shoes.
I'm sorry.
And I'm going to,
you know what I should buy in a pair of
you.
How much?
1,000.
Some of them you get for like,
they've got the new moon,
uh,
color yellow.
What does it fucking,
I dunno.
They're,
they're cool and they're comfy.
That's the codeine you,
it depends.
Cause here's the thing,
I will say it.
Mosaic Kuta did the code,
the code.
So it is,
it is to just go get the shoes because
they're popular.
There is a little bit of that in me
because I can,
I know that because when I see a shoe,
I think,
oh,
that's ugly.
But then it grows on me if I see it
enough and that's for sure.
Kuta um,
but it is a cool show.
I think so,
but thanks.
Yeah.
A lot of people,
a lot of people hate these and now,
yeah,
it's been a whole thing this year,
but I like him.
I think it's fun.
I think it's almost like a parody,
but yeah.
The Dad shoot yet at what point does
$1,000
shoe stopped becoming a parody jokes on
him.
Whoever buys them,
I guess.
I mean I just dropped 200 on these,
these oh yeah,
the adidas.
Yeah.
Those are cool.
Can you get a close up?
You get a close up Dan.
Really cool with the shorts and socks.
Thanks.
Six eggs.
I am somewhat of a fashion icon.
Um,
psychopath.
Yeah.
What's going on there?
That's a show you're working on for
Youtube.
That's,
that's tough to talk about.
I don't know where.
No problem.
Yeah.
But uh,
um,
here's something I'm super excited to
talk about.
I heard you mentioned I was watching
your hot ones.
Okay.
And I heard you mentioned Chris Gaines.
Yeah.
And garth brooks is like one of my
favorite fucking people in the world
because he's such a goofy guy.
He's like both a superstar and also like
a cringe Lord.
Yes.
Um,
well yeah.
Did you see the fucking when you joined
facebook?
That's what I want to watch.
I've had his facebook,
his inaugural facebook video on my
refrigerator for so long.
I think it's the best fucking video
ever.
I want to watch me.
I haven't seen a lot.
I,
this video has been on,
I have like a whole list of like great
content.
I want to talk about.
That one's been on there for a decade,
that's top notch that,
that when that came out and I watched
that my top lip didn't touch my bottom
lip and you know,
he's rehearsed it like 30 times the way
I want it to be.
Like I literally started thinking,
when is my tablet live?
We're going to touch my bottom lip
again.
Right?
Like that's her walked around all day,
just jog and people knew I'm walking all
day like I was like,
you bet.
Yeah.
Well that was kind of a loose official.
Was that each book?
Was it Chris Gaines or was it garth
brooks and that video and Keith,
who knows?
I thought it was garth brooks.
But you raise a good point.
Let me show you.
First of all,
let me just give you guys the premise
here.
Garth Brooks,
you guys all know Garth Brooks.
That's Garth Brooks.
Maybe give a short sprint of people that
don't know carf books.
He's a country singer.
He's like the most fun.
He's like one of the biggest artists.
Do you listen to country music?
Uh,
no I don't at all apps.
Does it trip you out?
Cause it does trip me out.
Country music is the most popular genre
of music and America.
And that just sounds like,
whoa.
Most of us are idiots,
right?
Yeah.
Country Music is,
is,
and I'm not saying it's not for smart
people as well,
but it's the easiest music to listen to.
If you're a dummy,
do you know what I mean?
Like it's the easiest music to get.
I'm not saying that it doesn't have its
smart songs.
Maybe it does,
but like you can understand why a dumb
motherfucker listens to it.
Well,
it was a transformative moment for me
when,
uh,
yeah,
all the country fans out there,
the both pockets.
I don't wear a cowboy hat.
Also.
Don't ever have a goatee,
dude.
If you're go the whole way bro,
go the whole way.
Well,
he almost,
he looks like the human body.
Men of King of the hill.
I mean,
yeah,
that's who we're dealing.
And then Chris Angel,
right?
So I just looked it up.
Uh,
he's the number two bestselling artists
of all time,
only behind the Beatles.
Oh my God.
This world is,
there's 300 million people in the
country.
Okay.
5 million live in La.
I had never in my whole life heard
almost even a single country song.
And then when I realized when I'm 18
that it's the most popular,
that garth brooks is the best selling
artists ever after the fucking Beatles
over Michael Jackson.
Uh,
number three is a elvis.
I had,
I had this real like almost
transformative like moment where I was
like,
oh my God.
Like there's a whole nother world out
there.
You just feel it.
Also really big in Canada.
A country music.
Really?
Yup.
Twisted.
I knew it all along,
but now I've got evidence.
Yeah,
Dude.
Um,
so,
uh,
it's a country music is,
yeah.
Come on dude.
Well this guy's a fucking goofball.
So this is number two.
Okay.
This guy sold this shit to the whole
damn country.
People are getting so angry right now.
All of these girls books fans,
but I haven't,
nobody's real,
nobody is listening to the show.
The since the Garth Brooks,
somehow the world is that segmented.
Oh,
it definitely.
So,
so he carves brooks,
who's known for his country music makes
this alter ego.
Chris Gaines.
Hey,
don't even have your first ego.
Yeah,
right,
right.
It makes the first one better.
Right?
That's more work on Garth Brooks.
Well,
I mean,
listen,
he's number two true.
I mean he's number fucking fuck do I
know we just,
we need to acknowledge is in the tea
sold more.
Jump out the fucking window Jackie.
Jack liked it then it would be number.
Yeah,
true.
The Beatles would be like,
who the fucking who?
The WHO also very bad.
I don't know.
I'm,
I don't,
you can say shit about the Beatles if it
can be,
what are they singing about?
You know,
I heard,
I know it was,
it was not.
Let's not,
let's not do what Garth Brooks and
Beatles.
I don't want to sound like the Beatles
are just your favorite band.
Mr fucking listening party.
You know what?
I don't,
I'm not really big on music really.
My favorite is to parked.
That's it.
That's as far as it goes.
I like a baggy.
Will.
What do you like Peggy?
I like to park.
Oh,
so you still holding onto the garage?
Yeah,
I like to park.
No,
I don't know.
Yeah,
I don't,
I like to park.
People say Tupac or Biggie.
It's like what did I like them both.
You can like them both.
I like to,
and Biggie was,
I mean,
he was a great rapper.
He was a great,
you know,
he,
his float was fucking amazing.
But come on until you stopped listening
to music in the 90 minutes.
Like,
because here's the other thing,
biggie rapped about his,
there were stories.
They weren't how he was very much.
The story wasn't,
it wasn't,
it wasn't necessarily about his life.
Sure.
To parks shit was about his life and
that shit.
I thought it was awesome.
Well,
I am a huge Tupac Fan.
Oh,
I'm not going to discount Tupac.
I mean,
he's,
he's got all the hits and much like
Garth Brooks,
they have
a lot in common.
Yeah,
that's correct.
They have a lot.
It really just,
when I say Tupac,
the first thing that comes to mind is
king of the hill over here.
I don't know.
Uh,
but yeah,
that facebook thing,
when it happened,
I can't,
I don't know if I put up a video making
fun of it.
Really.
No,
I sent it.
You don't listen to music.
I kind of got to go back to that.
I mean,
that's trying to strain.
Yeah.
I'm not ever listen to music.
I mean,
I listen to hip hop,
but who's your favorite artists these
days?
Days.
Um,
I don't know.
I'm not that passionate about it.
Well,
there's no one,
right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Like people,
I don't know.
Okay.
I'm like,
like,
like I,
I realize like,
like j Cole is fucking awesome.
You like Kendrick?
I mean,
I it Kendrick's fine.
You know what?
It's interesting you prefer j Cole for
over Kendrick.
Yeah.
Dan,
um,
j Cole fans rejoice.
Kendrick is like Kendrick,
the reason why I'm not a hundred percent
sold on Kendrick is because he doesn't
wrap in the voice that he talks,
which is,
which is like,
he does like this kind of Shit,
you know?
Whereas like j Cole,
he's a lot of different stuff.
Yeah,
he does.
Yeah.
But,
but,
but that's one of the reasons why I,
I don't,
I liked that I liked the authentic,
this is who I am.
This is what we do.
Park would be like,
fuck this,
fuck that.
And then come up and be like,
so we're doing this fucking interview.
And you're like,
oh,
that's how he talks.
Yeah.
Do you know what I mean?
It,
you're a fan.
I can tell you're a very much a fan of
authenticity.
Yeah.
That's what I like.
I mean,
you have this whole thing you've talked
about on your podcast about if you're
being disrespectful,
they're actually being respectful.
Yeah.
Because you're,
you're,
you're respecting a person enough to,
to do what you want to do,
even though big frankly,
nor,
uh,
like if I would've put my feet up on the
table,
I'm respecting you enough to be me.
And if I'm like put,
take your fucking feet off the table,
what the fuck's wrong with you?
I would take them down because it's your
place ultimately.
But because,
but,
but you are welcome to about it.
Yeah,
no,
I understand.
But like I,
I wouldn't think you'd care,
but,
but my point is I'm me being me,
allowing myself to be,
feel comfortable around you is like the
most intimate shit.
That's true.
So if I put my feet up on your table,
I feel very comfortable with you guys.
Right.
And I'm not,
it's not like I'm saying like,
Oh,
you guys are so lucky.
I'm comfortable around you.
It's just,
it's just make it,
it makes us,
it makes me feel close to you.
It's like when I make fun of people and
people are like,
what are you talking shit?
Like I'm not dude.
Like my whole family growing up,
whenever we grew,
when we were growing up,
all we did was bust on each other.
That's all we did all day long.
My Mom,
my dad,
my brother,
my uncles,
my aunt like we would make of you.
That's how we showed
love.
And like,
so when people are like,
hey man,
why are you making fun of me?
Which happens every now and then.
You're like,
what did I,
it's like giving you a hug,
like literally interesting in my mind.
And I get that that's not like that for
everybody and people have different
upbringings.
So I'm sensitive to that.
But yeah,
to me it's like if,
if you are comfortable enough to be you,
that's the most respect you can give to
me.
Interesting.
This truth to that.
Do I think I fucking honestly sound like
a cult leader for real?
Well that's,
well,
I wonder if Garth,
I wonder how God feels about that
statement.
You can join the cult.
It's a return back to,
um,
to we never a chat cause we have,
yeah,
we have to wash this.
Yeah.
But anyway,
that you can tell what a fucking
goofball he is.
Oh yeah.
For sure.
What this dime store,
you know,
either,
either picture is,
is ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
Yeah.
He looks like a fucking thumb and look
at his face.
It's weird because country like,
couldn't be cool.
It could be.
Yeah.
Well some of it probably is.
I don't really know Corny,
the kind of country I know.
It was just like a twinkie and all
about,
you know,
there's that one that was so popular I
fucking hate.
It was about,
I'm a little drunk and I need you now.
You remember that one?
The lyrics were so dumb.
It's like every country song is like,
let me,
I fucking saw you once and you're like,
and then they're like,
I fucking can't get you out of my head.
It was like,
you know what I want to do?
I want to Redo the first of all,
let's,
okay.
I mean,
250 million.
Well,
that's too many.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's too Max.
She was expecting more to be frank,
but I,
I heard this song every fucking where
for a long ass time.
It's a quarter after one.
I'm all alone and I need you now.
Said I wouldn't call,
but I'm lost all control.
I need you to now another shot of
whiskey.
Can't stop looking at the door wishing
you come sweep in my way.
You know what?
Here it is.
I'm a little drunk and I need you now
that I don't know what that really bog
awesome.
Perfect.
I'm a little bit wrong.
It's like,
it's like,
can you find a more poetic way to say
that?
Said,
I wouldn't call,
but I've lost all control.
I don't know what it is about this line.
It drove me crazy.
I'm a little drunk and I need,
you know,
I like that.
That drove you crazy because she's not
even actually drunk.
Just so I'm a little drunk,
bitch.
Get Ahold of your life.
You know what that is?
That's a fucking bro right there.
[inaudible] need.
You know I realized that it's not as bad
as I thought.
All acknowledge that too.
No,
no,
you don't.
Honestly,
it is as bad as you thought and I agree
with you back Batman guy who plays
foosball wouldn't say all right.
I'm a little dry.
It's so pedestrian,
but that's what they love drunk.
I you do.
Now I can sit for that red cup down and
get off the foosball too.
You want to get together some time and
do enlist preview Kanye album listening.
We'll fly to Miami.
I'll just meet you.
All right.
Let's get to fucking,
this is just this,
we're going to have to break down.
How many views does it have?
Well,
I think it's been uploaded.
You ripped like how many pets do really
shitty rehab bloated but 150,002
out.
By the way,
let's just say look at the title.
Let's just say before we even start
this,
facebook had been up and running for 25
years.
Yeah.
This in like Brett,
no,
there's nothing groundbreaking.
But just imagine this guy is more famous
to Michael Jackson.
I know,
but here's,
here's something garth brooks has
definitely said before,
something like this,
like,
I don't know how much milk is,
what is it?
$15 and you're like,
no,
you're not.
You're not salt of the earth at all.
Yeah,
yeah.
Here's,
here's $50 go get a carton of milk.
Like that's what he's done.
And you're like,
okay.
You know what I'm curious about that.
I want to check really fast.
Garth Brooks net worth is this guy worth
300 million?
It could be worth more.
It's a lot.
A lot of milk.
Okay.
That's like 10,
10 gallons of milk.
So anyway,
lit,
amazing us and she began trench warfare.
So anyway,
this is his first facebook upload.
We've,
we've,
we've introduced it enough,
right?
Um,
where's my mouse button?
For Christ's sake.
Okay,
here we go.
Well,
I guess it's official.
We're now on facebook.
You know,
he rehearsed that little chuckle.
Yeah.
Wow.
Okay.
And it's really annoying.
And here's the other thing that started
with,
well,
the official,
like we know already what the fuck this
is about.
That makes me want to fucking jump off a
bridge.
The rehearsing,
the thing is he's trying so hard to be
authentic,
but it comes off like you can't rehearse
a chuckle,
like it's so fucking awesome.
But he didn't get them had fishel.
We're now on facebook.
[inaudible] had to be authentic and
fucking 40 years old.
Why?
He doesn't know what it's like.
Yeah.
We're now on facebook.
I really wasn't sure about this at the
start,
but then a friend of mine said something
that just made all kinds of sense.
It was just publicity that I like that.
All right.
You know what I liked?
I like that.
It's almost like a dating video.
It's like,
I like do like this is like the saddest
fucking dating video ever.
You'd be like,
this guy's probably on a sex offender
list.
I like that.
It's something they just made all kinds
of sense.
She should think of it more as a
conversation.
I like that.
Oh,
right.
He's like,
it's so calculated.
Pause,
smile,
chuckle.
I like,
I like to think that he forgot about
what he was talking about.
The defendant thought of tits,
like what you can see.
I'm registering to go,
go back and do I like that.
Be Happy,
garth.
That's what happened.
Titties
what I'm already finding out on my own,
so it's wiping the walls out between you
and me and I really liked that.
Do the way he drilled that.
I really like that.
It's like,
Damn.
It's honestly very weird.
It is like a flirting.
Yeah.
He's trying to fuck me on face.
Showing it also,
or is somebody he's close to his face
has no pants.
That would be the best.
He's got no pants on.
Just a shirt.
I'm going to put a shirt on him.
They below this and he's in a hotel room
apparently.
He says,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I really liked that.
I love the fucking guy falls out between
the human thumb.
Look at his face.
He's like,
it's just a thumb with features me and I
really liked that.
I really like that.
Really like that.
It allows us into each other's worlds
where I can,
I guess in my case a hotel room.
When I think about things I want to
post,
I want to post cool stuff.
Slick stuff.
You need stuff neat for most of the
stuff I'm going to post is going to be
raw stuff like this.
This is raw as it gets baby on the
hundredth try.
Oh,
kind of makes my skin crawl.
Yeah,
no it might weird.
It might be
okay.
It might be the greatest video on the
Internet.
That's why I'm so glad that we're
watching.
It might be the watching this again,
there's so much going on.
Might be it should have more views than
I am.
Finding that it was the first thing you
said the facebook video and like,
cause I have no one talks about it.
I know,
I mean it,
it definitely got a lot of use because
it's him,
right?
Not Enough.
Not,
yeah.
Well why wasn't,
this is what he's is.
They shouldn't be.
What he's known for.
Yeah.
Well cause that's why I said,
cause that when you bring up,
anytime anyone brings up goldbergs this
is what I,
the from facebook videos.
Yeah.
The facebook guy,
they're like mark Zuckerberg.
None of them got back.
The facebook guy,
you know Chris gain.
Yeah.
Slick stuff.
The guy looks up what can only pour all
the ports,
raw stuff.
I like that.
I really like,
it's just who I am.
Let's go back and kind of enjoy this
whole last,
because it's just who I,
he's a grown
all right.
But most of the stuff I'm going to post
is going to be raw stuff like this.
It's just who I am.
So this is truly a conversation.
Then I say,
let the conversation begin.
All right,
I'll take off my pants and I'm putting
my dick out on the web.
Webcam.
Isla.
It sounds to me like you're not ready to
let the conversation begin.
It's just
not,
yeah.
Well don't push back.
Also.
Did it even begin after this?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
Well they got rolled into oblivion.
Everyone on the Internet.
Again,
I think just the buddies way to end your
video.
When you think about start and finish
the day that day.
It's just,
it's just very,
the fact that like a guy can be
thinking,
this is the thing that fascinates me the
most out of for humans for since I've
been an adult,
this is the thing that's fascinating.
Most,
this is also my,
my number one nightmare to be
the way you think.
You're not being to come across.
He thinks he's being authentic.
Yeah.
It's the exact opposite is happening.
Interest.
You watch that and you think,
oh that's,
and he doesn't realize it.
That's my biggest nightmare is to walk
into a role in understand what you mean.
Yeah.
But do you think that he,
like he's,
this is clearly extremely rehearsed.
Yes.
So you think it's possible for someone
to almost be,
have that duality of mine?
Sure.
It's possible.
Yeah,
definitely.
He could be doing that.
Yeah.
Maybe he is,
but either way it sucks.
Either way.
It's fucking so funny and crazy.
Yeah.
Like,
come on dude.
I,
yeah,
I I,
I don't know.
Maybe it's cause I'm a comedian and like
I,
you have to let people kind of know who
you are for it to work.
Unless you're going to do like a
character,
which I don't do,
but like you have a podcast,
you know,
you know you're,
yeah,
you can't,
you're not some corny radio hosts like
that.
That's what he is,
you know,
and it's,
I wonder,
do you think he drinks lacroix?
No,
definitely drinks coke and he
definitely,
if he does go to,
he's going to drink sparkling water.
It's for sure that high end like that.
Yeah.
They're a high end ones that I find
bubbles.
Bubbles.
He's drinking soda with Cherry Syrup in
it with a big ass green Straw.
Yup.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
He's done well.
I really liked that.
I think glass,
I liked that.
A thin Straw.
Oh really?
Liked.
I really liked that.
Kind of got to get let it hang big game.
Yeah,
I hear it man.
This is,
I almost want it.
I want to recreate it.
I want to upload this to my youtube
channel.
I'm edited.
I think.
I think I did this and then uploaded it.
Are you serious?
You did you recreate it it,
yeah,
I know.
I really,
I know I sent the video to jr row.
I know I sent it to Joe.
Right.
Okay.
Let's see what happens.
And I think the Brian Cowen,
I don't know if I ever uploaded it.
This is from five months ago.
Some
random person.
It wasn't hill.
Oh,
but somehow this ended on,
it's just five months ago.
It's not even that long ago.
Oh yeah.
So somebody found,
well that's why I guess it's official,
Tim first.
I really wasn't sure about this at the
start.
Oh,
so it's back to back and I will say
this,
I,
I didn't write it down.
I watched it so many times from patch
that I did it.
This is from,
I remember,
I remember straight feeling and
authenticity.
Yeah.
I really liked that.
Crepey I can't believe for,
I need to acknowledge that this is
pretty wild.
This is pretty insane that this exists
in front of you.
Thought you'd bring it up.
I'm like,
Bro,
I want to recreate this.
Well,
you're in a hotel room.
I'm immersed.
Well,
I guess it's official.
We're on facebook.
You know?
I really wasn't sure about this a bit.
A friend of mine said something that
made all kinds of sense.
She said,
just think of it as a conversation.
I like that you want,
I'm already noticing myself is that it's
whacking away the walls of communication
between you and me.
Well,
not really like that.
It allows us to take a look at line as
an invitation to,
fuck.
That's a fucking,
that's a,
let's fuck.
I think facebook was,
he thought it was a dating site.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Everybody can see this.
Yeah.
Fuck.
All right.
We're each other's worlds,
or in my case,
my hotel room.
What do think about the things I want to
post,
what to post?
Cool stuff,
slick stuff,
neat stuff,
but I'm probably going to end up posting
brow stuff like this because it's who I
am.
Yeah.
Well,
like you said,
if this is a conversation,
then I say lit.
The conversation began.
I cannot believe.
I cannot believe that was,
that was,
I got to say I'm blown away.
Yeah.
Here we are right now.
That's weird.
No wiring,
own video that we're live right now,
broadly as it's being suggested.
Wow.
Well,
yeah,
that's a strange one.
All right,
let's get off of Youtube.
That's,
so,
that was such a good luck.
We were like,
Hey,
let's bring this up,
but not let every week we did not
meditate that,
I'm so glad that we were both were found
common ground on that.
Yeah.
I can't think of one.
Garth Brooks Song.
Not One.
Uh,
you know,
our guests,
I can either here at Garden Grove Roping
in the wind or was that someone else
roping in the wind?
There's that something like,
damn,
he's kind of,
he's kind of looking a little porky.
Piggish right now.
Does that mean,
does that racist against,
no,
I just think that when you get older,
I feel like everyone's just kinda gets
bigger.
What do you think about the top on the
cab?
How it's just killer.
Like what are you doing?
That's pretty killer though.
I got to start doing that.
I really liked the Campbell.
The bow tie I look is pretty cool.
You like it well do you like well it
looks cool on some people like people
wanting to fuck him.
I mean he was a sex icon.
This man right here is the sex I was
fresh faced.
Include wire.
I will never wear a button down with no
color.
That's like what are you doing?
That's what you got our haircut.
That's why you'll never be the number
two selling artists.
But what I am curious about,
let's just hop back on over to youtube
cause then I liked doing this where you
can type the artists and sort by most
popular.
So let's see what kind of,
there we are again.
For Christ's sake.
It's weird.
Well I've know garth brooks filter view
count.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
that's it.
I guess he's just,
he's been around too long because that
is what it is.
I've been around too long.
31 34 millions is is.
Yeah,
because fucking Migos has 4 trillion.
Yeah.
Gangnam style is more puppies than cars
broken apparently on youtube uploads to
cause.
Look at the channels.
It's not even anything.
You're not afraid.
Am I tripping or is this the same guy?
The uploaded your video?
No.
Okay.
Let's get it out of this.
Wow.
Let's get it as quick.
That was amazing.
I just want to talk about cardboard.
I'm being frank and I see you have your
feet up.
Thank you for doing that.
Yeah,
no problem.
No problem.
Um,
you,
uh,
the kind of talked about this,
about how you hate could Chella you hate
the listening parties.
You hate the woos.
Yeah.
Is there anything on your top,
on your list of things that you hate,
the kind of want you've been thinking
about that you want to talk about a
little bit?
Um,
something that's Kinda hit you lately,
recently.
New anoosh thing.
I don't know.
I,
I talk about it all the time on my,
and it's not that I hated,
it's just that it irks me,
but yeah,
Roger,
uh,
the wrong way or whatever.
But um,
I don't know.
The last thing was like the listening
party.
Like when I heard that over and come on.
What's going on in?
I don't want to put you on the spot,
but the easy are good intern.
He,
he was at one of those listening
parties?
No,
Ian can you grab the mic?
Oh,
that was Ian.
Which listening party where you at?
Kids see ghosts.
Oh really?
Kids keep cutting.
That was in la,
right?
Yeah.
How was it?
When did she enjoy,
was it a great trends in dental
experience?
Transcendental.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Like what do you mean you were there?
What was it like?
So you get there,
you park,
right?
Like a fucking asshole.
You put the ticket,
you get,
you get a ticket right to park.
Did you park on the street?
Where'd you park mother fucker.
I want to know that cause I to imagine
you walk into this fucking thing I
parked like in this dirt field.
Oh,
all right.
So that is pretty Bohemian.
I wanted it to be.
I wish it was a good place where you
were just like,
yeah,
I just,
I had to find a spot if people have to
wait.
Well I got to say it was super
pretentious,
the whole parking situation cause they
made us park and then put us on a
shuttle and the shuttle drove literally
for 30 seconds.
We drove 30 seconds down the road and
then they kicked us out of the shuttle
and like,
all right,
we're here.
So Ian,
you left that,
you admitted that detail.
They're like,
you're wearing here we are.
And they're like,
why not?
We could have it here and it gives you
shit.
So just play it and,
and,
and I,
there was a bonfire right in.
Yeah.
Big,
big.
You know why there's a bonfire.
You know why there's a bonfire?
Because it distracts you from what a
bunch of fucking idiots you guys are.
Because if there was a bonfire,
he'd be like,
what the fuck are we doing here?
You don't have a bump.
Right.
Cause it's not something,
right.
It's a bonfire.
You need a focal point.
It's more of like there was a full
buffet though.
There was all this.
That's kind of like it was a party.
A party.
What party is in the title the best.
If you were like,
oh well do you have any fucking anything
else?
Any others?
Music cause you play,
you play hard knock life.
Well they did play other music right?
You know it had 40 minutes,
40 minutes.
It's a short one,
20 minutes because it's a short,
I'll pay in.
Did you sense because it was such a
short album was hurt.
Any disappointment in the crowd when
they're like,
aw man,
I will say the crowd and Dan can attest
to this.
I was dancing my ass off but everyone
else was like too cool for yeah.
That's annoying.
You been with the bonfire?
Yeah,
it was like it was for most of the
people there.
It seemed like it was more of a photo
op.
Yeah,
that's an Si.
That's Kuta.
Oh Man.
That's crazy man.
Why'd you go?
So why did you go then?
Why?
What made it made you want to go?
I'm,
I'm like a die hard as a super fan of
Kanye.
Gotcha.
I feel like he's going to get ripped
forever since I exposed the fake easy.
Yeah.
We don't have to keep saying that.
When I said fake easy.
Is that something that you were trying
to keep secret?
Not to keep bringing it up,
but I'm just genuinely curious how
people imagine you just don't bring it
up.
You know,
I didn't quite catch that.
Can you say the word easy?
It's like maybe seven or more time.
You with a fake yeezys to the listening
party.
You look at you and be like at you and
be like real motherfucker.
There's a video of a fan doing that.
Trying to get them to sign.
Oh whoa.
Connie looks in eyes and goes,
those are fake.
No Way.
So even con you cause the fakes look
good,
Connie.
Has that makes it,
even if I hate it,
it looks identical except like a couple
of stitches or no,
but he knows.
No Way.
Isla would know because she will know if
someone copied your joke,
you would know you came up with it.
Okay.
Yeah.
You're probably right.
Wow.
Yeah.
I like the stance you've taken though.
Not Budget.
Where do you get Vicky's?
It's a process and I frankly was
intrigued by it.
All right.
Maybe we should look,
I made them do it.
If he did that,
he's in fucking [inaudible] here on the
side of him.
Like that's,
that was the best.
My jaw dropped.
Like the garth brooks video.
I went,
oh,
I can't help it.
Sometimes I've walked by these people
and I go,
oh everyone's getting out of control.
But you know,
talking about Kuna Matata cause we were
at,
you know this club hoppies I've heard
about it.
We were hanging out or post Malone was
at the Hollywood bowl last night.
He's a friend of ours and we went with
him afterwards to this club poppies and
with the whole entourage and,
and I'm thinking,
Oh yeah,
cause he was on your podcast.
Yeah.
And so I'm thinking,
oh this could be interesting.
I don't really go up clubbing.
It's so fucking small dude.
Poppy.
It's,
yeah,
the club is soldier.
The room.
I mean,
the room we're in is,
oh,
this must be like illegally path.
Wow.
It was so fun.
It was barely a specialty practice
because he was there.
Yeah.
Oh,
I'm sure.
But like there's people outside the
lined up.
I'm trying to get out.
Yeah.
There's not even really an exit for
people,
but there's a lot of a short legal
stefan.
Yeah.
But what I,
what I saw outside was,
was a lot of people like,
I just actually don't know why anyone
wouldn't want to be in there except post
malone.
Why?
Because it's so fucking packed.
Why does he want to be in there?
Because he's the center of attention.
He's there.
Celebrate.
Right?
Yeah.
I guess though,
see that's the thing,
like I guess he parties,
right?
Like,
so if your party,
it's a different thing.
I don't,
so like when I'm at,
I'm a,
I'm a comedian and at my show,
and granted they're not as big as
fucking post malone shows,
but like after that,
I didn't want to go somewhere.
You're done.
He's a young man.
He's 22 years old ass.
Fuck.
Holy Shit.
38 year old.
I sometimes I forget because I'm 33 and
that's kind of fucking like,
I probably shouldn't even be talking
anymore.
I don't think anything talking.
Yeah,
I got one.
Um,
actually one thing that I learned about
you
that did intrigue me,
why is that?
Well,
first of all,
let me say that I love your bit about
the drunk girls driving and I'm like,
Oh,
this guy has obviously spent a lot of
times.
Yeah,
you know,
but you don't actually,
you don't drink,
you don't use drugs,
you don't smoke cannabis know.
And I will say is that,
have you ever tried these things?
And now I mean prefaces by saying I
always have to answer this question four
or five times in a row.
I've literally never been drunk.
I've never done,
I've never smoked weed,
never done any drugs,
never drank.
Well,
one of my favorite people ever.
Ever,
ever.
Why surprising.
But like,
well one of my favorite artists,
frank Zappa,
who was like the nerdiest guy of all
time and the guy that you think was on
acid all the time was completely
straight edge.
I refuse to believe work with people who
use drugs.
Oh Wow.
Really?
I,
uh,
I think it's really cool,
but I'm just curious what's the theory
behind it?
So I don't,
I,
first of all,
when I was young,
young,
okay,
there's a few things I don't like to do.
The thing that everybody's doing,
I immediately,
I'm like,
wait,
why the fuck is everybody doing that?
That,
that's gotta be weird.
Okay.
So when people sort of drinking in high
school and Shit,
I'm like,
why is everybody doing this?
I'm going to take a beat.
Maybe I'll fucking do it later.
Okay.
So there was that.
Then there was also,
when I used to watch like the old Batman
shows with Adam West and shit,
when he would like penguin and joker
would gas people,
that would scare the shit out of me.
So I would equate like being drunk to
another altered state of mind to where
like,
like laughing gas was.
So as a kid I was also a little bit
scared of it.
After that I grew up and I have a thing
where I don't ever do anything until I
regret that I haven't done it,
which means I didn't lose my virginity
until I thought,
oh,
I should have had sex that one time and
I missed out.
Right.
Cause then I know I actually want to do
it.
Um,
and same goes with drinking and drugs
and I just have never felt like I missed
out.
You don't feel compelled.
I never,
ever was curious about it.
I never felt like,
oh man,
everyone was high.
I should have done it to the other
night.
Really.
And when I do feel that way,
I will do it.
I just,
I'm not saying I'll never do it.
It's impressive as fuck that you have
never even had a beer.
I mean that's,
it's weird.
I mean it's good for you.
That shit is,
it's healthy.
It's all boys.
And I know I have an addictive
personality for sure.
Now being older.
So,
yeah.
What are you well,
okay,
uh,
working out,
like that's a good one.
Yeah.
But I mean,
standup comedy,
Dude.
I,
I mean,
you know,
and it's about jasmine good things.
I don't know if you can call it
addiction has like a negative
connotation.
No,
no,
no.
But like the obsessive nature of it and
there's like,
I want to,
I worked out today.
I could go ugly.
Do you have any,
do you have like,
okay,
vices?
What's the vice?
I mean,
come on.
Your addictive personality.
I mean I drink so much fucking calm on
the due date.
That's good for you.
Maybe not as much as I can.
First Nate and Garth Brooks,
that's what I do frequently is you
telling me you never did that at least a
hundred times before you filmed that a
hundred times.
I really like that.
That's cool.
I don't have a problem with drugs,
but usually when I do them I regret it
really just because you feel shitty the
next day and you're like know more
hours.
The other thing,
it's fun though.
Some of my best experiences,
some the his times I've had brought
drugs,
but here's the other thing though,
I feel shitty in the morning a lot
anyway.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Like you know when you wake up and
you're like,
oh,
what did I do last night?
And you're like,
no,
nothing.
You're like,
Oh then why am I in pain and why do I
have to shit?
So at least you have an excuse when you
drink and you exercise and you still
wake up like that.
You know,
once I started doing,
like the past year,
I've been exercising really a lot cause
I wake up like that and I don't exercise
how everyone was.
It's a lot better when you've helped
ours.
It's a beard.
I'll tell you what,
I'm,
I'm almost there.
I've been thinking about starting an
exercise for at least three years.
Well,
in the next eight,
nine,
10 years when you should give it a shot.
When I had my first heart attack,
you'll think back now.
You'll be old.
You'll be 40.
Yeah,
I mean I basically will be in silence at
that exercise,
dude.
Now I do like a,
um,
like a circuit training.
Like,
I just like,
I'll,
I'll do like,
like I'll run,
I'll do sprints and then I'll lift the
little weights.
A lot of body resistance stuff.
And you have a trainer?
I have had a trainer,
but you know,
I kind of adopted my own shit.
Now you learn some of his stuff and then
you know,
a lot.
I also,
and I like doing it,
um,
and uh,
you know,
I like to sweat and I liked her.
I like to spend an hour not checking my
phone,
otherwise they'll just,
you know what I mean?
Um,
so yeah.
Hmm.
Plus I wish I liked it,
but,
but you don't like it until you get
quoted.
How long did it take you until you liked
it and how was it grueling up until that
point?
It's a fucking hard in the beginning of
man also.
Have you,
have you ever been in a guy who
exercises?
I've gone probably at most,
maybe like six months of being like
real.
Okay.
So wouldn't know I was there because if
you've never done it,
it's like really fucking hard thing I
did was swim.
Oh,
that's hard.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
I don't know man.
I just like it.
I like to sweat and exhaust myself,
see if I could do more the next time,
you know?
Well,
being healthy and looking good is
fucking yes.
That also,
and also it's like if I'm going to be on
camera,
it's my job.
I tell myself that too as I eat a
hamburger every fucking time.
Farc hamburgers are the best.
Do you have a problem with food?
Like do you like now that you're
exercising a lot,
his diet,
something you think about?
I do.
Yeah.
Um,
I,
I'm basically like really good all day
and then at night is like where I'm
like,
you let it go.
I love it.
That's great.
And,
and I,
and I try to,
I try to forgive,
forgive myself about it.
I try to not like be like,
cause I don't want to beat some as look,
here's what,
here's what I don't want to be.
If you guys get a pizza,
I don't want to be the guy.
I was like,
Nah,
can have a slice dude.
Your national,
if you're like that you can get a pizza
you to fucking part of the pizza,
you know,
so,
uh,
you know,
you is your slice skipper.
No,
I agree with like the don't be such an
extreme to like ruin a party.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Okay.
The vegetarian theory of like,
I won't fucking touch it.
I was like,
and when my brother went vegetarian,
if my mom's still cooked something in
the pot,
which he can,
but let's say there's beans,
it wouldn't touch the beans,
but it's like,
okay,
so you're asking her now to cook a whole
either that becomes a problem.
It's like,
Oh shit,
goddammit.
Fuck.
So that's when I'm like,
well,
just I wish you,
and they compromise.
That's all.
I wish you enabled me more.
Is that too much to ask you?
Yeah,
no,
it's not.
Maybe,
I don't know.
You guys just,
was she,
um,
was she enabled me more.
We just ate a breakfast burrito and
today it's not enough.
So we're getting,
we're about to wrap.
Okay.
But I have a couple of things I want to
ask you first,
which is kind of become a thing with
our,
with our show here.
So this is something that we happen to
talk a lot about and I find it
fascinating because it's so private and
everyone has their own different
approach.
How do you wipe your ass?
How do you mean up to you?
You have a bad day,
but you're asking me about a lot of
stuff that I already have severe
opinions about and the script,
I liked it.
So it's like I prepare it well.
Why do you wipe,
first of all,
how do you do it?
Look at all the way that I do it is I,
I love baby wipes changed my fucking
life because you go dry drives a whole
mess.
It's just not feasible.
It's not,
it doesn't cut it.
You tried to clean,
you know,
it's like sandpaper.
You ever believe from your asshole from
wiping too much?
Yes.
Isn't that the fucking worse?
You see?
Yeah,
it's bad.
It's bad.
Baby Wipe.
You go and dry.
You end what you call it a fucking day.
Now.
There's been a whole debate about our
baby wipes cause that flushable babe
webs.
Are they actually flushable that's a
debate we have a lot of people say it's
destroying sewage systems.
Okay,
so at then there's a,
there's also a debate because I want a
thorough answer from you.
You go from the front.
Do you go from the back back?
See I,
I'm an unusual breed.
I go from the front.
A lot of people they reject.
I never knew it.
Probably the guy that did that.
So like that's what I know.
I lift the balls.
Yeah,
I know.
But you bring it closer to your bowl.
My balls are not that.
Well you lift it up.
You don't like at most I'll go like at
most I'll go like halfway up the chode
it since like so much more uncomfortable
just to be back.
I don't get this,
but it's like,
are you sitting or are you standing?
You fucking go under the boss.
Yeah.
Imagine what you look like.
People generally aren't watching me.
Imagine how you look like,
like this.
This isn't a good sexy.
I'm pretty like,
and I do it when you go,
Ooh,
it sounds nice,
but you could also go here.
But I'm just saying a lot.
I get a lot of pushback on that.
But I think I liked that you,
I own it.
I own it because you lift,
you cut the balls and the thing is like,
you can be quite comfortable at the
toilet with your hand.
Don't you get about this?
Doesn't your arm touching?
Yeah it is.
No,
you just raise up a little bit more.
But what I don't get is if you don't get
it all,
you're pushing shit.
God,
this is gross.
Pushing Shit closer to your Dick.
What is that like?
What?
The whole thing is just about how close
this shit to my debt.
I mean it does.
It does.
It doesn't mean it's on my desk,
but also I'm not,
it's not so much that you're bringing
shit closer.
I mean,
you're cleaning out your asshole.
Are you bringing shit close to your
head,
man?
Like difference.
You're completing your ass.
Okay,
so all right.
Alright.
So I,
first of all,
I'll tell you right up,
right straight up,
fuck baby wipes.
I,
I don't like baby wipes.
And then with a wet ass hole,
dude,
it,
it's moist.
It's not white.
It's very white.
So here's the deal.
I had a fissure or whatever once years
ago.
Yeah.
Which is just like,
you know,
that's why you bleed out of your buck.
That's just a cut on your ass.
Cause you're sounds like you're at your
real laughs.
No,
no,
no.
That's different.
That's not that you bro lapsed didn't do
that guy.
But um,
but so the doctor was like,
try just use baby wipes from the intro
heal quicker.
It was like,
okay,
so I use baby wipes and then I was in an
apartment complex at this time.
Am I told it would get so fucking clock
and I'd go down and I'd be like,
hey guys,
my toilet's clogged.
And they were like,
oh,
we're using flushables.
I don't mean,
I don't know.
Probably not.
Those will fuck your whole world up.
So,
and then they were like,
they were like,
we found that you're using baby wipes.
And they were like,
you can't use those in this department.
Come back.
And I was like,
no,
get better toilets like that.
My doctor from,
we use a shit.
I can get that far.
But you know what date you're supposed
to do technically throw them in the
garbage.
You'll have sheer fucking shit man.
So,
so look.
so I don't like,
I don't like baby wipes.
I don't do them.
It feels gross to look after every
white.
Okay.
So I used to,
and I started taking this thing,
which I guess is psyllium Husk or
whatever the fuck or like metamucil
thing,
dude,
I do wipe.
But you don't even have to,
you do,
you can take a wiping supplement.
No,
no,
no.
It's,
it's,
it's for your bowel movements and it
congeals at all.
And metamucil sealant.
This happened at time up at all with
when you started like exercising?
No,
I basically asked my friend about it.
I was like,
dude,
I eat burritos and how many times do you
wipe?
And he was like,
two.
And I was,
wow.
Hey Man,
what do you have?
An asshole?
And he was like,
yeah,
take the psyllium husks.
I was like,
oh,
because I was probably like 30 times.
Okay.
Yeah,
no that's fine.
I'd be like,
yeah,
I guess I got to finish.
That's how you'll end up with a fisher.
So,
so I,
I take this,
did you gotta I wipe once and then I
look and I'm like,
do I even have to wipe and I just wipe
one other time for good measure dude.
It's like boom.
So you don't need the baby wipe.
You don't need day wipe obviously,
but you don't need the wet one.
No you don't.
And you're shit's just go boop.
Did you just take the psyllium Husk for
real?
That's crazy.
So let me ask you,
I know you started taking it and how
long after you started taking you duties
and ever since then yes.
It changes your life.
I'll see.
I'll,
I'll show you what I take.
I'll tell.
I'll send it to you.
That why is that not that revolutionary?
I don't know.
Helium Husk?
Yup.
You see how much you see?
You're like,
oh,
this is a weird conversation to have,
but this is where you learned the most
about life.
I mean,
it helps you more than fucking what are
you going to do?
What are you going to do?
You know,
people are like,
ah,
you know,
motivation policies in the world.
You can,
you can change your bowel movement.
Right.
That's within our grasp as of now.
And literally,
um,
I wipe a lot.
It takes a lot.
It doesn't,
if you take psyllium husk dude,
even if you eat awful,
yeah bro,
I would have to,
that's fun.
Crazy.
35 times what I could wipe.
I just keep wiping his shit was like,
well,
didn't now do you go in deep because you
can,
there's different levels of clean.
Like some people are happy,
they go surface.
They do like a wax on wax off.
I clean,
I clean.
I'm not going to walk around with
anything.
I bake.
I basically finger my asshole.
It sounds unnecessary.
I don't,
I don't fuck around.
I don't fuck around either man.
That's why I took that.
That's where I take a supplement for it.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm on that.
I'm going to check that out and I didn't
get a picture of what this dialogue is
really genuine because Tom,
we had on recently and he was like,
the big day changed my life and the day
I don't care cause you're squirting
water at your ass while I've got an area
asshole that makes everything worse for
me.
Yeah,
I would think so.
The baby wipes too wet.
I mean you're scoring boy the water.
So he was showing us this luxury be day,
we'd like a dryer to the to rise your
fucking ass hole blows hot air at your
ass.
I mean I guess it's better
than using a hairdryer.
You better hope you got all this shit
blowing hot air out of it or like this
live.
That's how I end every shit.
Yeah.
Alright.
That was good.
That was fruitful.
What was that called to give me the name
of that.
She'll be mark.
I wonder if we should make our own
brand.
My face on it.
I'll give you a percentage.
Psyllium Husk,
which is important.
Let me bold and Italicize this.
Okay.
I'm underline it as well.
Mine's metamucil and it's orange.
It's like an orange container that I
use.
Psyllium husk.
Here,
let me pull it up because I think people
here actually have a lot to benefit from
this.
Some of you guys will use it because I'm
talking about it on the podcast and
you'll fucking think about me every
time.
Tickets shit go man.
Whenever works.
This is it.
Apparently it's like a grain or some
shit.
He had to go.
So whatever it is,
it fucking works great.
And the asshole,
can I just eat this?
I don't know.
I actually don't know.
Is it just fiber?
Fiber?
Well,
I don't know if that is but,
but the,
the,
the thing that I take is not,
I mean,
maybe there's,
you know,
I'm sure there's stuff in it and that's
like that,
but all I know is it fucking works dude.
All right,
I'm on it.
If it works for me,
then it works for anyone.
Let me put it that way.
That's what I thought.
And I was like,
all right,
we'll see.
And it worked.
The lem husk man,
I want to snort that shit.
Yeah.
Would that help?
I think it would.
Yeah.
Anything kind of helped me like get it
in there anyway.
We're in all your years.
Orfices so here's our last question and
this one we've been doing for a long
time.
Okay.
If you don't have a response that's
perfectly fine.
I don't either.
But somehow you just never know what to
expect.
Okay.
Do you have any ghost stories or
paranormal experiences in your life?
No,
I dying neither and I don't either.
And I just don't,
I don't be have Bobby Leon.
Right.
He's got like a million of them.
Yeah.
But why?
Why has it happened to him and it,
I'm going to be once.
That's what I know.
Oh,
all man.
People don't,
yeah,
I want to believe that.
You know,
I'm open to it.
Sure.
Yeah.
A one time,
one time I was,
I had a,
we,
when we went to fucking cute asphalt,
I went when,
one time I went to,
uh,
we had like a,
like not like we were my buddies
backyard.
We went to go sleep outside the
We took a tent out there,
went into the wooded area,
and in the middle of the night we were
laughing in the middle of the night,
somebody,
we heard an old lady's voice and she was
like,
could you guys keep it down?
We're trying to sleep.
And we were like,
how the fuck?
Where did she come from?
It's his backyard.
We don't know who it was that it
definitely happened,
but it was a person,
like he was just a weird thing that
happened,
but we were scared the shit out of us.
Man.
That's,
that's as good as this gus stories that
could,
yeah,
that was great.
Yeah.
Well we did it and I want to say thank
you.
Huge,
huge fan of everything you're doing and
I appreciate that.
I want to urge everybody to first of all
go check out.
Yes,
Andrea actually open these.
These are,
oh yeah,
we have a little treat.
We have a little anthrax.
I give these to people that I want.
Um,
definitely go watch.
Congratulations.
Yeah,
it's on Youtube.
I'm on your youtube channels is still
yet definitely go to [inaudible] dot com
slash tour.
Yes.
And get some fucking big gaming to your
thing.
Do not at any,
any reason say whoa during her second.
Yeah.
This is it.
Oh No,
that'd be known that Ethan client has
demonstrated an exceptional x elder.
You're an elder of,
of my coal commitment to living and
spreading baby ship in the world and
honoring the congratulation.
Show what the consent of Daddy Chris
Delea this person hence forth carries
the status of elder.
Yeah.
And there's your pin there to prove it
in their thing.
This is nice paper.
This isn't like a guy.
Yeah,
we don't,
this is after like we spend money.
This is real paper.
It's signed.
Yeah.
Daddy signed it.
And there's a little pacifier that says
elder,
which kind of is contradictory,
isn't it?
Yes.
And Sense.
But I buy it.
Yeah,
I'm in.
There you go.
It looks good on you.
Well,
let me put my pin on.
So guys,
uh,
I had to,
I had a lot of fun.
This was great.
It almost looks like a Ufo and white
too.
It does.
Which is a play on the whole court.
[inaudible] that's a good point.
My stolen.
You're still,
you're alright.
You're alright.
You guys,
she dropped the fucking food.
Anyway guys,
I hope you had as much of a blessed and
I'm so challenged.
I can't,
I don't know how to do this.
We're gonna really stand by making them
my state again.
Let me just,
Oh my God,
I'm covered in Dandruff.
Well,
don't look,
it's okay.
I don't think that we didn't know until
you,
let me just say that are real in line.
Boy,
you know this,
this space.
I liked that.
This podcast.
I really like those guys.
Go check out Chris on everything he's
doing.
God dammit.
Thank you all so much for watching.
We will be back next week with,
I don't know who,
I may not even be something that,
a good pitch.
Oh yeah.
He was not going to be here visiting my
family.
Oh Wow.
How long is our flight?
That's 15 hours.
It's 17 hours.
Some ways you out where's the short way
or yeah.
Wow.
Remind me.
Well,
have fun,
play safe and God bless you.
That's it.
The show is over.
Thanks guys.
Thanks for watching buddy.
We'll see you next time on the age three
podcast x experience.
You can end it now.
Hmm.