Welcome up.
My Dude's,
my doggies and Micah z boys to the
Gazebo only zone.
I am your host,
Ethan Klein.
I am sick as a dog.
This is my beautiful pregnant wife who I
love and adore.
She's the angel of my life and the light
of my life.
She's everything that I've ever hoped to
find in a partner.
And so much more.
We look like I am so sick.
I'm delirious.
I'm out of it.
You know,
you're still embarrassed by my
introduction,
I say,
but it's true.
It's all true and so much more.
I am so sick.
I am completely out of it.
I've been pumped with all the quills
that they quills the night quells the a
twilight quills.
What do you get when you combine NYQUIL
and dayquil?
I'm in the twilight well right now and
um,
started wiccan coil.
Oh hell yeah.
After today I'm going to be weekend
quilt out.
Oh,
and thank you to our sponsors,
Audubon,
Mandy's,
linkedin.
Almost forgot about those great dudes.
Um,
I am so out of it.
So this is going to be a roller coaster
ride.
Guys.
Thank you for joining us on this
beautiful,
blessed at Friday.
Oh right.
Don't we all love it so much.
Yes.
I'm happy to share this special day with
you all.
Um,
we had Tom Segura and Christina P,
two of my favorite people on the planet.
We're scheduled with her on Wednesday.
I was sick.
Unfortunately.
We're going to get him back on here
soon,
but I love those guys.
Went to Disney yesterday with my family,
which made my illness worse.
So,
um,
but you know what,
that's enough about what's going on in
my life.
Let's get to the science of why we're
all here today,
last week.
And it's been part of the show mythology
I would say is we have these twitter
polls,
which really illuminating,
I would say some of the darker parts of
our society.
Not Dark and the sense of being,
um,
being unethical or something to be
feared.
But I'm on dark in the shadows,
in the shadows in that it hasn't yet
been uncovered or looked at.
We are,
we are great searchers.
We just great discovers we are
pranksters.
Do like social experiments.
This is real shit.
I wouldn't do it.
I wouldn't be surprised to see some of
these twitter polls being quoted and
such reputable articles as wikipedia.
So we had one last week about do you
smell on your hand and you fart on your
hand and smell it.
I'm so out of it.
Do you fart on your hand and smell it?
So first we did.
Do you like the smell of your own farts
and most overwhelming,
obviously.
Yes.
And there were some naysayers like I got
kind of upset because I feel you're
kidding,
but you're saying that you're serious,
but it's like you're kidding.
Well,
the Paul speaks for itself.
So first of all,
there was some disbelief that people
liked the smell of their own farts.
But then we took it a step further.
We said,
do you fart on your hand and smell it?
And most of the people in here except
for Zack is the only honest being here
was like,
what is wrong with you?
They say,
they say,
Ethan,
you are.
You shouldn't exist.
They say to me,
so let's go to this pole because this
was a prolific vote.
I would say this was a paramount
benchmark vault we took place here.
Have you ever smart farted on your hand
and smelled it?
124,000
votes.
That is a huge number.
And let me say 51%.
Yes.
And after this poll,
I bet you it's going to go even higher.
We even saw a capo on when we were at
Disneyland and the guy had to tell me
that he does it too.
Yeah.
And actually it was golf and I said,
can I smell your hand?
Lenny Snooze,
I sniffed his hand.
He had a Turkey leg in it and it was a
fart in a curriculum.
It was a great time.
We had their Disneyland.
Um,
um,
so there you have it guys.
This is science.
This is real science we're doing here on
the podcast.
Um,
but then so I got an email from a fan
podcasts@hdsreproductions.com
and she blew my ass out with a new one
she wanted to broach with us.
So let me read this email from autumn,
autumn g Hello Ethan.
And Ila lately on the show,
you guys been talking about your gross
habits and Isla almost every time has
said she does not share these strange
routines.
So as it yield Kleiner I had met when
I'm on my cycle I will often smell my
blood.
Nope.
Sometimes I find it satisfying and
sometimes I find it gross.
Lately my blood has smelled similar to
red wine and I've never smelled my blood
when it's in a,
oh she says,
and I never smell my blood when it's in
a Tampon.
Well how does she smell it then?
So I hate the smell and that is why I
usually prefer to wear a tampon cause I
like you don't smell it as much,
but how does she smell it?
You just from the toilet.
If you wear like a pad?
Yeah.
Oh then you take it off and it was kind
of like a Wa it's like a strong odor.
I hate it.
What does it smell like?
Gross.
Like body odor or like blood?
Both,
I guess you like like stink.
Whoa it,
he has men.
I think all the men listening to this
are like,
wow,
we're not supposed to talk about it.
It's like the ladies pack don't break
the back.
Girls don't poop.
They don't fart and they don't have
their periods.
Did you all know that periods stink?
Fuck man.
What did you think?
I never thought about odor being
involved can,
I don't know,
maybe I'm not describing it right but I
find a girl.
It sounds like you're right.
I mean she says herself,
she sniffs her period.
Blood sometimes satisfying some.
Do you ever find it satisfying?
I always grows sometimes more gross than
other times if I smell it more.
But you think it's all equally gross
cause she's saying sometimes it has
extra stake.
I guess that's possible.
A fraud like it smelled like red wine.
Does it have anything to do with the
volume of blood that's in it?
Probably.
And does it have anything to do with the
wounds?
The last time you changed your Tampon?
Like if how much body odor and sweat
gets mixed in.
I Dunno,
the fascinating stuff.
It's like,
wow,
this is new.
So you're saying that it uniformly
always smells bad and you even go so far
as to wear tampons to avoid smelling it
all together.
Yes.
So what I want to pose to our female
listeners today is,
um,
do you ever smell your period blood?
So we are going to make a twitter poll.
Dan,
you've got the bigger yup.
For ladies only head on over to h
podcasts on twitter.
If you're a lady and cast your vote,
do you ever smell your period blood?
Now these are fully anonymous vote,
so you don't have to worry about being
out at or being discovered or anyone
knowing about your disgusting habits,
which we all have.
So not to worry,
but I am truly fascinated by this
period.
Blood smell.
It's a new concept.
It's a paradigm shift in my
understanding of periods.
How was the early voting?
I'm very curious.
So my initial refresh,
53 votes,
and it's about 50 50.
It's 49 51 right now.
Whoa.
I had a feeling it would be like a vote.
We're going to take going to be 50 50.
Was there ever,
no.
Yeah,
of course.
No,
there's been huge swings.
There's been huge swings.
We've had 70 thirties and yeah.
Yeah.
We had a 60 40 with the front and wiping
the fiasco.
Remember?
No,
that's what I thought it would be.
I think it would be.
I expected that because I,
if I'm a woman and I have stinky
periods,
I'm smelling it cause I'm already saying
I smell my farts.
I'd be sounds climbing in that that 50
50 ratio is holding.
It's holding steady.
I would think that I would be smelling
my period blood it.
Thanks.
So yeah,
I would,
because I scratched my balls and
smelling the hint.
I think they just be smelling it.
I think there's just two types of people
in the world.
I think so.
Probably the people like or in denial
me.
Yeah,
you're in.
I do think that's true because it sounds
like I don't want it to return true
because it sounds like you do smell your
period blood.
You're aware of the smell.
I hate it.
I know,
but you what ads on some level you still
do smell and assess it and make some
analysis of it.
The fact is that you're in denial and
you don't embrace it as something you
know that you can get into on a personal
level.
Right.
I don't know.
I'm happy that I got nine months right
now.
Period went out,
but then it's almost like the baby is
almost like the nine months of period,
like stored up and it's just like,
so it's like a break and then a burst.
Yeah.
I'll be,
oh,
you think you got something good going
on?
Just the wave,
but at least it has a happy end to
periods.
Don't necessarily have happy endings.
Excepted the rover.
I'll be right there with you.
I haven't.
I tell you,
I have so much admiration.
I have so much respect.
You have to go through that and I'm not
jealous of that at all.
I'm truly appreciative that you need to
do that because my god of myself.
No,
I know.
That's an idea thing.
I mean denial about the that has to
happen.
Yeah,
well it's really just something,
it's like,
oh,
the baby's coming.
Let's just do it.
You just have to do it.
You just have to do it,
but you're going to get drug,
then you're going to be smart about it
and just not feeling thing because a lot
of women are like,
I'd want to do it natural.
And then halfway through when they're in
excruciating pain,
they're like,
hey man,
they thing the band name.
My sister is crazy.
She,
she was like no painkillers and she'll,
she really didn't take anything
throughout.
Your sister's a superhuman.
She's a freaking nature.
But in your case,
because the reason women don't get this
because it could take longer,
right?
Yeah.
The Painkiller Fred,
that you,
because you're a nom,
you're won't push hard as much as your
word if you're not.
I prefer the painkiller from my
perspective to not feel pain and have it
take an extra five hours.
Well,
five hours.
I'm just saying that's an exaggerated
comparison,
but I think that you'll be,
but I agree with you.
You know what I'm saying?
You don't want to trust me.
Trust me.
A guy that knows nothing about it.
I have a friend who was like,
I don't want it.
And then halfway through she decided she
wanted it,
but then it took long ago cause they
didn't have it prepared for her.
Oh Man.
The whole time she was just like
[inaudible] you get the painkiller.
Is it like no pain,
like total numbness?
No,
it's probably helped the law.
It helps.
But I don't think because when I,
I had a,
um,
I don't know,
I had a huge mole removed on my back as
a kid.
Um,
I think I must've been 12 or 11,
but,
um,
it was a really big surgery where they
cut it out.
And um,
when they gave me numbing shots and it
was extremely,
extremely painful,
it was so painful.
These shots,
oh,
was price cause it was just a shot.
I think this one is also painful,
but I felt nothing like zero sensation
and I was awake.
But I time,
I think you're already in so much pain
from the,
uh,
what do you call it?
Contraptions.
Oh,
the contraptions.
Yeah.
So I think that pain of that shot is
like tracking competitor actions.
So I think,
I think they have amazing medicines that
I think will really minimize the pain
you experience.
But the thing is like when I had the
surgery on my back,
so I felt no pain at all.
But then when they finished they had to
sew me up and the doctor had to cat co,
what do you call that when you
electrocuted?
Catterick colorize cauterize.
He had to cauterize my flesh together.
So he basically,
he literally like burned my flesh
together and that was fucking,
it wasn't paid.
I couldn't feel the pain,
but it felt so weird cause I was being
electrocuted.
How'd that smell?
That's crazy.
I didn't smell flesh.
I just found it was just a wild
sensation dude.
But um,
yeah,
so there's a couple of people who
responded.
I do and I secretly think it smells
okay.
Yeah,
there you go.
Exactly.
I don't think exactly.
I think this is a very interesting and
healthy discussion guys.
This moment.
It's actually exactly 50 50 and then
there's,
I'm not sure what to choose,
but you can't avoid smelling it,
but it's still gross.
So there you go.
I think there really are two types of
people in the world,
you know,
and I think that was exactly 50.
I think that's what it boils down to.
You know,
people who are in denial as you said,
dance and people that are like,
I'm onboard with spelling my period and
my,
I bet you the same people that smell
their fear period blood.
So I'll still smelling their farts and
they'd probably pitched their vagina and
smell their hand probably,
you know.
Um,
all right,
well fascinating stuff here guys.
This is a science explanation,
but if science experience full beginning
fascinating.
Yeah,
I love it.
Um,
what else we got here?
Oh,
another fence submission.
This was the best fricking video I've
seen in such a long time.
You guys,
Oh my God.
Talk about Tlc.
We've been talking about Tlc a lot.
I haven't seen this yet.
So I'm,
so this comes from discovery o.
And.
M.
It's a [inaudible] editor.
Yeah.
I know.
They're like,
hang on guys,
we've got to stop,
make,
wait,
planet earth,
none of that.
I'll fucking cancel that.
We're working on a new show called
diagnose this or diagnosed me and we're
going to do epic reenactments of these,
of these diseases.
Now this guy,
Ron,
suffers from ceaseless belching and co
he's,
he cannot stop burping.
He cannot stop burping and they reenact
it and oh my God,
this is from devin mirrors.
So God bless.
[inaudible] this is the best thing I've
seen.
It's incredibly healing
before his condition began.
It's kind of scratchy it up.
Yeah.
Here.
Uh,
I think I might know what's up.
Hold on one sec.
We're all set up here.
Very Professional.
Always prepared and very alive.
That's right.
Folks.
How are you feeling?
You feeling pregnant?
I feel really tired and I think that's
part of this stage.
How was Disney for you yesterday as a
pregnant lady?
I could,
I go on all the fun rides.
So I thought,
what are already like a boring mom.
I felt so bad for you as I wrote all the
awesome rides and I was tired because he
fixed it.
Yeah,
I'm already lame yet.
And you're not lame.
It's not your fault.
You're amazing.
You have a fucking,
you're growing a human body and your
stomach.
That's as amazing as it gets.
Pretty cool.
Yeah.
You know,
laying your fricking awesome.
All right,
here we go.
It's wife sue.
Have a good day recently.
That's love baby
or stress.
Just working on growing my business.
I look at this,
this is the reenactment that gives you
any more.
That was like,
what am I watching?
Hello?
So the burping sound is insane.
It's always like,
uh,
and um,
but I soon learned is that the burping
soundbite they use is a sound bite from
the actual guy.
It is.
So he's actually,
so what they're doing is playing the
actual birth,
but the guy every time they say that,
no,
you could tell because they show one
brief clip of actual guy burping.
And so they use that one soundbite and
they use it every time in this
reenactment.
And it sounds,
it's the same stuff.
Oh my God,
it's amazing.
I'm sorry ma'am.
It started gradually
and he's so like,
it's like you just burp I,
and he's always like,
I'm so sorry ma'am.
But yeah,
I would be,
I'm looking trolling,
you know when I was at the customer's
house and then when I went outside and
real dump trunk,
I've just belching belching balls.
You got the brushed her off
three.
It seemed crazy.
Ron's no,
sorry.
I can't help it.
I balls for maybe 2030 minutes an hour
and then start up again.
Why do you have to Burp so loud?
Just close your mouth.
Well,
you don't have to Burp loud.
I don't think he can control it.
Does this show about it?
I don't think it can control it.
Lee.
He's burping a lot,
but I mean you could control how loud
you burp.
You can go or you can be like,
not always.
Really.
I've never heard you burp.
What do you know about it?
I see people burp,
but you burp quietly,
right?
Because you're a lady.
I don't remember.
Yeah,
thanks.
One of us should sleep.
At least one of us should sleep,
can be part of society.
Sat Up.
He literally said he wakes his
neighbors,
address a series of tests.
His doctor had a bowel obstruction and
suggest it's all in Ron's head.
Stop thinking about it so much.
What are you supposed to do?
Like Dang gone has been belching nonstop
for months cause that's
suburb.
I've never heard a burp like that in my
life and so yeah,
it has to be there using that soundbite,
going to dozens of doctors,
the one cure that's out working.
Look at that face.
Look at this reaction that seemed to
work.
Just stopped working with a vengeance.
Leaving Ron.
So desperate he wants to kill himself
there you got,
he wants to kill him.
Well he,
yeah,
I know.
I feel bad for the guy,
but like they do this sound editing
where they'll take the soundbite burp
like here and then they'll like damp in
it.
So it seems like he's far away,
but they're just using the same
soundbite
Ron.
So desperate.
He wants to kill himself dry.
How thing?
No,
they're making them
like,
yeah,
like he's turning into a wall,
like a Stephen King novel.
But yeah,
he's like a werewolf.
What is happening?
Yeah,
finds out what's going on.
She panics and calls nine one one
emergency room.
They looked over my records.
They said there's nothing we can do for
you.
We're going to,
Scott is assigned to mental health
counselor Lisa Gustin.
Right.
Rick questions open up the reservoir of
pent up.
Although he does this factor when he
birthed,
I didn't see the guy do that.
He just fit every criteria for anxiety
and depression.
He fitted
why way.
It turns out he needed an
antidepressant.
Really and he wasn't manifesting anxiety
and unusual way and that he's cared now
for.
I believe it.
You do what's on discovery.
You can't be wrong.
They wouldn't lie to us hitting me with
that sound bite.
That's the BURP.
The first time I started,
I wish I could wash the first time with
you guys cause the first time I saw this
I was just crying.
I hard.
That's all so good.
So fun.
Look at that diagnosis Ron.
On the general lines,
they worry,
they edit it.
He does this look like perfect like a
thousand times a day and he's surprised
every time it happens.
Adidas sorta combined with clinical
depression.
I of those things where I'll burp.
I guess I got out of the problems.
It stimulates the brain in a certain
area.
I love that.
That video is fricking Jim.
I did.
Oh,
shout out.
Wow.
Having a lot of fun here.
That's a great suggestion.
Um,
damn.
What's the pool at?
Uh,
let's take a look.
We've got refreshing a 49 51 man.
This,
this truly is the nature of what this is
going down.
You actually the yeses slightly down,
but I mean it's (485) 024-0850 two no.
Oh,
so no is slightly edging.
So that makes it feel more realistic.
Um,
I feel like the margin of error though,
like you got to say it that that's it.
That's a split.
Well,
the pro,
the problem is that you have to vote to
see the results.
And so a lot of dudes out there one,
is that right?
What I see the results.
It says ladies only.
So I know any dudes are voting.
There's got it.
I wish there was a way to view the
results and about,
it's so messed up because you know what
you we to add a third option that says
I'm a dude.
Oh then it doesn't affect the fricking,
you know what should we do?
Another one do a new one.
A race that one dan and start over with
a third option.
I'm a dude.
No vote and thank you.
All right.
I've been trying to say for many years
and I'm a brilliant mind to listen to me
more.
Cause there is a couple of guys here
including and from a smudge.
What did he well they sat,
I'm a guy so this is sexist.
Oh well you smell your period bug in.
You Smell Pam's period blood.
Yolande it's not your period blood.
I don't want to like I want to,
I'm kidding.
I don't know anymore.
You all smell it.
You see,
I don't know if she tried to be your own
excrement.
I mean you've got a cookie live.
I'm so out of your got a cookie.
Just straight on the table.
Like we have plates unfold at the
tweets,
the tweets back up.
Anybody that already voted you gotta go
back to you're obligated.
You should leave a comment and explain
why we re posted it.
I'm like,
okay.
I don't go fuck.
It's just a fucking sick and I don't
give a shit.
That was Scott.
Ian brought cookies.
I'm like [inaudible].
Every time I see doughnuts or cookies or
something on the table,
I'm like,
who the fuck brought these?
I get angry as I eat them because I'm
like,
I don't need this shit.
And it's always Ian.
He was trying to feed me.
Oh,
it is always the end.
I know he's a feeder and I yelled at him
every time I say,
don't bring this shit here is I eat
three of them.
Okay,
we got to go to a break or should we
move on to the Youtube?
Okay,
great.
System is broken pretty early for break.
How much time?
I think Youtube,
uh,
worth 24 minutes.
Okay.
You want to know about the new Paul?
Yeah.
What is it?
Is it a big difference?
Well,
I'm a dude is winning a lot.
Well that's not good.
But if you're removed that we have yes.
28 yes,
that's true.
And No,
24 oh this is,
this is so important.
This is such an important social
experiments or flat valid,
fundamentally flawed.
Well,
no,
not all of them.
Just gender specific ones,
which is like all of them not far on
your hand and spell it.
That's the big one.
Hello.
Trying to throw out my science.
I think it's the only guy in my head.
Can I get another cookie?
Those are incredible.
Um,
okay.
I got something to complain about here.
Everyone who likes to hear me complain
about Youtube.
This is just a fun little anecdote.
So I got a claim.
Oh,
you actually brought me a cookie.
I didn't need that to let you know that
your mom delivered all of her babies
naturally.
Oh yeah.
So I don't know if you could hear that
Ethan's mom delivered all of her babies
naturally,
but I think that was just the time back
then,
isn't it?
I feel like my mom did too.
Or like my mom would have a lot to say
about this chicken call.
It gives me more time to eat cookies.
I'm just trying to buy time to eat more
cookies.
These are sane.
Ian.
What the Fuck's wrong too?
Um,
all right theresa,
let me focus it.
Got this off.
This is the worst episode we've ever
done.
Good ball gets to everybody.
Um,
so loud.
Okay,
sorry.
Sorry.
Sorry everybody.
All right,
here.
I'm going to complain about Youtube.
Okay.
Yay.
We're coming here for papa.
John,
mute me.
Okay.
This is a highlight claimed by whoever
these cocksuckers are for a song,
sex on fire.
Okay.
Here's the interesting little fact.
We didn't use that song.
It's not even in the clip.
So I file a dispute and there's not even
an option for this.
Whatever you claimed isn't even in my
video.
[inaudible]
there's not even an option of like fuck
off.
Right?
So anyway,
I,
I what?
I don't remember what I did.
I think I did like,
I think you just doing like,
it's fair.
Use My,
my use.
Is there something I didn't know you
didn't use it?
I don't know what I did,
but how would that even get in there?
Well,
I didn't know what I did,
but I just basically said in the
scripture,
this song did not appear in the video.
So release your claim.
And so here's the best part.
These are these huge media companies.
Just go on rampages of claiming videos
because there's no,
um,
there's no recourse,
there's no accountability.
They get free money and they have no
reason not to claim every single video.
I waiting for one of these guys who just
claim every single video on youtube.
They're like,
fuck yeah,
no,
you use sex on fire.
The way the law's written there,
there's no recourse or well technically
or a false claim that it's so broad.
It says,
um,
and good faith.
So you could,
I think that a claim like this for
something that's not even in the video
is an end good faith.
But you're,
you're bringing a lawsuit,
I guess the company for something.
So,
you know,
it's just,
and there's no damages.
It's like,
it's pointless.
What do you,
what do you know what I'm saying?
You would need to have like a huge class
action lawsuit to show like tons of
damage over like thousands of users.
It would be so complicated to actually
litigate that.
So expensive and complicated to litigate
that and they know it.
And as far as I'm aware,
they've never been held,
recount accountable for this shit.
Here's the options.
Um,
these are all these except for fair use
I think or well,
most of them except for farriers are
just like youtube way of being like,
see you later,
idiot.
Here's what you get when you try to
dispute it.
I own the CD that's youtube being like,
see Ya.
I think if you click that they're,
you don't have a reason.
You don't know what you're talking
about.
Yeah.
I'm not selling the video or making any
money.
That's a skip.
I gave credit in the video.
That's his cup videos,
my original content.
I own all the rights to it.
So that one's fine.
Um,
I have a license or permission.
That one's fine.
Meets Fair use.
Content is public domain.
So those ones are all fine.
Actually find claims to make.
So I don't remember which one I did,
but their response is what's really
makes this a powerful.
Um,
they responded by,
I disputed it and they responded by
rejecting my dispute.
Okay,
who is they?
And this huge media companies,
I don't know.
Youtube,
not youtube,
these media company,
I don't know what spa and there's like
seven of them.
So I said,
hey,
this isn't your songs.
And even in the video,
that's the first level.
You dispute that.
And then they come back,
they rejected my dispute and they said,
ah,
I don't fucking care.
I'm keeping it sex on fire.
That's the worst thing is that they
accused us of using kings of Leon.
I didn't even know what that was.
Pop sign.
Never.
It's like,
what?
So I'm like,
okay,
that's insane.
Um,
the fact that they would dispute it.
So now I am forced to go one step
further in the process.
And at this point you basically say your
songs aren't in the video,
leave me alone.
And they have the option to strike and
remove the video.
So there's something wrong with youtube
though because three of our last three
videos have been claimed,
like the frequency of claiming videos
and just erroneous and shameless claims
have sky.
I mean three of our last view.
And it's still a bunch of new companies
that have like a whole division that is
just this.
I think that it has new claiming stuff.
I think they have tools because you
cannot go watch videos.
They have some kind of automated tools
that match it.
And this case it's wrong.
And they don't even put in the effort to
reviewing it.
I mean,
youtube has got to regulate these people
because they're running a muck right
now.
It has not been this bad ever,
I don't think.
Um,
and then just to show you guys where,
where's the video of all of our
demonetize monetize videos?
Uh,
Dan in the PDF.
I don't see the pbl.
I opened a tab of it.
You should stop reading.
Oh my God.
It's not tab and you're on the desktop.
Here it is again.
That does not work.
It doesn't work then.
All right,
forget about it.
You gotta put on my desktop next time.
Um,
so that's about it.
I'll share this pick when we get back.
This is the best episode we've ever
time.
This is the one that will be remembered
for.
So,
um,
we will be back with that picture that
you're promised.
We've got a lot to talk about.
Celebrity asm are a bunch of amazing
videos.
Elon musk is a weed and a call from Gb
Acmr who has got some Churros that we've
talked about.
She's got choice words for me.
She's got a beef with what I've said
about ace mar and we're going to squash
that beef here today or ramp it up.
You never know.
So,
uh,
stay tuned y'all.
There's so much more actually podcast
after these messages.
Thank you to audible for supporting the
h three podcast.
What would it look like if we all listen
more?
Listening to audio books motivates us,
inspires us,
and brings us closer together for our
audience.
Audible is offering a free audio book
with a 30 Day free trial.
If you want to listen to it,
audible has got it.
Just go to audible.com/h
three podcast or text h three podcasts
to 500 500 and browse are unmatched.
Selection of audio content.
Start Your 30 day trial,
download an audio book for free and
start listening.
It is that easy.
My Dude's there is no better place to
listen than audible because now audible
members get even more exclusive audio
fitness programs,
audio books,
audible originals and more.
And now with audible originals,
you can experience even more custom
content made exclusively for audible
members.
I'm going to recommend a book to Y'all
that I absolutely love.
It's called the subtle art of not giving
a bleep,
which is the f word,
but it's bleeped out.
Um,
this is,
uh,
this is an unorthodox motivational book
because there's been a whole kind of
slew of like self help gurus saying that
positive thinking is the answer to
improving our life.
And this guy says,
no.
Positive thinking is not only not the
answer,
it's the problem.
What we need is to accept that we're all
damaged,
life isn't fair.
And what we need more is to just stop
giving a frick.
It's hilarious.
It's raw.
It's powerful.
I highly recommend the subtle art of not
giving a bleep and it's very well
narrated and it is available on audible
every month.
As an audible member,
you got one credit,
good for any wall.
You'll book you choose plus to audible
originals from changing selection you
can't get anywhere else.
I will members also get access to audio
fitness,
health workout,
create,
excuse me,
for audible.
Plus your books all yours to keep with
audible.
You can go back and relisten to anytime
even if you cancel your membership.
They don't like your audio book exchange
it,
no questions asked.
So get started today with a 30 day trial
and your first audio book is free.
Go to audible.com/hp
podcasts or text a true podcast to 500
500 that's Aud,
ib l e.com/a
street podcast or text history podcasts
to 500 500 me undies.
You all heard me obsess over the amazing
colors and prints,
but did you know they've got the most
comfortable lounge,
pounds and t's.
Finally,
my dude's just in time for winter.
This is the,
this is like a one piece.
This is like a man skirt,
a little dick mark up.
All y'all could see that.
This is like,
you know how girls wear skirts from top
to bottom?
Guys,
worst girls skirts here,
let me just my Dick a little bit.
Guys.
Wear skirts from the bottom up.
This is just to prove to you how
breathable and comfortable and
incredible me.
Andy's is.
This doesn't even hurt.
This isn't even a wedge of that bothers
me.
I could go walk around in public like
this can be perfectly happy and
comfortable and warm.
Pants are unbelievable.
Okay,
now let me tell you.
Mandy's love,
solid writing,
fall season and Halloween prints.
Check out the Jacqueline at prince me
undies,
socks and bracelets.
The best part is when you join me at,
you can get all this stuff.
Lounge pants,
t's undies,
every gay damn thing for listen to
anyone else.
Especially.
Remember pricing is just one of the many
perks of joining membership.
My Dude's,
they are the softest underwear and
plainly as to see [inaudible] got fun.
Prints that I can match with socks or
Bra lists,
100% in fact,
it's Andrew,
we're said,
satisfaction is guaranteed.
You're going to love these things.
It's an absolute guarantee.
If not,
send it back.
It's risk free.
You get a refund,
they burn it,
the incinerate it,
you get your money back.
It's a win.
Win me,
and he's got a great offer for my
listeners,
50% off and free shipping on your first
purchase with me on decent.
It's a no brainer.
Look at this [inaudible] guys,
it's a no brainer.
I'm sick,
it's winter.
When I'm home,
I'm wearing these lounge pants.
My Dude's so for 50% off the most
comfortable undies you will ever put on
guilt to [inaudible] dot com slash h
three that's Mandy's dot com slash hd
100% the right people can make a huge
fricking impact on your business,
and that's why it's so important to find
the right people.
But where do you find those people?
You could try posting on job boards,
but let's re let's be frank with each
other.
Who's on job boards?
Weirdos,
all of them.
Okay.
Instead,
you need to find the person's can take
your business to the next level and
where do you find those people on linked
in?
That's right.
As the world's largest professional
network,
people go to linkedin every fricking day
to grow professionally and discovered
job opportunities.
70% of the US workforce is already
there.
What?
That's insane.
Linkedin job matches.
People do your role based on more of who
they really are.
The skills interest in even how open
they are to new opportunities.
This way your job gets seen by more of
the right people.
Most linkedin members haven't recently
visited top job boards,
but nine out of 10 of them are open to
new opportunities.
That means you are going to be stealing
the best people from the best jobs
because yours is even better.
So you can only reach them on linkedin
and that's why new hires made every 10
seconds using linkedin.
Now,
now new hires every 10 seconds and
business rate businesses rate linkedin
40% higher than job boards at delivering
quality candidates.
Guys.
If you're looking for the right employee
head and hurry on to linkedin.com/kick
ass and get $50 off your first job post.
That's to linkedin.com/kick
ass.
That's one word.
To get $50 off your first job posts,
linkedin.com/kick
ass terms and conditions apply.
Welcome back everybody to the period
blood smelling experience.
The missing pdf I was trying to find for
you guys.
I just want to show you,
youtube has been on a crazy on
monetizing just out of nowhere.
Your old Shit nigger.
This tried to explain half of these
prank invasion a closer look.
These horrible designs are unreal.
Crappy designs.
Prank of agent starts world war three is
Pewdie Pie.
Racist toy channels are ruining society.
Crazy feminists triggered by lyft
driver.
That's the title.
So cringy crazy feminists gets
triggered.
Oh,
that's so cringey to the different time,
wasn't it?
Featuring humongous dicks out for her.
Rhombi which is like a kid.
I mean I,
it's like Kik.
Give me a break.
Is the monetized because it has an
asterix?
I think because what we do is a face,
no,
it's the most wholesome Joey Salads,
the deleted social experiment,
prank invasion,
the dangers of social media.
Girl virtually assaulted in GTA.
See Israel of Loc.
It's a Vlog baby.
Love your body.
Alison gold,
Dj Khaled.
[inaudible] kissing pranks.
The original dg Kalb celebrates hold you
down.
Alison gold,
ABCD,
fg.
Um,
and so many more.
It's just older and stuff.
But like these are a lot of our main big
videos that people aren't videos.
That's the total at the top.
Yeah,
71.
I mean a lot of them are old.
Probably like 20 or 30 of them are.
But these,
these are our cream of the crop.
These are our money earners cause they
still give used over it.
That's a big one.
A lot of the old ones are unlisted.
Okay.
But the ones I'm showing you are our big
earners.
Those are really,
and some of our most viewed videos.
So yeah.
And the,
they don't tell you they just like just
a day ago I saw just randomly in my
email like five new videos,
like of our biggest ones,
like not suitable.
It's like,
okay,
that's weird.
Why?
Yeah,
why,
who cares?
So shout out to youtube and to the
copyright system for helping to
encourage creators and to be a very
encouraging environment.
Now since we created this,
do you smell your period blood pole and
added option for?
I'm a dude.
The results have swung quite a bit.
Yes.
Because I can see a lot of dudes just
being like,
no,
that's gross.
Let me see the results.
But the majority is giving us yes in
this,
um,
in this scenario here,
how do you feel about that?
Hello?
I'm surprised by it after doing this
podcast.
Not surprised.
All right.
Where were we?
Um,
Yada,
Yada Yada.
We've got the mail bombers car we got to
chose,
chases criminal down.
Let me get a Acmr.
Let me do this same more segment cause
we got gb standing by to give us her
opinion.
I came across this celebrity Asm,
Amr playlists,
who,
who put this together.
It was like a,
a huge magazine.
Um,
oh,
it's a w magazine.
W I ever heard what the hell,
what did they do?
What does any magazine do?
20th right?
Making youtube videos,
trying to make a viral videos so they
have celebrities do eighth or,
but I don't really,
they have a lot,
by the way.
Carra de,
I don't know how to say her name.
You guys don't know who she is and
they'll,
Dell Levine a gal,
good dot.
Aubrey plaza,
Kate Hudson,
Ashley Graham,
Emily Radic,
Koski Cardi B and so many more.
Some hike.
They're all females by the way,
which kind of supports my theory for
Jake Gyllenhaal as one guy,
but otherwise it's all females.
Supports my theory that GB is going to
try to dispute,
which is fine.
Gb,
um,
that this is largely used by men that
liked this virtual companionship of
females.
And I feel like especially the one with
Cardi B,
when you show it,
I'll show that.
But first I want to show up what most of
them.
This is actually the most viewed one by
Cora.
That's 5 million views and I don't think
they will.
It's,
she's just whispering.
Um,
really me so weird.
Westbury.
She just,
you know,
it's actually really bad for your
throat.
Fun fact number one.
Um,
I dunno,
I'm Kyra telephone,
which is just worth a frame.
I don't know what she has to mix.
Why does she keep switching mikes?
It's not really,
it's tomorrow.
That's a big part of it is because
they're pan hard left and right.
And so like us in the back right now
with the headphones were hearing her in
one year and then the other year and I
think that's like,
that's part of it.
Yeah.
But I think you're supposed to do like
use it as for the like,
but she's no expert.
We have an expert on the line.
Yes.
I played too.
At any rate,
it's niche.
It's just,
it's just a celebrity whispering,
you know?
Yeah.
Like Cardi B on the other hand does give
it a fair shake.
I'm actually impressed she got through
it.
Yeah.
Look at this dude.
My Dick is straight up at full half math
right now.
I wonder if she smells or period blood.
She probably does already be.
Probably next time you're approaching a
girl that you're interested in,
you're like,
gosh,
she's amazing.
She's so out of my league.
I can't even talk to her.
Just remember,
most likely she smells her period.
Blood life dude.
Yeah,
Dude.
Just remember she's human.
She's snips your period blood.
I'm getting tinkled I like the hand
gestures.
She's got her hand out on a client like
scratching my back or something
virtually.
Right.
Did she sell intuit?
Oh yeah.
Fucking a stroke.
It,
it's kind of weird with the Mike's and
Oh,
she's dual welding.
She's fucking,
Oh God.
She's taken both of them at once.
I saw it and I was like,
what the fuck dude?
I'm tingling and all the right places,
but she is actually doing good.
I feel like she is,
but I want to know what you think so,
but yeah,
so I think we've properly set it up.
So let's get the expert on the line.
Gba,
Smr,
um,
is with us here today.
Gb,
how are Ya?
God bless you.
Thanks for joining us.
Hey,
nice to meet you.
Thanks for joining us here today as our
resident,
a smart expert.
Now your channel is quite big and it is
very popular.
You're very good at what you do
apparently,
and so thank you.
First of all,
I have to ask you,
do you smell your period blood?
Yeah,
we were just talking about that in the
room because we were watching the
beginning of the podcast.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm glad you have a preference to that.
That would have come off really weird.
He didn't know what I was talking about.
We were saying that like that's the,
that's the consensus is you don't really
have a choice.
Right,
but the question really,
well,
okay,
let's,
we don't need,
we have who don't need to dive too deep,
but you didn't you,
you smell it against your will.
Seems to be your answer so you can
finally grows.
No wait.
She said no,
she doesn't know gross.
No,
it's not pleasant.
I would not.
I would not smell it.
Okay,
excellent.
Great.
I'm glad we got to the bottom of that.
Now,
what did you think about these
celebrity?
I'm a cmr segments that I just shared.
If you're watching those.
Yeah,
I've actually seen those.
So the W it's,
it's,
it's a women's magazine.
Yes.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Yeah,
it's actually really cool to see
celebrities doing asmr because,
you know,
just a couple of years ago,
it's something that no one was talking
about or I had heard I've heard of,
like I've been watching it for like
eight years on Youtube and since I know
my channel is all like two years old,
but I've been watching it forever and
like I was always embarrassed to talk
about it because when you come in on it
at first,
so like this,
this is kind of weird,
like objectively.
Hmm.
Um,
but when you see people like Cardi b
like doing asr,
less weird,
so they're sort of making it more
normal.
And so what is it that I got wrong or
what did I miss and my original segment
about asm,
our videos?
Because to me,
I think people I've previously spoken
that it does seem to be like the popular
Acmr channels are ones of cute,
you know,
cute young girls,
not,
not young,
young ladies,
practice two attractive young ladies.
And um,
it seems,
uh,
you know,
as a guy it's a nice kind of way to get
a companionship and relaxed and you have
kind of a wave spending time,
intimate time with a girl.
Do you contradict that?
I don't think you're wrong.
I don't think that's everything though.
Okay.
Um,
I think most like most people who have
never seen it before,
they jump in on it and they're like,
oh,
this must be a sex day.
Hmm.
Um,
and while you can absolutely find asmr
videos of sexual overtones,
you can find sexual anything.
You know,
people will always utilize that to get
views or you know,
to gain popularity quickly.
Or maybe it's just how they like to do
it.
Um,
but I have some art itself.
Like I keep asking people like,
over and over again,
I'm like,
so why do you watch it?
Why do you watch it?
I'm just like the overwhelming response.
It's just people need to be stressed,
you know?
Like they need to relax and it's free
and it's accessible.
Hmm.
Um,
and more people enjoy Asmr like,
like nightly,
like they just want to sleep,
I think.
Um,
but I have heard,
and I'm even myself,
like I've used the smr when you feel
like lonely and you just want somebody
talking for a while on a video.
But I mean,
you could do that with any youtube
video.
Yeah.
But there's this kind of the whispering,
you know,
this,
there's a sense of intimacy and like the
ticking it tough.
You know,
it's,
you know,
you know what,
so what does a popular misconception
about asm or that people get wrong?
He want to correct that.
It's not just sexual,
you said,
you said intimacy because it,
I think that we can all agree that it
is,
it's intimate.
Yes.
Um,
but I would say like,
it's more intimate in the way that like,
like when your mom like puts you to bed
and she was like rubbing your back and
singing you a song.
If you wouldn't want a stranger do that
to you,
but it's not sexual.
Um,
and so I think like when somebody gets,
yeah,
I think for a lot of guys it might be,
I do like the idea,
but I don't have a problem.
Yeah,
I agree that it's not only sexual
though,
but I know like with,
and the intern it is like,
no,
I don't want to embarrass you too much
about it,
but uh,
he is a fan of yours.
He was just watching you the other day,
right?
Yeah.
I'm honored in Jewish and he is too
embarrassing on it.
Monica.
Well,
um,
let's move on then.
He'll build up the courage as we could
tell to talk.
So how do you feel about this one would
Cardi B it is very sexual acts are like,
dude,
she was folic,
I dunno how to use given a double blow
jobs as far as I can.
That's an unfortunate microphone shape,
but she was like,
she listens to asm are a lot.
I'm like,
we've,
we've known that before.
Like she's seated.
Yeah.
That's cool.
How,
because you can tell when somebody is
actually seen it before and they get it.
Like it's hard to explain why.
Like I know she gets it,
but she does.
No,
no,
you can't love that.
Um,
do you know what your demographic
between male and female on your
analytics
[inaudible] 60% male,
40% female.
Interesting.
Pretty good spread that it's skewed as
you would think.
Right.
My Mail skews way more than that.
Got like 85% male.
People are watching your videos for you
baby,
you think?
Um,
do you ever get any creepy emails or
tweets from guys that get,
like,
there's gotta be some guys that get like
overly attached with you,
right?
Probably a fringe,
I'm sure about.
So what's the craziest Shit you've seen?
Okay.
There have been a couple people where I
had to like get police involved.
Um,
people are unable to sort of separate
the distinction of like,
I'm speaking to an audience and not to
you specifically.
Um,
I know a lot of people have had that
issue,
not,
it's a lot of like personalities and you
know,
people who talk to their audience and
stuff like that.
But,
uh,
I had this one person who sent me like
tens of thousands of messages before I
even saw it.
Wow.
Where did they sounding as if I was
responding to him.
Oh my goodness.
That must have freaked you out.
That was very freaky.
Where did what,
what a platform where the message is
sent on?
That's facebook messenger.
Ooh.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Like a friend.
Like they were a facebook friend.
Well,
I had a page for it,
CBA tomorrow and people could just send
messages to it,
but I wouldn't get notified.
Um,
wow.
Hazards of the job.
Now finally,
I want to say again in,
is a big fan of you.
Um,
he's,
I mean,
I don't know if you're familiar with,
and he's a big important part of the
show and it's really cool guy.
We like him a lot.
In,
would you like to say anything to a GB?
Harrison's?
We've got her on the phone.
I know you're a fan.
Yeah,
seriously.
In when he was just up the good work.
I can't hear you.
We can't hear you.
They hear you.
Can everyone oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He's like keep up the great work and,
and also,
and also Ian was wondering if you're
single.
I'm not,
I'm so sorry to burst that bubble.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Well we appreciate you.
We,
uh,
I appreciate,
you know,
ken on the phone and talking with us.
Um,
and yeah,
bringing some clarity because it is
interesting.
It's wild.
It's so,
it's weird,
like,
like you acknowledged from the outside.
It's,
it's strange,
but I have to tell you that I do when I
put it on,
you know,
you do kind of,
it is nice.
It is nice.
You know.
Oh,
I wanted to ask you,
I was going to say,
you said you liked it.
Yeah,
yeah,
I do.
Kind of like,
yeah.
And is there a,
do you know if there was a,
the opposite kind?
People hate waste brine.
Okay.
Yes.
I think that's Microphonia.
I think that's,
you know,
there's two types of people in the world
because some people,
you know,
like you,
you hear the sounds and you get like the
tingling feeling and it's like,
oh,
this is really nice.
Some people hear the sounds and they're
like,
I wanna die.
Exactly.
Like me.
Yeah.
The smell period.
Blood or you don't,
yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
Well,
what do you,
you know,
I'm not that.
I feel like I wanna die when I see our
channel.
Not at all,
but my initial reaction will this
trigger.
Yeah.
When I think of someone we spring is
pleasant.
Sure.
Um,
I don't necessarily feel tingles,
but I do feel kind of like a lightness
and a pleasant sensation,
you know?
It's like extra relaxation.
Yeah.
It's nice.
It is nice to hear though.
You're going to do some,
yeah.
A Smr for me to can't,
do you ever do a one like for your
boyfriend?
Would you ever do like a one person Acmr
sesh?
He doesn't get a Smr that was like super
unfortunate.
Oh,
it's like beet red out here.
Well,
I feel like,
um,
that's kind of ironic I guess.
And unfortunate that your boyfriend
doesn't experience any,
some more.
I feel like that's going to expert for a
girl could have been something there.
Yeah,
it could have been some great there,
but it would be interesting to do like a
one person Acmr show or like you could
actually like,
it's almost like a massage in a way.
Like if you have like a,
a a cmr therapy.
Right.
That's interesting.
Why not?
Yeah.
I his growing it exists already.
It exists,
Huh?
Yeah.
That was the smr spa that keeps popping
up.
There's some of that.
And then some in New York it's called
like a whisper lodge I think.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So people are really exploring with it
now and experimenting and doing live
shows and things like that.
Do you think it will ever become
mainstream or is it going to be
something that's always hard to explain
to people?
Cool.
If I compare it to a couple of years
ago,
like it is crazy mainstream now compared
to,
so I think it's really only going,
I'm in because every time it sort of
comes up in the media,
we get more people in the community who
are like,
oh my God,
wait,
this is really relaxing.
Yeah.
We've,
we've even seen like Howard stern talk
about it.
Um,
and all this celebrity doing it.
It's like,
yeah,
as mainstream as he gets not.
Yup.
I wonder if there is anything you'd like
Ai Mar that was so weird,
but now I was like our seemed so weird
but it's now fully accepted by everyone.
Okay.
Right.
A lot of people didn't get like twitch
when I came out.
Like gaming,
like live straight.
They're like,
why would you want to watch somebody
play video games?
Jimmy can make that joke.
And we were like a really tiny like
that.
So all right.
Just last night.
Yeah.
All right.
Oh my God,
that's so weird.
We have got G,
B,
a,
s,
m,
a R,
G,
I b.
I a s Smr.
Check her out.
She is the best in the game.
Um,
I've listened.
It's,
I get,
I feel it's nice.
It's relaxing.
He is a huge,
huge fan and,
um,
we wish you all the very best.
Yeah.
And uh,
thank you by the blessing weekend as
well too.
So thank you for God.
Thank you.
You too.
All right.
Take care.
Appreciate you.
All right.
Bye.
That was g,
b a s m.
R.
And so we learned a lot from GB
dentally.
Yeah.
It was interesting that she acknowledged
that it is because I thought she was
refuting that it's like it is not sexual
or not sexual,
but like intimate or a lot like a lot of
guys are like,
like the intimacy,
not sexual,
but like intimate.
But she did acknowledge that it's that
and it's more,
which I think I agree,
but,
um,
she's a professional,
you know.
Yeah.
So there you go.
There you have it.
Gb a smr.
All right.
Ian,
how was that for you?
Yeah,
like his parents.
That was incredible.
Can't I can't hear him through the
speaker.
Oh,
there you go.
Yeah,
that was incredibly embarrassing.
And I was trying to talk,
it wasn't working.
That didn't help.
But you do find her attractive right in?
I think she's very talented or what she
does great.
Such a diplomat.
He didn't like it's okay though.
But she does have a boyfriend,
Ian.
So we do a lot to you guys for that.
Take it easy.
Um,
she's cool.
Yeah,
moving on.
It makes me wish that I enjoyed it.
I feel like I'm missing out.
Have you tried though?
You know,
I just know that I don't like,
cause I actually,
I gave it like a good shot for five or
10 minutes and I was very pleasant.
It was nice.
And then cause like I was watching like
a cute girl and I was like,
okay,
I'm going to find a dude and I,
and there's this one,
I showed it like a gnarly bearded dude
and he's like insane.
Like he's all over the place and that
guy is like a king.
So I wanted to be like,
all right,
it's not about that.
But yeah,
that guy was,
was just as good.
But also you're not really supposed to
watch it.
You're supposed to just listen.
Right.
Put it in the background.
Yeah.
Let's be frank.
Being cute helps you in any field.
That's true.
If I was more handsome,
you think that I wouldn't have 20
million subscribers if I wasn't more
handsome.
You think that pure that I wouldn't have
more subscribers and cutie pie.
He's handsome.
That's why he has 60 million.
All right.
I mean,
well,
it's well known,
Mike.
When actors the attractive,
they say it.
The first rule of dating,
be attractive.
Second rule of dating.
Don't be unattractive.
Third rule,
ask them if they smile on their period.
Third Rural,
sniff the period blood,
the sniff test as it's called.
Why wasn't there a Seinfeld about period
blood?
Ah,
you're slipping actually.
Well,
the differences about the same.
Eight,
10% yes.
14% no.
Yeah,
six to 8%.
I'm into it.
I love it.
I love that additional amazing.
Um,
all right.
Moving on.
Elon musk is that we've,
this is an incredible story that needs
to be shared with the world.
He was banned recently for two from
twitter because he was shit posting so
hard that twitter was sure he was
hacked,
is security was compromised and they
said there's no way.
These are genuine tweets.
We need to shut this down.
They were real quick.
So let's see,
what was it that got him banned?
He first begins with Iheart anime.
450,000
likes.
I own H G v Wolverine now,
by the way,
did you feel about it?
Cause you're,
you have any man and you're a fan of
everyone.
I love anime.
So do you love him in a more,
even more than Whoa.
He's just shit posting.
I do.
I do like him less and I don't like him
less.
I just think,
I just don't know what,
what's with the tweeting.
I just don't really get him like,
like he's
so I guess I just don't why he's trying
to be like an edge Lord.
All of a sudden it's like a midlife
crisis.
Maybe.
It's like,
dude,
you're the coolest fucking greatest dude
ever.
You don't need to ship post on it.
And I have to try.
Yeah.
You don't need to try.
I mean,
it doesn't make me like,
I think it's funny.
I think.
I think that,
um,
I like him just as much as I ever did.
I love Elon Musk.
Um,
I support him and his company's 100% and
I as well.
I just don't know what,
you know,
it's just a little unnecessary maybe.
But yeah.
And then he tweets his favorite anime.
Love your name.
I haven't actually seen this one,
but apparently it's like a drama.
I don't really like,
um,
who's best.
I don't really like anime dramas.
I like to see that.
Okay.
I like,
like action enemies because for me it's,
I like the fantasy aspect.
I like the magic.
I'm making the power.
That's what I need to watch.
A drama.
Anime.
I can watch drama in any form.
Cartoons.
It's not real.
That's why you get sick ass fucking
magical powers because you can't
actually do that in real life.
Skip.
Um,
so acts that one elon calls himself Ilan
Chan.
Elan musk is a weep and he re re ponds.
Ahem.
Ilan Chan.
What?
I mean like where is he picking up this
terminology?
Just trolls read at all day.
And I'm saying,
well,
like what form is he spending?
Because the problem that,
that makes me concerned is the people
that talk with these kinds of means,
people who like joke around like this
are not the people that I want getting
inside Elan Musk beautiful,
pristine braid,
right?
Like I don't want him spending time on
four Chan or Anamae subreddits.
That's maybe that's what it concerns me.
It's more what it means.
That what he's,
why does he know all this stuff?
Like you can what you can.
I like anime,
but I'm not,
you're not.
And it wouldn't be more fun for me by
the way,
that Elon Musk,
we need his brain to be in good,
clean,
pristine,
beautiful shape,
not Ahem Ilan Chin.
Like wherever he learned that I don't
want him there and I'm not going to
genesis even going.
And that's amazing.
And I'm not,
what'd you say?
I just notice that the meme that I don't
know if he posted or somebody else
below,
but what?
It's an elan below,
you know,
it's uh,
uh,
it was whatever you,
I mean it's whatever.
Okay,
thank you Dan.
Oh,
this,
I don't know that or the origins of this
one.
It's just a pawn off of a famous
animator.
Um,
so ian along continues.
Hey,
what's going on with two factor for
Tesla Account,
which is weird cause it's actually like
a business related question though.
It's not directed to the right place.
So justifiably he says you want to buy
some Bitcoin,
which I think was probably when twitter
was like,
this shit's weird again on,
I don't know where you,
what's going on?
What forms your browsing and we got to
keep your brain beautiful.
Noninfected and I'm not criticizing the
people that do spend their times in that
form.
I'm just saying some people we need to
protect you.
Elon musk is one of those people,
you know,
I'm a cat girl.
What is this shit keeps getting weirder
every time I click here.
Okay.
Show us your bows at cos play.
He says,
actually I'm actually cat girl.
Here's a selfie right now.
Okay.
Now your twitter right now,
what's your call?
Suspend or keep open.
Exactly.
I can see where they came from.
Twitter ends up spending is suspending
as account because he assumed he was
hacked.
And then finally we end on,
um,
send me your dankest memes.
He tweeted what the fuck?
And then pheidippides said meme review
when he said midnight.
I don't think that happened.
Elon Musk.
There you go.
What a world.
What a world we live in.
You know what I'm saying?
My God.
But I will say on the,
on the uh,
on a beautiful positive note of Elan's
Tesla,
the be the most exciting progressive,
um,
risk taking future forward company that
this world has seen in so long.
Tesla,
the automaker of electric cars has
finally become,
they're there.
They have blasted the expectation.
Everyone was expecting them to lose
those,
those money,
they were expected to lose 19 cents per
share.
Their quarterly earnings came in.
It went up $2 and 90 cents per share.
They made a profit for the first time
ever.
Smash expectations.
Model three is become the best selling
car in the United States.
In terms of revenue and the fifth best
selling car in terms of volume,
the most revenue,
best salad car in the United States.
Unbelievable.
The model three.
These guys,
I love Tesla,
everything.
You know what?
I'm so happy that they're making it and
they're making money and they're turning
a profit.
That's pretty amazing.
I mean especially here in La,
you see it everywhere now.
Everywhere.
Dude,
brand new model three is everywhere.
I have a lease on a s N it's open a year
and I'm going to,
I think I'm going to get a model three
but I find it so amazing that as a
company they released the model three
with same features even better and for a
lower price.
The thing is the model three,
the performance version of the model
three is way less than the model s that
I have and it's faster,
has a longer,
any longer battery life.
Which of the two things I care the most
about?
[inaudible] it's a little smaller,
but I don't really give a fuck.
Most people,
but it's more modern.
It's more futuristic.
That's why it's going to be so huge.
The model,
the model three performance is like,
the craziest version you can get is like
$70,000.
I know that's probably sounds like a lot
to most of you,
but comparable cars that go that speed
could be like 10 times that price.
Yeah.
Like a model three,
it goes zero to 60 and like,
um,
like three seconds.
The closest thing of that is like crazy,
like porsches and Maseratis and shit.
You're looking at two or 300,000
plus hours,
70,000
bucks,
and it's got like 320 miles per charge.
But then it's just,
it has so much more,
and this is not a commercial.
No,
everyone knows that I am as long they
don't need to pay anyone how far past
everything else because the auto drive
is so useful and then it's fully
electric.
But the real,
the real thing,
the real genius too is the
infrastructure they've built.
There's so many superchargers now that
you can actually go on a long distance
drive,
which we've done many times and charge
your car fast and reliably.
Is that,
is that the case outside of California?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Just anywhere you can drive across to,
Huh.
You can do a road trip.
That is really impressive.
I mean that's the main,
that's the main hurdle that everybody
cross country for a long time we drove
to vegas and they're adding more and
more every,
you know,
all the time.
But uh,
yeah,
lots of people drive cross country and
their teslas now.
It's wild.
It's really cool.
Um,
so that's cool.
And uh,
and anyway,
I will be sending my dankest memes to
Elon Musk who congratulate him on his
excellent performance.
So,
um,
what else we got here?
I got a lot of videos,
but I'm so fricking owned.
My throat is so fucked.
I wasn't even a show how you were going
to do this.
I wasn't sure either because when we
first started this I was like delirious.
I was saying something to Isla.
She's like,
I don't even understand what you're
telling me right now.
And I was like,
all right,
well let's go live.
I hope you are comfortable talking today
cause I can't,
that it's true.
It really happened.
My throat really hurts.
So I probably shouldn't talk that much
because it's not going to help.
Spending 14 hours at Disney yesterday
was not helpful,
but we were planning that trip for a
year so I would be,
God damn if I wasn't going.
Um,
let me see.
I'll save this stuff for next week and
hopefully maybe we could get tom and
Christina next week.
Oh yeah,
that'll totally reschedule cause I saw
some people worry.
I hope we can do it next week because I
have so many great videos I want to
watch with them.
Um,
I've got questions but a lot of them,
more videos.
Um,
the period blood we talked about,
obviously,
congratulations.
What is this one?
Well I think technique,
this guy said this was funny from that
by the way.
Questions,
videos,
suggestions,
anything.
Send them to
podcast@hthreehthreeproductions.com.
Love to hear from you guys.
This one comes from Andrew Bentley.
He said he learned about the wiping
technique and he tried it out.
But unfortunately on my third try with
front wiping it ended in such tragedy
had revert back to back wiping while I
was trying to utilize the scoop
technique.
Um,
my,
my wrist accidentally make contact with
Poo Poo,
pee water.
And needless to say,
it's solidified my trust and the tried
and true method of bandwidth.
And how do you get,
he says,
unfortunately I have to conclude Ethan's
wiping method is too dangerous.
Second.
Well what the fuck?
How deep are yapping?
Like when I not,
when I say you have to lift your balls.
I'm not kidding dude.
Do you have to like lean back though?
No.
Do you cup your balls when you wipe for
a back to front on a little unit but you
grow.
I mean you have to like grab your Dick
and balls right in one hand you can go
around and doesn't not like talking.
Well,
the way I do it because I live my junk
with one hand,
I stretch it up and I,
I don't dunk into the toilet,
that's for sure.
I mean,
yeah,
obviously keep your hand out of the
toilet bowl,
dude.
I mean my God,
the mechanic we need,
we need to like get a life sized
mannequin and like have like a full on
demonstration.
Don't need a mannequin.
I'll show you right now.
You bring this up and you just,
you scoop right under like that.
You got your leg up right now though.
And see this is one of in objects.
He's actually,
he's got a different technique.
Do you want to come show us the yet come
show us.
Come in here cause he in.
Oh God,
you're,
yeah,
you're being so lamb come shows how you
wipe your ass.
Come on,
get in here.
Why do your legs and then side around
you go directly under.
Wait,
what?
How do you go?
You Go,
you go under the balls.
I spread the legs wider and go around
round.
He goes around the mountain like crimp
here.
Sure.
Come show us.
Come on.
I'm genuinely curious.
This is the science episode.
You're shaking his head.
No way too embarrassed.
I'm not blaming you.
Hold on.
Okay,
well at least let me understand because
now I'm intrigued.
You go from like this?
No,
you go from the front.
So you come like from like this,
I can't see,
oh you open your wet legs,
wider leg like super wide.
Right,
right,
right.
And you don't go under him.
You go around them,
you sit like super while you got
homework to do it.
Wait,
hold on.
Do Shit with your legs that wide.
That's a wide stance he got.
I don't go that wide.
Oh I understand.
So you scope it your Dick and balls to
like the left because I put them up
against my gut and you say Whoa,
I'm trying to understanding cause you're
not coming in here and showing me.
All right.
I'm tired of playing pictionary with to
the solidarity between the front wipers.
Is is cracking.
You're the worst uh,
pictionary partner I've ever had
switching to back after that.
No.
All right,
well I've got a conversion.
He gets mad at me today.
Embarrassed and a little bit,
but um,
her boyfriend doesn't even feel Acmr III
and so there is a chance and I think I
did lay a skewed either shaking her
head.
I'm very disappointed.
I what else we got.
So that's about it.
I have a lot of other submissions,
but I think I'll save it with the
hopeful,
hopeful that Tom and Christina will come
next week.
So again,
uh,
somewhat,
um,
light episode.
I'm very sick.
I should stop talking immediately and
get in bed.
You are a champion for powering through
this too.
When you walked in today,
I took one look at,
he was like,
fuck that dude is,
it should be in bed.
Right.
Thank you for saying that Dan.
The show must go on.
You know,
the show must go on and I'm,
and I appreciate everybody who tuned in
on this blessing lesson Friday and I
appreciate all the boys and back who I
want to always express my appreciation
to Dan,
the producer and interns,
Zach the sound boy,
love them all.
They're all work so hard to make the
show great.
And uh,
you know,
cheers to them and I hope that in with
the his new,
I think there's this,
I think there was a spark between him
and Juvie.
I really do.
So I'm looking forward to see how that
develops.
End Up lesson blessing weekend.
It's Friday.
My Dude's.
Yeah,
it's a beautiful thing.
And of course,
huge appreciation.
So all you Ngozi boys who come and spend
your day with us.
I hope I've entertained too.
I hope you've laughed.
Hope you've thought I did not intend to
make you cry.
So I hope you didn't cry,
but if you did,
I don't know why it wasn't my fault.
Here's a boy tears of joy from laughing
so hard and enjoying herself so much.
All right.
Make sure to burp rag.
Hit me with it.
So here it comes.
Here it comes.
Really ant,
can you,
can you crank it?
That was such a great video discovery.
It's crazy.
Oh,
all right guys.
Have a blessed weekend and we shall see
you next week.
Right here on your favorite podcast is
the music plane.
Oh yeah.
The,
your favorite.
The h three podcast.
The only place where we do science and
we take polls and we're getting to the
bottom of it.
Real Science,
real science,
real people.
I've said it all.
That is
they.
Bye everybody.