Five four,
three,
two.
Welcome to the age three podcasts
extravaganza.
That's right.
We're an extravaganza now.
Thank you to 23 and me,
postmates and hymns for sponsoring us
and thank you to everybody for joining
us today on this beautiful blessing frat
boy.
Do I love Fridays.
We started taking the weekends off and I
just get cut it on Fridays now.
Happy Friday to everyone watching.
We've got a lot to discuss today.
We're very excited.
We've got some Shane up dates,
we've got some Papa John Updates.
We've got uh,
some bouffy updates.
We've talked previously about a Gugu for
goofus slap,
slap,
boop,
a slap.
And Ian,
the intern has prepared for us one of
his notorious much celebrated powerpoint
presentation on Dis ciphering,
the meaning of Kanye West.
Wow.
That's a big task.
But I know it was up for it.
But before we get into all of that,
I've got a little announcement.
Not really an announcement,
just something I wanted to talk about.
But it may be that Ila is,
is there's a new thing of the
thickening.
It was going to be thickening up here
soon.
What does that mean?
What I'm trying to say is that Isla
won't be drinking alcohol if she's
responsible.
What I'm trying to say?
Read podcasts.
Extravagant.
That's me.
Sorry.
Oh Jeez.
How long was that going?
Oh,
it just start like just now.
You turned it off immediately and
flashback like,
no,
he lives,
there's two stripes.
She's cooking something up.
Anyone?
It's a cinnamon roll with rostain man
Ula.
It's weird.
Just Bro.
He loves,
uh,
there's something going on.
So we did it.
Well it's,
we,
we don't know yet if anything's gonna go
wrong.
She's pregnant.
You look pregnant.
I have been,
I've been wording
and Isla for a year.
I mean,
I'm just going frankly,
like a,
we've been to,
I've been,
you know what I'm saying?
It's been on,
we've talked about it a lot on the
podcast.
So it's a natural extension of our core,
of our efforts to get Ila knocked up.
And I have been a fully unchaste about
two years.
Dick has been out
and wording.
We did the test,
we did everything.
But I'll say that we got,
it happened naturally and just the good
old fashioned way you had sex grubs.
Yeah,
I know.
I know it is gross.
I Dunno.
I don't know.
I don't know how to feel about it.
Well,
just like two days ago,
two days ago we found out and Ila,
she will admit was a couple days late on
her period and her boobs,
Eh,
were Ra.
How would you say tender?
What your boobs were tender.
It just hurts.
I don't know yet.
Some tender as pity.
But anyway,
that's like what happens when you're
getting the period and I remember it was
like a week earlier like,
oh,
I'm getting my period not happening.
And I was like,
what is going on?
And the night before I was like,
maybe you're pregnant jokingly.
Yeah.
And I was like,
actually I already checked on it was
negative,
but it wasn't your first idea of the
Morgan do it.
Right?
Yeah.
But it's interesting because the last
two months we kind of doing really try,
we're like,
fuck this shit,
whatever.
If it happens,
it happens and we're just not going to
pay attention.
Of course.
That's when it happened.
So funny.
Yeah,
of course.
And I don't know how to feel about it.
I'm scared.
I don't know how to feel about it.
It's terrifying.
I'm more scared than you because you got
to shit it.
I I'm not,
I have utmost respect for that.
I'm telling you that the,
and people always say like don't tell
until,
I dunno.
I mean Israel even four months,
I don't know.
It's like,
but then you're going to see that I'm
pregnant.
Like it was just superstitious,
you know,
or,
but you had a really good point about
maybe something will go wrong,
but it's like if that happens then what?
I'm not supposed to talk about it.
Like it's a secret like,
yeah,
exactly.
You just carry this like sad thing you
can do and you don't tell.
I guess the theory is I think first of
all,
people are superstitious.
Second of all,
for those that don't know,
in the first like,
I dunno,
a couple of months,
it's very common that you could have a
miscarriage and I didn't move.
Yeah.
Because it's like you don't talk about
it.
Why not talk about it?
Like you'll say when you were sick,
you'll talk about it.
Yeah.
Or if you have to do a surgery.
So why is it that I'm like,
oh,
you're right.
And it's a,
it's a sad thing.
It's a vulnerable thing and it's kind of
sucks to just carry that sound.
Okay with you.
I mean,
but I,
I guess the theory is that yeah,
people would probably just are
superstitious about it and then you
have,
maybe it happens,
sometimes people have like many
miscarriages.
It could happen like five times and
you're like,
oh fuck,
I got to do this whole thing.
Like the whole congratulate were not
pregnant.
We're pregnant,
we're not
putting,
you know,
but I'm,
Isla approached me a couple of days ago
and she's like,
I was in bed just looking at the news or
something.
She's like,
eat.
Then we got a problem something.
And I didn't answer for a minute
listening.
I'll just kind of groggy and he said
something like two stripes.
And I was like,
what?
No Way.
Yeah.
When I did the test I felt like,
I felt like there's no way.
I'm like,
Oh yeah,
we've been trying for a while.
You know the boys can swim.
It's good to know though,
because it was kind of where I was
worried that,
um,
we don't,
you worry.
That's what,
well,
what's wrong?
What's going on?
You know,
why can't I,
why can't,
why can't they get in there taking birth
control like maybe almost two years ago
at this point?
So it could be,
that can take a while,
you know?
But,
uh,
so my,
so it worked.
The boys can swim,
the girls can catch and the team is
functioning.
You know,
Ella started like a week ago before we
knew she was preggo.
She's like,
I'm hungry.
Like,
yeah,
she started eating,
she had pizza and she's like,
and I have to tell you this,
this was shitty pizza.
And I'm not one to say that because
pizza and my opinions like sex,
when it's good,
it's great and when it's bad it's pretty
good.
But I'm like,
this pizza is kind of sucky.
And he was like,
really?
This is the best pizza I've ever had.
And I'm just like,
are you feeling okay?
This piece is not that good.
I don't know why you tripping about it.
But I think ilos starting to get getting
hungry.
Hm.
I don't know if it's even happens that
early,
but I can't,
I haven't been,
I don't know.
You said you feel something going on in
your stomach?
Yeah,
I feel like things are moving in my
stomach.
It's a fucking baby dude.
So anyway,
so guys don't tell anyone,
don't tell anyone please til 10 weeks.
So between all of us,
um,
and I don't know how to feel about it.
I mean we've been trying for a while,
but I was like just so used to not
getting pregnant.
I was like,
oh cool.
cool man,
fuck that shit.
But now I'm like,
I take care of a kid when I'm so
dysfunctional.
Isla believes in me and that's all that
matters.
Well,
anyway,
give us pregnant.
So there you have it at long.
Yes,
yes.
Thank you.
That is true.
That's how I feel.
Uh,
so we thought we'd share that happy news
with everybody and thank you for joining
us on this blessing Friday to share
these beautiful,
wonderful news.
Me inside internally.
No,
I'm kidding.
Um,
let's move on.
We've got Shane now the shame
documentary.
We had talked about it in a previous
episode and I give Shane all the credit
in the world.
I mean,
this guy has pioneered a new form of
content on you.
Okay.
And he's got this incredible fan base
and he,
the numbers are just like unpressed.
Unbelievable.
You had like 10 to 20 million that has
600,000
lights
on a tweet.
Yeah.
What is going on?
Yeah,
it's wild.
So I mean,
obviously hats off to the,
to the guy.
He's a friend of the show.
Even though,
even though,
even though he betrayed me after awhile.
Okay,
cut.
We're not yet.
We'll get there.
Yeah.
Not yet.
Let's at least get into a little bit
before the possible father.
Yeah,
exactly.
Reliving the memory of that great
betrayal.
Anyway,
so he goes on.
As we touched on in the last episode,
the chain starts exploring this theory.
What if Logan is the sociopath and Jake
is living in the shadow of Logan.
The sociopath took a weird turn.
We're just all became about who is a
sociopath.
Then like,
well the next episode was him sitting
for like 40 or 50 minutes with a
therapist
and
super dramatic kind of,
okay.
She's really dramatic,
kind of trying to diagnose him.
And
Anyway,
Logan Paul made a response video and I
mean a lot of people have been
criticizing Shane for his kind of,
the way that he's been trying to
diagnose him.
Um,
cause he does this funny,
anything that's there,
him and his editor are really good at
where they created this like a whore.
They create an atmosphere and a tension
in the editing is very good.
They're good at it,
but it's like you're also talking about
something serious.
You're talking about person,
you're talking about mental health.
And we know Paul Logan.
Paul,
which are like the two,
you know,
dom,
Youtube.
But regardless,
I'm not even trying to make a serious
point about chain.
I don't,
I honestly,
I'm not here to refute or talk about
any,
I honestly,
Logan Paul made a response video and
it's given us,
us all here,
one of the best gems that have ever come
across this platform.
And so this to me was what was most
important to share with you guys.
Um,
I'll let logan speak for himself now.
He,
he goes on the record,
he's,
and he actually says,
I'm not a sociopath,
but I do have sociopathic tendencies,
which is interesting.
It sounds like he's been diagnosed the
way he talks about it because he's very
knowledgeable and he goes,
you're not either a sociopath or not a
sociopath is it's a sliding scale.
And some people have more sociopathic
tendencies.
Yeah.
Others.
Um,
but he goes on to say something that
really resonated with me and made me
really understand what he meant by that.
So I'll share it with you guys now.
It or sociopathic mark jobs.
Nope.
Steve Zuckerberg,
Mark Zuckerberg and Steve Jobs.
A lot of people,
especially youtube tubers and Shane
touched on this,
you can't just say like you're a
sociopath.
The word I would like to use is
sociopathic tendencies.
A lot of us,
me included,
we'll do some dumb shit.
Maybe some stuff that lacks empathy
strictly for views,
right?
It gets US views which gets us
subscribers are motivating factor.
If it's to reach the next,
next,
next level.
Sociopath is boiled down.
Someone who is just more savage then
everyone else.
I know it sounds
so that's it.
I mean that's pretty much a clinical
definition of sociopath.
Somebody who is more savage than
everybody else.
And um,
I think Logan for that definition and I
just think,
and I'm just happy that that's in the
world.
Logan Paul saying it's just someone
that's more savage than everybody else.
Dabble.
Dab.
Double Dab will do.
Yeah.
Motivating factor if it's to reach the
next,
next level.
Sociopath is boiled down.
Someone who is just more savage than
everyone else.
I know,
I've just,
I have a,
I have trouble with that.
I'm having trouble with that comparison
cause he's always making it cool for his
friends because they're always like
Saburn yeah.
That's what savage means.
Cool.
Right.
His world.
So a Sociopath I think Aka ace,
antisocial personality disorder,
which is someone that lacks empathy.
Someone who has a general,
I mean I again,
I'm not going to,
it's not an,
it's not generally,
it's not,
I want to call it sad.
I won't call it savage necessarily.
You know,
maybe a psycho.
And then Ethan,
did you go through psychology school?
Cause I am not a,
I'm not a trained professional because I
don't know savage sounds to me it does
sound very clinical.
Yeah.
That it sounds like something you'd hear
in a classroom.
Um,
this whole argument though,
that between him and Shane,
like it's just,
I feel like we shouldn't be this whole
thing about self-diagnosing and I feel
like even Logan's definition is wrong.
Cause I was trying to read about it
online and educate myself a little bit
before I came and did this podcast.
And apparently sociopathy isn't even a
clinical term.
The real clinical term is antisocial
personality disorder.
And it's just this whole messy thing.
I don't like that.
It's just,
I dunno
everyone always just google lang and
self diagnosis.
Yeah.
And like,
but anyway,
Logan's defending himself.
He does make a lot of good points in
here,
but I'm a sociopath is basically someone
that's more savage.
So to add that to the Wiki page.
Yeah.
Essentially we need to add that to the
clinical definition of,
but it's someone that lacks empathy,
so much,
very manipulative.
Someone that doesn't mean they lack
empathy,
they cannot relate with human emotion.
So it enables them to do more callous
things that many of us will not feel
comfortable doing from an empathetic
standpoint.
And so I guess that would make them
literally more savage and a psychopath,
which is a problem.
Shane kept saying a sociopath and a
psychopath of the same thing and
applying,
I don't think he said it's the same
thing,
but he wasn't very clean and very like
it kept mixing them up at some point,
which is,
well he would say sociopath and then he
would show psychopath on the screen and
like someone with a knife.
So I was reading about this,
trying to figure out what is the
difference.
So actually all psychopaths are
sociopaths,
but a psychopath is a more severe,
um,
version of a sociopath.
They tend to be more violent,
they tend to be more criminal and they
tend to be more ruthless.
A sociopath can still have bonds with
like family members and strong friends,
but random people and did the meet on
the street.
They do not have any empathy for it all.
So there is a distinction,
but this implication that they're all,
you know,
creepy murders is not,
is not true.
But at any rate,
um,
at any rate,
that's that.
Then there was a part at the end of
Shane's new,
I've,
I,
I'm checking out on this,
on this documentary.
Honestly,
it's so long.
It's too,
it's a lot.
But this part made me uncomfortable.
I'm not going to lie.
So he's teasing.
This one's called the enemies of Jake
Paul and he is teasing.
And the next episode,
this therapist that he sat down with is
going to go undercover as a producer.
Secretly.
They're not going to tell Jake Paul so
that she can study him all day and make
a diagnosis of him.
It seems kind of unethical.
It's just,
I mean if was all here,
here,
here it is.
I mean I,
the whole thing is making me
uncomfortable.
Honestly.
Shane does acknowledge that.
I mean he knows that it's weird that
still's going to do it.
But anyway,
here it is
and she's there the whole time.
I don't think he's going to be like,
I don't think it's going to be
comfortable.
I think he's going to be kind of fake.
So I came up with a plan is I'm going to
the therapist to be,
he's going to be the whole day watching,
listening.
I love to shop,
wash this body language like a corner of
her eye.
Like that's how she makes her diagnosis.
Like she's,
this is her all day.
I just love the image of this therapist
with them all day like this.
Just looking at the side of her vision
at them anyway.
It's pretty with straight.
I don't know man.
It's shit strange.
Like,
I mean,
so here you,
it's like when the camera turns off
throughout the day,
she's going to take me to another room.
Jake will have no idea.
And then we'll go on to the of the room.
I'll just be like going,
what do you think?
Well first of all,
let me say this g specifically.
There you go.
I Dunno.
It's weird.
It like,
I feel like it's unnecessary because if
you,
if she went like jake would still be
himself over a long day,
you know,
if they're at his house,
well you'll put on a show for like five
minutes,
but eventually it'll be himself.
A sociopath apparently is capable and
well aware of the facade that they put
on.
Actually what I read is that a
psychopath,
so a sociopath generally is more messy
and how they present themselves to the
world.
But a psychopath is extremely efficient
that they can have a mask up all the
time,
even under stress and duress so that
they never let their guard down.
Yeah.
So it is one of the attributes.
But that being said,
I really don't think Jerry is like,
I really don't think jake is a sociopath
talking about Jake Paul.
Yeah,
I,
the thing is he didn't really need this
whole angle.
I would have been interested at just
one,
a really sincere look and to Jake Paul's
life.
Like I don't know why they were down.
Yeah.
I don't know that we needed this really
dramatic angle of sociopathy.
Yeah,
yeah.
Cutie pie made a video about it.
He made some good points about a really
long video,
but he was like,
when they were talking about sociopathy,
him and the therapist were saying that
it was like icky and gross,
I guess.
I don't know what do I know?
But it's getting bizarre.
It's a wild ride,
man.
This is some wild new territory here.
People are loving it.
Yeah.
And the thing is,
it's Jake Paul,
so it's hard for anyone to be like,
it's very difficult to ever take cake or
logan site.
Like Logan made a very reasonable
response to two chainz video and it has
like,
firstly,
yeah,
he did.
Like I was,
I was feeling kind of bad that like here
they're down.
Votes is like 130,000
down and he didn't really say anything
or did they have a downvote personally?
My pain,
that's the world we live in.
That's the tube we tube in and so uh,
I'm not going to lie.
I'm going to watch it.
It seems unethical but I'm going to
watch the fuck out of it.
What else?
We got Kevin.
Ugh,
Kevin on this fucking guy,
this cabinet guy.
He's trying to get on the supreme court
again,
there's a lot of politics going on here.
You guys probably heard of Kevin Hawk
and how he was accused of all this.
A sexual misconduct which is sexual
misconduct.
That's a nice way of saying rape kind
of,
but regardless of what he did or didn't
do,
I don't know.
My only interest in this,
my friends is the fact that they are
arguing over what is a booth now goofing
is a big part of this show.
As you may recall,
we have been trying to get to the bottom
of what a booth is for a long time.
I feel bad for that.
Right into the equation.
A booth and a goof and a gaf is alive.
What happens if you booth a goof?
Now we were wondering what's a booth and
Eric from common etiquette came in with
a definition as we were wondering what
is a boob?
And I look it up,
it's not actually a word,
but you found it on urban dictionary the
best,
which is the perfect place to define
something like this apparently,
and correct me if your definition is
wrong,
it's when you shove drugs up your ass,
when you go to a rave or dance party,
you boost it in.
We're on the same page.
So actually I've got to revive that
definitional that I'm pretty sure it
means taking drugs up the ass because
what I've heard,
yeah,
because apparently the,
the anus,
the colon is very absorbed.
Absorbative absorbative and so drinking
is like,
you know,
and it's like you're doing an Ama,
we'd all be like this,
you know,
this man where it's like I sleep,
I am awake.
So drinking alcohol in the mouth,
I sleep booping alcohol and your ass.
I'm awake.
Yes.
So basically the,
the aim anus sucks and as way more
membrane.
So if you're taking any kind of elicit
drug,
you put it up the ass boy and you all
going to be get taken that one rate,
right ticket to Valhalla.
If you're willing to do that,
you don't have to taste it.
You don't have to encounter any beds.
You just boof it right up there.
What do you shotgun a beer up your ass.
I don't know how that works.
I heard there was kids that were dipping
vodka or tampons in vodka and then
shoving it up their ass.
They get drunk.
It's like she's just drinking his
drinking.
Um,
but apparently you get drunk quicker and
it's a pleasant experience.
But I just,
I love,
you know,
postman is really good at shotgunning
beers.
I don't know how fast you can boot it.
Didn't a friend of the show Steevo uh,
in one of those jackass movies moved to
a beer out of like a beer bong.
That's what I'd like to see post malone
done.
I think that's the next rockstar that,
um,
I just like to imagine someone on their
back with their cheeks out in a bunch of
Bros shoving that tube up.
Dude's ass and vaseline ended up by tyra
banks and I'm just boof and a beer right
up the stink hall.
What was their ranks doing?
She's the vaseline goddess.
Shannon,
your picture of she,
they use vaseline from her.
It's the good stuff.
Yeah.
If,
if Austin is going to be goofing any
beers,
I want to make sure he gets the best
vaseline to lube that Ayn is up because
that's obvious.
So much easier than drinking it.
But at any rate,
let's watch,
let's watch a future Supreme Court
justice discuss boofy and this is the
greatest time.
What have you,
I don't know if it's booked or buffed
files.
Do you pronounce that Trevor?
First of flatulence?
No,
it does not refer to flashlights a.
We all know,
even if you support this guy,
you know that this guy is not talking
about flatulence.
So fights,
alliances,
the farm when in and guys,
and again,
I'm not taking sides.
I'm not throwing my shit.
I don't,
I'm so over politics.
Okay,
I'm here for the boots and the boots,
but we all know,
all of us watching,
even those of you who support cavenaugh
and everything he does,
you know,
whatever.
What the fuck ever.
You know what a booth is
and this man,
did they ever get to what a goof is?
They didn't ask that.
Michelle was there.
I'd tell them what is a goof?
Define a goof.
It's Kinda hard to define.
It's a laugh.
Giggle,
giggle.
Um,
this guy,
if he goes down for lying about what a
boof is,
perjury.
Now we've made America great again.
I mean,
he lied to the Senate.
right here.
We all know what a brewery,
right?
It's perjury of the highest order.
We've all,
everyone here who is a fan of this
podcast and listens here on regular
basis in your deposition that they asked
you to define what a meme is very
similar moment.
Meme is kind of hard to define.
A booth has a very literal definition is
not a flatulence.
Flatulence.
No,
it does not,
but I'm saying that we've all here
who've been a fan of washed along and
learned along with us.
We all learned together.
What is goofing.
Yeah,
and this judge who wants to sit on the
highest court in the world,
he committed perjury over what it means
to put beer up his ass.
He should go down for that.
I'm saying if you're showing us like,
I haven't ever heard that he's a nice
word for partying.
Yeah.
He's went to Yale so he's not allowed to
say fart.
He has to say flatulence,
but what have you.
It's just like that's when you put up
your ass that the,
because they'd be like,
look,
I was 15 I was 16 years old.
We were young boys.
It's a joke.
It's what happens is putting beer up
your ass and get him more credit.
Would people be like,
that guy's telling the fucking truth.
You wouldn't lie about that.
I mean,
I guess he was trying to be more for
him.
He kept trying to downplay his drinking.
So that's what it was.
He's always trying to be like,
oh,
nothing.
And there has anything to do with
drinking.
Look Dude,
you put some,
you,
you took some beer up the ass.
I get it,
man.
We're all trying to have fun.
You were a young man at the time.
Yup.
By the way,
this guy's name is Mr.
White House.
I wonder what kind of job that goes
after my jam in a president called Mr.
White House President White House.
This just in from the White House.
Like a papa,
John,
Papa Johns,
Papa John.
Dot.
Anyway,
I just loved that booth thing has been
the center of a national controversy and
uh,
I had to acknowledge it.
So judge,
hmm shouldn't have lied about the booth
thing.
First of flatulence with does not.
Absolutely does not.
And everyone listening you've got damn
well.
No it does not.
So up next we've got Ian,
the intern,
the wonderful beloved by all.
He has got a presentation.
Kanye has been all over the news.
People I've been waiting.
Yeah,
Connie's been up to a lot.
And you guys may not know this about Ian
to intern,
but um,
he is a huge Kanye fan.
He is a,
he's actually even written a screenplay
about Kanye is life.
Yeah.
I didn't know that.
You didn't know that.
No,
he's,
he is.
I mean he's obsessed.
It's a little weird.
So he is calm with a presentation and
I'm super excited.
I mean everything inputs together as
gold after that,
that's coming up after the break.
Then we've got papa John Update.
We've got all kinds of fun stuff
including this.
Check this out.
John operates on my favorite updates.
Oh God.
Every time it's amazing.
And this time is no exception.
A dream cruise on Australia was ruined
by 1300 Indian men partying from a
tobacco company that brought playboy
bunnies with them and ruin the boat ride
for everybody.
We've got footage,
we got everything you need to enjoy that
story so we're going to throw it to a
commercial break and when we come back
in,
your boy is going to be here with all
the Kanye updates that you could ever
want and so much more.
Stay tuned.
23 and me is a DNA testing service that
can offer insights into your ancestry
health,
wellness and traits.
My dudes,
I love this thing man.
You spit in a cup.
Yes,
send it off.
Some dude in a office throws it in his
mouth and then he tells you everything
you need to know about you.
I'm just kidding.
I don't think that's how they do it,
but you do spit in a vial,
you send it off to a bunch of
scientists,
they crunched the numbers and they tell
you all this interesting stuff about
you,
like your weight,
your sleep quality,
caffeine intake,
sense of taste,
whether you are likely to be lactose
intolerant and so much and if you're
likely to die from Alzheimer's or not,
which is a really fun one,
but it's good.
It's good to know and it's easy to do.
Um,
the bitter taste report.
Here's some interesting ones.
Do you prefer sweet or salty foods?
DNA could play a role in determining
your food preferences.
That's interesting.
Sleep report.
Are you a deep sleeper?
Are You a light sleeper?
Are you likely to move during your
sleep?
It's all in that vial of spit folks.
Saturated fat weight report based on
your genetics May,
are you likely to be a big fat,
fatty,
fat,
fat?
Or like Elan,
he's skinny.
We have different,
uh,
does imagines and frankly it's not,
it's not your fault.
You remember that scene from goodwill
hunting?
That's,
that's 23 and meets with their hand on
my shoulder going,
ethan is not your fault.
It's not your fault.
I'm lactose intolerant.
Hey,
they got it all and so much more.
They're gonna tell you about what your
background is from you.
Geographical background,
yet.
Dallian you're fragile.
What are you,
let's find out.
I get Dallian.
Let's find out right now.
Head on over to 23 and me.
This is interesting,
fascinating stuff.
You're going to learn all about
yourself.
It's so awesome.
Go to [inaudible] 23 and me.com/h
three that's two three the numbers two
three and me.com/h
three imaginal world where on your phone
you can order anything you want at
anytime of the day,
any day of the year.
That's what postmates gives you.
That's the power of postmates.
I love postmates.
It's the best thing that's ever been
invented.
Here's how it works.
You just download the APP 24 hours a
day,
three 65 year post,
which will bring you whatever you want
within that hour.
You can even see where your food is and
track your driver to make sure there's
no effin funny be business like a
personal assistant.
It's basically,
yeah,
a freelance personal assistance.
That's right.
You'll have a very good analogy.
You forgot eggs.
You forgot milk.
No effin problem craving a tasty burger.
Check.
Looking for some beer,
some cigarettes.
You know what I mean?
That's just,
it's nice when you're like,
man,
I'm,
I'm drunk and I'm at home.
I want a frozen pizza and some
cigarettes.
That's what postmates is all about.
Oh,
I want some for on this food APP,
but my favorite restaurant doesn't
deliver.
Postmates does every time.
All right.
Postmates is your new longterm munchies
booty call.
They wrote that,
not me.
I just want to make that clear,
but it's a good point.
That's a good analogy.
You do not get to fuck your driver
though.
That is not part of the deal.
So for limited time,
postmates is giving you $100 of free
delivery credit for your first seven
days.
So just start your free deliveries.
Download the APP today and use code h
three that's code h three for $100 of
free delivery credit for your first
seven days.
Save the Hassle and get the food you
love fast at boats,
mates with code h three listen,
sometimes we can all use a little help
and some people more than others.
Okay.
Here's what's the deal.
Sexual performance issues,
it's more common than you think.
Over 25% of new ed cases are guys under
the age of 40 and 40% of men by age 40
struggle with not being able to get
their dick rock hard like they used to
be able to get it and even the world's
greatest actors can't fake one.
That's right.
Even Tom Cruise can't fake having an
erection.
I don't know why Tom Cruise,
he's not the best actor in the role.
A Marlin,
who is the best actor in the world?
He can't fake interaction.
Why do you guys,
he doesn't need help.
Get an erection.
I got rocks around rock hard.
Why do guys turn a word selections or do
nothing when they can turn to medicine
and science?
My dudes,
this is the real deal.
We've got well known generic equivalents
to name red prescription to help you
combat and fight this erectile
dysfunction epidemic.
We as men need our dicks rock hard and
ready to fuck.
Okay.
These are prescriptions backed by
science.
There's no waiting.
There's no awkward in person.
Doctor Visit Zillow wides.
You're saving hours by going to
[inaudible] dot com slash h three it's
so easy.
Sorry.
It's h three Ed.
It's so easy.
Answer a few quick questions and chat
with a doctor for confidential review.
Products are shipped directly to your
door.
Severe Ed isn't just an issue for rich
old guys in bath tubs.
Why are they in bath time?
It affects men's in their thirties and
their forties doing whatever you do.
I don't,
I don't take a bath.
I don't know.
I haven't taken a bath as I was five.
Being your best means performing your
best.
It's a wreck tile without the
dysfunction.
Folks made hard.
Say stay hard.
Say hello to your foot.
A little friend by going to uh,
by going to four hymns for him.
s.com/h
three e d n.
Today.
You can try a month's supply for just $5
will get you started for just five bucks
while supplies last.
So see the website for all details.
This would usually cost you hundreds of
bucks.
Went to the doctor or the pharmacy.
That's for him.
[inaudible] dot com slash age three and
get your Dick Rock fucking art.
Welcome back everybody.
We're here with and the intern who has
prepared with us another of his classic
powerpoint presentations.
Thank you so much him for taking the
time,
but that together for us.
How are you?
I'm doing good.
I've been working on this a long,
long day.
It's your life at work.
It's the culmination of your life's work
emission of a full 24 hours for sure.
Are you are a Kanye mega fan,
is that correct to say?
Yeah,
I'd probably say top 100 top 100 fans in
the world.
I'd say so.
That's wow.
So if you know anyone disputes that you
tried to try me.
So the only way you be a bigger fan,
it's kind of by stocking him and waiting
outside his house and attempting to
murder and wearing his skin.
Yeah.
So you're,
you're just one step under us.
A psychopathic murderer.
Excellent.
Good.
Now what is it about sociopaths?
We shouldn't get any of that.
Yeah.
Now's not the time or place.
He lives at therapist spying on you,
but you gotta give me the side load.
Yeah.
Um,
now tell me,
what is it about Connie,
that intro?
Do you,
well,
let me see.
Are you fans of anyone else who has
Kanye?
Like he's your guy.
There's a lot of people I like,
but he's definitely,
he's your guy.
And what is it about Kanye that,
that you love so much that he's probably
the only person in pop culture that I
get close to sing like role model.
He's a role model.
What are the attributes that you look up
to of his,
like how his blame honesty that gets him
in a lot of trouble,
but he feels like one of the only
authentic,
like everything he thinks,
even though,
you know,
some of it is stupid,
he doesn't hesitate to let you know all
of his flaws or elders issues.
And that's more relatable to me than
everyone else.
He's authentic.
You're like,
yeah,
definitely.
And we see all the faults and the cracks
and all of that,
and it's,
it's like,
you know,
everyone's like that,
but he's like one of the few brave
enough to be like,
yeah,
this is,
this is how I am.
And I'm kind of,
you know,
and you're a fan of his music obviously.
Yeah,
no,
he's great.
He's your favorite musician as well as
artists.
Yeah.
I love this.
Have you seen his sex tape?
Wait,
he never made any,
oh,
did you?
Have you seen a sex tape?
Yeah.
What do you think about it and had good,
good.
It's not that good.
And all these celebrity sex takes are so
underrated.
It's like,
do you think that she,
and they intentionally released that
right eye?
It's like,
not quite sure,
but it's true that that sex tape was
kind of what put her on the map.
Right.
It definitely helped before that.
And then she was really close with Paris
Hilton and was around in those circles
and stuff.
I think I saw on porn hub that the Kim
Kardashians sex tape has like over a
hundred million views and crazy.
Yeah.
No,
it's like massive on there.
It's pretty wild.
Um,
okay.
You've seen it.
Yeah.
I mean,
okay.
Yeah.
That's good.
I don't know if I've seen it.
I mean,
you're not missing much.
It's just,
it's a lot of like Dude Pov,
right?
Yeah.
It's just,
it's bad angles.
You just can't really enjoy the show as
they say.
How many times have you watched it?
More than often?
Just every once in a while.
No,
not even recently.
I like multiple times.
Well,
no,
I respect Kim and the fans.
You don't watch it anymore,
but before,
how many times have you seen it?
More than five times or less than five
times less?
Be Honest.
Honestly,
I'd say less.
I would tell you the truth.
Like three,
three,
four,
four and a half?
Yeah.
Well,
obviously has,
I mean you have to be crazy to watch the
whole thing.
Um,
and are you a fan of Kim Kardashian as
much as Anya?
Not as nowhere near,
but I've come to like her through.
Do you see what he finds him?
Her like the,
yeah.
What is fine?
I'm serious.
Well that's another,
both of these people are so hated,
like vitriolic,
like fury.
And I think it's,
it's a,
you know,
a little unnecessary.
She's like everything she just did,
getting that woman out of prison.
That was very cool.
And she's actively,
it's weird.
There's pictures of her.
Just she's going to the White House.
No,
kind of semi-regular hanging out and
trying to,
she has a whole list.
It's trying to fucker.
Oh yeah.
All right.
Let's get started into the,
what is then,
what is this Kanye?
What verse?
The world.
What are we calling this?
A kanye decoded Kanye.
He coded.
Wow.
Yeah.
My hand.
Amen.
Go right in.
So,
jobs,
Ford,
Edison,
Disney.
I see where this is going.
And Stein Picasso.
How many of these,
how many please?
I'm,
I'm in the middle of something here.
Shakespeare,
uh,
Andy Warhol.
Warhol.
Thank you.
I forgot for a second.
As long as tweets,
a Dora the explorer launch Schwietz
apparent on Vanilla pea.
Von [inaudible] was strong.
Start here again.
The Vinci,
you know,
uh,
Hughes.
Phelps.
Did you rehearse this?
Socrates?
I'm get,
I'm getting to a thing.
Tesla.
You know,
Michelangelo,
my God.
Hawking,
are you trolling me?
Is there a presentation or is it just
thing they're getting their Beethoven
Jackson Buddy.
The Elf.
Not,
not welfare old then health,
but he's just west.
Oh,
are you with me so far?
I think so.
What is it you're trying to say?
And great mind,
these are all people Kanye is compared
himself to.
Wow.
Okay.
So you definitely,
you had a thing here.
Yeah,
there's,
there's reason behind the madness.
Hey,
so,
and I shouldn't have doubted,
you know that Elf,
what did you,
who was that?
A Disney.
Oh,
von Schwietz.
I need to compare itself to launch
tweets.
He said,
cause if you've seen record Ralph.
Yes.
She like is it the,
she's the glitch.
Kanye says I'm the glacier glitch.
We're going to decode that right now.
And you know,
that is what we're trying to do for the
Matrix.
Kanye d coated the enigma of political
affiliation.
A lot of people are upset about,
you know,
this guy's recent activities.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Uh,
it kind of kicked off a few weeks ago.
He announced his new album,
Yon d uh,
he said it was coming out September
29th.
Yani is Kanye and Gandhi.
That's not a bold claim.
And here's the album cover.
It's similar to his album from 2013.
Yeezus.
So this is the,
these making a play on word that he's
some kind of savior.
But does he actually believed that
because he is,
has manic states.
Does he believe he is uses probably in
those states.
He's gets close.
Uh,
especially recently.
He's on this whole love thing I'm
talking about,
but so he releases this September 29th
and then I gave it a little spin there.
SNL announced that he would be the
highest on the 29th or he'd,
he'd be the musical guest.
So everyone assumed,
okay,
he's going to come,
he's going to play some new songs.
The album will come out.
So first song,
I'm sure you saw this performance.
I love it.
Yeah.
It's catching a little pod.
Can My head song one?
We're having fun.
We're having fun out here song too.
So cool.
I think those are summaries of that
experience.
Yeah.
That's my review.
Came out and played a song called we got
love.
Great.
Very cool song.
Three liberals can't control me.
Takes a turn,
hold on.
Takes a turn.
And people weren't quite happy about it.
Uh,
he launched into his speech at the end
of,
he was playing ghost town and then NBC
cut the Stream.
Wow.
They cut him off.
Yeah.
I haven't seen this.
And some,
some people are saying,
oh,
it was just because they ran out of
time,
but it was right before he launched into
his speech and someone recorded it who
was backstage.
They cut it.
It never got aired.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
here's the recording from one of his
main producers.
It was backstage
one trump thing.
Cath laughing in the background.
Superman Cape on this means you can't
tell me what to do.
That's how we control.
That's how we're programmed.
If you want the world to move forward,
try love.
Thank y'all for giving me this platform.
I know.
I don't agree.
He's killing it though.
90% of news are liberal.
No,
that can't be true.
90%.
And they do your writers,
rappers,
musicians.
So it's easy to make it seem like it's
so,
so one sided and um,
they're just stuck up there.
Them hold them hostage a little bit.
I've talked to this country also.
They're very anti trump,
so he's Kinda bitching them out.
Yeah.
Got
It.
You know what?
I thought that was a beautiful,
authentic tender moment.
And to real goddamn shame they caught
them off.
Like that gives you a context to why
he's wearing this hat kind of feel like
they should have kept it.
It's not really,
I mean it is obviously very provocative,
but I understand,
I appreciate the point he's trying to
make of like stepping across the aisle
and seeing people as people and not
because it's so easy from the left or
right to just demonize and that's what
they do.
Cause like I wish a while a lot of left
wing,
uh,
media like Jimmy Kimmel and the Steven
Colbert is and all these guys and
they're just,
they talk about,
and Bill Maher,
it talked about the other side.
Like they're just monsters.
You know,
Bill Murray,
who was the only one that actually we'll
have a conversation without her side
only.
But like G-man,
chemo treats them like they're monsters.
Yeah.
So I appreciate the sentiment and there
was another part,
I don't know where it went by,
where he said like,
you guys kind of go at trump like a
little too hard and it's nonstop,
but it doesn't really help anything.
Yeah.
So he told them as well,
like I love how he's like thank you for
a platform.
And they're like,
dude,
we pulled the plug two minutes.
They're like,
we gotta get this guy out of here.
Man.
I feel bad.
I,
well,
I'm glad that somebody recorded it.
Yeah.
How have people reacted to that clip?
Not Gray.
No.
Um,
there was another one that everyone saw
first.
Chris Rock was in the audience and he
was filming it and he's just laughing.
Chris Rock filmed it.
What a weird twist.
Yeah.
I'm on his instagram story and you could
hear him chuckling and being like,
oh my God.
Right.
Well what do you expect this Kanye West.
Yeah.
You know,
that's,
it's weird that he would have that risk
surprised.
But also I find it,
I find that a little bit rude and
condescending to laugh at a guy who's
trying to express himself authentically.
It's like listen to the guy,
you know what I'm saying?
That's kind of the point that he's
making cause just because he's wearing
that hat is immediately labeled like a
joke and it's like why can't anyone
where like 50% of the country apparently
supports Donald Trump and rocks that
hat.
So why is it like that when you wear
that hat it's like wearing a swastika or
some shit.
It's like that's the
neighbors.
Yeah,
the hat is,
it's getting such like a visceral
immediate response from people and then
they don't want to dig deeper.
But again,
I'm sure there's,
I feel like I'm maybe supporting that
too much because then there's a lot of
people like,
well he said,
I'm going to say one way or the other.
I appreciate the act of trying to
reconcile these very fractured cup
country that we live in.
I mean I had that immediate reaction
when I saw him with the hat on the show.
I was like,
Ugh,
why are,
yeah my wearing that.
And like that was my first reaction.
But it's all just like,
Oh Paul,
we're all so sick of politics too.
It's like,
I just fucking make music and entertain
us.
Because there's also people that are
like,
oh,
well he's only doing that because he
doesn't really care.
He's just,
he's in the headlines.
Again,
I don't believe that because he kept
doing after his last album came out a
lot of shit for it.
So the day after that,
then he posts his photo.
That's the funny thing.
I have instagram and the caption.
This represents good and America
becoming whole again.
We will no longer outsource to other
countries.
We build factories here in America and
create jobs.
It will provide jobs for all who are
free from prisons as we abolished the
13th amendment message sent with love.
I'm not sure the trumps anything about
bringing people from prison.
Yeah,
he's,
and then this kind of in some trouble
because yeah,
this,
this is,
this is less about,
this is more political.
This is like I'm a,
I support Donald Trump.
Yeah.
And then the,
he said abolished the 13th amendment,
which is the one that,
yeah,
the whole sentence slavery.
But then there's like a section of that
that says,
except for p praise resins.
And he later said,
I meant the word amended.
It's like,
Bro,
you got to clarify that.
Like,
come on.
You got to know that doesn't come off
good with them.
With a maggot hat.
Yeah.
And I think he's still trying to be like
this.
I'm reaching across.
A lot of people have pointed out that
like the Migraine hat has a label that
says made in China.
And so it's like,
if you want to start the movement,
well,
you know,
there's this great clip of when Donald
was running for the Republican nominee,
he went on Jimmy Kimmel.
It was so great.
And camel had a bunch of trump ties with
the label made in China,
you know?
Yeah.
So then the response to this,
here's a couple reacts reactions.
Evans,
Captain America,
Captain America.
I'm with a lot of life.
He jumped in 600,000
lights.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
he's response,
there's nothing more maddening than
debating someone who doesn't know
history.
It doesn't read books and frames or
Myopia is virtue.
The level of conjecture I've encountered
lately isn't just frustrating.
It's retrogressive unprecedented.
An absolutely terrifying
that got 600,000
likes.
I don't think people even understood
like he got away too hard to sound smart
there.
Yeah,
he went all in.
He,
he got the webster's out.
He fought.
That was straight up cause sponsored by
thesaurus.com.
Um,
yeah,
curiously 600,000
people slammed that.
I mean that's just such,
I mean I,
yeah.
And then Lana Delray commented this one
had like right under his photo.
This one had like 30,000
by the way,
I want to say it once again for the
record,
not,
I'm not supporting in favor of Donald
Trump and in fact I want to say he
definitely made it to political at that
point.
Yeah.
I didn't like that one.
He cause then again,
it's like,
oh,
we're talking about bringing,
it's like,
Eh,
I like,
I liked the gesture of healing the
divide,
but then he made a political and using
these talking points and I so I
understand the backlash at that point
should have kept it pure about just
you've got to stick to walk point.
Yeah.
I like it where he's like,
don't scape goat me just because I liked
this guy along 50% of the America,
but now you got,
Chris Evans is going@thesource.com
and writing a dissertation,
a thesis,
a doctoral,
uh,
on it.
Dr America.
Okay.
I cannot believe 600,000
people pretended to understand what he
just dropped.
I can or you can't understand.
I can believe that.
That there's nothing more maddening than
debating someone who doesn't know
history,
doesn't read books and frames their
Myopia as virtue.
What the level,
unapologetic conjecture.
What the fuck?
Just say what you mean like you do.
Why are you writing a essay on twitter?
The level of unapologetic conjecture of
accountability isn't just frustrating.
It's retrogressive unprecedented and
Apps Shit,
dude.
I said,
when you're gonna to like criticize it
Kanya for not being educated,
then you come up with the,
I dare you to,
what about the dictionary and deep
belled this tweet such a pompous like
just fucking say what you want to say,
dude.
You don't like what the guy says.
You think he's on the educated and uh,
you know,
yeah,
he definitely went a little overboard.
And then Lana del Rey,
trump becoming our president was a loss
for the country,
but you were support of him is a loss
for the culture.
Uh,
I can only assume you were late to his
personality on some level.
Delusions of grandeur,
extreme issues with narcissism.
None of which would be a talking point
if we weren't speaking about the man
leading our country.
If you think it's all right to support
someone who believes it's okay to grab a
woman by the pussy just because he's
famous,
then you need an intervention.
As much as he does something,
so many narcissists we'll never get
because there just isn't help for the
issue.
Message sent with concern that we'll
never be addressed.
Hmm.
So that's real beef.
That's beef.
She performed at his wedding.
Well,
oh,
so tell me,
how do you feel about,
because about what Kanye said as a fan
and a student of his,
I think that,
I think that he's going about it the
completely wrong way.
Right.
And I see,
I see what he's trying to do and I'm not
going to get,
like,
I think people aren't shocked because I
was looking up like what celebrities
actually endorsed trump.
And it's a real row of character,
not the,
not the best.
Yeah.
Like far and away the most relevant
entertainer to everyone was the other
one roach.
Neat loaf and shit like that.
It's like meatloaf.
The first one was Roseanne.
That was the first one that popped up.
Oh,
sorry.
One Sec.
Yeah.
And like I'm whole Cogan you know,
so yeah,
I think people can't believe that
because no one else has even getting
close to that conversation who was
popular and so,
and then the last one was from
questlove.
He said,
you know,
we aren't even typing his name.
I find it strange.
She's and trending get,
we're all typing the same thing for all
that he's canceled talk.
There was an ounce of hope in our souls
tonight,
but all we got was,
well,
I'm kind of sad man,
that was about the snl performance.
So all three of those guys jumped in and
then snoop,
snoop,
snoop went in for the kill.
This guy named Dj Pooh,
uh,
re posted the photo and said,
Magda music ain't getting attention.
So he's saying he's kind of Promo.
Sure.
And then snoop and the comments make
your music again.
Bleep and word.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
With an a at the end.
And then he called him uncle Tom.
No,
uncle Tom.
Um,
for those of you who don't know,
cause he didn't know what that is.
There was a book,
I don't remember what it was called,
right,
but a fictional character.
It was called a uncle Tom's cabin.
Oh yeah.
Uncle Tom's cabin.
A black man that owned slaves.
So he's betraying his own kind,
in other words.
Yeah.
So he,
he said that
and he was a earlier posts from him.
What the fuck?
This was from one connie.
First put the hat on,
he said the new Kanye,
well all white now way to go,
dude edited him,
you know,
so he used to be mad at Connie for
awhile after this one on the left.
Then Connie went out and wore a picture
of snoop dogg on his shirt and then
immediately snoop dogg posted it and
said forgiveness is everything.
So he won him over.
He's easy.
And then like,
like,
yeah.
Of,
and then I look how good was like you
uncle Tom,
which is kind of like the worst thing
you could say to it.
Another block.
I mean that's,
that sounds a lot of hay.
Right.
And then he just wears the shirt while
still having them.
Yeah.
But I,
but again,
it's great.
That's what he's,
you know,
he's trying to do.
But I think Kanye beautifully disarmed
that situation.
Yeah.
And it worked.
It worked.
But I was like,
so who's forgiving who in that scenario?
You know what I mean?
Snoop,
I guess didn't,
was forgiving Kanye because he wore the
acknowledged him,
cause that's,
you know,
I'm going to have to use that.
Who am I wrong?
I got to start wearing this shirt.
It's the move.
That's the move for sure.
Yeah.
And then trump tweeted after the s and l
performance,
like many,
of course you have a trump.
You had one last week.
The Tra like,
man,
no,
I'm not like,
I can do my best as Stephen Colbert
doing trump.
Yeah.
That's,
nobody wants that.
Like many,
I don't watch Saturday night live.
You have a trump?
No,
not a good one.
Like man.
I mean it's all,
yeah,
it's just this.
It's okay.
Good.
Yeah,
we get it.
Let's go ahead.
Like many,
I don't watch Saturday night live,
even though I passed,
hosted it.
No longer funny.
No talent or charm.
It is just a political ad for the dems
word is that Kanye west who put on a
mega ha after the show,
despite being told no was great.
He's leading the charge.
Very cool.
Kanye and very cool.
Uh,
so everyone's kind of going,
but why,
why is he doing this?
Why is he,
you know,
taking his legacy like this?
Did you make this fun?
No.
No,
I can't.
It's a good,
good.
Uh,
so you got to go back to 2013.
This isn't the first time he's done
this.
A lot of people kind of forgot.
He put out his album yeezus and June of
2013 and then he put out all of the
merge and all of the merge was covered
in the confederate flag.
Wow.
That's pretty racy.
Yeah.
Literally.
And so that was a huge thing at the
time.
Then I didn't see that everything we
were falling client so close.
They look like a midget.
Oh,
kind of like until we met.
Yeah.
I'm not supposed to be a midget and I
guess I ain't either.
Yeah.
So a bunch of the merge had,
a lot of people were upset and here's a
clip of him in 2013 explaining why he
wore,
why he wore the confederate flag,
merge
the tour,
merge she I Red Eye,
which I thought was kind of like the
people.
I thought people just want to find
something to get.
Yeah.
You know,
I just want to get all riled up about
something.
But it was about the tour merchant,
the confederate flags in the skeleton
imagery and things like that.
I mean,
do you think people are overreacting
with this?
React how you want?
And I got said it's making react,
I guess.
Right?
Energy.
You got as good energy.
You know,
the confederate flag represented slavery
in a way.
The way my mom's shot,
that's about abstract take on what I
know about it.
Right.
So I made the song new slaves,
so I took the confederate flag and made
it my flat.
It's my flag now.
Now just go and do.
I like that.
Yeah.
That's great.
That's a great,
that's beautiful.
I love that.
And then just this was the day before
the snl performance,
or he was explaining the maggot hat.
I redesigned it.
I've been changed the Brim,
change the shape right here,
and I'll put positive energy into the
hat.
That's what he said about it there.
Yeah.
But he fucked it up when he started
talking about political point.
Yeah,
that's definitely where it's getting
fucked that up.
Yeah.
I think he started with this idea and
then a bunch of sort of a right.
You know,
I'm right leaning.
People in,
in media started reaching out to him and
he started taking meetings with them and
I think then they got in his brain,
he got some,
yeah,
he got some talking points from them and
you know,
see,
there you go.
He's becoming what he hates.
Kind of.
Isn't it true?
I think that he really,
I don't think there's any maliciousness.
No,
I know,
but he'd be coming,
but he's almost upon to the,
uh,
well,
whatever,
what the fuck do I know?
It's kind of like,
you know,
pulling whispering in his ear and he's
coming out.
Yeah.
Talking about the,
you know,
bringing jobs back or whatever.
Not that that's a bad thing,
but it is a talking point.
Yeah.
And then,
let's see,
so that was from that thing.
He's wearing a make America great again
hat.
And then his sweater is Colin
Kaepernick.
Um,
he's keeps trying to do this duality
thing.
These are all the people he follows on
twitter.
It's like Bernie Sanders trump.
Uh,
and then he,
he followed those two at the same exact
time.
Bernie and trump.
And then he followed Candice Owens who
is a Republican.
I'm a media personality.
And Emma Gonzales who was kind of,
she was leading the Antigua.
Yeah.
He followed them at the exact same time
to at exact same time.
Yeah.
It was like a media.
So he's trying to create a statement.
Only eight followers.
Yeah.
It's exclusive club.
Interesting.
Someday get in that club.
Who is your opposite match?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't want to have to find a nemesis
free.
Uh,
here's a tweet.
I haven't done enough research on
conservatives to call myself or be
called one on just refusing to be
enslaved by monolithic thought.
And all right.
Um,
here's a,
it's more of just him saying,
you know,
the hat,
it's not about policies.
I'm not a politician like that.
It represents overcoming fear and doing
what you felt.
No matter what anyone said,
you can't bully me.
Liberals can't bully me.
News can't bully me.
The hip hop community can't believe me.
Uh,
and here's Kim's saying,
you know,
we would talk about policies and he
doesn't agree with the policies.
He likes his personality and how he made
it to be president when everyone really
underestimated him essentially.
All right.
And then the next,
the dragon energy.
Yeah.
And here's one of his good friends after
the,
after the performance,
he has never said he agrees with trump's
policies.
Just the fact that no one would have
thought trump would be president,
meaning he did the emba.
Unbelievable.
And that's the connection.
Only him wearing the hat is his choice
and he feels he's stripping the power of
hate.
That people give that hat by wearing it
and wants to love all no matter how they
speak of him or whatever we don't agree
with because that's how God works.
God loves all.
If he was trying to strip the power of
hate that people give it by wearing it,
he would.
He's never said that.
No,
not well,
he said he put like positive energy into
the hat,
but what does that,
oh,
it means it's like diamond water.
They run it through and he liked it when
asked about the core energy.
And he's right.
He washed it and dining and water.
I'm going to ask you about the
confederate flag.
He gave it very straightforward
explanation.
He said this is represents slavery and
now it's mine.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well yeah.
God bless.
God loves all.
Uh,
and then here's a quick clip he was
asked about if you liked why he is
showing support for trump.
Oh wait,
where'd it go?
There we go.
So maybe that's what you liked the idea?
Yeah.
Not necessarily.
I do.
Donald Trump with the idea of an outside
of infiltrating.
Yeah,
I liked it.
It showed you that anything is possible
shows you that it doesn't even like
Virgil,
uh,
working at Louis Vuitton,
trump being in office,
it's a time for the unconventional.
I'm,
I'm very,
I'm not a traditional thinker.
I'm a non conformist,
you know?
So that relates to the nonconformists.
Pardon me now,
you know,
but I'm also,
I'm a producer.
I like to segue things.
I'd like to take Otis,
chop it up,
do it like this.
So,
so what's the gay version?
And the gay version of b,
the trump campaign and maybe to Bernie
Sanders principles.
That would be my mics and stuff.
But I think both had,
you know,
uh,
I need it.
So that's,
there you go.
So I don't know where he is with his
thoughts on politics.
Okay,
bye.
Are you though?
So really the question was like,
you know,
can you turn this into something
positive?
Sure.
I don't personally,
I don't think so.
And you liked them to charged like the
yeah,
you can't in a way like it's hard to
just say I just like trump because he
made it against all odds without
acknowledging everything that he stands
for.
Well,
I also recall him saying that he has he
redesigned the hat?
Yeah,
he has a yeezy version of the make
America great again hat that he wears.
And I think that's fantastic that he
made his own hat
there.
Yeah,
he changed the Brim,
changed the thing.
Yeah.
It doesn't look better.
I have to say.
It looks,
he looks a little goofy when he,
the hat fit.
Like,
if you recall the picture on Instagram,
that's like a total goof angle while at
any rate,
Kanye,
he's out there,
he's doing his thing,
he's authentic.
And you as a fan,
you love him.
You against all odds forever.
So what,
what if you could say anything to Konya
right now,
what would you tell him?
Kanya is right here.
What do you say?
I'd probably say,
well first I think that um,
I appreciate what he's trying to do.
Yes.
But it's like,
it's,
it's like a sisyphus task.
He's like rolling a boulder to Chris
Evans.
Yeah,
the source out.
Um,
it's like an,
I saw some people going well,
like,
oh,
like the swastika used to be a symbol of
peace and then they changed it to make
it a different thing.
But it's not,
once that happens,
you can't bring it back.
You can't take the Hitler mustache.
I said it's like,
it's easier to,
to poison the,
well then to like purify the water.
So that's my thinking and trust.
If he wants to use the hat,
I think he has to design,
redesign it a little further and stay
out of the political talking points he
was saying is trying to remix.
Yeah.
This ID as Buddy Dan change that had
enough.
My pitch.
I've got a pitch.
This isn't the redesign one,
but you've got,
you know the Democrats typically blue
publicans or read the trump has is very
red,
blue and red combined purple.
There it is.
Purple Make America great again.
That's a brilliant idea.
Yes.
You
change it to purple being or that good
ideas.
Just that plain hat.
What's the goal with make America great
again?
Right.
Well then you change the slogan as well.
I looked it up.
I went to the meanings of colors and I
was ah,
I,
that's,
I was thinking,
I was like,
what the hell?
Okay.
Violet,
the color of spirituality to energy of
red with the calm.
Who defines who decides what color
means?
A lot of these are marketing companies
as color plays very heavily.
Oh,
okay.
This is like got it.
A,
a color that inspires reflection and
self awareness.
It just the color of the sensitive,
compassionate,
intuitive soul.
Violet has long been associated with
royalty and characteristics of quality
and luxury.
Mom,
if you go back to his album,
cover the sticker on it was violent.
Yes.
You think he's onto this already?
No,
but I'm trying to leave Kanye.
Well I think you've got to keep the,
make America great again cause then you
have both colors the same meaning if you
go away from the phrase,
it becomes something to different.
Combine them.
Kanye who is listening for sure
obviously listened to end.
He's got great advice I think.
Or the slogan.
I think you could slight,
I mean it could go both ways,
but I think the color would be a good
change.
Maybe make America great cause it was
not,
again,
not everyone w it wasn't great for all
people at any point.
Yeah.
I'm Connie.
He has this whole thing.
He's always talking about,
oh we teach history class.
Why don't we teach future class,
right.
That's his whole thing.
So look,
look forward.
Let's make it great.
Make America Great.
Stop looking bad and not rely am and
that's kind of,
yeah.
Yeah.
If I'm maybe both,
I said this maybe took a little from
him.
Make America unified.
Yeah.
Combination.
Okay.
Or make America love.
That's a little corny.
And,
and can mayberry well,
I wanted to please all the people out
there and I like the upgrades without,
it just took a little the about he
closes his dream.
Make America Great.
I do like that one.
Okay,
thanks.
So change the color,
change the change of the Brim,
all that.
Everybody tweaked the Connie,
let them know.
I think we got it.
Yes.
Here.
If he did that then maybe.
Maybe.
And do you think that if Kanye adopted
your idea from the show,
would they give you back membership
tier,
the Kanye form that you were banned from
dance?
You already get it back.
Well,
no,
I don't think he did.
Every band I'm back,
but they don't know I'm,
I'm there.
Oh,
you have a new account.
But they,
they couldn't know who's here and there.
They're onto me.
Huh?
I,
I saw a weird,
gave me rolling.
Someone commented the other day and they
were like,
you,
the way you type makes it seem like
you've been here a lot longer than your
registration date.
They all know each other,
Huh?
Yeah.
Come get his weight.
How many active members is that
community?
Yeah,
well there's,
there's like,
uh,
like 10,000
people on there,
but then there's really heavy people on
your heavy.
Uh,
yeah.
How many hours a day are you on that?
Well,
not as much now because if I use it at
home,
they'll trace my ip.
I'm like,
alright,
I'm in deep know I,
the hatch should say unbanned Ian from
the forum.
But that's funny.
We got to pick up on those and you end
well,
thank you for decoding Kanye.
Rest in peace to Mac Miller.
I see you're repping that.
They're on your hoodie.
Yes.
Rustin penned a and thanks so much for
your presentation.
We will show you all the best you can.
Leave it out.
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
All right,
so there you guys have it,
uh,
the Kanye West d coded.
Hmm.
What do you take away from that?
He led,
do you think?
What do you think
Ian is always making me like see the
good in canyon that maybe I didn't save
it.
No.
Well,
Ian,
he's a good cat.
He's got a strong head on his shoulders.
Um,
so I,
I generally,
he's got good ideas.
Yeah.
So when he says that Kanye is his
favorite person in the world,
I listen.
Right.
And I'm like,
what's going on there?
Actually started listening to his new
album because of Ian's a doorstop and I
got to say,
there's a lot of the gravy cottey one.
Yeah,
there's a lot of good stuff there.
So,
um,
let's make America love again
and it's,
it's tough to,
I,
like I said,
when I saw him with the hat,
I was like,
what?
Yeah,
why?
But when you look more into it,
I see what he's trying to do.
Oh,
I see.
Hey,
God bless it yet.
All right,
well let's get into,
um,
yeah.
Speaking of,
uh,
conservatives,
Papa John is a prominent conservative.
Did you know that?
And he is currently under a huge
criminal conspiracy by the Clintons and
George Soros to remove him from his
pizza empire.
Can we close it?
Oh,
sorry.
Yeah,
that's me.
Papa John has showed up to court today.
What does it,
I think you just got to close that
window there on the top right.
Hey,
there we go.
I was like,
okay.
There you go.
Papa John showed up in court today to
testify in his lawsuit.
Papa John,
the Papa John,
and he gave testimony.
He asked for documents.
There's a lot of big updates I'd like to
share with you guys as Johnny's Suing
Papa John's.
Yeah.
As the story unfolds,
we've got a video here.
Here we go.
Mr.
Schneider is set to begin testifying
modern,
as you mentioned the wrong,
it's Shat Shat.
No,
it's not her.
Okay.
Papa John's Shatner's wife on air.
Yeah.
Schneider should change it.
She found her.
A former CEO and former chairman of the
board is seeking documents related to
his ouster as chairman earlier in the
summer.
Mr [inaudible] said he's feeling good
this morning ahead of his testimony.
Here's what else he had to say to us.
What's your message to shareholders?
You guys remember the Papa's in the
house where he had the Lav on?
Yeah.
And he didn't know that you could hear
him.
He was gone.
That's it.
Dead eight here a little bit.
You can hear him gone.
There's
right.
Same message we would have for 34 years.
You know,
we always act in their best interest.
What's your end goal here?
Do you
better interest,
better pizza,
better ingredients up at John's.
Always in their best interest.
The quality is low because of this
virtual desktop,
I think.
Okay.
Yeah.
Although it should be yours,
not mine.
Well,
we'll figure it out later.
I turned to the company and a leadership
position of,
I don't want to be in a CEO position for
sure,
but you know,
I uh,
I definitely want to be part of it and I
am part of the company.
I am part of the company that you want.
What's the name of the company?
Papa John's.
And who's the Papa?
Steve?
No,
he's actually suing the company.
And Steve,
he was going to fire Steve.
Did you know there's the pizza gus and
Gung Ho by Air Steve and now he's the
CEO.
Ah,
it's a drama is so good.
I'm telling you they should rename the
company at a pop.
Steve's Kinda Nevan the pizza boxes.
No one's going to buy that.
Steve.
My faith,
full employee one day.
I'm cool.
Steve.
I was going to let you go.
We'll go to part ways and now you've
taken everything from me.
Stevie.
You can take it in the mirror and her,
you've taken the fresh 100% Mozzarella.
You've taken it all and now you're
changing the name to pump stevie.
I want it's better pizza,
better ingredients.
And now stevie my faith.
Fuck out.
Come to me and you say you want no
problem.
My Heart's probably a couple of degrees.
You have a call against the family and
now I sit and quiet next to you,
Stevie,
my colleague,
my friend.
And you sit and you look many eyes and
you see this pizza.
And by that I built with my hands.
You take the Mozzarella at Marin.
I needed the door.
I Oman's Dave and you sit across from me
in court today at Uc Davis.
Oh,
I won't for Papa John's is for the
shareholders to make money better,
better pizza.
And how might some,
boy,
he's a slow point.
My boat,
my son,
boy,
he doesn't have much prospects.
He's got no prospects TV.
You'd think as pizza.
Em,
listen to this.
This is a real godfather tail.
Um,
better interests.
Better Pizza.
I am part of Papa Joe.
Here's part two.
You can go ahead and I feel like the
music companies,
the whole thing,
this is all a huge betrayal.
Yeah.
Here we go.
Hit me with it.
Don't you fucking lag out on me.
Now.
What about Internet?
Right?
Josh satirize actually just wrapped up
his testimony and we aren't getting on
his and his team to exit from the
courthouse.
This is one of two lawsuits that he's
filed against the company.
I hear he is just coming out right now.
You're going to get any comments from
[inaudible].
It has 17 different categories of
documents that are related to his ouster
as chairman of the board today,
he really appeared calm and reserved.
That's in stark contrast to public
comments that he's made and also
statements he's put out on his website.
Save Papa John's dot com it feels the
company didn't properly protect him as
founder.
After a Forbes reports that he'd used a
racial slur on a conference call.
It was about a kind of using it as a
racial epithet reports in the media
mischaracterize what actually happened.
Mr [inaudible] today also spoke of an
intuition,
a sixth sense,
a gut feeling.
It's something may have been going on
with the company and that's why he's
trying to seek documents that go back to
October 31st he made those.
Now Ms comments,
nfl and leadership,
so he doesn't know if the board's
actions and mount to a coup,
a conspiracy or perhaps they are acting
in the best interest of the company that
you want to obtain these documents to
try and figure out really what happened
here.
I also spoke to a source close to the
company but at the Johns seemed a bit
confused today about what documents he
was asking for.
That is troubling because he is a
direct,
just want the,
I just want the mirror narrow,
clear about what he actually needed.
Having that the company really looks
forward to moving past these schemas and
creating a better papa John's a better
culture for the company.
Also,
we should mention that because we are
struggling to meet away from a decision.
It was unclear today if the judge from
the bench,
but by showing again,
we're waiting comments from a John
and now josh motto and now I'm assuming
you going to point some down.
Fuck this shit.
Stevie former colleague and best friend,
my a fighter like concierge.
See,
how do you call that advisor?
Constantly air constantly there like the
Abbey because my consigliere nailed it.
A lie ask is support to return the
recipe of and my patented trademark and
Mozzarella cheese recipe.
Papa John's the Mozzarella.
It's diff.
It's to milk.
It's designed to melt evenly over the
pizza.
That's the pizza place.
I know.
What's your stiff?
You break,
you break.
Okay.
Stevie,
I have to take you on a lake and
execute.
Okay.
Listen to this shit.
He requests 17 different documents,
including the recipe of his Marinara
sauce as a joke,
but 17 documents Israel,
the pizza senses,
we're sensing a pizza conspiracy,
a coup or conspiracy.
Papa speculated that foreign agents
maybe act and covertly to overthrow his
pizza empire,
possibly speculating that it was little
seizures or possibly domine hose.
The I'm going,
I did write this by the way.
I spent,
I'm this morning right shares dom hose.
Yes.
Isla.
Thank you very much for acknowledging
that
common hope.
Everybody dominant hose.
Yes.
Only a great mind such as mine could
such an original joke.
Shares of the company have fallen more
than 31% over the last year,
but the company's whoa started long
before Papa John was locked in a bitter
battle since hitting an all time high of
90 cents per share in December of 2016
Papa John's stock has lost nearly half
of its value on disappointing same store
sales growth.
On Monday,
the stock was down more than 2% last
changing hands at around $50 a share.
So they,
they were already going down.
This supports his pizza conspiracy that
the company was not doing well and they
wanted him off because he was checking
what I pulled up a isla pulled up
something he said he planned to fire
currency.
Oh Steve Richie who knew his performance
evaluation would be subpar.
Wow.
And now stevie is the new pop this up on
the night of December 26
that won't be a change of events.
The or formerly known as papa re Stevie
Richie,
but no longer control side.
The shatner family is over and on the
east side we are going to control the
mirror and there were supply the moat
Sylvana supplying the tomato supply.
These boys,
the Ritchie family,
Dan.
Oh God,
no.
On the trustworthy.
Then their performance is subpar.
And so what is my well as Grandpapa as
the God
that the sea,
oh richie shall be no more.
And so on this day of December 26 pumper
Richie,
because I give him a kiss and I said,
it's the kiss of faith
and this time honored more Toronto,
this award winning Marin sauce torch.
I get the deal,
my son,
the,
the award winning cross that throw with
my own pants,
don't understand it's a pizza wall.
We'll go into a wall.
Here's the twist.
Here's a big twist within the
proceedings,
he was asked whether he had some
settlements with some women.
Shatner stated that he has
confidentially agreements with at least
two women but didn't specify what those
meant.
Uh,
the woman,
24 year olds all the time sued,
shatter,
Shat Shat big shanty boy,
Papa and 1999 alleging that he had
sexually harassed her four months
repeatedly visiting her house and
kissing her and groping her according to
court filing,
Shatner has denied the allegations and
as they say,
papa is and will ever for be in the
house.
What you just did when you sent that to
me?
So,
um,
it's an interesting twist of fate for
papa because he went to seek documents
to try to prove that it was a pizza
conspiracy.
But what he did is he unsealed other
documents about him being in the house
with a,
an employee that he allegedly kissed and
groped.
Papa has denied the allegations.
Do you think the Papa,
do you think he uses a lube when Esx or
Marinara sauce?
Probably the Bata.
You think he is a boiling pot of sauce?
Yeah,
he probably does.
Doesn't he?
Hmm.
Oh my God.
Oh right.
Marlon Brando,
the Godfather,
the guy that played the godfather was
famously in a butter scene where he used
butter to lube up his cock to rape a
girl in a movie in a movie.
So there you have that.
Everything connects folks.
It's a small world after all as they
say.
So that's it.
That's that.
You know what else we got?
We got facebook leak.
Oh was yeah cause it,
Shit.
Facebook sucks.
What's,
what's like Mark Zuckerberg or smoking
meats.
CSEC is a potential sociopath.
That guy acts like a computer emulating
him.
That's the thing.
If you're going to sell,
I'm not a therapist,
I'm just a fucking idiot.
Everyone becomes a sociopath.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's why I find it.
I'll just a little irresponsible the
therapist,
cause you're wielding trust like a
doctor that,
I don't know if the therapist take o's,
but doctors take boats.
That's serious stuff,
you know?
Um,
here.
So this,
this story cracks me up.
This is amazing,
amazing stuff.
Um,
Dream cruise nightmare.
1300 Indians partying from a tobacco
company,
went on a cruise with a 3000 other,
I mean,
3000 people in total.
So half of those from these Indian
company and half was Australian people
or just not just for vacation.
And these guys just don't took over this
cruise ship.
They brought playboy playmates,
they brought music,
they brought their own food,
and they just completely terrorized this
cruise and everybody was trapped on this
cruise and it was so bad that Royal
Caribbean's had,
they're very fond everybody.
But there's just hilarious footage of,
um,
of all this.
And it was like a 24 hour nightmare.
And the Saas Jillian station made this
really hilarious,
like scoop,
very serious.
Um,
they were very serious about it,
you know,
which I,
I just was loving this whole thing.
Cruise ruined by 1300 men on a work
bender.
Here we go.
It was supposed to be the cruise of a
lifetime.
But these excited ozzy families for them
soon got a sick feeling when they
realized they were sharing the ship with
1300 men on a work bender,
our work
Banda,
they turned
family cruise until like they set up
like a strip club.
Hey,
believe this shit.
These guys are the best and they're all
just out there with their phones out on
shit like,
God,
I love it.
I love it that a company was able to
just ruin a whole crew's paper like
traumatized.
They said,
yeah,
randomly.
Like they kept their doors open and you
were just walking by and not knowing
where you're going to see.
Yup.
Some fucking naked Indian too.
There's nothing though.
Love it.
Sorry.
They're in the pool.
They're dominating everything.
It was luck as the chain.
Hundred Bucks.
Not Pretty much.
They would just papers everywhere when
we didn't get our sail away party and it
was taken over by them.
That was the beginning of the end.
Disappointed.
I'm sure these other colorful words I
would use when truck dance teacher,
one cass and their daughter Talia
boarded.
The reason we focus on the personal
story of like people's Christine and her
hubby,
they were all looking forward to their
best cruise yet every day was getting
closer or was it just the heartbeats
pumping out going crazy.
But I know just don't go on a cruise.
I mean guys,
cruising is like the ocean version of
Zip lining.
I always say that it probably had zip
lines on that curve.
Zip Lines are so stupid and I've never
been on a cruise.
I thought about it.
I haven't been one.
It's awful,
right?
Yeah.
Every time I hear someone was on a
cruise,
it sounds so bad.
And the worst part about it is that
you're in the middle.
You cannot fucking escape that.
Oh,
I had a friend who went racing
and you have this cluster phobic tiny
room.
Hmm.
So you can't even let it go to your room
too if you're like Dang people over or
you want to go to your woman's tiny and
don't even get me started on rogue
waves.
What's that?
I'd like you to start.
Don't even get me started.
Rogue waves,
dude,
are anomalies on the ocean.
Okay.
Oh yeah.
He was scared of waves.
Rural waves.
My Dude's,
it's when it's when seemingly n
seemingly normal waves.
There's a frequency when they can all
just by some fluke of statistics,
we're like 50 waves.
Wave lengths can line up and make one
mega wave out of the ocean out of
random,
and I'm telling,
I'm not making that is a well observed
phenomenon.
Rogue waves.
There's videos of it.
I swear to God.
Go on Google and type of rogue wave.
In fact,
Ila,
why don't you do that and throw it on
the screen?
Thanks Craig.
Pregnant ass Ila.
I don't know what that means.
Oh,
it's under you.
It goes on their ear stuff.
Row Waves,
guys.
Oh,
this is stupid.
Which is wait,
and we've got to go to Vegas.
Oh,
can I not click your screen?
Can you know?
Oh,
this is confusing,
but a videos.
Wait,
wait.
What has happened?
It just clicks.
Really low lag here.
The second one.
That one looks too like click.
Baity.
They all know.
Yeah.
Porter joint.
All right,
I'll come on.
What's the middle class?
Why don't we have a AD block for
Christ's sake.
We're doing a show here.
Okay,
well it's real.
I'm telling you.
Do some research.
Go off there.
Rogue waves.
They're out there and you think you're
safely on the cruise.
You think those 1300 Indian men with
their balls out and uh,
and their hotel room with the door open
is bad.
Rogue waves.
My Dude,
I dunno,
that doesn't
rogue waves anyone.
Whatever.
I just think the crazy favorite.
Go Open Up.
Open a clip of cruise ship on,
on,
uh,
troubled.
See,
I'm telling you this shit's amazing.
I've like people getting like toss
around with furniture and shit.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
He won't caught me dead on those boats,
man.
Apparently you can gamble though,
Mike.
Yeah,
there's prostitutes because it's
illegal.
That sounds to bottom click on royal
Caribbean not on recruitment.
Sure.
Why not?
Unless you're with 1300 Indians from a
tobacco company.
It's on the conduct of a gamble there.
You're right about that.
Imagine the company brought like prepaid
prostitutes.
Everyone's just taken a turn.
What do we got here?
The lag is Karna.
Tough.
No sound.
Yeah,
it was just,
all right.
Let's see.
All right.
Yeah,
this is tough.
This is a tough one.
But imagine being on that.
That's a rogue wave.
My Dude's watch out for that.
All right.
Any rate love were,
where were we?
We were watching the stamp video.
I'm getting off track here.
We've got important things to talk about
obviously and uh,
let's stay on track.
Skip ahead.
Moved into voyage of,
of the sleeve.
No price on,
um,
because they would just stare and make
us feel really uncomfortable.
The families got that feeling from the
push off where we were seated on the,
on the pool deck.
We were actually asked to move.
We did because we thought these people
were from Royal Caribbean but they were
actually from the private party asking
us to move so they could sit up there.
And so we thought,
okay,
they're sitting up for the sail away
party but as a love how serious it is
still like would you like to comment to
our news room and up the sail away party
made room to these high jinks on the
high seas is the pool deck.
Because one guy,
Dennis,
sweaty mess if gyrating body,
I've never seen so many mobile phones in
my life.
Oh dear God.
Yeah.
Um,
no.
Anyway,
this feels wrong but um,
of it,
I just love the idea of 1300 and Dan
just taken all so much.
Just like what?
I don't know.
You got to love it.
And this is,
you know,
this is the top notch content that you
can come to expect here on h three
podcast experience.
Okay.
Um,
there's one clip here that I absolutely
want to watch with you guys and then
we'll get some fans emissions wash this
pasture claims.
I love this clip so much.
I love these guys.
He gets in front of his congregation and
he says if you do not give 10% of your
whole income to the church,
you are robbing God
even if you are in debt.
What do they call that?
A death.
A tilth.
There's a saying that it's a part of
height,
a type of being Catholic or Christian.
You're supposed to donate 10% of your
income to the church.
Really?
Man,
I ain't no fucking church word that send
me to hell.
I'm keeping that 10% I already paid
fucking 50% the Uncle Sam,
what does he do for me?
Shit,
you kidding me?
10% is that all it takes to get into
heaven?
10% fuck it.
I'll go to hell
and rob guy,
he says,
you're robbing me.
What are you robbing me of times?
Now,
what is the tab?
A tithe is 10% he says,
you're robbing me of both tithes and
offerings.
The 10% is what is what God requires and
then they all drinks.
Oftentimes some may require more than a
10% some this cannot,
cannot,
cannot live off that not live on 10% do
you understand why this is so weird?
You said that you don't know.
How much did I have?
What do you think?
Be deeply in debt and then real trouble
did he,
he is going to be hard for you to
believe that.
I'm telling you.
I'm seeing it over and over and over
again.
You want to get out of debt.
It's be around Ivan lift you so you
start start giving God 10% of your rent
account,
but there's no way I could do that.
Just try it.
I dare.
You can always use his pride.
He's like,
you don't listen to her house fan page.
Hmm.
So there you have it.
God cannot live on 10% that's so weird
because I've always liked sin.
Like if I would go to a synagogue when I
was a kid,
when my mom,
they would be like,
can you donate anything?
Like anything.
It's a blessing.
Yeah.
You mean they have some staff,
some like,
like a dollar and humility.
God cannot live without Yo 10% Dan,
do you Jesus.
I recently went out to lunch and I tip
my sweet server.
I gave him 20% now why don't I get 20%
Lord?
Now I don't care if you're broke.
If you miss in the kidney,
if you got cancer,
if you can't pay your debt,
boy,
I don't give up.
I don't.
God doesn't get,
you can't live on 10 but set by now.
You want to be good with Jesus.
You best be given me at least 10% of
everything you aren't boy.
Cause let me tell you what,
ain't no 5% b.
Buy me a private jet because I got to
pray all over this country.
Boy,
you think I cannot save on 5% people and
that's right here in the Bible.
That's that Tif.
Uh,
Tif.
No.
Yes.
Jesus by help me Lord.
And how am I supposed to afford these
little tiny crosses,
the mark,
the boys that I want to molest?
Yes Lord,
I need,
I feel that 10% hmm.
Preach.
If your kidneys failing,
boy,
give me that kidney.
I'll sell it on the black market.
That's 10% you good with Jesus.
You know you need medicine to save your
life.
Give me some of that medicine.
I'll sell it on the black market.
10% boy,
you feel me?
Yay.
Get Amen.
Amen.
Brother.
Oh,
you want me to give 10% she and I'm with
the church.
I'll give 10% I give 10% I am God.
Now let me touch your kids deck.
Hey Man,
can I touch your kids deck?
Amen,
Bro.
Hmm.
Jesus.
Are you telling me that Jesus didn't
touch at least one baby penis?
At least one I may come on.
Right.
You know Jesus at least look at a baby
dead.
Am I right?
Can I get an amen?
10% by I could the Christians I could.
Then they're good people to the fence.
There's a 101 he was like,
oh,
I get,
I kid the Christians,
they're good people.
The Catholics,
they're great.
Amen.
I was researching with all these kind of
goofy pasture videos and there's just
one other one I want to show you guys
and Isla you are going to love this.
Okay.
This is incredible stuff
in Calgary.
Oh,
his name was ben and that was running.
You could buy was there for a few years
and um,
was just,
he was a nice kid who was one of those
kids that was always just,
it's a real smart Alec who's this?
What's was a bright kid,
which didn't help things,
right.
Made it more dangerous outside one day.
And he was just just trying to push my
buttons and it was just,
you know,
kind of not taking the lord serious.
And I walked over to him and I went,
I punched him in the chest as hard as I
crop will the kid,
I just came in brother and I said,
I leaned over and I said,
Ben,
when are you going to stop playing games
with God?
I let that man to the Lord right there.
There's times that that might be needed.
That man,
the Lord right there.
He'd been in prison for 20 years now.
I love that.
You know,
everyone listening was like,
what?
And I walked over to
that little 13 chest as hard as I could
and I laid them out on the ground and I
said,
boy,
when am I getting that 10% because I
know your mama gave you $5 a week in
allowance.
And to me that's 50 cents a week by word
at 10% hmm.
That's when that boy found God.
You've been in prison now for 20 years
for murder.
That boy ain't right.
I love that story,
man.
I love that story.
Yeah.
Oh,
so good.
Anyway,
let's move it on to fans submissions.
Okay.
Now this is
podcast@hthreehthreeproductions.com.
You guys can send it questions,
videos,
comments,
whatever you want.
I love it.
Keep it coming.
This is so much fun.
So this one comes from clammy hippo.
I watched a shrew podcasts for the same
reasons.
Everyone else to make sure I have the
correct opinion.
Thank you very much.
You do have the correct opinion,
the recent debates on how you wipe your
arse.
Apparently this friend comes from across
the seas,
have been Imez,
immersive and captivating and I want to
just slam dunk a little debate here
myself.
Do you piss in the shower?
I've asked around in the answer is about
50 50 as a proud shower.
Pissed or myself,
I need to tell you.
I need you to tell me if I should stop
pissing the shower or carry on.
Just letting it rip.
Also on a little bit of a side note,
I'm not sure this is a stupid question,
but I'm sure you and everyone else does
it,
including me.
Do Shit,
but do you shit in the bath?
We simply need to know.
Well,
claimy hippo first,
let me start with the first part because
you took a quick turn.
They're peeing in the shower to me is a
beautiful natural thing.
It's like pink outside.
It's like,
it's a beautiful thing where you don't,
I love being in the shower.
I,
when I read this,
I was shocked that why would you not pee
in the shower?
I pee on 11 we're in the shower now.
Dan Zak.
And Do you guys pee in the shower?
You know,
I don't go out of my way to but,
but sure.
I mean,
I do.
If the,
if you go,
you hold it to hold it in the shower.
I mean,
I think that p 100% of the time,
I know hour because you're relaxed.
It's warm.
You're comfortable.
Ian And Zach,
Do you pee in the shower?
Zach says,
hell yeah.
And I think Ian said,
Nah,
he had,
he had recently such a contrarian,
just like conscious.
Now why do you not pee in the shower?
Dan and Ian.
I mean I'm just,
do you think that it's gross?
But yeah,
I mean apparently you go out of your way
to you like actually enjoy it.
I do enjoy like if you're sitting in
your own in the bedroom,
you pee in the bat.
I don't have you done baking tips it
back.
Chris Evans takes a bath probably.
It's crafted that tweet.
He was in the bathtub being in it now.
And do you find it gross?
What is it about shopping in the shower
that,
that I have roommates and it just
doesn't seem respectful really.
I who goes down with the water?
Who Cares?
I don't know.
I just,
yeah.
Well I appreciate,
do you jerk off in the shower?
I know because jerking off in the shower
fucking nasty because it can get caught
in the drain.
And I've actually had roommates where
they jerk off in the shower and you can
see it in the drain and that,
oh no,
I'm telling you that shit ain't right.
So I would say that jerking off in the
shower with roommates is a little
stickier.
Well,
it's none of that is as bad as this
guy's second.
But then he gets it.
He says,
I'm sure this is a stupid question.
I'm sure you and everyone else does it,
including me,
but do you shit in the bath now?
I think he's making chain,
but obviously shitting in the bath is,
I'm not,
this person's not Siri.
Sociopath.
Yeah,
I think you have to be homeless or
something.
I know how,
I don't know.
I would never shitting in the bath.
That can't be what,
I'll tell you a funny story about
shitting in the bath though.
I had,
I live with two dudes in college and we
used to play a game called doopy extreme
where where you tried to run an
elaborate dupe on one of the housemates
did the other two were on,
you would try to make them believe some
far fetched,
outrageous thing.
And so this was my crowning achievement.
I with the other guy,
we decided to try to convince our third
roommate who was kind of a Germaphobe
that we shit in the shower and that it's
normal and everybody fits in the shower.
So here's what I did.
This was fun.
I'm proud of this way.
So I arranged it with the other friend
and then I called a fourth friend and
said,
hey,
we're doing this prank.
I'm going to call you and I want you to
say that you,
of course you see shit in the shower.
So I was like,
oh bro.
Um,
I was like,
hey,
just giving them an I shit in the shower
when I was in there and he's like,
you did what?
And we've gotten this whole thing.
I was like,
yeah,
you shouldn't.
The shower.
I push it down with my toes down the
drain.
It's normal.
My whole family,
everybody does that.
And he's like,
he's like telling me you guys are
kidding.
He was like,
I can't you tell he was dead serious.
tell me you guys are fucking kidding.
Like you don't Shit in the shower.
And then my third roommate comes in,
he's like,
yeah,
I shouldn't have shower too.
You push it down with your toes,
you stomp it down with your tufts and
he's like,
you guys are fucking with me.
And then we called up the fourth friend
and I was like,
I'm talking to Isaac,
we shit in the shower.
He doesn't believe it,
but you shouldn't have shower.
Right?
He's like,
yeah,
everybody should sit in the shower,
stomp it down with our toes.
And he's sitting there having like a
mental breakdown like on to have a name
for it.
We called it,
we did,
I don't remember what it was.
Yeah,
the waffle stomp I think.
we called it a waffle stump when you
yeah,
exactly.
And so a waffle stomp.
Exactly.
So we convinced him for a good,
like 20 minutes that we will feel
stumped,
shit them down the,
so no,
I do not shit in the bathtub.
And I sincerely do hope that you do not
it in the basket of,
and then nobody fits in the bath tub
because that ain't sanitarian.
Frankly,
you don't need to be waffle stomping
poop.
We have,
we have systems plumbing in place to
handle that and I sincerely hope they
use it.
So thank you for the question submitted
from Danny Kelly.
This clip is just fucking amazing.
I have never seen this.
And it's one of my favorite things I've
ever seen.
I gave me so much joy and so much
laughter and I share it with you all
today.
Shit.
Fucking how these shouting at Berg
fucking bird shit.
Fucking mouth and it like takes it in.
Oh God,
it's so bad.
Tom and I went just as hard as I
crumpled the kid.
The kid.
When are you going to start taking
Jesus?
Seriously not give me 50 cents 10% I
know that's what Jesus wanted.
I think it said in the Bible it said
when disobedient crumple children with a
powerful punch to the chat.
Hmm.
This is a weird on hello ron for the
cube.
You guys may remember him from my recent
or not a little,
a hd video we made about this really
weird kid channel where he's got this
crazy voice,
but he reviewed one of ilos products and
a here for the queue for the QP.
I love,
I kind of want to do it.
No,
you're me and what this guy I know if we
can keep what?
Do you understand what he's saying?
No,
it would be really strong.
Strong,
strong.
I I want that fucking scares me tightly.
Tightly.
Kids don't want no nine more feel so
tiny.
Oh No.
Does that make you feel your light shine
tiny to Ku title bean and see what
you're not cutting it open at the box.
How do you feel right now?
I don't know.
Ooh.
T freeze.
Teed.
Ipr.
How's that tie night?
Tti freeze TV could have just gone with
like a NASA,
the tweezers.
This just so weird.
What did the gloves loves?
Shiny bright likeyeah.
Diamone shiny,
bright likeyeah thought your mom.
God.
What is wrong with
you?
I kind of want to do a know your meme
though.
I want to try to reach out to them.
If you are watching this,
which you have a feeling he'll see it is
email us around the cube.
I want to connect with you.
Dude.
You're the weirdest fucking guy I've
ever heard of in my life.
But uh,
anyway,
he was very gracious and he put a link
in the description and stuff,
so that was nice.
But my God,
I,
I'm scared of him.
He's got a nice following,
like 70,000
views.
Is that his normal viewer siblings?
Let me take a look and see.
Kind of used as this guy.
Usually Paul this.
Oh,
it's the weirdest video.
It's us as this trailer.
What the fuck we've ever seen?
Steve's channel name is run for the
cube.
It should be a month from like you've
got him.
I'm funny man.
Oh,
he hasn't made a video and this was the
last few we made two months ago and then
six months after that.
Holy Shit.
This guy is obsessed with us here.
We're in his trailer.
His last video he made,
he's hunting us down with those tweezers
and gloves on.
Yeah.
Cube Ron for your life.
Just take out the cute trailer goofing
on you.
Oh Wow.
Oh Man.
I guess run for the cute wait,
look at another video again.
Remember the vision for the next couple
of weeks.
Have you guys ever watch,
watch people kind of talking about this?
Oh Hey,
Yay.
Run from the hill.
Yeah,
that was crazy.
Um,
there you have it.
How did that make me feel?
He reviewed your,
uh,
I guess honored,
honored.
Cool.
And then Ella,
did you want to talk about the rip and
did Teddy Fresh Club?
Yeah.
So there was a rape and dip and 30 fresh
collab,
which is crazy.
You've got picks.
Yeah,
it's on there.
They're under your video.
Where's my,
and here's our model.
That's me.
I said to you,
Ella,
thank you for being progressive in using
a plus size model.
We all really appreciate that.
And um,
so,
and this will be coming out next week.
Do you not have a better picture of the
[inaudible] right Mystro,
the closeup.
There you go.
And I just wanted to say that we're
gonna be doing a meet and greet in their
store in La on sunset boulevard.
No Fairfax Avenue that you just type,
rip and dip and they,
yeah,
yeah.
But what is it?
It's Saturday at 11:00
AM they're going,
uh,
so a limited amount of time talking
about the 13th of October,
right?
Yeah.
So noon,
Saturday,
October 13th,
four four oh one north Fairfax,
avnet.
We be there
slinging some teddy fresh and ripping it
up.
And then it will be dropped online the
next day,
Sunday on their website.
Very nervous.
I'm excited.
Oh,
cool.
I love it,
man.
It came out so good.
This is there.
There a mascot,
the cat.
So the cat and the bear teamed up and
they're crushing it man.
Um,
and finally,
thank you to all of our sponsors.
We have a little sponsor button on
youtube that you can smash to the
support us.
Thank you very much to those of you who
have done that.
Thank you everyone who has a watched the
podcast.
Whoa.
Love you so very much.
Thank you Ian for the presentation.
Thank you to Cognac.
Very cool.
Add a,
have a blessed and Friday.
That's about it,
right?
I mean there's a,
I mean that's it,
right?
You know,
I mean there's more stuff but it's close
to two hours.
Yeah,
it's worth close to two hours.
I start to lose steam at two hours.
Two hours gets bad.
And that's when I started talking about
like pedophile priests and stuff and he
was like,
oh,
we already snuck in the music.
Oh,
you already,
you're already playing me off the booed
stage while guys join us next Friday for
another episode.
Looks pregnant.
She's still be pregnant.
Probably,
or not so weird.
I don't know.
I'm just saying that people are so
stupid.
I'm,
I'm being played off right now.
I know that I can't hear the music,
but my family was like,
no,
don't say anything.
They'll 10 weeks.
Yeah.
It's like,
come on.
My family said,
don't say anything until four months.
I say,
don't say anything until the baby comes
like halfway there.
I say,
don't say anything until a year to make
sure the baby's healthy.
You know,
we're in this journey together.
We've been very vocal about the process,
so we don't see any reason not to
continue that trend.
Guys,
next week we'll hear again,
have the blessing to beautiful Friday
evening.
The weekend is upon us.
We made it.
Thank God it's Friday and remember to
give 10% boy.
Otherwise you're going to get punched in
the chest by your pasture.
Thank you for watching.
Have a blessing.
Beautiful weekend and remember this
safe Papa john.com.
All right,
we're good.