I agree.
Look who's back again,
this guy and his wife,
couple of people just sitting at a table
talking about also known as a podcast,
that podcast guide.
Today's episode is sponsored by Meant
Mobile Felix Gray Hymns and Robin Hood.
God blessed them and God bless you.
Yes to you watching right now,
me know Dan.
Bless you too,
Dan.
Bless everybody.
I'm blessing the world.
Thanks dude.
Dan was walking back.
No,
that's how everyone felt though.
Touching souls here.
Dan.
Bless you guys.
Give us a ring at eight.
Oh,
eight hot meme.
One lucky color will get a chance to
play.
Know your meme.
That's right.
So it's fresh online to win a brand new
Samsung Galaxy s nine.
Compliments of Samsung featuring run for
the cube.
Yes,
run for the cube.
Does the legendary green beloved candy
surgeon hit me with some of those sound
effects.
Was a pipe refresh their memory if we
could.
More sound,
but that's great.
Excellent.
Next week on Wednesday,
we've got the two legends with Thompson
and Christina p.
they're back
on Wednesday the seventh at 4:00
PM.
Guests,
what's also back to suggestions,
thread
read on our subreddit if you have
questions for those two lovely people,
leave them there and excited to announce
bill wirtz,
the incredible youtube legend.
He is a youtube legend.
He's doing.
He's on an island in a sense.
He's creating some of the best original
creative content I've seen on youtube.
I'm not much is known about him
actually,
which is I'm super excited to meet him.
Have him on the show.
That's at a couple of weeks from now.
I'm very excited about that.
Thank you guys.
Halloween,
uh,
how was your Halloween,
Neela?
Very boring.
Yeah.
We didn't even have one person knocking
on the door.
Not One.
What happened to Halloween when I was a
kid.
It was like a block party.
I was telling Isla I walk.
I see kids these days with little
pumpkin buckets.
That's cute.
I used to walk around with a fricken
pillow case because I was out.
Candy.
What is currency at that age?
Are you kidding me?
That's like getting once for the Strip
joint.
No,
I could imagine because in Israel we
don't do it,
so I don't,
I've never experienced it.
I loved candy.
Well you had a little taste of it
because,
um,
we were walking down the street.
There is nobody there.
The Sun is like set.
It's a beautiful.
People have decorated,
you know,
and there's one some kid
and,
and I'm like,
dude,
we only saw one kid,
super long suburban block,
just one kid and two parents.
And I was like,
that's just,
that's so crappy.
What's going on?
That is bizarre.
Just one poor kid.
I was like,
I'd be embarrassed about that kid.
Where's everybody?
Um,
but anyway,
there was,
you know,
how people,
when they're not there,
they bring,
they have a little bucket that says,
only take one.
So me and Isla,
we're walking our dog and somebody was
kind enough to put out one of these
buckets and we took one and it was a
joy.
I have to tell you what the joy wasn't
an enjoy.
What Kennedy did you get you a gummy
bears,
gummy bears.
I got the uh,
milk duds.
That's,
that was always my favorite.
The milk duds,
uh,
as starburst person,
but as I,
as I get older and I eat milk duds,
I realize not good.
I liked the flavor,
but it's such a Schlep to put those down
is the Carmel just gets everywhere.
Damn.
As a kid,
you don't give a fuck that you eat those
like aspirin.
When I was a kid,
reese's cups that,
that was like the Bitcoin,
the one candy there would always be
like,
you get this huge pillowcase and then
over the course of a month you would
have like whatever,
eat everything,
have little kitty diabetes,
and then all this shitty candies would
be left that you don't like.
So the ones that I,
there were always left for me where I'm
nerds hate nerds.
Oh Dude.
I hate nerds.
They're these sour little pebbles hate
nerds.
They're so lame compared to a male
judge.
But that's what I'm saying.
Yeah,
you would,
you would broke,
you would broker the shitty candy with
other people.
Be like,
you want some nerds?
And they'd be like,
you want milk duds?
And I'm like,
no,
this is,
this is like a little less than in world
trade.
You know what I mean?
It was a beautiful thing.
So the suckers like these little shitty
suckers you get in doctor's office,
like give me a break.
There's cock suckers in this planet that
are giving out.
Like I remember someone giving up
pennies,
and I remember people can and got like
fruit and I'm like,
oh,
cool for you dude.
You're doing a little protest against
candy on Halloween.
You get a fucking life on another day.
Yeah.
But I love Halloween and sadly,
I don't know.
In La you just have to know where to go.
I guess our neighborhood was literally
empty.
Yeah,
last night at the same thing.
Not even an exaggeration.
It was actually empty.
But I hope you all had a wonderful
blessing.
Halloween full of spooks and streets.
I've got some great halloween footage.
Just share with you guys at the top of
this beautiful Friday afternoon.
Uh,
I just remembered I did want to give a
shredder or update.
A lot of people still think that it's
poop.
Oh No,
no,
just because I say it sometimes I just
want to say stop doing that.
He's a good boy.
Now.
He's a sweet angel.
He's a big boy.
He doesn't need this.
I don't want to misrepresent shredder.
No,
he's not a shitty leader.
He hasn't eaten shit and I know he
doesn't do it anymore.
One day he was like,
Hey,
you know what,
I'm going to stop eating shit.
And wasn't that a great day for all of
us?
Because sometimes he come and lick you
right in the mouth and you'd be like,
dude,
cute.
And also I can taste shit.
You just eat shit.
Like threw in the towel,
but I love you.
Anyway.
That's kind of what parenthood is,
right?
Probably you just shut my mouth and I
love you.
So we spoke about these gracious people
that leave the buckets of candy in the
front yard that says only take one,
but as you may or may not know as
Halloween is new to you,
there's always some piece of crap that
dumps the whole fricken bucket out into
their pillow case and it just,
it's not right.
It's not right,
but here now I've got some clips of my
favorite that I've found of this year.
These are all fresh of parents getting
in on the good spirit.
Halloween,
no isla take.
We are about to have a kid,
so notice on the good parenting.
Now I want to feel.
I want to point something out.
This sweetheart.
Take one.
Exactly.
The kid has a sweet,
pure heart.
He reads the sign and he says,
I'll only take one.
I'm a sweet,
pure soul,
but life.
This is what happens when life gets to
you.
You become this lady and here's why.
One Hand not,
not only for the bucket full can be.
What is he going to deal with it?
She's scooping it like it's her life.
Depends on it.
And she got the poor kid like that's the
example that he has to follow.
I know it breaks my heart because he was
a sweet kid.
It's like it's just candy lady.
What is,
what is he saying?
Like,
no,
at the end there.
Let's see.
I'm curious.
He's like,
Mommy,
Halloween
sacred.
The kid is saying,
mommy,
come on.
Oh man,
that breaks my heart.
Yeah.
I said,
mommy,
come on.
You can only take one.
Good.
What a sweet soul.
What do you mean?
What's the,
is still candy.
It's insulin.
You know what I mean?
Uh,
what are they,
you know,
this kid,
this kid is not,
doesn't have a good shot of coming up.
Right?
But he has pure heart and I love that
forum.
When your eight year old has a better
moral compass thing.
Also don't people under like I always
see videos of people stealing packages
from front doors.
It's like,
you know,
that everybody has like,
ring now we're all watching them.
People didn't catch up yet.
Yeah,
we're watching.
Um,
so there you go.
You know,
stealing it like her life depends on it.
I saw one comment on the video that
said,
what are the chances that kid sees any
of it?
That candy?
Yeah.
I'm wondering too,
because is it for her?
Why would she care about that?
And just buy a candy.
You can get so much candy for like $1 at
Ralph's.
Yeah.
Also the sales the next day are freaking
nuts.
So here's a family that ran sensible
little a pick me up on this Friday
afternoon,
ring.com
monster.
Yes sir.
Okay man,
this is a few years later.
The kids got used to it,
but it's like,
Yo,
it's not a riot.
There's flooding.
There's not a Zombie apocalypse.
Some fucking snuck one in the house.
Look there.
Well,
gender,
that's like,
come on,
let's go.
You don't rob people on any other day.
That's what you're doing.
You're robbing.
You don't go feel shit.
What happened?
They left the little girl and she's,
they opened the door.
They left the little girl.
Yeah.
Ooh,
I missed that.
Great parents take note because we have
a lot to learn about parenting.
I can't wait to ransacks.
And uh,
and then finally,
um,
the theme of Halloween,
this one is old.
Do you sometimes wish that April theme
of,
you know,
dressing up in a costume.
These guys were promoting a musical and
Ninja turtles musical and they started
talking about wanting to bang April and
there's like all these kids there who
are like turtles,
mega fans that I was just blown away by
this clip.
It's a y and incredible thing
was the turtle.
Actually.
That works for me,
but April was a turtle.
Do you wish April?
Actually,
that works for me so far.
I've been trying to talk her into an
inter species relationships for months.
She do it.
No,
she can't hold her breath long enough.
You know,
want to run
sprain on April.
That's not Canon.
That is not part of the Ninja Turtles.
Laura.
Hey,
April.
You want to ride?
You want to have an interspecies
relationship with all four of us.
Too Bad.
You can't hold her breath long enough.
I'm going to drown her in ges.
Well,
because the turtles aren't in water.
You know they walk around the earth.
Did they mean that they think she says
they can't hold her breath long enough?
I assume he means because turtles are
water creatures.
I've gotten beaming because they think.
Why would that?
Why would she need to be underwater?
Because they stink.
No,
they'll hold her breath.
Oh,
I don't necessarily understand the
application,
but it doesn't seem right either way.
You can't hold her breath long enough,
I assume because they're drowning or in
com.
So a bunch of fucking heavy sectoral
here.
You know what I mean?
Look at that.
Look at this.
Kids on the left.
He is traumatized.
I love that black sweater with the two.
Yeah,
that was pretty bad.
Uh,
I love that.
As far as good at this poor kid on the
left,
man.
He,
that no kid should see.
Hey,
because you know,
every kid has a kind of a crush on April
because she's kind of a hot cartoon
character and he probably wants to fuck
April and now all of a sudden he's got
to imagine his turtle friends blocking
him.
Yeah.
He's ahead of his time.
He's like,
this is a me too.
Me Too moment.
Donna Tello.
Yeah.
Panels are going to perform their hit.
Did you want to change?
I love to.
The kids
cut to the kids dramatize.
It looks like an adult just like,
Damn Donna Tello.
Did you want me to say something?
I'll see you after to say that being in
a report type for me not to analyze,
and a good thing about these guys
is that they're huge turtle Cox.
They might be turtles,
but they're hung like a horse,
so there you go.
Happy Halloween.
Everybody.
I'm feeling better by the way.
Thank you for asking.
Still have a cough that is just brutal,
but let's talk about Isla.
Who's pregnant?
[inaudible].
How are you feeling?
I feel okay.
No morning sickness.
No,
you're gaining weight.
Gaining weight.
I'm not fitting in my pants already.
And didn't you?
I have to say this.
You got fucking bat dog.
I have to say it,
dude.
Why do you say daddy's got fucking math?
That's not good there.
All right.
We're talking about being pregnant.
You know,
I'm just.
I'm just noticing the changes that are
happening to your body.
I Guess Daddy.
Oh,
we got our first ultrasound.
We saw the baby.
You're thickening up is my point.
Like it's.
You get.
How much weight have you gained since we
found out like a five or six pounds.
It's pretty amazing.
Something that.
No,
you look.
Did you look amazing?
I just want to say you look so
beautiful.
So radiant.
You look amazing.
You were like,
I'm telling you,
you're free.
Even like to think it's amazing that
you're pregnant.
Yeah.
And so we saw,
we saw the little pipsqueak because we
did an ultrasound and I'm here.
I got a video for you.
It's such a trip to me.
Uh,
you can see the heartbeat in this whole
fucking bought this little fuck.
And the doctor said he looks like a
gummy bear.
Yeah.
He's a little gummy bear.
He,
she,
I don't know.
But you see the heartbeat right here.
Here.
Let me pull the screen up
thing man.
That's inside Ila.
That's not crazy.
And it's like moving.
Yeah,
he's swimming around.
He's legs are wiggling and shit.
So crazy.
So this is the head and the body and the
arms and legs are starting to form and
he's got a little heartbeat.
Good to go.
That little guy is cooking up in your
stomach.
It's so weird.
How does it feel like that?
There's like a license life growing
in you and so weird because I don't feel
it don't,
but like do you know that it's there.
It's crazy.
It's pretty magical,
I guess.
I don't know.
It's like,
yeah,
what we're meant to do,
but it's so insane.
It's interesting how we're so removed
from nature in a way that we find like
birth to be so magical,
but it is magical.
Yeah.
It's really something.
I just fuck it.
We just did it.
You know what I mean?
Now there's a little heartbeat inside of
you and are we run the danger of gushing
over our kids and nobody cares.
I'm already gushing over this little
because I saw people.
I'm asking for the baby updates.
Right?
So I guess let us know because I know I
hate hearing about other people's kids
and I,
and I was like,
everybody does.
And it's like because you don't,
you know.
That's true.
I never understood how special it feels.
Yeah.
And so I don't know for already running
that danger.
It's like an ultrasound.
It's like I already loved that little
gummy bear looking at him.
He's dude,
his heartbeat is so strong.
His heartbeat is so strong.
What they say on the DNA test at the
super athlete body,
a super athlete heartbeat.
I'm telling you,
he's going to be president someday.
I want to wish I wouldn't wish being
president on my worst enemy.
Talk about the worst job in the world
right there it is,
man.
Isla is doing great too.
You are doing great.
You get a little tired.
Sometimes.
I get really tired and I,
I get pretty hungry and then eat and
then I'm like,
then I'm ready to sleep.
I'm kind kinda like a baby.
Like I'm eating,
sleeping.
You have a life for sucking your energy
out.
You have a foreign.
You're a host and I do have cravings for
people who were wondering if it's true
or not.
So like all of a sudden I really feel
like eating something Mac and cheese
this morning or I'll really not feel
like eating something.
Mexican food.
Yeah.
It's so weird.
It was like,
I don't want Mexican food anymore.
I'm like,
what's up?
Usually I love it.
It's like all wheat this morning.
She's like,
Ethan,
you need to make mack a treat.
Cope,
and I did.
It's like,
Oh,
I was walking straight and all of a
sudden I'm like Mac and cheese.
That's what I did.
But the interesting thing is about the
cravings is that I wonder if there's
really some actual science behind it.
We're there is because there was one
week where all of a sudden every night I
want to add a mommy.
I feel aware.
Yeah.
And so soybean and it's,
I think it's really good for you to be
so and,
and now I'm completely over it.
I don't,
I can't touch it.
Interestingly,
that was before we knew you were
pregnant,
but I was,
I dunno,
but like you were craving Mac and cheese
and I wonder if you needed like calcium
and the vitamins and all this dairy and
stuff.
Some awesome.
Even butter and cheese,
fat,
lots of fat,
you know,
very cool man.
Very exciting stuff.
You know,
but I have so much appreciation.
I really do know that you are raising
this child and your stomach and you're
going to give birth to this child.
I'm really afraid of that guys have to
do is not.
There's nothing easier in the world and
nutting I think I'll be okay until like
the fifth month or something.
But then things started to get hard.
I'm scared.
I'm scared of that part.
I know you're scared,
but I'm excited because I know it's
going to be fine and I know you're going
to be great and I can't wait to see the
transformation and everything and all
the changes and like you growing,
it's going to be so wild,
but I understand you're scared.
It is scared.
I'd be scared too if it was me,
but I know everything's going to be
great and I'm looking at like maternity
clothes and it's so not my style.
It's got to be hip.
Oh No.
What am I going to wear?
I already don't feel my clothes.
I wonder if there's any Gucci,
maternity pants.
We can get you all swagged out.
And we started looking at baby stuff.
We bought some baby clothes for our
friends and they're like so freaking
cool and obviously way more affordable
than like adult clothes.
And I was like,
Oh,
I understand why you have multiple kids.
It's like,
I'm not going to let this sit close.
Go to waste.
I'm having another kid just so I can put
them in this dope ass clothes again.
You know?
But I swear to God,
I'm just like,
I'm gushing over ela because it's just
amazing.
I know.
It's amazing.
I shear so cool.
Seriously.
Something else,
man.
So there you go.
There's a baby update for you.
Let us know.
It's too much.
You know,
if you're over.
Stopped with the baby.
I get it.
He's got a heartbeat.
All babies have rp.
No,
but not all babies have a heartbeat like
that one.
Did they all look like a gummy bear?
No.
By the way,
that heartbeat is like a sick.
I could tell he's got like rhythm and
soul too.
Like this guy is artistic ash unit is
empathetic.
Like you're a warrior.
Basically.
Gandhi mixed with everything out of the
best things you can imagine.
Boom.
Right?
They're presented with the opportunity
to steal a bunch of candy.
He would take one politely.
Say,
no,
Daddy,
let's get off this.
Now I'm pushing it in too long as the
title of the episode indicates,
Post Malone is under fire by the media.
Now,
let me preface this by saying that post
Malone has become so popular,
so successful this year has been
incredible.
I read something that he has been the
most streamed in the most popular
musician of this entire year.
He is the biggest musician in the world.
Two thousand 18 or maybe the United
States,
I don't know,
but like combined with his first album,
his first album.
You guys,
Baroque Michael Jackson's thriller
record for being on like the top 10
billboard for the longest consecutive
weeks.
Okay.
Do we have no internet?
Oh,
I have internet.
You know,
I think so Dan.
I have Internet.
Thank God we have a backup system for
them.
Anyway,
so post Malone has been wildly
successful and I would say he has
critics,
but from the fans and the people that
consume his music,
he always loved you.
Always had gotten a lot of shit.
Yeah,
he's gotten a lot of shit.
But the people who give him
shit are kind of like the old guards.
These,
these,
you know,
but the fans,
the consumers,
he's beloved because he's such,
he's got such a great personality.
He's such a chill dude.
He,
he,
you know,
he's just a great guy.
There's,
there's no question about that.
Never claimed to want to make anything
more than just some good music.
Right,
exactly.
And this article is exactly,
that's the problem apparently
problem that this Arthur seems to have,
and this is in the Washington Post,
so this is a big reputable.
This was shared with me by a lot of
people.
So I think a lot of eyeballs fell in
this article.
The problem he seems to have is that
he's not woke enough of some sorts or he
sees Postville and success as
symptomatic of all of the problems in
the world and he makes all these grand
comparisons to like conservative
movement.
It's very political who he makes
comparisons to him being like Donald
Trump,
the factory setting it then info.
It's somehow like,
now we all need to judge him,
right?
Um,
that he's pro gun or like an Apoc,
you know,
like a doomsday or whatever you want to
call it.
It's all,
you know,
use to paint this picture that he's some
sleeper,
conservative outright troll I think is
kind of somewhat
to tone for sure because there's
not really any proof to support that.
So they kind of try to build this case
using things that aren't really direct.
Right?
So they don't really come out and say
it.
But um,
the thing about Austin that I know is
that he's never tried to do or be
anything.
He's just making music that he likes.
Exactly.
It's from styles that he likes and
everybody is like,
if you don't like his music,
if you don't like,
it's like,
I don't know,
I just.
The thing about this article,
like it's,
it's interesting and it's worthy of an
analysis of who he is and why he's
popular now.
But it's so mean spirited.
It's so mean.
Maybe you should read some from the
beginning.
Well,
let me show you.
First of all,
really pop this open.
The video is so obnoxious.
Okay.
Let's start with this post malone.
You think you know,
but you have no idea.
Also,
the title is post Malone is the perfect
pop star of this American moment and
that's not a compliment.
Sounds like one God,
that sounds like a nice.
I mean,
why don't you just say what you want to
say that?
Yeah.
Because she is the author.
He or she,
Jeff Weiss is trying to make this point
of like he's perfect because of Donald
trump and everything.
And this is why he's.
Let's watch this video.
Thanks for having me.
I,
I'm just so,
uh,
you're just so likable and I,
I really am interested in your story.
You might know post Malone as the
soundcloud rapper who went triple
platinum for his debut track,
White Iverson.
You might know him as the genre bending
artists combining country.
Granted,
you know,
pop in just about every since
also raped babies.
No.
Okay.
Or You may not know him at all,
but you should.
Malone is huge.
For context,
his album,
stoney beat out Michael Jackson's
thriller for most weeks and top 10 on
the top RMB dies.
That may surprise you.
In fact,
this talentless a hack actually dethrone
Michael Jackson.
Do you understand the artists a bit
better?
Born Austin,
Richard Post,
he became post malone the same way.
Donald Glover became childish Gambino
through rap name generator.
Malone wasn't always focused on.
Absolutely.
Music is very eerie and in,
in,
in anything.
It's like crunching the numbers a little
fucking spooky,
a little.
Something's wrong here.
He learned how to play guitar by playing
guitar hero.
I started playing a guitar because I
felt cool with the controller,
so I says,
let me do the real thing in Hollywood.
They're part of a heavy metal band.
He credits Bob.
Dylan is one of his major influences.
Executives.
Record company.
Republic records have described Malone
as the Donald Trump of hip hop because
quote things that should have killed his
career.
He only made him bigger.
So here they're trying to make an
unjustified parallel between him and
trump.
Things that should have killed them.
Only made them.
I didn't even know what they're talking
about.
This was one dude's quo,
but they're just even just by being like
post Malone,
Donald Trump,
even though they say it again in another
context in the article.
So like they're kind of,
almost subconsciously in a way being
like he is Donald Trump and he supports
Donald Trump and you know,
they make it like everything's got to be
political,
but he likes guns.
Yeah.
It's like if you're a liberal,
they say like,
if you're a liberal and you believe in
resisting Donald Trump,
then you should hate post malone.
And it's like,
no,
it's got nothing to do with politics.
Twenty 16.
He said he considered playing President
Donald Trump's inauguration fast.
Wow.
That's pretty much in 2016.
Wait,
I don't even.
I guess you.
Yeah.
What did he know about trump back then?
Like,
nope.
Yes,
but also if a president asked you to
play the inauguration and it's few years
ago too.
He wasn't,
by the way,
in 2016,
his first album hadn't even come out.
He wasn't a megastar every word he said
wasn't dissected.
Did it seem like,
uh,
somebody asked him.
He's like,
yeah,
I probably did like,
Oh,
this mother fucker pizza gate,
you know,
it's like God damn,
I didn't vote.
Oh,
he didn't vote.
A No vote is a vote for trump.
He's not woke enough.
How has that damning?
He's fucking also,
by the way,
this interview took place when it was
like 21.
He's 23 now.
Why political would make it a political
standard.
Our votes don't count.
Malone
is a second amendment comment by the
way.
They're just like,
watch this,
and then they go into.
He likes guns.
No,
really?
Yeah,
he likes guns.
You guys.
Hey.
Oh,
we got mentioned here.
Top comment.
Watching this h three video right now.
That's when people used to like us.
Those were the days a large collection
of guns on the personal front.
He's friends with Justin Bieber and has
even opened for him on tour.
Did somebody say Justin Bieber?
He's Canadian.
Did you know that he.
The babies in the ass?
No.
No,
he does not do that.
But what?
What does that,
what does that like what,
what?
I don't know.
Somehow they're turning everything into
like having a negative tone even though
they're just saying like,
did you know that he's physical
accomplishment.
He opened for Justin Bieber tour.
Exactly.
Showing him on Jimmy Fallon.
Like that's a problem.
So you know,
that.
Did you know that he has tattoos on his
face often associated with criminal
gangs?
Was it true that like Justin Bieber
talked you into getting a tattoo?
I figured because we were working on
stony and then um,
we had a tattoo artist come through and
then it was just like,
you know what,
Justin Bieber's got some tats and I love
you,
but I know I'm way tougher than you.
Why would they show that he's kidding?
He's obviously kidding.
But like what?
So what is living cut it off before the
laughter of the audience.
I just don't understand.
So this is the video.
This is the kind of preface this toe
that sets the tone.
It's like,
wow,
point with this video is entitled.
You think you know,
but you have no idea.
So what did I learn?
He likes guns.
He didn't vote.
He's friends with Justin Bieber.
Wow,
let's send this guy to prison.
Okay,
well now let's get on with this.
Weird to see such a,
like that's a hate base,
right?
As much as,
as much of a hippies as you can make
without being like so obvious about it
because they constructed a way that
people who are sympathetic to them don't
see happen.
Manipulate too.
So we see right through it.
Exactly.
But it's very normal.
Washington pulse,
obviously.
He's a liberal of liberal leaning paper
and I'm like a reputable.
Oh Yeah,
Washington Post is like on par with New
York Times.
I mean just one of the most famous
newspapers in the world actually owned
by your boy,
Jeff Bezos by Amazon.
But this is the op Ed and this is not
like.
I don't know,
it's probably got a lot of traction.
I wonder if has views or anything.
But um,
you know what?
I'm going to read this article.
It's time for a break,
so do not go away.
We're going to dive right into this and
mount a defense of our good friend,
sweet angel posts Malone on this
blessing Friday.
See you guys soon.
Big wireless doesn't want you to know
that there's a way to cut your wireless
bill down to just $15 a month.
Introducing the disruptor meant mobile.
I love these guys so much and what
they're doing.
Okay,
these guys are changing the game.
They are everything that's wrong with
wireless providers,
cell phone providers.
We are talking about saving thousands of
dollars every year without sacrificing
quality of service meant mobile changes
that fricking game.
They be mail your Sim card,
you pop it in,
boom,
you are good to go.
There's a little guy and they're
changing.
The game memo will take us.
It's so easy to cut your wireless bill
down to just $15 a month.
You use your own phone with any mint
mobile plan.
You can keep your old number along with
all your existing context.
You choose between two,
five and 10 gigabyte l,
four g lte plants.
No more paying for unlimited data that
you'll never use.
Every plan comes with unlimited talk and
text and if you're not 100 percent
satisfied meant mobile has you covered
with our seven day money back guarantee.
You've got nothing to lose.
Give them a shot.
Ditch your old wireless bill and start
saving today with mint mobile to get
your new wireless plan for just $15 a
month.
Plus,
free shipping on your Mobile Sim card,
go to mint mobile.com/a
tree that has meant mobile.com/age
three.
Cut Your wireless bill to $15 a month
and get free shipping on your Mobile Sim
card@mitmobile.com
slash [inaudible].
I'm telling you,
this is changing the game.
It's just as good.
They all use the same network.
These guys are just hooking it up.
You don't have to pay $100 a month
anymore meant mobile.com/h
three.
There's a lot of debate about whether if
you sitting in front of video games and
computer screens can actually damage
your eyes and I'm sad to say that
research is starting to show that the
blue light coming from screens can kill
you.
No,
I'm kidding.
They did not necessarily will kill you,
but it can give you discomfort,
dry eyes,
blurry vision or headaches.
The discomfort is real from sitting in
front of screens and now the technology
exists that you can keep your eyes fresh
with a pair of Felix.
Great glasses available with or without
prescriptions.
Let me tell you about this sweet little
babies,
Felix,
great a couple of the life.
Say they filter out 90 percent of high
energy,
blue light,
and eliminate the glare coming off all
the screens so you can be the ultimate
gamer broccoli assassin that I know it
resides in each of your soul's usually
it seems like a hassle to have to
protect your eyes and that's why most of
us don't do it.
That field is gay.
Grasses are an easy fix.
Get pop them on.
You can feel your eyes relax and even as
the action ramps up on screen,
you're following the action.
Guess what?
Your eyes are chilling behind these
beautiful blue light filtering,
Felix gray glasses.
And here's what's great about Felix Gray
glasses.
They filter blue light without the
Yellow Lens Tint.
They are handcrafted from premium
Italian acetate.
That's right.
Do you hear how fancy that word is?
Acetate from Italia.
In fact,
it's pretty stylish too.
Uh,
yeah.
Felix wearing glasses are available and
non prescription prescription and reader
versions.
You got it all folks.
Here we go.
Take down your competition with the help
of some Felix graves.
Go to Felix gray glasses.com/h
to protect your eyes today with free
shipping,
free returns.
You got nothing to lose.
That's Felix gray glasses.com/hie
felix gray glasses.com/h
three.
Listen,
some of you are losing your hair.
I know it sucks.
All right.
Here's the solution for him.
[inaudible] dot com slash age three.
That's it.
These guys specialize and keeping your
Dang hair before it falls out.
Okay?
Because let's face it,
you're in the shower and you're and I,
you know there's hair coming out of your
head.
It's got to be scary.
It's freaky.
Let's face it,
get on over to [inaudible] dot com slash
h three and let's do something about it.
Because with science,
you don't have to watch your hair flow
down the drain,
like a scene from psycho.
Okay?
Let's,
let's avoid that.
Here's the deal.
They've got well known generic
equivalents to name brand prescriptions
to keep your hair.
This is the real deal.
A prescription solutions that are backed
by science,
so there's no waiting room,
no awkward in person,
doctor visits.
You're going to save hours by going to
four hymns.com.
It's easy as it can possibly believe you
answered.
I,
I'm speaking all over the place.
Answer a few,
uh,
quick questions.
Dr.
[inaudible] will review and prescribe
you products are shipped directly to
your door.
Okay.
Or right now my listeners get a trial
month of hymns for just $5 today while
supplies last.
See the website for full details.
This will cost hundreds if you went to
the doctor or a pharmacy and who's got
time for that anyway when you can just
go to for himss.com/hp.
That's for him.
[inaudible] dot com slash h three
forums.com.
Robin Hood is an incredible place to
learn how to trade and to trade stocks
and even Cryptos etfs options.
They've got it all and here's the best
part about Robin Hood.
What should makes some Robert Hood
Commission free?
That's why if you're a beginner or even
a pro,
it's a great place to come trade and
it's a great place to come learn how to
trade because it's a lot of people.
It's like a speaking Greek as
Shakespeare.
Once famously wrote,
um,
probably was him,
other brokers charge up to $10 for every
trade,
but Robin Hood doesn't charge a fee.
Okay.
That adds up.
Folks,
it's designed to be easy to use and
understand the show you charts and
market data,
place to trade and just for taps on your
smartphone.
Robin Hood's wed platform also lets you
view stocks,
collections like 100 most popular
entertainment,
social media curated categories like
female ceos,
which I am fully diversified in and
analyst ratings of.
Buy,
hold,
sell for every fricken stock.
It's the perfect place to learn to
trade.
Learn how to invest as you build your
portfolio.
Discover new stocks and track favorite
companies with personalized news feeds,
custom notifications for price movements
so you never miss the right moment to
invest guys and hear their offer is out
of this world.
Robin Hood is giving listeners one free
stock like apple or sprint to help build
your portfolio.
Boom,
one free stock.
That's chattered cheese and the fricking
and the Guac dude,
that's Guac and Cheddar and your bowl.
Sign up at age podcast dot Robin Hood
Dot Com.
That's h three,
podcast dot Robin Hood Dot Com.
Get started today.
Welcome back everybody to the h,
three broadcast.
Love.
Thank you all for sticking around.
Back to the article.
I don't understand this.
They start off by saying Dallas,
him.
What does that mean?
Him Low
regardless.
The most popular young artists and the
most unpopular young nation is a
rhinestone cowboy who looks like he
crawled out of the primordial swamp of
Nacho cheese.
I'll hand that to them.
That's pretty funny.
But Post Malone well,
okay.
He's making fun.
He says he looks like he's a little
sticky.
People have said that a lot about them.
I can tell you he doesn't stink,
but regardless here it goes on.
This is when it gets mean.
Post Malone is a Halloween rental,
a removable platinum grill,
cubic zirconium proposal on the jumbo
screen of a last place team.
I am getting mileage out of that.
A English degree right there.
No,
he's like that.
By the way that I mentioned.
I went to college,
uh,
his music,
one of the shallowest bastardization of
rap to date.
And I do not say that lightly type
ticket from Mr,
which was basically him saying,
I hate everybody.
White German for white.
Literally.
Jeff White.
Yes,
Dan.
He's an authority authority on rap,
on the rap music.
Your last name is a white dude.
Mind your own business.
Dan said that,
not me.
I don't care.
I don't see race as the creative tension
of associates at a down town.
Dude,
stop with the analogies.
Has the creative tension of associates
at a downtown law firm complaining that
a hundred and $50,000
a year just doesn't cut it?
What are you talking about?
Just getting to the point.
He looks like he clubbed over that.
It looks like it was clubbed over the
head by a cartoon.
Peacock.
He just turned 23.
So poetic.
Alright dude.
This guy so bitter.
He's so you could,
you could taste is better and America
just can't get enough.
And somehow in that sun insults that.
Well,
yeah,
because in his mind the only reason that
America get could like this guy who he
who went to college and is so in tune
with the hip hop and knows what's good.
The only reason the only way that
America could,
could like him is if the world was just
upside down.
Enough sense.
Kind of like Donald Trump did.
We mentioned possibly Nielsen recently
named a the suburban Dallas raised
rapper 2018 is the most popular
musician,
so it was only a matter of time before
malone had his own festival of
contemporary rite of passage for nearly
every major pop rap star who has his
face plastered across spotifies get
turnt playlists.
I'm sure he's on other playlists than
get turnt.
More like most popular songs.
How about that one asshole get termed
the inauguration.
Post-Defense was held Sunday night in
Dallas's Dos equis pavilion.
Watched it like,
oh,
and did it have to be on a beer?
And it was a less a festival than a
behemoth.
What is sae a?
Do you know what that is?
Dan?
Rush mixer held on a few acres of
corporate branded concrete.
Many festivals pride themselves on
offering non musical diversity diversion
such as art installations or novelty
culinary options.
That sounds awful.
There were none of that here though.
Just $5.
Jello shots.
That's exactly what I want.
When I go to a show,
a novelty culinary option.
I think the essay is a reference to a
Frat by the way,
so he's just saying like a.
it's like a frat party.
I think he's confusing a.
A concert with a farmer's market.
The shot,
the concerts that I usually go to remind
me of.
Calabasas farmer's market.
There were a little to separate.
There were a little separated from
regular postal and concert.
Other than that,
the big name opening acts and true
religion sponsored post Malone Bandanas,
featuring an extreme closeup of Austin
post itself.
Glade squinting as ever.
What is wrong with having a festival?
That's him plus other big artists.
Is that the first festival?
You know,
it's not that easy to put together the
crazy through that together.
So I know he was working on it a while.
I don't know what he's comparing it to,
but maybe in five years they would get
crazier.
You know,
honestly,
compared to a Lollapalooza,
this thing sucks.
There was no novelty.
Arts and crafts stations.
This should have ostensively been a
coordination is unequivocal.
Ascension to the a list pops
superstardom of mano named visionaries
do stop.
There are artists who dictate the Zeit
geist and those who reflected possible.
One is to the ladder,
an Avatar of algorithm culture that
rewards pleasant banality over the
creative leap.
Vexing.
I need to.
Oh,
when I'm listening to music,
I want to be vexed.
I want to be confused,
or it's like you're trying to figure it
out.
It's.
I mean,
this guy needs to be thinking all the
time.
Sorry about my cough.
Guys.
I'm still getting over this illness and
his own festival in his hometown.
He had the opportunity to lucidly stayed
his mission and values.
Instead,
he revealed himself to be Jack Johnson
of the Ada weights and nakedly grafted
hip hop.
So I love that.
He's like running for office.
Okay guys,
here's what I believe I read.
He's like,
he didn't reject trump.
And tell everybody to vote,
you know what I mean?
That's kind of what he's saying.
Right.
He had the opportunity to state his
mission and values.
Like I feel like that's what he's
saying.
He's like,
unlike Jay Z and beyonce who say they
hate trump and urge everyone to vote.
He didn't actually want to say that,
but that you know what the thing is.
That is kind of why he's popping and
I'll tell you why because young kids,
they may already have their mind up and
then maybe politically motivated,
but this article is part of the problem
in that it politicizes everything.
And Post Malone is decidedly
unpolitical.
He said even two years ago,
he doesn't vote and he's a young guy.
Okay.
First of all,
but like you,
it's nice.
It is nice to separate politics from
some fucking thing because it's
literally everywhere.
You know what I mean?
You don't need to be preached to all the
effing time and is doing it as a
decision.
That's what he,
that's what he wants and like it because
he's trying to have fun because the
point is that he's trying to have fun
and that's his personality.
When you hung out with him and you know
you don't have a political conversation.
Well this is just.
Yeah,
but Isla,
you basically today,
right now on this live podcast,
have the opportunity to lucidly state
your mission and values.
Right?
So
what do you believe in Isla?
Or are you just a naked,
grifting hip hop slang,
slang,
slang by 9:30
PM,
chance of posting,
filled the APP amphitheater,
15 year old blonde girls in days.
Daisy do that.
This guy wasn't there the whole time.
I guess he was there every minute like
these,
you know,
these youtubers that could jake,
Paul Kohn,
although those guys,
or at least having fun kind of in a way
this guy's like back there with a
notepad.
Let's look at all these young kids
having a good time.
He didn't even state his values.
He didn't even give us his mission,
state markers,
values.
He didn't even tell me to vote.
Postman did not want to tell me to vote,
you know,
fucking asshole who was this guy has no
friends by the way.
Maybe he does,
but they're all like,
I have a feeling when they're,
they have dinner parties and for dessert
they'll lay in a circle,
knows to ask and Fart in each other's
face.
It's like a snake.
Like,
okay,
you guys ready for dessert?
Let's all get in a circle.
And then you put your nose right in
your,
uh,
your partners asked and then you fall
dinner back in each other's face because
they liked the smell of their own farts
as the joke.
Arrogant.
It was just what I'm trying to say.
I'm by 9:30
chance of posts he filled the
amphitheatre,
15 year old blonde girls and daisy dukes
and champagnes and blunts shirts,
shrieked as if postpone.
We're next to the lineage of backstreet
boys.
Girls that I wanted to fuck,
but sadly will never have the
opportunity,
the Jonas brothers or one direction.
The main difference this time is that
they honored their hero with matching
temporary face tattoos,
barbed wire on the forehead,
a knife like crucifix.
On the cheek and his trademark phrase
inked and cursive.
Stay away and rest.
Easy temporary faced.
Yeah.
I know a bunch of gang members with
their rose in Troy Aiken,
jerseys and beer bong,
Bentley.
March,
a merge grunted with Siemian Glee.
1,000
people rocketed up,
stood on their seats for a brief moment.
There was palatable fear of being
stampeded the death at postmortem
concert,
which of course requires the deceased to
be buried in a racecar shaped coffin
wrapped in the rockstar energy drink
logo to it.
Are you trying to be funny?
Three M and m's song served as his
intro.
Oh,
I love that.
They make this about race watch,
presumably a tested nod to his fandom,
but also a heavy handed reminder that
postman was the most popular white guy
and hip hop since Marshall mathers.
Who the fuck criticizes a m and m at the
moment when the hysteria seemed in
danger of laney posts took the stage to
definitely tears.
Scorching jet flames and billowing
clouds of smoke like a groupon version
of a kiss concert in 1975.
A group on version.
First of all roof.
There's no group on version you when you
get groupon,
you go so you can get a discount.
You get a disk,
you see kiss.
Your analogies are all twisted.
Buddy.
You should have said a dollar store
version because group on gets you into
the show.
That was a weird one.
You know what?
Get me.
Maybe you need to go back and finish
your degree.
Big Shot.
Groupon version,
sipping from a Red Solo Cup.
He soon began slurring too young.
He's like,
he's not.
He makes it sound like he's so drunk.
He can't say anything to talk about.
Now with a voice like bong water
bubbling and the casual misogyny of a
member of a red pill subreddit.
What the fuck?
Come on.
So here you go.
A direct connection to like some
outright red pilling.
It's like,
dude,
that's in your mind.
That's not what's there.
I actually can't read it because he
believed everything out.
My whip fast,
my bitch bad.
I guess I skirt,
skirt that coop fast.
My coop fast.
Your bitch.
No,
my bitch slow should do what I say so.
And she always keeps me on my toes.
Those lines are as good as any
representing weapon alone is working on
a lyrical level will have to say if he's
picking out the most misogynistic stick,
red pilled Eric's lyrics,
that ain't,
that's not that persuasive because
that's gonna be a real task to start
looking at lyrics.
So hip hop.
Yeah,
I mean,
and the truth that like Kendrick Lamar
who is applauded by all has a great line
and from his new album where he says
he's fears being judged by his,
um,
his most baselines.
You know,
and if this is the best you could find
through this,
not,
that's really not convincing me that
he's a red pill subreddit,
you know,
on recordings,
his falsetto is afforded a modest four
cylinder strength,
but on stage it comes off slurred and
sloppy.
Switching like roadkill,
twitching,
like roadkill,
limp off.
Key notes underscored by a booming
backing track that operated like a life
preserver.
I'm going to get amped up tonight.
Who was left up tonight if I forget the
words because I'm too drunk,
helped me sing along.
He told the crowd is the same applause
line that he used at Coachella is entire
set list was essentially identical to
what he played at every festival all
summer long.
Right down to the mono Cylo syllabic
curse laden between song,
babbling about haters,
the importance of
rocky raking out.
That's what caught.
That's what's called a set.
Pretty normal.
Yeah.
That's why it's called a set.
If you're like,
he's been doing the same thing for 10
years.
That might be interesting.
He's been doing the same thing all
summer.
It's called a set.
He tours a lot.
You've got to know.
You know,
you got to set.
You guys hear that the rolling stones
played painted black at their concert.
I love that.
Post Malone dare to come out with a set.
When I go to festivals,
after I'm done with my arts and crafts
booth,
I like to enjoy spoken word.
It's different every time it's performed
as if as if the people coming to a show
don't want to hear the fricken classics,
and by the way,
that guy has two albums.
It's all there.
You know what I mean?
Even if it's voice barely slithered
passed the 10th road.
It doesn't matter if fans who knew every
word,
they were there to commune to songs such
as better now,
his latest anthem and interchangeable
heartbreak,
presumably made for streaming at that Wa
who's fished up those kiosk and lax
wet.
Uh,
the problem isn't necessarily that it's
crass,
but that it's meaningless.
I thought he was crashed.
I thought it was a red pillar.
It's not that it's stupid,
but it's vacant.
It's the losing difference between
appropriation and outright theft.
Woo.
So there he's actually accusing him not
just of a cultural appropriation,
which is a high charge enough but
outright theft.
And by the way,
this music is only fit for streaming at
Wa.
Who's fish taco kiosk at lax?
Did he get a kickback from the Taco
Kiosk?
Does see this guy is involved in big
fish taco kiosk money,
by the way.
I know this article upset him too
because he tweeted out,
fuck you.
The same day it came out,
which I presume was in response to this
article because you know,
it's like,
dude,
he's not trying to be anything.
He's not.
He's not trying to be,
he's not being a fraud,
he's not being,
you know,
he's being authentic,
so if you don't like it,
I understand it's not for everybody,
but it seems to bother you that
everybody seems to like about you,
but you have to make it seem like it's
the fabric that's tearing our country
apart and it's really not.
I personally find articles like this to
be more damaging than anything possible.
Loves doing it.
It's not his fault.
He's popular.
He's doing what he's always done.
He's making music.
He likes people,
liked him and they attached to him and
they like what he's doing.
It's not his fault.
He's popular posts.
It's like,
okay.
He didn't cheat his way.
The top yard in Postville as music is
dead eyed in ignorant,
astonishing Dole and it's materialism,
abandoned an abandoned lot of creativity
with absolutely no evidence of traffic
and it's cerebral cortex who you are so
smart.
You are so smart,
and there's also a negative side.
Wait,
wait,
this was all good.
Even if it's intention is sincere.
Homage,
the blood during wet.
What lists limit imitation can't help
but feel like minstrelsy good verbiage,
verbiage here,
wait for like a minstrel show,
like face kind of thing,
right?
While people will inevitably appropriate
the most culturally relevant music
genre,
one that's becoming almost interlink,
intrinsically bound to the modern
conception of pop,
but it's not asking too much to attempt
modest synthesis or the incorporation of
a single new idea,
or at least to not be so grotesquely
desolate.
We went from eminem to Cheddar Bob
[inaudible].
Shout out to Cheddar Bob.
If posted one were black,
he wouldn't have sold half.
He simply wouldn't exist.
There you have it right here from Bob
Weiss.
More and more we don't read the thing
and you get the idea,
but I just think it's just,
you know,
it's a little dramatic.
What's most,
what's most damning?
This post Malone's bloodless abyss of
soul and funk.
How do you have a bloodless attempts at
being emotional feel like hallow
gestures?
It goes on and on.
I'm president at a bullseye on his head.
You could go to right here,
plus most problem Postville.
His problem is that he isn't a bad
person or even completely untalented.
Thank you.
Thanks a little towns lists.
I'll,
I'll admit this,
you're not completely on talented.
Um,
it steady stands for nothing at all.
I think almost in a way could for him,
you know,
because music doesn't need to be
political.
Not everything needs to be political.
He's an entertainer that's supposed to
be an escape.
He can afford to feign the swagger and
cool and hip hop when it's convenient
and opt out when it's time to see who's
writing for the cars.
It's always been a fairly
straightforward compact when it comes to
hip hop.
If you're a white person eating off of
what has historically been black
culture,
you have a certain obligation to repay
that creative debt.
Eminem continues to attack.
The hypocrisy is and contradictions that
allowed him to leap frog equally gifted
artists.
That's a strong statement.
Macklowe or may have lex subtlety or
rudimentary understanding of when to
share text messages,
but there are no questioning.
His dedication to confronting his white
privilege.
Even g eazy repeat,
even g eazy dropped out of that racist h
and m advertising campaigns.
So here you have it,
you know,
one more.
Can you say,
um,
yeah.
Post Malone so perfectly represents,
is idiotic currents that have carried us
into this present cultural submersion.
We're an objective notion of the truth
has been systematically muddied.
Come what?
That's not a stretch.
Come on.
Trump lies,
therefore,
post Malone as popular.
Damn facts aren't negotiable and any
hint of criticism and be it for lacking
integrity,
dignity or talent can be brazenly
dismissed as the pitiful cries of
haters.
So congratulations.
I guess who allowed this to happen?
What a whole new system allowed this
grease.
Discarded.
Barbecue,
a wrapper to prosper if fake Pale king
sitting on a tin foil thrown returned to
sender.
Oh my God,
you're so bitter.
Dude.
I love how bitter you are.
Who allowed this guy to write pitchfork?
He's like a,
here's my English degree.
And um,
here's a list of all the.
I couldn't believe how many it was when
I was reading it.
Like that's what articles are.
I feel like there's,
you know,
I feel like there's a point to be made
here,
I'm not agreeing with it,
but I understand if somebody wants to
make a point,
but,
but to be so mean and better to comment
made it into an Arctic.
Right.
It's like an elegant youtube comment.
Um,
you could make the point that like pop
music is vacuum,
but one,
you wouldn't be the first person to make
that point by a long shot.
And two,
it's not like he's even like the biggest
example of that.
I mean,
you know,
he's competing like he compared us to a
post unfavorably to one direction and
like backstreet boys,
it's like,
that was just as vacuum.
Like their lyrics aren't fucking deep.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Yeah,
hit
me baby.
One more.
You know,
it's the same.
Even write the music.
They were like fucking fully.
At least he's a songwriter.
Exactly.
I'll admit he has some.
He's not without talent.
I don't know.
The guy is just a dick.
He just seems like it.
And people who don't know anything about
him read this and.
But you know what,
that's,
that's part of the game.
The bigger you get as part of the game.
But the good news for Post Malone is
that he's got a lot of love and a lot of
fans.
And it's funny you say that because if
you compare him to his contemporaries
and my opinion has music is a cut above.
It is more,
it's nicer,
it's better I think.
Yeah,
whenever we put like a random playlist
of like top top hits or whatever,
well I can't stand most of them.
Yeah,
I agree.
I mean,
and again he,
he,
he makes it seem like he owes a debt to
hip hop.
And again that's a whole theoretical
debate.
I don't know.
But what if you're going to talk about
that?
His genre is not.
Exactly.
He's not really a wrap merge of.
He doesn't.
What actually he does it wrap.
He doesn't wrap.
He said even in the video they say his
biggest inspirations.
Bob Dylan.
I mean he's closer to rock and roll.
Then he was like hip hop or rap or like
rnb maybe.
I don't know,
but he doesn't know.
Anyway,
whatever.
So there you go.
I read that and I was like,
damn,
this is a dick and he's wrong.
And the thing is,
he's,
he's so desperate to make it political
because most of them doesn't.
He's just not a political guy and they
hate that.
So if anything,
you're the problem buddy.
Musicians are political.
I mean there's a lot,
a lot art mean a lot aren't.
A lot of them are a political,
a lot of them just want to stay out of
it.
Well the problem is that he's posed with
guns screw spooky and he's from Texas
extra spooky.
So like,
um,
a lot do speak,
but as part of this whole,
you know,
it's so obnoxious man,
like let people be a political.
He can be a problem with that.
Just let him be like,
you don't have to drag everybody into
the fight.
If he doesn't care about politics,
does it have to force it?
Like,
I don't know.
And he's a young guy too,
like he's focused on music.
He's not reading about maybe later in
his life maybe he wasn't exactly.
No one needs to force it.
And like,
he likes guns,
like again,
you can be on either side of the
spectrum and be pro.
That doesn't mean he's not in favor of
sensible gun laws.
I don't know what his political stance
on that is one way or another,
but it's like let some,
let people be unpolitical.
Maybe he votes and maybe he cares about
politics,
but like,
just fuck.
Just the people that listened to him
want to chill anyway.
Spoke enough about that.
Love only love to my boy posts alum.
Um,
and it doesn't smell.
He doesn't understand.
For the record,
he does not stink.
I want to clear that up.
Let's clear the air.
Smells good?
Well,
I haven't smelled him.
There's no smell.
There's no suits.
Neck and took.
I took a big old stacks.
It was good.
Yeah.
Dance.
He hasn't washed his nose since.
I'm all right Ron.
So guys,
it's time to play.
Know your meme.
That's right.
The biggest game on in the world.
The biggest game in the world.
Hands down.
No.
Me.
Yes.
Today's guest is legendary.
Run for the cube.
We've got him.
He's recorded eight different phrases
for our lucky color and they have to
guess what he said.
Okay.
They got to get five out of the eight.
Correct.
To win a brand new Samsung Galaxy s nine
plus or retail value of a $1,000
for our lucky color.
So let's get started.
Here we go.
We've got chancellor on the line.
Chancellor,
are you there?
Hello?
You're on the air.
Oh yeah,
I'm here.
How's it going?
And chancellor or you feel unlucky
today.
Are you familiar with run the cube?
Run for the cube?
Yeah,
I'm feeling lucky.
BMP.
Yes.
Chance store.
I love to hear.
Now tell me about yourself.
Where are you calling from?
Well,
I'm in Tyler,
Texas.
All right.
And do you think uh,
you know what,
I was going to make a post malone thing,
but let's not get political here.
Uh,
I liked posty going.
Yeah.
No,
I like both,
but I think I just talked about it for
like four years now.
Tell me,
tell me,
have you watched a lot of run for the
cube videos?
Are familiar with his style,
his delivery?
Well,
without you guys was video like four
years ago.
I would never have known about him,
but I've seen a little bit of him,
but let me actually in our audience with
run for the cube really fast,
for those who aren't.
Oh Wow.
This one is 13 million views,
so he only shows around.
That's right.
That's his classic.
He only shows his hands green surgical
gloves and he takes a scalpel and
tweezers and dissects them as if they
were living creatures and the cadence of
his voice in the case that he has some
sadistic pleasure in it.
Let's see if nice to have a g line.
P like rat glue.
My Kanye love.
He's just a strong.
He's obsessed with eyeballs.
Be Brain surgery,
so there you have it.
That is
run for the cube.
As I said,
run from the cube was more more accurate
in some cases,
but with that being said,
chancellor,
are you ready to play?
Yes,
I'm ready.
All right.
Hit me with the tension.
Let's start from the top.
What is he saying?
Here we go.
Are you.
Are you doing for your mind?
Are you Chris?
That's there.
What did you hear?
Do I have options or what do you think?
I'll play it one more time on options.
The thing is if I give you multiple
choice,
that will be too obvious.
The guy speak in English.
Just got a chance.
Chancellor.
I'm going to play for you one more time.
Okay?
Okay.
Here we go.
Listen closely.
Are you?
Are you.
Are you doing for your mind?
Are you
good?
All right.
What did you hear?
Chancellor charge gibberish.
I thought he said something about are
you crying at the beginning?
I'll give you a hint.
Colby person is your hint.
Oh,
are you crazy?
Are you coming on the board?
Strong.
Great.
Pleasure that.
Hey.
Come on in this together.
Okay.
We got to navigate this guy.
Now let's move it on to round two.
Are you ready?
I'm ready as I'll ever be.
All right.
Here we go.
Chancellor,
for us newbies don't view where we keep
it out of you.
Yes.
Yes,
yes.
Yes.
What did you here?
Can I get it one more time?
Why did you make out any words?
Any words?
I think I heard Ethan in there.
Here.
I'll give you a hand.
Michelle Obama.
Yeah.
Wow.
Ethan.
Great moves.
Let's play it one more time.
You want to play it again?
Yeah,
I know that he knows.
Well you asked me will be key page view
because I,
I,
I see it written so maybe I know,
maybe it,
maybe it's not yellow.
It's one of those optical illusions
where and when you hear like the one
that was 70 anyways.
Well here we go because I thought those
two were going to be easy.
And this one,
this is the one that I thought that was.
That was the start with the freebies.
All right,
well you know you only need to get three
more,
right?
So you've got all the chances and.
Okay.
Here we go.
Theory.
I,
Mike,
Iraqi,
rocky.
Just for you.
Just by you.
What do you got?
I'm here.
I'm here in my garage.
Just bought my new Lamborghini.
It.
You're understanding you're entering the
cube,
getting put on your shirt.
You guys,
all of us still we love,
we love run for the cube and get.
I hope you have a green surgical gloves
on and your scalp already because we are
moving on.
Here we go.
I love the company.
That's a tough thing.
Is it?
Can I get it one more time or drink or
something?
I think I might have something but.
Well,
what are you thinking?
I heard I lie or I love it.
I like it.
And where does that lead you?
There was more.
I thought that's all.
He said.
Three words.
Okay.
Zap You with it one more time.
Me.
There you go.
Three words.
I love words.
I love.
Time is running out tension.
There's no hint.
Uh,
I love.
I gave you two of the three words that
is a hint here.
We call related to videos we've made.
Yes.
So I'll relate it to you.
What time call me?
I think this is,
I think where we're at a time.
Do you have a final answer?
Oh,
I love memes.
That's all I got.
So the real answer was I loved big
connect made famous by.
Of course.
That's okay.
Your three out of four,
which is very good.
That's an excellent record.
Um,
here we go,
this one is going to be tough.
So listen closely as if you are
performing surgery on a road and
eyeballs and clarity and focus.
So here we go.
I wipe from.
Yep.
Wow.
He thought he was more like you than
that.
I'm watching,
right?
Of
course he is a,
as all good men are taken from the
front.
That is right.
It's incorrect.
You want to live for the balls and
performance?
Scooping motion as discussed at great
length with those gloves?
Yes.
With the green glow.
So what are we at right now?
I believe it's four to one.
You need one more?
One more.
All right.
I got to tell you because there's,
there's,
there's three more.
So a lot of chances.
We got a lot of chances here.
Sorry.
Don't fuck this up.
Here we go.
What are you looking forward to?
Getting a new Samsung.
Do you need the phone?
Yeah,
Kinda.
Uh,
I dropped mine and cracked it up pretty
bad recently.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Is it a iphone?
I know it's a note eight.
So you're in the club,
so you're already in the Samsung Gang.
But it's A.
Yeah.
Well good.
Are you.
We're gonna.
Get rid of that.
Hopefully you got three chances left.
Hopefully.
Yeah,
we're gonna.
We're gonna.
Lock this down as,
as record.
I will say in your favor.
Nobody has ever lost around them.
No,
you're me.
It's totally not designed at all.
Right.
Here we go.
Hey,
can you guys sign the phone if I do?
Um,
yeah.
Yeah.
Just write on the glass.
I'll sign off on it or on it.
Whatever you want to give you some
germs.
Yell.
I'll use a sharpie and cover that.
That'd be great.
Alright,
here we go.
Well,
don't be counting your eggs yet.
I know,
I know.
I'm getting hooked up.
Be counting your gummy worms yet,
right?
You can use.
I wasn't looking at the words and I have
no fucking idea what he said.
Play it again.
Okay.
Please.
Until you can use to landline veto you.
Please tell me.
Do you have an idea?
Yeah.
This donut is slamming doors.
Wow.
Not only you are a winner.
Um,
you have completed the challenge
chancellor.
How does it feel to be the owner of a
brand new Samsung Galaxy s seven plus?
It feels good.
Honestly,
if I would've lost,
I still would have been happy to just
talk to you guys.
So you find what a sweetheart.
I love you for that.
I kind of want to continue.
We have um,
so we played the last two.
I've got a lot here.
Yes.
By all means here.
Let's go.
These are the bonus rounds if you don't
get all right.
So again,
you'll get merged.
Oh,
that's a good idea.
this round you get that's or a or
whatever you do you prefer?
Yeah.
Okay.
Uh,
uh,
really it's just either one.
Okay.
So here we go.
For every one you get correct.
From here you get something,
you get another item.
Are you fucking go?
Okay,
here we go.
No,
it's okay.
This is,
this is,
this is it.
Okay,
here we go.
We'll see you.
See,
we'll get them ready.
Papa cancer,
the best man
clip of millionaire,
the first guy.
That one,
who wants to be a millionaire?
He goes,
I want to use the last lifeline to call
my dad to tell him I want.
You got that swagger.
I love that.
Alright,
well you want.
What would you like?
What,
what do you want?
You want to be surprised.
That's one item.
Um,
well let's go ahead.
I'll take this one and then if I win the
second one,
then I'll have you guys surprised me.
I would love to have one of the,
uh,
the fascinating shirts.
We have one of those.
Dan,
welcome.
All right,
here we go.
When another item.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
You're crushing it.
Here we go.
Try to click it.
It must be no close family day because
he said,
can we play a quick game for a quick
wow.
Gansler winner?
The big winner here today.
Such an exciting day here.
Podcast.
So much happening.
So much excitement.
So proud.
Tell me,
what are you going to do now that you've
won?
Are you going to Disneyland?
Oh Man.
I'm going to go tell everyone that I
know of my friends that watch you guys.
I want to be bragging all week.
Well Chancellor,
I'll stay on the line.
I want to thank you for calling in.
You're a great.
Awesome dude.
I appreciate you being a fan of the
show.
We're going to hook you up with
fascinating and a surprise item and the
Samsung,
what you have won.
You've earned here today,
so thank you so much.
Appreciate you and have a blessed.
Blessed had Friday and a great weekend.
Thanks for calling.
Alrighty.
Thanks guys.
And congratulations on the baby.
And of course I want to run for the cube
who was gracious to participate with us
on this.
No,
your little legend.
I appreciate all of our members who are
legends in their own right,
who come and lend their expertise to us
and a love,
love,
love.
So thank you for the cube.
Um,
wow.
That was thrilling.
Shoot.
It's always really fun.
I love those.
I can't believe that we got him.
Yeah,
I know all the people.
He's for the queue.
That's right.
We've got a lot more to get to.
My goodness.
We've got quite an episode here.
My dudes on this blessed at Friday,
so next up is the.
Oh,
we've got the mom.
Let me see here.
I've got Kanye,
but actually we were going to do harass
the teachers suing her student.
Let me do that first and then we'll have
a in hop in here to give us a Kanye
update.
Kanye moves at light speed.
A lot goes on in that man's life.
So this is a story that blew my mind.
And listen,
I'm not,
I just.
This is not like a social justice thing.
I'm not,
that's not my angle here.
I want to say I'm genuinely confused by
this.
I'm just,
I'm perplexed.
I'm vexed in the words of the Great Bob
Weiss who wrote that article about post
Malone.
I like to be vexed at my concerts,
like to be like that when I relaxed in
the new music.
So there's videos on buzzfeed and it is
about a teacher who is suing,
I believe the age was 13,
still suing her 13 year old student for
making fun of her in class.
Um,
for being gay.
I guess.
I don't know.
It's really hard to tell from the video,
but it's so strange.
The whole story is so strange and I just
find it strange,
bizarre that buzzfeed is taking this
approach,
like they're doing a journalistic video,
but it really doesn't answer any
questions and doesn't.
Yeah,
and it's just,
it's why it's a wild ride that I want to
take you guys on.
So with that being said,
let us enjoy.
I was harassed by my student for being
gay on buzzfeed video.
Can you have with your students.
I really care that we accomplished
whatever we set out to do,
but I'm also the first teacher to
volunteer to get a pie to the face or an
egg cracked on my head,
like whatever it is to reward students.
One of the highlights of my job is the
fact that I probably laugh cry at least
once a day because the teenagers are
funny and if you let them be funny,
they're really fun.
Such she's drinking Pellegrino.
Wow.
That's fancy for a school teacher.
Usually you have to note that she looks
the part.
You have to note it from them.
Let's up.
We're all thinking it,
just saying she has a.
She has a cervical look.
Okay,
moving on.
Don't have to note it.
The thing is,
they were all looking at her and being
like,
alright,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
There's something going on there.
She's got a specific look,
you know,
that's okay.
Like if I saw someone walking around and
like a Pekichu hat and like a reflective
less than huge pants,
I'd be like,
oh,
that guy's a raver.
You know what I'm saying?
She's got to look.
That's all
is amy asked.
If I'm an eighth grade English teacher,
I've been teaching for about 12 years
now.
How the school system,
knowing that I've impacted a student or
had a good day in the classroom is
really indescribable because while
education does not necessarily pay well,
what it does pay,
um,
is knowing that you've had a chance to
impact future generations.
My goal is always to really understand
where students come from.
Bear in mind while they're,
while they're showing this and urbino
electron fit in,
great.
She's still selling a 13 year old
student [inaudible].
I just find that those,
that dichotomy of those two things.
Yeah.
You're assuming a 13 year old.
What the fuck?
What a person,
not just A.
I dunno,
I dunno.
This is so weird.
I guess because he,
he harassed her,
but the examples she gives doesn't seem
that bad.
It's more like for bullying,
her not harassed I guess.
Um,
but I guess let's,
let's let the do over and apparently it
didn't work
or a grade.
My story begins at the start of the
2017,
20,
18 school year.
I had several students approached me
privately out of concern to let me know
that a former student of mine who was
following me on instagram because they
wanted to keep in touch with me,
had taken a photo of me and my partner
and posted it to her instagram and let
my current students know that I was gay.
Prior to that,
I had never discussed my sexuality and
the classroom intentionally because I
know that I teach in a very conservative
climate and it wasn't something that I
felt I needed to share right off the bat
with students.
As the year progressed,
somebody,
somebody's picture them with their
partner.
Yeah,
and I can't imagine that's gotta be hard
to be a teacher and you know,
it's so weird.
When I was a kid there was no social
media.
Like I can only imagine like stocking
your teacher and taking photos and then
sharing it with all your classmates on
instagram,
like cad.
That's messed up so kids can be men.
So kids are straight up eve,
especially 13.
That's like the most evil age.
Absolutely.
You.
They're all.
Every 13 year olds have freaking psycho.
I mean the worst thing.
The worst thing I ever did do a teacher
when I was in high school,
I think it was our principal because you
such a Douche.
We like to Peter's House.
It's pretty bad.
It's not that.
It's not that bad is it?
I haven't ever done that.
It's not that bad.
We followed him home and we're like,
we found out where he is,
we're going to tap as hell.
Shit.
I did what they're talking about in
this.
I took pictures and yeah,
but there was no.
There was no fucking my space or
anything like that.
Like what did you take photos with a
camera when I was a kid and then we just
like draw nasty shit on it,
make fun of the teacher.
But this is like amongst friends.
This is sharing it with the world.
If you drew a funny picture of a photo
and that everyone at the school saw it,
right.
It just amplifies it times a thousand.
Right.
Hey,
so anyway,
I'm,
I'm sympathizing
me to let me know that this was really a
hot topic on the Internet.
It was a hot topic on campus and people
were continuing to discuss it.
I went to my administration multiple
times
in this day and age,
I can't.
I have a hard time seeing that.
That'd be like,
oh,
she's gay.
Maybe I'm wrong though.
She says she's scared of area so I
could.
It could be hard probably,
but also you're kind of the adult in the
situation.
Well,
at any rate,
no,
I'm not judging her yet.
Let's watch.
No,
that I was concerned about this and I
felt like things were getting out of.
I love the shot of her just walking the
area just like a.
and the initial response was that this
was the word that was used and that it
would die down and to be fair,
I hope so too.
Unfortunately that's not what occurred.
Okay.
So she says everyone hoped there was
drama with die down,
so it's not what occurred.
So what's leading me to believe that
somebody like started writing like slurs
on the door or like keying her car or
some shit like hate crimes.
Right.
Fix My mic here.
Okay,
so let's see what happens.
During that school year,
I was also pursuing my master of Arts
degree.
I have to maintain an online youtube
channel where I responded and reflected
on things that I'd read or activities
I'd completed.
One night I noticed that a flood of
students started to follow me on that
account and then I received a comment
that said,
don't be stupid.
Be a smarty.
You can join the Nazi party now
accepting dikes.
So that's good.
Haunt
this comment on youtube.
This is what she said.
Sadly it didn't end there.
She had one person write a rude comment
on Youtube.
We get like 10 times,
but especially it's like,
are you kidding me?
One every five,
every personal,
every defect I have as a person is
apparently,
it's almost a relief for me to know that
every negative attribute of my,
of my personalities because I'm Jewish
and that really actually takes the load
off.
I thought I was just,
I guess I guess I can't do anything,
but yeah,
no,
I thought I had a,
like a lot of development and maturing
to do,
but it turns out I'm just a job.
It's kind of a relief honestly.
Um,
but,
so this,
this.
What happened is this comment sets her
off down at the bench.
So weird because it doesn't even seem
personal.
Like to honestly honestly,
as someone who's been on the receiving
end of shitty comments,
like it's not that bad.
It's not personal and it's kind of like,
it's kind of just a stupid thing because
it's like the Nazis
are accepting dykes.
Like,
that doesn't even make sense.
It's just being cheeky.
Obviously rude and I entered what I
understand being upset by it.
But what happens is it sets her off on
this personal crusade of trying to find
out who wrote this comment a comment on
youtube.
So now she goes on like this war path.
And that's what was going on
my mic.
Okay.
It's
why is this thing not tight?
Little droopy did I don't understand.
Why is it true?
They got pills for that.
Where that.
Oh,
here.
I think.
Is your mic drooping?
I know I should do that during our
testing.
Why it's dripping.
It's dripping all over the place,
Dude.
Alright.
This is where the podcast is.
Good technical issues.
Coffee.
My exhale.
Fuck that.
So anyway,
she goes.
So if she just ignored the comment and
she was like,
she said it's just drama.
It'll die down.
But she goes on this war path to say who
wrote that comment?
And this ends up being her demise as far
as I can tell.
But like here we go.
I immediately took a screenshot and send
it to my administration and asked them
to sit down with me.
It took my administration month to meet
with me.
What do you want me to do with the
decision was made
someone at your school.
It's one youtube comment.
So like she,
she sent it to the principal and she was
like,
you haven't suspended anybody yet,
but anyway,
here,
let it,
this little app shut up.
I'm going to play the video about
tolerance to presented to the class
I did that immediately,
sent it off to them and unfortunately
they decided that they didn't like the
direction of the lesson and I was told
that it would occur later on what
someone else had a chance to review it.
I had started to experience some severe
depression and even more severe anxiety
about being in class because I felt like
I didn't know what was being said about
me or what was being done and I also
felt like I wasn't being supported or
kept safe the way that I believe I
deserve to.
It was this bananas,
this one comment.
Now all the sudden she's,
she's,
I feel like it's just not the right job
for her.
Being a teacher is tough.
You got to have like really tough skin
or you know,
especially like we said with their
middle school teacher.
Yeah,
he's our fucking brutal man.
Nobody's going in as a gay teacher in a
conservative area.
You kind of have to know this would
happen and you didn't know and she
purposely kept it.
Yeah.
But you know,
there's a chance that someone will find
out.
So I was surprised she was a teacher for
12 years.
I've never encountered anything like,
but I just find it you,
she said she's tougher toilet and she
had a meltdown over one youtube comment
and I just imagined like print the
carrying a print of it to the principal
and being like,
you need to do something about this.
Like what?
It's like I,
even if you sympathize,
it's like,
what do you want me to do?
Trace the Ip called the cyber police and
so I,
I can only imagine what that
presentation look like that they vetoed.
They're probably just like,
this is weird.
You're going to make a presentation over
one random comment and also you're going
to get worse.
Yeah.
Okay.
Everybody.
I saw this comment calling me a dyke and
saying that the Nazi party is accepting
and I want to know who was it,
and I put together a presentation that's
like inviting the old,
don't feed the trolls as they famously
saved,
okay.
By the
I asked my students to those shots Topia
during a presentation,
one of my students made some disparaging
comments about gay marriage,
which elicited quite a response from my
students,
a lot of excitement and looking at me
and definitely awaiting a reaction after
that.
Upon reviewing the student's written
work,
I noticed that some more derogatory
comments were used about gay people in
her work and I brought that again to the
attention of my administration and my
administrators felt like the best course
of action.
There was simply a teachable moment.
I contacted my union at that point.
From there it escalated to me getting a
regional rep involved from my union who
eventually hired me.
A lawyer.
Just imagine wanting to expel a student.
It's like you're ruining.
You're trying to ruin the kids alive.
It's like you're the adult.
I know they said something really mean
and rude and homophobic.
The 13.
Okay.
They're pretty ignorant,
but I feel like if she took it in a
different way,
maybe she.
Yeah,
maybe she could have turned it into
exactly something that would teach them.
Like you be tolerant about it.
What did you,
what did,
why did you say that?
What do you think?
Yeah,
but.
And then the principal actually seems
like pretty cool,
like even headed about it,
but like wanting like what is she?
She's like,
this person wrote something homophobic.
She's like out for blood.
Like you have to expect like the fuck
you know,
you're going after a kid man.
I mean they didn't threaten her or do
anything like totally insane.
And then the realm of normal child
behavior to be a Douche due to anxiety
and depression.
Amy took a mental health leave from
teaching.
Her case is currently being litigated
for what?
I haven't been in the classroom since
January and I would say that there are
two things that I missed the most.
First and foremost,
I love my colleagues.
I am lucky to work man.
It's like a commercial for depression.
She's just out there picking grass.
She's not in the classroom anymore.
Fuck
incredible educators in terms of
students and very sad that I didn't get
to read Fahrenheit 4:51
with them or be there for their eighth
grade graduation.
It was really challenging for me to miss
out on both of those things.
I don't feel frustration or anger
towards students.
I think that,
um,
as teenagers we're always,
you know,
they're growing and they're changing and
they're formulating their own opinions.
The onus really lies on the adults in
the system to do better.
And that's what I feel most disappointed
in.
I don't even feel anger towards the
adults in this situation.
I think that,
you know,
my ultimate hope is that everyone learns
and grows so that we understand that,
that
close up man,
buzzfeed shots way to close up,
show me the ear and Jiggling and picking
grass
next time.
A situation like this occurs.
We create a culture where
she's got a job up per of plural feed.
What do you call that?
Dan used to be a Raver,
right?
Laura?
Laura,
peace.
Love,
unity.
Respect,
right?
Yeah.
You got to do you.
You're not the only one that's partnered
for life,
baby
excepted and doesn't happen again.
Oh,
you walked at a screen.
We reached out to amy school for
comment.
We include an excerpt from the response
in the description.
You didn't want to show it to too many
people.
Okay,
so she.
She's suing the school,
not the student.
Is that.
Am I understanding that correctly?
Why?
I thought it was the student,
but it doesn't actually say it says.
Yeah.
It doesn't say.
It says [inaudible].
Litigation is ongoing.
I would think it's.
If anything it's cool.
I don't know why I thought it was a kid.
I remember reading that somewhere,
but I am an idiot.
I just don't understand what the school
could have done.
I don't understand what the litigating
is for.
I don't understand.
I don't even understand why this is a
video at all.
Yeah,
like there's no story here.
How is her making a youtube channel even
under the responsibility of the school?
Exactly,
exactly.
It's youtube.
Do people can find your videos.
Yeah.
And did she say she was a.
She made the youtube channel for the
master's degree that she was trying to
get.
So this is like an extra trip.
This doesn't even have to do with her
work.
How does she even know it was a student
who made don't know.
Here's a statement from a school's
boring.
It's very just what you would expect to
be very illegal,
but I'm just.
I just,
I wonder why this video even exists.
There's no information.
Nothing happened as far as I can tell.
It's like,
what?
What are you trying to prove with this
video?
She's out there.
Kids are assholes.
Like that's it.
She got us good.
Yup.
Got It.
This Day and age,
I was such a dick to.
My teachers.
Definitely took,
you know,
and they,
they,
they were adults about it.
They just,
I just moved on every time some one of
my students,
me,
I want
their life ruined and them to be
expelled from school.
Had to have to switch schools.
I want them in prison.
I want them at juvenile hall for any
crime.
So there you go.
I don't know.
Buzzfeed is like,
it's like,
did you.
You didn't even have to make this year.
There's a no story.
They just.
They had this artistic vision for the
close.
Yeah.
They're like,
we start with the closeups and we build
around that.
I had this vision of a bouncing,
hearing,
Chubby hand picking grass
art right there.
Yeah.
That is art,
isn't it?
There you have it folks.
I don't know why.
Well Shit.
Do we have to change the title?
We change it.
When we finished,
I was thinking the same thing.
Y'All got baited not as spicy.
No.
Not as spicy,
but still pretty spicy.
What else we got?
Kanye is back at it.
Ian,
do you want to come?
You want to come?
A decode.
Connie decoded.
I'm sending them in.
Here we go.
Here comes in.
Let me play you a song.
I got a song here.
Where is it?
Here we go.
Thank you man.
What's going on with my mic?
But it's drooping like my fricken,
like every,
like it's giving me flashbacks.
Don't need this.
My face did.
How do I fix this?
Hey,
and having mic issues.
Fines very.
This very virile Mike over here.
Yeah,
you're a young man.
You're a young man to know and is also
sick,
so I don't know how to fix this.
There you go.
Now I popped a couple of eds.
I'm upright.
I'm.
How's.
How's the sound right now?
Sound good.
Really isn't not supposed to been filed
that.
No,
that one's less directional.
Just popped a couple.
I took more than directed.
Commoditized.
Ian.
How are you today?
God bless.
And good evening.
Good afternoon.
There's something about you immediately
want to touch and stop.
Yeah,
I'm doing good.
I'm,
I'm back there.
Coffin to and places of fucking petri
dish of Ebola.
Um,
now before we get into this,
I want to say congratulate you.
I heard the great news.
You've been made an honorary moderator
of our Kanye.
Then youtube red,
which is,
but that's a,
that's a huge community.
Yeah.
They told me this morning,
so congratulations.
Thank you.
Now I know they got up to those guys.
I know the Kanye.
If a community is very important to you
and how do you feel about being given
this honorary title?
I feel like the queen kind of
[inaudible] because he was like,
you don't have to actually moderate.
We don't.
It kind
of was like,
we don't want you to.
Don't touch anything.
We want to put your name there and.
Wow,
that's cool.
That's cool.
Good.
They don't want me to start banning
people and digging around,
but yeah.
So I feel you're getting street craig,
you're getting acknowledged for,
for um,
there was also the invitation to the
Kanye podcast,
which is coming up.
Uh,
what's the name and when is that
happening?
So people can tune in a,
it's on the 10th,
I believe.
Next I'm going to record it.
I don't know when he puts it out by the.
It's called watching the throne.
Watching.
Yeah,
the premier Kanye West podcasts.
In fact,
the Kanye himself follows them on
twitter,
a recent development which has led us to
believe that Connie is a fan of Ian and
it's been a along as,
as happened with the purple hat and
everything.
So congratulations.
I'm waiting for you and it's going to be
against.
Yeah,
I'll be on there.
So watching the phone,
it's only a matter of time until I get a
knock on my door,
I open it and there's Kanye someday be
be a great guest.
Me.
I joked about it.
I said,
if Kanye ever comes on here as a guest
into going to sit here,
I'm not gonna say Shit,
I'm not going to be in the room.
I'm just going to.
Maybe I'll sit there and I'll just,
I'm not going to say shit.
Wash these two thought,
but be that as it may,
there's been a lot of Kanye development
actually.
Is this a good place to start in?
Uh,
yeah.
This is,
he tweeted this out.
He's trying to Kinda clarify his
beliefs.
Political beliefs a little bit.
Probably got tired of all the heat.
He was getting lots of heat,
lots of heat friends and family,
you know,
dumping him.
But he didn't really like.
I know I read these tweets and these,
this doesn't mean much.
Let me read you.
Yeah,
go ahead.
I would like to take my family loved
ones and community for supporting my
actual beliefs of my visual.
Is this before or after?
He disavowed,
this is before,
okay,
so I support those who risked their
lives to serve and protect us and I
support holding people who misuse their
power accountable.
I believe in love and compassion for
people seeking asylum and parents who
are fighting to protect their children
from violent ors.
I support creating jobs and
opportunities for people who need them
the most.
I swore prison reform,
I support common sense gun laws that
will make our world safer.
What I see this as [inaudible].
This is a lot of liberal kind of left
Lincoln leaning,
uh,
beliefs and I think he's trying to reach
out and be like,
Hey,
I don't disagree with you on these
points.
I just like Donald.
Yeah.
I think he's trying to,
um,
which is what I've said before.
He's not like a heavy political guy.
A lot of this is kind of vague too.
I mean like,
you know,
that's true.
I support holding people misuse their
power accountable.
That's like a fun thing to say,
but I don't know what that means.
I see it as me too stuff.
Oh,
okay.
Or like Wall Street stuff too.
But regardless,
it does heat up as he lives a lot of
room for interpretation.
Does d dot,
I mean,
I.
So here we go.
So now there was a thing called black.
What is blood exit in?
He's had this woman around him for a
while called Candice Owens.
She's kind of a right leaning political
figure and she's been very close with
him kind of ever since he put the hat on
and like in his circle going wherever
he's going,
she's always around.
Interesting.
So she has this thing called black set.
I hate saying the word,
it's not a good,
it's not a,
how do you say?
A elegant to say no legs.
It blacks it,
right?
Black say.
But I mean that's,
if you're trying to like combine the two
words that actually makes brexit.
It's a play on brexit.
Yeah.
Well because you need an exit,
like the equity.
But yeah,
it's like the black exit from the
Democratic Party is what she wants.
She wants everyone to leave and mass.
And uh,
so she put out merge and told people
that Kanye designed it.
And I think that was kind of the
breaking point which sparked all of
this.
Here's the logo and question actually.
Um,
and also I will say not a very well
designed a.
looks like someone's being crucified.
And Jim Merge.
Yeah,
it looks like some of my camp counselor
would wear and
not very.
Not very spicy.
No,
it's not great.
And so after that happened,
he came out and was like,
no,
I,
I didn't do that.
Yeah.
And you're,
you had an interesting theory about.
I think,
yeah,
all of this.
Everyone thinks,
oh,
he's like,
come to his senses.
Oh,
he's realized the error of his ways.
I think he just didn't want to be
associated with a shitty design.
Right.
I think that he's like,
I'm not offended at all by your
political beliefs.
I just asked Shit Week.
I don't want anyone to think that I put
my name on that.
Yeah.
What he said in response to this design
was actually something that has got a
lot of attention.
A lot of people interacted with us.
We'd have like hundreds of thousands of
likes and retweets.
And here it is.
He said,
my eyes are now open,
and I now realized I've been used to
spread messages.
I do not believe in.
I'm distancing myself from politics and
completely focusing on being creative
and that Brexit logo was whack.
He said,
yeah,
and the one before he didn't so well.
He said essentially he had nothing to do
with it.
So what do you make of this?
Is this a genuine.
And when this came out I just
immediately started everywhere.
Like everyone thinking that it's about
trump.
Yeah,
well that's what I assumed that it was
about like,
hey.
Yeah,
I mean that's really
the only assumption that make really.
Well that's why.
Yeah,
the so many likes and everyone
immediately went,
oh fine.
So he's back to,
you know,
just chilling out.
And that means he doesn't like
Republicans at all.
I think that was,
we both jumped in,
which isn't the case because he
clarified with TMZ,
which is the next thing,
but his statements.
So dramatic.
My,
how could it mean anything else when he
says my eyes are now wide open,
it's like I've just,
I've been awakened to this great.
A misfortune,
you know,
I think it goes back to like with the
first few tweets,
I think he does it on purpose.
He leaves things vague and interesting
to hear.
We have a,
what do we have here this,
so this is from the TMZ article.
They reported it and their headline was
something like Kanye has done with trump
and then he reached out to tmz right
away and it said Kanye contacted us to
make it clear he did not mention Donald
trump and his tweets and he's getting
out of politics altogether as for being
used.
He says he was specifically ref
referencing blacks and that's it.
So interesting.
So it kind of.
Let's see.
Is there a more,
uh,
you know,
there isn't more.
Well,
just more.
Is there anything genuine going on here
or is this just more of kind of this
Kanye trying to drum up attention?
What do you make of this?
He's what's happening here.
In part I think the honorary,
a moderator of our continent,
speaking for the subreddit Kanye Fan.
No,
I honestly,
I think that this may be why I have the
flu.
I'm like,
I'm tired.
I'm worn out,
I mean it just,
I just want the album at this point,
you know,
it's,
it's 20 days away,
is it?
Well,
if he's got a lot of work those out,
I don't know.
And then I can't take what he says.
I don't know if he means it.
Like when he goes,
I'm done with politics,
maybe that's this week and then he's
going to debut it and he's gonna have
the Maggot hat on again.
You know,
it seems that that's a common theme.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
We need a segments.
We can empower port credit.
It seems to be a common segment among
his,
a sentiment among his fans that it's
like we're getting tired of this.
Just give us the music.
Yeah.
And I,
and I don't also,
he can believe whatever.
I don't care about that,
but you know,
keeping track of it all.
Like you said,
it's like this whirlwind,
it's nonstop.
He's always in the news.
There's always things going on in it.
It's kind of tiring.
Right.
Also there was a thing this week when
easy as being like available for
everyone now where you're following
that.
Yeah,
he because he said a while ago that he
wants eventually to make it available
for everyone that's production cells out
and then you're going to go to resell
this.
Interesting.
So now I think it was available,
but then people were reporting that it's
not doing that well and they wonder if
it's because of the drama or which one.
All of the past models are the new black
one,
two models.
The last,
the release before the last one was the
biggest one he's ever done.
He's the most wide release ever,
so there were going to be shoes
available,
but people took that as oh everyone
hates Kanye now buying them.
It's just that's the most they've ever
made and I think it's the same case with
the new release to.
Got It.
But I did see a few people reporting.
Oh yeah,
that's because everyone.
Well you are wearing a pair,
you know,
not right now.
Not right now.
Okay.
Well Ian has already closed,
like easiest are fundamentally for
everyone and no one cares.
You don't care.
And then yeah,
they make it about politics of course.
And there you go.
Well,
Kanye is political,
so I guess,
but you know.
Well we thank you for keeping us updated
on the world of coming.
Yeah,
I know.
It's complicated stuff.
Keeping up with the Kardashians.
It is pretty much.
Do you think that Ken's reality stardom
has affected Kanye in the sense that he
saw.
Oh,
keeping up with the Kardashians.
Everybody cares about this kind of real
life drama.
Is that something that maybe lead off
into Kanye?
No,
I think he's always had a talent for
this and I think that's why they're so
great.
They're just these marketing machines.
Yeah.
So you know,
it's powerful.
Smell Ian's to keep your ear to the
grind stone.
Is that a saying?
Is that what they say?
I don't think so.
What do you keep your ear towards?
Your ear to the ground.
Oh,
ear to the ground.
To the ground.
Keep to the ground and I'll go listen to
the grind plate,
but listen to every one grindstone and
on the other.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Where's the song?
Sorry guys.
Everyone is sick.
Jesus did not breathe yet.
Don't break the law and the intern.
Everybody we love you and the enter,
he's wonderful guy.
He's an asset to the show and a boy.
Boy,
where would we be without one?
Would know a lot less about content,
that's for sure.
Twitch,
uh,
we've got a twitch streamer who had a
great little clip.
Um,
this is kind of funny because this guy's
not even a big streamer.
Oh Man.
Oh No,
nevermind.
It's not a racist.
He's not even a big streamer.
That's what makes it so great.
Oh my God.
This twitter clip has over 3 million
views,
but because what he says is just so.
And he's a twitch streamer that has
like,
well,
I don't know how big he is on twitch,
but he has got like 5,000
twitter followers.
So man
for streamers that I want to relate to
them.
I want them to be witty.
I want them to be cool.
I want them to have that unique aspect
that all of us strive to have.
Um,
but I need there to be a little bit of
time
coughing super loud in the mic because I
keep turning away that I want to make
sure I'm not,
you're raping everybody.
It's helping turn more if you can.
Yeah.
Or relationship because I don't want to
talk to a fucking wall.
Okay.
But will,
part of the thing for me is,
is I specifically don't want my viewers
to have any kind of relationship with
me.
So like that's like it kind of works
out,
right?
I'm Kinda like I'm hitting my goal but
I'm,
that's kind of a bad strategy which I
know I kind of,
I'm doing a live stream and I don't want
to be connected to anybody.
Maybe make videos.
No,
you totally are.
And as weird as that sounds and it's
like,
it's kind of like low key like God
complex kind of thing is I don't feel
like many of my viewers should relate
themselves to me because.
And this is like super,
like Kinda like I got caught like kinda
weird.
It's like I do think of myself as better
than,
or not better but like bigger.
This is going so there's no good way to
say this.
I think of myself as like above the
average person,
so I don't feel like many people could
relate to me as like bad as that sounds.
I know why.
Like what would even if you're so
superior and intelligent and like a 2:20
Iq,
huge rick and morty fan.
Why would you think that was a good idea
to say?
Sounds like such a prick.
You're just a fucking like ta also.
He's like not even a big deal on twitch
and it's nice just pulled up the social
worker who's got like 11,000
followers.
I just want to say I just want to say
this and I don't want you to take the
wrong way,
but I do have 11,000
followers on twitter and I do think,
and again this comes off bad,
but I am superior in every way.
I mean how many followers you have on
twitter?
What?
Like what?
Like 200.
I mean case in point.
You're fucking pathetic.
Damn,
this guy got reamed for this video.
How did you think that that could be
anything worth saying?
Also,
I like how he keeps referring to it as
like a gum God complex,
low key God complex.
It's like,
well that he knows that it sounds bad,
but it's like,
yeah,
it did because it is bad.
I can say that like what are you doing?
But I feel like he's flattering himself
in a way of like saying he has a god
complex too because again,
you're not,
you're not even justify.
You can't even have a god complex when
you have 11,000
twitter followers.
Like imagine.
Imagine that guy's a god.
Yo.
I'm so.
I do.
I am somewhat of a god complex.
I feel like a god complex.
So there you have it.
Twitch and apparently there was like a
video.
No,
it's just like kind of weird text.
Not Better,
but like no bigger than just long and no
good way to say this.
I think of myself as like above the
average person,
so I don't feel like many people could
relate to me as like bad as that sounds.
I know what a fucking idiot.
There you go.
There you have it.
Nice.
Oh,
this store is fantastic.
You,
you're going to love this specifically
you Ila,
um,
porn watching employee infected
government network with Russian malware
that the fucking title you've ever seen
in your life.
Listen to this shit.
Government auditors traced a malware
infection back to a single porn watching
employ within the US geographical survey
and the interior department watchdog
recommended the US Geographical Survey
Ratchet Up Internet security protocols
after discovering its network had been
infected with malware.
So I guess there's like a government
agency network that kind of connects
everything and they have really strict
rules about what,
how you can use the internet because
that's where so slick that Russia,
they're like banking on the fact that
some employees meeting off at work do.
Did you ever like put on porn at work?
I'm like,
why would you do that?
I'll say this,
I'll say that you have a lot of downtime
at work.
You can have a lot of downtime.
Okay.
It says that he reportedly used the
computer to visit 9,000
adult video sites that sell fucking.
That's a lot.
Like if I'm browsing Reddit,
you know,
at work and my,
my desk is facing the wall.
It's like,
yeah,
you see some titties on the home page
and you probably,
you probably,
you take a look but you don't do when
you're not.
I'm not downloading porn videos.
Not like augmenting my catalog.
This guy's like on fucking pornhub,
like downloading shit.
They said 9,000
sites.
How do you want that?
That's his job.
Watching porn is his job.
I don't know what he does with the
geographical services.
That's not just popping over to pornhub.
You either.
Are you asking if I got my dick out and
masturbate?
No,
you.
Yeah,
that's what I'm asking.
But I did exactly.
That's why I don't like watching porn at
work because it's like I'm not,
some people watch porn,
like it's like a cooking show.
So for me it's very.
When I put it on and let's be frank,
I'm not cleaning the pipes,
getting the poison out as they say.
And so,
um,
it's like that's kind of the reason why
I don't understand going to a strip
club.
It's like,
okay,
I've never been to a strip club and I
really have no interest because it's
like,
okay,
yeah,
what do you do?
Go home and beat off.
That's the same thing I was going to do
anyway,
saved the money,
watch some porn,
and then let some Russian malware.
But you got to,
you got to admire the ingenuity of these
Russian,
like cyber warriors putting like putting
ads on porn sites with malware.
I mean,
that's crazy.
That's amazing.
Um,
I love,
by the way,
there's like digital detectives that
they go.
Our digital forensic examination
revealed that the employee had an
extensive history of visiting adult
pornography websites.
The hosted malware,
a rope.
The malware was downloaded to the
employees government laptop,
which then exploited the USG s network.
Isn't that awesome?
This is the best episode of CSI ever.
The employee no longer works at the
agency.
We imagine trying to get his next job.
He had a good run having to say why it
was firing his next job.
He can host a porn site.
He's got 9,000
videos.
Um,
do you have a recommendation of me like
his next job interview?
Oh yeah.
So tell me what part do you like over
the last 15 years?
Similar scandals have enveloped the
environmental protection agency,
securities and exchange commissions and
irs.
Last year a DC area news network
uncovered egregious on the job
pornography viewing at a dozen federal
agencies and national security officials
have reportedly found an unbelievable
amount of child pornography.
Wow.
That threw me off.
I didn't expect that on government
devices.
Fucking hell.
What were the people watching child porn
and downloading it and they work at the
government.
Fuck this problem.
This problem is so prevalent that a rep
Mark Meadows has introduced legislation
banning pornography at federal agencies
three different times.
I don't think you need a,
uh,
what's the legislation going to do this?
God dammit,
you guys stop watching porn on your
government computers putting national
security at risk.
That's amazing.
I hope that in 15 years there's like a,
there's a story of like a movie about
this,
about like how the Russians hacked the
wine guy watching and dumb ass
downloading porn.
But I bet you isla of people that have
private offices have,
a lot of them have been off at work.
It's like,
well of course.
I mean,
you're not going to beat off in front of
people.
It's kind of nuts,
isn't it?
Yeah.
So like,
dude,
right here,
hey,
you're just like this.
We have seen those videos of people
doing it in the library.
Yeah,
that's why.
I mean,
those guys are deranged.
I don't have to say.
Yeah,
I've seen videos of like a drifters who
come in and just start beating it in the
library.
It's like,
Dude,
magic bean that depraved though.
You see some titties and you're like,
all right,
taking my dick out.
Um,
yes,
of course.
So we made it to the two hour while I'm
on.
I want to finish what we've got.
God it.
This is a lot of male bombers,
car whatever.
I don't care about that anymore.
Children Fight Club don't really care
about it that much.
Judge dredd pretty cool.
I'm parking intentionally break.
Oh,
this one.
I like this one.
I need to show you guys.
Party intentionally breaks the floor and
everybody falls through.
Now before I show you this,
I want to tell you that I read that
there was no life threatening injuries
and no fatalities as a result of this,
which is surprising when you look at the
footage.
Looks so horrific,
but it is hilarious.
And especially when you learn when you
read the article is that um,
they felt the ground shaking and they
were trying to break it.
Now that's a party turning up.
I don't know how to view it.
And so were they placed in the screen,
but um,
hopefully you can make that out.
Don't fullscreen the uh,
the window.
Just drag it to the,
to the right a little bit.
Oh No,
what I'm saying.
Yeah,
I got centered.
Is that good?
Perfect.
Okay,
so fucking hell.
So these guys are like,
whoa.
The ground's all wobbly and so everybody
starts jumping and attempt to actually
fucking break it.
And so here they go.
Having the time of their life and a
woopsie daisy,
a thin ice.
And now some of the people if you watch
some books.
So yeah,
but I mean there's like 100 people or
some of the people slanted standing up.
One Dude in the white shirt,
you'll see he landed.
He's like,
watch this guy in the white shirt here,
right here.
I think he slides down and he's just
like,
right here.
He's like,
what the fuck?
That's crazy.
Huh?
So there you have it.
Like the commentary just Yo,
that guy just almost fell to the ground
by the way.
I love that.
He's like everyone,
like the guy right in front of him falls
into an abbess.
He's literally at the edge and he's
like,
all right,
this is the presence of mind to just
keep rolling.
Yeah.
What a legendary cameras.
That's a new video.
Wouldn't you be panicked when you want
to get out of the room at that point?
Like maybe more of a idea?
No,
that's why you'll never be.
I love it.
I just loved it.
They were trying to do it,
you know that I grants Gretz lady drives
through marathon,
you know,
it's just a bunch of bids.
I'll save it.
I want to watch a lot of these with Tom
and Christina.
I think we'll have a lot of good bands.
Yes.
Should I have this message from the,
from the email,
but it's kind of emotional.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
uh.
Should I read it now?
I asked you so it's uncomfortable so you
can read it.
I can already say that I probably won't
be able to speak because I can't handle
this show's over.
No,
I'll sit here,
but I just am probably.
I can't really talk about these subjects
because I get too emotional.
Okay.
Nope.
You just give a shout out to the.
Yeah.
Hey,
we heard your message.
I thought it was such a sweet message
and a very wholesome.
It's very nice message.
So I want it to read.
It comes from heart bridges.
Hey Ethan,
in Isla and podcast crew.
My name is Hart bridges.
A month ago my mom was unexpectedly
diagnosed with stage four lymphoma.
She recently passed her second treatment
of Chemo.
She's doing pretty good,
but morale is low.
She was such an active person,
always working out and doing different
projects around the house,
but now she feels weak and unable to
accomplish anything.
We started listening to the podcast
together about five months ago.
We listed in the car sometimes around
the house and now at the hospital during
her six hour plus treatments.
We both find y'all absolutely hilarious.
Her birthday's coming up in November on
the seventh and I was wondering if I
could get you to sign a shirt for a pay
for the shirt and shipping.
If even you could just sign it.
She would love it so much and I know
it'd make her smile.
Just pick a great shirt.
She wears a large love Ya bark.
Bridgett Hart bridges.
Well obviously.
Yeah,
dude,
do we have his address?
I'll have to follow up.
Dan.
Maybe you can follow up and get the
address,
but yeah,
of course we are definitely be sending a
care package out and um,
I just,
that's so sweet.
I love this.
That they're watching together and the
mom,
I don't,
I love it.
I think it's so.
I wish you the best and I wish her momma
healthy and speedy recovery.
We know all too well ilow especially how
tough that is.
So it's very nice that you took the time
to write that and share,
you know,
it's not,
uh,
I appreciate.
I appreciate it man.
And I wish you all the best,
you know,
fucking life.
It gets tough sometimes.
Unbearably tough,
you know,
and it's an honor that we're able to
provide some kind of comfort for you
guys.
I mean,
that's,
that
means a lot.
I mean,
it really hearing that,
like this dude with his mom getting
chemo and watching our podcasts,
getting relief,
like all the shit we get and everything.
It's like you got to cut through it for
these kinds of stories.
Like,
no,
no.
I appreciate you taking the time right
then.
And of course we're be honored to hook
your mom up.
We Love,
love,
and appreciate you.
So thank you for reading us.
I'm not to end on a heavy note.
Should we watch a psychic slam dunks a
bunch of people?
No,
no,
that's very long one.
Um,
you know,
I guess there's a,
you have to assume that somebody likes
this podcast because people listened to
it.
If you listen to the comments and the
and go to a homepage on youtube or read
anywhere,
it feels like nobody likes this podcast
and everybody wants it to go away,
but somebody likes it.
I mean,
people will watch it,
right?
Mean there's a few out there.
This person likes it.
So I guess we should keep,
you know,
it's like.
Okay.
Right.
Well on that note we.
Did it.
Have a guys.
It's Friday.
It is Friday.
My,
what the F.
Oh,
this is our playout.
Sorry.
Can you mute it in my room at least
because I can't even hear myself.
There we go.
So everybody can hear this.
Dan.
Dan Is.
Dan is basically,
I met that.
I met Dan is playing.
That is run for the cube,
doing an Acapella h three they've
signed.
Hopefully it's low enough,
but this is a max exodus.
Everybody's leaving in droves right now.
My dudes have a blessing.
Beautiful Friday.
Happy weekend.
You know what?
Life is a challenge.
It's rough,
but if you listen closely,
the music is playing to merit
sweet.
It's so full and it's out there to do
out there.
You just got to listen to it.
Front of you.
Boy,
do I hear loud and clear?
Beautiful Du du Du du Du du Du.