When it's like upside down.
Welcome everybody to the second annual
age three podcasts.
Live Bonanza.
Thank you Alex.
Again with the usual suspects that
Justin Roiling and Alex Hirsch together
last year we raised $240,000
for direct relief and we are back again
with the goofs,
the gaffs,
the laughs to bring you comedy.
That raises money.
It's all wholesome baby laughs and
charity together.
Welcome.
Thanks for having us.
Yeah,
it's very,
very nice.
Thank you.
Now if you want to donate,
there's so much to get to.
We have a fricken bananas
sit here.
I'm going to,
I'm not waiting.
I'm going to drink with my bag.
Justin
serenade,
everybody.
Now if you want to donate the link is
into the description,
but it's tilt to [inaudible] dot com
slash they have an h three h three
productions where I found strange.
I've never seen an ad in a url,
but there you have it work.
It works.
Yeah,
I mean I've,
yes,
it works.
It's in the description.
We have got so many prizes.
The prizes are.
Um,
let me go over these surprises to let
you guys know what's on the line now.
First of all,
$1 is one raffle ticket.
Now do not be confused that
he can,
I'm having flashbacks the last year.
Right now do not be confused.
One,
you do not have to donate multiple times
more.
You donate the more they can't.
They don't have the technology though.
Unsettling.
It's really creepy.
It's a little skin to animate doll face.
All right.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
I go ahead on a $1 equals one ticket,
$10 equals 10 rebels or you do not need
to donate multiple times.
[inaudible]
the more the more likely it is that
you're going to,
but even somebody who only donates a
single dollar can technically when the
pride,
correct.
Yeah,
but so you could be,
you're not to,
you're going to have to,
you know,
the odds are stacked against you.
If you only didn't have to kick down
like a lot more than you might.
It's pot.
You could,
you could.
It's a,
if it's a possibility,
Justin's playing those mind games.
But I,
but I,
you know,
if you really want to win,
you've got to throw down to beef up
your,
I'm hoping one of our prizes goes to
somebody who donated a single dollar
people who won donated large amounts.
But there was one person that won a big
boy prize and I don't remember what it
was,
but here we have,
was it the lint was skippy's was the
lucky one that was,
you know,
I thought when I thought about flying
skippy out so we could smell his real
belly button,
like the source of the lint to kind of
continue the story.
But you guys vetoed that one.
I mean,
I know I was like,
whatever you guys want to do.
But
no,
he didn't just like texts like,
hey guys want to sniff his belly button
and we just like me and justin just did.
There was somebody else will get this
one.
Somebody told her flat out.
But I'll tell you what,
not to be outdone.
Last year we had one of the most
powerful moments I think in live
broadcasting history when Justin pepper
sprayed joey salads and the face.
Yeah,
that was a beautiful,
wonderful thing.
Charity.
But did you feel spraying and other man
of the fact that felt bad?
I worry,
you know,
as the years go on and we can tackle it
like alluded tick.
Well you know,
I mean I felt bad but also I couldn't
help you know,
laugh at the scenario but,
but the uh,
you know,
I feel like as the years go on and we
continue to do this and hopefully the
numbers that we raised grow,
uh,
I hope we don't end up killing joke.
You know,
cause I was coming up with all these
things like,
oh man,
what if he,
you know,
we,
we get them like one of those really
dangerous like,
like one wheel.
Well I guess it was,
those things are dangerous but some sort
of dangerous contraption to ride on a,
that's going to be really hard to do to
produce and be like,
what if he falls and breaks his neck?
And then it's like,
oh I now he's paraplegic.
Not that there's anything wrong with
that,
but I think paraplegic,
if he dies this year,
what are we going to do next year?
We got up,
we got to keep,
if he dies
charity foremost.
Yeah.
We need to make sure that um,
we have some
tissue samples,
sort of DNA that we can clone him
because that technology is probably not
too far down the line.
There's a good,
and then he's going to be puking today's
who will be collecting if we told them
guys,
we have four milestones that we would
like to hit during this live stream.
Twenty five thousand fifty thousand
seventy five thousand a hundred thousand
every 25,000
Joey's going to be eating progressively
spicier peppers.
Go ahead and cut to joey so everyone can
see what is going on in the backstage
there.
We've got a kitty pool set up.
Joey is sant milk.
Yes.
With milk whole,
what are we looking at?
Where are we right now?
I think it's the whole,
it's whole baby all the way.
And you know why not?
A couple of little little packets of a
half and half.
Oh,
we can see.
Yeah.
We got the doc.
We're filling up the pool with the milk.
Now.
Joey is going to be eating a Jalapeno at
25 and how be narrow at 50 a ghost
pepper at 75 and a Carolina reaper,
right?
75,000
does the Carolina reaper.
That sounds terrifying.
It's the spiciest pepper in the world is
it really surpassed but it whatever.
At a certain level.
It's like the crazy ones.
By what though?
I wonder if they keep them up her.
Oh,
pepper acts of course.
Eight tens of Grendel,
I believe it's called A.
Is that what they tend to at all saints?
Satan.
Sharp
crickets.
Yeah.
Hit me up.
That's great.
Yeah,
for that.
so we're very excited.
We're very thrilled to be hitting these
milestones.
Let me tell you what you can win because
we have some incredible prizes
throughout.
Now,
first of all,
if you donate $100,
these are all on the prizes section of
our donate page.
A hundred bucks.
You get to write something on Joey's
body.
Anything you want that's not racist or
that will get us banned from this live
stream for uh,
for a,
uh,
how much is it to read on my neck?
Was it a thousand or 500 because we did
this last year and we opened the page
here.
Yes.
Sworn it was 500 bucks to ride.
Her neck is 500 that's right.
So you guys can write on me.
Yes.
Let me show you this.
I might donate 500 this legendary shot
was produced last year and this is sharp
sharpie.
So you have to walk around like that for
500 bucks.
Anything anybody wants could be written
on your face.
Do they get to choose the part of your
foot?
Whatever they like.
What about,
what about,
what about inkbox?
Like I have some inkbox free hand.
Like you know,
it,
it you,
you let it dry but it wouldn't show up
until tomorrow and it lasted 18 days
after the flood.
I was,
I would like for a certain amount,
you know,
maybe it's worth it,
it's just,
and I do have a life that doesn't sound
though.
He might be up for it,
you know,
a little almost up to $5,000
guys.
So we are approaching our first,
yeah,
there's a bunch of cool stuff on the
site and there's a bunch of rare,
well,
let me,
let me go ahead.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So you can draw on us now.
This one is super,
super amazing.
Um,
oh yeah.
You can buy,
you guys gonna be doing,
uh,
original art throughout.
Yes.
We bribed that.
We will.
But it's like,
I don't know how good it's going to be.
I figured we let something else right
now,
but we'll be dropping somebody some
sketchy ruse.
Yeah.
I figure we'll let we have frames,
you know,
for,
for what size paper is this?
11 by 14,
I guess.
Maybe not.
So we'll be creating these three amazing
artists.
We'll be creating art and as they finish
them,
we will throw them up for your bidding
pleasure.
Or we could ask them like,
hey,
like,
which ones should we throw up?
Because some people would be like,
yeah,
sure.
I think we'll sell them all just okay.
Up Next Post Malone.
Was that,
uh,
rolling loud?
Is that,
am I saying that correctly?
Yes you are.
Thank you Dan.
Now Post Malone as you know,
has been smashing the quiet.
What do you mean?
Sorry?
It has been smashing a what?
I'm sorry what Justin?
I just said who rolls quiet,
you know?
Oh wait,
what did you go for it?
Uh,
what's that?
Double Cricket.
Yeah,
we dealt with that.
So,
so post Malone,
this was smashed just last weekend
during his show at rolling,
loud,
signed and,
and dedicated.
This is,
I truly believe a valuable part of music
history that we will frame
professionally and sent to the winter.
So this is really,
I think,
an amazing donation by post malone who
we think very much next up.
This is something amazing.
Justin,
why don't you go ahead and explain?
This is a rick and morty episode number
one side by just rolling.
Right?
It's a comma.
It's the,
it's the first issue comic,
uh,
the cover I did and then I had seen,
I grabbed harmon to sign it and I signed
it.
So you valued this at,
I don't know.
It's weird.
It's like on Ebay they go for all
different ranges of amounts.
I've,
I'm not kidding.
I've seen themselves for like $5,000
and that's what that might be the most
I've seen itself without the signature
of the creators,
like 2000 1500.
But,
but,
but honestly I think that's the low,
it's weird.
I haven't looked in a while so I don't
know valuable.
It's pretty valuable on the Ada.
But with the two sick,
with both of both of our signatures,
definitely pretty rare.
I've,
I feel like that should,
that should be,
that's a good one to two to raffle.
Oh,
that's there.
That isn't a premium premium price.
Go ahead and tell us about this because
this also your fans have been going,
uh,
yeah,
Nana's for this.
So,
uh,
like for,
for any gravity falls fans or people who
have gravity falls fans in their family,
I'm watching,
like we released the gravity falls
journal number three.
We've created this limited special
edition where it has black light
messages and like it's interactive and
it's like this incredible book.
And there was so difficult to make it so
expensive that Disney was just like,
we're making 10,000
of these and we are never going to do
this nonsense again.
Like we can't even believe that anybody
would buy these because they're
expensive and rare and hard to get
ahold.
And they only made a few.
And then once they were done,
like for the past year and a half,
my entire twitter feed every day,
it's just people like where can I get
another gravity falls during number
three special edition cause there and I
was like,
they're gone.
There's not another single one left on
the planet earth.
There's only one left that I have and
it's mine and I'm not selling it.
And then I was going through my stuff
and I found one final journal number
three special edition.
These have gone on Ebay.
I've seen them go for 4,005
Jesus Christ.
Really?
Yes.
And this one is rarer than those because
May,
the reason this exists is because this
was a test.
This was the very first test printing of
this book,
just to see if it would all work.
So I think there might be like a few
like typos in there.
Like it's like it's a first,
first edition.
Wow.
It's unlabeled.
So it's like when you get a normal one,
it's like one out of 10,008
out of 10,000.
This isn't even labeled.
It's off the grid.
It's the rarest journal number that is a
real collectible.
That is a real heroes right here folks.
So,
uh,
so yeah,
just like everything else,
you know,
one,
$1,
one raffle ticket for $1,
you could win this.
It's totally possible.
Um,
but I'd,
I'd hedge my bets,
maybe throw some more data.
The throw in like
half the value of what it is,
what it would sell on Ebay for.
What do you think that would sell on
Ebay for considering it's one of a kind.
I couldn't say.
I mean it's been like a year since any
of these were available.
So,
but not to mention that's literally a
production that's like the first one off
the presses.
Yeah.
Oh,
it's like when they make a stamp and
there's like a misprint,
maybe only one of those.
Those are incredibly collectable,
like the,
the,
that stuff is accurate and I value it at
right.
That's like a prototype toy or
something.
I won't lie.
I don't know.
I don't know if like signing it would
make it less valuable if I should just
include a signature with it or
something.
Cause I don't want to mess.
Why don't we,
why don't we ask the winter?
Yeah.
We know what to choose.
Signed or not.
[inaudible] is not a bad thing.
I can't imagine the winter being like
don't,
don't put it down and touch it.
And this is true.
When I found out he was,
Alex was bringing that I,
I was like,
you tried to trade up.
listen,
I have,
I have seals of book three.
I'll treat you to auction off for that
fucking one that wasn't even hitting.
I know,
you know,
it's an embarrassing sad.
You're a pro.
You're not too proud to,
I'm a,
I'm a fan and I am a collector so we are
at 6,200
guys.
Let's keep going.
Come on,
get it together.
We got joe sell ended up outside fucking
proper and then retaining chuck.
You know what I mean?
We got to get the money gone stuff.
Yeah.
And then Ross Butler for all you the
heart throbs Justin heartthrobs for all
you girls that want to get Ooh,
Ooh,
yeah,
yeah.
This sweet treat.
He,
he's uh,
he's gonna eat like a up for auction is
a private message is going to kick off
for an MRI.
Oh No,
you don't get to see as being a no,
no,
of course not.
No,
no.
God cause I was going to say it's all,
it's all a pg 13,
13.
I actually don't even know what a little
nip maybe cares.
It's like a,
you know,
it's like a private message,
a or whatever you want,
like a video that,
that Ross we'll send Ya.
And that's fair.
The tweet and God blessed.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and Ross is great and,
and I,
I felt like that.
Oh,
awesome.
Yeah,
this will come in handy.
Um,
but yeah,
uh,
I figured,
you know,
he's,
he's got a massive fan base and I think
that could help us.
Raise a good chunk of absolutely and
thank you to both of you for coming
together on that.
We also have a switch bundle with smash
and that'll be signed by everyone here.
No,
I'm kidding.
I don't know [inaudible] we've got the
xbox with fallout 76 damn brought this
back.
I was like,
really?
You had to get the 76 bundle?
That being said,
it is the x box one x.
This is the premium top of the line.
New Console that won't lad like the
Shitty one that I have,
but they sold me two or three years ago
and of course we've got the PS four
bundle.
That's that new bomb ass ps four pro red
dead redemption
get.
These are amazing,
amazing,
really good raffle.
And then we realized there's so much
more,
I can't even list it all,
but this amongst so many others is oh
rick and morty original script.
We have four of those.
That's really amazing.
And I was going to tell you if we wanted
to kind of bundle some of the rick and
Morty,
it's too late,
but I was going to say that it may or
may not be too late because if we wanted
to bundle it,
you can just carry over the,
the,
anyone who bid on a certain item that
bid could carry over for whatever bundle
that item goes to.
Does that make sense?
I don't know how complicated that would
be,
but I just thought of that last night in
his mind.
But I mean,
it's probably more work than it's,
we have an Alex Hirsch message donation.
You,
are you showing your Dick or are you
just saying stuff?
It's going to be a,
an audio adventure.
I'll be live ventures.
Uh,
yeah.
for any gravity falls fans,
uh,
you know,
I can do any voice of any of the
characters that I do.
I'm just like,
send me,
what message do you want me to say?
And uh,
as long as it's not like ridiculously
places,
I will say it.
Um,
and uh,
yeah,
same is everything.
Raffle tickets for that.
Oh these are very frank are completely
sold out.
Rep and dip X.
Justin's going to steal every fucking
fine.
There's a ton of limited edition is who
it is.
This call I will not be restocked.
I see some people are waiting for that.
It was a one time thing.
So these are the last ones.
Yeah,
that's it.
And then we have some,
I know teddy fresh one off samples of
things we've tried and then decided not
to go out.
Like for example,
let me show something like,
um,
you have the sweater.
We made these,
this happy like that sweater.
And so we,
we tested one an orange.
That's one of a kind that only exists
there.
We have one in blue.
These are ones that we sampled but never
went ahead with.
This one's in blue.
That one actually.
That's pretty good.
Yeah,
that's really,
yeah.
I don't know why he didn't go.
I think maybe you might want to
reconsider them.
Reconsider.
So it won't be that rare breed.
There's like this was another sample.
This is one of a kind.
It doesn't exist anywhere,
but that's official teddy fresh.
This one was a really interesting story.
We got this sample and then when I,
when we tried it on and took it off,
we really liked how the inside looked.
You can kind of see that's how we ended
up making the rainbow one,
the new one.
That is basically,
it was based on the inside of this
sweater.
That's cool.
That's awesome.
We liked it better inside out.
Well let's just do that.
Um,
and,
and so,
so much more.
You guys have to go over to the prizes
page and see there's a fricking buttload
of amazing prizes to win there.
So with that being said,
in a couple more prizes,
[inaudible] 9,009
big donation,
Bam.
We got to get Joey Salads
on that,
right?
Yeah.
Uh,
nothing,
uh,
huge.
Huge.
Yeah.
We got a couple of like hundred dollar
ones,
which is pretty awesome.
We're not people,
people are going to get shout outs for
500 plus donations.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So thank you.
Um,
so
also guys,
if you're watching this on the Vod,
you can bid on all of these items for
the next week.
They are going to be up.
So if you're not watching this slide,
rest assured you can still win all of
this stuff by donating on the campaign.
Uh,
and the description.
So why are we doing this direct relief,
direct relieve beneficiary of this uh,
live charity event.
They are one of the highest ranked
charity organizations in the world on
charity navigator.
They are one of the only,
are they the only or one of the only Dan
uh,
rank charities 100 out of 109
transparency.
They are number one.
They are ranked number one.
So I imagine they are the only a a 100
out of 100.
They have a perfect record on
transparency and how much money actually
goes to people that need it.
Paying out executives,
it's like,
it can be so hard choosing charities
because like all of them are doing some
good,
but you don't know how much of your
dollar is going directly to the people
who need it.
How much of it is going into like
printing fliers for the company and it's
like this one,
like every single rating system says
like,
yeah,
your money's going to someone who needs
it immediately,
that dollar raffle ticket that might get
you this prize also is like directly to
some of the,
it's also,
it's also they're,
they're going to be,
it's,
it's northern California and southern
California right there.
Like hitting everybody.
Yeah.
Which is great.
Um,
and so,
and so we are doing this in honor of
the,
of the tragedy,
the tragic loss of property and life
that occurred here in California from
the fires.
Actually,
I feel like a lot of people think about
what happened here in California as just
a bunch of rich people lost their
houses,
which is,
you know,
true as some and to some degree here in
Los Angeles.
But what happened in northern
California,
in the city of Paradise,
this was not a rich community.
The 14,000
homes were destroyed,
the entire city was wiped out.
You can't really wrap your head around
just how destructive that is.
Let me show you a video that,
I mean,
I agree,
but here I pulled up some media to kind
of show you guys the scope of
destruction.
So like this is the city.
I mean it's just gone.
Oh Wow.
That was a wall.
That's,
that's a Ariel.
Ariel.
God.
I mean it's gone.
One House.
Just here's dean.
Yes.
That would want hilarious.
Well not,
I mean,
I guess not funny.
I guess more this one.
Good.
Who's like,
as you're panning across,
destroyed home footage.
The phrase,
wouldn't it be funny normally?
No,
you're right.
You're right.
No,
it's fucking terrible.
Horrific.
Yeah.
My,
my,
my partner at squatch games,
her brother lost every like everything.
Really?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's like,
no.
I don't know.
I keep asking,
but do you have,
it's like you do,
like everything is going well.
It's not like,
oh,
I have insurance.
Cool.
Get back to normal tomorrow.
It's like,
no,
you're,
yeah.
It's going to be about paperwork and
also all the irreplaceable,
I couldn't even imagine.
Like I,
I,
we,
we were talking about like what would
you grab if you had,
you know,
I don't know how much time,
like a couple of hours,
what would you grab and load up?
And it's like,
no matter what you're going to get out
and the next several days you're going
to be thinking of all the shit you
forgot you're going to,
cause I have the worst,
that moment over and over again.
Oh my God,
I forgot to get the fucking whatever,
you know,
I don't know,
15 minutes.
What do you grab?
Obviously the dogs,
right?
Yeah,
I mean that's all I really care about
books.
Like all my cash flow,
that's the first thing.
I'm just like,
I have years of original art and
sketchbooks,
like going back to high school.
So it's like,
yeah,
like,
so I would grab all that if I could.
I don't even know where it all is
though.
That's the thing.
I'm not ready.
I'm not ready to hire.
Like,
yeah,
you're,
it's like,
give me a second.
Maybe my laptop.
I probably would just because it's like
there's too much shit on you guys.
Keep talking.
I'm just going to show foot.
This is somebody just driving through
and then it might blow up.
Sex dolls obviously replay.
Irreplaceable.
I'm not going to leave them.
I don't know.
I don't know that I would grab anything
but the dog and maybe my laptop.
Yeah.
Well my mom,
I think my mom rubbed off on me in a
awful way cause like she would like
throw out my childhood art like that.
It was like,
oh my God,
like an old receipt.
That's horrible.
Yeah.
Why would she do that?
Trust me,
this is a long,
long,
long time coming and I'm in therapy.
All right.
We just had a really true that I'm in
there don't know that she would throw
the rock art that I was super proud of
that I made in high school and I left
there.
I have,
I'll tell you what I haven't painted
since.
It's almost as tragic as this in a
winton I in a way that's kind of helped
because like I don't throw away a single
sketch book.
I have a closet filled with like every
drawing I've done since I have like
drawings from highschool.
Sounds like just like,
it's like I don't,
it's like I don't need it.
I can throw anything.
No,
I wish she didn't throw it away.
I wouldn't eat them.
Like tomorrow we gotta move Ileus,
pack a suitcase and I was like,
okay look.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well I feel like I'm good.
That's good.
I felt like healthier cause you know,
take it with you when you die.
You know what I'm saying?
There's certain things who just said I
have no,
I'm not going to look out and I really
don't care about like you can carry
around everything you've ever touched in
your life or heard about or done or,
but like there's somethings that you are
going to need and the majority of it
you're never going to think about.
Even if you bring it,
like how much shit is in your house
there that you will never even think
about.
If it was gone,
you wouldn't even notice.
You know,
I liked who were arguing for like,
yeah,
it doesn't matter if you lose all your
stuff in front of this mountaintop.
People losing their entire house.
Oh,
well,
I mean,
if you had a choice.
Yeah.
The difference between having everything
just blinked out is horrific.
Got a lot of media.
Does anyone know how these started?
These fires?
How did the campfire start?
Dan Fires,
right?
Well,
the problem is that it's just so windy
and dry.
Yes.
It's the combination.
It's like you,
if you breathe wrong,
some brush,
you start a wildfire or it's,
it's a thing that's happening every
single year now getting worse and worse.
The campfire specifically we believe was
started by our friends at PG and e
company,
mother fucker.
But like I said,
you could almost just like take a,
a spicy shit and start a fire.
That's true.
But yeah,
some of their equipment,
uh,
overloaded and caused the spark and
that's what started it.
I shouldn't eat.
Why chewing into the mix.
People talk shit about it.
We'll talk good about me.
Actually.
The problem is that he was,
a lack of rain was,
they're amazing.
There's no rain.
The Santa Ana's,
which are these,
we got rain like the week after like two
weeks after the,
it was like blood barely and not the
why.
Knowing the worst.
It was like,
come on,
are you kidding me?
Now you're going to rain.
Well then they're like,
oh,
the mudslides,
they're going to fuck everyone up.
Will that,
exactly.
It's like a,
it's,
yeah,
on the whole everything is super dry and
then you get the Santa Ana's which are
these really warm dry wins and it's just
a fatal combination by the way.
We don't know.
We don't know that much about it.
That's all that we,
he doesn't know what he's talking about.
Thank you Justin.
Appreciate that.
If you can just keep on supporting me
throughout the,
just to make sure.
Have we explained what the Fuck Justin's
up?
No.
What are you doing?
I'm doing um,
I don't know if the camera could see
this.
Justin has laid out over the table.
He's assembling some sort of animate
figuring doll.
He just showed up with a bag full of
toys and just wordlessly silently just
started.
We're going to auction off when I'm done
building these,
someone's going to win it.
It's like this creepy little school girl
and I'm trying secret notes inside each
piece.
Um,
hey guys,
I'm going to send Joe in because uh,
I have three donations for write
something on Java.
We have one for writing something on
Ethan.
So I'm going to pop that.
[inaudible] was,
tell me all about it.
What do we got here?
Their name is,
uh,
why zoo deep like Tommy Wiseau.
Dude,
why Zoghbi it's the real Tommy,
go ahead and pop in on guys.
Come on.
We're almost to that first landmark
now.
Justin.
I did donate 1000 cause my mom wanted a
drawing from you.
Okay,
well that,
that,
that was your won.
I got whatever you want.
I've got to draw something good.
Anything,
something,
something not yelling as valid hook
here.
Here.
Yeah.
Why don't you join us on the couch and
then when the first you can just join us
here.
Do we have,
do we have like the,
like they,
they,
they've specifically requested like,
yes,
a thing to be.
All right,
hang on.
What's it going to be?
It's going to be hard to beat.
Last year in June,
we right on Joey,
Bernie Sanders Fan boy subscribe to
Cutie Pie and unsubscribed from Jesus
Christ.
So where,
where,
where are we?
I subscribe to see series.
I just want to acknowledge was
subscribed to a PD pie unsubscribed to
two series,
but since the other one was subscribed
to Pewdie Pie,
I figured,
you know,
we could,
we could break that up a little bit.
Thanks.
We're done.
It's a little redundant and the names,
give them a shout out if you would.
There's not much,
what do you want to know?
Whatever.
Where could we do it?
Just go ahead wherever you got space.
Not a lot of room.
Yeah,
let's start with the neck was out there.
just like on,
so just try to start,
you know,
riding on top of writing as we continue
through the,
just get in there.
So you've got first Bernie Sanders fan
boy is that true jelly.
They see my twitter somehow I suspected
that wasn't true.
Um,
subscribe to Pud Pi's next and
unsubscribed from t series is
interesting.
Joey's skin is,
is,
is not accepting the really Joey Joey,
you have unusually soft hands.
Do you know that?
Every no law.
Okay.
Well does that make your hands soft?
I masturbate a lot to the lotion.
I got good lotion.
Yeah.
Seriously.
Because every time I've shipped I'm
shook your hand show you,
I've noticed you have a remarkably soft
skin.
Whenever you talk about me on your
podcast that you always bring up my
socks because I thought it's just so
bizarre.
It's like I don't ever shake someone's
hand and notice that they have
remarkably soft skin,
but you just,
how many times a day do you jerk off for
really with lotion?
Cause that's like a whole thing.
I use cocoa butter.
I like,
but it's all hours.
I lotion my arms sometimes before,
before.
Yeah.
That makes sense.
It makes more sense.
Yeah.
By the way,
the uh,
the donors who donated for Joey is
Garrett runcorn,
buddy foster and solid shaggy.
So thanks.
Thank you guys.
Thank you.
We're up to 16,000
Shag.
Are you?
No about the Jalapeno
watering,
but I'm like,
my body can't like rejects it really.
Well,
if you need to take a shit we've got,
you can do it in the pool.
What?
Uh,
what else am I writing?
a bribe.
You can just say unsub t series and sub
two
Pewdie Pie.
All right.
I like how Bernie Sanders,
impunity pyre equally important in the
imaginations of our donors.
They're like,
these are the two causes of our time.
This is what matters.
Tea Areas series.
Now while you go ahead and so grateful,
I don't know what any of that means.
I have an interest.
I have a human interest story.
This one really touched me about from
the fires.
The dog waited outside.
They had to evacuate.
Oh No.
And this dog,
this dog ones mess me up,
man.
This dog is such a legend.
Somehow survived on its own in the
middle of this fire and waited outside
the house for a week.
This was something a dog apparently
stood guard at a burn home four weeks
until his own or returned CBS to Sandra
Mitchell.
That was the story.
Look at this name of this guy now that
he's finally,
and then also,
okay,
good,
good boy t series on me.
Paradise Fire.
But she had to leave her no jokes about
her name and his brother Miguel.
Behind 85 people died in the fire.
14,000
homes were destroyed,
including gay lords.
Miguel,
come on and then a few days later,
face rescue workers spotted madison that
is burned out home.
The loyal,
hey man,
through the worst of circumstances being
so emotional,
the animal rescue worker left,
so they just bought the dog and she went
back to try and capture heads.
Survived,
founded.
Just sitting here waiting.
I mean,
that's the heart Anatolian shepherd.
It's a brain.
Three weeks week,
one week,
one week.
That's when they rolled up sweet
creature.
God,
Gaylord was allowed to return home for
the first time in almost a month.
How does she brought Miguel with her and
they didn't know if the dog was okay or
not treat.
The dog came running in additional
looking at warmed his heart.
I need him.
He's like,
oh wait,
hold on.
That's a heartwarming story,
but I just have parts.
Let's,
I want to pick it apart.
Dissect that emotion.
So it's like,
how much time was she given to evacuate?
I want back.
Well,
it paradise.
The fire was so,
a lot of people parish because it was so
fast.
I don't wanna I don't wanna I don't
wanna I don't want to do whatever answer
is most heartwarming.
My dogs would be like the fucking number
one,
the t series.
Well,
she's an old lady.
She can't carry that little old lady.
Miss gala was outside.
It was out,
you know,
roaming free.
Yeah.
Two series.
Let's do it here.
Thank you for,
I don't know what that means.
So yeah,
it's fine.
You guys done it?
Okay.
It's,
the donations are going up fast.
You guys 17,000.
Let's me.
Once people see t theories on your
cheek,
they're like,
oh,
I could,
there's some real estate.
Look guys,
this amazing face.
Real estate money donations are blowing
up.
Left cheek,
forehead.
Forget [inaudible] almost 25,000,
25 k 25 k the first hot pepper.
You were raising a lot of money.
Yeah.
You don't have to,
uh,
Jalapenos nothin.
You need the,
uh,
the Carolina reaper if we raise 100,000.
So that's something you should feel
really proud of.
I'm proud that I'm so like not looking
forward.
I know we got a problem with um,
with his mic.
Oh,
he's Mike with Joey's.
Mike.
Sorry I haven't lean.
Lean up to one of your guys.
Mike,
if he's talking to a microphone and
throw me in the corner.
Well I'll fix it in a second,
but we care one or two times.
You can talk into my mic here.
Can you hear me now?
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
You want to,
you can use mine cause I'm drawing
anyway.
Yeah,
you can go ahead and meanwhile,
have you guys bring a chair meanwhile?
Um,
what are we up to right now?
We're at the total right now.
The total right now is 17 and a half
thousand.
I mean like,
I know we raise a lot of money last year
and I should be like desensitized to it.
But like that's an amazing,
that's amazing.
Well and I think the donations that you
guys gave and the prizes are,
they're amazing.
They're warrant.
So you get to give money and when,
incredible,
beautiful thing.
Oh Great.
We've got another one to ride on me.
Congratulation.
I got another one.
The writer who's the next person.
By the way,
we also have this,
there won't be any sweat this this year
to drip it off.
It's,
it's cold and this year it is frosty.
I,
last year they started to melt but these
are going to stay for a long time now
guys,
we have the c o of direct relief joining
us on a call later on because last year
we're going to really lay,
sent us,
we're going to end up make really,
I'm not sweating,
but he will be,
um,
I have an email here from them where
thatF is.
It is my question.
Oh my God.
I thought I had it all organized,
busting open these mystery snacks.
By the way before,
I don't know what these are.
Justin brought them.
Where did you get this stuff?
Um,
Japanese.
Uh,
why is it not here town?
Oh,
I'm in the wrong one.
It almost a quarter mill.
Last year.
Yeah.
Last year we raised 240 that was the dog
off stream we got,
so here's the letter from direct relief
that I got from them before we went on
this livestream here today.
They said,
hey guys,
just want to drop you a note and let you
know how grateful we are for your sport.
They history last year was by far our
biggest online marathon and we can't
tell you how much this means to us.
We're excited to have our CEO calling in
later day,
but please know that you always have an
open invitation to come visit our new
headquarters and distribution factory
and Santa Barbara.
Just let us,
yeah,
you Yada,
Yada,
Yada.
Thanks again from Ya.
Boy Kevin,
you know Kevin,
he's like our new headquarters.
Be flossing.
No,
I would have been sober.
Look at your calling Kate Bay,
so there you go.
Dylan.
Good when and great prizes.
It's all happening now as we inch
forward to this first milestone,
we had 18,000
guys.
Let's enjoy a holiday video together.
What I want to can real quick before you
do that to me.
We have a $500 donation from spoon and
he would like to just put the label papa
on your forehead.
Uh,
now that you're going to be a dad.
All right.
Sweet.
It's not even like trollie or mean.
That's so much more respectable than I
love come last year they'll trickle it.
Oh my God,
this is really good.
Yeah.
It's some kind of like a,
was that a cherry flavor like crunchy
but gets blue raspberry.
It's gets kind of like you want to try
that fan on.
Does it have carbs the best?
Uh,
while you were about,
I mean,
you're going to shit everything out
anyway.
That's true.
Like I wouldn't worry too much about
what you eat in a way.
A $500 donation from Cameron booster and
they didn't actually leave anything to
write.
They just wanted to shout out to his
girlfriend Chris Mcmurry and her beloved
cat,
uh,
tight Tenneco's titanic.
Titanic.
No,
Alex.
Oh wait a minute.
And they hold on.
I'm dropping the lincoln discord.
If you could throw this up on the screen
real quick on my book because this is a
beautiful cut.
Oh,
just what they want us to show the
patents.
Show that titanic.
Show that kit.
Whoa.
Look at that cat.
Yeah.
That's a cool cat.
Is that photoshop?
This looks so beautiful.
What do you think that natural radio,
gorgeous cat's looking at in that
picture.
What do you think it's thinking about
man,
that's a,
that's thinking about America's future.
Yeah.
It's like where are we headed for
president know?
He's replacing Tucker Carlson the
planet.
Thank you.
Got Cameron.
Boaster beautiful cat and shout out to
your girlfriend Chris.
Guys,
we're inching closer to this.
We're at 19,000
joey.
Good.
Pucker up your asshole because we are
about to get on a wild wild ride.
Now let's watch a Christmas video that I
saw on youtube today.
That is one of the greatest things I've
ever seen.
You guys know this thing's going
absolutely viral.
Five 15 million.
It was supposed to only a couple of days
ago.
This is mark rope rubber.
This is,
you're going to love this.
[inaudible] can tell them.
You've seen this,
Alex.
I've seen it.
I haven't seen this.
So as you guys know,
box theft is a huge problem today.
People going up to your head and
especially around the holiday,
they go up to your door and they steal
your package.
So this guy was tired of this happening
and what he devised was a bomb,
a glitter bomb to go off with a camera
in the box so he could record there.
We had the wrong people get called.
Now this is going to cut it.
Now this guy,
this guy is a,
was as a former NASA engineer.
Yeah.
Like being sent to Mars.
It's half with the wrong guy.
Exactly.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly right.
Having fun making glitter bomb packages.
So great.
He does this a bunch of times and he
captures just unbelievable footage.
So let's,
all right,
I may be biased,
but sometimes in your design,
and it doesn't just throw it up,
literally four cameras capturing live
and it also has,
um,
barb on,
but as a fart bomb also the fart bomb is
just incredible.
First,
the glitter shoots out.
This has been really hard bump shoots at
like every 30 seconds.
So they have to get rid of it when they
realized,
because at first they're going to be
like,
Hey,
what is this?
And then it keeps going.
So amazing.
So the,
and then the best thing about this is
that I expose,
this guy's got to mass produce these and
sell them.
Yeah,
it was about to say I would buy it the
most fine grained glitter in the world.
Impossible to get out of carpet.
[inaudible] package has been moved off
the property.
So I put it out on the porch and now all
that was left to do
what's his weight and he could have done
a better wrapping job.
Okay.
So I was at work and I got a
notification that the geo fence we set
up had been tripped.
So then I checked the cameras and sure
enough the package has gone.
So I checked the GPS and sort of tracked
it and it appears they're in a car
because they seem to leave my house
pretty quickly off.
It seems to stop in a parking garage,
which is where I'm headed to now.
And if you're new here,
this isn't a prank channels.
So I am completely out of my comfort
zone.
Rubber by the way,
this legend and there she is.
so we're covering,
it would still work even if I didn't get
the box back,
the footage would upload to the cloud,
but it's just faster to plug the phones.
I'm gonna go home and find out what he
thought of everything,
how I ended up here.
So it appears he was walking down the
sidewalk and then suddenly makes a hard
left.
They take these clothing,
actually makes it to this parking garage
where this glorious sequence unfold.
Um,
like four cameras.
Oh,
okay.
Look
at that.
They're looking at my car,
dude.
Everything.
Oh my God.
I don't know what this is.
Literally like everywhere.
My friend CC is also had some packages
stolen.
So you make her a few days.
He didn't.
Oh Dude.
That's what I'm saying.
I would,
I would buy,
I would spend more than what a home pod
costs or whatever want to do whatever,
whatever it is,
the actual item.
This is more of this needs to happen
like this is too good.
I saw another video of a guy who cashed
it and Piss in a box and now the best
part of the FARC coming.
Wait for that.
I like that he's upset.
Like,
come on.
How could you play me like that?
I don't deserve this at all.
Life is fair,
dude.
You never going to get that stuff out of
your car.
Oh yeah,
that'll,
that'll be there for,
that's the FARC spray and his car with
the windows up genius down to the Fart
spray.
Oh,
it's a beautiful thing.
this is,
I listed,
they go piss like someone did something
awful to them.
I also like that they're narrating to no
one.
They're so pissed off that they have and
be like,
this is too good.
This is too good.
It is.
People are assholes.
They're like stealing shit and then the
camera didn't work.
He said,
I lifted.
It keeps going every 30 seconds.
It just doing it.
You probably spend a lot of money,
but he grabbed that.
At least these are having a good time.
They're like cracking up of the Jelly,
a draw.
Lee Burglars Him saying,
you shouldn't have even taken that.
It's like,
yeah,
that's the moral of this episode of
legends of the crypt keeper or whatever
like that.
Man,
these people are so brazen.
I love about inside.
He's just like stunned trying to figure
out what to do with this
on Myers.
Did her launch mechanism.
Just don't take other people's stuff.
Not only is it not cool,
but on the plus side you'll never find
yourself in this situation or perhaps
even worse.
This one will get in here.
Then
who you had in there,
you have it.
One of the best videos ever made just in
time for the holidays.
Why?
Once again,
Mark Rober,
God bless his soul guys,
we are up to $20,000
Oh,
when's the first pepper chowning five
hours were 5,000
away from this Chi eating on.
What kind of a power on the first one is
a raw jalapenos and is it?
Is he eating the whole thing?
Whole thing.
Can I just take a bite?
It's a Jalapeno Joe.
Give it,
cause I don't want to drop dead because
if you think about it,
well what if my don't get people never
do like eight the entire pepper.
What I'm saying is like people eat the
ghost pepper and that's that.
They go,
you don't have,
you don't have to eat the reaper and
then that shit,
but I got,
oh,
okay.
You don't have to eat the whole of those
do does he?
Maybe you're the challenge.
All the spices are going to be trying to
weasel his way out.
Well,
we're talking about the Jalapeno.
You,
you owe us here 25 or let's say when we
do Jalapeno,
that's not,
that's the entry level.
I mean,
I'm just listening about ahead of time.
Let's set the rose.
Okay.
And era.
Our whole a whole,
he's got hold of the whole gang,
a whole hub in Europe.
I then you can go half on the two.
Oh No,
no,
no.
It's got to eat the whole thing.
Justin says you got to go.
This is why the money's coming in.
Just those saying he felt bad about
swearing you last year and now he's
like,
[inaudible] I have to abide by what?
The audience,
your expiry.
I'll do it.
I'll do whatever.
Donating this money.
Also,
the donations are slowing down.
I mean we're at thousand 300.
They nail it because they heard these
knocking.
It's like,
what a,
wait a minute.
This is affecting the stock.
The warning label says,
um,
handle with gloves.
You can't even touch the thing.
It goes in your mouth,
not on your hand.
All right.
Hey,
I've got a couple more messages that we
got to right.
Oh,
excellent.
Excellent.
What are the hot,
so I've got,
uh,
two more for Joey.
A sub to Ryan McCarty.
Um,
Yup.
So why don't you join us on pouty?
Joey can do the writing.
Yeah,
sure.
Keep going.
So it's up to Ryan McCarty.
I'll put it,
I'll put it in discord so you see how
it's spelled and buy Bitcoin,
both of those on Joey.
And then I have some for Ethan to,
uh,
we have,
we just want a james wine Hoff
wants you to write Jacob's sausage on a,
on somewhere.
And then Simon is asking you to write
hightail,
which,
uh,
is the name of his video game and he's
going to use a screen cap from the
screen in his trailer.
Okay.
The,
okay.
All right.
Go ahead.
That's a,
that's a good capitalism.
Exactly.
Advertising honestly,
I mean 500 bucks for,
yeah.
What we could do,
by the way,
is once we could do a thing where once
real estate has completely taken,
we clear some room cause it's like,
you know,
the,
the uh,
the footage of you,
the phase.
That's true.
You know,
I don't want to,
I don't want to play a realistic,
the point where there's literally no,
well,
so far I think it'll be a while.
And so far these guys,
I mean,
we're at 21,000.
am I right?
We're getting close.
Oh,
what are you writing on my face?
I just dropped it in discord for me.
Oh Wow.
Here you go.
Oh,
it's in discord.
So what,
why are you doing that,
Alex?
You've got a big part of the Netflix,
Netflix family now.
Oh yes,
that's right.
Yeah.
Um,
uh,
the streaming algorithm program company.
Netflix giant.
I worked for them now.
So tell me,
what does that mean that because you,
they,
they like bought your whole,
they bought my life,
right?
They tattooed the end lower back,
the equivalent of what Justin's doing to
me now.
They did essentially.
Yeah.
Also,
I was working on this,
uh,
I was working on the secret movie that I
guess I'm not allowed to talk about,
you know,
I can't even say,
I can't even say what it is.
It's,
it was big.
It was,
it was a thing.
Um,
but uh,
it wasn't creatively.
And a Netflix made me a really amazing
offer to basically make anything in the
world I want,
which is kind of an intimidating thing
if just like,
you know,
like a company just like plops down a
bag of money on your chest and it's just
like whatever you want to make,
make it.
Um,
almost you're saying it's almost too
much freedom.
It's awesome.
But it is like,
it is one of those things where you're
like,
wait,
so like what are the rules here?
And other sensors,
you know,
like I came from the Disney channel or
was like,
everything was censored,
you know,
and it's like,
it's like,
no,
like whatever you want,
man.
I'm make a movie.
You want to make a show?
What do you,
what do you,
so I'm working on a new top secret,
untitled Alex Hirsch project.
Cool.
Um,
that I'm very nice.
Did a cartoon is a live action.
Can you say anything?
Uh,
I,
they probably would be fine with it,
but I want to keep it a secret.
You want to keep it a secret?
Secretive?
Yeah,
just always been secretive.
You've back of the Disney days,
man.
I remember on fish hooks you were like
hiding in your office and I'd knock on
the door and you'd open it a crack and
he got it.
And I'd be like,
Hey,
can I come in?
I want to talk.
And then you'd be like,
hold on,
close the door,
turn every single screen.
Worked forward around every,
like all this shit.
I'm like,
all right.
Uh,
that's like God damn it.
Probably because like I was fan of
justice before I met him,
so I was like intimidated and I was
like,
oh,
this guy's going to see my stupid
cartoon idea.
Like that's when I was coming up with
gravity falls at the time I was like,
I don't want him to see my stupid
drawings,
but I have a hard time throwing when
people are like looking over my
shoulder,
you know what I mean?
At the same time,
like I have a hard time writing when
there's like lots of people around,
like I can't write and like a coffee
shop for some reason.
Like I need to like lock the door,
dim the lights,
and then,
then the demons enter,
you know what I mean?
But I'm working on something really cool
for Netflix right now,
but I can't say it to this.
How much this body and what's the
timeline?
How much time do you,
or is it just totally,
do they put a timeline on yours?
It just like whenever,
whatever.
Yeah.
Um,
it's,
uh,
around,
around a year from now,
there's going to be a lot to talk about.
Um,
like,
uh,
I'm also producing some things.
Uh,
there's,
Netflix is like making a big bid for
animation.
They just like notice like,
okay,
Disney bought Fox and so now they have
like simpsons and family guy and Netflix
is like,
okay,
all right,
let's go all in,
let's,
let's make a bunch of Rad shows.
We need the next generation of
animation.
Um,
and it's like happening right now.
It's very cool to be a part of it.
Like,
it feels weird because I'm used to just
bitching about my parent company.
Right?
It's like I was always like whining
about Disney and like,
they were great to me,
you know what I mean?
But like,
I was just so constantly aware of all
the rules and things I can't do,
you know,
on the Netflix is just like,
yeah,
whatever crazy thing you could think of.
You want to make a movie,
you want to make a mini series,
you want to mix up shot holes,
bro.
So get ready for the Butthole Bros
starring me and Justin reuland.
Obviously I'm pop a butthole.
He's a jimmy bottled juice and we are
two brothers who have big gaping
buttholes right in our faces gimmick.
And it's why the ladies love us coming
to Netflix.
Uh,
so for that I would watch that.
Don't,
don't give him,
don't give him too many ideas.
Don't give away the good one.
And Justin,
what secrets can you tell us about all
the things happening in the Justin verse
right now?
Alex through that oval on over to Justin
mass fine.
Oh no,
go ahead.
I mean I'm like,
Oh yeah,
I can't do that.
No,
I get,
I get that you are,
I'm just,
I'm fat.
No,
let's go over to judge.
I mean like keep,
keep like I can't talk about it.
That's why I was just ignored it.
I just wanted to hear more about how do
you,
cause you said you haven't like no
rules,
you can do anything.
It was still hard to you.
You have to come up with something,
right?
Sure.
Yeah.
Well,
I like my,
I don't know,
everyone has like a different creative
process I guess.
Like for me I kind of do like my own
like mental hunger games where like I'm
constantly coming up with like different
variations.
Like when I came up with gravity falls,
I actually came up with three TV shows.
Um,
and I pitched like three shows to
Disney.
I'm like,
one was about time traveling dolphins,
the other two were terrible.
Um,
it literally was,
I'm not making that up.
That was going to be my other show if
they had picked that up.
But so like I just like,
like fill a sketchbook with like lots
and lots of characters and situations
and stuff.
And then I like kind of compete them
against each other.
In my mind I'm like,
which one is delighting me more today?
You know what I mean?
And then like make a little like power
bracket of my own ideas for myself and
then like show like maybe a few people
like,
what do you think,
what do you think?
And then I'm like,
all right,
this is the thing I want to spend a
bunch of years on.
So is that what kind of what you've been
doing?
Yeah,
that's what I've been doing and I've
like finally narrowed it down to some
really exciting stuff.
Wow.
I'm like stoked on and come up with your
arm timeline.
Like deadlines or do you have deadlines?
It's,
I mean it's all,
it's kind of like,
it's like sort of the wild west over
there right now because it's brand new,
you know what I mean?
But they're like very supportive.
Like they have,
they have deadlines and they have like
their producers structure.
But within that,
like the very,
all the cart,
like you can be like,
hey this is a different kind of thing.
I want to try something else and maybe
we put more time here and they're so
open to it.
Like it's also like there's no
commercials so you can make episodes
like longer.
Super interesting.
Do you don't have to think like I was so
used to like,
oh,
if it's two seconds over,
Disney is like,
you've got to find those two seconds.
And here it's like,
whoa.
You're like,
you don't have to worry about act
breaks.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a different world man.
Um,
but it's really,
and the executives they are,
do they give you notes?
Cause probably Disney's all up your ass
with notes.
Yeah.
Um,
the executives basically are just like a
first audience so far.
Um,
like they're really cool.
They just want to see something that's
funny.
And like,
I think the traditional development
model and television is network spend a
crap load of money developing like one
or two projects that they like put all
their hopes in and they promote the shit
out of him and then if they're not
immediately hits the,
cancel them.
Right.
Um,
and it's like,
that's not good for anybody.
That's like putting way too much
pressure on every single project where
it's like the new kind of streaming
pipeline.
Like the way Netflix does it is like
we're just going to empower a bunch of
creators who we think have something
cool and we're going to make smaller
seasons and put them all out there.
And if people watch it,
you get more episodes.
And if people don't,
we're not picking up for a second
season,
but those episodes aren't going
anywhere,
you know,
like,
so it's like,
it's almost like,
like,
like low risk,
high reward,
you know what I mean?
Um,
and it like content.
Yes.
And they want it on demand.
Lots of content and lots of ideas.
I'm just kidding.
It's a little scary.
There's like so much shit.
There's so much shit on streaming.
It's weird to be making tv in an era
where there's never been more television
in history and you're like,
how are people going to notice?
But I feel like good stuff is still
recognized.
You know what I mean?
Like definitely there's so much junk out
there with it when like something really
hits or something,
it's not at all.
Like,
I remember that there was that show,
high profits,
that show was so fucking good.
Well,
I've never even heard of it.
No one's heard about it.
The critters profit.
It's a,
it's a reality show or it's like more of
a documentary.
It's done like documentary series.
So it's not like cheap,
it's not like a cheap reality show.
It's like a well produced documentary
series about this couple that opened up.
Um,
you know,
we'd store on the main strip and
Colorado in this town in Colorado.
This is like ski town and it's just
fascinating man.
It's like,
so all the picking it up,
I'm greenlighting it.
It's on Netflix.
Oh wait.
But it was bringing it back,
but it was originally on like,
like CNN,
CNBC or msnbc or one of these other
channels.
Sort of these deep cut channels.
And in their first wave of,
hey,
we're going to make original stuff,
but nobody only,
no,
everyone only knows us for our news
content.
You know what I mean?
So,
so it just,
it just slipped through the cracks.
But I watched it on Netflix and I was
like,
I would kill for a second season.
I wanna I wanna I wanna I want to see
where these characters and maybe the
justice people are going to get it
picked up.
Maybe you talking about tweeted about it
a long time ago and nobody cares
exclusively for like my own,
like if you find a toy that is slightly
broken Uri and I need to,
I,
well the problem is I got,
I started getting scared of twitter.
It was like,
I don't want to tweet any like original
thoughts because God only knows where
that could lead.
So it's just like 20 year old like
personal yelp for like everything you
buy by default.
That's kind of what's happened
unfortunately.
But yeah,
yeah.
God forbid thoughts.
Yeah.
It's like going to look man,
we gotta be careful on twitter.
You know,
it's like,
but the other cool thing about Netflix,
cause you were just talking about like
that's such a common thing is if
somebody makes a great show for the
wrong channel and it shot,
that happens all the time.
I mean that happened.
Got Two more,
uh,
oo much here.
By the way.
We are up to 23,000.
We have,
we got more shit to write asking.
You've got to,
which is a Jew word for a Jewish word
for Munchie stuff podcast.
Schmutz oh yeah,
there's trip hightail.
Jacob's sausage.
And then uh,
let those some muddy as long name.
What you wrote that you on the podcast.
I wrote those already.
So did you do the furry one?
No,
no you did the high tail on the Jacobs
sausage aren't perfect.
Those are take a look.
Take a look right there.
Hold up,
hold up high tail.
He needs this for his marketing did
well.
It's like literally like on is on,
is on a part of his face.
Kind of look to your left I tail.
All right,
there you go buddy.
That's fine.
If you ever spent,
um,
so we should just choose the longest
word they can possibly think of for your
face.
And entertainment wants to work for
Netflix now.
Justin,
are you jealous that he is working for
Netflix or you have to be really cool to
work for Netflix?
Just based off of everyone I've talked
to you asshole.
Like you could show like,
like the wrinkles on a,
on a butthole and everything's okay.
No,
no.
Uh,
I mean you could,
I,
I presume the whole gimmick of the
butthole brothers.
Yeah.
I mean that's really exist anywhere
else.
I do want to say though,
I have so much to ask you justin.
We're at 23,500
guys,
please go to the rewards page.
We are so close to our first milestone.
Joey's buttholes getting puckered up and
ready,
ready to diarrhea and that kitty pool
guys,
we are so close to that first milestone.
There's incredible rewards at stake
yesterday.
Throw this up.
It's almost done.
Absolutely.
Look at that or well,
it's a raft way to your,
uh,
hold that out in front of the first
piece of original art has been
conducted.
Isla Klein.
It is going up on the rewards page.
You can raffle now.
We've got a rich dude.
We've got so much value up there.
No,
I don't think we're going to raffle.
We're just going to sell the pieces of
art.
Wait,
it's at a raffle.
A yellow or a sale.
Um,
let's raffle it a,
yeah,
the rafts.
Raffling all right,
we'll rappel.
Kick.
Can we ask,
is there like a,
I'm assuming there's some kind of like
live chat happening right now or
something or no,
there's no chapter though.
It must be just on like twitter or
something.
I just want it like if there's any way I
could get a request for like what to
draw or write.
Oh,
cause like,
yeah.
Why don't we do a poll,
by the way,
I want to do a poll.
You guys can give options.
You got to donate and donating.
You get to participate in the polls now.
I would,
I would be willing to for a thousand,
I wouldn't be willing for $1,000
donation to tell Lynn what?
Oh,
to lick a pepper.
I would be willing if somebody donates
$1,000
to touch it to my tired.
Scared at one.
No,
you don't have to use that one.
But Joe had trusts me.
A drop of my saliva is a law.
You pee.
You want that one?
Are you doing,
I don't mind.
For a guy that's stuck his dick in a hot
dog bun.
You really,
uh,
overly overly guarded about cooties.
That being said,
we are getting so close.
So guys,
Post Malone,
Smash Guitar,
Rick and Morty original.
All right.
Stop with the donation.
We've got the limited edition journal.
That thing's worth by my estimation.
At least a hundred thousand dollars.
Get the in there.
Eva Klein original art.
Get in there and drop somebody.
Thank you.
Can we do the furry thing?
Oh,
shredding the first thing.
You got it right.
It's um,
look at this fucking suck about
sweethearts.
Busy here.
Training.
What's it got to say?
Is he over here trying to say you want
to do it?
I'll do it.
It's um,
it's something about a furry,
uh,
it's written here as um,
as Amea Kinda.
Wow.
Whoa.
Geez.
Good.
You said you could write it on their
neck.
Justin,
rick and morty.
Huge Rick and morty news.
The show was renewed big time.
Yeah.
Tell me about that.
So we got,
we got a,
we got a big hefty order for more
episode.
Tell me about how big was the order?
Um,
it was like another six seasons.
It's,
it was,
it was [inaudible] 70 episodes.
70.
Ooh.
Yeah.
And we're in the middle of production on
the,
Oh God.
I mean,
well,
the jury's out on that one.
I mean,
hopefully not,
uh,
you know,
a crazy long amount of time.
Now you guys are currently in production
of the new season,
right?
Yeah.
And how's that going?
It's great.
It's
going good.
We've got,
we've got really good,
uh,
we got some really good stuff like that.
The,
in the can,
uh,
we have,
we have some animatics and the can,
yeah.
Like we,
I mean we're,
we're,
we're shipping stuff is getting shipped,
uh,
or about to be episodes are about to be
shipped for color animation.
But yeah,
like this is so long.
We're,
we're,
we're moving along you,
Ethan and your,
and got a good season.
That's great.
Yeah.
I,
everyone's super going to be cool and
spoilers,
boilers for us.
Jay,
real quick.
Some exciting news.
Yeah.
Oh,
can we hit the first milestone?
Well.
Just not want to pick up this
conversation and we'll hold on that.
Alison.
Guys,
we think
you so much.
This is milestone number one.
Keep it coming though.
For Christ's sake.
You guys that the value of these gifts
far to pass 25,000
that's right.
That's right.
We're taking a loss here,
Joey.
Let's all go.
Let's get your ass in the Kiddie Pool.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
Yeah.
I don't think I should get in the Kiddie
pool,
but this one,
you want to do it here.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
No,
no.
He's,
he's a writer.
He's or I'll give them a good view and
let's make it happen.
Let's bring it to the tail.
That's a fair,
yeah.
That's a fair compromise.
No milk.
No,
I'm kidding.
So are you going to be,
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
There's a lot of peppers in that bowl.
What are we looking at night?
Oh wait,
wait.
That's it.
Those will be no salad and Habanero.
Wait,
what?
Wait.
Hold on.
So those are all just Jalapenos.
No,
no,
no.
Have an arrow.
That's a Jalapeno.
Are you sure that's a Jalapeno?
I don't,
I'm not a look.
I'm not a,
I'm not a pepper expert over here and
spicy.
I want to make sure this is spicy.
I can smell it.
All right,
take about you.
Tell me if that's like,
if that's like a mild Jalapeno.
I'm gonna be pissed.
Oh boy.
But these would be little babies will
get you for sure until the spicy.
Him keep going.
Keep going man.
You got it.
Oh,
is there a carbs in this?
Uh,
no.
No,
no ma'am.
As I said,
you will be having diarrhea,
so don't worry about Carla.
Don't worry.
It's all out.
Are you guys hungry for your free a
gummy bears?
It'll be good.
Oh,
thank you.
Uh,
Holy Moses is here.
What spice level is that?
How many?
Two,
two little babies time that spicy,
but like,
it's kind of good,
but I'm not.
It's Huh?
It's really quiet.
I'm a little underwhelmed.
I was expecting cartoon flames to shoot
out of his mouth.
Now he's just loony tunes his license.
But it happened down like a pepper.
I'm good.
Hang on you guys.
We're not here for good.
Yeah.
This is chopping this puppy down like
it's no problem.
We need to get to the next goal.
Well,
I'm going to hustle though next goal.
Good that you're being real because then
we'll know
for sure just how much the real one
messes you up.
Now this hub,
he narrowed this,
we'll get ya these guys.
Sorry.
It goes a lot.
So it's starting to burn building up
now.
I have a friend who wants made a stew
with these hobby narrows in Mexico and
we were all up at 4:00
AM shitting your brains though.
This is great.
Great Party series visit friend.
Good time.
We shall shit in the same bucket and
made a stew out of it.
I hate,
as I was saying,
she'd be like,
I don't want to finish a sentence but
I'm halfway through it and I want this
to blog and write a little about the a
bunch of dudes shit and in the same
bucket and then making a swirling into
the same potion.
You know,
we all say something in our lives it's
remembered is like our most powerful
quote and that might be yours.
That might be just chiseled in stone.
Well guys,
50,000
is next.
Can you bring in the ghost pepper and
the Carolina very with those things look
like.
That's my dog,
Dan.
I'm almost done picturing the pepper.
Really Getting Ready to tread.
It was going to jump into the milk bone.
This doesn't,
I feel it.
This is not even that much and I'm
already feeling it like in my stomach
because I'm never eating this much ever
before.
It's usually like a little sliver.
You know.
You feeling it more in your stomach then
your mouth.
Yeah,
more than the stomach.
Oh Man.
Your job when it starts,
I'm in trouble signing up.
I'm in trouble,
man.
You're going to be eating the entire
pepper for all of these.
Yeah.
See not that big yellow ones.
Well,
well bring in the Carolina reaper in the
wait,
wait.
Oh,
just just to show you in a reaper.
Terrifying name.
Just,
Oh,
we're at 26,000
guys,
keep going.
Keep in mind.
Or if somebody donates $1,000,
I will lick the Carolina reaper.
I know that doesn't sound nuts.
You had to like lick the inside dead.
Tell me about your experience earlier
date.
Thank you so much.
Yeah,
I was just curious.
So I tore off a tiny little piece of one
of these Carolina reapers,
which by the way,
they are dried because they are not in
seasonal current Lord.
And yeah,
I found out when I looked it up,
the dried ones are actually even
spicier.
Oh boy.
So yeah,
I just,
I just licked the tiniest little corner
of it and it was about 30 minutes of
pain go out of my mouth.
Yeah.
So,
well,
let me see.
Oh Wow.
Where'd you guys get these from?
They'll order them online.
Yeah.
Okay guys,
what things are moving along?
We're at 26,000
and a half.
Come on close.
Want to donate some money?
I have only a thousand dollars.
I want to get,
I want to,
I want to sweeten this,
mix it up.
I want to sweeten this a prideful.
What if we do?
What if we do a,
um,
one of these poles where either your
licking this,
either you're looking at the pepper or
who you're at this table is brave
enough.
Justin,
you're not even anything.
We'll do it.
No,
I'll do her in it.
You can't because she's pregnant or even
the intern or in the intern.
And so everybody who donates like how's
it about,
how does that work on the poll?
Let's,
let's start there and we can build our
way.
Okay.
Like taking a little nibble.
Yeah,
but can we say,
I don't know,
cause I find out what you get in on this
with us licking the pepper.
It's just licking it.
Can somebody,
but I don't know.
Or Sheeko can you take poor a little
frederick out and he's at the door
maybe.
I think he needs to go outside possibly
for a little diarrhea.
A little foreshadowing of what you
always sell.
Does it?
Yeah.
So let's make it,
let's make it three ways.
Three way,
Paul.
Every,
every donation is you get to vote for
it.
Either you,
Justin or me who takes a lick of a
pepper at the end of a certain amount of
time to do that.
I'm,
I'm in,
I'm totally,
and we set that up easy to get turned in
or no.
Oh,
sure.
Yeah.
Let's make it four then just because of
the little wildcard.
Yeah.
And do you copy that?
And so as a pull between who you and the
intern,
you,
Alex,
Justin,
who gets for Hulu and people can donate
to vote for who has to look the pepper,
let's say.
Let's put it all together.
Let's say after whatever.
We have the call with the CEO of direct
relief right now.
And after that call,
yeah.
Coming up and I'm a woman yelling in a
couple minutes to answer that call.
We'll go to the,
to the poll and we'll have a pepper
lick.
And can someone send me in water?
We need water for the site.
I hate milk.
I like almond milk.
It's a good thing we're filling a pool
with milk crate.
More uncommon.
Um,
now,
um,
Dan,
let me know when that poll is up so I
can get all the good people donating.
We're at 27,000
guys.
26 your way to do a like a,
a chat only for the people who donate or
only polls from you.
Only polls just pulls.
Now Justin,
we were talking about rick and morty.
Now you,
uh,
thank you Mitchell.
God bless you.
Appreciate you.
Now you guys were Ho now tell me about
the negotiations because you guys were,
there was a bit of a,
there was a lot of media,
a lot of speculation about what was
going on about that.
If they were going to renew the show or
not paying the new season.
Yeah,
no,
I mean it was,
you know,
it was a complicated,
just a complicated,
uh,
I don't know how much I can get into
the,
yeah,
well you're going to get justin in
trouble.
No,
don't say anything.
You don't want to you,
I'm only talking about what's in the
media,
so I'm not,
I mean ultimately it's like any show,
like at a certain point that there,
there has to be,
are there that you just renegotiate and
it took a little bit,
but we did it some haggling repair that,
that,
that's old news cause like that,
that that renegotiation was like we lock
that stuff down like way earlier this
year.
Like we've been in production for a
while,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
hey that poll is up.
The poll is up.
How do people vote?
They just go to [inaudible] on our,
on the donation page,
uh,
on the left hand side there's a little
category for poles and you can just
donate to whoever and uh,
early lead to in the intern pulls.
I see.
So there's a cat.
Yeah.
Well it's just $1.
Just $1 for who likes the pepper.
So click the link in the description.
It's tell defied.com/i
don't know why there's an APP,
a social strange url at free productions
on the left,
there's a donation button.
So I'm not sure.
A pull button.
Sorry.
There's only one color.
You are you kidding me?
Come on guys.
Well,
Ian,
it looks like $1.
Oh,
Justin,
$5 Ian and the intern $21 so that we
know when to cut it off.
So maybe,
you know,
at the five o'clock hour,
whoever's winning how long.
Yeah.
Good call.
Um,
so keep those,
keep that cash.
Why the way I just want to show this
off.
I don't know if there's a way we can get
a,
Ooh,
oh,
I'm done.
I'm done building this and whoever wants
it,
it's up for auction.
All right,
allison,
what's her name?
This value,
but I don't know,
cause I haven't seen this show,
this anime show.
Is She just a torso in the show?
Like,
I don't know.
I that'd be pretty rough.
Just like bone.
She flies around.
Yeah.
But,
uh,
this is,
this is it.
It's done.
I'm putting it,
I'm officially finished.
I'm going to,
we can write all over it or do whatever.
Do you assemble a day?
Oh,
not that many.
Uh,
I'm done.
I'm not,
but I'm like,
I'm done doing other anime girl models.
No,
no.
I just weird other ones,
but I'm like,
I the,
this was too much of my,
what is the significance of this?
I don't know.
I just felt like building something.
Uh,
I don't actually know.
Just regular porn.
No,
no.
Have you?
I've,
I mean I've checked it out,
but we're all married and Heela I've
literally adults under,
what's the hubbub?
Hentai porn is like God telling me,
Oh,
life Hentai porn.
Uh,
in real life.
What do you mean?
Like what that means?
It's like they take like,
you know how the ads all animated?
It's weird.
I don't constantly watch it,
that's for sure.
I'm like,
you're it with live action.
It's like cool world because they have a
lot of like tentacles and shit.
So like they have that,
but they have like prop tentacles and
they like crepe prop,
mother's porn where they put tentacles
and they insert that.
I mean you can probably,
have you seen that?
Have you worked off too?
I haven't worked on it.
Did we pull that up and take a quick
look?
Maybe not.
Yeah.
The CEO of drugs.
Let's ask them.
Hey,
let's show him.
Oh,
Isla.
Show your art.
You guys want this fricking original
rare,
a Sri pug guests relief stream.
Isla kind.
2018 look at that.
That is pretty Rad.
Pretty Rad.
I'll dude,
come on.
If it's not for the fire victims,
do it to watch Joey Salads.
Eat a hobby.
Neuropeptides.
Yeah,
she just whip that out right now.
Next to you of drawing.
I'll draw something.
Goddammit.
Here.
Wait,
kettering all over this.
This,
this anime character.
God just,
Oh,
why it's special to make it worse.
Bidding on.
You should sign it too.
I did y.
Oh,
nice.
Yeah.
There it is.
Oh No,
you're right.
You're right.
I gotta Watch this be the biggest item.
Oh,
no way.
We're up to 28,000
guys going to donate $10 million just to
get his hands on that.
No,
I'm winning.
You got a little popular.
You want it to look that pepper budget
and 19 verse 179 and the intern that's
moving.
Nobody has put it on the screen.
Yeah.
Can we see this?
Wait,
when did I just like alive?
Nobody.
Fuck it.
I was like,
oh,
this is great.
It was all in,
not me,
dude.
There's no way I have to look that
peppermint a year and I should have gone
in for something worse.
All right.
Oh,
Ian's got shooting right in there and
put in on the mic for him.
How is he sweating?
How's he feeling?
Dare.
I'm going to go,
I'm going to go out in the main room for
two seconds just to get this,
get this.
Justin's going home.
Sound of a door.
Slam car.
Driving off.
Can I not hear Ian?
I want to hear him.
Who Do you think is going to win this
one?
I think they gotta be,
it's gotta be you.
I feel like someone's in a drop 500 on
you real quick at the last second while
I'm already winning.
I mean,
Ian,
come on.
Did you drop money watching?
She's going to drop 500 on me.
Oh,
that would be fucking amazing.
And she would wait until the last second
to that.
She's kind of a dark horse that way.
That would be something special.
Dude,
Justin's lucking out right now,
man.
Yeah,
somebody I,
you know.
Well,
we're going to keep on it.
We're going to keep,
donate some money for Justin.
Well,
let's see.
I wonder,
is that cheating?
No,
no.
I mean we just invented the rules the
second ago,
so I'm going to say it's not cheating
then here.
I'll put it thousand on.
Just uh,
well I don't want him to know though.
Yeah.
Also we've got to do it quick while he's
out of the room.
I think I hear you just ran out to the
bathroom.
Can you put it Dan,
can you put a thousand on Justin for us
from you?
Yeah,
that's a great idea.
We gave Dan our card,
so I have,
I have Thomas a on standby.
Are you ready to do to for me to pipe
them in?
Um,
yeah.
Hold on one sec.
Let's wait for Justin something back or
maybe we'll do it real fast.
I was saying we gave Dan our card so
that he could bid for us.
Donate for us while we're in here.
So Dan is going to throw down on our
behalf a thousand.
Justin's gonna come back and be like
2000.
Good luck.
Outbidding us.
Um,
so on hold,
we're waiting for,
Justin is the CEO of direct relief.
Who's the beneficiary of our charity
stream?
Thomas Tighe.
If I'm saying your last name wrong,
that's because Mitchell betrayed me.
You betrayed my trust.
Um,
so joey,
tell me what's the weirdest thing you've
jerked off to you?
I don't even know.
I don't jerk off to weird things.
What's your category?
What do you like?
Just like,
I like skinny bitches.
Why do you say bitches?
Well,
when I'm watching porn,
it's like you,
you like the demeaning factor.
Do like you say skinny bitches.
So that implies somehow that you like
the demeaning and I just,
I mean,
any grill does porn.
It was like,
I feel like he couldn't call them
bitches,
you know,
like,
hmm.
I might say women,
they're doing porn.
Did Skinny,
skinny chicks.
Do you not like sick leave Guinea?
Just like Ben bitches.
Petite.
Petite,
petite.
That's the word.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
You like the t?
Where did you watch?
I'm asking the questions here.
What do you watch?
You know,
I don't,
I don't watch weird stuff.
I like,
I like it.
you know,
I like pretty girls.
That sounds so good.
It's so perverse.
That sounds so scary.
Monster.
That sounded so weird.
I said I just,
you know,
I like pretty girls.
God.
Your tone embarrassing.
No,
but seriously,
let's not talk about what I like.
I like Fart porn.
Bart.
Yeah,
me too.
Do you have a favorite a star?
He's the CEO of direct relief and
listening are probably,
luckily he is.
Is he like reevaluating his choice to be
associate with like,
you knew what he's getting himself to.
Justin rolland pepper sprayed joey cells
in the face last year.
I can't say.
You don't know what you're getting
yourself into,
Joe.
Uh,
Justin is pooping.
You know,
you know what I'd like to do?
Do you want to talk more about your porn
preferences,
Joey?
No,
let's not do that.
Justin's walking back in right now and I
have Thomas on Stan.
We're up to $29,000
guys,
keep it going for this.
This,
you're eating that mall.
No,
this is small but deadly.
And Joey here is looking a little too
frank.
He's looking a little too jolly.
He's look a little too happy.
We got to get the milk flowing.
But in the meantime I do is we have the
CEO of direct relief on the line with
us.
Thomas Tighe go ahead and uh,
please welcome to the show of Thomas
Standby.
I'm going to pipe them in in just a
moment.
Here we go.
All right.
Taking them live right now.
Here we go.
Hey Thomas.
Hello.
Welcome.
Thanks for calling in.
Thank you so much.
Pleasure to be here.
Thanks for what you're doing.
Oh well let me ask you,
how do you,
how do we say your last name?
Is it tighe.
Okay,
thank God.
Because I was going to fire an intern if
they,
if I had a mispronounced,
so,
so thank you so much.
Um,
now since we got you here,
maybe you can tell us a little bit
about,
you know,
how the money we raise affects you guys
and specifically how it goes to help the
people who lost their homes and
everything and the wildfires.
Well,
first of all,
I really can't thank you enough for what
you're doing.
It's um,
you know,
these things.
He had a lot of attention at the time
and then there's so much news coming at
people,
it's easy to forget.
So I think what direct relief does every
day is try to work to make sure that
their health services available for
people who need them and can afford
them.
And on an everyday basis we work with
the local nonprofit community health
centers,
um,
free and charitable clinics all around
the United States.
And you know,
we're based in California.
So that's where we started.
So that's typically where we plug in and
in Butte county.
And um,
just like last year in Sonoma,
Napa when the fires hit,
these places that serve people who are
vulnerable,
even on a good day is where we plug in.
Cause there's such,
so deeply rooted in the communities.
And unfortunately I think,
um,
what happened in paradise was just kind
of unprecedented.
I think it,
again,
it caught us by surprise here in this
kind of new abnormal mistake and kind of
the devastation that just,
you know,
cause a lot of deaths caused a lot of
people to flee.
So what we did is kind of what we do and
checked in from a health perspective,
what can we do immediately?
And ended up just rushing on daily
deliveries,
things from kind of the masks for the
smoke and the inhalers for people who
were,
you know,
had breathing problems,
the oxygen concentrators,
um,
that,
that seniors often need,
but particularly if they're evacuated
and putting a shelter,
um,
and just basic drugs and things like
that up up.
All the evacuees ended up in these
temporary shelters and they all got hit
with the norovirus,
which is kind of this horrible disease
of like vomiting and diarrhea.
So it was just about as bad as you can
imagine.
But you know,
the people who we were working with who
were kind of staff from the hospital
that was burnt out,
they set up a clinic in the East Avenue
Church up in Chico and were just so on
it,
you know,
just really,
just working 24 hours a day with
nothing.
So that was kind of where we started.
And since then we've been continuing to
work with the kind of the local public
health officials who were kind of
overwhelmed and even the firefighters
and um,
kind of the first response teams that,
you know,
they,
so many people got deployed from around
the state and we've worked with them a
lot and saw last year,
even here in Santa Barbara where we were
burned out and then had a debris flow,
you know,
after five minutes of rain the hill came
down.
Um,
sometimes they need help for specialized
gear or just terrain vehicles.
They can go out and do the,
unfortunately in paradise,
it's the remain recovery and kind of
identifying that.
So we're working with all of them.
And um,
you know,
we get money like what you're raising
for a particular place.
It's for that place.
It's not for director leaf.
It's,
you know,
we look at ourselves as trustees and
make sure that the people know that it's
there.
The money's going.
If they want us to buy something for
him,
if money is needed,
we'll transfer the funds and we've
already started committing funds to some
of the local groups that are just doing
such good work,
nothing.
And um,
and we're in a position where we can
cover all the expenses related to that
out of,
you know,
our normal organizational expenses.
So anyway,
really appreciate it.
Particularly now after it's kind of out
of the headlines what you and your team
are doing,
um,
for a whole different audience and the
type who probably think about direct
relief,
her stuff like this all the time.
It really means a lot,
you know,
can't thank you enough.
Thank you.
I mean,
it sounds like you guys are doing
amazing.
Yeah.
And port and work so grateful that this
exists.
That we could set this up.
Can I ask a question?
I just wanted to,
I just wanted to know,
um,
you know,
there's been a,
we were talking about how you guys have
this like amazing rating,
like you're number one in terms of its
transparency and I just was curious like
what goes into that kind of,
what,
what's,
what's the reason for rating like that?
Cause you guys are so trusted.
Yeah.
It,
a lot of it's just,
you know,
what you'd expect.
I mean,
how much money did you spend on
fundraising to get the money that you
received?
And that's a big point of contention.
People don't,
generous,
big surprise.
They don't like sending a dollar in and
having half of it's sent back on the
mail that they're going to throw away.
So we've never done that.
I mean I think our model has been,
you know,
we work out of a warehouse and um,
kind of functionally what we do is,
you know,
it's a distribution center so we can,
uh,
we have to have specialized licensing
for the medications that we hold,
but it's all provided free of charge.
We encourage companies to,
you know,
make their products available at no
charge,
we will handle them as well.
And with all the same accreditation that
any pharmacy or chain drugstore would
use.
We're,
we have the same accreditation that,
to handle these things.
But that's kind of the dilemma we're in
as a society,
right?
Cause if you have money,
you're very well served and people
target you,
they know a lot about you,
they know your preferences.
And if you're not a consumer,
you're kind of off the grid.
So I think what we're trying to do in
general,
it's just bring that level of kind of
efficiency in delivery of services to
people.
Not because there's any,
we do it for free.
So there's no profit incentive.
But we know that it can be done well
with these tools that exist
technologically and that,
so they can,
that's everyday trying to bring,
um,
kind of the resources that exist and
efficient way to the people who need
them and can't afford them for health
services.
You know?
And,
um,
it's pretty basic and,
but we have big gaps.
Even like California,
the richest state in the richest country
in the history of the world.
And yet,
you know,
we have kind of a big problems that are
chronic,
um,
up and down the state.
And so I think what we can do as a
private group is we're not political,
we're not religious,
but just deal with the people that we
know are deeply committed in their own
communities and try to say,
look,
how can we help?
Let's see if we can put together a
structure that's going to serve you well
and get your patients stuff that we know
they can't afford.
Cause it's expensive,
whether it's insulin or an inhaler,
things that if you don't have,
you will get sick,
stay sicker,
skits,
stay sicker longer and often die sooner
then just because of your financial
status.
And I don't think anyone wants that,
but,
um,
you know,
I think we just are so committed to
really help these,
you see these people up in beauty.
Like they were reluctant and we said,
look,
we've received money.
This is for you.
We want to spend to give you $50,000.
Cause I personally was up there,
I delivered the insulin when they needed
it.
I drove up there and um,
and I wanted to see them and let them
know.
It's like,
look,
there's a lot of people pulling for you
and this is what we can do.
But you know,
we said,
look,
how are you paying for this?
You guys are working for free.
And they said,
oh,
but you know,
we're okay.
That seems like too much money,
you know,
$50,000
to,
you know,
take care of a,
basically a standup hospital and clinic
for hundreds of people who had no other
options.
So,
I mean,
they were really reluctant to take it.
And we said,
look,
it's for you.
We have to give it to you were a
trustee.
But that reluctance of,
um,
kind of acceptance because you know,
the concern that there may be someone
else who needs it more was,
you know,
quite touching and inspiring and sad and
a lot of ways too.
So anyway,
it's,
it's a privilege for us to do it and to
have people like you and your audiences
and I'll,
you know,
amazingly talented people on the
creative side.
Um,
it means a lot to pull together and help
folks like that.
And so anyway,
sorry,
that was a long answer.
I appreciate it though
here that the idea that the money is
going to is actually going to be
legitimately on the front lines and
helping a bunch of people.
Like,
I dunno when I'm donating to something
like this,
I'm like,
ah,
what's going on?
We're all very cynical and skeptical in
this world that actually get you on the
phone and hear it.
They can hear your music is very
powerful and we thank you for what you
do and we thank you so much for calling
in and uh,
we wish you guys all the best and I'm
just thanks for being the best,
the best of us.
Well,
thank you.
I really,
I got to tell you,
and I'm talking to you,
right?
Tony,
Tony or communication guy.
He kept running in here first is
laughing and then increasingly nervous
giving me little notes about like I
wrote down,
I have the following written down,
which is weird for me.
Fart bombs,
question,
market commission,
raking over the coals and then some
other things.
I can't,
can't recall the nature of my job but I
thought I'm freaking out.
I just thought these guys,
I mean we know you guys,
you've done some stuff for us in the
past and uh,
so I'm so thankful and whatever it is
you're talking about,
he also said there were,
we were looking hot pepper,
so please health related organization
please don't get hurt.
Well one of us gets hurt for the safety
of thousands.
It's a,
it's the least we could do as you're out
there doing the actual hard work and I
don't know if you have the stream open
right now,
but this,
uh,
this young man in the Santa suit here is
about too,
is very close to our next goal of eating
this raw habanero pepper.
So we're to need his,
your blessings
and your,
your best wishes for him.
Is that Joey,
because I was watching earlier yesterday
getting nervous,
but you always,
sally,
please be careful.
Don't take a triple dare you know,
but thank you for all you've got to stop
out there,
Joey.
Yes.
Well you,
you've got to hedge your bets there,
Thomas,
because if you will,
if you wish him to much care you've got,
we're going to raise less money for you
guys.
Okay,
joey,
go for it.
Within the bounds of sanity.
Tone it down,
Thomas.
Right.
Thank you so much for calling in.
We appreciate so much what you do and
happy,
happy holidays.
Happy holidays and way to go.
I can't,
can't thank you enough.
Thank congratulations on all your
individual successes.
It's really cool.
Thank you caroline.
Thank you.
God bless.
All right,
thanks guys.
Take care.
Bye Bye.
I didn't have,
I didn't have the heart to ask him the
stupid questions.
He's waiting to see that guy.
He's like so sincere about what you
mean.
You had silly question.
Ah,
I was going to,
what are we doing?
A baby wipes.
Oh Jeez.
[inaudible]
is way too,
I don't know your rights be the right
call every day.
Trying to like,
I wasn't people like save people's lives
and we're just like,
you made the right call.
I didn't know that was the question.
Nothing.
Yeah,
exactly.
So tell me,
Thomas and I drove up there myself and
was passing out insulin.
So do you use baby weight?
Yeah,
I saved myself there.
I was watching Justin draw this thing,
trying to try and have a conversation
and just drawing the most obscene thing.
Help me.
What is this three loving?
It's false.
Three characters that are,
that are like,
you know,
they're just having a moment together.
Yes,
I want that.
How much is I want that.
I don't know what we're going to put it
up like I my mom,
cause I donated it though.
Okay,
well if your mom,
I don't know how many of these are going
to get shaped.
No,
no,
no.
That's mine.
I want that.
Okay,
I'm going to donate for it.
You want it.
You want to do that now?
You want to,
you want to wait till they're all just
buy raffle.
Oh yeah.
Well let's,
I'm going to,
I'm going to bid on that.
I am and fuck you guys.
I don't think we've been on what,
okay guys,
we have wait,
hold on.
There's only hold on.
Oh my God.
Ian Still almost won.
So Justin,
you're at 1059.
Ooh,
wait,
hold on.
Hold on.
There's only 1000 here.
Dan.
Not adding up.
I see you at 1059.
Yeah.
Uh,
Alex,
did you uh,
wait,
are you guys,
are you guys going in there and playing
games here?
Cause that's not,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't do that.
You donated a Dan on our behalf.
How do you,
I want to be able to say I haven't,
I done
well,
it's done.
It's done.
Okay.
We have until five o'clock.
10 we have 10 minutes for somebody to
pass Justin to get someone else to look.
That guy's number.
Okay,
that closes in 10 minutes.
Somehow we're going to be the only ones
that fucking actually looks these
because,
and Mike,
dumb ass.
1000 donations.
Still the top one.
Come on you guys.
And then by the way,
excuse me,
it said definitely not Ethan Klein was
the top.
Oh wait for real.
Oh,
not you can client.
Is that us?
Because the last one was a thousand.
That was us.
Maybe.
Okay,
so there you have it.
Nice job then.
Now guys,
listen,
it's going to be us that are going to
end up looking this pepper because we
are only $33,000
guys.
Now that journal alone is worth a
hundred thousand.
Do I need to go over the side?
These rick and morty?
Issue Number One.
Okay.
Um,
sign by the creators.
Did you guys talk about the,
the um,
primitive,
a skateboard decks,
the rick and morty perimeter ripped,
so I don't know where they were.
I don't know where they are,
but they're basically,
it's,
no,
not that.
Not that,
that's,
that's a,
that's a crew gift.
Hang on,
I have wrap gift to have the list.
Let me pull it up and it should be,
it should be up there.
But yeah,
like over more prizes cause y'all need
to open up your wallet.
What's the,
um,
also I just dropped in to more a group
of messages for uh,
for you ethan.
Okay,
great.
I've got another subscribed to Pewdie
Pie and read and read colorless
comic.com.
And these guys,
these cutie pie guys are opening their
wallets.
God bless them.
Got Big hearts a grudge for whatever to
beef is happening right now.
I can't keep track judged.
And you want me to show the skateboard
decks?
How do you tweet?
Like I,
it's been sideways even know how to,
I'm not even fucking kidding.
Where's the fucking button?
Bottom.
Oh,
I see.
Okay.
Pickle Rick,
the most famous episode,
one of the most famous episodes.
Here's the red it didn't that win the
Emmy pickled.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's,
that's an actual record draft.
So there could be like should auction
off your emmy man.
It could be writing in there,
there might be notes in there.
I just grabbed it.
I was like,
cause we keep everything.
So like that's a drafted,
someone had it at the record.
There were multiple records.
So I don't know.
What do you think there's any
differences in this draft between the
this,
and that's the other thing is these
scripts are going to be different than
the episodes that air,
cause they're in production.
So there's going to be dialogue in here
that no one's ever seen before.
Different jokes that you tried it.
I've never been out there.
It probably the biggest,
like there's another one,
uh,
the,
the um,
uh,
wasteland episode.
What,
what's it called?
I Dunno.
But like there's another script that's
like going to be significantly different
than what era then one went through a
lot of changes in production.
Pretty sure.
Yeah.
So these are original scripts did a bit
on some of these.
I'm curious about what's in there.
That alone is like kind of amazing.
I never get to see that.
Go over to the prizes.
Don't do it for the chair.
He'd do it to win this incredible shit.
Where's that skateboard deck?
So I want to show that because you're
very passionate about those.
On these,
on here,
Dan,
the skateboard decks,
I don't see them on this list.
The uh,
the crew gift,
skateboard decks are on there.
That's not what you're talking about.
Sure.
Justin.
Oh,
the new ones that he brought.
Just a primitive.
So there's a,
there's a set of four.
Are they on the new,
the new rick and morty?
It's like the second.
Yes,
yes.
Oh,
that is it.
Yeah,
So anyway,
the second,
it's the second,
um,
in,
in the primitive a skateboard company
decks the,
so it's like that's the full set of the
second series.
The first series are all sold out there.
Awesome decks.
They're like really,
really just beautiful looking in person.
And then this also comes with four tee
shirts.
They're all rick and Morty,
primitive collaborations and then three
pairs of socks.
But really the decks or what?
That's like the prime,
that's like the full set and that's like
the prime,
uh,
that's,
that's the real,
a real dude by the way thing.
Get these,
these can all be signed that like,
like for like we can definitely like I'm
happy to sign them all.
Um,
they're not currently signed.
They're stolen their original shrink
wrap but whatever,
whatever,
you know the winter wants.
I'm sure they'd want it so we should,
I think I have a feeling we should sell
these instead of raffle.
I know we have the way to go,
I promise.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I think someone's more likely to just
buy it for a thousand outright.
No,
no,
no.
Let let Robbie been donating for it.
No,
I mean the one that is,
okay,
let's,
let's entertain the people right I to
draw and draw one.
Here we go.
We got one.
I know Paul's fans out there and work.
You can use it to motivate your
employees.
You can scare your friends and family.
When this putting this up somewhere
somehow.
Oh we got it.
We got new one from all we gotta do is
just is just take,
take these out and it throw them in a
frame teddy fresh and then give you a
hug by Isla client.
It puck as charity stream fire relief
campaign 2018 yo,
there's art up right effing original
shit right now.
The current poll score is 1000 Justin,
you are bricked,
buddy weight and Ian to enter and coming
in a cool second at 500 come on,
let's,
let's get in the intern boost.
Boost it up.
Come on guys,
let me do this and you can donate to
Ian,
the intern if you don't want to look
that pepper.
How do I donate to the actual tilt by
the tilt tilt tilt.
If I were to buy.com/at
a street,
actually productive.
Wait,
I'm doing it right now.
Let's see.
Let's click on the green donate button
and we're going to raffle for these two.
Go
to Poland,
Holland on and off with it.
Well,
you guys think raffles better,
so let's Raffia.
Yeah.
Raffles.
The way to go.
Let me show him off raffle is the way
to,
cause you know Alex Hirsch raffle or
Uncle Stan.
Oh,
I keep forgetting.
I've got a thing there.
Also,
we're framing it right.
These will be framed.
Oh,
and just done by Joey Salads.
Right.
Are you donating your ges?
I will.
I will choose.
Well,
okay,
hold on.
Let me see.
I think shreddies from ready for another
walk for a little guy.
Original Isla Klein,
Teddy fresh,
sending a hug.
This is cute,
adorable and credible.
Original art.
Incredible up for donations.
How many people are watching by the way?
That's good.
We should have lit myself on fire for
this one.
Oh we have more.
We have more writing.
You guys.
Dan,
why don't,
why don't you guys just come in because
it's too complicated since someone into
right and we don't have to think about
it cause we will,
I want to entertain,
I've got a lot of shit.
Haven't gotten to go to the bathroom.
We'll wait here.
I got a question for Justin because I
was thinking about this the other day
cause I went into one of those like,
stores that like sell like a bunch of
like random shit from TV.
Like when you guys make rick and Morty,
do you think about merchandise when
you're making it or is it just something
that happens?
Um,
I think,
I mean I have a very sort of toyetic
approach.
I hate to use that word because it's so
lame.
You are toys and you love your love
toys.
I have a very full of toys.
Your offices full of toys.
I over did that.
But whatever.
Um,
yeah I have like a,
I have a,
I have a toyetic approach to design.
So like I,
I grew up loving toys.
Yeah,
I'm obsessed.
I've been obsessed with toys.
He has a lot of like merchant,
it's what it was like for,
for example,
like season one,
we didn't know that that was going to be
the case.
You know,
like no idea but still hoped best.
Like best case dream is to have is to
have a single Rick Dahl is,
yeah,
but,
but I guess it's sort of like by default
my design sense is like designing things
to feel like they,
like they would make cool toy,
you know,
like every character has that feeling,
like that's,
that's the holy grail is if you can
design characters that would make cool
action,
figure it out.
Then now I'm on the same principles that
make a good cartoon design.
Make a good toy.
Like something that's simple,
that's bold there reads from a mile away
that clear in silhouette entertaining,
interesting contrasting shape demand.
If you're making a fucking cartoon,
it's probably also going to be something
that's like really catchy as a toy.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
For character design for sure.
Um,
yeah.
All those rules apply for good toy
design.
So yeah,
it's interesting.
It's,
but I don't think it's been outright,
I mean they're there,
believe me,
there's times where I'm thinking about
like,
Oh man,
you know,
certain things like rick's gone or like,
I like the portal gun was definitely not
a thing.
We were thinking about a toy for when we
made that.
You probably,
that made it a little bit like fancier.
It's,
yeah,
totally aliens of them.
You'd like make it a little bit.
That was definitely one that was not
even considered.
But um,
but yeah,
but,
but a lot,
but there's,
there's been certain characters,
I'm trying to think of like a specific
thing I think that I think is gone maybe
or just a choice to like use a certain
gun a bunch of times or like go back.
Like we have so many guns design and
it's like,
Oh lets some of the cock sucker put
$1,000
on me.
It wasn't me,
wasn't me saying I'm just trying to make
this a little interesting man.
Spiring to uh,
two out to vote you off the island
double agent man.
My God,
Alex is sitting pretty at 30 hour.
Alex Alex is good.
I'm happy with this guy.
Joe.
You can put down a thousand on Alex.
I'm kidding you two D monetize it.
So when,
when do we get to the next uh,
Joey pepper?
Like that's what I want to know are we
are getting a what do I got to click
here?
What do I got to click here?
If you got a bunch of lame I was
watching,
they ain't donating.
Thank you.
Flash,
your lemos prove him wrong.
Red Pepper,
35,000
over a dollar a viewer.
And that's incredible.
I really think that,
uh,
we got,
um,
so go ahead and get,
we got to shout out to find people who
have,
there's other,
there's other prize things that we
haven't really talked about.
Yes,
but we have Zach sees Zach subtype Cutie
Pie.
Ashley Marie,
Google.
Oh God.
So Ashley Marie wants a ghoul
vibrations.
Did nine 11 written on Joey.
Okay.
We'd eat the whole pepper.
What does that,
uh,
so yeah,
I wasn't sure.
D dbss or dbs student,
uh,
donated $500,
for,
or I'm sorry,
$100 to joey saying eat the whole
pepper.
I don't know if he wants that written or
if he was just trying to get you to eat
the whole prepper.
We're at 37,000
guys,
keep it coming.
And then a ricotta,
this comic that was anonymous,
but thank you to whoever you are.
Someone's he on me.
Joey,
you just go ahead and we'll continue
with the show as you.
Um,
right on me.
No,
I've got some great things for us to
watch.
If you guys would like,
I'd like to get your takes on some
things we real quick.
Can we,
there's a couple of other really,
I mean,
I don't know how easy is it for the
people that are going to the site to
peruse and just find this out for
themselves.
But like there's hell let's talk to up
there.
But like anyone here hasn't checked out.
Surprises should know that you need to
check that out.
There's two massive Cryptozoic game
prize packs.
All that stuff will be signed or all the
rick and morty stuff will be signed by
me here.
Let me show it.
Which one?
Um,
it's the CRYPTOZOIC Games prize packs,
like these big ass.
Um,
there's also,
uh,
rick and morty trading cards.
Two of them.
One of them's a sketch card by me,
which is,
those are going to be really,
I don't think there's,
I think there's,
I don't know how many there are,
but there's not a lot I like,
literally there's not a lot of them.
And then there's also an autograph card,
which also not a lot,
um,
mixed into the decks or into the packs.
You know the,
the blind,
it's like trading cards,
you know what I mean?
Oh Hey little guy.
Um,
so uh,
that's,
that's also up there.
What else?
What other cool shit is up there?
I guess that's probably about it.
There's so many rewards including for
all the guys who just want to get
something bad ass.
This Christmas ps four pro and xbox x
switch bundles all up there.
Yes.
Justin did you brick cause you had pet?
Oh is that what that should be?
Part of the thing that's by itself that
is going to,
that's not rare.
It's not,
well I mean maybe justin either.
Justin is trying to play it up now,
but I was like why?
Why are we putting a rick she pet bites.
Well that's why I know,
I was like can we bundle this stuff too?
Like no,
no.
Cause you could take all the,
all the donations for the ric Chia pet
and pull it in to what the bundle that
then the one guy's like,
I just want the ric cheap.
They still limited.
How long would the other,
I have a Rick Chia pet.
I don't know.
By Justin reuland.
Oh,
I don't know.
Zero I guess.
Yeah,
let's hope there's also uh,
uh,
the squanch games or trover saves the
universe pack.
Is that up there?
Oh,
it's five.
The,
the bidding is over.
Yes.
Did you want to continue?
So let's going up there.
No,
we'll wait until it gets goes up.
So the pole that our first poll has
completed and then Ethan somehow thanks
to Alex,
I'm sure a double agent anonymous
donation a moment ago.
Can you put it up?
Yeah,
let's see.
The final tally.
That wasn't me.
I,
you say a moment ago,
you're talking about when Alex was on
his phone,
right?
Weird coincidence was on my phone,
but I was not doing that.
I promise I was too.
Right.
Alex,
you wise guy.
So,
but there you go.
We just raised three.
Like what?
I mean that's like 2000 right there.
Almost three almost.
Great.
Well,
it looks like you got to look that
pepper.
So we are at,
okay,
well let's,
let's create the next bowl.
You crying over licking it?
Giovan munched a tasty little Jalapeno.
All right.
Yeah,
I got ready to eat anything reading
this.
I'm going to end up with more spice in
my mouth.
Then you are,
oh,
James Wean Hoff gave us 1,100
wait,
we're not missing any big donations.
Are We?
You guys able to,
okay,
thank you.
Oh,
this is like real time donations coming
in.
Yeah.
Oh that's,
that's really cool.
Again,
you guys don't have to donate separate
raffles.
If you
donate $1 separately,
it doesn't increase your chance of
winning anything.
Oh yeah.
You could donate,
like you're saying,
like if you did,
if you did a dollar 20 different times
on one thing,
same as 20 pinging around like do a
dollar and this one I'm going to,
that's why I was saying bundle some of
the ship.
There was a lot of confusion about the,
yeah,
I don't know how.
I don't know.
Really.
I wonder if you're still trying to
change the rule.
What if we could raise the mammo because
all these $1 guys are killing it.
Okay,
that's fine.
No,
no,
no.
That's their,
their odds are less,
but like they're still able to
participate.
All right.
Thank you for all your work the h three
team has done in this livestream and
podcast.
Happy.
See Isla Ethan putting out great content
on the h three sheet page.
That's the luck with your baby,
Papa.
Bless.
Thank you Wayne.
Why in,
Huh?
Well that ain't,
did he,
um,
was that a poll donation or was that
just a random thing then I'll go check.
I'm not sure what that was.
All right.
Well regardless,
I have to,
it's the liquor pepper now.
So we've got the Carolina reaper.
No,
I'm going to choose one.
Oh my God.
It says Carolina reaper.
What are you doing?
Okay,
so all right.
Yeah,
it does.
You're right.
Oh my God.
Do you want it right now?
Threader yeah.
Do we have gloves?
Yeah,
let's turn up that pepper music.
Yeah.
Turn the pepper music.
Jumanji Hanson that have shredder.
Like Lick my hand.
Oh yeah.
Be Real good.
It's a good point.
You're going to want it.
You're gonna want to wear gloves while
you,
uh,
guys,
let's think of a new poll before I do
this so we can get things moving so we
can raise some cheddar cheese.
Is there anything I can donate?
Let's see.
Let's see guys,
we're at 37,000.
Wait to the next goal.
Oh,
come on.
Come on for crazy.
Why don't we do a thing where,
well nevermind,
actually,
were you about to suggest something that
would require you to look something?
No,
no,
no.
I was,
I was going to say what would it be
possible to rather than a pole.
I was thinking like maybe the next
person who donates x amount,
like decides what you draw or something
like that.
You know what I mean?
Like sure,
sure.
Yeah.
You're way better at like,
like Improv draw.
Like,
I just do.
I like drag weird stuff that I,
if we were trying to think of something
that was valuable that people would want
to donate for it probably be probably be
a message from our old buddy Rick
Sanchez.
Right.
Seems like that seems that seems like
that around and give it a smell.
You're touching it.
Oh Dude,
I already touched with my finger.
It's super
dry.
So Sma,
everyone's pass that around and give it
to pass it around.
Mallet
smell.
Okay,
well I did this art.
It's either,
is this skin spicy though?
This is either going up for auction or,
or Ethan's swiping it.
All right,
well I'll tell you what do you call
those Bros?
Cause let me tell you what I'm gonna do
with this because I don't know,
like I don't know how many more I'll,
I'll do more,
but like,
let me tell you what's going on with
this either.
I'm getting this for $1,000.
If somebody,
doesn't this be a straight purchase?
No,
no,
no.
Everything should be,
it's mine.
Like me money or less money.
Everybody still be raffled is all the
original art up right now on the
donation.
Thousand Bucks,
man,
right now when you're holding isn't up
yet.
But look at this.
This is freaking incredible,
dude.
And I will eat it.
Let's not go overboard.
All right.
Do you want,
do you want it though?
I do want because your mom already
donated.
He's not going to appreciate this.
Well I'll drop whatever she wants.
Whatever you want.
Okay.
Yeah,
I'll draw something cool.
I don't,
I think she just wants like a little,
well let's show rick and morty.
Let's put that up.
You know what?
We have that chat,
that chat stream.
Wait,
listen,
if you donate a dollar,
can you put a comment next to it?
Yeah.
That's how we can get a chat stream
going.
So why don't we put that up.
Okay,
good.
Okay.
And then why don't we ask the people who
are donating a dollar,
do you,
should we add this on the thing to be
like a raffle?
Like,
should we add this stupid thing as
around,
I'll do as many $1 donation as I like to
show how people can donate.
W What are people choosing?
That word is asking.
We're just asking like do they want,
do they want,
Oh,
next year there should be a way to pick
many raffles and have one transaction.
Oh we need a new,
we need a new port.
We need a new poll.
How about the next bull?
Someone has to take a nip,
like actually eat a little piece of it.
Did you hear that though?
He said he's somebody posted a comment
saying next year there should be no way.
Oh yeah,
you're going to probably need some milk.
They saying that next year there should
probably be a way to donate to multiple
with one transaction.
So you like add to cart,
add to cart,
add on our head.
That functionality exists on,
on the site.
Well we'll have to get on it until the
whatever the next poll.
A little nibble.
Come on.
No,
maybe you should know before I go.
Here I go.
I'm looking at this.
Okay guys,
we watch.
I'm nervous for you because I know we're
about to see.
I've just going to touch it on my tongue
is that is definitely,
I think you're looking at when you have
this up in the background,
people are,
it's going crazy.
Damn.
What?
Stick that all the way,
right click and give it a good good
lift.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's a good lik,
oh my God.
Oh,
what's up?
What you want to show some stuff?
I rubbed it on my tongue and it was like
immediately like a lot of pain.
He's still tasting it like,
like where are you at?
Just hit me.
Oh my God.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm curious.
The Carolina ghost pepper in your mouth.
The doctor's office.
Smiley faces.
Like,
like chart what number?
No,
it's not,
it's not very,
well I can't say because it's actually
getting worse.
It's still,
it's still working its way into your
already going for the milk though.
You're like not even letting it get to
it's,
I mean I was,
all I did was kind of rub it on my
tongue and I was shocked by it.
Like immediately blasted.
Show your,
we're not even going to get there.
We'll be lucky if we even,
it gets you to eat a fucking,
let's do another poll for that.
Joey's solids flew here and you guys
can't even get him to eat a hobby
narrow.
I want to,
I want to get to the Habanero Habanero
quicker.
People are saying add the drawing as a
raffle.
See,
look,
people want the drunk.
Let Ethan keep the drawing.
It's all over the place.
Someone's gave $5 just to let me keep
it.
Everybody's saying raffle it and one
said I'm missing from the rewards.
Whoa.
What does that mean?
Oh No,
she'd be at the bottom.
I just looked this up there.
Yo,
what the fuck?
What the fuck?
We're not getting donations.
Oh yeah.
Why?
Hey Joey's not on the thing anymore.
Huh?
What's going on here?
I took it down for a second cause uh,
cause we're backed up on his Oh okay.
We got,
we got to go send someone in here with a
sharpie.
All right.
Give me a second.
Full time.
Right all day.
And don't take it down either.
Brought some,
yeah.
Don't take it down.
Either.
Brought these decks.
I Dunno.
I thought we should show some of the
stuff cause I'm the pictures maybe don't
show how cool it is.
Definitely don't.
So this is,
this is two of them.
Yup.
Of the,
of the new,
um,
primitive decks.
Oops.
And then the back is like different or
like different color.
It's cool.
There's also,
I think,
see,
I don't think there is any grip tape and
on this is the other two.
Whoa,
whoa.
There we go.
And uh,
again,
like interesting.
Yeah.
These are,
these are,
these are really cool looking in person.
I mean it's like the,
it's like foil.
It's like a foil back.
But yeah.
So the whole set and then I'm gonna look
through
these scripts and actually see for
myself,
dude,
Justin,
should we do a thing where if these are
old people can request what you draw
next with their comment?
No.
You,
you,
me.
Yeah.
Way Better at that than I can't see.
Um,
okay.
Uh,
how,
how do we set it up,
I guess?
Uh,
even how do I set it up if I'm trying to
get people to request a drawing for me?
Like it's just this I'm,
and then just look at it.
Just like,
all right guys,
I guess a donate a dollar to suggest
what I should draw an almost 40,000.
God don't arable here or boards could,
I mean you could choose what I draw.
I would say 50 bucks.
We'll consider your suggestion.
If it's over 50 bucks.
I mean if it's,
if it's 50 bucks,
I'll,
I'll do it.
Um,
let's see.
Let's see what people will ask for 50
bucks.
The first $50 gets to,
gets to pick.
All right,
well we'll keep it up.
Keep it up by the time this is a
relatively like,
like this draft is pretty close to what
ended up on screen,
but I know that there's change or like
I'm seeing that there's change though.
I took a little lick and I'm feeling
fine now.
Okay.
Now,
by the way,
a pay.
A lot of people have been donating to
joey and to write on my face.
We're backed up,
but we're working on it.
We're sending people in.
They're going to be working the faces.
We
got to,
we got to do right by you.
We're working on it.
Please be patient.
Joey,
please be patient with us and you got
to,
you got a $50 donation for.
What'd you drew?
I think,
let me see.
Let me,
I can scroll back down.
Whereas it,
Alex,
I think you're cool.
I don't watch your show,
but I will.
I like that.
Oh,
that's sweet.
I like,
I like someone just being a fan of just
me as a human.
I can't,
I can't scroll up.
It's just zipping right by.
That's kind of the sweetest thing.
Anyone,
anyone can really say.
I have no idea what you do or what your
value is in this world,
but I'm a fan.
Joey,
why don't you give this a lik I'm
totally fine now.
I just want you,
you want to look a different one,
Mr.
I don't know.
You don't want to have anything to do
with it.
I just want to,
okay,
get it done and over with.
Next poll y'all.
Next poll.
I think so.
The next,
the next Paul Ladies.
Okay.
Here.
Look,
look,
look.
These are the script.
We read out a line.
Would you like to talk a bit about this?
Do you want me to hold it?
No,
I'm just showing it.
What would you like me to do?
Rick and Morty,
the abcs of Beth by Mike mcmann episode
three Oh eight.
Well by Justin reuland and Dan harmon up
next original original,
uh,
going through those and I'm noticing
that they're a little broad more sketch
and he grabbing false Terry Walls fans
is the actual [inaudible].
So hold on one sec.
I need to draw.
Those are legitimately,
no,
no drawing.
Let me draw something.
I did see someone asked me to draw.
You guys don't want to style.
I think we should both draw ethan.
He was joking,
but we good.
What our prediction is,
get in here now.
Now,
Dan or somebody,
if Mitchell can say it or you,
if you have the person who,
who donated for the writing,
we need the names.
Go ahead and get the names or Dan can
read them as your,
as your,
uh,
writing them.
Let's go ahead and go back to you.
The names are,
we have Ashley Marie dbs student who may
or may not have asked,
uh,
to write the whole pepper,
but we're doing it regardless.
And a Matt Westcott.
So you three thank you so much.
Thank all our donation each getting
their start right.
And God dammit.
All right.
I'm taking the request to draw it,
Ethan,
and he was child.
I'm,
if anybody has any suggestions about
what that drawing should look like,
a donate and say some suggestions,
but uh,
I know what's going to have the combined
aura of the both of you to somehow,
all right,
I'll get this out.
Is it,
I guess I should,
should I draw it?
It's like an adult.
Like what?
It's going to turn it?
Yeah,
just like,
yeah,
cause a baby's just like,
all right,
I can't really like dunk on a baby.
I mean you could try it,
whatever you're like.
Okay.
I'll do both guys.
Here's the next poll.
Okay.
Here's the next poll though.
Loser of the next poll has to eat this
flake.
You see that?
Oh,
that's just a flake.
Okay.
Eat.
All right.
You meet Justin.
Everybody okay?
Okay.
All right.
Yup,
Yup.
I'm doing it.
Justin,
I want you need to consent,
right?
Mitchell,
what are you writing?
So on his socks and his boots vibrate.
Google vibrations did nine 11 on his
cheek.
Okay.
We're all familiar with that conspiracy
theory.
Yeah.
At kids on bikes.
Six on his forehead and now I'm ready to
eat the whole pepper.
Okay.
On his nose and other cheat.
All right,
thank you.
I'm beginning to look like six,
nine joe or Dan.
Really finish it.
Oh,
wait a minute.
Hold on a minute.
I couldn't do it.
Well Wayne,
I even like,
it's not a Michelin Star restaurant.
It's not supposedly had to rat me out.
Keep eating.
Yeah,
I just saw it.
Okay,
so Dan,
let's make a new poll.
Okay.
This is,
this is one flake torn.
Is this lame or is this good?
No,
I think that's good.
A whole flake if just looking at made
your whole mouth on fire for a minute.
I think of like as a pretty good and I
think that you should have to like chew
it and kind of enjoy the joy and
following that likes to put it on your
tongue like a drop acid.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh yeah,
I know what you're saying.
Let it do its thing.
The bottoms,
the worst part.
Do you know that very well?
Yeah.
I'm just trying to figure out,
trying to figure out how to combine your
guys' faces here.
Now Joey,
you are famous for put,
you are known in the gay community.
Is that right for putting your Dick and
hot dog buns and sharing pictures?
I've run into more gay friends than like
my youtube fans.
Mm hmm.
And so do you get,
do you get a lot of gay offers for Sec?
Like are people interested and is that
something you would ever consider if I
needed to do it a full time job?
Like selling my underwear?
Yeah.
Or like selling photos.
I could easily have people offer to buy
your underwear used or or do they prefer
it?
You want to use you and have you sold it
ever?
No.
Why not considered it and I was all can
make a quick line.
They they ask me sometimes I'll feel
like 40 50 bucks.
Is that a good price for you?
It doesn't cost me anything.
Just got old underwear.
I have a lot of ripped up on the way.
That's true.
Huh?
Now do they want it kind of where we're
at 40,000
I would make it fresh for them,
you know,
41,000
almost now what you far in it?
Would you have a streaks Jane?
Like what makes a good pair under what I
should do is have like a website where
you buy joey's underwear.
Then you customize it by Joey's under
weight gain.
Come stain s g and would you try ask
cheese?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm so glad to.
CEO is gone.
I'm sweating.
He's still watching.
He's like no cash.
She's as she's all right Justin.
We're doing the second the the winter.
I guess it is what it has to eat this
flake of a Carolina reaper.
Okay.
All right.
I feel like this is not that
interesting.
No.
Yeah.
What are you doing that's going to cost
some real serious damage to somebody
that's not interesting.
I don't think we could do better.
I feel like we could do better in severe
pain.
I did that before the show for noma.
Wait,
you ate a flake flake.
Really?
Okay.
Oh sorry.
Sorry.
Um,
I'm just going to eat this then because
this shit is fucking boring and you're
all a drawing.
I'm not doing shit,
so I'm going to eat this.
You know what?
No,
I need,
I need to see written the whole thing.
I need to see a hundred dollar donation
top donor replaced.
He needs,
someone's got to replace the top donor
of $1,100
he said we'll eat that flight.
Yeah.
Oh,
can you guys cut to the pool?
I want to see Joey's a kitty pool.
Y'All need to see this sad sight cause
y'all aren't donating enough mind.
Show the Kiddie Pool.
Look at this.
That's disgusting.
That's where Joe should be laying right
now.
Let's,
let's,
let's kick this thing up a notch.
We got a car.
I got it.
I got a full of milk's bracket to get
into that pool and eat that next.
Oh,
we're getting close.
We're at 41,000.
And what do we have to reach?
Ghost pepper.
I'll go and I want to see,
just give me 100 bucks and I'll eat this
flake.
I feel like I'm back in grade school.
Just give me five bucks and elite this
hot dog and a draw their baby as posted.
Okay.
I got 100 bucks.
I was fat.
I got a hundred bucks from Sephora
young.
Uh,
can we,
are we all caught up on the writing by
the way,
Dan?
I believe so.
I'll,
uh,
I'll check back in and,
all right,
cheers everybody.
I'm eating a plague.
Nobody cares.
But I mean,
I want to see what happens.
Let's see.
This is going to be brutal.
Or are you holding it in your mouth and
you know all your thoughts?
Oh God,
go vote.
I growed up.
I regretted it for 100 bucks is worth
more than a hundred bucks.
I thought we're going to do it.
If somebody replaced the top,
the top boat I want gave a Hyundai,
but like I'm the only one that's going
to eat a carolina reaper.
This whole episode with Ed Joey Salads,
underwear as a reward.
We can do that.
Yeah.
I want us,
I'd be interested in know how much that
would embrace.
We'll,
we'll do the underwear that I'm going to
get in the pool with cause I want to,
I want to replace it anyway.
Milky underwear.
Yeah,
add it,
add it.
I want to know $10,000
who exactly is going to be handled?
Link Shipping.
That item.
Okay.
This is no joke.
Fucked up.
I cannot eat this for $100 I'm sorry I
put it in my mouth.
My mouth is on fire.
No,
no,
you gotta do it when somebody would top
the top,
the top donor.
That's all right.
I'm going to eat.
I'm going to tear off a little tiny bit.
These God damn fire core off a little
couple of chunks and I'm like,
God,
I'm the only one.
Oh my God.
Alright,
what's the next poll?
All right.
Wait,
I got sucked in to taste.
Got some art that I made.
Oh,
is that you suck in your opinion.
Yeah,
it's me.
It's me being in my own mountain,
so put it up.
Oh my God,
that's so spicy.
Signed it.
I'm really afraid of shredder.
Getting a hold of one of these flicks.
Yeah,
be careful man.
I'm just keeping it all right there.
All right.
I drew Ethan and he was baby.
Let me sign this.
Oh Wow.
It looks just like,
hey will you know it's weird.
One of my old dogs,
right?
Got You.
Don't want like dogs trueup like corners
and shit.
They still like this spray and it's like
hot pepper spray.
Okay.
Oh it's beautiful.
Who wants to buy this?
Or I can give a close close to your mom
and that she would love that.
This baby,
I kind of want that I draw are maybe
too,
so this is up.
Oh,
like your homie.
This.
My mouth is on fire just from licking
that.
Huh?
I ate a couple of flicks.
Right,
but I'm going to call her.
That's up.
We need a new cove.
We need a new poll.
What's the pull for crime and Justin was
the pool.
Um,
um,
all right.
You're the creative guy.
I mean,
I'm trying to,
I'm like scanning for ideas here.
Let's see.
Anybody,
anybody in there.
I have a good idea for a poll.
What torture do you want to inject into
our life for cash?
If somebody,
somebody makes a Paul.
Wait,
wait,
what's the poll thing?
It's like if this person has to do
something,
I feel like pulls into limited.
I would rather say that Joey and Ethan
will make out tongue kiss if,
if somebody donates $1,500
no beats the top donor.
No,
and they've already agreed to it.
Ethan is actually married,
so,
oh,
okay.
All right.
How about the non-married guys here?
I'm staying out of this.
Yeah.
You know what?
You're right.
That was a dumb idea.
There's five people on Tumbler who
already want to see all of us making out
drawings of whatever you can imagine.
Um,
to see that pop up.
All right.
I don't know man.
Like should it be spicy pep shit?
This shit is real hot man.
Well I want to get,
we'll be careful with that shit back in
cause I don't want shredder to get it.
Well if it stays up there,
he's not going to be a dog.
Is that the fish skin?
Yeah,
it's fish again.
Well I was trying to tell a story
before.
Oh go ahead.
So,
oh wow.
So know what I'm saying is they have
like this pepper spray that you spray on
like woods so the dogs don't chew on it.
Okay.
Yeah.
And my dog was like impervious to it and
it,
it was like straight up pepper spray
that you said it was like a wolf dog
seasoning seasoning.
So she was licking at it the whole day.
There you go.
That's actually pretty good dude.
Hasten oh my goodness.
Good.
That's a good mixture of like two of
you.
That's like a pretty incredible and can
be,
which in eyes and then he got ethan
eyebrows going to town and then like a
little baby food free food started
wearing fresh.
It's wearing teddy freshies repping this
fresh immediately.
What the Frick?
That is so good.
Yeah,
it's cuts.
It kind of debate.
It's kind of disturbing.
That's pretty good.
We're going to have to compare when your
baby's born,
how close it is,
which one of us is like.
Got It.
You got the drawing closest?
Oh yeah,
here.
Sorry.
Yeah,
lots.
Lots.
Heart.
Okay,
listen.
The next,
let's just do a poll.
Yeah,
go ahead Scott.
Okay,
I'll tell you what,
I'll drive it.
Okay.
Whoever,
whoever gets the most donation on the
next poll has to drive to the nearest
blockbuster and rent a really
embarrassing move.
What do you guys think?
What people want to hear Justin do the
ric voice,
man,
that's the thing.
You got to auction off,
man.
You Mind Justin?
You know it seems like a,
that's not a poultry level.
Whoever gets the most money does the
Rick Voice.
Yeah,
that's right.
Heel has to do.
Rick eat.
Didn't man.
Delicious.
Okay.
It's gotta be spicy pepper thing,
right?
I don't know,
but I don't want to outdo outdo joey.
Like I'm over here eating Carolina
reaper and Joey's sitting there like
fucking on his phone.
Okay.
Where are we at?
Where are we at with the donation?
40 2042 though we are getting close to
that 50 man.
Yeah,
that's going to be entertaining.
The 50 should be like after tongue kiss
for the victims.
The fuck is this.
I love that.
This is our chat stream.
This is great.
And we pull a prank call.
Are we wanting to do that or is that a
note?
Was there any fallout from last year's
prank call?
It was all,
no,
because that was one of the most
incredible things I've ever seen.
Like you know,
it was sort of,
it was,
it was in good,
good fun.
It was all in.
Good Fun.
Well,
we should have
donut,
a drive where if we get a certain
amount,
I love that we're on the fly trying to
set up a challenge for for that.
What does that mean?
5,000
Oh,
like little little challenges that fill
the channel brand.
Call Papa bless.
Oh,
I don't know.
Like it's,
I feel like I,
that's,
that's a,
that's a scary path because there's all
kinds of laws and shit,
right?
Aren't there?
We were a little more cavalier about
this last year.
I think we were just drunk or like true.
We are all very sober right now.
Oh,
I'll tell you what.
I need to drink alcohol,
you know,
let's do a thing where it's like,
we all have to take shots or whatever.
That's what was missing from this.
This is the mystery ingredient.
We got to give our baby fecal.
Oh,
I forgot about that.
Yeah,
he was,
he was off the table for that.
But the dream,
but I think I've seen Ila about as drunk
as well.
Maybe not,
but I've seen her pretty drunk and she's
like exactly the same as she is sober.
We go,
we were just,
we just put,
just put three shots on the table and
then we make that a challenge.
Whoever has the highest has to do all
three.
Oh God,
three shots.
Yeah,
man,
that'll get interesting.
I didn't say of what can we just do a
spicy pepper Schatz?
I'll do it.
I'll do it for free.
We'll get some,
get some drinks.
Skype,
bathroom.
Be Right back.
Oh,
if someone,
nobody drinks a glass of milk from the
pool after,
after joey goes,
that's a good one.
Oh God.
That shot of the little shot of very
nasty.
But Hey,
you know,
if the money's there,
you know what?
That's the pole.
Dan,
did you hear that?
Nope.
What's up a poll?
The four of us,
same victims including Ian,
Alex,
myself and Justin,
the,
the Louis Low.
We'll go in and instead of me has to
take a shot of the milk from Joey's
Katie Pool.
Okay.
Uh,
Ian says he's lactose intolerant.
He's out.
That's a bullshit.
That's bullshit.
And that's what he's saying.
And get them,
we need to get,
we need to get a separate pool with
lactaid or whatever.
[inaudible] you for real.
Are you for real getting out of this
right now because of your lactose
intolerance?
Yeah.
I should probably sit this one out.
Come on in a shot of,
it's not going to kill my do it for the
fire.
The people who it's going to be 50% shit
and piss.
God forbid in,
he could get a little taste of milk.
How about your whole house burned down
and you have nothing left.
Exactly.
There.
There's people out there that need this
money.
Put it in and the Po Ian,
come on.
Look at it.
Slowly creep up.
We're getting closer and closer to 50.
We got to get to fuck it.
We got to get all the way.
Meanwhile,
let's shoot the big cabinet.
Joey,
how do we,
how do we do this?
If someone drops a quick 10 grand,
we'll ship them a bottle of my urine.
I'm like,
God,
right now,
nobody's gonna donate.
Good Job Joey.
If I see a $10,000
thing in there,
you're eating the pepper man.
Oh Man.
Oh yeah.
So,
uh,
let's see.
I got a bunch of entertaining stuff
here.
Uh,
yeah,
let's look at some,
I thought
some stuff.
Hey everybody out there.
Got Any,
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Anybody up there got any a ginger beer?
Not Alcoholic.
Just just,
just good old sodie pop.
I just want to split it.
I just wanted your beer in this cup.
I wish I could drown out the wine.
Drink Ila or I should stay sober.
What happens if he drinks?
What happens?
I turn into a Gremlin.
Oh,
like on the,
like if you turned them on a drug,
I'm on an antidepressant.
Oh yeah.
They don't drink.
Yeah,
I really want to,
but you guys can get drunk.
I'm like,
what do you mean you try and do at
Gremlin?
Like the mixture is like I turned in
like at Lackland Gremlins.
Touch water and you start multiplying.
Is that what it is?
I thought they turned to evil.
They're multiplying when they touch.
Why did they turn evil at midnight?
Yes.
If they've eaten before midnight.
There's a lot of rules to that.
There's so many rules,
man.
Gremlins is like,
it's,
it's a lot of work.
Owning your Gremlin.
I have got our mcguire,
I guess technically,
but you guys keep the donations going.
We're so close.
Come the F on to my face guys.
What's going?
I love this podcast is just us like go
and come on.
I know this is not entertaining at all.
Munching on Japanese snacks in front of
the microphone is a little mushroom.
I fucking awesome.
Yeah,
they're really delicious,
right?
A little cookie with a mushroom.
And I'll tell you what,
Japan does not fuck around when it comes
to making snacks.
Look a board.
Julia is going to show her joy.
Don't,
don't change what you're doing right
now.
Just give God a shout of joy.
He's literally,
this is so lame.
We gotta get that pepper map.
Okay,
well let's talk about this three miles
north of mold.
Calm.
Oh,
here we go.
You dug this one up.
Only 420,000
views.
Is that on a card?
Actually,
I don't know.
I don't even know what I meant.
The other video,
I had a thousand views you showed.
Yeah.
Thank you for,
thank you for noticing.
Wait,
no,
what it did.
Oh,
the dog.
One dog.
We're getting held up.
Okay.
These are amazing.
These are the best candy I've ever had.
Yes.
Salicious.
Let's talk more about this.
I think that every burger,
which is another delicious Japanese
treat candy,
I don't think I brought one.
Very good.
Very good treat.
Um,
this is the worst.
All right,
and we're waiting for you.
Alex is the worst.
Just the worst.
KIPP.
So this year people have a spiritual
retreat and Norway and this guy,
oh Norway teaching them how to repel
energy using their psychic power.
Oh,
I think I've be.
Yes.
And so he is kind of doing a
demonstration.
Is this from like a larger yes thing.
Okay.
Three miles north of,
I don't know what it's called.
Not here it is.
So this is the instructor?
Yes.
Are you sure we haven't watched this
touch?
Can you come magnus,
I've seen this.
I've seen so far because she was still
out here on the podcast before.
I do watch a video of you watching this.
I'm afraid.
Can we watch videos of people just
destroying convenience stores after
this?
After this please.
I know I've seen this before.
These poor people are one step away from
being in a cult.
What are they trying to do?
They aren't if they aren't already,
so he's teaching them how to repel.
We needed the pole.
When you're standing on the,
on the,
on the edge of a lake doing this,
you might need to ask,
you might be in a call doing that rugby
man's,
if you're standing at the edge of a
lake,
per chanted up for Jack to energy on how
other people by God,
God,
Geez.
Oh Geez.
While she tries to pull it off like he's
having a seizure.
Oh Man.
Somebody give this guy in the house.
What was he trying to do?
What was supposed to happen?
You're juggling at the,
he was going to pretend to be repelled,
but they were goofing around and he
tried to make a point.
They show how real it is because is that
blood?
No,
that was just like her shawl or
something.
Just gave her a tumble.
Oh,
now he's like,
oh,
come into like,
I just woke up.
What happened?
Oh,
the spirit.
Listen.
He blames it on them.
Watch.
Where the fuck were you guys?
Will you guys,
I kind of want to give this guy my life
savings in that follow him into the
woods and where would he wears?
Like a little cheese.
He's healing or just by shaking his
hands and,
no,
but that was like step aside,
I'm the real good rule rollover.
You idiot.
I just act like she was shot.
Yeah,
come on.
Take it easy.
You're like,
you're acting like somebody raining.
Raining.
This is my favorite scam as being a
faith healer who injures people and then
tries to heal them.
What you just did to them.
It's like,
I've crippled you now I'm going to make
you stand like,
you know.
It's funny.
It's like she's kind of having to,
he might've broke her neck and he's like
Jocelyn,
her head now he knows.
He's knows what he's doing.
Suddenly he's better really hoping this
shit turns out to be real.
Well,
it's part of his scan.
He did it to show them is there a snake
root that it comes all wrong.
Yeah.
Let's zoom in on these people.
They're like,
I wish these people would stop coming to
this lake.
Just trying to have a nice weekend.
July.
They keep ruining it.
Join us in the circle.
All right.
Can you stop a Guy?
Who can you feel your legs?
All right.
Listen Lady.
I love it.
Huh?
You think youtube would have been the
death of these types of people like
that?
They wouldn't get away with it,
but it's just like somebody who's
watching this right now,
who's super it.
I think these folks probably don't watch
youtube.
They probably are pretty disconnected.
Deep emotion.
That's probably part of the whole,
she's quitting soon,
but she has given up that it's her
fault.
She's really trying harder to not get
body-slammed by this dude.
I watched this whole documentary.
This guy's like a enso.
It's again,
it's a getaway.
They come together for like three weeks
every year in Norway and this guy's all
desperate.
What are you?
Are you going or did you sign up or
you're going to go?
Those days are behind me.
There's a ghost in here.
Somebody let this guy out,
so there you have it.
I would just,
I just wish she was stronger.
She got injured and it's really her
fault.
She's pointing.
Yeah.
Tell him,
look,
you can bring in the mood down.
She,
she bombed everyone out by,
you know,
getting hurt when he rammed into her and
I get it.
It's like I'd be bummed too.
You don't want someone shattering your
weird culty belief system by being hurt
to knocked over.
You want them to like,
you know,
be like a god and and float or something
when tackled by as a fully grown,
ripped,
fairly repeated gentlemen.
Scientologists like when you go clear,
you're supposed to have like perfect,
like perfect mine,
perfect spirit.
You could like project your mind and
like your entire body's balanced,
but it's like,
if that's the case,
why was l Ron Hubbard have the grossest
teeth in the entire world to his teeth
looked like a right.
It's like right now I'm going to look
like a gap.
A gap is like an like a gap in your
teeth.
It was like a hot,
that's like the hot,
what's Madonna started doing it?
Give it some time.
Alan Hubbard teeth.
They're going to be,
that's going to be a thousand years.
It's going to look going to be a thing
and he's just so far ahead of training.
He was like,
he was like,
I want my teeth to look like this.
I fully believe that you could be a
successful cult leader in a weird way.
You kind of are feeling like,
what do we got a better memory than
mine?
We got messages from,
you guys can hit us up with some sound
effects.
What do we have for go sick?
What are we play that message music for
chattoway right in front of Joe you can
use,
we have a new thing that we can like so
awesome for the pull up.
Throw the pole up,
throw the pull up.
Listen,
Aussie is going to come and play
whatever song people want her to play
like completely awesome.
So like,
so we have to figure out a way to do
that.
So it's like if somebody bids or
somebody donates x amount,
like the same way we're doing this with
like the face stuff.
If somebody donates,
like whatever the price is,
then they can pick whatever song and
she,
she'll go in the other room,
listen to it,
figure it out and come back and play it.
Cool.
So she'll be here in like,
I dunno,
a half an hour or something.
Should we order some pies?
You guys hungry pies?
I don't want to eat.
No.
God Damn Pie.
You son of a bitch?
No,
no,
no.
A slice pizza.
Yeah.
Pizza.
I don't want to eat any meat.
No.
Why don't we,
why don't we a order some pizza?
I meant get some pizza.
Get it from Domino's and give me that
Goddamn Hawaiian pizza.
Piss everyone off at some pizza and put
up that God damn.
All right.
But hold on.
I got pizza.
We should get,
I got to read off these donors or
writing on Joey and by the way,
$100 to write on Joey too little money
because they started coming in way too
fast.
Uh,
so we have one from Anna,
one that was anonymous,
uh,
one that is from Fuck Youtube,
one from motivation app,
a one from Hunter Dutton.
And one from blue harvest.
And lastly,
one from,
uh,
a WTF.
Boom,
dps.
How are you?
Cool,
thanks guys.
Names.
You did have a big a deal with adult
swim.
Where's that?
$2.
Finally,
finally able to Justin Smiley donate it
finally came through.
Finally able to find a spot for,
is it room on the floor?
We'd go in the neck.
The pole.
Dan Is uh,
is Ian not in it?
Is He really not in it?
Dan,
would you be in it?
What?
Pool?
Sure.
Dan.
Alex,
meet Justin.
What's the pole?
The loser or a winner takes a shot of
the,
of the milk.
Water.
Well,
I'm lactose intolerant.
That's the pole.
Throw it up for Christ's sake.
No,
I'll take a sip.
I'll do a sip at most.
So if you vote for me,
get ready to be fucking disappointed.
No,
it's a shot as one measurable.
No guys,
it's 40th.
Oh wait.
I'll tell you someone get Justin Viagara
my mic and me to,
um,
the uh,
I was going to say like,
I think that the,
I think that if we're going to drink it,
if,
if we're going to put up a poll,
let this be a pull that runs in the
background all the way till the end of
the fucking thing.
Because this should,
this should also,
by the way,
if the pole,
um,
collectively doesn't raise pass a
certain amount,
we're all,
we need to get a,
we're off the hook because if it's like,
oh,
we raised $2,000.
Now if someone has to take a shot of
fucking joey milk,
like I'm not going to be like,
what are they doing that I wouldn't do
that if somebody gave me $2,000.
It's gotta be like the plus.
There's nothing even gross about the
joey milk.
We can get the pinning.
This guy's going to be sitting at an
even sad it,
he hasn't eaten anything more than a
Jalapeno for Christ's sake.
I mean,
he flew up from New York,
I believe.
Anyways.
You know what?
Let,
let me see if I can't do some stuff.
I'm on.
Oh,
hey aussies almost here.
Pull though.
Maybe the polos up.
Meet her at the stairs.
Holes a office
here.
If someone can meet her daughter.
She's almost here.
The poll is up.
Who takes a shot of Joey Salads?
Pool milk.
Oof.
No.
One more.
Let me see.
Uh,
who can I,
how do I get this?
This,
how do I get this stream more widely
distributed so we can get some more?
Uh,
yeah,
we should do a second round.
And the promotion got these
motherfuckers out.
There it is.
He loves original article.
Kanya I get it.
Get it gets a retweet.
He'd say Ilan,
Mikaila connected.
Has He launched a submarine over here?
Either of those people,
Ilan and say,
Yo,
I know you're probably free right now.
Not a busy guy.
Christ.
[inaudible]
when we get some drinks in here,
hey,
what's the,
what's the drink's going on?
Get some,
uh,
it was whispering the word drinks into
the microphone.
Opening drinks magically appear.
Kid.
Somebody out there bringing in much
rank.
I already got.
I just went and made my own.
I was like,
I got,
I need a drink.
Um,
what's the,
what's the link to the podcast guys?
Whoever just donate a dollar and post
chat with the link to the,
what is it?
It's youtube.
Did we have the president,
uh,
doing an interview or what?
Oh,
is,
is President Donald Trump going to be
president of the United States yourself?
So many questions for president trump.
If he's,
if he's,
uh,
we need a pizza when he drinks,
we need a president.
Get the Hawaiian a ultimate from
dominoes or whatever it's called.
So it's youtube.com/slash
hv podcast.
You've told me that like four days on
twitter,
but there's a directly to cast,
right?
Yeah.
Okay,
so hold on.
we got surprises throughout.
Let's watch some more stuff.
Some stuff.
Here we go.
Oh,
did you guys know that Carlton is suing
fortnight?
No,
I think that's a joke.
it's real.
It's from the guardian.com.
Carlton,
I'm telling you.
What do you guys think about this fresh
prince actor soon for using as iconic
Carlton Day?
I liked the guy,
you know,
I mean I think,
I think he's,
I think he's great.
It is his stance.
But when does he expect the to get to
here you go
watch the similarity.
It is slow.
It's a straight up ripped off.
Carl though.
Is that
fallen?
So the interesting question about this
and they're not just ripping off well
known dances.
There's little people who have invented
dances and dumb them very brilliantly at
fortnight is frame for frame stealing
their dances and now we're at,
we're at like 45 k and then fort night
is stealing their dances.
Like frame for frame and getting famous.
People are buying these dances.
Yeah.
By making money off these people
property.
Yes.
They're making of money
and they're not credited.
When's the last time you heard a legal
case like you did my dance,
but it's a,
it's a new,
it's an area.
I think it's a brave new world.
That's what,
well here's,
here's,
here's the issue with that because if,
let's just say he,
I don't think he has any legal case for
that,
but let's say he wins at that point.
What stops him from copywriting,
all the videos of people doing the
debts.
You know what I mean?
Between somebody who's monetize buckle
and end just asking for like millions.
No,
really,
you know what,
here's why this is happening and I don't
want to say about this.
This is a bit,
this is a bit of a different probably
thing than what you were expecting to
hear.
That was a horribly constructed
sentence.
But um,
I,
this is,
this is proof that actors and people in
the entertainment industry are not as
rich as you think they are.
Number one,
like you're telling me this guide and
dancing with the stars isn't as rich as
I think.
Well,
no,
I'm just saying like everyone,
like you see a guy on a couple of
sitcoms and you're like,
oh man,
I can't even imagine what kind of
mansion that person lives in.
And the reality is you get paid sag
scale.
I'm sure that,
um,
what is the actor's name that played
Carlton?
I don't want to keep calling him Carlton
and I feel like that's,
what's his name?
Shit I know is on it.
You know,
it's funny,
even in his party phones Alphonso he,
I know it from a,
that that food show on,
because even in this guardian article,
they refer to him as the Prince French
French actor.
His name is Alfonzo.
Okay.
Yeah.
So Alfonso,
it's like,
you know,
he probably made a good chunk of money
and some residuals off of fresh prince
and he's them host.
No,
he did.
I mean,
he made a decent amount for sure.
And then I've seen him host a couple of
other shows and he's great.
He's funny,
like,
you know,
but that's just like the fact that he
sees,
well,
first of all,
he probably,
he probably believes he's completely in
the right.
I mean it's,
it's pretty much dead on.
It's exactly what they referenced.
This video.
Yeah.
That literally do it.
So,
yeah,
I mean,
I get it.
It's like,
I totally get it,
but it's like,
you know,
if he was just flush with money,
he wouldn't give a shit.
He'd be like,
yeah,
I don't give a shit.
But because fortnights taking billion a
billion dollars a minute and it makes
sense.
Right.
Because if this guy who's not that well
off,
it's like,
oh,
these guys,
by the way,
I'm just jumping to the assault.
I think most people in the entertainment
industry who are actors,
they're not as rich as people think.
They are.
Definitely.
Particularly because the acting
acting's,
it's not a nine to five where you clock
in every single day after your Gig is
over.
You're hustling,
CIG,
so between jobs,
you know,
if you're not getting residuals,
you're literally not kidding.
Hey,
and by the way,
a lot of times you're paid per episode,
so we're working a whole year and going
in every day,
but you're only getting paid for each
episode and each and every season,
depending on how many episodes are in a
season,
it's like the tree are not really making
that much.
Very small amount of people in
entertainment are actually rich.
I,
you know,
it's so funny because I used to pull,
you'll see on mainstream shows,
actors that you see on huge shows on
television are probably not even
millionaires.
No,
not anymore.
Not even in the 90s.
It was like this big explosion of like
there was money in them there hills,
but now it's like,
no,
and I used to think like,
oh man,
that's where the money's at.
Uh,
and it's like,
yeah,
I mean I feel like I'm more informed
now.
I'm like,
wow.
Yeah,
there's not that much money and why he's
not splitting the pizza.
That's [inaudible] I saw you got two
bucks.
I know,
but I,
I have to tell you,
where did you get them sharpies at?
Sorry,
go ahead.
At the first,
you know,
at first I was saw that and I was like,
oh great.
You know,
that's ridiculous and silly that they
actually steal like frame for frame.
Like it's not based on him.
It is him.
I didn't know they sell,
did dance.
They sell it.
That's the thing.
I it,
I don't [inaudible] you,
you play for night dial.
They sell the dances.
They saw the dances.
But I don't know if some of them are for
sale.
Some of them you want lock.
Would this change if it was an unlock or
a free like right out of the gate does
in my opinion.
But it change.
It can change and anyone back there find
out early,
they could easily get a royalty.
So it's like,
I call this court to honor.
Tell me,
do this.
No questions.
What's the car?
No,
was it unlockable?
Oh,
it was available from the beginning of
the game.
It was such like a beautiful family
disordered imagining that then you end
to court by saying course the court
disorder,
but like to imagine anybody in a sort of
legal authority and shit about
technology.
That was the night I've heard.
Oh nine he did read it and dogpile.
Dot.
So it looks like I'm going to be drink
pile would be so your worst nightmare
come true and it looks like I'll be
taking a shot at Joey's.
No,
no,
no.
This is what,
this is what I'm going to say.
If the collective total is not more than
10 grand,
it's not happening.
Right.
So get outta here.
Everyone who already donated,
I apologize.
It's like,
you know,
you gotta you go to 7,000
so close to 40.
How about how I'm giving another
thousand so wait,
when we get to 50 is only going to eat
the yeah,
the,
the not even that.
I think we got to change the rules.
We can't choose the rules.
We listened.
We did.
We not happening.
I think we're going to go take it easy.
I wanted to say something about Alfonso
in this thing.
Um,
Dan,
I don't need another thousand 3000 for
anyone to see.
Just to wrap this up.
Donate it on the,
on the baby Joe,
which will drawing.
Do I want,
I'm going to bid on it.
Fuck.
So hold on real quick.
I want the xbox.
Dan Put it.
I'm kidding.
Just donate $1,000
because I'm freaking tired of this shit
real quick.
I can I just say thank you Dan.
I noticed something and I'm so out of
the loop on this shit,
but somehow I saw this and I didn't know
what the fuck it was referring to.
So thank you.
Now I know the origins,
the welcome,
but I saw a thing where he admits to
borrowing that dance from someone else.
Oh,
anyone caught up on this?
You want to pull this one up?
Cause like,
well I'd rather you can use everything.
Well yeah,
because this is the dance that they
stole.
Well it depends if you went well.
Yeah,
no you're right.
That's lit.
You know what I mean?
So the questions I have is,
was the dance inspired by someone else's
dad fired by something?
Know what I the only question,
literally the only question that matters
to me right now and you guys in back
should be able to help.
What's this?
What's this sole lawyer or a judge?
I think if,
if it does go to Cortland,
say he wins,
I think it opens up the door for like so
much bad things with copyrights because
it's similar.
That wasn't my identical,
right.
They could made it similar and I think
there's more to the dance.
They could have like given him a royal.
I think there's more to the dance
though.
No,
you there?
I think it goes beyond grab seconds.
At a sink with them.
Yeah,
look it up.
There's a longer one that that shows
more because if,
if you can copyright dance moves,
how far back?
Why,
why is her dancing in this game?
What's the game?
I've never played 49.
My Life Justice.
If you played fortnight from everything
I've heard about it,
it's got nothing to give.
I feel like I shouldn't because my
partner,
uh,
basketball,
go watch games was executive producer of
fortnights so I should,
that's gotta be awkward that you haven't
played a lot of it.
I just,
I haven't had a lot of time to play
games lately.
I'm making a game.
Look at this guy.
Um,
I'm writing to TV or the NBA Two K as
well.
You know,
I,
you know,
listen,
I don't know where I'm at on this.
Like you've gone all the way around and
look,
this doesn't look that good at,
it's hard to decide.
I don't know.
Well,
no,
they changed.
They definitely energized it.
That one's identical.
Identical,
but that's for fortnight again.
But the,
the,
the NBA of those guys ever mine.
Okay.
Whatever.
We've,
we've,
we,
who are we to say,
listen,
I say,
I say defer to Joe on this one.
Yeah.
Joey,
what do you think?
Let them have the money on in favor.
I don't think he's going to let the guy
have the money.
49,000
did you donate a thousand for me?
Damn,
I sure did.
Thank you.
That's why it jumps up.
We're so
close.
We're creeping and crawling.
What are people saying?
We're creeping and crawling on this.
Papa bless.
Appreciate you guys.
25 pop pup.
Pudi bluffs.
I mean it's rolling in.
We got,
he said what else you got on the docket?
I feel like that that's entertaining
stuff.
I feel like,
Hey,
yeah,
let's keep watching.
So I've keep looking at and having and
talking about entertaining.
Would you like to watch it later?
That drinks on pit,
would I?
We have a pie on the way.
We have many pies.
Hawaiian for Justin,
half Hawaiian guys.
Oh wait,
I want it all Hawaiian.
Ooh.
So apparently this poll is not doing
shit for anybody because I'm going to
have to drink his pissed and I get a
string of that.
So let's watch a lady drink on pit.
Grabbed a little,
rip it.
Well,
I need more leverage in that.
There you go.
Come on.
You got this Justin.
Where do you get this?
Every time I go,
Gosh,
and talk to you as a weird Christian
candies,
go to a Japanese store.
Okay.
Any Japanese store understands candy.
They understand cartoons.
They understand things that are
appealing and [inaudible] and strange
and novel.
You know what else?
They understand the art of the dopamine
hit when you're opening a blind box
item.
Oh yeah,
they,
they do the best blind bond doing that
forever.
Well,
before we even were like,
but we were dabbling in blind box items
50 years after.
They're like,
it's so funny.
And then,
and then there's these lol surprise
toys.
Anyone know about these lol?
They're 90% garbage and 10% toy,
but it's all,
it's,
it's all like
perfect ratio.
Yo,
do you guys want to watch your lady
drinker?
I'm pissed.
Yeah,
I mean,
why not?
When in Rome or here?
I mean,
well,
if you want to watch the lady drink you
a Piss,
y'all better fucking donate.
Oh,
we're close.
We're close.
Somebody kicked in.
Somebody can,
cannot believe James Wiener is still our
top donor.
I should have donated over more.
So I get the spot.
James Wine,
Huh?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Be Cool.
Yeah.
Whatever.
He is our top down.
Yeah.
I guess I should be more
and actually he's donated,
uh,
several other times for a bunch of the
items in like $500 blocks.
So I think he,
he's kicked in probably three or four
grand at this point.
So that guy's a hero.
Yeah.
All right.
Let's watch a lady drink her own test.
And by the time this is done,
I fricking better see that be a 50 k and
then hopefully that's entertaining
enough that we go up to 75 get Mr
Beeston.
Where's the,
where's miss?
Should be eating it.
Yeah.
Meet them.
But it's so delicious that you can't
stop eating it.
Yeah.
Got The resistance of gum,
but it doesn't chew like so crazy.
Right.
How are you loving that Isla?
I love it.
It's kind of like the plastic.
That was my first reaction and then,
and then started growing and then I was
like,
you know what?
I don't give a guy.
I love it.
I don't care.
I love the texture.
Getting your system.
I was supposed to tap your buddies.
It's like you found a tiny,
you started eating like a plastic candy.
You,
Oh,
you're still training for the fight
because I didn't know what was
happening.
One more drawing here for the granite
falls.
Vantage is a cute little mabel.
She's sitting there.
He's going black.
It could be yours,
wouldn't her and putting her in the
pile.
Everything.
She's seen,
the horrors that she's heard.
Original art.
Are you freaking kidding me?
Oh wait,
let me finish one last part of that.
Yeah.
Call.
I'm going to call it that mountain and
then it's done under the bathroom.
Hopefully when I get back.
Yeah,
we're a 500 away,
so someone in the comments and Ian going
to date wouldn't mean whoa.
Sticking to that for a sec,
buddy in on the mic.
Ian,
are you still
dating that girl?
Are you single?
I'm dating right now.
You offer a day.
Now he's uh,
he's taken about charity then.
Are you seeing somebody,
uh,
nobody.
Seriously?
Would you be willing to go?
What do you mean nobody?
Seriously.
That's what he means.
Really well listening right now.
I can't touch him because I've got
pepper hands.
Yeah.
So Dan,
can we raffle you off for a day?
You're doing this for,
I don't know about that.
We're trying to raise money for the,
the cow,
the California wildfires.
Oh,
somebody donated $500 for that.
Thank you.
Good job.
Right?
Finally hit me with the music.
Come on.
Yay.
Kelly's not even here for three,
but this is going to be,
can we make him eat?
All right.
Hey,
joey goes into the pool.
Adam,
will you add an option
for someone if they buy?
Um,
I dunno.
What,
what,
what should it be like 200 bucks.
If,
if,
if basically for 200 bucks they can pick
any song and Aussie has to learn it and
come in and pull it in,
play it,
and just add it to the,
to the thing.
Yeah.
Got me Addicted to just fuck any song.
Just more in it and play it.
I'll,
I'll see if I can figure out a way to do
that.
However you have it set up for us.
Writing Shit on.
First of all,
everybody,
we're at 50,000
then a round of applause.
Thank you.
Oh dollars is a lot of money going
straight to direct relief.
That's straight to jody buddies tuning
in right now.
What's the,
uh,
what's the next,
what's the next?
Don't get thanked.
The route should make him skip one,
two,
the spicier.
I don't know.
Do you think,
I mean,
I guess he's not here.
He might not know
which one would give up,
but once a fresh ones dry all of the
other two.
So this is the Carolina reaper.
This is the shit that I had a nibble of
and fucking lost my mind.
So what's a reaper?
So,
oh,
they're both Carolina reapers.
So what's up next for him then?
So up next would be the ghost chili.
No,
no,
no.
He's,
he's going to eat a whole hobby nero.
Yeah,
that's 75 is when we get into that.
The Ghost Chili [inaudible] 75 I just
will fuck him up.
[inaudible] 75 wishes.
Cute.
They habit an hour.
We can't,
should we?
I feel like,
I feel like I say we'd go to the hard
shit.
I'm ready to go for as long as it may
too.
And the,
and I'll tell you what,
I've donated a $3,000
I'm willing to put down more down a big
get.
We've already been live three hours.
We've been live three hours.
Well last year we did five,
right?
So I think,
yeah,
that's true.
That by the way,
by the way,
I'm sick and pregnant.
Let me remind everybody,
even though we raised 240 last year,
I believe we only raised 100,000
during the lights.
That's absolutely right.
A quick hit.
100 okay.
Because I remember we kind of had the
same fatigue last year and I remember
like I was drunk and sober and I was
like taking a nap.
Like you hang over your outside for five
hours and there was,
there was,
and we only raised 100,000
sorry,
some alcohol fucking rally for the Fire
Vic.
We can just get to 75 let's do it for
first.
A fire.
Big fucking rules for those guys.
So guys,
we're almost a 51.
Hold it up for 1000 Justin,
we'll do the Carlton and then he'll get
sued for 4 million.
I can't answer it.
I'm sorry.
Answer it and tell them,
hey,
share the link.
Dan.
How many people,
how many people are watching this shit
show?
22 k last time they're hitting.
They're consistent.
They're watching.
It's a beautiful design.
I just want to say there is a $500
donation from somebody.
I think you guys know a Dana terrorist.
A terrorist.
Legging.
None.
Did she suggest something to be drawn
on?
Ethan's face?
Let's see.
What did she actually donate for?
Uh,
she's donating for,
Ooh,
she wants to what?
The Teddy fresh criss cross sweater
protocol.
Hope she went once and she did send a
message that just wanted to say love you
guys.
All caps with a whole bunch of hearts,
so we love you too,
Dana.
Thank you for your donation.
By the way.
I saw someone donated 500.
Was that to write on me or just a
sweetheart?
Is that just for
a couple of lower ethan?
I just pulled up the,
uh,
the spreadsheet with the most recent
donation.
So yeah,
we'll,
we'll come in and write on you
fresh stuff.
It's here in the box.
Oh,
by the way,
we're up to 51.
You guys keep it fucking go and strong.
Joey's back
time.
It's time.
It's happening.
Oh,
his face.
It looks like a bottle of Dr Bronner's
soap.
Joey,
what you're going,
you're going in the pool?
Yeah,
dollars all the way out here.
Okay.
All right.
I'm trying to find it new then.
Which one do you think going to be like
another couple hours?
No,
come on,
Joey.
People gave $50,000.
You see this?
All right.
Make it happen.
It happen.
51 I like how it this kind of event like
it.
It shows like our deepest kindness and
are like deepest cruelty.
The same time it's been only exist in
equal and opposite proportion bid.
How do you bid to draw some shit on
somebody and Sunday rewarding the list.
It's just mixed into this muddle
like 50,000
like yes.
I love a stream where it's people
watching us try to figure out how to
donate like driving a dollar though.
I can do I have some feeds on that
question.
Hey,
welcome to the $50,000
milestone.
I'm your host Ethan Klein.
Today we have a scuba Santa's about to
enter the pool of milk.
How are you feeling right now joey?
They won't be able to hear you.
My Cup.
My cord is actually caught.
Can Zach you help me out there?
Thank you so much.
God bless.
This is like a really bad like a news
broadcast on cable network right now.
Joey,
we have a a snorkel and goggles for you
to put on as well.
I do think this is going to be the first
spice.
He won 50 k we need another 25,000
to get to the,
uh,
the chair not wearing shoes.
Excellent.
Joey,
how are you feeling?
Disgusting.
Can you walk on over to me so he could
talk in the mic?
You fucking sloshing through that milk
is such a great site.
Ready to,
uh,
to accept your challenge.
You want me to insert it for you?
Okay.
Wow.
Dan is way too excited about you.
Please do this.
This is a fairly spicy,
I don't know.
It's a hobby narrow.
So it's about as spicy as you could find
in route.
So let's say it's from route.
So how bad can it be?
All right.
Well,
so you want me to take just an hour,
move the stem and you pop it all in
there?
Yeah,
there you go.
Can you discarded that so it doesn't get
it?
Okay.
Bon appetit.
So this is for charity.
Joey,
this is a for a good cause.
You're a sweet man.
$50,000
is a lot of money.
How are you,
how do you feel about raising that much
money as it taste tastes pretty good.
Oh,
got a really well,
hold on.
Hang on.
I thought that one would be spicy.
This is disappointing.
You can't get it out.
Would you eat another one?
Joey kept grabbing another one.
He's the fact that even considered it.
Grab it.
Because guys,
we,
we uh,
how much money have we raised you inside
here?
It's a small one.
All right.
He say he's so high milk.
Can you just grab him a jug of milk from
the,
from the carton.
My stomach hurts.
Verse Cement.
Now that's a bad sign shredder be if you
have to Puke,
puke in the pool.
No,
that,
that if it gets $10,000
we will.
But if you puke in that will make it a
lot more interesting,
that's for sure.
All right,
good.
Then that poll that someone has to take
a shot that,
that that's got to get like way higher
than no.
If he pukes 10 I mean at least 10,000
the way up all the way up.
Oh.
Oh well.
Okay.
Well,
careful.
Keep it in the pool.
Tready shredding.
Shredding.
Oh my stomach.
My mouth like 50% better.
But My,
if you'd,
if you do Puke,
please keep it in the cool because I
don't want to shredder her to get spicy
vomit.
I don't think I'm going to Puke,
but it's like there,
it's like,
it's pretty close.
Well I won't blame you.
Oh Zach,
stop laughing at Joey.
Zach.
I told him Joey and as the spicy salad,
if you have to Puke,
just if you need to sit down.
You all right.
Are you in pain?
He's your stomach hurting.
You.
Okay.
Go ahead and Puke it out.
It will make it all,
I mean like the pre,
pre.
Is your mouth salivating?
Oh No,
no.
Shit.
I mean,
I think so.
Uh,
should I say that joke again?
Okay.
We here too.
All right,
well I have,
if there's any updates we can switch on
over.
You want to chair?
You can,
we can get you a chair.
You can just keep your feet soak in.
Well go ahead and do it in the pool.
Jelly shitting in the pool.
Actually,
if you want to shit in the poor,
just don't show it.
But I'm down for a minute.
Shit in Nepal.
Zach,
what do you think should Joe Shit and
the poor joey if you need to shit.
Justin and Alex,
if he needs get him some toilet paper.
Dan,
this is in your show.
You can shit in the poor justin.
A fee shuts you down if he shoots in the
pool.
No,
but forget about drinking it like he's
going to shit in the pool.
Wouldn't youtube shut us?
Wouldn't,
wouldn't youtube like shut this thing
down immediately?
I would say Tom.
I would say don't,
don't you don't.
Why don't you instead of in the poll,
give them a little bucket.
Make sure that there's no skin showing.
I'm sure there's some line between,
I wasn't,
I didn't want to show it coming out,
but I just wanted him to shit and the
pool.
We won't.
We definitely wouldn't show it.
Joey,
show the poop phoning around.
I think so.
Why not?
I think we can.
Sure.
Yeah.
We could show the poop floating around.
No,
no.
Hold on.
Let's take a poor Dan,
Justin and Alex.
Come here,
please say,
and everybody.
No,
but it's so good for content.
He what?
We know.
Okay.
Some sanity.
Alright.
Well Joey.
Okay.
All right.
No,
no,
that's,
that's a horrible,
okay.
Alright.
Well Joey depth.
Pooping is an as a no go.
If you have to Puke,
go ahead and do it.
How are you feeling right now?
My mouth is perfectly fine.
It's the fucking stomach.
You were pepto Bismol,
pepto Bismol I think so.
Broken.
Look at shredder.
Shredder.
He wants to help.
Oh,
he shut her your way to
kill it.
Okay.
All right.
Well Joey,
it keeps you get a shot of his feet.
Where'd Ya are his underwear?
His,
his,
uh,
milk silk.
Hold on.
This is milk soaped underwear up for
donating.
Oh,
well.
well we weren't kidding about that.
Where are we?
Well,
he's,
you probably farted in her underwear at
least.
And that's valuable.
Yeah.
Alright.
[inaudible] careful.
All right,
let's go back.
Enjoy yourselves.
Joey,
you,
there's towels.
If you feeling better,
you can go ahead and,
okay,
good.
Well that was,
I'm the house.
If that is an incentive to get to that
next milestone,
I don't know what it is.
This is making me feel that way.
Then go ahead and try that again.
Don't touch the money.
What,
what is wrong on my hands?
I didn't touch anything.
Number one rule.
Don't give up the mind.
Okay,
so the ghost,
I'll,
I'll 99.9%.
I will vomit.
The reaper might actually kill me.
Like I'm actually concerned that like
I'm just going to be eating it and I'm
just going to like fade out.
Well there you have it.
Get those donations rolling in.
We got to hit these deadlines.
Alrighty.
Well I'm having fun.
We have more,
uh,
face riding.
We've got more videos.
We've got more content on the way.
Joey is looking like a sad,
tattooed Santa Claus.
He should have stayed in New York is
what he said.
So there's a towel right behind you.
You feel free to join us.
Um,
how's everybody doing back here?
Everything's good.
Uh,
we should get Aussie set up in the,
okay,
cool.
Cool.
All right.
Your kidneys hurt.
He says,
all right,
let's continue where we were.
Congratulations everyone on the second
milestone.
That was thrilling and very exciting.
So I'll put this back and see you guys
back in the room.
The shitting in the,
uh,
there's a line,
there's a line.
It wasn't unclear.
Note to me exactly why not having
shitting in the,
have some bread,
not show it live.
Do people want this?
Definitely.
Um,
Nixon was innocent.
I love it.
Uh,
his feet and the milk was just
hilarious.
I was going to donate money and so I'm
going to save that for therapy just to,
just to process what I've seen today.
Now,
um,
did you say we're going to have a call
from the president of the United States
herself?
Uh,
yes.
That was cute.
Up on the line.
I feel like I want to,
I feel like I want Justin to pick the
president's brain.
I Dunno.
I don't know about you.
I definitely want that.
And we have that lined up.
There's something about that shot out
there in the back office that's
hilarious.
Every time with the handheld mind.
Um,
it's exciting.
It's thrilling,
isn't it?
Dynamic one would even say,
I want to show really quick all the
teddy fresh stuff that you could get the
sharp hoe bucket hat we were gonna make
it with the sharp.
I look,
but we were like,
I don't know how many people will buy
it.
Yeah.
Too Much Sherpa.
And we've got this bucket hot.
What's adorable,
cute little teddy bears.
The delightful,
I'm still taste that reaper fanny's to
match your clone blocks.
We never made those.
Nevermind does.
Those are cool.
I think people would like those new
callers though.
We never made that hat.
This is all super rare.
One of a kind.
Really.
This is also us trying to renew the
logo.
Make it a little cleaner than the old
one.
We haven't decided if we like it better
or not,
but you can see our process.
I can't believe how many prizes you guys
lined up and sanity,
like all the rick and morty stuff.
All right.
Pull your mic over,
Alex.
Oh,
sorry.
Oh yeah.
Um,
the orange sweater,
that thing is pretty,
that is one of a kind size large.
Oh,
right.
This is also such large,
you know,
looking at the blue wheel,
I think that turned out pretty good.
I don't know why.
I feel like that's a cool sweater
actually.
Yeah,
it's very calming.
It like after seeing like Joey Joey's
feet and milk,
that's the only thing that could calm me
down is looking at that like knitted
bear sweater.
Yeah.
So peaceful.
This one was bid on by Dana 500.
This is also one of a kind.
It's also like show the inside Dana
could like live inside that thing.
Oh,
it is a size large.
Whoops.
But you cannot see girls like to wear it
oversize.
It's okay.
So here you can see the inspiration for
the rainbow sweater.
Yeah,
the inside we were like,
Whoa,
that's fricking awesome.
Whoever tried it on,
we took it off and we were like,
wait,
this is really amazing.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Happy accident.
That's such a cool color scheme.
Yeah.
So we ended up selling the rainbow
version,
which was a hand sold out really fast.
Oh,
we've got amps.
We got donations,
donations are going up.
We're at almost 53,000
great,
nice.
So this is,
this is just as,
um,
we'll set this up somewhere,
but yeah,
I think that couch right here.
Karaoke mic.
Um,
yeah,
but so a lot of our stuff isn't showing
up on mobile.
I think that's the majority of people
are on their phones and they're not
seeing like the ability to,
to buy,
to be able to write on your face or on,
are you kidding me?
There's more tilt five.
Oh,
and I get on it.
It's fucking us again,
Dan.
Oh No.
Dan Are you,
are you there?
Yeah,
I wouldn't say fucking that's right on
mobile.
And you can't donate for reaching out to
him right now.
I would out,
you know,
take it easy.
I don't,
where do you see,
I'm like playing both sides.
Where do you see it?
On the laptop.
Even on a laptop.
I'm not sure I supposed to here,
let me check.
I haven't looked on a laptop.
Well here if you,
I'll do it on the screen here.
Go to rewards and go all the way to the
bottom.
Oh,
they're not here.
It doesn't show Dan.
Yeah.
Why is that?
There?
Turns off cause we have backlog.
No,
I mean I didn't turn them off.
Hmm.
What are we missing?
What else do I seen?
Well,
let me look into it right now.
I guess people can donate if they donate
that amount.
We'll see if you donate 500 and tell us
what you want to write that.
Don't do it.
Don't do that.
Let me,
that's very hard to keep track of.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'll have a hard time finding it on
mobile.
It's not there.
Like I'm seeing all the,
I'm seeing all the drawings and stuff
and I'm not seeing any of the messages
went up on mobile either.
Please.
No more gross gross humor.
This person does not want joey to shit
in the pool.
I love,
I love Katie spending that dollar.
Like no more gross humor will have to
turn off the stream of jellies shits in
the pool.
Um,
um,
can someone bring me some water and
also,
uh,
do we have more writing to do?
Yeah.
Yeah,
I think,
I think we're back with you some water
and yeah.
One thing and it's on,
hold on one sec.
I'm trying to fix the missing stuff
first.
Okay.
You guys entertain.
Okay?
You Want me Ladies and gentlemen,
you for watching right now.
Let's see how many people are watching
us?
20,000.
Hello?
20,000
people.
It's the,
uh,
it's the Alex and healers show right
now.
As you could see,
uh,
we,
we are both sitting in chairs and it is
thrilling.
It's thrilling to watch.
We want to draw things for you.
We don't know what to draw though.
Why don't you go,
oh no.
Oh my God.
Hey,
Justin brought in a pretty amazing,
hello.
Hello?
That's weird requests for what we want
Justin to sing.
Yeah.
Hey,
no,
I'm not doing that.
I don't know.
You're kind of singing right now.
You sound pretty great.
That was like a kind of little Bob Dylan
Guy you were doing there.
I like the sound of that Fella.
That's not for me.
That's a new jam.
We're watching the donation.
So if you guys want to suggest stuff for
us to draw or to make sure that this is
for Justin to sing.
I remember it wasn't working earlier.
Something for us to watch.
You guys want to be entertained?
We're rating the Oh,
okay.
Waiting back.
Are we back in the groove?
A nice camera and the microphone.
Uh,
just what are you doing?
Who me?
Yeah.
I'm just making sure that this
microphone works.
Okay.
Why your phone?
G May I please buy one?
Ethan?
Dump Extra Brown.
Extra moist.
15 bucks.
Yeah,
I'll mail you some shit.
I don't know.
I feel like yours is worth more than 15
come on.
Oh.
This is our little chat stream.
Anyone need water and your water and
water?
Something something.
Kingdom hearts.
I'll trade you this water for that
water.
I do not understand.
Okay.
For some reason the Internet really
wants me to play kingdom hearts and I,
hold on.
Why?
Oh,
Don,
he was going to watch a lady drinker on
pit.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
What are we doing?
Nice.
Jesus h get back on track.
Yeah.
Come on,
let's get back on track.
Ref 53,000
y'all better kick open those wallets.
Open them balls.
Open opening walls,
donation.
I feel like making a sizable donation.
You haven't already.
I think I'm going to wish we had more
interesting poles,
but we really don't.
It's a,
it's a tricky thing.
Figuring out something that's like
perfect.
Yeah.
You need to figure out exactly how
torture the people in this room and
equal terms equally torturing to all,
all of us had a good idea of like a
competition,
like some sort of competition and,
and how do we monetize that?
Again,
I can't even remember.
Thank you.
I mean if we were just playing any kind
of game,
we could just put down money.
We would pass.
We would bet her own hard earned money
on it.
What can we do that involves US spending
money?
Well let's wash your lady drinker on
pissed.
All right.
Yeah.
I think when in doubt,
here we go.
Why?
I don't know Ethan,
you think this is too gross?
Is that one girl was going to have to
turn off this stream?
Well,
I mean,
how realistic is this drop off of John?
Alex,
do you want me to draw Papa John?
Alright.
Strange.
Addictive thinking that was fun.
Which she believes will maintain her
house cast.
Carter,
my strange your that you love this show.
Honda's my strange addiction.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I feel like you guys are late to the
party though.
This is stuff I was watching you know,
years ago.
What have you moved on to,
man,
I'm so far.
You're going to be like,
what?
What are you talking about?
It's futuristic,
man.
No,
but I have been watching a show that's
a,
it's a,
it's a BBC show that sorta like Bachelor
in paradise.
I can't remember the name but you know,
whatever.
Oh somebody donate a dollar and remind
me what it's called.
But it's like,
it's on Hulu.
I think it's on Hulu or someone donate a
dollar and remind me what channel it's
on,
but it's a higher oh idea.
Hey stop.
No,
no.
Justin refuses to see there's no,
no,
let's by here.
Cause Aussie Aussie can play and then
you're dumb asking,
saying,
wow,
really.
Also Justin should draw on know what
crashed for me.
Oh,
I see Justin
[inaudible].
I don't see it.
You don't see it?
No,
I don't see any.
I am
a Ba,
Ba bop,
bop,
bop mother f pain.
Crapless wash this lady,
drink therapists.
Watch this play at a drank her pad.
This is,
we got to get to 75 guys.
We got to get Jodie you one of the
really hot peppers to,
oh,
we want to unite and do so many good
things all at once.
I'm going to donate at least another
2000.
I mean the guy flew all the way here
from New York,
so that's already Alex,
tra,
rick and Stan.
So those,
uh,
those uh,
writing on incentives or backup.
Okay,
I need 100 bucks and they want you to
draw a rick and Stan celebrating the
holidays together.
So add that to your list.
Make that happen.
All right,
somebody?
Yes.
Hi.
You're buying and somebody wants me to
sing country roads.
I don't know what that is,
but I could try.
Let's watch a lady drinker on Piss.
You all keep donating in the background.
You guys drink,
drink,
drink your own pets.
Drink your own pit.
Sorry.
Here we go.
Nice.
Oh,
on the fucking lauren.
If you guys want to draw on the,
on everyone's faces,
it's a up again,
I think I do some as well.
Um,
let's go ahead.
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm watching Carrie and 50 years old.
I'm from Colorado.
I'm watching drinking my urine break.
Your color,
your vitamin D vitamins,
that's for sure.
It's easier to drink than water.
They drink the water.
Carry all the liquid is all easy
streets.
Well,
uh,
well,
you know,
I would disagree with that.
You consider,
uh,
you know,
first flyer viscosity.
All right.
You got this.
Gostudy are fine.
I mean,
saltwater is not,
you know,
Alex frankly,
speaker
my building the largest one or yarn
morning.
Now she consumes up to five glasses
every day.
You know,
I feel like I'm wasting
great urinary.
No,
this is great.
no,
keep going.
I'm sorry.
I'm buckled this big common buckle.
Then let's go ahead and buckle down.
I'm here to get eight glasses a day.
I heard that eight eight,
eight oh nine.
She is addicted to it,
but it looks like she's suffering when
she drank.
Well,
let's listen to her.
Listen guys,
let's,
let's see.
Let's go over this.
Let's listen for a minute and see where
we are.
Where we're buddy.
Focus right on it,
dude.
Drinking your own year.
Let's see where we're at with her.
All right,
everybody ready?
Okay.
It's comforting.
It don't make fun of this moment.
I'm trying to make sense of it all.
The first time I drank my year and I
didn't throw out and it wasn't horrible.
So I thought you trusted can do this.
So
you know what the first time I drank my
urine,
not bad.
I didn't throw up.
I can do this.
Yeah.
So
I have a couple of questions.
Why,
why did you,
what,
what I,
if she was here,
I'd go,
well,
what,
like very respectfully,
why did you want to drink your own
urine?
Good.
Um,
I think she was doing it as some health
kick.
She's like,
Oh,
I saw it somewhere.
I was at the,
I was at the corner of a lake or like at
the edge of a lake and a charity stream.
Dude,
she was just like us.
This is what it escalates to get joey to
drink his own piss her front.
Oh,
free sleep.
Her making that kind of money.
I mean if it's this easy for her,
well Joey's piston his mouth famously,
but if he goes to the bathroom contract
with a jar,
piss would we kicked down to watch them
drink?
Thank you too,
but just would shut the street down.
He hasn't done one show deck is just,
he comes down with the yellow.
I mean we're watching her drink piss.
What's the difference?
I mean,
listen,
I leave it up to the audience and uh,
you know,
pay with your wallets or what is it a
vote with your wallets?
I mean,
do,
who wants to Wash Joey?
Let's do a poll.
Well wait,
hold on.
Can I get back to this?
Like what?
What on,
hold on.
I want to,
do you want joey to drink his own piss?
Yes or yes or no?
Thanks.
Joe Even agreed to this.
He just said,
I'm not doing it.
That going to poll,
you know,
drink his pool water.
But the problem is I'm not doing it
unless the entirety of this bowl hits
like fucking 50 grand or 40 grand,
which is,
you know jody not going to happen.
Will you ask him?
I did.
He said No.
He said,
hell no.
He said he hasn't done that in years.
He's over it.
He hasn't done that fast.
No,
no.
Better time than now.
Dog grown up to know what can we get a
bike joey?
Yeah.
Once you drink tasting your own piss
here.
No.
I'll let her know.
How much for you to drink your own
person today.
That's not happening.
I'm not seeing stuff still.
It's like fucking pissing me off.
Dan,
are you making an equivalence between me
drinking my own piss and Joey Salads?
I mean the guy's,
he's a known mouth.
Buser he said no,
so I was seeing if you'd be down.
Are you down to drink your on pissed?
Absolutely not.
Okay.
Well obviously you don't care about burn
victims.
We got pizza here.
Standby.
Yeah,
it tasted it did four years ago.
Sometimes the southgate,
champaign,
sometimes it tastes like champagne.
Sometimes it tastes like lemon.
I liked this raw shit in my mouth.
I want to know why.
I want to like why she started like what
got her start like what was the day
where she was like,
I'm going to do this here.
Listen to this quote of her saying,
you know,
I tried,
it wasn't so bad.
I can do this.
It's a health kick.
It is.
Yeah.
There's a whole counter or there's a
whole help saying that,
but I'm telling you,
there's a bunch of pissed drinkers out
there.
She's not the only one.
Rain.
Florence is another one.
Yeah.
And will you enjoy this?
Maybe a little lemony,
a little lemonade.
You can taste different things going
through your bodies.
There are certain things.
I don't like to eat it anymore because
they know it tastes good.
Oh,
you mean like this?
Love,
love,
love asparagus.
I won't need it.
And he gets,
nope,
it makes the hearing tasting.
I'll take a Hawaiian Hawaiian.
Yeah,
a pizza already a flavor Hawaiian.
Oh,
we have cheese,
we have mushroom,
the works.
I'll just take a slice a,
what do you guys want?
Yeah,
I mean we can come out and grab a slice
till two.
Yeah.
Uh,
yeah.
We'll just come up.
We'll just,
yeah,
whatever.
Flex the cheese.
Yeah.
Well we really hit a low point on the
street.
Everyone's just sitting here.
I focused on this drawing.
She's got a daughter.
You guys,
her daughter's going to comment on the
piss.
Drinking show the drawing.
All right.
I'm watching this piss video y'all can
do it.
Body has decided to filter through and
get,
get rid of.
So it doesn't seem healthy to me that to
put that back into your body.
Yeah.
Carrie doesn't drink urine just because
she loves the taste.
Her addiction began two years after
being diagnosed with cancer.
Really diagnosed with one of the,
of course,
the number one a month.
Got It.
That's of course the,
uh,
the doctor recommended.
That's just a sign of how fucking loss
we are as a species when it comes to
something as horrible as cancer.
It's like,
yeah.
I'll just,
I have,
I guess I'll fucking drink my piss then.
I mean,
it's like,
okay,
what else am I going to do?
Maybe that'll work.
I mean,
that's just fucking depressed.
Really sad spin on this story.
Well,
I believe Justin,
she's cured and she's still drinking her
peers.
All right,
so don't be too sad.
Oh,
she loves it.
Stage three and they took out 16 of my
lymph nodes found cancer in three of
them and do this and they told me with
the chemo I'd have a year to now.
Carrie decided against chemo instead
turning to urine therapy.
Is it working ancient and long
discounted practice to maintain health
ancient and long discounted.
Okay.
Is it,
does it work for four years later?
She still uses it to five years later.
He's crushing it.
She's alive.
She has never consulted a physician
about her unorthodox treat.
Wouldn't that be funny if the cure of
cancer was just actually this whole time
drinking your own piss,
it sounds like that's what they're
saying.
Yeah.
They couldn't put it on tv,
but it wasn't true.
Here we go.
This is,
this is your pocket,
John Right here.
He's admitted.
He's devouring this.
We're drippy pizza.
Alex tried to capture his stolen.
I tried to capture like,
he's like a wrestler.
What was happening inside his heart but
devouring his own pizza.
There it is.
This like a play on like a saturn
devouring his son plastic for all your
art or art fans out there is amazing.
Wow.
Is this this right here,
dude.
That's amazing.
Bring in mind close.
Sorry.
Yeah,
sorry.
yeah,
that.
Wow.
That is incredible.
That is so for someone in the Papa
John's family is going to be bidding on
that [inaudible] himself.
Man.
John's going to want that above his
mantle.
It's going to remind him of the power he
gets from eating his own pizza.
It's can remind him of how high he's
climbed,
how far he's fallen.
Oh yeah.
One of these.
So much art to sketches.
We got a karaoke machine there,
right?
Yeah.
We gotta be doing Karaoke.
We gotta be doing care.
Rio.
Can you want to sing it?
You want to sing with me?
My favorite song.
So what's the deal?
How do we get people to pay $500 you
named the person on the list like people
are,
people are,
people are able to donate and she'll
learn whatever song,
um,
$500 you named the song,
you name the person.
I think that's $500.
You understand?
You hear that?
What if,
what if the person doesn't know the
song?
They just have to wing it.
Well,
we can probably pull up the lyric.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's right.
We'll just find a karaoke video.
Yeah,
exactly.
All right.
We're doing this.
I'm in,
I'm in on this and I'll sing any songs
for 500 bucks for charity.
Absolutely.
Dan.
Hey,
500 bucks.
Sing any song.
And they get to choose.
They choose the person in the song
person.
And we doing this instead of for Ozzie
to come in and in a company.
Well,
this is an addition.
This is an addition.
Oh,
this is an addition.
Okay.
Yeah.
Oh,
copywriter.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's why I was asking you what are you
gonna get the music exactly.
Oh,
like,
like do,
do the music,
you know?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Ruined the of the rules work.
Fuck yeah,
good point.
Good point.
You guys know like you're,
you're,
you're this tilt defy is a absolute
frustrating fuck show.
Like,
like,
I mean,
I've never seen anything as long bought
a phone on broken,
you just can't find the draw.
I just,
I like,
I give up.
I can't,
okay.
So now,
all right.
I give up,
I give up what's happening.
I don't even fucking know.
It's like,
I'm so,
it's so it's impossible.
I try.
Okay.
You want to know,
why don't you do,
okay.
So I tried to,
I was trying to,
to,
to pay to have,
um,
to fucking draw something on your face
and,
and every time I fill it out it like
resets
and then it's like I have to fill it out
again and then I go to paypal and it's
like,
oh no.
And,
and,
and I just give up.
I give up.
Are you guys having trouble with tilt to
five?
Donate?
I don't,
it's fucking room.
And the,
the,
the entire p lady thing.
I was trying to fucking do something and
I had to start over nine times and I was
ready to jump out the window.
So that could be why we're only at
$55,000
because we're,
it's,
it's a broken,
it's a bright fucking mess.
Can we pick another Goddamn company?
Tilt the Phi you want to call it?
Let's get tilt.
Defy on the phone.
I want to get the CEO of tilt to fight
and I want to,
I want them to atone.
I want him to fix our problems.
You know,
take it easy.
That's a,
that's a prank call right there.
Yes.
Britain called the act.
The thing we're using to generate all
this money here.
Their website crashed on us.
Oh yeah.
Guess that they had made a lot of gains
because the thing about tilts,
fight,
they had a lot of question.
Let me ask Dan.
Dan,
if you're listening,
you look,
can you bring some zoo?
How many,
how many face drawing things have sold,
how many Aussie music things
I haven't seen for Aussie yet because we
just threw that up a few minutes ago.
I mean we got a lot of those slots in
any nuance.
And if for Jenny for uh,
even,
uh,
let me,
let me check if there's some new ones
right now.
Cause man,
I see a face that's just begging for
drawing.
You just get forehead wants to mink on
it right now,
man.
You guys need to watch Elan's
announcement.
Who steals a cheese grater?
Wait,
what?
Give it another shot.
Thank you Justin.
This isn't,
well,
so now we've got
okay,
uh,
sold out.
Oh I can't.
Oh and then,
and then you're sold out and it says
Aussie's thing says sold out then.
Okay.
And your thing,
your thing is like,
just drive me fucking crazy.
Let me see.
I want to see what you want to see what
happens.
I'll be,
so justin is a type,
I'll go watch it.
It'd be like,
this is where I,
so justin is typing his request.
It says,
don't,
don't say it.
Don't read it.
Okay,
sure.
It's a surprise,
but I need to narrate the frustration
they see.
That's good.
I want that.
I need that on me now.
It's great out,
right?
I want to hit that button.
So I think you have to write something
here.
Maybe.
Okay.
Just say hi and then write out what else
should we email.
Oh,
okay,
fine.
Was that,
what was the butter?
Okay,
I was doing that before.
Let me delete this because I don't want,
that's confusing.
You won.
So now donate.
Now watch what happens.
Watch what it does.
We have to sit.
So he's so justin the donate with course
of course.
No wedding.
Your email.
Yes,
I was.
Every time.
Okay,
well we're in business,
right?
Frustrating.
We're in business.
Whoo.
Thank
you.
What?
I wanted to fucking,
I want this for wine.
I Love Hawaii.
What's wrong with a client?
Go ahead.
Just gets a bad rap dude.
Yeah.
What?
Um,
all right.
So wait,
Dan.
So Dan,
can you check and see?
Okay.
Ah,
I just think tilts.
Fires.
What?
What are you looking to do?
Did you just donate?
Well.
Well,
there's other people who donated
apparently,
at least from my,
from my phone,
unless that's a Delta Phi is broken
situation.
Okay.
Tony's in the mic.
I said,
know what man?
We got it.
We got beloved.
I mean we're in personalities.
We're and so deep on fine eating pizza
and there's been a lot of trying to
figure out what this is on the flight.
We're kind of building the plane while
we're flying it a little bit here.
He could sing and I,
while we can't talk.
Well,
how about,
okay,
Cigna,
old man by Neil Young.
Bam.
Why don't we bring us,
he and Brian to come in and she here?
Yeah,
she's here,
but I got her set up.
Let's bring her in and does,
does this Mike g work?
Is this on?
No,
that one doesn't work.
We'll have to pull it.
I'll,
I'll come in and get her set up.
Okay.
Hey,
little blooper.
Okay.
The book,
donate him.
Alex called Disney.
Yeah.
I just,
I dial one 800 Disney.
I'm just like,
Hey,
thank you for the television show up by
the very polite and respectful.
You tell me more about working for
Disney because I always hear awful
thing.
No,
I mean,
here's the thing,
like trying to talk about Disney is like
trying to talk about an entire country.
Like it's such a huge company that like
if somebody be like,
Oh man,
you know,
I was,
it'd be like trying to talk about
Google.
It's like,
well what?
Yeah,
which department?
But there's the park,
there's TV,
there's movies,
there's interactive.
Like I mean for me,
like I was just working for the kids
channel and like the main problems
weren't Disney's fault.
They were my fault for trying to work at
a kid's channel.
Cause like that's not how my brain
naturally works.
And it was like one of these things
where they're like,
oh,
we're going to pick up your show and I'm
like Rad.
And then I was like,
oh no,
they won't let me use any of the funny
parts.
Do you have a good example?
Is aware of stuff you would fight?
Like hell yeah,
no,
I mean we,
um,
for,
for my wrap party,
for gravity falls,
I printed out a giant list of all the
most bullshit snp notes that we ever got
and I just,
we did a dramatic reading of them.
We had like somebody playing the
Moonlight Sonata in the background
because it was so depressing and I was
like,
I read my butt back and forth and
somebody else read that cause like I,
I started out with this idea at the
beginning of the channel.
Like,
okay,
it's a,
it's a conversation.
We're going to do our best,
you know,
if they have a disagreement,
we'll try to hash it out and I'm going
to be respectful and by the end I would
just be like,
I'm not changing.
Like I've got,
like if you'd just like flip through all
of the emails,
you'd see a man slowly losing his mind
because they would just ask for the
dumbest,
craziest bullshit.
Like,
um,
oh my God,
where do I even begin?
Like every puddle,
every shape,
every Bush,
every,
every cloud,
every puddle,
they'd be like,
let's looks like a dick.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
it's like if you're an s you're looking
for day,
their job,
it's like you're going to cost you.
It's like you have to write a ticket.
You know what I mean?
Like they've got a quota,
they got to find these problems.
Even if they don't exist,
that's what,
that's their job is like,
see dicks were dicks don't exist.
Right.
So like constantly having to just like
feel these questions,
they'd be like,
is that a secret deck?
I'd be like,
no,
that's a carrot.
Like constantly believe they pay people
to just watch for dicks.
They find double entendres where there
were no double entendres constantly.
Um,
imagine the,
well we would,
we,
we would like even,
I mean,
I don't know how much we should be
talking about this,
but like on fish hooks,
it'd be like we,
we would,
we would write something and then
without even thinking about the,
that it has the potential to be some way
in which,
yeah,
they'd always find it and then they
would take the thing and they would be
like,
oh,
like they dig up this lane,
it's like,
it's fine.
Like definition 12 on urban dictionary
and they'd be like,
that's a,
that's an offensive phrase ever heard of
before.
It would be like this Rube Goldberg
machine of like how it's offensive or
how it could be perceived as a Dick
Bush,
you know what I mean?
A lack of a better,
it was,
it was pretty well,
but I will say great place to work.
Uh,
a wonderful company.
Oh yeah.
I mean just don't tweet jokes and years
ago the company was tweet jokes.
10 years ago,
whatever you do,
don't get in a time machine.
Not to be a show 10 years ago,
period.
Not do it.
Like they were Rad.
It was mainly just the standards
department.
They were just like gigantic tools and
that every firm from day to day,
week to week,
they would constantly change.
I remember one time we had like,
there was like,
there's like some scene where it was
like,
oh,
we're going underground and there's some
trolls.
Um,
there's some like dwarves,
there's some ogres or whatever and
they're like,
oh,
you cannot,
you cannot have dwarves anymore.
That team,
that term is kind of offensive and
update and we would never allow,
we would never allow a dwarf to be in a
Disney production.
And literally as they were saying that,
I was looking out my window looking at
the giant stone,
seven dwarves holding up the roof of the
Disney filling and I was like these guys
are so I've completely gone off the
fucking reservation.
They reboot the seven dwarves.
It was like a newer,
they call it the seven d maybe they
can't say the word door,
I'm not sure.
And maybe they're right,
but it was just like the hypocrisy of
like you guys just the roof is literally
being held up by giant stone one you're
playing like a,
like a like a world of warcraft and you
and your role at dwarf characters and
that,
I mean yeah I'm not up or like I'm not
an expert medical term.
I guess maybe it,
it is medical term and now like,
but it wouldn't be one thing if they
were like,
I have a few door friends and that's
what they prefer to be called.
Like war ride it cause I've paid.
They don't like what did you say it in
the mic?
Furries rule from I believe C K N c.
A n.
C a way to go.
I'm going to talk on Ethan's fancy mic
wait ago.
Hey,
got,
what else?
We got 56,000
how are you feeling about the next
round?
Yeah,
I just want to get it over with.
And your dog keeps licking my feet.
Oh,
I paid for one,
but all right.
Hooks ready up?
How many,
how many people on the donation check?
It's just throwing a dollar.
You know,
it's not that much to just answer this
question.
How many people have paid to either
write on joey or Ethan's face or for a
song by Aussie and it's just kind of
never happened?
That's a great question.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
I feel really bad that I'm,
we're,
we're working through them right now.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Sorry,
I just,
I don't know if it's tilted by or,
or,
um,
that was from,
we've got tube charts.
Dot Net [inaudible] dot net,
which is from tube charts.net.
Oh Wow.
What is tube charts and styles go to two
charts down that it's not like I'm a
little afraid to go check.
And then we've got at s squared is from
I from Ihg.
I guess big money is getting involved
here.
Um,
uh,
Moses,
can you come hook shredding up with some
food or treats or something?
You should read it on the front.
It's not again,
you can start over.
Yeah,
I've been asked to draw something in
Justin's style.
Justin,
don't be offended if I fuck it up.
Oh,
nobody's watching the feed.
You ask them a really important question
and now nobody's watching and they just
donated more money.
I can't watch if people had donated in
vain.
Oh my God.
Not My mouth.
Mitchell stashed there.
What did you,
uh,
right.
Okay.
Thank you.
In my mouth as well.
Straight.
Go get joey.
You're up next.
You look like kind of crushed joey.
Your stomach.
All right.
And you can't eat pizza cause you're on
a diet.
Now tell me,
uh,
can you,
give joey the Michaela now tell me about
your diet,
if you would a why are you dieting?
Um,
I was training for the fight.
Yes.
So that's why I'm just kidding.
Binom I'm doing not well no,
that's a fair point.
We were going to have this battle meme
royale and it was supposed to happen,
but um,
we had a production company looking at
and they just straight up ghosted us,
which is strange.
When I was trying to train,
I was doing the Quito cause I want her
to look ripped and uh,
I mean I'm back on it now.
Hopefully the fight eventually happens,
but like I,
I've been,
I was training hard every morning for a
while and then I slowly stopped.
You stopped just because I didn't know
what was happening.
It's too much work now.
Are you,
are you interested in fitness?
You're trying to get jack to,
um,
read what this says.
So we just got furries rule
once more and we also got race.
Oh Wow.
You have it.
Not True.
That was no.
Oh,
there's no a race.
Baiter hey man,
that's great.
Congratulations.
What else is left?
Thank you for your donation bag.
Topic topic.
Thank you Mitchell.
Now Joey,
are you,
you were had a significant other last I
saw you.
Is that still going on?
Not,
not that one new one.
Oh No.
On what happened with the last one?
Seemed like you guys were hitting it
off.
I don't remember.
We broke up like a year ago.
Where were you guys living together?
It seemed real serious.
No,
she was just over every day.
And so the new one,
tell me about her.
This new one or do you guys making like
a facebook page that you guys had a hope
that prank channels?
Facebook doesn't,
let me change the name of the page.
It's ready.
It's done.
You're done.
All right.
And what was the new one?
The new one.
Her name's actually Gila or what's the
new?
A little sharpie subscribed to lab coat
and toppy the topic.
Can you say that into the mic once more
subscribed,
a lab coat and toppy the topic.
Thank you guys.
Hey,
I mean it's moving slowly.
We're going to be here all fricking
night.
Bus 57,000.
So wait,
listen to this.
The new ground scene,
she's half black,
half Jewish.
So I'm very exotic.
They can't call me a racist Nazi no
more.
Is that why you were with her?
Yup.
Covered everything.
I don't care at all about her.
I just need a date or for like a week.
How long have you guys been together?
A couple of months.
Yep.
And does she sympathize with your
political beliefs?
Yeah,
I'm red.
Pilling are a little bit,
hmm.
Is it red is red pilling um,
do you find it strange that this whole
movement is based around a matrix
metaphor?
I think that's kind of cool.
It's a little Corny,
isn't it?
But it's an easy way to like put it
know.
And do you think that being enlightened
red pill is,
is like as if Morpheus,
we're giving you the option to blue or
red?
I don't think it's that serious.
It's not that serious.
Okay.
Do,
what's the difference between woken red
pilled?
I think they're the exact opposite.
Right?
It's like,
depends on what side you're on.
That's what woke means,
you know what I mean?
So it's like,
oh,
you can be woke.
But it's like you can also be on the
left or you going to be woke and you can
be on the right.
It depends on what you're woke to.
So red building woke,
does it mean the same thing?
It depends what side you're on.
I've attempted to draw,
do a drawing and Justin royal and style
way as close as I can to something that
might look like adjusting oil and
drawing.
Oh,
let's see.
Let me hold.
Let me hold it here.
And I ain't got the fake,
uh,
saying,
Hey folks,
I'm Mister Malora.
So I'm an original character.
I'm scared of dying.
That's my gimmick.
That's my thing.
I'm really scared.
We should all be scared.
And this mouth is saying number three,
bro.
I'm less scared letting up,
Do.
We've got a new official,
just character.
Alex.
Don't,
don't let Justin know.
Alex,
it looks pretty plausible.
Think I'm going to do a second careers.
Maybe it's close as I could remember it.
Uh,
what he's,
what his signature looks like.
I know there's curling reuland original
by Alex now he needs to do it.
Alex was original by Justin Roiling.
I'd be curious to see.
I'd be curious to see what it would look
like.
I'm hoping they make mark that somebody
can take straight out.
He's getting a little restless now.
There's more pizza.
There should be a lot more pizza.
It's a fuels.
My drawings ma'am.
So we're at 57,000
guys,
let me tell y'all this.
This day is getting long.
I mean,
here's $57,000
there's a lot of money we shouldn't,
we shouldn't be a,
you know,
this isn't chop liver here needs 75 are,
we're all stuck here.
That's true you guys.
We are physically a contractually.
We're unable to leave until this guy
pukes ups and peppers unfortunately puke
and shit.
And I mean those are the,
how long does this stream lesson four
never would get to a hundred there is no
end because we can be here for 24 hours.
If it takes that long to get 75 I'll be
right back.
I think we'd all be happy ending on 75.
I think that 75 is good,
but we can do is if we get 100,000
off stream,
maybe we can just,
we'll get a widget thousand offers room
for sure,
but I'll,
I'll eat the reaper for like another
broadcast or something real there.
That's pretty amazing because I forget
what we're doing.
A recap on Friday.
Hey are we live?
And I think we'll hit it before then.
Hey,
I could take one of them back with me to
New York and then I could just do it
though.
That's awesome.
Can you maybe save this for,
uh,
you know when we're done you guys,
your defeatist fucking like I'll do,
I'll figure out how to do it then we'll
share defeat.
It's happening tonight.
All right.
Everyone share it on their twitter right
now.
Just,
just share the everyone.
Okay.
Did you see Alex's,
uh,
Justin?
Somebody has adjust and reuland style
drawing.
This looks great.
Oh my God,
this is so consistent advice.
Very close to what I would actually
draw.
Now,
do you have notes?
What would you have done differently?
How do I make this more like a justin
royal and drawing?
What are like the telltale giveaways for
like an art curator?
Wow.
No,
I mean you really,
this is a,
this is pretty dead on.
Justin is kinda shocked here.
I think a,
I think it might be out of business.
What about,
what about the signature?
What are the telltale mistakes in the
signature?
The signature is a shit show,
but everything else is like they,
the handwriting and signature of the or
the or the,
that character is like,
like if,
if like if I put that in a drawer and
like a few years later I would not even,
I wouldn't just assume I drew it.
That's pretty amazing.
Are you going to draw a,
you going to draw an Alex Harris drawing
now?
Are you going to try to talk the world?
I'm not the chameleon of artists.
You know,
just like I'm not the chameleon of voice
actors.
Should we go over the reward
impressionism
impression?
Do we need to tell these people what's
at stake here guys?
We really are trying to help $500
people.
Oh no sir.
A hundred bucks.
That's all it cost to draw to deface
Joey's face,
500 to face my face.
Those were not,
those were down for a while,
right?
Or or what?
I mean it's up now.
We figured out what it was actually.
So we originally thought we were only
going to six and we didn't want those to
go after and so they had expired and so
I just,
I just reinitiated them and I said it to
eight,
but if we get close to eight and we're
still going,
oh you got to keep going and half hours
we got,
we got to go to at least seven hours.
I mean we did five hours last year,
so we still have an hour and a half,
but we definitely get to thousand.
We're not that close to 75 though.
No,
we got to hit,
we got to hit a Christmas miracle.
You know what it was,
you know what it was?
It was my fault for building that
fucking toy in the beginning.
I wasn't contributing.
I wasn't like given the given the show
the energy not too late Bro.
For game changing.
Prank call.
That's all I'm saying.
Who can we prank?
No,
so the law is as long as we call someone
outside of California,
it was also recording.
Some states have a one party consent
call enzymes,
which up out I was like,
well we can call it enzyme.
We can call like scammers.
I mean let's call it,
let's do some print color.
Let's call it scammer.
Like cash for gold people or a role.
This is legitimate company.
No,
but if you go on Google and type like
type something like how to send money to
my grandchild and click one of the ads.
Oh it was like a straight up scammer.
Yeah.
I don't know if we'll do it as good as
like some of these other ones like,
well why don't you guys recommend some
people that we don't have to feel guilty
about Pradco.
Are there any,
are there any guilt free frank calls?
If you could give us some suggestions
from the donation spot cause we would
love to,
frank calls him the dollars.
I'm like no.
Karma.
Karma points docked on us.
Yeah,
we got a call from the president of the,
yeah.
What's going on with that,
Dan?
Where's the park?
We president.
I heard we were going to,
and we'll get a call from Donald Trump.
Me Check my text messages.
Just cause I'm in tight with the,
I'm going to fight with the president.
Let me ask you a bunch of questions for
the president.
Donald,
are you ready?
Yeah,
hold on.
Will you let me sort of like talk to the
president when he's on?
Yeah.
Yes,
absolutely.
I mean,
that's why we're doing this.
I thought,
I specifically thought that you would
have a lot to,
a lot of questions for the president
that I think are like,
you know,
important and I would love just an
opportunity of like an uninterrupted
little moment for me to ask some of
those questions.
Can I use that?
Oh,
for fuck sake.
But don't mess with it.
No,
I,
let's watch another video.
Come on.
I want to prank call post malone.
That's not happy.
No,
no,
no.
Um,
Alex,
let's,
let's watch a video.
Come on.
You got all these great videos,
you've got a whole stock.
Do you want to prank call?
I think we got to do a prank call.
Of course we will,
but let's while we wait.
Hey Justin.
Yeah,
check,
check.
Quick.
Did you hear about the dude who got
tried to rob a convenience store and got
caught in the currys spent for three
days?
Let's hear it.
That's it right there on the screen.
That's like some shit right there.
And then it looks like a pretty hostile
painting.
Justin,
look at the TV.
That's your boy.
Wait,
so is this a video?
Are we watching the video
covering after being stuck in a grace
event of a California restaurant for
nearly two days,
authorities say the man is believed to
be a trespasser and possible burglar
firefighters were able to free the man
after taking out the hood and duct
system.
Suspect is now in custody,
no word on his condition or possible.
Do you know what?
Let them go.
I would say,
you know what?
Go go home.
Let his greasy ass off.
I'm not kidding.
Then it's like,
it's like,
look,
you learned your lesson.
You learned your lesson of a California
resident.
Oh,
reverse sneezing.
Yeah.
I think he's all right.
Nobody can just cover his nose.
I don't think he's in a gunny gunny
advice about a folks we should a prank
call guys.
People that were still bellow the key.
Joel osteen was such a perfect villain.
You know what I mean?
Well,
at that particular moment in time,
yeah,
sure.
It was like,
I mean,
I'm sure he's still a piece of any of
these filthy.
I really like big blue.
Really like my whole ended up prayer
lines in general.
Just because you're playing with fire a
little bit though,
because you had a lot of those people
that,
why don't we,
why don't we call it like one of those
paid psychic line scientology?
Psychic lines are fantastic.
Hey them.
Uh,
yeah,
so they have to stay on.
Exactly.
And not only that are damn,
well,
let's call,
let's do a late one,
900 it's like good number blind because
they're getting paid.
What did they complaining and then,
and then we'll do.
This is good for everybody.
I love that.
No Bad Karma.
Both sex one 900 phones south.
It might get a little growth.
[inaudible] you take it wherever you
want.
I'll go.
I just want you to pretend like you're
cleaning my room with me.
Yell at me cause my room isn't clean.
I mean,
there's only so many angles.
All right,
well let's go it up.
The very first thing you're buying.
Well,
I'm thinking like nonsexual actis little
tooth.
Yeah.
That,
uh,
Oh,
right back dad,
dad,
Dad,
dad.
Dad is getting his,
he hates us today.
We're just like dad,
everything,
do everything.
Trying to find a,
it's like a guideline for you right now
and all that.
Then one more person.
There's a lot going on.
Astic okay.
What's shredding?
Walked.
Yeah.
He's got a couple of walks and,
uh,
also I'm going to grab a slice.
You want one of the guys who,
uh,
drawing so they can see k nine c,
um,
was somebody who had just donated so
that we could write on them.
Uh,
we set their name wrong so they
terminate and another $500 so that we
could just correct to the name.
What's his name?
His correct name is c,
k nine c.
Uh,
we said something else before.
You say night night.
That's amazing.
The dollars in total that we should have
said it wrong.
So he donated,
right?
Yeah,
that's a good point.
Yeah.
Is there another regional dry?
Oh,
I'll,
I'll cook what happened one minute.
All right.
Feed.
What should I draw?
What do you think guys?
Donate a dollar.
Tell me what I should draw.
Hmm.
Let's see.
You love you guys.
Keep it up.
I love your positivity.
Can't draw that.
I mean,
I guess I could draw the concept of love
is a little difficult.
Thanks for the awesome work,
dude.
Thank you guys.
Eat a slice.
A piece of backwards.
Want Pepperoni or like by backwards?
Is there just cheese?
No,
I don't think so.
There is,
yeah,
right.
Justin reads out messages and the ric
voice.
If you donate $1,000,
oh,
I 100% would do it,
but doesn't seem super reluctant to do
the ric voice right now.
Maybe it busts his throat up,
but yeah,
I would,
I would pay,
I would pay two grand for that man.
What does eat a slice of pizza
backwards.
Do they mean like from the crust?
For no amount of money.
Would I ever do that third no kids off.
Well thank you.
Oh,
no problem.
Thank you.
Oh,
what happened?
We got another donation?
Yeah,
he's got some shits or be written on,
excuse me.
Sorry.
I'm shut her eat draw shredder and a
vape nation costume that I can do.
Yeah.
Do it.
That I can do,
he wants me to write on his food.
Ba on Joey Salads.
Oh,
that's cool.
Oh yeah.
Careful.
There's a whole bunch of gear behind Ya.
Don't think we need to be this or I
guess maybe the is on his food,
but to be unused don't enter them.
Like,
wait,
what's that?
I just took a bite of this beats an oil
scored in and my face,
we heard every,
every little squirt.
That's,
that's how,
that's how you know it's,
it's a tasty little slice of pizza.
Um,
yeah,
I'm googling around for a paid a psychic
hotline.
Um,
do these exist anymore?
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
I'm looking for a 901 and then what
about the president?
Just,
just,
just google.
Which do you want me to just want to
know this?
I could go,
there's the president and then look for
the,
let's get the president on the line,
but wait,
hold on.
No,
no,
no.
Okay.
President on the resident then psychic.
Well,
okay.
I don't know if,
uh,
if it,
is Aussie ready to play one of the
songs?
Cause like Brett,
do we have one at lined up?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's three songs.
She's got to come in and play.
Go Out and learn.
Come in and play.
So she's,
she's learning the first one.
I'm so fucking pissed cause I wanted to,
I wanted to pay for one of those.
Oh,
I wanted to,
I have a song.
Well you can just,
you don't have to donate to that
incentive.
Just,
uh,
just donate $200 to the
general.
I mean,
you're here so I know what's going on.
I didn't know that president is ready.
The president is ready.
I'll get them on the line.
Standby.
Everybody focus.
We have the president of the United
States.
Takes me about a minute.
Incredible.
Listen Up.
Questions for the Pres.
Tell me when he's a in Dan.
Yes,
I will.
Okay.
This is very thrilling and very
exciting.
Um,
little known fact.
I am very close and tight with the
president of the United States.
Donald Trump.
Good old friends.
We go way back,
way,
way back.
You went to my bar Mitzvah and
everything.
Um,
grabbed my mom by the pussy but that was
fine because he's such a superstar.
Um,
is he there?
I don't hear him but he decided to call
us in to help donate for the cause is
wonderful cause and to do an Faq with
us.
So he is piping in right now.
The secret service is establishing a
connection and it should only be a
matter of moments now,
shortly before Donald Trump
zipped right in so many really like
super important questions to ask
residents.
What kind of buried the lead.
I mean it just says Alex version and
Justin Reuland has guests and we kind
of,
I know,
I downplayed it.
Just wanted it to be surprised.
And it is.
So without further ado and coming up
very shortly,
the president,
Donald J,
what's The j stand for?
Nobody knows.
It's a mystery,
but only just
cool [inaudible].
I only his closest friends know what the
j stands for and as proof of our
friendship,
what's The j stand for?
As as proof of our friendship.
I'll tell you right now,
a stands for John,
by Golly,
and nobody knows that,
but me as close for anything client
Donald Trump deep,
we're almost a 60,008
out of boom,
Bada boom,
Bada Bang.
We're creeping up AA credit.
All right,
so the president is connecting.
Just got word from the secret service.
He is on the phone.
Somebody just gave us a one 800
psychics,
one 800 I took.com
and a number w w.
Dot.
1-800-PSYCHIC psychic and a website.
We have to call the Hollywood www dot.
Hello Hollywood psychics will all these,
all these,
we'll,
we'll get to that.
Dan,
are you a taking stock of these?
Well,
I want to save it here.
I'll send these to Dan on discourse in
the one right below to buy your beer.
Nerd bird,
dude,
I can't wait to call these mother
fuckers calling the press right now.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Pipe through as we speak right now.
Donald J.
Trump,
only his close friends know this,
but it stands for John Gone.
Such a cartoony middle name.
John Simpson Bowles.
Jay Moose,
right?
Michael J.
Fox,
everybody.
Jay.
Well that person.
Mr President,
are you there?
Nope.
Hello.
Oh my God.
Oh my goodness.
What a honor to be.
I think guys were joking.
We get some precedent music.
Please.
Thank you.
The music down.
He's the president is to quiet music is
still out.
I can't hear.
Interesting.
Mr President,
is anybody back there?
We turn them up.
Stop talking over him.
Yeah.
Well the music is pretty loud.
It's an honor to have you here.
I,
I had a few questions that,
uh,
I think,
you know,
the larger populous would,
would really like you to answer.
And I answered them honestly.
Um,
what do you,
what do you think about that?
Oh,
that's all right.
We'll do it.
I think whatever of life that took it,
nobody will do it.
But go ahead.
All right,
so,
so the first question I have is what do
you think of slender man?
That whole,
that crazy cooky.
Oh,
you know,
there's so many complicated things to do
with others,
but it's true that this person got to,
Alli sent through,
we don't talk weight.
We tried to throw a fit.
That's probably,
but first what we will see static and
that's that good.
So we're looking at today,
I've got my cup.
I said,
yes,
Mr President.
It's clear you have a strong opinion on
a lot to say about slenderman.
We didn't,
we didn't quite hear most of it,
but I,
I hope the audience out out there
watching the screen and see on Air Force
One right now.
President,
are you on Air Force One or what's going
on here?
We are totally bobby.
All of the countries worldwide initially
started.
It's total chaos.
Hmm.
Well,
well as it,
as interesting as that line of
discussion might be,
I,
I'm,
I'm actually more curious to know what
do you think of these Weird Nintendo?
You know,
Nintendo just sent out these little
like,
you know,
original nes game pads that kind of
slide into the side of your,
your,
your switch system.
You know what I'm talking about?
They just,
they just recently sent those out and
you had to,
in order to get them,
well,
just what she's doing started with the
company as long as you rest,
but you're looking at Mario and you look
at least gets you out of bed the whole
day and it doesn't make any sense.
Okay.
I little,
I look at Barrio,
I say,
what is he?
It doesn't make sense.
Why does he want to be a bit?
Okay.
But they are totally fairly,
from what I understand,
you see,
you get it.
It's family and May in the dumpster.
Okay.
What you should really invest it is new
soldier boy cut.
So that's what the body is dead.
I kill you.
Yeah,
I have,
I've been hearing,
I've been hearing good things about the
soldier boy console,
so that's a really good thing.
Um,
what,
do you know what,
yeah,
sorry,
sorry to interrupt.
I know.
Uh,
what,
what do you,
what do you think about the,
the um,
this whole,
uh,
you know,
digital streaming channel that lets you
watch nickelodeon
depo her and,
and they are both really the Boogie
board vote people in or what to did you
bond?
They stripped out Jeff,
three,
four,
five up to five days.
So you have a evolution.
So that's something we liked but we have
to look at Yoga.
Mr President,
I just have to ask,
you know,
you brought up,
did you mind um,
you know,
Michael Huckabee is famously come out so
that he doesn't believe in,
uh,
did you,
did you evolution,
uh,
he doesn't believe that.
Uh,
did your mind can ditch evolve?
What is your,
what is your take on that Mr President?
I think if you put shit people compared
to a get you by Roy Taylor then,
which I think if I have to be right,
it's totally about get be a puppy,
be what gives it,
did you post right?
You get of through the circuits.
I said you would be a very different
story.
Yeah,
that's the,
that's a pretty,
I mean,
I can't disagree with that.
No.
Mr President,
as you all know,
the power rangers was a very popular
show and the 90s now a lot of people say
the pink power ranger was,
it was the most powerful,
but I,
but many also say the red power ranger
was the most powerful.
Yeah.
You were looking at the power rangers
and the black one was black.
I don't know what was going on there,
but it was just total dictatorship.
I don't really talk about it,
but text off.
Yay.
Go ahead.
Um,
uh,
w what do you think of Japanese candies?
I mean,
are you,
are you familiar with these little
monkeys?
Sure.
You look at Japanese women and they look
a little bit younger than the rest of
the world.
Right.
That joke yet.
But it's legal and the whole thing is
legal and they say the people go there
to get a white people go to give hand
because of the way every,
I show younger than six fit because of
like white guys.
But that's the case,
so.
Okay.
But Mr President,
what do you think about the,
the treats,
the Japanese treats like the pokey or
Paki Hello Panda Panda.
You know some of these mushroom shaped a
little chocolate.
Three avoiding the question.
Romney's soda.
How do you feel about the light full?
Avoiding.
Avoiding both.
We could just judge you how you see
yourself.
You people put this fake stuff.
Okay.
But this is what the truth is.
I'm telling you it is okay.
I am totally cool.
Why?
I love the animation epic.
Okay.
That's what I love.
I keep telling you people,
but they would print it like you beside
your [inaudible].
So I've sat though,
I love Japanese culture.
I love the pictures.
Right?
The contracts that was present.
Mr Braden,
as I have super powers.
Ed,
I see pizza.
I say it's crazy.
Okay.
Now Mister President,
do you consume a Hentai?
What do you think that Hentai it should
be illegal.
I know a lot of Hentai depicts very
young girls in it and a lot of people
find that question.
What do you,
what do you think about this type of
Hentai that depicts very young girls?
Mr President.
Well,
I was sitting there and I never heard of
this.
I said,
how did it all by people?
What am I tap?
People came up to me and it shouldn't be
surprised.
What did you think of head size has ever
heard of it?
So they gave me a laptop with that guy.
He said the elders and they left me
alone for third one out.
But you're looking at these pictures and
they're horrible.
And his knees.
I look,
girls look so young,
but they like it.
It's sort of like,
but that's okay.
We can talk about that because they are
like it.
But you look at these authentic,
those fucking Webinar.
So weak Leo Speedo say this.
That's okay.
Um,
do you,
uh,
what was a really thought provoking
answer?
Yeah,
that was going to answer like,
well,
what do you think?
What do you think of these?
Uh,
what do you think of these?
Like these,
these scooters,
lyme or bird,
all these companies,
these scooters and,
and,
and what do you think about segway,
the segway pro.
Wait,
hold on.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
You took video.
2 billion views.
Thinking there's 2 billion people.
That's a lot of people.
That's a lot of people killed,
but it has 2 million views.
I sorted edit with a little boy,
a little Mexican boy.
I,
we showed one of these scooters.
I said,
what is that?
But the little boy,
he falls off the scooter in the video.
Okay.
Yes.
Uh Huh.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Are you,
is that the,
so you're,
is that Mr President,
are you there?
Are you,
is that you saying?
Yeah.
Oh,
I really,
yes.
That was a little boy fell off the stool
and that's it.
Okay.
So,
so,
okay,
got it.
You're against them.
Um,
I'm,
I'm kind of curious,
Mr President,
who do you mean?
Maybe he's for them.
I,
yeah,
not quite clearly dodging the Co.
I think the president wants to move on
the little boy,
the [inaudible] the four simple than I
am.
Maybe you take things typically,
I just know,
pick up,
look at the little boy.
And once you see that video you'll just
stared.
Okay.
Mr President,
what,
what's your take on Mario paint?
The classic Mario Paint for Nintendo
Super Nintendo.
Do you think it should be remade?
Do you think there should be a modern,
more,
more featured,
uh,
more features,
more fleshed out version of Mario paint?
Hmm.
Barrio be released for the switch 2019
and then there was easily 20.
Thank you Lord.
Okay.
That's,
is that a basis?
Yeah.
Can I ask who do you mean and smash?
Mr Who?
Who,
who do you mean when you play smash
brothers against other world leaders?
Yeah.
Where are you looking at?
You're looking at what you gave is right
there.
There's all these killings doesn't sell,
but that's just,
okay.
But I saw somebody playing the scale by
playing the game.
They should be on.
What is that?
He said,
dad,
don't look.
I said,
what is that edge?
I realized that Super Smash Brothers was
epic.
I looked at word right.
If you've heard of this,
we have heard of the word man.
It gets fucking sweet.
Lowest,
every religious great,
right?
This is what we'd like to talk about.
But,
so I saw his very far.
They shared my thoughts with this.
I don't get it.
There's all these gay,
they're fighting.
That's what's,
what's with the fighting
you're,
you're saying you'd like to see a,
a more peaceful,
uh,
a version of
Oh,
smash brothers.
The situation with all the kids so that
we will get into that.
But you're looking at bowery [inaudible]
Gel dot.
Okay.
And it's so great.
It's so cool.
Now,
Mr President,
what is a,
what is done?
What do you think about?
So when you think of the game,
Zelda,
the,
the main protagonist,
the hero of that game is link actually.
But a lot of people think that it's
Zelda because the name is Zola,
but that's the name of the princess.
Now,
do you think that this name,
that this game should be called the
adventures of link?
Do you find that that the way that it's
branded is inappropriate?
I talked to get totally this lady.
I say it should be happy.
Look to do,
we will be putting my copy both.
I would like to look at the public.
Not People.
You want to do it?
Your president.
Okay.
Uh,
yeah.
Um,
so what do you think of Bitcoins,
Mr President?
Are you a big fit coin guy?
He are.
You,
you buy a couple of bitcoins or what
though?
They per se do the Bitcoin,
they were second best.
The best of best did I looked at doing
it.
It looks like a total fraud.
Just see what the stem,
I think anybody about bitcoin before the
crash is stupid.
That's okay.
We won't get it today.
But what I did was I invested heavily in
goats going judge.
Cause I could write babe of course
thing.
Now Mr President,
if I can ask you something a little more
personal,
uh,
do you,
how do you wipe the Ed when you have a
debt,
when you defecate in the bathroom,
do you end with a wet one?
Do you use baby wipes?
Do you have a,
um,
do they,
how do you clean up the feces around
your,
your asshole,
Mr President after that
covered look at us and off the both
feeling a certain way,
right?
A very good day.
I do that pretty much a bad day.
I just feel bad.
I should wear where you have two people
come in and do it themselves.
But there's a lot of ways to do it
right.
It's that great,
but there's a lot of ways.
That's right.
Well,
Mr President,
I have to say it's been very eye
opening.
Uh,
you've dodged some questions,
but for the most part you've been very
forthcoming.
Yes.
I love all of you people.
I think you're all great in sales.
I don't be,
you keep video,
get it shoved communities.
My favorite one of all,
I love this.
It's great.
Okay.
That's the president.
Well,
Eh,
gut.
Please.
Thank you for,
for all of your hard work.
I know that being depressed,
being done the hard work hard.
These are hard questions.
We held your feet to the fire today.
I really appreciate you really held,
you really like telling us the truthful
answers to some of these hard questions
that we,
we lobbed at you and we appreciate it.
But I have to tell you before I leave,
I have to tell you,
look up on Youtube.
Pitcher 40 do videos.
They calling it viral.
Okay,
that's probably fine.
But what they say to you is if you look
on youtube and you type,
it was a funny,
it's still funny.
It's the funniest thing I've ever seen
before.
Okay,
so you would just stay.
That's all I wanted to tell him.
Well,
I'm the president of the united well
Mister President,
I'm sure you have a lot to get to.
You must be very busy,
man.
Um,
so we wish you all the best and uh,
good luck running the country and thank
you so much for calling trouble,
Huh?
Yes,
absolutely.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Your ledger for peace out.
Hmm?
I don't know.
Yes,
of course.
Well,
did you say something about he did say
yes,
he did ask him about all the,
all the aliens,
but I guess we missed our chance,
but we know about slapping man.
We could have really gotten into some
CIA actual helpful thing.
I,
well maybe not.
I had,
yeah,
there was a lot of questions about
policy and stuff.
Yeah,
I had written down but we never got
there.
There's a lot of stuff,
but really want to know it was an area
51 on next.
Well that was fascinating.
Yeah.
60,500
guys.
He got the trump bomb.
Trump bump.
Thank you.
Thank you Mr President for the bump
15th.
Oh,
we got more to right.
So Dan,
do we have a Saturday?
We've got a song.
We've got a song,
a song by song time.
Yeah.
Let's,
uh,
let's go back and real quick,
can I show you I got,
I got another heart might full guys.
Whoa dude.
Alex,
let me show this quest.
Look at this.
See very talented artists.
Freaking kidding me.
You a little redder red.
They tread boy that I think.
I think I have.
I'm getting this.
I'm getting the vibe that maybe Ethan's
going to try to snag that one.
I need to be maybe your bullshit.
Well,
what do you,
what art do you want to bid on?
Mom?
Is this the one you want?
Mama approved every mom on earth once
that are made above for kitchen.
She wants that image.
500 500 to a,
I'm working on some random,
I could draw on him.
I don't know what.
Oh Jesus.
It's all that.
So was working on something spicy
and hot.
Okay,
here we gotta.
We gotta get,
we gotta get you.
Oh by the way,
take these out and you should all go up
for auction.
The grease on them.
That's amazing.
Original or y'all better fucking bad to
me and then is ready.
So let's get her in here to play.
Play player first driver.
Justin.
I feel like I'm being violated whenever
Justin writes on me like look at this my
head,
it's a very personal thing like on a
head back against my back.
Come on.
I'm looking up under him as if like the
girls view and the blow job made me
think,
Oh God,
what are you writing?
It's just so somebody asking to be sub
two so we'll say it for pizza to case Z
K nine seat.
I was that the guy who the same person.
The same guy.
Man.
What a hero.
Well,
let me make sure that that's clear that
that's a c.
Yeah,
there we go.
That was e k nine c right?
That was his name.
Nicey nicey.
No one else.
All right,
here we go.
Let's keep it going guys.
Let's keep it going.
This is already set up so,
all right.
Any moron.
Any more drawing requests,
drop them in.
Drop them in the truck by men to chat.
Let's bid on one of the drawings.
Which one he wants.
These get to 75.
Can we please get to 75 I like the first
one that Justin made stories up the
three characters.
Okay.
Damn.
Oh,
you're here to here.
All right,
let's bid.
And these apparently let's bid.
Should I wait?
Should we bid 2000 on it?
I'm going to be pissed.
Maybe do it.
That wasn't on Alex's drawing of our
baby.
That one was also,
yeah.
Do you really want to see that every day
then?
I want to see that in the paper.
How long is this?
Well first let's introduce our guests.
We have Aussie here from chaos,
chaos,
uh,
previous,
welcome back to the show by the way.
Yes,
we can see her.
Yeah,
you can move.
Oh my God.
My face is fuck.
I realized.
Yeah,
scoot that way.
Screwed that way.
So we have a performance.
What was the request for?
Let's say,
yeah,
Ossie.
Yeah,
you should just hear it,
but somebody donated.
Can we shout them out?
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
So to do this right,
I have to,
I'm going to kill off your mics.
Okay.
Okay,
cool.
Yeah,
there's so many things that could go
wrong with this.
All
right.
Uh,
uh,
yeah.
[inaudible] then for the charity.
Wow.
Keep and creepers never sounded so cool.
Is that going on your new album?
Are we are Mike's back on deep and
creep,
peep and creep.
Oh my God,
I didn't know that was awesome.
So who is responsible?
Who?
Yeah.
Dan.
Who?
Who indeed.
I don't know who it was.
Dan.
Okay.
Was it you just told her?
I though I couldn't get through.
I swear to God,
be able to choose.
You definitely got to be able to choose.
I was trying to like get one in like
every time I would try it with like
another,
it would be a slot would be taken and
then I'd try again.
That was a fan named Spencer that
requested that.
Tell me,
I see you were backstage at rehearsing.
How was your preparation for that?
Um,
it was,
it was interesting up.
Do I need to talk in this mic?
You don't want to hear Mike's now that.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um,
all right.
it was interesting.
I was like sitting out in front of the
bathroom and there was a guy,
actually,
he was kind of interesting with the
context of the song,
but there was a guy walking around with
the flashlight for some reason just like
shoot,
like shining a flashlight is puffin and
creeping.
And he was explaining on me,
I don't know,
is that normal around the building?
Oh,
that definitely,
that happened the whole time.
And I was like,
you're a while you're playing.
People think so.
I think what it was like for him,
mommy,
Justin dresses up as a security guard
and walks around with a flashlight.
It was not me guys.
You guys would know that there's going
to be some like really rational reason
why that was happening.
Building.
But he died and he was like,
we called them flashlight,
flashlight on.
You did,
he was already doing it.
He was doing it before I got there.
And then and then kind of like continue
to know why I should have just chose a
different location.
I am.
I sat like right next to him.
You can,
you can do them right in this room.
So it seems like you probably want to
be,
you can just do it.
Any song.
Right?
If you,
if you have a moment,
one of hers,
he's just not like sheet music for peep
and creep is available on line listening
to it.
I was looking at your lyrics.
You bet you got three more to learn and
come back in and play.
So I feel like I should leave on this
note though.
But I know.
Learn the next good leave for good.
Just go out there.
How many songs should shit doing?
I should pay for one.
I know what's up.
I should get,
I should pay for a song.
I do.
I think we only thought we already
capped yet.
Well it's like,
it's like once she gets through the next
we do or be popular.
So we put a cap of,
we only saw three or four.
Dan,
what did we sell those we sold for?
Because you've got to look at my $500
donation that I did and that's copy
that.
All right,
we'll take a look at that,
Justin.
I snuck around the barriers.
I have a song I want guys,
we're up to 61,000
we're getting close.
We're getting close.
Come on,
but it's going really slow.
Thank you.
Aussies,
aussies performance.
Just donate.
You know,
five bucks,
10 bucks,
whatever.
$80 you should get a shot of joey salads
sitting on the couch,
on his phone and let's see,
this one's got a shot at Joey Salads.
Please on the couch for Christ's sake.
Look,
and like,
I mean,
look at this guy.
He,
he probably doesn't even know like,
look at this.
Eat that pepper man.
He's like,
where's that pepper?
And he's like,
why?
Why are your fans so so,
so heartless that they can't even like
think of these poor people?
Can we play some more sad videos?
Let's play some more sad videos.
Show up.
Fuck devastate.
Maybe that's what we need to do is to
really using up tug at their heart
strings.
I don't know,
maybe it was incredible.
That's creep.
Well let's pray called the psychic cause
we actually have,
okay,
let's do it.
Dan,
can we connect to the psychic?
I gave you a website.
Hollywood
psychics.com.
Yeah,
let's do it as long as your phone
number.
Um,
Hollywood psycho.com
but I think we should do karaoke as
well.
Hello?
Be Bank.
Greed will set you giuffre I don't
remember the words be.
Do you want to sing it?
You know my throat P I can get glue
helped me out.
How's it go?
You just be one person who just knew it.
Just,
yeah.
Oh,
hey Joe Greene.
The cuties at the beach.
The cuties at the,
yeah.
All right.
Enough.
If that fucking thing out of your face.
[inaudible] is this Mike actually
picking up the vocals like Oh God.
Well on.
I'm just curious.
Hopefully not.
Oh No,
it's closed right now.
I mean we can,
we can hear it just from the ambiance a
little bit,
but I wonder like was it too loud like
it was,
it was her vocals were quiet in the
room.
But I want,
but in the overall mix,
was it like if anything the vocals were
yeah,
cause we don't,
we don't have,
we don't have her a keyboard Mike.
So what else we got here?
Vocals were way we may do.
I mean it was okay.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's no hard line in for the,
for the,
for the stupid,
uh Oh yeah.
What the fuck for that keyboard?
It's all good.
Hello?
Hello guys.
What the fuck is this?
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
61,000
we're going to be here a while.
So which one do you want to donate for?
Hey look,
we've,
how much have we donated so far?
3000 so let's drop another two.
Where do you want to put them?
He creep.
I'm on the drawing height,
by the way,
Ethan,
I think you should leave this raffle up
for more than just a week.
We can't extend it.
I think you should.
Well,
we can always extend it.
And you know what,
I'll be the bad guy.
I'll take the bullet.
We're going to extend it for a month.
A month.
That's what we did last year.
Did we really?
Come on?
No,
I don't think it would matter.
I think it was two weeks.
We had three weeks.
We also got to get all the,
I say it's never let it end.
That's a lot of work.
The thing is,
I don't think they get the money until
the campus.
No,
that's not true.
They get the money.
All these for us.
People are like waiting.
We just keep extending.
Um,
I want to create Paul.
I want to prank call,
but I'll tell you what guys.
No,
let's just call a psychic hotline.
Assigned me to prank calls.
Just those call a psyche.
Cause my prank,
I got this number.
It's not even 900 numbers patches
through patches through,
but let's wait for,
actually,
let me pee and let's get Alex in here.
Well,
how about let's,
we'll do a few of these.
So patch us into the first one.
You Go pee all he this,
I'm a,
this is,
this is this is it a p and I've waited
all day up.
Joey Get,
Can I pee in your,
it's not the first time he's asking if
he can put it in your mouth.
Joey wants to pee in my mouth.
I want to be in his mouth and somebody
go grab some ginger beer like from the
local.
Okay.
Down the street.
Liquor store.
They were the ones from ginger beer.
Oh,
I would kill for it.
I'll see what I can do.
You can just post mates.
It's a known as to go to a porsche or
you can send somebody to do it.
Let me know somebody.
Postmates it.
I'm afraid to do it on my phone.
Don't worry.
We got it.
And why is I'm broke.
Yeah,
I know.
I'll pay.
I'll pay whoever it is.
Okay,
so Dan,
can you do me a favor?
Ooh,
but people,
so can you bet $1,000
on the Justin's first drawing of the
three characters a.
Okay,
you got it.
And then do you want to put another
thousand on another drawing?
Ila One.
Do One.
I don't remember.
I remember there was ones I really
liked,
but I don't,
let me look on the rewards
thing.
Yeah,
I got it.
I got to donate.
So man,
I got to drop down a big donation.
Let's see.
A big boy.
Big Boy.
Yeah,
you've got to get to 75 k because let's
see which thing do I want the most?
So maybe I'm just going to try to get
that morty Chia pet.
You lose to the one taller.
It dropped three k for the morning.
Chia pet.
Hilarious.
And you still lost.
Okay,
so I have worse all the art.
I feel like it's too dark.
You can't see the Goddamn Shit.
I'm mobile.
I see as like a muddy,
muddy wall of,
of of things.
I can't see it.
And like $1,
$1,
$1.
And it's either Justin's baby Klein,
there's a little vote you wanted a baby
klein that rick and morty crew zip up
Hoodie.
That is legitimately fucking crazy.
Crazy.
Fucking rare.
Rare,
valuable.
That's like crew only.
And if you look at it,
can you click on zoom?
Like,
can you get a bigger,
I can one sec.
Wait,
do you get to like what do you have to
open up a special arc?
Like can you do it through till to fi
really here.
Actually here.
Okay.
Here we go.
Fucking for Christ sake.
So,
so,
so like these are all like all the
drawings are from the original doc and
Marty Short,
right?
That got this whole thing started and
um,
I added some new ones for the interior
hoodie and this is by daylight curfew
and um,
there's not,
I mean I'm,
I'm,
I'm not shitting around.
There's like,
there's like,
I'm not shitting around guys.
I know that varies.
That's a famous spray familiar with,
there's like maybe a hundred of these
total made.
Um,
so you know,
if you're looking at,
if you're looking to,
if you're looking for bitcoin style
investments,
well,
and then if,
I dunno if you want to pitch this a
little,
but this,
this is worth 100,000,
I think.
But it is like,
it's literally priceless because there
aren't any,
there aren't any more of that.
Yeah.
There's no way.
There's,
there's nothing one of the
Bible,
but it's also one of a kind because
it's,
it's the first one ever.
It's the test print with mistakes that
you like.
There's some like there's some,
I think there's some typos in there.
There's some slight differences between
the final version dude guys.
Oh,
also by the way,
you should,
you should in the front cover of that.
You should write down like all of that
information's in the bush.
Sure.
Yeah,
because that will really fucking like
authentic,
utilize it and if the winter wants it
signed,
I'll sign it.
If they don't want it signed,
I won't sign it,
but I'll find go back.
Wait,
Dan,
did you already donate a thousand?
I was actually just filling it out.
Don't do it.
Okay.
Stopping please.
For the love of God,
do 1,200
so I can bump this guy.
No,
I want the bump him.
He's had it all day.
You know what?
You're right.
I think you've got to bump it.
A real person has to bump at night yet.
No bumpers person.
I'm a real person.
I'm donating to directly.
You bump it.
Bump your bump.
Yeah,
you go,
this is how it works.
Poppers,
competition,
game 1,200
being no,
because they do it.
They're going to be like,
oh,
well then I'm out.
No,
they're going to bump me.
You have a guy or girl out there who's
going to be like,
I'm going to bump a whitmore phillips.
I only put a hundred above him.
It's a total bumper bowl bid.
What other fun stuff do we have here?
We got,
we got,
we get saggy.
Is this the one?
Yeah,
this one.
Yeah.
That's the way.
No,
no,
not this one.
Not this one.
Look at though.
The sack.
You asked for the hugging it out is what
we called it is looking at three guns
right there.
Right there.
Bam.
There you go.
To 1,200
on hugging.
Oh my God.
Well,
I colored it.
I want that one.
I colored that one.
Should I put 2000 on this one?
Well,
I mean don't,
don't do all this.
Art will be framed when it shipped.
It's going to be put in really nice
frame.
Holy Shit.
I really hope I win this.
Justin,
can you just make 1,200
here we go.
How can you just draw me something?
Just kind of like football pushing on
this guy in the middle.
None of them look like they're enjoying
themselves.
They all look like they're in pain.
The guy in the middle does with the
other two look like they're in pain.
I should put 5,000
for a video from Ross.
Yeah.
How,
how are we doing with the,
with the Ros one or I guess we don't,
we have no fucking clue.
Right?
Well Dan does have,
um,
well we we should,
we should not know that that information
cause that that'll,
that'll totally wait.
What does that Mr.
Moore Mo oh that's [inaudible] I did
look at that.
Wait,
click on this cause the cause like it
says,
look,
it'll Justin Roy.
Oh my God.
It's not by me.
It needs to explain it that original
cause otherwise and you actually need to
sign them your own way.
We'll edit the title right now.
Yeah.
I want to see that one bump around in
such a good job.
Imitating,
look,
believe me,
I,
I said the same thing.
I was like,
oh my God,
I needed more saggy pendulous breasts.
Oh guys.
You know what I'm going to do while
we're waiting for,
you know,
all kinds of fun and,
and I think the next video that Ethan's
going to pull up,
I'm going to go ahead and build a
skateboard.
Ooh.
That we're going to put up for auction,
but before we build it,
we're going to draw something on Joey.
Like,
should I buy like a 10 things to write
on Jelly?
Yeah,
I think so.
Can I?
I want to write 10 things to write on,
Joey.
That's six things here.
I'm trying to,
I'm trying to donate.
What?
Can you bring a tent?
Yeah,
of course.
If I donate $1,000,
can I draw a huge penis on Joey's face
where the balls are over his eyes and
the peanut.
I want Justin to do it,
but the balls are on his forehead and go
all the way.
Let me just send him in so you can ask
him.
All right guys.
So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna make a skateboard that I would
ride.
I don't know if you guys can see this is
signed by Paul Rodriguez at the top.
Can you see this real quick?
This is signed by Paul Rodriguez.
Rodriguez.
He's a fucking bad ass skate boarders.
Where the fuck have you been joe?
So Joe,
if I donate $1,000
can I have justin draw a huge penis on
your face where the balls are each above
and then all the way down?
Well,
you got a beard on though.
I would say do it for,
just do it.
Okay.
No,
no,
no.
I'm not doing anymore.
You know,
I always,
I was walking to the bedroom before and
I'm just walking around.
I'm like,
why the fuck is everyone looking at me?
Yeah,
no,
I go into the bed now.
I look in the mirror.
I'm like,
oh,
you're also dressed up.
I had that same thing.
When I see myself in the preview,
I'm like,
oh my God.
See this,
this $1,000
some people making some funny jokes
about how I look.
Oh yeah.
What are they saying?
Oh dear.
They call me like a cracked at Jesus.
Mr Jokes.
He make joke on me.
Dot.
How about that?
If I donate $1,000,
what's the funniest thing we can do to
joey?
Um,
can we paint your whole face black at
the sharpie?
Is faces already covered?
I mean there's,
there's not any room or where can I show
the grip tape?
I'm going to,
I'm going to put on this skateboard.
So cool.
That drifting.
Whoa,
whoa,
radical.
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
That's pretty tubular grip tape.
Oh my God.
That's going to go on this side of the
board.
So,
oops,
sorry.
It's going to be Bam,
right?
You can see her fucking and you're going
to whoa.
Whoa.
It's going to be morty.
And then I'm gonna,
I'm gonna also,
I'm going to do this board with risers
and some big fat 70 millimeter wheels,
and I'll build this today on building
skateboards.
Now I'm Dan.
Okay,
well,
I'm going to run to the bathroom.
I'm doing 1200 for the first drawing,
right?
So I'm gonna run to the bathroom and
then when we come back,
we're going to call a psychic.
Okay.
All right.
I love back in five minutes.
Um,
Ooh.
Shout out to not go away.
Where at 62,000
guys pull it together for Christ's sake,
but thank you to everybody that's
donated a,
yeah,
it just rolls off the tongue,
doesn't it like three and a half hours.
It was pretty well at that.
Shout out to the grandma's virginity
podcast.
Justin.
Ah,
you've got an old school dry Yang.
Oh eat.
Oh Ethan,
you asshole.
He should have left that dude up there
as the top donor.
I'm telling you he's,
he stole it man.
Well that means that means one of us.
Oh No,
no,
no.
That means the fans have to outdo you
ethan.
Like fucking knock him off.
And I was like someone looking for knock
him off his little pedestal not to
donate.
All right,
I'm getting drawn on me.
Uh,
I don't know if,
uh,
I think that was Ethan's brainchild.
Ethan's got to decide what exists on
your face.
It's up to him,
man.
Your face.
This is property,
unfortunately.
Yeah.
They,
uh,
people in the,
everyone donating.
Any suggestions for what I should do for
my next,
uh,
drawing dropping on me.
Let me know.
$1.
Just $1 to believe a comment.
It could be a,
it could be anything.
Got this tattoo.
Oh,
look at that little guy.
Peanut.
Should I be drawn one of those drawers?
Joe's showing me the Dick on his leg.
He's got a leg dick.
But um,
it was,
it has to be requested by the audience.
All right.
And you got to see what they're going to
ask for.
I just want a sweater.
I'm sorry.
Sad bear.
I can't give you a sweater,
but I was,
I was having a hard time donating.
I was just trying to donate right now.
It's just so hard.
I should like,
I shouldn't be like pointing my phone
towards the camera.
Entering my credit card number.
[inaudible] Santa Joey,
we got,
we got was popping.
You know,
we've got the dyngus
love you guys.
Hey,
every single person.
Look,
I know there's been a little bit of
negativity,
a little bit of like,
why don't you guys fucking donate more?
But Hey,
like literally every single person who
donated a dollar is like bureau.
Like every single dollar is going
straight to a good cause.
All of you guys would feel amazing hours
ago.
I'm almost 64 grand.
That's a lot of the money.
That's like a nice car.
Somebody keeps saying draw.
Ethan has post Malone,
but it's like all we have to do is keep
drawing on his face and he's like
[inaudible] he's getting there.
He's getting closer.
Just write like always tired.
Right?
Isn't that it on the,
on the eyelids.
Keep it up.
Proud of you.
Thank you.
Michelle Obama always tired too.
Fuck.
That's relatable,
right?
Lots of thick boys in this dream.
Wowza.
I don't know if that was,
I don't know if I can take that.
Yeah,
that's probably me.
I feel like I want to take the
compliment,
but I don't think I'm thinking of for
that.
Do you guys want to see me light myself
on fire for the next okay,
here.
$1 donations.
Yes.
$2 for no.
I know I kind of took the prime real
estate but you will,
you will.
You just,
right.
You want me to be some there Paul Paul
Rodriguez,
the skateboarder wrote it.
This is like,
this is like and then and then and then
when you just,
just,
just like somewhere in like the cold war
in like Zig Zag.
The foil.
Yeah,
the core foil.
I want to get Ethan to sign it.
Like everyone should sign it once,
once and then I,
then I'm going to fucking,
I'm going to like,
I'm going to literally build that.
That will be a full complete deck.
If I sign it you'll get devalued.
So yeah,
Joe,
you're not allowed to sign it.
Draw some cool shit.
This is a pretty great prize.
I think it is cause it's amazing.
We're all going to draw on this deck and
then I'm going to actually,
I'm going to,
I'm going to set this deck up.
The Wa like as like a deck that I would
ride.
Like this was sort of my,
you know,
preference.
Justin,
would you describe yourself risers?
Oh by the way,
keep in mind you're drawing,
right?
Well pads are going to be speaking out
the corner so like yeah,
he's peeking out of the corner so,
but I'll put the signature over there.
Yeah,
like keep drawing but go and draw mabel
like like right,
right here.
Probably just going to frame it as it
is.
I don't think they gonna ride.
No,
but it's going to come to them complete
with,
oh,
I'm going to build it.
I'm going to,
I'm going to build it all at school
full.
But they could take the trucks off and
then frame it if that's what they want
with the trucks were actually true.
We could,
here we go.
I'm putting some big fat fucking a 70
millimeter wheels on it and then eat and
this and this.
Amazing as the thing.
Which side do you frame?
What company is is?
Oh enjoy.
This is some good grip tape.
This is fucking great.
Better than just plain old.
Like flat,
flat black.
Yeah.
The Joan donations of slowed down.
I feel like we got to think of like a,
Hey,
donate in the goddamn money.
Think of like a sub one for a 65 until
we fucking just just burn the midnight
oil.
Just get some coffee man.
It's Tuesday.
Well what could we do to get more people
to your friends?
Tweet it to your very famous friends to
have like millions of followers just to
save way more famous friends and you do
but he's not going to bug them.
So you got a bug.
Your own famous friends grabbed some
famous friends for sure.
I have been sort of pinging be nudging,
pinging and nudging and then they like,
it's a gentle and then they like pop
into the feed and just see it's like
eating pizza and like dropping a pencil
on the ground.
Let's go.
Let's do it.
This is commitment man.
Sorry Ethan.
Will you do the graver phone call now?
Will you just sign right over here?
Keep in mind there's going to be,
there's going to be a riser pad right
here.
Right here.
So like right in this neighborhood and I
want Elo to sign somewhere like along
along the side here for credit card.
Put it in.
This is a tax write off because we were
doing a benefit for a church or a
church.
Whatever weird stuff you see we're doing
a charity event.
What have,
see by the way,
I'm
really sick today.
I'm taking you the,
let me list a total fucking trooper.
She woke up this morning like
sore throat,
not feeling good and by the way,
gargle some salt water and did it work?
Did it help a little bit?
Yeah.
Helps that.
You hear that ladies and gentlemen,
Garbo that salt.
We'll have my signature.
That's how I sign everything.
You asshole.
I actually like it.
That's great.
Okay,
so you look right here.
Okay.
Just anything you want.
Maybe even draw something cool.
Okay.
You can do it.
Portrait or landscape,
whatever you want it.
It's crazy that the president called in
earlier.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
I'm still like tripping out.
You know,
none of us expected.
I'm glad we hit,
you know,
I'd love to have him call back in,
but after I kind of think about
a few more things I'd like to ask,
right?
Yeah.
We kind of,
we missed some opportunities.
Crayola crayon color names.
That'd be a good one,
right?
Yeah.
I want to know what he thinks about like
polly pocket and mighty Max.
That whole war from the eighties you
know,
which one's better?
What's his opinion on these,
uh,
on these new rereleases of,
yeah,
the Shama Gotchas.
It's like,
you know,
why don't,
why do Japanese people get all the cool
Tamma got cheese?
You know,
I really do want to ask such a good
question.
Does he think that Amiibos gives an
unfair balanced,
I mean,
what's he going to do to prevent the
rise of ai in the form of Amoebas?
Amoebas is not fair.
Like Amoeba is.
Ain't ain't fair there too expansive.
All right.
Where are we literally gave some psychic
hotline.
Oh my God.
It says top donor $2,000
shredder.
Give me one more minute.
I'm getting us set up an account with
them.
I don't see that to me.
Why do I see that?
You got to refresh.
Maybe.
Maybe it's in your need to refresh and
there it is.
There we go.
Nope.
Draw Jesus eating.
Oh wait,
wait,
wait.
Who is that red or is someone that
someone here,
Lex Machina.
The higher that gets,
the more unlikely it's going to be that
it'll,
it'll be from like a real fan.
Most of that 75 just see that joey
salads eat that yummy little mugs.
Gummy.
All right.
We're going to call it an where we got
to get to that 75 you guys eat do it for
Ila for Christ's sake.
She's sick.
She,
she's pregnant.
Yeah,
she her.
He wants to sleep but she has had 25 no,
I'll stay,
but you list style.
It's already been five hours.
The dying to get out of here.
The crows dying.
I don't know if that's going to happen.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's going to happen.
Maybe we tell they get the call if we
get to 70 what is you been on with?
Shredder.
Oh,
that was you toes literally having such
a hard time like getting all the pieces
to work that I just dropped it.
I just drop it in the hard.
You were having a hard time bidding on
something.
Are you decided?
I just kept,
every time I kept selecting it kept like
popping off.
So tell [inaudible] was fucking you.
I mean,
I'm also an idiot,
so it might've been my,
you're not that dog ready?
You getting into anything?
Where are you being a cutie pie?
All right Dan,
how are we doing on the psychic draw?
A T rex surfing on a chainsaw.
Happies them 70,000
we call the psychic.
Yeah.
If we get to 70,000
just in really wants to prank calling a
psychic and maybe maybe it'll turn out
the psychic has like our future and like
maybe we'll actually learn something
like this in reuland.
We're Joe not humanity hangs in the
balance.
Oh,
Zach says he's on the phone right now.
I get it.
Less plus.
Okay.
Wow.
This is really fascinating stuff.
I didn't know you were into
skateboarding.
Justin.
What?
I didn't know you were into
skateboarding.
I just realize I need a fucking like a
box cutter style blade.
Do you skateboard,
Justin?
Really?
I'm not fucking out there and do.
Well you can create,
you can like,
you can roll your role.
When you were younger did you skateboard
like as its mode of transportation?
No kidding.
That's really pleasant.
I'm sure all the podcasts,
this nerves,
y'all put my mind towards that.
The only thing tops that is me chewing
into the mic.
Well,
I'm excited about this.
Uh,
uh,
people are saying isla go home girl.
Well we wish it was possible.
We're getting close to 67,000
yet cock suckers.
Anyone have a fucking,
I forgot to bring my little razor blade.
Like there's probably not a box cutter.
I can just take the blade out and just
going to shit.
I already got the grip tape on,
but how does it stay on there?
Did you glue it or something?
It doesn't load sticker.
Oh sticker.
And so you can see,
wow,
that's a CIC board.
Yeah,
that looks pretty awesome.
This grip tape and then the signature
and once I get the trucks and yeah,
I think,
I think this will be this,
this one's good.
That's a nice option.
And I think that's a nice build.
Would you say it's a pretty nice,
I'll call that a build,
right?
While we wait for that,
for that little razor blade.
Let's see what other fucking stuck in my
Dan and Sarah,
whoever's out there.
If you have a razor blade,
help help a brother out.
I haven't got a video.
I'm not sure I wanted to show it because
I love it so much that I wanted to save
it for a main channel,
but nobody's doing paying.
I'm paying attention,
but I'm not going to play it unless we
get 70,000.
We need to some hip hop Ila Ethan drop a
beat freestyle.
Oh yeah,
that's a,
that's a blast from the past.
Um,
Oh,
you know what?
I want it to reminisce a little bit.
I was,
I was thinking how did we raised last
year,
so much money.
And then I watched this clip back and I
was just,
I thought it was so wonderful.
So I want you to reminisce,
reminisce a little bit here.
I love so much.
Oh,
it's so well [inaudible] it's just
legendary I guess.
Like you really can't talk this right
since is Christmas morning.
So happy about it.
Just so fun.
Just amazing.
I'm like telling him there's so much
horrible for him.
I was like,
come on.
All right.
Who Do we have to dig up that,
that Pepsi versus bringing it back?
I mean,
it's dark.
When do we do it?
Last year,
what?
It was about September,
I think.
Oh,
so it was before the time changed.
Just yeah.
Or wait,
what was it was before?
Probably was 50 bucks from anonymous
ruins my life.
I hate it.
I was,
oh man.
Well,
we're only eight guys.
We are here.
We are ratcheting.
We're getting up there.
We're getting up there guys.
Hello.
We see you guys eat me.
Eat me up inside boys.
The um,
the psychic Dennis queuing that up.
Uh,
Zachary Ian.
Almost there you say scrambling.
Trying to set up is insane.
I love how they are like charging you by
the minute and they're like,
they're probably start right dude,
I just need a,
Oh,
we're getting some big donations.
Yeah,
I think it helps having,
having the donation wall up people.
Yeah.
You can see the name up there.
We read some of this.
Oh yeah,
we're,
we're the rolling in.
Thank you guys.
M nickel,
Katie.
She's almost ready for the next.
Excellent.
That's perfect guys.
75 k's a great,
that's,
that's nothing to be ashamed.
Yeah.
That's nothing to sneeze at.
That's just a lie.
Pepper.
Right.
Ready?
Let's get her in and play the next song.
I'm stoked.
What while we,
while we wait for,
shall I pull up some media?
No.
Well I mean,
I don't know.
I was going to say,
let's get onto you to go until so
awesome.
Should I save this video?
I mean people got this good shit.
We're going to get to the video.
People got to pay.
They want to watch this.
People got up there and do a God damn
monster.
I'm just saying,
I mean I'm giving up some good shit.
He's like a,
I need like a,
like a,
like a thin little like,
uh,
like I,
I gotta I gotta I gotta poke the holes
through right here.
I just got up.
I'm sure we've got some of,
I think,
is there anything in this chick?
Tell me,
how are you feeling right now?
As a matter of fact,
I don't know.
I wonder if I should go.
Do you want to lay down in the other
room?
Maybe bloody low.
Lay down dealers earned,
uh,
that check.
Okay.
Look sick.
Actually I don't know why but
back really hard because you're
pregnant.
I guess you've got like all this weight.
You never even get that jacket.
Looks fricking amazing.
Is that one coming out in January?
Oh my God.
I love the zipper and the yellow like a
cough.
I want it.
You got it?
Fine.
So why don't you go lay down in the
other room and I think we're gonna be
hitting 75 here pretty soon.
All right,
hold on guys.
You guys,
you two guys,
your that.
You too.
All right.
We'll keep it.
We'll keep it home and take care of.
All right,
let's do two new vibe.
This is the 70 5:00
AM we have all the sound stuff.
Every sound that you get.
Roll them.
Roll.
We've got whatever today about Munchkins
and I'm not talking about what you
think.
We're pressing all the buttons,
non offensive month type of Munchkin.
I do like this groaning crowd.
Whoa.
Oh,
oh,
hello.
Whoever's still watching this chaos.
Listen,
I'm just trying to build me a god Dang
skateboard deck and I'm just trying to
have a good time.
All right.
Can we get some,
let's see.
Yeah,
let's,
can we get some,
let's see.
Oh,
he's draw ethan doing the George.
Get Stan let Georgia state at the time.
Got me all right.
Sorry.
Sorry Lou Lou Lou hanging free.
All right.
I think I'm going to do that.
I think I'm good.
I am going to draw Ethan as George
Constanza.
I liked that.
Oh yeah.
That's a good,
that's a good,
when can we get a downward,
uh,
as he draws camera angle.
I don't think that camera exist.
That would be fun.
It's like an unboxing style camera.
Okay.
Tell him aussie hero nation.
The hockey song.
Yes.
Yeah,
we got the donations up.
Raiden renards they're,
they're right up there.
Let me clear,
you're clear this out of the way.
Oh,
thank you.
Hand that over to me.
Yes.
You're going to need that.
I've been requested.
Ethan's actually really hard.
Now this,
this deck is like,
all I need to do is cut the grip tape
off and then I can
move onto the next step.
Alex,
have you left the room since our
oh yeah.
Once.
We never lead the rule.
We've always been here and we will
always
be here.
No Shit.
Oh fuck.
Sorry.
I knew I forgot the fucking box.
Like the razor
blade.
I knew,
I forgot that.
I didn't know,
but I was like,
I know I'm going to forget something for
the skateboard.
I know it.
I mean it shouldn't.
How hard,
how long does it take to finish
something up like that?
You just have to cut it.
Right.
I got to do is turn it around and like
it's so easy to just cut that off line
and ran it down and then you're good.
And then,
then I can,
then I can do the rep really good one.
It's going to be,
by the way,
I'm going to build three decks.
That's awesome.
So,
and each in all three.
We're going to draw all over them.
It's going to be awesome.
Okay.
So guys,
we're getting close to that 75 I'm
impressed.
We're getting close.
So Dan,
um,
aussies about to sing,
so I'm going to just,
you tell me.
Oh yeah.
Turn the volume up on that because he
said this is way too quiet.
It was quiet
second.
Oh well hold on.
Can Can,
can no,
okay.
Okay.
Hang in here.
Hanging here.
Hanging in here.
Just,
just handling.
You can chill.
Yeah.
And by the way,
by the way,
w w wait
Dan,
well this Mike Pick Aussie up liquid.
Oh,
thank you.
You guys dance about the connect the
psychic.
He says it's $5 a minute.
Yeah,
just that like that you talked about,
even though he's had to do like 30
disclaimers I guess because like that
Miss Cleo,
there was like a huge lawsuit.
Oh,
we just had a $200 donation.
Guys,
if you're donating for like drawings and
shit,
we're about to do this prank call,
which is taken down like 30 minutes to
set up.
It's $5 a minute.
So Justin,
you just take the lead on this and not
like vodka,
ice or anything else like come on,
I need a linear Freud.
Sure.
Yeah,
it can.
Somebody just fly in a lacroix.
I'll get you some vodka and just some
ice.
This ice is this ice because Justin
taking the lead on the second.
Yeah.
Let me,
let me,
let me take the lead.
Okay.
I Fuck I had a good angle on it earlier,
but now I don't really know but
okay.
You Want Vodka and soda?
Vodka and Lacroix.
Okay.
But you've gotta be entertaining.
Right now.
Oh,
Karen,
Michelle.
Okay.
No,
no,
we've have,
we were,
we were trying,
hurry,
hurry eats it.
It takes you two seconds.
Just it's right there.
Grab,
grab.
Okay.
If you could somehow like grab a piece
of pizza for me to be off.
Of course you can.
Do you want Pepperoni or bedroom?
Alright.
Alright,
you're listening to the money.
raise.com
website show and we are live.
Hi.
Welcome to the live money raise.com
shock about,
let's talk about it.
I want to talk about how we might all be
living in a simulation.
Here's why.
Give me some evidence.
Every night you dream,
you'll wake up,
all that shit you believe in your dream.
And it wasn't real.
It was all a bunch of nonsense,
right?
You got me there.
I'm curious to me every night,
I'm like,
what?
Curiosity.
Oh my God,
I'm going to fucking magic a candy
house.
So Shit,
there's a witch there.
And uh,
um,
and Oh God.
Oh,
what was the one I had last night?
It was a,
okay.
Oh,
it was so fucking,
oh my God.
Well,
like my sister had like a coin,
uh,
like an old ancient dime.
Oh.
Like,
like,
uh,
like an old,
like,
like 19 or 18 hundreds dime,
which may not even exist.
And I was like,
oh,
I got to get that time from her,
cause it's haunted and it's causing
ghostbuster ghosts to appear and she has
no idea.
And you've got to stop.
She was evil and demonic and she was
like,
and I was hiding the diamond in a penny
or sorry,
I was hiding the dime in a fake.
A nickel.
Oh,
sorry.
We,
you're about to get on the phone.
I'd have to look royal.
It's coming.
So we're about to get,
we're about to get on the phone with
Roxy.
She's a clairvoyant and a dream
interpreter.
Okay.
So let,
let,
let them try to make this happen at the
talk.
I just want,
I'm sure.
Yeah.
Roxy,
roxy,
or just leave it here.
Most trustworthy name ever.
But anyway,
so yeah,
my sister,
but I'm headed to afraid that she'll
hear us.
So just,
I don't want you to be entertaining
anymore.
Okay.
So no more,
no more.
No more talking about my tragic hope.
Oh Shit.
It's happening.
We ate w ethan will you call and give me
a Red Lacroix Cup?
The red one.
Hurry.
It's right in the fridge.
Curry.
Okay.
Oh No,
the red one.
Oh,
fuck it.
I'll take whatever.
You know that she,
that's her.
Okay.
No,
I mean,
I kind of wanted the record.
It's in the fridge.
It's right there.
Don't complete the doors up in,
be quiet choosers.
Beggar's duck blow it.
You hear a long,
he's been on the phone with this fucking
roxy.
He's setting up a call with a psychic,
but they're charging is $5 a minute and
taking 30 minutes to get on the phone.
Thanks man.
I'm going to end up donating more to
them than I do it to the charity.
We're at 69,000.
Okay.
Then did you have this should,
this should be good.
Cause if you really appreciate this,
this psychic reading,
then uh,
just,
just throw that month.
Get Ready,
get ready.
Get ready.
Get ready to close the door.
Close the door.
Okay.
Where are we going to hear?
Dad Is.
Hello.
Oh,
dad's got to pull it to me when we're
already okay,
so coordinating.
Okay.
Dan,
everyone's really being really quiet and
Dan is on the phone recording.
No,
I am.
I have to.
No,
but I'm at 200 really sly way.
Don't trust me.
Our amps,
Roxie.
Roxanne recording so I can listen to it.
Okay.
Right.
All right.
Thank you.
Talking to Tom Tom,
so everyone's wiser right here.
My name's Dan.
Dan has coordinating.
He's about,
he's calm.
He had history with,
it's bad for your vocal cords to
Westbourne.
Oh,
uh,
July
Jesus Christ.
It's,
it's hard to give away your,
to a fucking
scam artists.
This is how she's asking.
What's his birthday?
Yeah.
Hello?
I can hear you.
Yeah.
How are you?
Hello,
how are you?
Okay.
Okay,
let me,
I'm good.
I just had a couple of questions.
Question number one,
thinking of opening to chucky cheese
franchise and I am just,
it's causing me a bunch of grief.
By the way.
I just want to let you know that I'm
recording this just for my own purse,
for my own playback.
I'm not even going to say personal,
but just from my own playback.
So this is important.
It's important because you know this
isn't,
this isn't a pennies we're talking
about.
This is,
you know,
this is,
this is the real mccoy.
So I can listen.
We can so we can all listen to this back
later and really get it all figured out.
So I'm trying to,
I'm thinking about open and um,
um,
e cheese.
Uh,
but really bringing it back to the old
school,
like awesome.
Animatronic,
that style,
you know,
chuck e cheese,
variety hour,
like the rock fire explosion style,
you know,
the,
the kids get called in.
Yeah,
I know exactly what you're talking
about.
So I'm thinking about doing that and I
have a little bit of money.
I'm going to get some loans and some
investments from friends and family and
I'm doing this in Bakersfield.
So,
you know,
I'm thinking,
I'm thinking it'll work.
I'm thinking it's going to work and I
just wanted to call and see what your
opinions are.
Do you think that this will fly?
Do you think that this will really,
this,
is this going to put the wind in my
financial sales?
Okay.
What I'm going to do is wrong with this.
I'm going to go straight to the cards.
I'm going to do a three card pull.
Let's see what we get.
Three Card Monte as they call it.
In my lap.
I gambled,
gambled all my money away last year.
So that's,
that's why I said that.
Okay.
Let's see what we get first cards and,
and by the way,
you might,
this could be an evaluation call,
this could be an evaluation call.
So just letting,
you know,
don't,
don't mess it up.
Are driving a brand salary like a
negative nancy,
but we're talking money in here and,
but we're also talking dreams.
Whoa.
Um,
I've got the through with tenable's
direct pedicles are known as the points
is fine.
So the Druid pinnacle direct,
is that what you said?
Okay.
I've tentacles direct.
I using the grandmom yet from the deck,
the Grumman Deck.
I'm just trying to like,
you're a bit,
it's a bit hard to hear,
but I'm,
I think I'm following you.
I know.
I think you've got me on speaker phone,
which is making a very fuzzy on my end
also.
Hold on.
Okay.
Can you hear me?
Yeah,
yeah,
I can.
Okay.
Is that better?
That's a little better.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Panicles
right.
When you look directly at finances,
my concern is the level,
um,
it's reading low.
Oh,
you like my finances are reading low.
Okay.
We're reading directly on the thought
process of starting this business,
doing the chuck e cheese investing.
Okay.
Chuck e cheese.
Are you saying I don't have enough coins
to do it?
Yeah.
Big,
big,
big money,
right?
Oh,
oh well that's quite an upset.
Yeah,
I mean,
you know,
you,
you know I,
I'm a big firm believer of of the chucky
cheese original model.
I'm like,
you know,
we might be living in a different time,
but I think where they went wrong was
when they started taking out the cool
animatronics and then they started
taking out all the fun,
weird,
creepy rooms with the flashing strobe
lights and all that kind of stuff.
As soon as they got rid of that stuff.
Yeah,
you're with me there.
Well at least we have some common ground
to build this.
Okay,
well see,
you know what I'm talking about.
So I'm ready to bring that back to
Bakersfield with a punch to the city,
right in the throat of the city.
I'm going to bring this thing back and
I'm going to,
and I think that,
so you're saying,
so the first card is the card of coins,
which could be good or bad,
right?
Tentacles
the three of pentacles
when you read directly.
Okay.
And so,
and three is that 3 million?
Is that 300 is it 3000 how many levels?
Like a hundred levels or 10 levels.
All right.
Oh,
okay.
So
I'm at a three
so you know,
I mean,
you know,
you look at it from a bitcoin
perspective,
it's like,
well,
if I had,
if I had bought $300 a bitcoin in 2009
or 2008 or if I bought $100 a bitcoin in
2008 so it was three versus 10 or sorry.
You know what I mean?
So it's not so bad.
Always a glass half full type.
I'm always a glass half full type.
Go ahead.
The next car is upon.
My other concern is the progress.
Well know my,
I hired my uncle and my cousin Dave,
they're out of work.
They need a job.
That's part of the reason why I'm doing
this,
uh,
to dress up as the mascots and to help
me oversee business and accounting and
financing and all that stuff.
So I'm pretty confident on that front.
What,
what is,
what's the,
what's the next card you got
the middle car represent the movement.
I'm a mover and a shaker.
Well,
it's incorporated with the numerology of
the five.
It represents change.
You said something about a crawl space,
like number one.
Oh,
sorry.
No
number one is the side of the mover and
a shaker and it's a crawl space kind of
scenario where it's like you're going to
have to crawl to get to your dream.
I never said that.
And let me tell you something.
I have crawl,
I cry.
I crawled 12,000
feet.
I think it was our 12 12,000
feet out of a tunnel just to escape from
a situation.
I'm not going to get into it.
Good.
All right.
Can you hear me?
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm sorry.
I can hear you.
So you think about a crawl space.
Oh,
okay.
Sorry about.
Okay.
So I must have misheard that.
So you said?
Yeah.
Wow.
I was explaining,
go ahead.
Oh,
I was at,
I was explaining the numerology.
Oh,
I'm looking at the flow of a business.
How is it going to flow?
I mean,
it flows,
you know what I mean?
It's just like with all the,
the,
just the relaxation and just
[inaudible].
You go with the flow and you put all
your heart and soul and effort and
energy
and you're not,
you're not understanding.
Oh,
but what I'm trying to,
I'm looking at it.
Are you thinking of it like a
psychedelic kind of a way?
Like,
um,
like,
uh,
okay.
No,
no.
Okay.
I'm okay.
I'm doing a business reading.
Okay.
Yes,
please.
Okay.
Hello.
This is ever going to be consistent.
Okay.
There's,
there's always going to be okay
downs and I'm ready for that big up.
Okay.
When we opened the doors that were
rolling in it,
buying our maseratis and all that stuff.
Okay.
This is where I've got to do this.
I'm not going to give you false hope on
this.
My advice to you would be they spend at
least the next six months doing some
major research possibly.
Oh Man.
Are you kidding me?
Demographic.
I'm going to cut you off right there
because I,
the last year,
last 12 months I've been doing major
research.
I watched a bunch of rocket fire
explosion videos on youtube.
I went to a bunch of chuck e cheeses.
I talked to the employees,
talk to some of the children there.
I watch.
I watch that one video.
Have you seen that video of the little
kid?
I can't help you.
No,
you're helping me.
This is incredible.
You are giving me,
you're giving me the fire.
I need to go achieve this situation
because we got a lease on the building.
I'm not going to give you false hope
when it comes to putting out a lot of
money,
but you know what though?
False hope.
A hope floats hope.
Okay,
tonight I'm ending the call.
I'm not going to give you false hope and
I don't want you to waste your money.
What about Bob Hope?
Would you give me a little Bob Hope?
Let me just hear it.
Everyone can do a good bob hope.
Okay.
$5 an hour.
You're going to turn that down.
$5 a minute.
I think we lost her.
Yo.
I have to say I'm depressed that she was
pretty honest later just to give you
good advice,
but like I said,
like it sounds like you're the
connection wise with money were no
longer being,
oh,
so she ended the call.
Maybe I noticed it in a way too still.
She was taking advantage of a man who
had gone bankrupt who crawled through it
now for some reason,
just think his life savings into it.
Chuck e cheese.
He was a decent lady.
Oh by the way,
no offense to chuck e cheese,
although I do think you've got to bring
back those animatronics was in the ball
pit.
Do you know what can we each do one of
those?
Oh man,
this,
yeah,
please.
Versus wait two hours to you.
I'll do one by the way,
by the way,
how much,
what was the total on that call?
How long?
What did that cost delight?
So the introductory rate is a dollar as
president and we can't,
we can't hear Dan.
Hold on.
There you go.
And so the introductory rate is a a a
dollar a minute.
Um,
but that's just for the first 30.
And then after that it's a $5 a fucking
minute for the first 30 minutes.
So right now that was only a dollar a
minute.
Oh,
okay.
So he,
she done shit.
How so?
How so what was that?
How many minutes was that?
Uh,
I think we had her on her about,
no,
it was less than that.
It was maybe 10.
Okay.
So hold on,
hold on.
Before we do that,
before we do that,
Aussie has the song cause it,
cause like people have paid for
something.
So hold on.
Is it,
that took so long.
Is it going to be easy to connect now or
should you were caught up?
Now we're ready to just throw money.
Right.
Can you just,
can you,
should you start working on that and
then Aussie will perform.
So we're working on what,
sorry,
we're on the next call because I want to
do one.
Oh,
you want him?
You want to call back?
Yeah.
Yeah,
we'll get,
I don't want to talk to Ron a callback.
It listens.
A roxy isn't like we're,
we're good guys.
We're almost a 75.
Come on.
Keep it calm.
And guys,
this is,
this is when the real fun starts.
Once we get to 75,
that's when it gets real wild and crazy.
Well,
if ozzy is ready to go,
I think we should probably do that.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Do that.
It's ready to go.
Okay.
All right.
So hold on.
Standby.
Let me make sure we get her audio setup.
Yup.
And ethical.
What's so for watch,
her vocation is,
was so sweet.
Are Ripping people off.
Yeah.
She's like,
I can't,
she ended the call.
Faith I'm going to do,
I think she may be really believes those
cards because she looked like don't do
it.
It's not going to work.
And he's just like,
oh.
She's like,
Oh fuck what have I.
Oh wow.
Hey good.
Maybe to her it's not,
it's maybe I should,
uh,
maybe so much take [inaudible] home.
Save her.
Oof.
I think so as,
as Dan,
is that is that is,
that sounded good.
You let,
do you want to go home?
They look,
yeah,
it looks a whole lot.
Let me,
uh,
it's,
it's this Mike,
so,
yeah,
it's it there.
You don't even like that.
I don't know.
I think,
I think it's gotta be sort of like both,
just it again.
Yeah,
go ahead.
Okay.
That looks okay.
All right.
And by the way,
let us know if the audio sucks for the
music.
Will keep adjusting.
We're,
we're figuring.
All right.
Uh,
whenever you're ready.
Yeah.
Close the door and we'll,
we'll,
we'll dive in.
All right.
You Ready?
Here we go.
What is the song?
Could you tell us?
Okay,
cool.
Yeah.
All right.
MMM.
No.
Oh,
I take much.
Some stuff.
Uh,
maybe.
Huh?
She was like,
I'm just,
Oh man.
Smile.
Okay.
Oh,
it seems,
I don't know,
but somebody who did,
Dan who pay,
who,
what is a song called and who paid for
it?
Like if super familiar for me.
Now the song definitely far away by
black field.
It's called a far away by black field.
And that was a request from a Jack O v
Daily.
So thank you very much for the $200 Jack
be daily.
All right,
so we're gonna let Aussie go out and
learn.
Learn Song three.
So Isla I want to say first of all,
I want to say a couple things.
First of all,
Isla is going home.
She's not feeling well.
She's a soldier.
She made it all the way to 70,000
and that is,
Hey,
we're at 70,000
by the way,
and we are inching our way.
I heard that,
uh,
some people were unable to donate
through the website for some reason,
so thank you to everyone that's stuck
through the frustration of trying to
donate.
Yeah,
no wonder it's a,
it's an issue with mobile.
So yeah.
Yeah.
We looked at some tweets and I people
that are tracking is what I was going
through.
Yeah.
So I'm,
I'm reaching out to tilt by and I'm like
Ethan said we are keeping this open for
a week at least.
I think you should double that because
just for,
yeah,
for the fact that we've had issues
because we would,
we would be at a hundred right now if it
weren't for it.
Cause I think easily,
I feel like I feel like 90% of the
people are on there.
Well maybe that's not true but I would
be,
most people are on their phones.
Even if I was watching it on,
on my,
at home,
on my laptop,
I would be trying to donate on my phone.
Yeah,
100% for sure.
If you guys keep trying.
Thank you so much.
And also I do want to say to all the
people giving one,
two,
three,
four,
$5 how much we,
that all makes it dead.
Still Matters.
Yeah.
We appreciate it.
You fucking don't listen to cheat by the
way.
I also want to stay,
you know,
last year we did this in September but
this is right before Christmas.
People have already tapped their bank
account,
you know,
oh,
everyone is big in super deep and
helping us raise,
we've already at 70,000
in just fricking
incredible.
You guys are so selfless and so amazing.
That's a ton of money we've already
raised for charity.
So everybody who keeps trying,
everybody who has donated from $1 even
and beyond.
I thank you all so much.
Every,
I mean it really,
it's all money man.
It all matters.
So thank you guys so much.
And we're so close.
So
close to that 75 baby.
I can taste it.
Yeah,
we're going to get there.
So I don't want to,
I say,
I say we do it.
I say we stick with it and um,
you know,
I know Ilos gone,
but that just paints a different,
weird vibe to the,
it's weird to the,
it's all weird.
No,
I want to call a psychic.
Can you get me on the phone with another
sec?
Let's let Ethan to have some fun with
the site.
I kind of liked how you were like,
I'm going to record this call.
That was Kinda,
I feel,
I feel like,
I feel like it's also their mice of laws
you and it's like,
oh,
that's a genius move.
Just say,
listen,
I'm recording this for later.
Just say that just so I'm recording this
for my,
uh,
for for later.
Yeah.
Case I needed it.
You know,
just say I'm recording this for later
period,
so see I'm recording this now.
Yeah.
Just say,
listen,
I'm recording this.
It's important to me to have this.
Yeah.
I will see you say,
yeah,
I'm recording this,
but I just,
I want to,
I do want to pause it.
If anyone thought that we didn't value
the $1 and everything,
dude,
it all of that money,
look at a 70,300
can we get a shot of Joey Salads sitting
board on the coast?
I don't know if he can hear us,
but he's just that poor guy.
He's waiting.
We're showing her what alleged,
so I'm going to tell you this milk,
it's been here since about three o'clock
this afternoon.
It's starting to smell guys.
We've been going now I want to say for
five and a half hours.
That's commitment.
I think there's some commitment in this
room.
There's commit in this room.
I have to say 70,000
bucks.
That's fucking fantastic.
That's pretty fucking him.
All things considered when we haven't
even like,
you know when the whole tally closes and
win all the prizes,
all things considered,
you guys,
we should all feel very proud and happy.
We've accomplished a lot and I want to
thank everyone back there.
They've all day.
You don't see the guys in back get a
shot at them.
Dan Pest,
let's,
let me,
let me see what's going on back there.
I want to thank everyone who's Isla just
slept with her brother.
He was here all day.
Bless his soul.
But we've got Ian live switching.
We've got uh,
Zach on sound.
Hit us with one of those soundbites.
Sac.
There it is.
That's there ma'am.
We've got Dan show yourself,
Dan.
There he is the legend,
this word.
And we've got a Mitchell here who helps
us with research.
He's given us a hand.
Mitchell.
God bless him and Sarah,
the legend,
the xl wizard.
She is the incredible love.
Sarah,
thank you so much for your help,
the gang.
We couldn't do it without them.
It's a whole operation.
Really.
What we've got going on here.
I'm very happy.
I love the people that that we work
with.
I mean,
it's incredible.
It wouldn't be,
wouldn't be this without them.
Those guys are back there grinding man,
so thank them.
Thank.
Thank you to them so much.
This is it.
This is beautiful.
This is a Christmas miracle we're get,
we're inching closer every second.
Yeah,
man,
we're almost there.
Somebody has the novel idea in the
Aussie songs.
That's wonderful.
If she could just,
she hasn't,
she hasn't played these songs before and
just like not even heard of them.
She'd be like,
just went out.
Listen to her once on her phone.
Man Powers.
It's crazy.
She's,
she doesn't realize how talented she is.
Hey,
by the way,
I got a new original piece of art.
Oh my God.
What?
How long we would have full
that we're going to put up for auction.
Just want to love and be loved.
Accept me for who I am.
Here.
Let me,
she can let me get a nice plus guys get
this damn.
We should be,
um,
throughout the week just tweeting like
all the,
all of us,
our work with a link to the donate page.
Me That's going to be raffled off.
So you know,
let's get it one.
It,
should I color it?
Fuck yeah,
sure.
I coloring is like my most,
my least favorite part of it.
It all depends though.
I was asked to draft Freddy Freaker.
Do you know Freddy Freaker?
Do you know?
That's fucking wait,
you've never seen Freddie freaker
before?
Neither of you guys know what Freddy
freakers.
Oh,
you got to pull this up.
It only takes two seconds to watch.
This is just the weirdest fucking video.
So like,
and I'm lining up another second.
Great.
Now by the way,
the other a face tat core request I saw.
Oh hundreds.
We'll take a look at that as well.
Alrighty.
Is there a way to give Sarah access so
she can just what?
I know she's,
she's been filling it out.
In other words were,
you know,
we got a couple of cake,
right?
Uh,
Freddy free.
Let me set this up.
So Freddy Freaker.
Oh Wow.
Look at this.
This is kind of creepy.
Yeah,
there used to be Justin,
you've never seen this thing before.
Wait,
wait,
hit pause.
A pause.
I just wanna I just wanna explain like
in the fucking,
like what?
Like late,
late eighties maybe like they,
you know,
they would do these like phone sex.
Sure they had that.
But also they were like anything we can
do boggling.
It's like call them any,
exactly.
You'd be like,
talk to the fucking toy.
I bought it with the garbage pail
grants.
Right.
And so they were just,
they kept making these up and this,
this one was very brief.
Like it only existed briefly as one of
these and people saw it like at two in
the morning and they thought like,
was I hallucinating?
Because it's not clear what they're
advertising or trying to sell.
And then it was just gone.
And until the Internet,
like a lot of people out there,
we're just like,
I think I was losing my mind.
All right,
let's,
let's watch the free phone.
All my fucking,
wow.
You nailed it.
By the way,
by the way,
I was looking at some references and a
little greener.
But is there,
what's that?
A person with a fingers.
Listen,
the sweet song,
why do you,
why are you calling?
What are you calling for?
This exists now wound up Chicago.
All these curious.
Yes.
$2 car and
then he disappears.
Yeah.
That's pretty freaky.
And that's all you know.
So is it just a goof too.
Dot.
They're really trying to get people to
call to talk to Freddy Freaker and what
they're promising is,
uh,
it's the free phone.
He's the party freak.
Freddie freaker across the nation.
He's a sensation.
Call now.
$2.
All this is a drug only information.
Like a message.
Like there's no one else cause it's $2
per call.
So they probably just play your
prerecorded.
Hey there.
Welcome to the freak zone.
We'll come to the party.
Yeah,
it's fucking pretty cute.
Let me talk to her.
Just some pervy guy who calls himself
Freddy Freaker.
But what if he tells you where the
hotspots are to buy drugs?
He's,
it's like a,
the the,
the Alex Jones voice.
Someone said,
I've got,
now let me tell you,
uh,
now,
Freddy Freaker a lot of people.
Good.
Not a lot of people say that.
Fray.
The freaker is the life of the party
now.
He now freddy barely takes enough
happens to me when I do the record here.
Maybe that the rep boy impression or
not.
I can't cook.
He does cough.
A fair amount.
Alex Jones.
Yeah.
Every now and then there's a free
course,
a Goblin.
Goblin blood.
What's up Joey?
Joey.
Now Joey have a seat here because Joey
Salads here.
He's a good man.
Now he,
we're tattooing on him,
but really what's in this tattoo is
going to turn.
It's going to make your penis small and
that's why you need to be taking on.
Oh,
well joey letting out the globalist will
happen.
Don't be shy.
We're going to get your butthole ripped
out out.
Joe got Corn is not joe.
We've got a supplement here.
It's made of,
uh,
what,
what we do is we grind up kidney stones
made from about Korean baby fortune.
And what you do is you take that and it
lifts your testosterone levels so high
that basically your penis are going to
blast out of your pants like a rocket to
the moon.
Man,
I never actually went into the movement.
This will make your penis.
Well Kayla goober bake that for the
resident of this guy.
That's the best impression in the room.
Sorry,
the keys to just,
uh,
you know,
just lit up really badly.
Now.
What did he say about the church?
But you got something to write it up.
Don't be shy now destroyed the child.
Don't be shy.
Bot Mitchell's looking real good over
there now,
but look,
I'm real fine or whatever that do I
needed to grant,
uh,
that was me or no,
that wasn't you.
That was Alex.
Yeah.
Shredder or I mean shredder,
frankly speaking now that was Freddie
freaker.
Now,
now,
now the coastal liberals will have you
believe that?
Uh No joey,
why are you laughing?
Because you know now Joey,
cause Alex Jones is hilarious.
Not hilarious.
This is serious and I know I'm trying to
warm the people.
I put it in a humble [inaudible] of him
up just doing the,
you don't need a copulation sorry.
I like the one person who asks for
Freddy.
Freaker is definitely not going to see
that this drawing is there.
I just love that this is,
this is in there for the one person
who's heard of this thing.
I would have sworn that you guys would
know what that is.
I never heard.
It's so fucking weird.
And there's like a puppet tier guy who
like look on reddit explaining like,
oh I'm the one who designed pretty
frequent.
I don't know why.
Like the people who paid me,
they never do
told me what it was.
It was a device by liberals to brainwash
the kids you call a bop to party.
But what they're actually doing is that
they're whispering this liberal messages
from another dimension.
Right.
And they're company in your ear and what
is just doing as a target?
Neat.
Our kids,
transsexual.
Okay.
And kids are chopping off their penises.
They're tucking.
The penis is in there growing vaginas
and it's all Freddie Freaker is,
is spreading subliminal messages.
You know,
I know Hillary Clinton frog and it's not
furby greater this monstrosity.
Oh,
knows he's on campuses.
He's destroying free speech.
He just wants people to call the free
catiline.
Frankly,
he sounds like a cool guy.
Oh,
you call that fruit hotline?
Oh my God.
Joey,
what was getting sick?
This is gone sexual,
I mean need is back to,
yeah.
Can we show that we are really backed up
on writing.
We've got to stay on top of this.
We need to be a character limit because
it's like the writing full paragraphs.
Yeah.
Well whatever it is,
it actually that it expired at eight
o'clock so we're getting caught up right
here.
Yeah.
I keep catching up full guys where it's
71,500
we had a big donate.
I can connect you guys with a psychic in
just a second.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Let let,
give me the background.
Give me the background.
This is Taja is her name.
It's the same lady.
Probably it might be.
All right.
I'll connect you in a second.
So standby.
Be Ready.
So much trouble.
Sorry.
Hello.
Is this tolerance?
Yep.
Hi.
Stand by him not to get your title.
Thank you for all the donations.
We are really surging.
Hey,
we can't wait for y'all to keep donating
and really hit,
hit.
Hit this donation.
Mcnugget it's connecting.
It's connecting.
Okay,
hold on.
well you want to hit that donation?
Make Nugget.
And by being nugget,
I mean 75 a hundred
sorry.
So we are waiting for Dan to connect us.
He told us it's connecting,
but nothing's happening.
Okay.
What is it takes so fucking long for
these cause they charged by the matthew.
These psychics.
It's like they're taking your $5 a
minute.
She talks super slow.
Did you notice till he,
didn't he do it to
weed out people like us?
People like us or like they're listening
on our money,
right?
That's what I'm saying.
What do they care if they're getting
pranked?
Yeah.
Oh,
Alex is trying,
Justin.
In all seriousness.
I really do want to do one of these
where it's like super,
super real dance and let's,
let's,
let's be a total ernest,
do your bit and then,
and then out should do a bit and then
one more where,
let me do one where it's like,
yeah,
super serious and like see how,
how close they are.
I think,
I think you guys blew it.
I was trying to get you to be quiet.
She,
it was ringing and she heard you.
I never heard the colgate connect yet,
but I know but she said hello and I
connected it and you guys were in the
midst of saying these fucking psychic,
well let's get another one on the far
right.
I'll work on another one.
When I say it's going to come,
we got it.
We got to just stand by for a second
cause they,
that she will be coming.
Dan,
can you just pipe in on your mic and
just say,
all right,
I'm about to connect just so we know to
shut the fuck up.
Oh he did.
But it was like we had like a couple of
minutes of silence but no,
but it's got a ring on it be like right,
okay.
It's,
it starts ringing and so any moments you
might pick up.
Got It.
Okay.
Theoretically it was a different one.
I think these probably work for me.
Yeah.
So it probably got to be some lady.
God bless and God bless him.
What,
what,
what?
I will try,
I will try a different lady because uh,
because we blew our cover on that one.
Dang it.
I was sorry that was my bad
fault.
I'll take the full responsible blame for
that
guys.
We are nearing on 72,000
we are surging more.
Is there any face,
whoa.
Let me get a close up that this one is
amazing.
So this one's for all you folks out
there that are,
you know,
just want to supply.
That looks awesome.
I want to support you want to support
the right side of the debate.
Do you want to be on the right side of
history here?
I love that.
It's pretty much no matter who he,
who buys a lumps on the right side of
the debate.
I'm a fan.
I'm a fan of,
of creating art.
That is that either side,
that either side could get behind and
go,
you know what works for me and listening
to the audio.
And if you are,
and you've made it this deep,
I don't know how that's possible,
but he's drawn a man with the,
let's see,
excuse me,
a man sit,
oh,
sorry.
It creatures.
Creature person.
Creature Tuesday living being with the,
how dare you sits t six tits in three
penises and vaginas.
A human being.
That's a very sad would you feel man,
that's offensive.
It's a thing.
It's a thing is intense.
You person being joey,
let's throw this off.
Uh,
on the uh,
oh,
what's left when somebody gets an
auction block.
All right.
Work,
work,
work raffle.
This pie.
Draw this kind of shit ever.
I literally not been drawing lately
at all.
This is all I do is coming out here.
I want to get a tattoo.
Oh,
Ooh.
You drawer it can,
can,
can somebody bring in the ink,
the ink box?
Free hands.
Cause I'll give joey it's right now.
Oh yeah.
Right now I want to,
we had to make a goal for that.
Okay,
well you realize it only lasts for 18
days,
right?
What kind of tech is it's called flux.
Yeah.
Grabbing box.
So it's a,
it's a,
it's a one,
a real talented.
This is 18 days.
So this is basically like,
I will draw it on you.
Not My thing.
Why not?
It's 18 Christmas dinner with my family
on my face right now.
18 minutes here.
Let me see.
By the way,
I want to show,
I should probably,
this is a good time to show all of our
backer or all the people that are that
are the backers.
The fuck the back.
Hold on.
Hold on there.
There there's,
there's two.
Oh wait,
where is it?
Nice surge.
You guys keep it up with the donations.
You guys are crushing it.
Almost a 72,000
thank you to everybody who's dropping
big donations right now.
We've got 20 half.
We got one of these.
We got fives.
We got ones.
You Boy Jack.
Yeah.
Boy.
Jack,
don't get 89 really not put any 50
bucks.
Thank you so much.
Hey,
uh,
I got one.
I got it.
Okay.
All right,
so here.
Standby.
Everyone.
Shut the fuck up.
20.
All right.
Standby.
Connect connector and a second.
Abigail.
Hello.
Have so much shit.
This is Abigail.
All right,
I got the whole music.
So standby.
Hey Dan,
can you get me a razor blade while we
wait fucking kill you.
Super important just to stop.
You Rolling.
District can connect at any moment too.
Careful Abigail.
Sweet Abigail.
Okay.
That's very flattering.
What she hung up or they onto us.
Can you,
can you block your number?
Why is this 1-800-FUCKING psychic.com
go to a different one.
Why do they care?
I Dunno.
Good.
I know we're paying.
No,
no.
Go to a different psychic.com
number.
Hey guys,
look,
I just want to show some of these custom
inkbox hang up right here.
Flip,
flip.
I think she's just changing her name
every time.
One person Mac thing.
That's pretty cool.
Yeah.
Right.
So what do you put it on me?
I don't think it's,
I don't think if I give $1,000,
you could just sharpie your whole face.
Black.
Can anyone to see this mean black face,
black face,
sharpie face.
Oh,
you don't show it on yours.
So what,
what this,
what that is,
is that,
that that's a,
that's a,
um,
that's a tattoo that you can put on
yourself and it'll last for 18 days.
Um,
and it's a kit.
And so,
and we have it,
we have a fucking ton of them and
they're all rick and morty custom lunch,
a different cool rick and morty ones.
And so this is part of the,
um,
this is all part of the,
the incredible inkbox raffle.
We're going to pick 3000 more,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight winners that have this actually
eight,
10 winners out of this.
So buck onto your little 3000 more guys.
We are so close to relieving us of our,
uh,
suffering here over,
although joey will just be entering.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I swear to God,
can you ask the team out there?
Was there any other baggies like this in
this box?
So if you guys,
Roger that is,
do we have any more of this?
No.
Yeah,
I think there was just that one and then
a bunch of the,
uh,
by the way,
for those watching.
So we're going to hit 75 k tonight.
We're 3000 away.
Joey's going to eat one ghost pepper.
Hey,
if we hit a hundred joy ablate the super
hot pepper and I will give him a free
hand ink.
Well,
short of somebody dropping a box to pull
last 18 days and he'll take a photo of
it tomorrow.
You know,
he's getting signed up for all this shit
and he'll,
and he'll show it.
This is,
this is,
this is the lead.
This is like a pretty mellow,
like,
cool.
I'll do like a hi people at h.
Dot.
I'll do a cool one.
Would you let me do a swastika?
Still just be a bunch of dis for 10
days.
18 days.
Hell,
it's just going to be a bunch of dicks.
That's,
but anyway,
so we're going to hit a hundred what?
The vod,
so joey's going to do one of these.
When we hit 75 he's going to take this
bag of Carolina reapers with him through
the airport and while on the plane.
Ooh.
Would you do that on the plane?
Oh my God,
Joey.
Oh Dude,
you better not that my book.
That might be,
that might be too dangerous because
Andrew's,
yeah.
Yeah.
Don't,
don't,
don't do when you're in the fucking,
you're in the air,
the pool full of milk,
wherever you do this.
That's very important.
At the time of your choosing,
we are going to give you this whole last
hour,
it's going to record himself and send it
to us so that we could on Friday when we
did the recap on,
enjoyed the video of joey
living,
living up to his,
his honorable name.
He's an honor.
I'm going to do some try to live up to
it.
We're searching.
We're searching things.
You all come on.
Thank you.
How about we're getting there.
We're getting there.
We're getting close,
strong guys talking right now to see if
there's any last plop that money hours I
one or two songs.
All I want us to talk to a psychic man.
Do you want me to try it one more time?
Try it one more time Dan.
Try the other.
We are the,
they give us to this one more time.
Getting set up with the psychic thing.
I can't even tell you how crazy it was.
It was,
it was a 30 minute process and I bet,
and I bet you the reason for that is
because the second they realize they're
being fucked with,
they have the ability through that
process to completely block you or,
or just like cut you off.
Right.
And I played it really cool when I was
signing up.
I just,
he played at night so cool.
So I think we might've blown what it's
just been justin like yelling at the
time like got my box.
So Cy,
the way,
Ari,
I read your message.
Thank you so much for the donation.
God bless you know m and?
M?
Yes.
Weird Al's hairs.
Very good work or good work are also,
I'm still doing drawing requests,
so people,
if you want to draw in the crest,
donate what justin like Doug,
funny world.
You got to,
it looks a little like a doug.
Like,
yeah,
a nineties Nickelodeon for 100 bucks I
will definitely draw anything,
but if you just want to make a request
for,
you know,
a dollar five I might do it.
If I feel like it,
Ethan needs to dance bucks more for
that.
I just want to talk to a psychic man.
Yeah,
I mean I'm really surprised that it's
that hard to get ahold of them.
I'm surprised that they hang up on you.
It's like if you're a psychic,
your phone's not ringing off the hook.
You should be really excited.
Just let me fuck with you,
dude.
That lady could have still been on the
line still getting those $5 every
minute.
They don't care about the money.
They're dedicated and given people
there.
You think it's all about the real big
beat.
I'm starting to maybe think that list
based on that.
That last girl was like,
I don't want to waste your money.
I'm hanging,
you know,
which is crazy.
I was blown away.
I don't want to waste your money is mind
blowing to me.
Let me tell you about these psychics
sub.
A lot of people think that they're fake,
but every single one of them is real
man.
Break it and consulted board parker
brothers,
they are part of the Illuminati.
Destroyed the child.
Can't do that.
I kept you the super deep.
That's the hardest to do.
How does anyone do a voice that deep
destroyed the child has an incredible
voice.
He does have an amazing,
beautiful voice.
If he wasn't like a horrible,
I think he once said that he was,
he got a lot of offers to do trailers
for movies.
Oh,
interesting.
Thank you Alex.
In a world
where you're writing them as cabin side
pizza,
one man,
where is at Mr Beast.
I know.
Where's Mr Base?
We need to sponsor us.
You stick boy.
I think that's really,
really inspiring that they would ask for
that.
I,
if somebody donates $250 all dance to a
song of their request,
I feel like I'm on a strip club.
How about that?
Sort of weird like it's the purple
couch.
No,
no,
no.
It's the,
uh,
oh,
you want me to dance for you?
I need 250 bucks.
What?
I mean,
not,
not that,
but maybe script strip club.
Right.
It's like,
well shit.
I will show my Dick for $1,000
right now alive.
I will pay $1,000
for him not to show his Dick.
I will,
I will pay you have it.
Thanks.
All right,
Alex already in for three.
Tallakson Justin,
if you both don't donate a thousand
each.
I'm going to show my peanuts show,
show,
show.
You're a little peep.
Congrats on the pregnancy healer.
Alright.
Yeah.
If he's not here,
but I'll take it a little later.
Congratulations.
Good for you.
Heela alright,
here.
Hildago as they say,
Oh,
do you want to bring out a thousand
dollar donation?
Okay.
A friend of a mutual friend of ours,
uh,
clothes.
He wants to see your Dick fucking dope.
Yeah.
If you're willing to beat the top donor
for God.
Um,
Shane Gill from,
did you know gaming?
Thank you so much.
We're so close,
Shane.
That was amazing.
Oh my God.
Was the floats.
Y'All want to do it?
And you went here.
You went here.
Oh,
oh,
oh.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
Gotcha to
beat.
Wow Shango.
It,
you walked me out.
Honestly,
I feel like that was kind of the
highlight of the stream,
man.
That's pretty exciting to work.
Fuck am I?
Wow.
That's amazing.
Like a Shitty,
this goddamn came through big.
Woke my ass up.
Yeah,
you got your second wind.
You ready for the next 10 hours?
I'd go,
dude,
it would take us to get to a hundred.
We just need 1,301
you guys,
this is stuff we're close.
This
is the worst fuck I need.
Like a regular fucking,
oh man.
Two 50 someone just gave a hundred.
What does this mean?
That means you're going to dance.
Oh,
that's Alex to 50 I'll dance to any song
you want it to 50 he'll dance to it.
Although it's gone.
They can't play soccer.
Yeah.
What are the rules you'll get?
Dude,
we're surging big time.
Anonymous.
Yo,
we getting,
do we have any writings to do,
cause I see big donations here.
That's a great question.
Let's see.
Uh,
no,
I just checked and uh,
we're,
we're up to date.
This is just your love coming in,
right?
How are we getting on a queue for
another psychic?
Uh,
I was about to call them and then you
started dancing and I had,
so let me them on the line please.
The Blue Raspberry is when washing for
four hours.
Ethan's left cheek is still undrawn
upon.
That's prime.
Realize the stream.
Adobe premiere settings.
Oh wait,
was it this?
I'm tripping balls.
Wait,
was that a adobe premiere?
Danner.
My tripping.
You're tripping.
Yeah,
I've been,
I've been spending too much time on
adobe premiere.
I thought it was like,
Hey,
I just want to let everyone know I'm
cutting.
I'm cutting this cutting 74.
Oh guys,
we're still fucking clue.
We are 1000 away.
You want to know what this is from?
It's like my favorite video of the year.
What is that from?
It's a new meme that's just taking the
world by storm.
I was wondering why someone chose to
draw that on me.
Yeah.
Let me show you guys.
You just wash it.
Good.
Yeah.
I won't even say anything.
Just watch it
does.
This takes place in a store.
Then I met.
Oh yeah.
Fuck that shit up.
No,
Sarah Nigga,
Nigga.
Right now I want to hit this guy for
real.
You just roll this guy to convenience
stores and just like he's still going?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
He just started giving you put him in
the bag.
Just most like the primary emotion you
feel when you see this is all about a
game.
I'm going to make way too early to talk
with the squatch games,
but I'm telling you watch games is going
to come to the table with the game.
That is this.
How can you briefly two bags and the guy
said family to put the come and gee,
you got to see that Uno game.
I'm like the police coming G.
Yeah,
the police coming homie.
That's your game.
It is still knowing.
Fill that bag up.
I was trying to rob at bag.
You can just pick him up,
pick him and thought he was saying
something completely different right
now.
All these coming,
come on.
Come on please.
Just trying to help this guy.
He just refuses to get help.
Oh my God.
Wow.
He's still going.
What's the aftermath of it all starts
and ends.
They want video sitting here when you
got it.
Everybody to attention the best takedown
ever.
I'm just struggling here with these.
I feel like you're going to cut your
thumb off.
Don't cut yourself now justin,
do we have an update on the psychic?
Huh?
I'm calling.
I'm trying to get one on one with Dan.
I mean Dan for credit.
Yeah,
I'm working on it.
All right,
so thank you Dan.
Here's the take down of the century.
You tripping on me.
I love the mess he made that there
wasn't any exertion.
Man.
This nigga eat the mic
so tender.
Just tenderly.
Sweetest man.
Ever.
Just wear it.
Little kids were like almost,
oh my God,
guys were so close.
500 away.
You're away.
Somebody said Dash 83 I think we want to
see that.
All right.
I'm on that theme.
I'm going to run to the bathroom since
they're going to hit it.
Yep.
Now's a good time.
Just kidding.
Yeah.
Gotcha.
I think good donation,
man.
Thank y'all.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Awesome.
All right,
look,
thank you for the donation.
Did we miss anything?
A,
a quick shot over here?
Uh,
I just want to show at the grip tape on
who we're good.
All right.
I got the,
I got the a beautiful board.
Yeah,
that's doodled all over this board.
Now I'm going to put the trucks and
wheels on and we purchased.
We are so close.
This is going to be,
and then I have another board I want to
make.
I want to put together,
but you know,
whatever is here.
Did we miss any big ones or Dan want to
make sure we didn't miss any cause as we
look away,
I haven't exhausted either.
You're a champion.
I need needed to do it.
Then I need to get putting this together
for dancing on like the 10th hour of
this thing.
Male sex.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Lucas' name.
Do you want to talk to Lucas?
Standby.
Okay.
It looks like we're going to hit this.
Well we get on the phone with Lucas.
That'll be a special moment.
We got to keep it quiet.
Justin,
please don't mess this up.
He's in a mess is literally got like one
minute.
I got to wait for his voice message,
Dan and then I'll get them in as this
lucas.
Hello Lucas.
I got a problem because I have a
problem.
Hey look,
my name's Lucas.
I'm afraid that the water to be gay.
All right.
Lucas is on his way.
Justin.
Okay.
Hello Lucas.
By the way guys,
I'm just showing that I'm using crux
trucks.
Now's not the time.
I don't even know why.
Be Silent.
No,
no,
I'm just kidding.
This sounds like it.
Stop,
stop.
Stop.
Can Be connected anymore.
Piano music reminds me of Sims to or
simple one.
Psychic readings may be recorded for
quality assurance.
Do you and your connection at anytime
you allowed to legally,
you are now connected.
Hello.
How may I help you?
Hi Lucas.
How are you brother?
I'm fine.
How are you?
Let me ask you how,
what's your a spread,
you know,
are you good with dreams?
Do you know how to analyze dreams?
I had a doozy.
Well,
where do I begin?
Oh,
just by telling me about the injury.
Okay.
And or asking whatever questions you
have.
Okay.
Well I,
myself,
I'm about 65 and my pappy passed when I
was still around,
uh,
12.
So it's been a long time since I've seen
my pappy,
but I'm what was visited in my dreams
last night by my pappy and uh,
it's a strange one.
So bear with me.
It's a little embarrassing.
So I hope you forgive me.
Um,
okay.
Well my back while I was sleeping in my
bed,
I was a little boy and my pappy come in
my room.
Yeah.
And he lifted the blanket and say more.
He said,
Ma,
ma,
little johnny,
that's my name,
Jonathan.
He called me little johnny.
He says,
well,
a little Jonathan.
I had peed the bed and it was soaking
wet all the way and the dream I was,
there was so much yarn.
It was like I didn't stop and the whole
room was filling up with a yard.
And so he comes swimming in and he said,
boy,
a little Joanie,
let me,
uh,
let me turn the faucet off for you.
And this we want to get real
embarrassing because he put his mouth
on,
you know,
uh,
on my penis,
my little penis.
And he say,
let me turn the faucet off for you,
a little johnny and he suck and you suck
and all the gear and come out.
And he's turned it off,
like turned it off with his mouth and
then the urine keep slowly drain it out
of the room.
The urine.
Well,
I'm getting a little emotional and the
urine clear out.
And when it was dry,
my pappy lay down next to me and the bed
and he gave me a tend to hug and he
kissed me on the neck and he said,
little johnny,
I just want you to know that anytime you
need me to suck on your a little penis.
Well,
yeah.
Disappeared.
He was a ghost.
So what do you,
what do you think about it?
So let me ask you a question.
When you were 12 before he passed,
were you ever afraid of him?
Well,
yes,
because sometimes my pathway would come
home and he would,
uh,
what,
what he was a nurse and he sometimes he
would,
he would change colostomy bags or the
old folks and he would come,
smelled of urine at home.
And I thought that was our thought.
That was a little strange.
And I do think,
well,
yes,
I was very terrified on my pappy.
Okay.
Second question.
Did you really peed the bed when you
were young?
Oh yes.
I peed the bed a lot and fact I,
okay.
I'm ashamed to admit it once again cause
it's quite embarrassing.
But I,
well I sleep with rubber sheets because
that had been,
I'm afraid has never,
uh Huh.
I'm afraid that habit is not a left me.
Beautiful thing about this can really be
your breakthrough of being able to leave
this pattern.
So the metaphysical reason for peeing in
the bed,
it's fear of a parent,
especially a male parent.
So it makes sense that a with the way
you felt about him,
that you would do it and that b,
that your memory of him would involve
that.
So the sucking away represents you suck
in a way.
This kind of,
if I'm looking at my father who think
about it in the dream,
he was so sensitive and he was so tender
and he was so loving,
so kind.
So when he was here,
you paid attention to the scary part.
Now years later you ready to move into
this next part of your life.
So you made it to leave that pattern
behind.
So you focused on the tinder,
they're loving,
tender and loving part was there when he
was alive.
That's true.
Not what you focused on as a kid.
Well that's true.
He wants Mary tend to with the whole
what?
The penis and the mouth.
But the problem I'm having now,
and I do think what you said was
fascinating,
I'm really struck by it,
but the problem is I've gotten my wife
and she has a thing she likes and I
don't know how this all connect,
but she liked to poop in the bed.
I tell you and I'm,
I'm okay with it because,
well,
my father used to poop in the bed and he
thought it was a good time,
but my wife is into it now and I think
it's a little uncomfortable too.
I like,
I loved the wife,
but I sometimes think there's a little
too much poop in the bed.
Oh wait real quick.
I just want to say real quick,
hold on.
Before you start talking,
I just want to say also that I,
I in my dreams,
I would poop in the bed too.
And I used to poop and spray poop all
over the room.
And lately,
and this is why I'm calling the last few
days,
I'm just been Skorton ropes a poop out
of my butt all into my bed and I,
and that's why I'm calling,
I'm trying to figure out,
is this some sort of source that this is
coming from where I'm just Skorton these
ropes.
So what you're saying is that in your
quest to move away from urinating in the
bed,
you think it may disrupt what your wife
likes.
So tell me.
Okay.
I'm worried about that.
It might have something to do with this.
In my quest is get away from urinating
in the bed that it's now been the door
to Skorton brown ropes in the bed.
Just huge turd snake.
Yeah.
So what is it that your wife likes?
What form that she preferred?
Well,
my wife likes it when the poops in the
bed and I think it's fine,
you know,
every once in a while.
But she asks me every evening,
I tried to go to the bathroom.
I liked to,
you know,
uh,
let it out before the bedtime.
But she says,
no.
She says,
no,
Johnny,
I want you to poop right here in the
bed.
And she likes to cuddle because we lost
a child and she likes to pretend that
the poop is the child.
So if she cuts,
does it matter to her?
Which one of yours,
whether it's hers or yours,
in terms of pretending is the child?
Well,
I,
you know,
it's just the most important thing,
not so much about the child,
it's just that having shooting these
ropes,
a snake like poop in the bed,
just splattering them all in around the
bed and,
and pn in the bed and just,
it's a wild situation.
Okay.
Is,
and I mean,
I feel that,
oh,
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but I feel like that's the most
important part of the conversation.
Okay.
You know,
I keep bringing up my wife,
I keep bringing up my wife and all this
other stuff,
but really it's about me just Skorton
these brown rope,
snake ropes,
just shooting these snake ropes out
it.
I totally get it.
And I do think that's important,
but we have to relate it back to the
dream.
The dream is,
was this conversation.
So I think that there's some
significance to the fact that you're
paying on a bed of fear of a parent who
is the male period.
So when you started telling me about
your wife,
it made me think about the actual
activity that your father did in the
drink
real quick.
One last thing is,
I don't,
when I say my wife,
I should make it clear that,
I mean my pillow because I don't
actually have a wife.
I have a pillow,
but I,
but to me that is,
is my wife and,
and,
and I'm,
well it's,
it's a little ball of cotton inside of
the pillow is,
but,
but to me,
but to me it's a real baby.
And I want to just say that when I'm
Skorton these snake,
like,
like four feet.
Yeah.
Johnny.
I'm sorry.
When,
When I'm scoring these four feet snake,
like ropes of Poop,
snake ropes in my bed,
I'm starting to put that onto my pillow
wife and I'm starting to project the,
she's doing that.
But it's really me and I'm by myself and
I'm by myself and,
and I,
and I'm a bit,
I'm a bit ashamed to,
to,
to come out just right out of the gate
and admit that.
So that's,
that's my problem.
That's okay.
I want to just be yourself.
So can we please go back to the dream?
Tell me the part again about what your
dad was doing to get rid of the urine.
So my daddy,
what had my little,
my little baby penis in his mouth and he
kept on suck in and buttons it.
Yeah.
I think there's some significance there.
I think that that's the key.
The key is that your father,
well,
just to,
just to make it clear,
just not to interrupt,
but I just want to let you know that one
important part of my dream is that my
dad,
he was actually in my dream was a
pillow.
Okay,
so it wasn't your real no,
no,
no.
In the junior real path know,
in,
in the dream.
My,
pappy was a beautiful,
like a long pillow,
like one of those leg pit,
like the kind of pillows you put it
between your legs and cuddle with.
And in my dream and,
and,
and when I say suck,
I think more accurately would be brushed
up against because he was a pillow and,
and I,
I'm so confused and contort it about
these things,
but I don't know,
I just think that it's more,
I'm just,
I'm,
I'm fighting against being truthful with
you and,
and,
and then,
you know,
the,
the fantasy that,
that the,
the lies,
you know,
the truthfulness and the lies.
So my question is,
who do I pee?
I should I pee or poop in the bed?
Okay.
Well,
I think that's a good question,
Johnny.
But I think a deeper way to look at it
is,
what does it mean when you visualize
your wife,
when you're awake and your father when
you're asleep,
but they're both close.
Oh,
exactly.
That's the significance right there.
That's where you really have to look at
and say,
what does that mean?
That,
um,
you had a real,
there's another piece of information.
It's the important thing.
You should know that I'm an heir to a
large pillow company.
I can't say which,
because it's very private and I only
grew up around pillows and I only have
pillows around me and I refuse.
I'm very rich,
so I've sent away all human interaction,
only pillow interaction.
So,
and people that help me and work with me
or in giant pillow suits,
uh,
and that could be a part of it.
And I've been living that way for the
last 17 years.
But,
uh,
I don't know.
No,
you're,
you're real.
Pappy died when you were 12,
is that correct?
That's right.
He really was.
He really did work at the hospital and
deal with those [inaudible] bags.
Correct.
Oh,
well that's so that poppy.
So that was the poppy.
That was my pillow,
but my real poppy was the,
the owner.
He established a big below company.
I don't want to say which one it was.
Oh,
of course.
But uh,
the one that was changing colostomy bags
as a nurse.
Well that one was a,
that one was a pillow.
Okay.
Oh,
I see.
Now.
It all makes sense to me.
So what do you,
what?
What do you think I should do?
Like just,
I'm going to let you talk and sort of
let me know what you think.
Yeah.
Well Johnny,
I think that both pee and poop represent
parts of your life that you want to
release,
parts that you want to get rid of to
excrete.
So the form does it really matter.
What matters is that you continue to
have a method to be able to take all the
things that you deal with in life and be
able to release them.
So the question of which form of release
should I use is less important than it
should.
I believe the answer is yes,
you have to release because it's really
a symbol.
It's a symbol for the,
what has gotten you this far in life is
your ability to be able to take in
things and then be able to release them
so you're not holding on to them.
That's the real significance here,
jen.
That's incredible that you were able to
decipher that.
So I will tell my wife that you said I
will keep shitting in the bed and that's
fine.
And that,
uh,
I'm sorry,
what was your name again?
Lucas.
Thank you so much.
I will keep shitting in the bed and uh,
I will tell my wife that Lucas was told
me I need to release God Dab it.
Right.
And so I will keep shit and some comes
up because black,
you got to shit the bed sometimes and if
that sometimes was every night and then
by Golly,
I'll shit the bed every damn night.
Amen brother.
All right,
well Lucas,
I tell Ya,
I recommend it to you.
It's a very cut the dick situation to
shit in your own bed and I recommend it
to you.
Well you'll give it a shot for me.
Okay.
I'm open to everything.
I also just want to say that
I called in,
I paid for the Guinness World Book of
Records People to come and uh,
I do squirt the longest brown snake
ropes out of my butt in w in my bed and
I think I might get a Guinness World
record for that.
So I'm pretty excited about that.
So that's at least a bright,
that's one at least bright,
bright light in my life.
So I thought I'd let you know about
them.
They really would.
Thank you for sharing that Johnny.
Well thank you.
Thank you for your call,
but thank you for listening.
I hope that you'll be pooping in your
own bed cuddling.
Get Ben.
Appreciate Ya.
Right.
Take care now.
Bye Bye.
So I have a question real quick,
real quick.
God,
anybody here skate?
Whoa,
wait,
we got a lot to talk about.
What just happened?
Well,
I all,
I can tell you it's fucking ethan
comedic sensibilities and I'm like stop.
Like I keep trying to reroute it like
you're talking about like,
like child rape.
I'm like,
can we make this more about like it was
a dream because the headline here is how
that guy commonly encouraged you to
never stop shitting for the rest of your
life.
Pull you around like a localizer
headline.
Fairly impressed.
I was really impressed.
Like the type of people we're going to
be calling this person up or people who
are at the end of their rope who have a
lot of legitimate problems and you could
just like scam him and this guy's like,
at least this is a voice to talk to.
He's like kind.
He's gentle.
I'm pretty impressed with psychics.
Yeah,
two for two.
For two.
The first one didn't want to take your
money.
Second one was just like,
you couldn't face him.
By the way,
that was my real problem in life.
That guy helped me like that was,
I think he's like a good therapist and
calling themselves shitting the bed for
17 years.
You know,
now's not the time to stop.
Keep shitting that bed.
Little Johnny.
He's just like,
keep going.
Just don't feel bad about it guys.
I mean,
I got to say,
first of all,
I do want to say that we did hit 75,000
words back,
read 76,000
all we did it.
We did it,
guys
do.
Well,
let's do the pepper and then we'll do
our thing.
Yeah,
perfect.
That best way to do it.
Okay,
sure.
As you guys are doing the call,
I already ate the peppers.
So yeah,
those donation money's coming.
They're going for a good cause guys.
It was a dream.
My Dad didn't,
he peed in the kid beat.
He stuck the pee out of the room through
his penis.
Was that an autumn reasonable day?
I was trying to steer it back onto a
well,
I appreciate the poop snake.
I was just trying to make it just trying
to,
I just wanted to get it back into where
we're all laughing really hard and not
going,
Oh God,
this is maybe a little too real for some
people.
Wait,
where the fuck?
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
I was just a feeling you're just having
fun.
We're all having fun.
I want to make you feel bad.
Um,
do we?
Wow.
The question is,
and we don't even know what this third
song is.
I know what the fourth song did he know
that there was two of us when we were
goofing around cause he was taking it
very serious.
I don't think he did because I was
copying your pitch was like raising and
[inaudible].
My name is miss social experiments where
like a white guy will be there and then
they'll turn around and then like a
black guy stands up and they act like
nothing happened.
No.
Yeah.
Are only paying attention with like 30%
of their brain.
And they tend to like that video where
there's like a,
there's like a guy in a gorilla suit.
Yeah,
yeah.
Ask a ball field and you're like,
did you see most people just tend to
kind of assumed you it again and you're
like,
oh,
these 6,000
I wonder what the CEO of direct really
thought of that call.
Oh,
so sorry to the CEO of [inaudible].
I was making,
sorry.
No,
all about poop and stuff and you are
making it about your bottle or whatever.
He was sucking urine out of my penis to
help bring the room guy.
The important thing is $76,000
and $76,000
for charity.
Patrice Wilson.
I'm still watching.
Oh,
that's gotta be a gag.
$1 30 frosted Patrice,
Patrice,
the fucking coffin on video.
All right guys.
We did it.
We are fucking killing it.
We've got 70,002
we got a dollars.
Take you to every single person has done
it.
We're going to throw it to Aussie to
play it.
The next requested song,
we're going to go back into the lobby
for joey to eat a pepper.
I'm super excited.
This,
this night is just beginning.
We're going to keep going.
I think we could do it.
Let's do it.
I'm down.
I mean it's going to be a 10 hour
stream,
but oh no,
I don't.
By the way,
if we open it up and doesn't look happy
about that,
we,
if we opened up aussies,
there'd be like a ton more.
Like,
all right,
here we go.
Throw it to her.
Hey wait,
wait.
How does this sound though?
Like in the,
in the old setup switching.
So we're going to switch over to music
mode now,
so,
okay.
Okay.
So don't start.
Don't start until they go ahead and up.
Keep doing that so they can hear
good check,
check
to see the words.
Well,
welcome.
Yes.
Pay.
You said well,
yes,
yes.
Yeah.
Wow.
Nope.
No,
dude,
this is incredible.
You've never heard the song before you
went out of the room and by the way,
you were ready a long time ago,
so no Aussie fucking nailed it.
Chaos.
If you want more.
So that was a,
that was a year zero by ghost.
And that was donation was from a tech
data tech data.
Tag it up.
Dan,
do we have any other more writing or are
we good to go to the pepper?
No,
no.
We got to go to the pepper.
We are so ready for the pepper,
but,
but I just want to say that aussies
still has one more song.
Ready?
No,
you got it.
I paid for that one.
It's a minor one.
Did you grab that one?
Okay.
Bull Shit.
You're doing it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Also Dan,
should we open it up for more Aussie
songs?
I mean that's,
that's up to you guys ultimately.
Um,
a,
by the way,
Justin,
even,
what do you think a lot of the donations
are saying that you're setting up the
skateboard wrong?
I don't know if that's accurate.
Not really.
Yeah,
but they saw you doing it.
I know there's been multiple people
saying that.
So am I fucking it up?
I don't know.
Let's go.
You're probably right.
I'm a little guy.
It's pepper time.
No,
I'm not sure at all.
I'm just saying what the donation
stream.
I think it's good and can get somebody
just like donate $10 any $10 donations.
I'll read your comments and like,
tell me,
am I doing it wrong or what?
I feel like the trucks might be wrong.
I'm not going to lie.
I think that's what people are,
but I feel like I got the trucks right.
Like our,
aren't the bushings going in or do the,
are the bushing is going out,
but waiting for Groin for advice guys,
am I the only way they can communicate
with those?
Like,
I know,
like,
I fucking know this and I'm like,
just being retarded,
I think.
I think,
you know what?
I think they're right.
I think would go out.
Oh No.
What have I done?
Well,
that's just on me.
I got a fucking,
uh,
just re-installed the bush,
but I feel like,
I feel like that's the way it goes.
Right.
You're asking the wrong dude,
man.
I got on a skateboard for two seconds
and Mike,
can we get a,
can we get like Tony Hawk or somebody on
the line?
Do you think about it?
I was trying to drop Peter Griffin.
What do you think?
It's more,
it's more good,
right?
Keep going.
Yeah.
That little spot.
Like make that be more,
more Simpson.
Okay,
got it.
That's,
that's a,
that's a fucking bat.
That will go for some money.
Um,
is there anybody out there they could
confirm or deny?
I should have brought my own square when
we were switching over down here.
Here we go.
All right.
Hey everybody and welcome to the second
annual h three podcasts,
charity bonanza,
and give it up.
Everybody.
Thank you to everyone who participated
so far,
so glad to have you.
Now,
as you know,
we've hit our third milestone here today
with me.
I have the notorious,
didn't ghost pepper.
Yes,
that's right.
It was one of the spiciest peppers in
the world.
Attila was dethroned recently by the
Carolina reaper.
Yes.
Well,
Joey Salads.
We have here dressed as a crackhead
Santa with his life fest and rotting
milk that has been there for about eight
hours.
Joey,
how are you feeling today?
I feel like 75 grand.
75 grand.
That's right.
We got a superstar here with a great
attitude.
Now tell me,
Joe,
what's the temperature of the milk?
Is that Luke warms at room temp on your
feet?
Tell me about it.
Finally,
lesson room temperature.
Slightly less than room temperature.
It's how he,
yes,
we've got Kurds forming on the bottom of
the pool.
That's how cheeses made Joey.
Well,
we didn't actually quite,
I don't believe we,
uh,
con enough donations for that,
but thank you for bringing that up now.
Joey,
are we going to be able to be donating
your underwear today?
Um,
Daniel,
we're going to have to get it nice and
soggy.
Well,
a Napo enough to do enough to do about
that.
Let's get started.
Joey,
do the honors please.
You can remove the stem here.
I'll hold the stem.
Okay.
And now you have to consume the whole
thing as you know that as the rules.
And that is $75,000
raise for direct relief.
Thank you all so much.
Ian,
how are you feeling?
I'm excited for this and wait and we've
all been waiting patiently.
It's been a long day and everyone has
patiently awaited this big,
big,
big moment.
And we've all,
we're so happy that we made it here to
75,000.
So Joey,
what,
what's going on here?
What are we doing?
Well I probably not.
That's probably the least of your
worries there joey.
All right to pop that little baby boy.
Well pop that little mcnugget in your
mouth.
Here we go.
This is a thrilling moment.
Everybody sponsored by make nugget.
Yes sir.
Good.
And you could chew it up.
I recommend just enjoying the flavor.
Savoring the Melanin.
Looks like a weird,
uh,
like,
I don't even know.
Like,
uh,
what's the Guy Charles Manson?
Like you look like Charles Manson.
Yeah.
Little Charles Manson and a little a
pool of milk here.
Folks trying to raise money for a good
cause.
We got Charles Manson and the pool.
Charles Manson,
who is uh,
in the,
in the milk pool about the eda yet make,
go ahead.
Go ahead joy gus,
get this over with.
All right,
so joey has put the pepper in his mouth.
He is chewing it.
He is coughing.
He is going already for the water.
Oh No.
Oh No,
no.
It makes it worse.
It's like stuck in my teeth.
So it's like,
Eh,
you're,
you're a,
you're a hero.
Jewelry making up for all the,
oh Jesus.
All right.
What are you feeling right now?
Oh,
he's shaking.
He's trying to drink milk.
His hand is shaking.
Zack is going absolutely.
Tell me,
tell me.
What is that Joe?
No,
no,
no.
Just smell.
Joey,
tell me what you,
what do you think of right now?
I'm thinking he's having trouble
speaking was,
I'm assuming it's very spicy.
He's gargling milk,
said all the way in the back of the
throat.
It's stuck there.
I'm trying not to laugh because this is
quite a site.
Get a shot of Justin.
He's high.
He's a concerned,
oh,
he's going for the coke zero joey.
I hear,
I hear coke zero has a really good
calming effect for hot peppers.
Uh,
that's,
that's a shout out to you.
Coke zero and also McDonald's mcnuggets
are delicious and good.
Joey is the heat.
It's still getting worse than worse.
Oh No,
it's starting to hit the stomach now.
So you guys,
this is why we got to get to $100,000
tonight.
We got to do it.
I mean,
not because we want to torture joey,
but also because you know,
look at how fun this is for us as we
watch this poor guy.
Now Joey,
just remember as you are suffering,
they're in a pool of a spoiled milk that
we did raise $75,000
and remember,
at least she didn't get pepper spray in
the fucking face.
Joey,
what's worse?
Pepper spray or this?
Probably the beverage spray,
but then pepper spray,
I was like blacked out for us.
Yeah.
No,
he don't eat a pepper spray was worse.
Pepper spray was worse.
Nope.
No.
Do you need water or anything?
Are you okay?
You will need some.
What do you need?
Do you need anything from us?
I'm actually feeling dizzy.
Oh No.
We'll stop drinking that milk.
Do you need to sit down?
Lay down.
Are you okay?
You all right?
You're doing it right.
You,
you can garner the milk and spit it out.
If I pass out,
you guys can laugh.
Oh No,
no.
We're not going to laugh.
You're right.
No one's going to laugh at you want
to pass that?
Do you want water?
You want some?
I don't know,
but I'm actually like really dizzy.
I think he needs a big nugget.
It's like I'm somebody.
Get on.
Can we get Joe's smart water?
Well,
we got you covered.
Joey is dizzy.
Build pool of milk.
I swelling.
He pays.
No,
we're not going to let you die.
If you do Saint Peter's gonna at those
pearly white gates,
he's going to look at you and go,
Joey,
you atoned by eating those peppers for
charity.
You atoned there,
Joe.
We've got another glass of water for
you.
You're doing great.
I don't think I'd be able to survive the
reason.
Ah,
come on.
That's what we're here for.
Now can you get a shot?
There's a,
there's something floating kind of dark,
like a dark patch in there.
Can you get a shot of that?
What is that?
Oh,
Santa Shit from the beard now joey.
How's the heat?
Is it a kill it dude,
stop.
Joey,
tell me,
what are you feeling right now?
Is it getting worse or
but has the heat,
is it getting worse or is it staying
about the same?
Are you
same now but like I know it's stuck in
my teeth a little bit so if I like try
to lodge it out,
I like reactivate so I'm just leaving.
I'll,
I'll deal with that later.
All right,
well there you have it.
This is Santa,
his lowest point and North Pole history,
but it was for a good cause and the kids
are definitely getting presence this
year.
Fox.
Well let's,
why don't we show,
we sit here and report or should we head
on back and let,
yeah,
we'll head on back.
We'll let Santa think about things here
in the North Pole.
You just let us know if you need thing.
If you pass out,
we'll make sure not that you don't drown
in a pool of spoiled milk and I think
you're a,
you are a hero and as Joey said you are,
you will be accepted by St Peter.
Okay.
All right.
This just got real,
real word now.
All right,
let's go back in there.
Yeah.
Good job.
Oh my God.
The donations,
the donations.
Keep her on it.
Yeah.
People like what they see,
man.
People are starting to,
people are waking up right now,
street getting right now.
Finally the screens picking up.
Oh,
thank you so much.
Okay.
If there is a god,
he's against this.
If there's a god he's against
everything.
All at one point we were thinking of
letting them shit in there.
So don't say weed.
That was all on you.
He was like,
I'm not sure that's a no,
that's why you two are perfect for each
other.
You guys both wanted to make it happen.
Me and royal and just like you guys got
it.
May have been getting,
there's a line.
You guys have been giving me a lot of
hard vetoes.
Well,
I'm impressed.
We got,
you guys were at 77 now.
We're almost,
yeah,
we're basically at 77,000.
It's amazing.
There's a huge amount of money made in
nation considering that we had a little
bit of tech issues.
You know what I mean?
Like incredible,
incredible Justin,
where it's 77,000
and the donations are rolling in people
having a good,
this is only the first
day.
We're going to have a week of these
prizes up there.
Um,
well I dunno,
should we wrap it up?
Should we share it?
Feel like,
uh,
what else?
You Ready?
I think that's a high end.
A little ready to wrap it up.
I mean,
we started at three,
which at six and a half hours,
which we're starting to hit that,
starting to hit that wall.
We'll try not trying to fucking call,
call it a half day.
I mean,
come on guys.
Bushings go in.
So if that means anything.
Yeah,
no,
I'm good.
Hey,
I know a lot of people going,
hey,
you,
you making it skeet?
Who would rate for us?
I'm impressed with royal and stamina.
This guy's running shows.
Three video games.
Uh,
20 hour live stream.
I'm just trying to make sure that we at
this rate,
I think we would take us like another
two hours to hit 100,000
and I'm not sure at least,
dude,
here's what we're going to do.
We're going to push.
I don't know that Joe has got to eat
that.
We're going to push for one more hour.
What time is it right now?
We're not going to make it.
You're not going to make it dude.
It's nine 39 30 by 10 30 we have to do
it guys as a team.
Everybody please hold going.
Get to 105 by 10 30 cause we are going
to stop at 10 30 we have to,
we have to call it at some point.
So 10 30 we stop cause all,
listen guys,
we have to,
we have to fucking,
we have to.
We have to believe.
Should we do another part time down
here?
What are we going to do for an hour?
Yeah,
we've kind of done all the things that
eat the peppers.
They called the drawings.
Build a skateboard.
All right,
well we're at 77,000
we did you guys,
is there any chance we can raise another
$23,000
I'm not sure.
Yeah,
Nobody's even beaten shredder as a top
donor.
You know what I mean?
Like I mean,
I could kick down another thousand that
would put me out like 5,000
if we just,
okay guys,
this is what we gotta do.
Everyone watching,
just send a link to your friend,
send a link to that friend.
Every link gets,
if you say you do that whole thing where
it's like if you don't spread this to 12
friends,
you die and like an hour lions
threatened whole thing.
I mean friends overseas,
should we do another guy?
They got to get to how or we have to do
it.
We have to do it.
It will be the best for you.
For us in the studio and also for the
world and for the poor vern.
Burn and burn victims a little inspired
right now.
That wasn't,
that was the cat backstage.
You inspired to eat a pepper.
It's hard time down here.
Uh,
Dan,
can you,
can you give joey the Mike and switched
to him?
Let's get,
let's talk to Joe and see if he's up
shot.
I
don't know that joey can eat another
pepper because Joe said he's in.
He's ready.
He's ready to push it to the limit to
raise.
It's um,
it's about,
I feel it working its way to my asshole.
Ah,
so I don't know if you want to get up
bathroom cam going.
Are you throwing up there?
We're going to do this.
You look like a hero.
Saddam Hussein popping out of that hole
after her.
It was,
my mouth is perfectly fine.
It's like just,
it's,
Oh my God.
It's boiling this stomach.
Oh No,
you're all right.
I'm just going to break my Kito Diet.
Give me a fucking pizza.
There's a fucking pizza.
Hey.
Hell No.
It's worse now.
Joey,
where are you?
If we get 100,000
are you going to eat that last pepper?
Yeah,
just do a quick,
come on guys.
Donate.
Donate,
click.
I get this shit over with.
I want to have one giant shit.
I don't,
I can't even afford to discount what I'm
saying.
We're all in this together.
How are we going to do this guys?
Come on.
We all died in a car crash on the way
here and everyone is donating.
Please wait until I finish and start
building the staple.
The donations or roll tape.
We're dude hit osseous by the way,
for us.
He's got two more songs she's got to do.
All right.
Get,
get,
get it over with.
Well,
I want to thank everybody.
The dollars to $5 the 20 everything's
thrown in jail donation.
How many people are still watching this?
It's so late.
Yeah.
At this power,
how many audience members do we have?
A,
it looks like we're at about 15 k,
which we've been at for the last like
hour and a half.
It's kind of holding steady at this
point.
I don't know if we can,
everybody who's still watching and tries
are fucking troopers.
I got to tell you.
Team cares.
If you can just tweet it,
tweet it.
Famous people like at like famous
people,
you know,
just people that have big followings.
Just be like,
Yo,
we're trying to raise money for uh,
you know,
the California fire victims no fucking
way.
Northern California fire,
the people have forgotten about the like
people who have already moved on.
Yeah,
that's part of the problem.
And that's true.
But that's also part of the problem.
Why it's the last,
it's a tough time.
Last time we did it,
it was like right as it was in September
to when people didn't show what a
fucking shit show humanity is.
Man,
we are,
we are fucked as a,
as a,
as a species.
We're just a parasite on this planet
because listen,
listen to how sad justin is.
You need to give them hope.
Hope.
Give me some fucking smoke.
By the way.
She just went out to go learn the next
song.
So she's,
she's saying was already listening to
it.
I want to see what Ellis thinks about
all of that.
I wish you look.
Could you dial in?
Can we use type thing?
She says,
yes,
I'm watching.
I said,
I said get her sickness words and I want
to point out,
uh,
it,
I don't know if it was exactly her that
pushed us over the edge,
but she doped from home donated another
$200 and she said,
I donated a to top you guys off at 75.
K what?
Allege?
Yeah,
she is amazing.
She's alleged.
Seriously everyone watching.
Just like you said,
parents,
neighbors,
uh,
Isla said everyone was donating those a
team actually.
Your tenacity,
Justin,
the louder you get the big guys.
I'm the about these port for victim.
What about the burn victims?
All right.
What about we gotta get these burn
victims and it and get money for them?
I don't get,
I don't do this shit for free.
I mean,
I do do this shit for free.
How many people or how many people are
watching right now?
15,000.
It's actually climbing every single
person watching donated two bucks.
We'd be golden is,
I'm not even kidding.
We have to hit a hundred.
How can we share this?
I came here today.
Go.
Should we share this?
Should I like,
should we put mics?
You know what Justin type is working on
really kicking up.
Okay.
All right.
Can you put up a cup of coffee?
We're going all the way.
Here we go.
Doing this or doing this.
Close to calling an uber,
but Justin's no is firing me the fuck.
Let me right now.
Let me just promote this more.
So here,
Justin,
do more yelling for my,
you get the fucking works with trying to
raise money.
Tuna.
It's the final hours.
If the final is the final,
our final,
final fucking these poor people in
California,
it's done well.
I'm convinced.
Perfect.
That's going everywhere.
Justin,
you tweet who?
Mister fucking who?
Midnight Hour.
Send a tweet out man.
Of course I'm going to,
I'm building a Goddamn skateboard that
we're going to put up for that.
By the way,
this skateboard signed by Paul
Rodriguez.
It's signed by weight.
Is that?
Oh,
thank you Maggie.
Thank you.
Uh,
Alfredo Alfredo,
a c k nine k nine seat keeps coming back
from war drawing donations back on.
Donations are off,
Dan.
All right,
let me get him back.
I'd send them to expire anyway and then,
and then when we're done,
turn them off.
We need your help to reach 110 can I
just say that?
Uh,
this skateboard is like literally
exactly how I would,
this would be my skateboard.
Thank you.
Talk to panda.
Our Bas.
Thank you.
Tall.
Cool.
Should we do another prank call?
I mean,
we got,
we got ab,
Bro.
You think of another place.
Okay,
so Alex,
you should do a site.
Oh Man,
I am.
I get stressed out,
dude.
Show it off.
Showed off.
Can you,
oh,
are you out of bed?
I have one of my pocket or my pocket.
Oh,
look at Joe and get a shot of joy where
you get a shout of joy.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Get a shot of joe going in the bathroom.
When you show this off.
We can see going to shit.
Wait,
is he asking him if he's going to shit?
Ask him what he's going to shit based on
his speed.
He's definitely going in the hall
on your,
on your camera.
So go ahead.
I'm doing socials.
Okay.
Oh,
well,
okay.
I don't want to fuck anything up.
Bump it.
But guys,
so the,
the,
this is a,
this is a skateboard.
This has got some risers.
Uh,
as you can see,
it's got a really cool grip tape.
It's one of my faves.
Um,
and uh,
this is a morty skateboard.
Those I drew all over morty shirt.
Uh,
we got,
uh,
let's see,
we got,
who drew on a isla?
Isla,
Isla sign right there.
Oh God.
We've got to get the light on it.
There it is.
It's a foil.
It's a foil deck.
So it's like very,
very,
very light sensitive.
Paul Rodriguez,
who was the,
uh,
I feel like he might've been the
instigator of all these decks.
I don't know.
100%,
but I know he's a bad ass skateboarder.
I hope I'm going to say yes.
I'm just a dumb dumb.
But anyways,
uh,
and then,
Alex,
you drew some shit that'll sketch to the
ca alex joy right here.
Oh,
man.
Out of the cigarette,
sir.
Alex drew here.
Sorry.
Oh,
right there behind that.
William and uh,
and Ethan drew here.
So this,
this deck is really like,
oh sorry.
All right Justin,
drop the skateboard.
I am covered in water.
The computer is covered in water.
Justin dropped the skateboard and all
the electronic keys now scooping water
onto my lap.
We are all still hold sober right now.
We're just exhausted and that's why this
has just been knocked.
The mic over.
Justin is drunk for sure.
Um,
so we have a bit of a travesty here.
Everyone is scrambling to clean the
water on the desk.
We have water on the laptop,
make sure it's coming in clutch with the
towels.
Zach,
the swarming,
Sarah swarming with paper towels.
Dan is in there quick with the paper
towels.
I've got water on the mic.
I've got water on my pants as well.
They're all over the place.
The mic is all loose and Goosey.
We need some bag or we need some quick,
we need some male stimulates here.
We need a fluffer.
Juston keeps trying to pitch.
The escape party is not missed a beat.
We are in the middle of a travesty and
Justin is pitching the skateboard as we
to everybody tuning in,
who is wondering what is going on
because I just tweeted this out.
Welcome to the Stream,
Jessica.
10 years to squirt water.
Justin continues to spray water
everywhere.
He's been to scale.
Welcome to our nine of the h three h
three charity podcast.
All right,
thank you guys.
That was a quick APP by everybody.
Excellent work.
The donation screen went unresponsive.
How do we make that thing a shit?
How do we fix that Biz?
Everything is falling apart.
Refresh.
God himself is trying to stop this.
Uh,
livestream this off and we're going to
justin put that damn.
Put that.
Oh No.
Is the Internet down?
What's going on right now?
Just in broke.
The fucking everything is good,
right?
But the page isn't loading.
It's loading on this monitor right here.
So you fucked my computer.
Probably.
There's water all over the electronics
down here as well.
Down.
No,
you're good.
You're fine.
There's a bunch of water on the table
coming to the last h three h d podcast.
This is a historical moment that we were
all here for,
excuse me.
Uh,
we are having issues on the donation.
I can someone confirm that the stream is
up cause I'm still up.
It's all can see me here.
Yeah.
Okay.
Ian,
you're switching.
Everything looks fine.
We're still going.
We are almost at 80.
These goddamn donation numbers we need
to,
okay.
Can I say something?
I just tweeted it out for the second
one.
I said so can you guys please do,
come on.
We're going to be here all fucking
night.
Hey guys,
look into the camera and talk to your
audience.
Ethan,
this is your fucking dad.
Put on that camera right there.
Wait,
I want to fix my laptop first.
That you spilled water on your fucking
bitch.
You do it on camera.
Fuck you justin.
Reuland people look into the camera and
tell him,
tell him how you really feel.
Ethan,
tell him how you really feel will.
Okay,
we're back.
Oh,
that's what I'm saying.
I'm going to build it on a skateboard.
I'm going to build another skateboard.
Well hold on,
hold on.
I think it's a skateboard.
I think it's cause I built that school
for hang on now tweeted out justin and
I'll do and I'll make a plea.
Tell Him we need help.
The link to your social media.
No one cares about me.
Weed it out regionally.
My video on the on,
on,
on what?
On what?
A platform and instagram and I did a
story.
I did everything then.
Oh,
someone just simple.
Just donate it.
Fido grid.
Whoa,
whoa.
I think it's probably the right on your
face.
Let me,
uh,
let me check.
Yes,
you're doing it.
You're doing it.
What must the 81 that's what I'm saying.
Oh my God.
Talk to your fancy.
It's Ted to talk to everybody.
Huge bubble blesses.
Cub it out to everybody.
This is our seven.
You think this is a fucking joke?
No,
don't hit me with that music jazz.
I want some real shit.
Let me give up some like give them some
like really hardcore heart.
Listen,
we're over 81,000
now.
This is the seventh hour.
You think we're going everywhere?
No.
$1,
$2.
Three,
five every fucking dollar account.
Because they love the fuckers up north.
Oh,
when my house burned down,
poor me.
Well that's why we'll come in and help
you out because they're not little cry
babies.
They lost everything and we,
we'd have everything and that's why it
just did.
I don't have everything.
I mean like,
Oh,
you told me to talk it.
His screen I love good at do I of those
like go swimming pools.
They have it a Mandalay bay now.
They've all their goddamn houses.
You got $1 in your bank account.
That makes a big difference.
It's December.
I know I'm not.
I bet all your needs,
your house.
You don't care about the fire victim
because that happened a while ago.
Let let's stop eating.
Stop even stop Viva.
No more Ethan.
Okay.
Hey Sue,
it's too abrasive to embrace risk from
squanch was the donator for $500 so
Chris from,
and he asked her or a drawing of a power
baby on a Ethan's face.
I,
Justin,
do you know what that means?
Yeah,
absolutely.
All right,
well let's get a power of 80 gone.
By the way.
Kay Kay.
81 by the way,
have we have we put mother watch games
package up yet?
Uh,
let me check.
Hold on a second.
We should put the squanch games package
up and we should talk about that for a
second while I get really passionate
about really seriously getting to a
hundred grand.
No Zack Cause I've just hitting that.
That's somebody in there.
I think Alex is jewelry that goes out.
We're about to introduce a whole nother
tier of shit you can throw your money
into to win because God dammit we are
living in a,
we're living in a world where it's time
to fucking get serious.
Someone's got to do it and win or not
win,
but you know,
get us up to a hundred grand so that we
can help these poor they were fuck sake.
Cause number one I got to draw power
baby.
You keep it cut a lose
in our mind for Alpha two why do I feel
like you're sexually assaulted me every
time your fingers in my mouth,
we deal with the devil that by
sovereignty at least a little bit too
much.
I'm going to cough in your face.
Thousands of dollars as a up.
There it is
guys.
That's a power baby on Ethan's cheek.
And then can we get,
by the way,
Howard,
maybe for the case,
can you,
can you do me a favor,
and I'm only saying this because I'm a
little bit tipsy,
but can you pull up Mike?
The video,
the trover saves the universe.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Cause like I don't think anyway,
just wanted to keep it at three m yeah.
Oh yeah.
Show that power baby.
Show that little horribly drawn power
baby.
I can't see it.
So yeah,
it's a cute little guy.
You want the e three trailer Justin?
No,
I want,
I want game play.
You're going to have to dye it a
thousand if you want to watch that.
All right.
Okay,
well I will,
I've already,
I've already donated millions of
dollars.
You want to watch the game play?
Well,
how long has it eight minutes.
This one have to watch the whole thing,
but like,
yeah,
watch your fucking like,
show that shit.
So Justin's working on this game is
coming out.
Um,
I can't say when,
but it's going to be in 2019.
And uh,
and um,
we have a big prize pack that if you,
if you throw some sheckles into where's
that?
Uh,
those are,
that's a currency shekel.
It's a type of currency.
A dollar.
Um,
I haven't seen this.
This is awesome.
You,
you,
you can win a trover saves the universe
prize pack.
This is a video game.
That's,
this is my game.
I've played it.
It's incredible.
I completed,
it's stupid fucking crazy.
It plays both in Vr and uh,
on a regular,
you know,
right.
Like non vr.
So you don't need vr to play it.
It's really fun and non vr.
He climbing inside Justin's brain.
It's pretty surreal experience.
Now vr is the preferred method of
playing justin.
No,
no dude,
it's so much fun.
Oh,
it's great.
Either way.
It's great.
I don't like rotating my chair marriage
to work correctly.
Your chair got damaged.
Just use the right thumb.
Stick to it.
And I went out here.
No,
I'm hearing it.
A little bit of crack.
Oh wait,
a stop.
There's some crisis.
I think the video might be cracking.
Try to a different video.
Let me just play this dumb shit.
Let's see.
Oh,
I hear crack.
Oh wait one second.
Yeah,
maybe went into the speakers or went
into the call me mister crackle.
By the way,
when I get pumped up and I want to
fucking raise money for a charity,
I caused crackling and people's computer
by spilling drinks and water everywhere
and I will do it every single time.
Okay,
so if you want to invite me to a
money raising stream,
I will spill crackled juice in your
computer.
Donation donation.
Moving right along.
Katy.
Dan,
can you tell me why Jay,
when Joey in and creed?
Haley just texted me that he's having a
rough time in bathroom.
Really?
Yeah.
All right,
well let's let him have that rough time.
We can.
It's probably going to be just enough to
get us to a hundred.
I think we're again,
I think we do a hundred in the bathroom.
Maybe you can phone,
maybe.
Can you ask him to do a little
interview?
Hot,
hot.
Hot.
Yeah.
How about Paul Paul in Joe calling from
the bath,
calling from the bathroom.
Justin.
Josh.
Josh wants to know how do we get to the
secret zoo level asks Jack.
Oh man,
dude,
the Zeke secrets you level.
It's like one of the most difficult
because not only did,
not only did the crows,
crows,
guys,
Kelly on the line.
Oh here.
Hold on one second.
So guys,
we have Joey Salads.
Who's in the stall right now having a
rough time.
Joey,
you're on the air.
Oh my bad call.
A static not static.
Can you hear me all right
cause I spill water everywhere.
Healing Buddy.
Sorry.
Oh,
is that how you feeling?
It's like it out.
You like buttholes.
So Joe,
you like bottles
Dan,
it's not working.
So maybe ask him to just record a little
update for us is not a voice update.
Oh No,
it is signed by.
Do we have any,
I'm writing updates.
Dan.
Uh,
I'll check.
Okay.
We don't fill that bag up.
Wow.
We are the,
we're up to 83 guys.
We were up to 83.
Oh it gets off.
We are moving.
Then you put the uh,
the,
the trover saves the universe.
Perko yeah.
So I can just tell everyone what that
is,
right?
Oh,
he fixed your,
rotate my chair.
I still repeat.
Okay.
So,
so this is just the beginning of the
game.
This was like just this is a dressing
are too fucking game but ground or the
thing it's an adventure game.
You're,
you're a co op.
It's a cooperation and interact with
them by pressing on yourself.
First person,
third person.
They don't have time for this right now.
Action,
exploration,
comedy.
We need adventure.
And when you have a cool pack for
people,
donate,
donate to the cause and you're going to
get all kinds of rare shit that no one
else will get it.
Yeah,
it's still playing.
I just muted it.
We're going to get a bunch of fucking
cool shit that no one else will get.
And this is the only game maybe ever
made in history where the plot involves
a monster who steals your pet dogs and
uses the dogs to go into his eye holes
and power is,
but then also you find out that he's
part of a weird collective of like
beings.
It can see every version of the future
and it's fucking insane.
None of that red dead redemption.
I'm muting none of that in Super Mario.
Hey,
open up.
Come out here.
Sounds a lot like some other characters.
I,
that's my fault.
It's definitely the right place.
You're the one,
we don't have time to get into it right
now,
but you're coming.
Oh,
this is the funniest shit ever because
full ground points,
it wasn't breaking numerous giant big
monster.
You heard that right?
A motherfucker giant damn near half the
city stolen science equipment
microscopes because I'm talking about
that's a great idea.
Hundred dollars and they are powered
him.
I've never seen,
he's scared people.
My grandmother's afraid.
Your dogs.
Literally.
That's the beginning of the fucking
game.
I'm gonna text him,
Yo baby,
you're going to be seeing a lot of these
throughout the whole game.
I mean,
I really wish we were playing this right
now.
Like it's so much fun announcement.
Go ahead.
Breaking announcement.
I just wanted to show you,
we will continue.
Oh,
that's a rip dip on.
That's awesome.
This is going to be a uh,
uh,
rick and Morty,
Rick deck signed by.
I'm Paul Rodriguez with a rip and dip,
one of my favorite grip tape,
some of my favorite,
uh,
trans nerve as it's called.
We have a breaking announcement for
$500.
You can call into the show and chat with
your woe.
Favorite Pizza.
He tried to pull the same shit we pulled
on those
fucking uh,
it's great cause you paid 500 bucks.
You earned it.
Yeah.
Do we put that as a,
as a goal I guess?
Or if you donate five,
just say,
but we'll put it on the,
as a goal.
500.
Give us a call.
Get us to our dream of making poor joey.
He's on this call right now.
He's going to have to come back in and,
but if you,
do you want a limit on how many calls?
No,
I mean people are $500.
There should be no,
listen,
why don't we start,
why don't we start with like,
well we can hang up on them,
right?
If they fucking brain gum.
Yeah.
We're not obligated to talk to them if
they suck.
But before we do it,
can you just finish this part because
this feels like how the game works and I
really,
I'm excited because like the,
the,
the price pack includes me doing a bunch
of original art,
the game,
uh,
trover figure,
joey video and you look so crazy.
Look at the thumbnail from this video
from prison,
dude.
Yeah.
That's 100% of poison video.
Dan,
I'm going to forward this to you.
I wonder if we can edit in it.
Well,
I guess it's just a livestream.
here,
let's hear what he has to say.
Here we go.
Can you hear this?
I'm trying to throw up.
It won't come out of my stomach is like
swollen,
like a big bubble in my stomach.
So I be tired.
He's a toning for his sins.
Guys.
You know what?
Why don't I send this to you Dan and
maybe you can throw it up on the screen
on the,
like he said the were dying and there,
should we send somebody to check it out
now you know he's,
he's,
he's hamming it up.
He loves the camera.
I don't doubt that he's in pain,
but like,
yeah,
he's not dying.
He's fat here.
I'm going to,
he wouldn't be here if it wasn't like,
you know what?
I got to atone for my fucking horrible
prank sin.
Hold on.
I'm going to email this to me.
Why is it just,
what the fuck?
It won't let me email this fucking cup
video or listen,
is Aussie ready with the next song?
Cause like I want to hear another
fucking song.
I don't know.
I'm emailing this to myself and I'm
going to pull it up.
So we go on joy.
Um,
US says we're at 85,
85.
Oh my God.
We are really close to 85 this God.
Noah's Ark says don't fucking quit.
All right.
Do we need dinner?
Is anyone hungry?
Ethan?
Actually,
I need to,
I need to actually cut our record for so
long and just restart it to ensure that
we don't lose our footage.
So,
but the stream won't go down the stream.
Just the record.
So we're just going to stop recording
right now for just a brief moment.
Standby guys,
we are here to fucking help the fucking
California burn people.
Please help us help the California burn
people.
Got a dark world.
We need the need to pick it up.
Oh,
by the way,
next year.
It could be your house,
your town,
it next year.
It could be your home and you don't know
what it is.
You could have been a fucking weird,
a water balloon,
a giant water hits your town.
Super Likely.
But anything's possible.
No,
and we're here every year.
We do this every fucking,
all right,
I've got joey salads like Ethan stand
tall and strong and we're going to beg
for your pennies and peanuts
trying to throw up.
It won't come out and my stomach is like
swollen
that angle almost look and all this shit
all over him,
man.
I've never seen a man broken like
picture him after this stream walking
out onto the street.
Like what do people think is going on in
this guy's life?
I'm s I'm crossing the road.
Yeah,
yeah,
absolutely.
Let's watch this one more time.
Oh my God bless.
You can watch it without sound and just
enjoy.
You got to love the guy.
You got to appreciate him.
He flew out.
You know he's here hustling.
He's gonna eat another one.
Do we really want that?
I mean,
we want that hundred thousand so I guess
we do want it right guys.
Guys,
this is all part of helping people
going.
I don't know.
We still have 50,000
he's try to hit that wall a little bit.
Starting to hit that wall.
Justin,
we need another need,
another speech.
Justin that's been hitting that wall all
night.
I'm not going to accept it.
We're going to keep going and we're
going to fucking do it.
Right?
Look at this drawing,
that fucking Hershey's she's working on.
I get a drawing to work on I.
We are going.
All right.
We're going to send it.
I'll tell you what,
you can leave Ethan.
I think Justin has hit a wall.
We should have Aussie and then let's do
another prank call for Christ's sake.
We just got to keep things rolling.
You're not leading it.
I'm Justin.
I,
you know,
I'm feeling the vibe I'm getting.
You know
Jesus.
That was like really too much.
He just somebody saying your flies down.
What somebody's saying.
Oh it is totally fine.
It's totally now.
By the way,
on purpose.
On purpose.
It's on purpose down and if you get a
sneak peak,
you get a pq peak.
Oh wait.
There was a $500 riding requests.
Oh,
someone monitoring those.
What is it?
Oh there,
it means it's somebody just said like
don't ignore it or whatever.
Love you too James though.
Thank you Stephanie.
Thank you.
Tinkled bird.
G off regular.
Ooh Gee off.
Says intense gastrointestinal pressure
can cause a rupture,
which is a medical emergency.
Pay attention to Joey's responses.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Jeff.
Thank you.
Yeah,
good thousand please.
Next pepper.
That's what Justin says.
No,
I say we care about Joey and Justin next
pepper.
Well,
no,
ha ha ha.
Raise a hundred grand so we can give
joey another pepper with medical
supervision.
We've got better.
Be careful
who here is the medical supervision,
by the way.
Hey listen.
Look,
I didn't fucking organize this thing.
You're pretty up and he ain't no
stopping to the stream.
Hoppity thank you.
Thank you.
Colby Mitchell.
Yo,
I'm on these coast.
Keep me up til two please.
You?
Yes,
of course you can.
Yeah.
Betty McKay.
Maddie says,
this is my last $5 from my pappy.
Thank you.
Someone keeps saying Justin ride the
skateboard.
Yeah.
You saw what Justin just tried to,
when he tried to hold the Skateboard,
right?
He,
he almost broke the entire ustream.
Maybe you shouldn't write it in here.
All right.
Here we crossed 85,000
whoa.
We're getting
a surge.
You guys were getting a surge.
We're getting a surge.
Somebody saying the face drawing isn't
open right now.
Oh again.
Oh yeah,
no it does.
I'm just saying what that guy said.
Joe,
how are you feeling?
Oh,
Joey's back.
How you feeling buddy?
Joey turned the mic towards you and tell
us all about yourself.
You want to know everything about me?
Let me talk to joey.
Joe,
you want to know?
You want to know that you're okay?
Are you?
Yes sir.
No ma'am.
I'm good.
Did you always sell a drawing is not up.
Uh,
Dan,
of course it's fine.
We should all prior joey salad drawing.
You and I should draw Joey Salad drawing
so that we could add more money to the
money bucket.
Come on people.
What are we doing?
We're,
we're all living in a fuck it shit hole.
We're trying to say.
Hold on,
hold on.
Hold on.
Justin.
Sorry Joey,
tell me,
how are you feeling dude?
It,
my mouth is 100% fine.
That dissipated in like five minutes.
So that's good news.
Yeah,
but it's this,
does it feel,
it feels like someone's stabbing me in
with what are you doing skateboard?
It's is important.
Where he ended up like we're having an
important conversation with,
oh,
by the way,
when you,
when you put a grip tape on,
you cut off the excess.
You got to sing in that puppy down.
Justin,
hang on one sec.
We're literally trying to find out if
this man is dying.
It just as like,
what about my skateboard?
No,
that was getting picked up and I'll
wait.
Go for it.
I didn't know that was getting picked
up.
Dan.
A face tat is not up and then it's super
quiet after that.
By the way,
this skateboard we're all going to write
on and uh,
this is gonna be a big Joey skateboard
situation.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
All right.
Good luck.
Go in and talk to them.
Just say you or out of fucking control.
Please talk to him.
Not getting stronger.
The like the later,
this goes,
just as like gaining power rising.
As I get more passionate about it,
like as we get more exhausted,
he starts to radiate super thing in
lunatic energy.
Look,
Bam.
Done.
Look at that.
Look at this.
Look at this fucking shit.
It's a rip.
It's up right now.
It's a rip and dip fucking grip tape
with a brand new primitive,
uh,
rick deck with bill foil moisture
magician.
Why does this keep crashed?
His name waste and then,
and then we're all going to draw on it.
So,
and then I'm going to put a bunch of
wheels,
trucks and wheels on it.
Okay.
So,
oh,
we are surging.
We're almost to 86.
Hello.
Hello?
She said that,
uh,
she feels like the little alien in the,
in the cat's stomach is what's going on
and in and joey
stomach,
right.
Like are really good.
So we weren't.
So Joey,
tell me,
first of all,
you said you're,
the pain in your mouth has gone quickly
after the pepper,
but we're,
so what is happening in your body right
now?
My stomach is not able to handle it.
And did you have a diarrhea?
It wasn't diarrhea.
I don't think it's sitting.
I don't think it went through my system.
You didn't know it was fly or not
pooped,
but like it wasn't spicy.
I think once it gets old digested,
that's when my ass just going to
explode.
You didn't have a spicy pope,
just a normal pole.
It was like a normal,
he was a fly hurry.
And Are you,
is your stomach and pain?
Are you feeling better?
Are you afraid of 100,000
it's like 70% I am afraid of 100,000
but like if I have to do it again,
I have to do it.
Good question.
Oh sorry.
Please go ahead.
Well,
Justin says you have to do it.
He's been wasted.
You don't have to do anything,
but what we have to do is get to
$100,000
pool.
How many people are watching right now?
Yeah,
that's right.
Because we're getting fucked up because
we're getting excited,
excited.
It gives $1 with hell scape.
So here's what we're going to do.
Aussies going to play.
We're going to print out their psychic
call.
We're going to do another cycle call,
continue to build the skateboards.
So we're going to put away,
anybody wants to do drawing requests,
just we all donate another thousand just
to get this party started.
Justin and also,
by the way,
oh,
let's get some mcnuggets you've been
talking about.
No,
I do not want to make Dan.
If it mcnugget even comes close to me,
I will fucking have a panic attack.
You've got to get justin doughnut place.
You or we don't all agree we're donating
another thousand.
I'm going to just give it 500 500 what
was that for?
Call me boy.
He's got a call.
We got a call.
Rick,
we got a call request.
So Damn,
when you're finished here,
please donate another thousand for me.
And I want you could just,
I don't want to steal prizes from anyone
I've worked,
so just donate it a thousand and if you
could please say that as a note,
if you could please Dan,
say that little johnny has got some,
uh,
his justin,
what do you approve of a comment about
the little johnny's papa taken some
urine out of the anus.
Wait,
wait,
wait.
Oh,
the top donor.
Just donate it.
Thousand for me.
I'm going delirious here.
All right,
so go ahead.
We're getting close here because I
really feel like we can do this.
And we can help these people.
And I think also ethan,
you got to extend the raffle to two
weeks because you have to,
I'm going to,
you have to.
Yeah.
I'm not going to have to,
I'm going to reduce it by the way.
Guess what?
We're gonna,
we're gonna,
we're gonna.
We're gonna to
the raffle.
You've one day,
it's down.
This live stream is your last dance,
so you better because right now that's
what we should say now.
And then I'll be like,
oh shit,
we're going to do it for like half a
year.
Yeah,
guys,
I have donated to $6,000
total.
We need to get there.
And we're getting close.
Thank you to everyone who's donating
every 200 every one a hundred every God
damn everything.
But in the meantime,
Aussie as a song ready for,
so let's all sit back and enjoy fucking
pretty song quippy and pieces of shit.
Check.
Oh,
that's awesome.
Switching off.
Yeah,
it's gotta be it.
Yep.
Okay.
All right.
Free one is completely different.
Yeah,
correct.
She came from Greece.
She studied sculpture at St Martins.
Good.
Oh,
tell me that her dad was looted.
I sit in that case ramen and then 30
seconds I want to do sleep with people
like you to see what I can do.
I took it to a supermarket.
I don't know why I had status,
so it started then I said,
but you've got no money.
She laughed and say yes.
The funny I said,
I can't see anyone a smiling and here
are you sure you got I want to sleep.
I'm asleep with common people that thank
you like
Yay.
Yeah,
so fucking good guys.
You reach some of the record.
Yeah,
like while you did that,
while you did that,
we crossed into 91 close to 100,000
I didn't think we were going to make
food.
I thought it was impossible.
We were right there yet,
but we're getting close so we're almost
at 91 dude,
we're at 91,000
you fuck it.
I got it guys.
I got to mention there's a hero named up
dog who keeps donating $1 and saying
Justin,
cute,
Kiss Ethan on the mouth and he's been
doing this for an hour and a half.
It does not stop.
Hold on.
Can we see how much he's donated?
Yeah,
I'm curious.
I'm curious,
how long have you seen it and they're
getting more aggressive.
You kiss me.
Will you give me a peck on the lips for
like,
Oh of course I will.
Can we,
let's set a goal.
Uh,
Dan,
well let me,
let me get the other thing.
Well,
what about Sarah?
Could she help set up goals?
Oh,
what?
Why is this afternoon set up a goal for
where?
At your mortgage.
Blessed in our blasting off.
We need a goal for Justin to get me a
peck on the lips.
Aussie.
That was amazing.
If you guys enjoy that,
just incredible.
Frosty.
Yes.
Can I do well done for no os we have
more.
We have more.
They say a thousand.
Whoa,
whoa.
One box for file like shorts and George.
You are,
you are.
You are helping.
Like hold on,
hold on.
Hold on sir.
Please,
please,
please tell me what's going on because
we are getting huge donations.
Yeah.
What is that Aussie playing?
That was of all the shit that's going
on.
There's so many amazing donations
happening right now.
If the play,
there's face tattoos come back.
Thank you.
Spacey Trash.
Oh,
little puppets.
look at you throwing the old pup out.
Uh,
so,
so what does that mean?
No,
there she goes.
Okay.
They're going to be,
it hasn't been that long.
I,
the pups are there.
They're going to be all right.
What?
We're again close.
There's not gonna be that much longer.
Will we remember Humble Ella?
Come on up.
Doug again,
Justin than,
so hold on,
hold on.
I didn't want to let all these
incredible heroes.
Hold on guys.
This is getting weird.
Mommy and daddy are five for life.
Okay,
I'll see you.
The incredible,
amazing musician can check her out.
Okay.
No,
stay as long as you want.
I'm not kicking you out.
I'm just want to give you a credit chaos
cascade.
If you want to hear more,
go check out her original music.
She's incredible.
She,
she also score is doing all the score
for,
um,
my video game chair received the
universe if you want to,
if you want to buy that when it comes
out and not,
not the turn.
A fucking charity.
Oh,
weird gross blog way.
People who are trying to get justin a
kiss me wait cause we're going to set up
a goal weight.
Ethan client a thousand.
Oh that was from Dan.
That was your idea.
That was the one you asked me to do.
I just,
okay.
So cool.
[inaudible] have that melody.
I still do have your sculpture.
Thank you.
And the guy,
the guy who uh,
donated to have the call and somehow we
didn't get his phone number.
He just emailed me.
So let me,
uh,
let me set them up and I'm going to get
him on the donated in total.
That dude a lot.
Yeah.
Wow.
I'd have to crunch the numbers.
Well we'll have a,
we're doing,
like Ethan said,
we're doing like a report this Friday.
Took over everything and uh,
yeah,
we'll,
we'll definitely shout out all these
awesome donations up dog.
She changed her name to up dog.
I'm a girl asshole because I kept
guessing the gender.
Ron Up dog wants to hurry up.
You are so thirsty for these two thick
boys to lock list.
I never had someone donated in total up
dog.
I think it's amazing.
We're pretty impressed.
You guys are crushing it.
You guys are fucking crushing it.
We're almost a 94,000
this is incredible.
This is a,
this is a holiday miracle right there.
I'm rallying right now.
Awesome.
I didn't think we were going to make it.
You guys are fucking Joey.
How do you feel seeing these numbers
right?
I'm excited but scared at the same time.
Every time I see a big donation I'm like
now Dan is legitimately worried.
He keeps taking me aside and being like,
I don't know if we should make them.
I'm worried for myself as well.
My stomach still gargling and it's like
my God,
I can't not do it.
I don't want to,
I don't want him.
I don't want a medical emergency.
On our hands.
Well,
maybe make him eat the whole thing.
Just half of the whole thing.
So just take a bite.
I'm not even,
I wasn't even screaming before when I,
when I felt like I was on a pest out,
like,
oh,
I didn't think so.
Yeah.
So what we're going to do joey,
and you don't have to commit to this.
Okay.
Um,
first of all,
we have to,
there's two Carolina reapers.
Which one looked?
This one kind of looks less scary to me.
This one looks like more lame,
but you can decide which bag do you want
to hit up?
Let's wait for Justin.
It's before we take the call and media
to eat.
So you think you think those ones,
I mean they probably does it really,
I don't know.
You decide,
you pick your poison as they say and
literally,
yeah.
But would you still rather get pepper
sprayed or would you rather do the
question?
Yeah,
yeah.
I think I'll be good if we just take a
bite out of it.
So here,
let's see.
I'm going to pick one out for you.
A small one.
Okay.
It's crazy.
Yeah,
I'm going to have to at least need a
real small one minute.
What do you think?
That's still,
I mean,
I'm reading up on this pepper right now
and uh,
there's like multiple farmers being
like,
Oh God,
no,
you would never put the thing in your
mouth.
Well,
you put a little bit in it for cooking.
You know what I'm saying?
Like,
well,
people do.
It is,
it is something people do for a
challenge.
Okay.
All right.
Like retinal link have done it.
I've written linky they were fine,
fine as a,
you know,
subjective,
but they survived.
God,
that smells so strong.
Dude.
Smell that.
That's a Carolina reaper.
Well,
the second,
you know,
spiciest pepper in the world.
Now smell that Alex.
I mean,
that is fucking putrid,
man.
Okay.
You can be like,
yeah,
send,
sent shivers down your spine.
I think I saw somebody fake eating a
online and it was like,
I'm sure there's a lot of people faking
it.
So,
hey guys,
uh,
c k nine,
see who's been donating a ton all night,
Aka Jack is his real name.
Thank you.
Jack is on the line.
So I'm going to pop them in right now.
What's that?
Where's Justin that get them in here to
say what up?
He just walked back in.
Okay,
great.
Perfect.
All right,
so hold on one second.
Here comes Jack.
Jack on the line should be live now.
Jack.
Yeah.
What's up baby?
You man,
you're crushing.
Hey you're,
you give us some extra wings to fly too.
Thank you so much man.
A lot of donations.
How many total huge fucking benefit.
It was kind of over like 16,
$1,700.
Thank you man.
That's very generous
member.
These are all tax deductible donations,
which does help a lot at the end of the
year.
That's my boy.
Well the thing is when you make a
donation,
charitable donation,
you pretty much depending on your tax
bracket or getting like half the
government pays for half of it.
Essentially everybody,
it's good.
First you're donating to,
it's good for you Karma wise.
It's good for you tax wise.
You also might get gifts
out of it.
A win win.
Well thank you.
So tell me about yourself as much as
you're comfortable with.
So,
uh,
I'm a fulltime utuber nowadays.
I make really weird music about video
games.
Oh,
nice.
From team of animators who helped me
make animations for all the meats.
Amazing.
What's your Youtube Channel?
Okay.
It's a c k nine
which is short for chaotic Canine Nine
Culture C K nine.
See,
let's see.
Let's shake it out.
Oh yeah,
you got some Nice thumbnails.
Doggy.
We don't get a lot of subscribers,
but our views are pretty crazy.
Songs about about five.
Oh,
a lot of views,
bro.
55 million.
Dot.
Can I walk through this with that?
I'm going to close expecting it either.
Can I wash this without getting claimed?
I'm curious.
If you watch this,
I will.
White List your channels like right now.
Wait,
so you could so wait.
You would auto claim it if it,
that's this.
I'm not gonna.
I don't wanna deal with that.
I don't care.
We know how it works.
John.
I'm still pretty new to the music scene.
I'm only about two years into this full
time.
This is our biggest donator.
Get Rich,
man.
This guy's youtube famous.
Look at that.
And 54 million in those views.
Whole shitload of views.
I want to take your shit out.
4 million.
54 million.
I cool.
Congratulation.
No,
I've seen everything.
Congratulations.
This is really amazing.
Thank you so much.
Well,
thank you so much for supporting us.
I mean it's meant fricking the world.
Justin,
do you have a message for this guy?
Your donor?
Yeah,
thank you.
Um,
you know,
we're just trying to do something
positive for the southern California.
Torrance,
California.
Whoa,
whoa.
Everybody who's donating for kiss,
justin kissed me on the mouth.
Set up that goal.
Damn.
Say again.
Sorry.
So set up a goal when they get to 5,000
there.
Justin's going to kiss me on the mouth.
By the way,
by the way,
I'm Aussie still owes us one song.
I'm not,
I'm just seemed a little reluctant.
She owes us a song,
I think less worried about the dogs.
This a fucking anonymous for the $250.
By the way.
I'll say that it's,
well,
he doesn't play the song she owes us
then she's letting down every single
fire victims of California.
She's done a lot of brush.
She's done a lot for us.
We appreciate her.
And you can check her out at cass.
CASS.
Dan,
how are we've forgotten?
Any big donators we're uh,
we're actually right now,
Sarah is going through and uh,
or spreadsheet to uh,
put together everybody that did big
donations in the night so we can just
rapid fire,
do some shout outs to me.
That's still in fantastic guys.
We just crossed 95,000.
I can't believe we're actually going to
you guys.
We can we get one more song from Aussie?
One more song.
Why the one song that I pick?
God dammit.
So,
uh,
can you,
can you tell me the suggestion?
Here's what we decided with Joey.
We've got this too by the way.
Went to a good cause.
Okay.
I know,
I know.
I feel like,
I feel like a,
a fan.
Like,
Hey,
I,
I paid for Justin and,
and just want to see Ethan shake that
make out.
And it didn't happen.
Just Justin,
Jesse Var,
everyone's decided that they want you to
eat the pepper instead of fucking shit.
So Justin were talking about,
uh,
what Joey's going to eat now.
Here's the smallest one.
We can find it.
Are you going to nibble kind of the tip?
Like what are you comfortable with?
Just the tip.
Just the tip or are we talking about
guys?
We can,
we can just cut the tip off.
I feel you eat the tip or the stem.
I mean this shaft.
I mean like the head of the penis.
Which part do you want to head?
Half of it off.
Let me see it.
Yeah,
I know.
I want it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we know you still there buddy and God
bless you.
[inaudible] heard that call.
We'll just rip it off.
I'm a very quiet person in the
background.
Usually killing it.
We might have to like cut it off.
Glad on your part of this part of the
straight.
You can pay when a troll bro.
Yeah,
make a song about it.
There's a university.
Joey,
why?
Cause I want to know what he's doing all
in music for taking the safe as you're
so close.
So close.
Here's what I'm going to do.
Finally escape.
Look at this.
It looks like that one's nasty.
Look,
I'm going to lick it.
You're going to lick it nuts like get to
100,000
no,
I want it.
Know what I want to in consolidate,
consolidate,
consolidate and consolidate.
Consolidate.
By the way,
by the way,
we've been going for seven and a half
hours.
My charitable motherfucker.
It feels like 20 hours.
There's a lot of charitable energy in
this room,
so when are you going to like black
pepper?
This is why I think Aussie needs to
learn the last song and I think because
here's what's going to happen.
We're going to hit a hundred and joy's
can have to use that last pepper and we
need it.
We need a beautiful song.
Yeah.
I mean you're not arguing with us.
We're not in charge of what have herb or
not.
That's up to her man.
Have her play as we do the outro.
I'm going to lick this fucking pepper.
Y'All want to do that or I want to see
it now.
I don't want us,
I want to see it.
Justin smelling like tension music.
Do we have any like kind of intense with
the tension going stand by.
Okay.
This tension music's coming up.
I'm going to look at,
don't do anything stupid though because
you're drunk,
but give it a lift.
Bite.
Bite the tip.
Give it a look.
Just just eat it.
Then I'll
tell you what.
I will like this.
If Aussie goes and play and learn this
song,
so she's in the other room.
If she learns,
I will look to the song has to learn the
song and come in and play the song.
Okay,
here we go ahead.
Oh Yup.
Might as well eat it at that.
Oh boy.
God,
Joey.
Justin went in for a little suck.
Yeah,
a little sucky suck that you're doing.
Okay.
You might have to fight it.
That's apparently no,
I can tell you from experience,
just touching it to your lips.
Yo,
he's just sobered up the spiciest pepper
in the world,
dude.
And I'll tell you what,
I did that.
Now I want Asi to play Justin war
winning.
Whatever this argument is with argument.
It's just,
what's that hot?
It's really good song and I'll see you
shit.
How's the pen?
We've got the pepper.
Uh,
it's,
it's a spicy,
and this is going to be my home.
Can I just say my whole mouth is on
fire.
I'm just,
I'm just playing
cool.
But my whole mouth is on fire.
It's very painful.
I'm going to look at everyone's taking.
Yeah.
I just want to hear this secretly that
somebody donated.
Uh,
uh,
we have,
but lips are our good friend.
But out there,
$600.
Can Justin do a mighty,
mighty Leben grabbed screechy scream
for 600 bucks.
Go ahead.
Just wait right now while I'm thinking.
That's the idea.
Yeah.
I don't know how we'll do it.
As long as Aussie men is a psychopath.
All right.
How are you feeling about the whole
thing in his mouth and he didn't react?
There's long as audrey problems turned
up inside my mouth.
She's not in the room right now,
but I'm sure they're learning the song.
I think so.
I'm going to give it,
I'm going to give it a good shot.
I'm going to do it.
What do they,
you go first.
The exact words.
A mighty,
mighty lemon grabs screechy screams.
Oh,
so just say anything like lemon grab.
What should I say?
Probably.
I mean,
everyone just wants unacceptable,
right?
Or you know,
how about this hub of this?
God,
I don't know.
Fuck my vocal cords up.
Ended up in the ent doctor again,
getting cortisone shots in my fucking
arm is $400.
Here comes Justin [inaudible].
Here it comes,
baby.
Go ahead.
Um,
so suck.
That sucked.
That tip.
Oh my God.
This shit spicy is
[inaudible] pepper on earth.
I'm going to give it a sec.
I want to be at that point.
We're going to do,
let me grab it.
Okay.
So,
uh,
all I'm trying to think of like a clever
twist on it.
So scream as lemme grab.
Okay,
got it.
Uh,
wait.
Oh,
okay.
$96,773
and 66 cents.
Those extra good.
Considering that you're,
you just licked the fucking ghost
pepper.
Okay,
here I go deeper.
We all and solidarity with you,
Joey,
which we appreciate.
I'm going to suck this little baby.
Oh yeah,
dude,
it's fun.
Oh my God,
Dude.
It's fucking hard that touch your tongue
or just hovering in your mouth that
touch my fucking tongue.
And now the heat is,
the heat is building.
At first you feel nothing.
Yeah.
You don't feel anything builds.
That's why I was trying to eat the fast
one.
So cool.
Oh my God man.
Describe it.
Well,
it's building.
It's like pepper spray in my mouth.
So when I did it,
I like sucked on it.
I did that and it hurt,
but I was just like,
I'm going to pretend like it doesn't
hurt.
Well sure because you didn't eat it.
Yeah.
Cool Hand Luke over here,
man.
Good poker face.
No,
I'm saying we,
all we did is laid on our yeah,
but no,
but I think if fifth would I be,
I,
I did like I went like I saw you gave it
a good suck.
I wouldn't fall on like,
I love you too.
Mcnugget Eaton,
Chris,
thanks for 150 bucks.
Mcknight.
Cringey Chris in the house.
Let me shout out a couple that we,
uh,
let me read this.
Okay.
Chris in the house.
Ethan,
just 11.
It'd be so much.
Y'All help me through my trying times.
Airfare.
I based a lot of my improv on Y'alls
humor.
Alex search.
I don't really know you 500 bucks.
Oh my God.
Fifth Janet might about they treat rick
and morty and I really wouldn't be
honored to speak to you guys.
I also have my own youtube channel.
Oh,
it's gone.
Did that person want to call or was that
just more like they want to get home but
they were close.
We're so close.
We're at 97 and a half.
I think we have another call in a is
what?
That seemed like Dan.
Uh,
let me check if that was a private
hallway and I'm just applying.
Oh God,
dude is there my nose.
The fucking heifers are my nose.
Yeah,
that was bad.
We do.
Oh,
okay.
That was a call in request.
So let's go over it.
So thank you so much.
Thank you.
Let's get a new calling fucking ledge
and check out his youtube channel.
Everybody.
Thank you guys.
Thank you.
[inaudible] just saying that.
Oh,
are you first rule right on.
Yeah,
man.
All right.
I guess that's a 54 million views.
Can't be wrong.
Well,
I'm looking forward to interviewing.
That's allergic to furries.
He's sneezing.
Papper Dude,
I'm not kidding.
Nikes.
Right.
Okay.
I'll get the next call set up.
You Man,
I'm looking forward to interview with me
now.
I said Oh yeah,
yeah.
Oh my God.
Jason Ritter.
I'm really looking to donate it or
interviewing of our next season when we
come back from our break.
Hold on,
hold on,
hold on.
Fuck copper.
What have you done to me over?
The big donor says,
I want to make sure we think it so fun.
Box a donated a thousand.
I like shorts and shorts and,
and ask maybe what did he or did he
donate for anything or for any,
is there any thing he won?
No,
I think that was just,
that was just an angel invest.
What's his name?
Uh,
funbox fun.
Bon Box.
Fun box leg.
My leg.
Thank you.
Who else we can,
there's another one up.
Baker Bruh.
Don't even 500.
Keep those buttholes tight.
He said keep a [inaudible].
Uh,
I think you guys saw this one already
cause I think I heard you shout it out
but I'll just say it again cause it's a
huge one.
Mr Donnington.
Mr Donington $2,500.
Whoa.
Wait,
this is donating that Fella Mr donating
to me.
Sounds like Alex.
Alex.
Alex doesn't even like try to hide these
fucking donate a hell of money.
No,
I know.
It's not a real donation.
We got Alex.
Thank you.
You fucking generous caught fucking
piece of shit.
You guys are gender tells him want to
say it reminds me of Channel One on one
days where it's like,
oh we got a new fucking good pilot and
then,
and then we'd find out,
oh it's was made by people.
We fucking who are already here.
We know.
And except in this instance it's just
money for people.
That's good for the world.
Who has got,
I got a couple more to get there.
It's all gone.
The $400 for goose.
Just Justin,
tell us about the secret zoo level.
Thank you.
Goose.
Sankey goose,
blah blah blah.
That's a,
that's a really healthy,
so it really,
ah,
you guys are amazing.
Oh my God.
Thank you Adam.
The secret to staying late given up 400
Fremont Lips.
Thank you for this.
Screechy the secrets to lever level 900
which has happened.
We're at 99,001.
Whoa,
whoa.
Thank you people.
Dan.
My Heart's racing.
All right.
We got a johnny $100 we'll sell you will
sell my soul to you,
Justin.
Uh,
we have to do that.
Even Sierra $135 no message.
Thank you so much.
Another 200 for talking about this two
level.
Talk about [inaudible].
You tell people about the zoo level real
quick cause it seems to be a really
important long time.
They didn't three fuck hell of some
sorts.
Cameras.
People see you talked about that too.
How's that work?
Zoo level.
I got to keep shooting these guys out
because we've got some big ones.
Is Shane Gill?
Thousand Dollars from earlier tonight.
Really?
Greg will cheer up donated twice.
Five 41 time.
400 the other.
You're doing amazing stuff.
Sorry,
I can't donate much more than it is.
That is a lot.
Don't be sorry a,
and I'm so glad you're doing all of this
and since Dana couldn't be here this
year,
wish her the best smiley face.
Really?
Was there
Ridley here.
Let's call it revenue right now.
Keep going,
Dan.
Zak backs a 250 it's for the fire
people.
Yeah.
Come on.
Listen to Zach backs.
You knows what's up.
Uh,
we also have a sign Sino Sino who donate
it to 51 time.
111 another time,
100100100 and another 111 just keeps
doing it.
Let's get this you guys rock efforts.
Thank you.
Just dropped on.
JV.
Cassie.
Thank you.
Hold on to you.
Denver loves you.
Download David.
Cassie says,
Justin,
shout him out.
I'll give another hundred.
David,
David Cassi Davis,
you're getting shouted out.
Here it is.
Here's the show.
Let me tell you all that.
Cassie,
I got a lot to say about my prayer here.
Thank you guys.
Ethan,
what are some of your fondest memories
of your time?
I'm a terrible stories about me and
cassie on those guys.
We are hovering right on the edge.
Okay.
Any other ones down?
I mean,
yeah,
we keep adding on.
We got goose.
Uh,
no,
we already said goose.
He wanted no,
that was another one.
Everybody wants to know about the zoo
level.
That's the same guy we already did it do
to 150 bucks.
No message route,
dude.
You're the man.
A hoodie,
Allen.
100 bucks.
A hundred bucks.
I think there's a conspiracy.
I keep wanting to jump on the airplane
right now.
It's crows,
Crows,
the guys at Crows,
crows.
Dude,
you guys are fucking amazing.
[inaudible]
okay,
hold on.
I gotta.
I gotta get a really bad bad.
I got to tell them the zoo level,
the,
Oh my God,
you guys.
I love that.
Everyone is,
didn't believe this is going to happen.
Oh No.
I still feel peppers in my now that last
30,000
flew by you guys.
You guys are heroes.
Lutely amazing.
We have blasted
that record.
We have slam berry that record fucking
thank you guys directly.
The best ice rink charity in the world.
We are talking about hundreds of you
level out in dollars.
You guys are fucking amazing.
That is so freaking amazing.
I want to give a shout out to anybody
who sat through this entire thing along
with us and in and enjoy this adventure.
Dan,
we had a,
we had a couple of huge ones.
Why don't you read them off David?
100.
He wants to call.
So fifths.
We'll,
we'll call you in just a second.
What else was I going here?
Beard.
$100 a good job guys.
Brett Williams,
200 papa.
Bless her heart.
Jackie.
Tyler.
A hundred bucks.
Uh,
we still got to catch up with some more.
More to come.
Let me,
uh,
let me get these people that donate 500
per call on the line system.
Well,
I mean it's pepper time.
It is pepperdine,
but I'll,
I'll get away from him before we hit off
that as a song.
Joey's going to prepare himself,
so stay tuned.
Wow guys,
these donation had pouring in.
We just pass through.
The hundred thousand guys were still
dropping them down.
We're not done tonight.
We have,
first of all,
Joey's prepared for pepper time.
We have a couple of calls to take
justin,
or is Aussie preparing another song?
Are you kidding?
I think she's out in the hall doing
another 200 danger.
We're almost at 102 fucking amazing.
Absolutely the same.
The numbers the puck has numbers are
growing by the way.
Almost back up to 17 it will rallying
speeches.
Crazy night of fun.
By the way.
I say we keep going Tuesday night,
buddy.
Ready to to I say I say we keep going 30
minutes,
honey.
God Damn.
I have another skateboard developed.
I mean look at me.
500 you boy skinny phoenix.
Oh my gosh.
Thank you.
You boy.
Oh Man.
Where do you go for now?
I don't know how to scroll down.
Oh,
I can go buy rip and dip grip tape with
the,
I think Justin [inaudible] justice seems
like he's having a harder time with that
ghost pepper.
Justin,
how's your mouth doing right now?
Somehow deteriorated since that it got
into my nose and like fucking dude,
listen to my voice.
I've been sneezing like a dog that got
into like a bullet pepper or something.
Cool man.
That shit fucked me up.
Dried Carolina reaper peppers and then
you want a cough like it's not,
it's not okay.
Actually watched the whole thing.
God bless Zach is a year old.
Can we get,
can we have a trump calling him
president,
congratulate the president when he was a
damn poor Dan.
He's got so much to do.
Can we get the president?
Okay,
so we have two calls to take from fans.
We need the president and we have the
solid pepper.
This night is really just begun.
We'll offered him to come back and play
a really good song.
And then by the way guys,
if aussies cool with it,
we'll,
we'll open up another.
Uh,
we have to raise the price up though.
Cause like the,
that shit so bad to know.
We should close it up at this point.
Someone keeps asking me about my fondest
memories of interval.
Yeah.
You've got to give them that memory.
Hundred dollars from Neil kibbutznik.
Thank you nail Christmas miracle.
You know,
we are going to help a lot.
All this has just been amazing.
This has been inspiring a fuck then
amazing.
I mean to say that our charity last
year,
it was like the most by far by far I and
it looks like we did it again dude.
I can't believe it.
This is incredible.
We have to keep this going for two
weeks.
I know it says seven days.
It's kind of same last year.
We'll do it for two weeks.
So I actually know what after this.
Uh,
thank you neil.
Thank you card Lynn.
My fondest memories of they say
something.
Can I,
can I just say something like that?
And by the way,
I want,
I want the audience to sort of weigh in
on this,
uh,
in the,
in the uh,
paid chat chat stream code,
custom kiss me,
I'll,
I'll wait.
Go back.
You guys just need to do it.
That bar has been diligent that we
reached that goal because we can't do
the goal retroactively back to that chat
stream.
We can't do it retroactively,
but they've been,
they've been insistent on this.
It could just be a little,
we need to go.
We need a goal.
I don't kiss for free.
I caught him the way there's a lot of
people.
Wayne person set up a goal for $2,000
uptalk starting to get more aggressive.
She's starting to,
we'll set up a goal of 2000 Dan when
I've got a bag.
What I want to say?
It's not what I say.
Y'All shit in the shower.
I need to,
no,
no.
Listen,
listen me,
it's a Tuesday night,
right before Christmas break.
What else did we get to do except make
out?
Except for fuck's sake,
raise money for people's Egos.
Anyway,
Lips.
I'm saying,
Hey Fox.
Mine.
Thank you for your hundred dollars.
I don't know what you said.
I don't understand what that means,
but thank you so much ty.
Kisses.
Oh yeah,
dude,
the donations are rolling.
103,000
so that's what I'm saying.
I'm saying.
I'm saying that we stay here for a
little bit more.
We're not going anywhere.
We got shit and Austin is going to play
some more songs.
We should open that back up for the
Jews.
Sounds gnarly right now.
God Damn fucking pepper the Johnny Cash
right now.
Jeez.
Rick Moranis voice.
We're bagging it up.
I'm going to fucking,
uh,
I'm going to take you in a shed.
Morty cheese.
Rick.
Geez.
Rick,
what are you talking about?
This is the GS.
Rick.
I don't want to go on the shed more to
you.
What do you mean what?
Even a fucking suck in a buttholes that
had gonorrhea.
This is a flu nightmare,
right?
Jeez man.
Suck it hard.
But Jose had gonorrhea.
Morty,
you're fuck I had gonorrhea but holes in
my mouth.
Morty,
you're a fucking mess.
I am just trying to hang on and raised
money for fire victims.
Rick morty.
I don't know what the fuck you talking
about.
Fucking this is that we're doing.
It's working.
This is what the book obviously in
everyone to everyone.
By the way.
We started this fucking thing.
It like what type?
What type of oil?
Boy,
three o'clock.
That's when everyone's at home.
Eight fucking hours.
Is that the Gazebo?
This is the real time to fucking do it,
right?
Cause email comes down when you reach
100,000
man.
That shit to do.
Dan Do.
We got calls to take a fifth who donated
for the call twice actually.
So Tony had $1,000
to do the column on the Goddamn fucking
file phone system won't let us call
internationally and nationally.
So why don't we call him from my phone
and just hold it up to the mic?
Okay,
let's do that work for you.
I'll get him on the line right now and
I'll come into the room
and then,
and then you'll take the yes dude.
That fucking pepper fucked my tender
suck.
No,
but can I tell you they're going to get
me a spicy?
Can I tell you that?
I can never do that again because like
my voice,
your voice goes,
we'll see.
You've been shouting like a lunatic.
No,
that has nothing to do was to fucking
pepper.
I was fine.
Are you doing all right?
How's your stomach?
It's just your mouth.
It's my,
it's my fucking throat.
Sounds like it's closing up guys.
Or is anyone hungry?
I mean,
we're probably not going to be here that
much longer,
right?
We shouldn't.
No.
So order order,
um,
food.
Let's hang out.
No,
stop trying to look at you trying to
fucking check out dude.
You have to try and have a fun day and
it's like 10:00
PM and that it's 11 my fucking God.
Half Day motherfuckers fucker.
You're going to be the one that we're
aggressive and a half day ass
motherfucker.
Come on.
Regret.
If you don't fucking Kiss Justin and I
will personally come everyday costs is
dumb.
Well listen guys,
take off little body.
You're that guy who tested me.
Soy Boy,
that's dog.
She's got,
she's starting to get abusive.
Vern.
This must be what?
Like,
like if they're paying to say that now,
I guess so.
I guess that's true.
All right,
let's look at this deck.
Another.
Justin,
please.
I'm just a young,
hungry boy grow and be nourished by your
wisdoms.
Secret Zula Rick,
Rick Deck.
Oh Shit.
It jumped to for some reason to jump to
you.
Okay.
So yeah,
Justin,
so drunk dude,
it's my justin's because my voice is all
fucked,
Justin.
That's from the pepper dude.
That fucking shit got in my,
I'm not just before your throat closes
up,
somebody paid another $80 to hear you
talk about this zoo level man,
that we've reached 1000 bucks.
But just give us a little zoom.
Okay.
God Damn.
Han Zu secrets courtesy of Justin.
All right,
so Chad,
let me tell you about the zoo secrets.
So,
oh my,
why do I sound my voice is fucked me.
That's from that fucking pepper dude.
Come on half day.
I'm not even kidding.
Well,
I'm saying I'll be here.
I'll stay all night.
I'll say all fucking night.
But what I do,
he wants to hear about the zoo.
Dude,
wait real quick.
I got to do a shout out.
I just got an email from somebody that
we missed,
um,
that donate 500 bucks.
Nicole Sands.
Um,
I think we,
we actually did get an earlier donation
where we wrote their website called
those comics.com
on,
I think it's on Ethan's Fubu somewhere.
I think that was an ethan one.
Yeah.
Said let's take a look real quick.
Is that side.
And so what are we told me to look at?
Well,
listen,
thank you so much.
We're sorry we missed you.
And she also wanted to say it was
important that she said she loves Ila.
Should we appreciate her so much as an
artist?
We're all sad.
Eli's in here.
Very Sad.
Those are the name of the website again.
Damn.
It's colorless comic Dotcom comics,
not comics,
comic.com.
Check it out.
Sam's that little button.
I know that for some reason.
Is there any other,
you wrote it on Ethan over here.
That's why I know you're right.
All right.
We got shit to do.
Let's,
let's pump through it.
Um,
Ethan,
can we just hang out here and like while
we're together,
just you and I pull up a fun video and
make comments on.
Absolutely.
Let's do.
Thanks Bro.
Oh Shit.
I need some fucking bearing.
Yeah,
we got all kinds of good shit.
Okay,
wait.
Oh,
somebody wanted me to talk about the the
the zoo level.
Yes.
So there's so many donations actually.
So no,
no,
no.
In all seriousness.
So,
so 103,000
accounting accounting was made as a
collaboration between me and some water.
You good?
We got water.
I don't know man.
This shit is like fucking to mucus.
It's like a mucus buildup.
I'm starting to write.
It's fucked it all audio trying to
protect itself cause
it feels good.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Good too.
It is not cool from,
if I had known that was a case,
never done that shit sound like Duncan
trussler right now it's just the mucus.
I Love Duncan trussell I sound like I
ever want to sound like Duncan trussell
I'll just eat a hot pepper and then
people will be,
and I'll be able to do the Duncan
trussell family hour podcast.
Mr.
But it'd be like Holy Shit.
$60 about the zoo level so we can just
check it.
Oh yes.
All right.
So,
so the zoo,
the secrets,
who level is a zoo is a,
is a thing that,
oh fuck God.
Oh my God.
Okay.
So no,
no,
no.
Start at the c level story about 14.
Okay.
So no,
no,
I mean it's,
it's a real,
it's a real fucking,
it's a real thing.
And is,
this is a partnership between,
between me,
uh,
between squatch games and,
and,
um,
and um,
and,
uh,
crows,
Crows,
which is one of the,
they did the Stanley parable.
One of the best,
by the way,
if you haven't played the Stanley
parable,
fuck you go on steam right now.
And by the Stanley parable,
it's a fucking name.
If I'm not even kidding,
if you have not played that game,
fucking get on there and play it.
It's fucking amazing.
It's brilliant.
It's a brilliant game.
But anyways,
he level so,
so,
yeah.
So is there a zoo level?
Well,
guess what?
Yeah,
there is.
And,
and they,
they went out of their fucking,
uh,
they went out,
they went out of their way to make sure
that you couldn't just like data dump
the fucking game.
Um,
God,
it,
this isn't,
there's so it exists.
It exists.
You can play it.
They went out of their way to make sure
you couldn't,
you couldn't just like do like a,
like a data dump of the entire row,
uh,
the game,
you know,
all,
all the data,
the game and like find it and go,
oh,
there it is and here's what we have to
do to get to it.
Like,
pretty,
like,
pretty like awesome.
Like,
you know,
Revolutionary Indie Shit.
Um,
so there you have it and the [inaudible]
and the fuck is who level does exist
and,
and like good luck finding it because
nobody has yet.
Oh,
for real.
It's an Easter egg that nobody's,
nobody's found and,
and,
and um,
yeah,
yeah.
And,
and,
and I think a big part of is because
they're like,
picked it up.
They made sure that you couldn't
actually,
for teaching me to love myself.
Love you guys.
All right,
well there you haggle.
Dan,
can you set up,
I seriously want to do for $2,000
goal.
We mean Justin will
finally give her a little peck.
Okay.
Why do you want a thousand dollar goal?
Because they keep begging for it so I
don't want to let him went down.
Yeah.
But I want to go 2000 starting when,
right.
Well when I just want Dan to set up a
bowl.
Okay,
no problem.
Also,
we've passed the eight hour mark,
which I think is actually the Max that
the live stream we'll store said,
are you for real?
Yeah.
I mean maybe we could talk to youtube
and see if they can make an exception
for us,
but uh,
we,
we might either have to re up load or
the end of this is going to get cut off.
No,
we're way,
if you're watching live just literally
never done an eight or a license,
then that means fucking this.
This is a special that we share.
Are we sure about that?
That.
That's a thing I can definitely for sure
it is a thing at least because we didn't
get the seven hour and 40 minute mark,
so we're not that dangerous.
Okay.
Joey's eating that pepper we got to get,
no,
he's not.
We got to get him and we're only have 20
minutes left.
Hold on.
I know,
but,
but I thought,
I thought that we would be able to lower
and slower.
It's getting painful.
We only got 20 minutes.
I'll just shut us down.
We got to give people what they paid for
it.
Yeah.
Okay guys,
you're the Joey's a are you doing God
damn songs?
The old first
the peppers and then youtube is going to
shut us down if we're going to do
anything.
Yeah,
the fun there.
How are you doing?
How you doing?
Thank you,
Brian.
Joe Jovana you've been watching since we
started.
You're a glutton for punishment and
you're a hero.
Thank you so much for your donation.
You're a glutton for fun.
No,
that's bullshit.
Are you kidding me?
Welcome back everybody to the second ad
charity stream.
We have just crossed $100,000.
We have defied the expectation of
everybody,
even ourselves.
Joey,
how are you feeling about this
incredible,
incredible milestone we've hit?
Yeah,
that's how a lot of hype,
a lot of hype,
a lot of excitement.
Um,
what is,
what are we at,
by the way right now?
Can we uh,
wow.
103,
dude,
you know what?
We only have 20 minutes left on the
stream before youtube cuts us up.
We are closing in on the eight hour
mark.
So Joey,
why don't you Whoa,
get to take a seat and uh,
prepare yourself after being in this tub
with,
you know,
my feet being in this tub like my feet
feel great.
Oh,
well there you,
we just,
we stumbled.
We stumbled upon something of area
valuable.
They're good.
Keep a close eye on that.
I don't want to make sure we go over.
Don't go over that eight hour mark.
But Joey,
um,
now is the time really true that if we
go over eight hours,
I yes,
it's true.
No,
I've,
I've heard it is true.
What?
We can go longer,
but I want to make sure that we get this
because I can talk to them.
So here we go.
So Joey,
this is for the people.
This is for the fire victims.
I'm think that you're a superstar.
Think you're a trooper
or you're looking like a cracked out
Santa and this is rock bottom.
Yeah.
People aren't believing anymore.
So go ahead.
Whenever you're ready.
Can we get a drum roll?
Can we get some music just to tip baby.
Just the tip.
You know how they do just the tip.
Just the tip spongebob.
Where he's like,
we didn't have time for memes,
unfortunately.
Only got 20 minutes.
Good job.
Jelly.
Took a nice clean bite off the tip.
He took a nice clean bite.
Munched it down.
Yep,
he's working it.
He's tilting his head.
He's in pain.
He's wincing.
This is it.
Well second is faces can volted go ahead
joey.
Tell me about it.
It's hot.
It's hot,
it's hot.
The word is in a todd.
It's less.
It's not as bad on the stomach cause I
didn't eat the whole thing.
But like all the spices in it.
That's true.
I'm glad you didn't get the whole thing
cause that would have been a tragic,
but he swashing he's slashing.
They get,
he gets,
it gets dry.
So you gotta like water it down.
Exactly.
That's right.
Joe.
Joey.
Joey goes in for a second bite to prove
his merit.
It looks like he's regretting it though.
He spit it out.
It doesn't look like you swallowed it.
Joey.
Joey,
how about this?
You don't have you chew that up.
You don't have to swallow it.
You can chew it up and the spit it out.
That goes to is worse here.
Well you ate more.
Here's what we're going to do,
cause I don't want to destroy your
stomach.
Chew it up,
chew it up and then spit it out so you
don't,
your stomach doesn't have to deal with
all that.
Hold on.
Wait Joey.
The legend is putting it in his mouth
and he's crunching it and now he's
spitting it out into the,
into the mill.
Yeah.
That's good.
Shit.
Not Spicy.
You know what?
I think my,
my taste buds are all burned off.
It's not that bad.
Should we get another one?
Well,
there's another bag of ghost peppers.
Okay.
Joey is challenging us.
Grab the other bag that goes.
Peppers.
Great.
No,
no,
no.
There's another bag of Carolina reapers.
Grab those please.
The big fat ones.
So Joey is being a fucking absolute
legend here.
Yeah.
What is this shit?
What'd you order these?
I Dunno.
Back.
Bring the bag.
No,
the other ones.
The other one.
Now there's another bag of low fat,
chunky little boys,
Chub sisters.
If you will bring those right in here.
Joe Are you are really turning up here
today.
Yeah,
well said.
Not these.
Just bring all the bags.
Bring all the bags.
We're trying our best here at folks
today and I hope y'all again
entertainment or this is a lot of value.
What are we at here?
A hundred and fourth under three.
What are we out here?
Sarah?
There you have it.
These chunky boys.
All right.
Oh Man.
All right,
so joey,
this is the,
so here,
chew on that one.
That's this is,
this is a dried Carolina reaper.
There's two different types.
Well here,
let me put this down over here.
Well,
he was calling them a little bit shit.
And you don't have to swallow it.
Remember took a big bite.
Half of the bite of the big Chubby,
spit it right out of the media,
right?
Yeah,
there you go.
That's the real deal.
Cause you never know,
you know with the farm.
Those are a little chubby boys.
Huh?
Give me the ghost.
We'll give them the ghost.
Justin,
his scream and give them that goes from
the other room and here we go.
So you've already gone above and beyond.
Well,
he's not slowing them down,
so we're safe,
right?
Yeah.
All right,
Justin screaming.
Give him that ghost chewed up.
Chewed up.
I mean,
you know,
shoot up.
I'm getting,
I feel the pepper.
Maybe just cause there's three of them.
It's possible there.
They're all in a bit,
a larger higher league and it's Joey,
whatever you got to do buddy,
they want you to eat it.
I mean,
that's just the truth.
You're not in pain.
Well,
you're not chewing them up and you're
spitting.
You're just giving like you gotta like
you gotta like a totally chew it up,
right?
I mean,
here's,
here you go,
Mitchell.
Thank you so much.
I'm,
I'm feeling the pepper.
Thank you.
Chew it up all the way.
There you go.
Keep chewing.
You don't have to swallow it,
but keep chewing it up.
There you go.
Now there you go.
Now he's getting there.
We have it and there we go.
So did that hit the spot?
Yeah,
I did it.
He did it.
Yeah.
I think you've got to really chew it up.
Is that right?
Are you an end more or less pain?
Then the third one,
I think my,
um,
I grew up an immunity.
You're just a meal.
Yeah.
Well there you have it.
We conducted a little science experiment
here and I think we've all learned
something.
And most importantly we've learned that
putting your feet in a rotten milk,
we'll give you a nice glossy finish on
your feet.
Is that right?
That is true.
Well,
okay,
Joe,
you're a trooper and we thank you all so
much for your service.
You're doing okay.
All right.
Joey,
your legend,
man.
Yeah.
Big,
big up.
Big applause.
Good job.
What a legend.
That's bad.
That's,
that's the bad Santa sql we all deserve.
All right,
well what's going on in here?
I think we gotta wrap it up and we're in
eight hours.
All I know is we got another fucking
skateboard we get,
I gotta have another skateboard to put
together,
but
all right,
fine.
You want to fucking you in a fucking,
not give as much money away to,
sorry for victims of the,
we're reaching eight hours,
which at that point youtube cuts it off.
So there's literally,
oh,
is youtube the one that's going to say,
sorry,
you almost raised a bunch of money for
poor people in California that we're
fucked over by a fire.
It is us rich youtube.
People are going to have to say no.
We draw the line.
Here it is burning my mouth now.
I'm like,
thank you.
Nothing.
So Dan is,
do we,
so we owe a couple of calls,
is that right?
Is that it?
Uh,
it just one actually,
and they,
they sent me an alternate number,
so let me try him right now and if we
could squeeze it in real quick,
that would be awesome.
And then do we have another song?
Is Aussie want to perform one more song?
Yeah,
I don't think she's going to tell that.
I don't think.
I don't mind.
I just,
I don't want to let her down.
If she's ready.
She's going here.
I don't think she's doing it.
Awesome.
And then let me know if there's any
other big ones that we've got to shout
out.
You guys are amazing.
One Oh four.
I mean,
this is like,
I'm,
I'm honestly so happy.
Yeah,
I'm blown away.
This is fucking amazing.
You guys are so,
oh,
did you set up the,
uh,
the milestone for the kiss?
No,
I just do it then.
no,
no.
Set it up and then we'll move forward
because that's big money.
Are you saying it's not more important,
Dan?
Nothing's more important.
You sign down here.
You want the bottle thing like dee dee,
yeah.
To your whole thing.
Okay.
Is this on film?
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
We've been on for saying this is all
right.
Yeah.
Okay.
So,
Hey,
wait,
no.
Come on right here.
Oh,
right here.
Uh Oh no.
Here.
Wait,
let me go.
Let me go.
Let me get over there and show this.
Show this.
Show the camera.
It gets a little blurry,
I think when you get close because it's
got a focal range.
God dammit that I'm in.
I can hear myself that what's going on.
Um,
we need that.
Sarah,
is it possible for you to set up a,
uh,
incentive,
the 2000 mark for a little smudge?
Because we're not going to make it.
Who gives a fuck?
All right.
We got six minutes apparently according
to Dan to kind of make the most of it.
I'm just going to wait.
Why don't we,
uh,
why don't we let you too.
Why don't we stop and start new new
stream?
No,
what do we know?
It's not good.
That would,
uh,
that would actually solve the problem.
Thank you Stewart.
Alright,
up dog.
You,
you need to chill is up to,
I'm telling.
I've done.
I'm trying,
but these guys are not doing that.
If there what I mean,
I'll go over eight hours gentlemen.
I don't mind going over eight hours Dan.
It's just that your dream.
Ethan,
stop talking about money.
What are you talking as a charity
donation you could kiss this image is
beautiful drawing of just the oil and I
love that.
It's like I'm fine.
It would basically be be him dude.
Your,
I guess it's obvious to say but you are
an incredible artists out.
Hey Man,
I'm doing my best.
Trying to capture,
trying to capture a spirit.
Ethan sergeant draw though cause your
face has been in so many memes.
It's like I got all the memes in my head
and I'm like how do I capture the memes
and the man at the same time?
Interesting.
I'm happening.
You've done a good one of me in the
past.
It takes a minute though.
It's hard after it.
It was even harder to draw.
I'm donating the last dollar.
I love you all and have been watching
the whole stream.
All they want us to see Justin sink,
Terry folds and see this message.
I don't,
I don't really,
and I'm flat broke.
I love y'all and I want to be like you
all some day.
Thank you.
Austin.
Should we do a q and?
A?
I wanted to do another going on out
there to do it.
Third a skateboard,
but fuck it.
While we should probably just,
um,
kill ourselves.
Justin's head too much ginger beer.
Hey,
you've had too much Japanese candy.
Justin Aussie.
He's going to perform as Dan.
Chez does like this out.
Okay,
well we can set that up there until for
the next dance.
Don't take,
don't hurt yourself.
Milky.
I literally don't know what that means.
You want to prank call some shit after
we'll start a new track and then we'll
just prank call people.
Yeah.
Why not?
Fuck it where it's late.
We're up.
Okay.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
you can.
Can I get a merry Christmas from Justin
for my brother Dominic,
can you up on that?
Can you say merry to Donovan?
Merry Christmas.
Donovan.
Yeah.
Little [inaudible] event.
And that's uncalled for you right?
I don't think Donovan is Shalonda you
want of it?
That's not okay.
I think so.
Yeah.
Okay,
so here we go.
Go ahead and switch over to the music.
All right.
Whenever you're ready.
Okay.
Wow.
Casio,
what is this thing as c g k four 80 from
like hold on,
but let's acknowledge that you are the
one that bought that song.
Oh yeah,
I bought that was cute.
Fucking some cute shit.
Yeah,
I bought that song.
that was,
I wanted to hear us play that song.
Yes.
I wanted to hear us play that song cause
I know she could do it for that was,
I would buy all the lovely,
I'm like,
let's stay all night so I can just keep
buying songs for us.
Yellow,
you drink?
No,
no,
no.
Okay.
We have a challenge up guys.
John Dollar,
Ethan and Justin Kiss.
By the way,
the a $1.
How does this,
we're at,
we're at s seven hours and 59 minutes.
Literally 60 seconds until the record
comes out.
You guys don't have one minute.
You guys have one minute to raise $2,000
the stream will go down,
but it'll,
it won't appear in the Vaughan when I
understand how this works.
Honestly,
don't donate.
Let's wrap it up.
No,
it was eight hours.
We got we,
we should finish this off.
Everyone in the back's tire get home
until,
well,
let's wrap it up.
Joey,
how are you feeling by the way?
I'm like 80% better.
Let's a pepper spray.
Is that pepper spray was way more.
Yeah,
you can wait for real.
You going to have to kiss no fucking
laugh.
What happened from last year producer,
congrats on another amazing cherishing.
So make foul him is lost their home.
This is huge.
Much loved you guys in the upcoming baby
food budget.
[inaudible] an incredible composer.
Composer.
Unfortunately,
unfortunately he's going into the
composing world,
so this is Aussie from
chaos,
beautiful singer and wonderful band.
Unfortunately,
Steve Tobolowsky did not donate to
Ethan.
Justin Kit.
That doesn't help the challenge at all.
A favor.
Joe Blonsky.
What a legend.
Yo,
that's not going to be really gotta be
2067 with just broke 105,000
okay,
so guys,
Keith ended,
we got ended rather url keep it going.
We're going to have this thing out for
two weeks.
That prices are fucking amazing.
Key bit and keep watching.
First of all,
I have to give,
if you can use the camera back there.
Dan,
I want to just first of all,
thank everyone from the cast.
You have a cat like my God.
No one predicted they'd be here this
long.
No,
no.
I thought this was going to be a three
hour stream.
This has turned out.
Last year was our longest at five.
We're at 1120 that means we've been
going for eight yeah,
eight and a half hour.
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
So show me what do we got here?
This is h three history right here.
What do we got?
We have in the intern who's been
switching for eight long hours.
We got Mitchell who's helped us with
coordinating and research.
Make sure we appreciate you so much.
We've got Sarah,
the legend,
the xl wizard who's helping with
everything.
She's an incredible,
amazing help.
And in,
and Zach,
the sound guy,
he's got finals tomorrow.
He stayed eight hours,
way longer than he thought he would.
That guy needs to go to bed and get some
sleep.
And of course,
Dan,
the producer,
this word love who makes it all happen.
And uh,
and there's Ila who has,
has moved on,
had to go home because she was feeling
sick.
He's Milos now.
She's alive.
I didn't mean it like that.
And uh,
he'll,
his brother who was here all day was a
huge help.
And now finally,
I want to thank jody Sal's who risked
life and limb at,
came up stronger for it.
Not over tonight on his way to watch
that shit.
I wish we pepper sprayed you though.
Well,
there's always next.
No,
I'm kidding.
That always neon.
Next you wanted to do the stun gun,
but we want it to,
I wanted to shoot you with the nonlethal
beanbag,
but I don't what allowed that just
hanging out for another couple of hours
while we don't have a bean bag.
Unfortunately,
I start a new stream.
I'll pay them double lung.
He's got,
I'll pay your team doubles.
Not much even though I'm kidding.
I'm kidding.
We pay them very well.
Who Do we need?
No,
it's not justin.
We have to end this.
Alex,
her show,
second grader of gravity falls,
who's got so many amazing things to look
for it on Netflix.
Go take you out for spending all day
with us and your amazing generosity,
all of your amazing,
uh,
donations and your generosity in
supporting.
Thank you so much for being here.
We love you justin.
The legend.
Incredible generosity.
I'll tell you what I am is a fucking
annoying little cry baby.
Who wants everyone to stay later.
I will pay everyone in this room,
including me,
including,
well,
I'll give you like a dollar,
but I say we go for another round of
eight.
All right?
I still need to be here until everyone.
Let's fucking,
Stan,
thank you so much for your credible
generosity.
All right,
your,
I know you guys are all busy dudes.
You claiming spent eight and a half
hour.
We grade the hundred and $5,000
Aussie.
Thank you for coming.
Spending time playing beautiful music
for us.
If you guys liked her,
you could check out more for music and
chaos.
Chaos that's online.
You just type chaos guys.
You're going to find more amazing music
there.
Word chaos just twice,
just twice.
That's it.
Chaos Times too easy and of course all
of you,
you have exceeded our expectations.
Special have blown our minds from
everyone who donated a $1 the $1 made
such a huge difference.
We Pat,
we got 205,000
but I mean I was saying I'm not going
home.
I'm going to hold everyone.
Hospital made that happen.
That's true.
No,
you did that.
You did do one final shout out to our
host Ethan Klein.
Oh,
you didn't?
Maybe you may lock on babies.
How he does it have I love come on his
forehead this year.
Thank you Alex.
Thank what?
He does have something else on his
forehead.
I can't quite read it,
but it's beautiful.
It says Papa Papa.
Well that's a sweet or a bunch of
blurry,
but every,
everyone who dip deep during this
holiday season,
from $1 up,
you all our heroes and saints,
you,
we all helped this incredible because it
has been a beautiful Christmas miracle
and it's just been incredible.
A fucking miracle.
Listen,
everybody,
anybody that's still watching at this
point,
uh,
this Friday on our final episode of the
year,
one of the things we'll be doing is
recapping this stream and we'll be going
through all the donations that were so
many,
so fast that we probably missed some of
you.
So sorry if we did and we will,
uh,
definitely shout you out on Friday and
make good on all of our perhaps.
Yes.
So guys,
with that being said,
we will see you on Friday for a final
episode and thank you everyone for an
incredible evening and have a great
evening and we'll see you guys holes and
God bless.
Thanks for [inaudible].