Well,
hello there.
Thanks for joining us today.
We're back on this blessing,
a beautiful Friday afternoon and America
and evening in Europe.
Either way,
thank you for taking the time to join us
here today.
Thank you to our sponsors,
honey express vpn,
me undies and stitch fix.
I am happy to announce that on Friday,
two Fridays from now,
the 30th of November,
the great bill works will be here with
us,
which I'm so excited about.
So if you want to leave questions for
him on the subreddit,
there's a thread up there slash a
reproductions.
Been a wild week for us here,
California.
And California's been getting slammed
this week.
I'm sure you all heard there was.
Oh,
insane wildfire here in La and Ventura
County.
And uh,
starting with shooting though,
we almost didn't even get to pay
attention to because of the fire.
There's like,
the new cycle is like,
it's just a tragedy.
It's sad,
sad stuff.
So yeah,
right around the corner from my parents'
house,
there was a shooting and thousand nodes
and then the neck,
the neck night after the fricking whole
town's on fire from a wildfire.
You know,
I read something,
I heard something,
and correct me if I'm wrong,
Dan,
but pretty sure this is true.
I fact I did fact check it myself.
There was one or two people that was in
that shooting and thousand oaks that was
also in the vegas shooting at him being
like,
it's like,
dude,
what?
I mean,
well that's,
that's a mind melt for that person.
But uh,
I do want to say yeah,
my parents were evacuated from their
house.
They were staying with us.
We were,
luckily not that close to the fire,
but it was smokey and there was ash
everywhere.
It was really scary.
The whole,
the main freeway in La,
the one on one was shut down.
I mean,
it was,
it was apocalyptic out here.
It was wild.
Um,
we just had the news on like the whole
weekend.
Yeah.
I'm going to.
Couldn't believe it because it was one
day.
Just everything's on fire.
Yeah.
And you don't know if it's,
it could spread over to where we live
and just,
if the wind changes and it goes the
wrong direction,
you know,
but um,
we're looking at a place for my parents
just a week ago in thousand oaks or it
was a Westlake village is where was it?
Yeah.
And just so we could go and it's this
really beautiful little community,
the gated community and it's in the
woods,
kind of in thousand oaks is like a
nature preserve.
So a lot of the decks and they have
trees coming out of the decks and all
the trees are marked and it's like a
protected area.
But I remember being like,
man,
this is pretty.
Like,
I feel like a firewood ravage this place
pretty easily.
I was telling my parents,
and that was a week ago,
that whole place burned down.
But yeah,
the whole plate,
that whole community burned down.
It's crazy stuff.
And just,
uh,
there's a been a real tragic loss of
life and property.
And uh,
I will talk about that more later
because there's a lot of amazing footage
and stories that came out of that that I
think is interesting and I'm crazy wild
stuff,
dude.
But before we get now,
as you guys can tell from the title,
we have got to address a lot of the
criticism that people have been saying
against me.
A lot of people are tuning in probably
to enjoy an epic meltdown for me to wash
me,
make a fool of myself.
So that's why I'm here.
Dan doesn't usually.
He's,
he,
I sleep through the episode.
Yeah,
it has it on mute.
So I promise we will get to that.
I'm just going to be fireworks guys.
It's going to be a firewall.
But before we get to that,
I do want to do a goof for the day to
kind of lighten it up a little bit here.
What this vape God,
the Fda,
uh,
Tommy the vape God.
Somehow this epic troll got on Fox News
too,
I guess.
Uh,
he's speaking on behalf of the,
how do you call those?
Damn the jewels.
Yeah.
Which is these tiny little vape pen,
it's like a pocket vape pen that
apparently like in middle school and
high school,
everybody's hitting these jewels,
which is so crazy to me because when I
was a kid smoking was already not cool.
There was a couple of people that like
went out in high school to smoke a
cigarette,
but now all of a sudden with vaping it's
like cool again and these kids are
hitting these jewels that like 16 years
old.
Um,
so this,
this guy got on the news and it's just
instant credit
installation specifically with regard to
flavored varietals that have helped
propelled explosion in the use among the
young here.
Now to focus on very separate sides of
this issue that Schwab is Dr Tom Scott
Gabelli,
a blogger at barstool sports.
Who affectionally goes by the name.
Tommy smokes.
So because of the videos,
the first thing I'm gonna try sick.
Yeah.
That guy rips that zone and know both.
When they give me those,
do they think,
I really think that Fox News always
does this,
where they'll bring like I was watching
this video during the cabinet,
that whole thing,
they brought on a guy who says he's an
actual,
which that does incantations against him
and he's like the most absurd looking
person you can imagine.
It's like they always bring on these
people that you can't tell if they're
serious or not,
which are like the perfect punching band
to there.
So this guy is a apparently I think
she's taking him seriously,
which is wild bird song.
Joel Kenya.
Wow,
that's cool.
All right.
Sell me on why these flavored e-cigs
shouldn't be regulated even,
uh,
when teens are using them and these
increasing numbers will look.
I'm 22 years old so I'm using them
legally and honestly they're just cool.
They're cool.
You rip them.
There's nothing cooler than blowing a
fat cloud.
Right?
That's truly the Colossus of cloud.
It helps my swag,
it helps my drip.
I just love walking around.
It's really good for getting chicks too.
So honestly,
I started about a year ago and I know
that I haven't looked back since I have
a question.
No,
it's.
You use your cell phone quite a bit?
Yeah,
quite a bit.
Okay.
So why don't you rig it up to your phone
and that way you won't have like the,
the actual calories burned by grabbing
your phone so you can visit
what I'm talking about.
She completely lost.
Wait,
where's it gone?
Hold on.
Whoa.
Wow.
Ape and kind of check email and texts at
the same time you have like right off
the side.
Okay.
You could,
that'll be your invention.
I'm giving it to you so you can vape
like this.
Yeah,
right.
Like you don't have to keep switching
devices.
The humor that.
Did she preplanned that gag or what
seems like I'm throwing the.
She's like,
yeah.
The whole writing team came together and
we decided you should vape betty or
phone.
Well I don't know if this goes anywhere,
but I just wanted to give a shout out to
Tommy smokes.
The vape.
God what a legend.
You know,
he went out there and Fox and he goes
into the lion's den and he and he fought
the good fight.
He held his own.
Yeah,
he,
you know.
And for those of you wondering,
does vaping help you get checks?
Yes.
Isla didn't truly loved me until I
started blowing fat clouds interface.
So shout out to Tommy now.
Let's get to the reason we are all here
today.
I've been thinking a lot about this.
Let me take a little sip of water here.
This is difficult for me to talk about
because it's something I've been
thinking a lot about of late trying to
wrap my head around it and think about
it,
you know,
honestly and critically and trying to
deal with things in a healthier,
more mature way.
And it's kind of.
I have a long winded kind of story here
that I hope that will be interesting and
maybe helpful for some people.
Maybe it helps some people explain and
understand where I've been coming from.
There's been a lot of criticism of me of
late,
uh,
there's been a lot of people that have
said,
uh,
lots of lots and lots of videos and,
um,
I have a natural aversion to criticism
specifically,
which is something that I've been
learning about myself through therapy,
which I've started recently.
And so
throughout my career I've.
Well,
let me start from the top.
I'm getting ahead of myself.
What do people have been saying about me
recently?
Okay.
That I'm a hypocrite.
That I prioritize money over everything
else,
that I've thrown friends under the bus,
that I'm ignorant and poorly informed
and spread misinformation that I'm
arrogant,
that I cannot handle criticism and that
I've used to people just to name a
couple of the reoccurring themes.
I'm sure there's so much more you could
say about me.
Um,
and let me just say this,
okay.
For the record that I am guilty of all
of those things and I'm not going to
quantify it or make excuses or anything.
I've done those things.
I am guilty of those things.
And,
uh,
and this is something that I've been
aware of myself over the past couple,
last two years or so,
is that I have been kind of slipping
into a very unhealthy place mentally and
uh,
I want to try to go through this and
make sense of it.
Okay.
So it's been kind of a slow moving
process.
It's been like a self fulfilling process
in a way where it's gotten worse and
worse and I get criticized more and more
and I get more defensive or more hold
up.
And I went and,
you know,
early on in our youtube career,
I went very early on to somebody that
was universally liked.
I remember in 2016 I could do no wrong
on youtube
and like on,
on Reddit,
everybody loved us.
We were voted like Reddit,
reddit,
youtube channel the year or something,
2016.
And like the concept of being criticized
on,
on that level was something I hadn't
dealt with.
Um,
and I think the problem was that I,
people had me very high on a pedestal
back then.
I mean,
people thought very highly of me and
there's no doubt that at the time it
definitely started to go to my head as
well and I'm pretty sure,
you know,
looking back that I started to become
more arrogant and overconfident and on
some probably deep unconscious level,
a feeling of almost infallibility that I
could take anything on that.
Uh,
when I had,
I had like this one.
I really did.
I mean,
it's hard to come to terms with that and
to confront that because at the time
you'll never rationally be like,
oh,
I'm,
I'm out of control.
I need to tone it down.
Right.
And so because of this combination of
like overconfidence and feeling like I
could take everything on,
it led me to make a lot of mistakes.
And then when I was criticized for those
mistakes,
then I would act extremely
defensive and nasty and not really
processing them in a healthy way.
Like for example,
the leafy thing was and the Wall Street
Journal thing and stuff like this where
I kind of just handled things in a
really overconfidence,
really thinking that I can take on the
world.
And not and not do wrong.
And then when I ended up fucking up and
finds out,
it comes out.
Then when I get criticized,
I completely shut down.
I really,
I have the cycle I'm learning now
through therapy,
which I've just started doing about a.
I've only been doing it for like a month
or two,
but I have a psychological,
a problem where when I went for,
for whatever reason that I don't want to
get into.
But the way I was raised is that when
I'm,
when I'm criticized,
I psychologically shut down.
And so before I became like famous on
the Internet,
I had a problem with criticism,
but it was so much less amplified.
But kind of like when you become famous,
whatever,
for lack of a better word,
it,
amplifies certain aspects of,
of yourself.
And it definitely puts you through a
gauntlet of sorts of kind of,
um,
learning about yourself on an emotional
level and brings out all your flaws,
amplifies everything.
And so that thing of not being able to
handle criticism in my personal life was
something that I could get by on my
life.
And not really have any problems,
but then when you have like hordes of
people on the Internet criticizing Gill,
it can get so overwhelming that it
actually can cause for me like a real
psychological shutdown,
which what I mean by that is like,
I just feel it feels to me so powerful.
Like it feels like somebody died.
Like I get so emotionally and so well.
The result of that one is like I'm
extremely lethargic,
like I'll just lay down on the carpet
with like,
no.
Well then the other thing is that like
obviously I get super defensive and
super irritable and super aggressive
towards those that criticized me in a
way that's not healthy.
And,
and instead of learning from criticism,
deflecting it all the time and making it
the world's problem and not mine.
Right?
So that's kind of where my head was
after these first blunders I made from
overconfidence,
I would say.
And did you know things that I regret.
And it shattered my ego in a way.
And a real fundamental way that I've
also learned about myself is that I'm in
my mind.
And again,
this is through pet therapy that's been
really helpful for me,
is that I'm in my best,
most creative place when I have that
confidence and that kind of,
uh,
not,
not a place of a overconfidence or
arrogance,
but just feeling like that people like
what I'm doing,
that I like what I'm doing,
that it should be a wholesome,
great thing.
I said that.
And so I think that's one of the root
problems with why I've had so much
trouble creating videos for such a long
time is because I've kind of lost my
footing.
Um,
I've lost that wholesome place.
And so everything became very difficult
for me,
having shattered my ego and never having
address that or deal with it or
confronted it.
And so what happened from that is that
it changed,
it set off a chain event of,
of defensive behavior and caused me to
be depressed.
So I want to make clear that I'm not
using depression as an excuse for acting
shitty.
It's actually the opposite.
I was not processing and handling
criticism.
I was losing my confidence,
my ego was shattered and therefore I
couldn't make videos.
And all this other stuff,
and that's what caused the depression.
And so what happened now is that the
depression actually made everything even
worse,
right?
It made it even harder for me.
Um,
so it got worse and worse.
I get criticized more and more.
I get more and more defensive and closed
up.
And uh,
I want,
I want to make clear,
you know,
I just kept shoving it all deep down and
becoming more and more depressed
essentially.
And it's only been,
uh,
recently that I've been.
I've kind of hit rock bottom a couple
months ago where I was so amped up.
I was so,
so the depression that amplifies all my
negative feelings,
right?
That's kind of what the problem was.
And,
and,
and worst of all,
it made me extremely irritable,
which is,
if,
I don't know if you know,
like irritable on that,
on that level,
but it's the worst.
It's the worst because not only do you
piss people off,
but you start to hate yourself to them
because you're,
you know,
you're acting irrationally.
But the emotion is so strong that it's
like,
it can't be ignored.
Like just with Isla,
for example,
at home,
like um,
a lot of times when I would get
aggravated or upset,
I would direct my frustration towards
you even though it had nothing to do
with you because I was so irritable and
I,
and I'm up to and in that moment I know
that it's fucked up and I'm being an
asshole and I hate myself so much for it
and I see that it's upsetting you and
then you get angry at me.
But it's like,
it's just this overwhelming Iraq
journal and I've even learned
irritability.
I would know that.
It's almost like you're not being
yourself right now,
but it's such a cycle that I can.
I still,
I can't not get
upset because you're being worse,
dude.
You being crazy.
So I have every right to be upset and we
know that and then it's just such a
cycle,
like,
can't get out of it.
So because of this crazy irritability,
I was really.
I'm just making everything more
amplified.
I was reacting way too strongly and way
too negatively lead almost everything.
Even the slightest annoyance.
I would lash out at things and people
that were completely blameless,
Super Moody,
irritable,
guilty,
always in my head about something and
even a negative comment or somebody even
criticizing me and the slightly
slightest would like set me off and I
would just shut down.
Even people that like respectfully would
disagree with me,
with turn me like bitterly against them.
So on so bad,
right?
I was feeling I was being attacked,
like fit.
Like it was,
like I said,
it feels like somebody is dying.
I feel like I'm physically being
attacked,
almost like a flight or fight or flight.
Um,
so for the longest time being stuck in
my head and not being able to.
So the first two years I've,
I've,
I've always felt like I'm not been able
to grown or learn or maturing,
which is so difficult because I have
felt so stuck in like this really dark
black hole of negative feelings.
Just such an awful place.
And being so frustrated [inaudible] I'm
like,
why am I stuck here?
How do I get added here?
What do I do about this?
And growing more and more desperate,
you know,
by the week and just falling deeper into
that black hole.
And so I would say about a month or two
are about two,
three months ago it was when I kinda hit
rock bottom and I was like,
it was so.
I was just so miserable that I was so
tired of being myself that I was willing
to do anything to be anything I want.
I didn't know longer want it to be
myself because I was prescribed
antidepressants so long time ago.
And all throughout my life doctors have
been trying to get me to take them.
But I've always not wanted to take them.
And I think the reason for that is,
was probably that will.
One of the reasons was that I always
felt like I wasn't,
hadn't done enough to fix myself.
Like I kind of had this unreasonable
expectation that I should be exercising
two hours every day and eating salad for
every meal and that somehow it's going
to Jeremiah depression.
And until I had done that,
then I had no right to take
antidepressants.
But I think another aspect was that I
felt that it was weak or that it was
that it would,
that I was weak or that it was somehow
giving up or that it was,
it would change me.
I was afraid I'm not a big drug user
because I don't like altering my state
of mind and I don't like becoming
reliant on drugs.
But I was afraid that it would change
me.
And I think at that rock bottom moment I
felt so strongly that,
you know,
what,
if it changes me good because I don't
want to be this person anymore.
Whatever.
I remember hearing,
I don't know why I was thinking about
this quote from Paul Mccartney and John
Lennon talked about acid use and Paul
said he never really loved it because he
was afraid of it changing him.
But John loved it so much because he
wanted it to change him.
And I will always thought how,
what an interesting perspective.
And I feel like I felt both of their
perspectives now,
you know,
my whole life I was like,
I don't.
I'm scared to change and that.
And then from going from that,
like I'll do anything to change.
I'm praying that it changes me.
So I had this bottle of antidepressants
and my bedside and I said,
you know,
after dealing with this and hitting rock
bottom,
I just,
I started taking it.
Um,
I just,
I had nothing to lose and I couldn't
really go on anymore like that.
And so,
you know,
I was,
I'll say this,
the antidepressant is not at all what I
thought it would be.
The first two to three weeks was a
little rough,
I think as your body adjusts to their
medicine because there was kind of,
well,
first of all I was in such a bad place
mentally.
It's Kinda hard to tell what was going
on in my mind and what I was feeling.
But it definitely made me feel kinda
like foggy and loopy and zoned out.
I'm really zoned out.
Like sometimes I would just be like,
just not just totally absent.
I can remember once in the driving lot
of Ralph's,
we're driving and like,
um,
there was some,
uh,
crossing the street and you're almost
done instead.
Well,
I was driving super slow and he was
walking slow watching my car so I was
ever going to hit him because he saw me
coming,
but like he was standing there waiting
for me to stop for him and I was staring
right at him,
but I was just inching forward and I
just was like,
are you going to stop?
And I was like,
what he taught and I just,
I didn't see it.
I was just so,
like.
So I almost,
I actually almost gave up on the
antidepressant.
Uh,
there was a time where I was like,
oh,
this sucks.
But then I would say around like three
or four weeks because everybody says it
can be rough in the beginning.
And then it starts to work after like
three or four weeks and the side effects
go away.
I had a lot of anxiety too about being
able to perform,
being able to come out in the podcast.
We're make videos and feel like I'm
myself.
And I kind of proved to myself that I
was capable of that,
that he's a lot of my anxiety about
taking it to.
But what I noticed about the anti
depressant after all the side effects
went away and the fogginess and all this
annoying stuff is that I was,
it's Kinda,
it's kind of crazy.
But I was not irritable anymore.
Yeah.
I was still depressed.
I was still anxious.
I was still miserable.
But what it did for me that has been so
amazing and I'm so thankful for is that
it first of all remove the irrational
irritability and kind of gave me the
foundation and the tools to start seeing
things more for what they are
and not
this kind of crazy irrational,
irritable madness that I was
experiencing the world through.
And so that for me was the first huge
breakthrough I had in dealing with my
situation.
And I would just notice it and things
mostly at home with Isla and stuff.
Yeah.
Things that usually cause somehow fight
for no reason.
All of a sudden we were like,
Oh wow,
we did this without Friday.
I didn't even get a little.
Yeah,
almost removed my irritability
completely.
And I'm telling you this was
like
a godsend.
I mean life changing,
really life changing.
And it hasn't changed anything else.
I'm calm.
I'm completely the same.
I'm just less irritable and it's just,
it's amazing what I learned about
antidepressants that it just,
all it does is blocks to your serotonin
receivers.
So there,
as I understand it,
and I could be wrong about this,
but it's called a serotonin uptake
inhibitor and so your body produces
serotonin,
which regulate your mood and your
happiness and contentness and stuff like
that.
And so this drug blocks the receptor
that absorbs the Serotonin,
so it makes more serotonin available for
your brain.
Teasers.
So.
So,
um,
so it just makes you a little more.
You're,
it's,
it makes your moods a little better.
Really.
I began for me,
it didn't change me at all except that
my irritability completely went away.
And so things that were making me crazy
before I was able to see it for what it
was,
which I cannot.
Just little things like it's just
irrational.
So all of a sudden you see it as like,
oh,
it's just a little thing.
It's not there.
You know,
where before it would set you off into
like ruin my day,
running your day
or we will get in a fight and then it
would ruin and then I would feel bad
about making,
about snapping at you.
And it was.
But like how was it for you?
And when I started like,
yeah,
I noticed it immediately.
All of a sudden like it's almost like we
switched all of a sudden ICM,
irritable compared to you.
I know,
I know that like I'm not an irritable
person,
I think.
No you're not.
You've always been like super sane and
grounded and,
and great.
And I and I,
I wouldn't notice situations where I was
like,
so it's like we switched a little bit
because I would be like,
oh,
come on,
something that would upset me.
And you're like,
eh,
it's fine.
Yeah.
So,
but you're certainly.
Yeah,
definitely.
But you're the same person.
Yeah.
So that was the first really important
step for me because I could now see
things clear.
I could analyze things,
clear and boy,
what a difference.
I mean,
my goodness,
there's so much stigma against
antidepressants and I really,
truly,
and I,
and I was guilty of that
two I taught,
you know,
Eh,
you don't want to take it if you don't
have to.
I don't even know why they had that.
Well,
if there is like you're a,
you feel almost like a loser,
like you're weak.
Like you failed to solve your own
issues.
Now before we started doing youtube and
stuff,
I wasn't that irritable.
Right?
No.
So was,
it kind of made me feel more like how I
used to remember being in a sense that
I,
I always prided myself on being a more
calm,
rational,
rational person and that kind of the
self image I had kind of melted away and
replaced me with this really grumpy,
obnoxious person that I was starting to
hate
so that,
that was huge.
I mean,
that's huge and I'm still on it and I'm
so happy that I'm taking it.
I remember in college once there was,
um,
I was having awful anxiety and you guys
might know I had like generalized
anxiety disorder.
I could have benefited so much from
antidepressants in college and I
remember there was a sign at my very
progressive school ucse and it said
something like,
it had like Prozac and PROZAC nation
making some artsy claim that like,
oh,
we're all overmedicated and we're all on
PROZAC.
And the undertone being like,
you don't need this,
you're weak,
you're a sucker if you take it.
And I remember seeing that being like,
yeah,
that's interesting.
Who needs that shit?
And um,
that was a very popular sentiment.
I would say very.
It was kind of like a anti-corporate,
like anti,
like we don't need your medicine.
Also,
I'm,
I'm a person that's very,
like I said,
I have,
I have an ego problem.
And so admitting to myself that I'm weak
and that I need the help of a medicine
for me was difficult to [inaudible] was
difficult to accept because it's in a
sense felt like a weakness that I
couldn't handle it myself.
The truth is about that,
that I've learned is that looking,
reaching out for help outside yourself
as the first and the most important step
and recovering from a situation like
this because it's not a weakness,
it's,
it's truly a strength because you have
to get over your own ego and you have to
accept the grace and the help of other
people and the tools.
I mean,
this is a well researched,
funded,
backed by an incredible intelligent
researchers and doctors and
psychiatrists.
And to just write that off because you,
it's like,
I mean,
that's,
that's stupid.
That's not strength.
That's dumb.
Right?
So that was one aspect and now I'm,
the antidepressants are helping but I'm
obviously still depressed and I am
still,
you know,
not cured by any means.
Um,
excuse me.
So what was the next really important
step is that I was recommended a
therapist from a friend that I've been
doing for about like a,
probably about a month or two months,
a month and a half.
And um,
the therapy has been.
I've always been skeptical about therapy
too.
I think probably for the wrong reasons
because it feels like week to say to
another person,
I need help.
No,
but again,
it's like to think that you can.
You cannot.
It's so hard to understand what's going
on in your own mind.
Like again,
therapist,
this.
My doctor is a phd.
I mean this guy has learned,
studied,
schooled.
This guy knows how the mind works and
he's trained to diagnose it and to
almost debug it.
I think it's probably seen so many
people in so many patterns can
immediately like,
yeah,
put together something from what you're
describing that you would never even
see.
Yeah,
he's seen it all man,
but the thing that like stuff from my
childhood and the way I was raised and
the way that I reacted things,
there's psychological explanations that
are so important to explore so that you
can deepen your understanding of not
only yourself but the world that gives
you this incredible empathy for how
other people's minds work and how
they're affected by their environment.
And as I touched on earlier,
there is a very good psychological
explanation for why I get so defensive
and shut down from criticism that I
don't want really need to get into.
It was just goes back to the way I was
raised.
But just learning about that and knowing
about that and talking about it is so
therapeutic and it's so important that
it's given me such a good vantage point
and it's given me kind of the tools and
a little more support and foundation to
talk to even come here and talk to you
guys about this like this now and to
think about it more of a healthy way and
to
um,
it'll last time I came in here and
address Chris and all the podcasts I was
ranting and raving and going look in
like a freaking lunatic.
And,
and,
um,
that's just the symptom of everything
that I was describing.
And so for me,
being able to come here and talk about
this with you guys I think is important
for me because I see the podcast as if
nothing else honest.
You know,
like when I sit here for two hours,
live,
unedited over the course of nearly 100
episodes,
now 100 and hundreds of hours of footage
of me unedited.
It's nothing else but at least honest,
right?
Because I cannot hide who I am.
I cannot hide my defects,
cannot hide my stupid comments.
I cannot hide my um,
short temper.
My dushene is my shitty hosting it,
you know,
if I,
if I recorded this and put it into a
video,
I would cut all that shit out.
Yeah.
Or like you,
you'll try a joke.
And they were like,
well that didn't come off right.
So let's do it again.
But here you don't even to.
And you can't know.
And to be honest with you,
it's,
this podcast has been one of the most
difficult things I've ever done in my
life.
Like physically,
if you talk about it from the standpoint
of just sitting and doing it,
it looks like,
um,
it's easy to do.
Just sit here,
you show up,
you talk and you know,
but from a psychological,
from a mental,
from a,
from a lot of other positions,
this is the hardest thing I've ever had
to do because one,
um,
there's no take backs and so not only
are you,
the fans forced to see me more clearly
of who I am,
but I am forced to see them more clearly
of who I am because I'm someone that's
criticized youtubers and people on
Youtube,
you know,
what you see,
it's very people,
it's very nice when you post videos and
you can manage your it and put it out
and you put it out for the people to see
you one way and you get to see yourself
one way too because you cut out the
stupid shit and you forget about it.
And then people see the video and
they're like,
this guy,
this guy is great.
And you're like,
yeah,
I am great.
And you forget about you while you're
kind of a fucking asshole.
You're an hour of you being an asshole
and then 10 minutes over your bearing.
Good.
Exactly.
And so,
um,
I'm not surprised that so many people
have watched his podcast and been like,
Whoa,
that's not the guy I thought he was or
people who are making videos about like
all the things I mentioned because yeah,
it's,
it is all in here.
Everything you guys have said bad about
me and that you've noticed all my bad
personality traits and all that it is.
It's all in here,
you know,
I can't lie about that stuff.
It's all here.
So it's been difficult,
especially with this condition I've had
of being like depressed and irritable
and having a psychological Lee,
a unhealthy response to criticism,
but it's all played out here
and,
and it's Kinda the only way to do the
podcast.
Like our first five episodes.
Maybe we were trying to edit it down the
footage and thinking about it.
Like we used to think about a video but
it just wasn't right.
Like,
you're cutting now in conversation and
then you're making decisions on what to
live and it's not natural.
Exactly.
We came to the conclusion that it has to
be like this.
That's,
that's right.
It's a podcast.
Needs to be honest,
it needs to be uncut because you've got
to see the essence and the soul of
what's there.
A lot of times,
like you were saying,
you though we would try to cut out a
part of me saying something stupid or
are not just me,
but the gas stove.
We're like,
oh,
this is a boring moment.
And um,
that's just,
I think a lot of people were feeling and
we're feeling that,
that it's like,
this is a weird.
And so we took this leap into doing it
live and it's been really tough and
really challenging and
um,
very exposing of me.
I'm here bare naked in a way.
But I also think it's been really
amazing for me too because it's kind of
brought me here now where I've been able
to just take finally a close look at
myself and see it for 'em,
see it more clearly in a way that I've
craved so much these past two years to
just feel like I'm maturing and I'm
growing and I'm becoming a better,
more wholesome person.
And I'm just stuck.
I'm just like,
why am I so fucking stuck with trying to
be crazy?
Yeah,
you would say that to me a lot to stop.
I just feel like I'm stuck.
That's where or how or where,
but just feeling like I'm just pinned to
the floor or you know,
in a way in a hamster wheel.
Um,
but I think it's been a,
it's been an amazing experience in that
way that we've all,
we've all been just,
you know,
here.
Here it is.
I said those things,
I did those things.
I am that person
and it's good.
It's good to acknowledge that and feel
that and be like a,
you know,
it's good.
You got to,
you got to accept that catches walk
blindly.
And I mean it's just so messed up,
dude.
Like I said,
it's just a black hole and it's not,
it's just what I didn't understand.
It's just,
it's strength.
It's not weakness to come before
yourself and confront your many
shortcomings as a human being instead of
ignoring them.
And I think I was just,
I couldn't.
It was too painful for me too.
It was,
my ego was hurt and I was just too
painful for me.
Um,
it's so weird.
The psychology of it is so weird.
You know,
you think it'd be so easy to just be
like,
yeah,
you're right.
You know,
I fucked up,
but it can be so painful.
As Elton John Famously said,
sorry.
Seems to be the hardest word.
Um,
yeah.
I don't know why.
So it can be so hard.
Maybe not for other people,
but again,
this is my specific problem.
I think that I'm now learning about
myself.
And I said the Ila something recently,
I'm still depressed,
but for the first time in such a long
time,
I feel like there's a light at the end
of the tunnel,
which for me it was this black hole.
There was no escape,
there was no answer.
All I could think of was just permanent
darkness.
And now a subtle name with the help of
friends,
with the help of therapy,
with the help of antidepressants,
with the help of Isla has been with me
this whole time.
There's just finally I can kind of see a
path forward to getting better,
a path to walk towards the light,
you know,
and you know,
with a kid on the way,
my God,
I don't want to be,
I want to be better than this,
right?
Like asking them to be tough,
tough enough.
I don't need to make it harder.
Um,
I,
you know,
I want to say,
I readily admit that I've been at times
the awful host,
a terrible interviewer here,
the awful habits as a podcast host,
um,
you know,
speak on things that I don't know nearly
enough about.
Speak with certainty about things that I
shouldn't and I definitely need to do
better on these fronts.
I need to be better,
I need to do better and I expect myself
and I want to be better.
I've been,
you know,
I've heard someone say,
I forget who said it,
but they said if you're under a hundred
podcasts,
then you really have no idea what you're
doing.
And I really hope that's true because
we're co,
this is number 93 and I know I still
have so much to learn and improve as a
person,
as a host,
as an entertainer,
as a human being,
and we only have seven figures now and
yet,
despite all that,
so many of you have continued to support
us and show us love and appreciation and
to see the goodness and the sweetness
end me despite my best efforts to thwart
you at times.
I think part of me was so I was so,
um,
felt so distance from the fans in a way
recently because on one hand there's
people that hate me.
And so I'm like,
Oh fuck them.
I don't even want to read the comment
because I'm too fragile.
And then the people that love me,
I feel like because I hated myself and
didn't love myself,
that the love that they will show me
wasn't genuine,
that I couldn't accept it.
It was just them being nice or whatever.
I don't know.
And so I think that,
yeah,
I just,
I dunno,
I couldn't accept any of it.
It was just too much for me,
but I do want to say that from the most
sincere and appreciative plates for the
people that have continued to believe in
me and see something good in me and
something here that you like,
that it is amazing and it means so much
to me and I wanted to thank you all for
your kind comments on the episode before
the Tom and Christina episode.
I had made a side that nobody seemed to
like the podcast when there was a huge
outpouring of love and support and the
column is telling me that I should keep
it up and that you guys love it.
That was unexpected and very much
appreciated and a time that I really
needed to hear that.
I have thought about quitting the
podcasts honestly.
A lot.
Yeah.
Um,
because it's been such a pain,
you know,
it's been such a pan.
It's been so painful at times,
but I hope there's been good things.
It's easy to focus on the pain and the
field of pain and talk about the Pan,
but I hope there's also
no
another side to it.
And if you do see that side,
I thank you so much for sticking with
us.
And in closing to this long monologue,
which has gone quite a bit longer than I
expected.
Um,
I wanna say that if I have disappointed
you,
I'm sorry,
I know I can be better
and I want to be better.
And to those that have continued to
support us and spend your Friday,
your blessing Fridays here with us.
I want to say thank you for believing in
me and looking past my imperfections and
giving me the strength and support to
push through it.
And I do think that it's important for
me to talk about these things because I
think there's a lot of people out there
that can relate to my feelings of this
whole depressive attitude and putting
off getting help.
Because somehow for whatever reason in
your head,
I'm sure everyone has their own reasons,
but that it makes you vulnerable or weak
or whatever it is.
But I hope that people can take anything
from this.
That it's actually your weakness and
your vulnerability is part of what makes
you human.
And acknowledging that and reaching out
to help his strength,
not weakness,
weakness is shutting yourself off from
the world.
And then you can fix all your own
problems.
That's just bitter self-loathing
weakness.
And I hope that,
um,
anyone out there that is feeling,
you know,
feeling anything similar to what I said
that you do try antidepressants and
therapy.
There's a reason they're studied,
developed and used by millions of
people.
And professions is a science.
This is a discipline.
Um,
these people are amazing and they're
here to help you.
Um,
yeah.
anyway,
I don't know.
I hope that was interesting.
At least.
I don't know if that's what you all
wanted to hear for me,
but that's it.
What do you think you'll,
um,
anyway,
thank you guys all for listening and
bearing with me through that.
Um,
so love y'all.
And we will be right back after this
short break.
Nobody wants to feel like they're
overpaying while shopping online,
especially during this holiday season.
Gifts travels,
ugly sweaters.
That all adds up.
But you know,
there's an easy way to always get the
lowest price.
It's called honey my dudes.
Honey is a free shopping tool that
automatically saves you money while
searching the Internet for the best
promo codes.
When you shop online,
that means that wherever you're
shopping,
you're getting the best deal without
even trying on your favorite sites like
Amazon,
Ebayj,
,
crew,
Walmart,
so for expedia and more.
So much more.
Honey has over 10 million members and
each user has saved on average passively
without even trying $28 and sixty one
cents.
They've got 100,005
star reviews on Google chrome store.
There is no reason not to add honey to
your browser today because let me tell
you this,
it's free.
It works passively and immediately.
All you do is go off the checkout and it
does a little.
It enters the matrix and it's like,
boom,
here's your coupon.
It's that easy.
My dudes try it out.
You've got nothing to lose.
Get honey for free at [inaudible] dot
com slash h three.
Join honey.com/h
three.
Honey is the easiest way to save money
online while you shop online.
With all the recent news about online
security breaches,
it's hard not to worry where my freaking
data goes,
making an online purchase or simply
accessing my email could put my private
information at risk.
You're being tracked online by social
media sites,
marketing companies,
and weird fricking pervs in the bathroom
of airports that are still in your
credit card and your nude pictures.
That's right.
If you're using public Wifi,
Internet anywhere in a motel hotel
without Vpn,
you were putting your butthole some
shots at risk and I've sent Isla many
and trust me,
I don't want anyone else seeing those.
I cannot live with that being leaked.
Okay?
That's why I decided to take my privacy
back.
Using Express,
we be an express VPN,
has easy to use.
APPS that run seamlessly in the
background of my computer,
phone or tablet.
Turning Express,
vp on protection only takes one click.
Xpress vpn secures and anonymized is
your Internet browsing.
By encrypting your data and hiding your
public ip address,
protect yourself with express vpn and it
costs less than $7 a month.
That's a lot less than it's gonna cost
you to fix your credit after somebody
steals your stuff.
Okay,
and or the emotional damage of
strangers.
Senior butthole.
Let's put it that way.
Protect your online activity today and
find out how you can get three months
for,
for re@expressvpn.com
slash [inaudible].
That's e x p r e s s vpn.com/
[inaudible] for three months free with a
one year package.
Visit xpress xpress vpn.com/
[inaudible].
To learn more,
this is the year you can finally tackle
your holiday shopping early.
And guess what?
You get everything you need for you and
your loved ones at me.
Undies.
That is right.
Mandy's has the coveted micro modal
fabric that is three times softer than
cotton and if you've never felt this
fabric,
get ready to experience pure bliss and
underwear.
For now.
As you guys know,
I've made famous how stretchy and
breathable this me undies,
micro modal is.
Okay.
Now to spare you a shot of my genitals.
I'll put a hand here,
but name of fabric that you can drape
over you like a body bag and still being
cooked perfect.
Comfort and breathability.
This stuff is a game changer.
Okay?
They've got a.
You got to try it.
They're really true.
This is bliss.
Okay.
Now they've got holiday prints.
They got new prints every Tuesday.
That means you've got no excuse not to
celebrate the holidays right down to
your core and why stop it.
Andy's me.
UNDIES is launching holiday print and
lounge pants as you can see,
and one sees as well.
Both are made from the same beautiful
coveted micro modal fabric.
How can you not get you and your loved
ones?
A matching pair of this breathable,
beautiful me undies,
micro modal,
so listen up first time purchasers when
you get me undies,
you get 15 percent off and free
shipping.
Whoa,
that's a no brainer because you get 15
percent off the most comfortable pair of
undies you will ever put on to get 15
percent off your first pair of free
shipping and 100 percent satisfaction
guaranteed.
That is a no risk proposition.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible].
That is [inaudible] dot com slash h
three.
If you're like me and most guys hate
going to the store,
you hate shopping for clothes.
You hate picking out clothes.
I liked when I was a kid and my mom used
to dress me.
I'm not gonna lie.
It's so much more convenient.
It's so much nicer and let's face it,
she's got better tastes.
That's what stitch fix does for us guys
today.
Okay.
They're an online personal styling
service that finds and delivers clothes,
shoes,
accessories to fit your body budget and
lifestyle.
Go to stitch fix.com/three
and you tell them your size,
what style you like,
how much you want to spend on each item,
and you'll be prepared with your very
own personal stylist who will hand pick
items and send them right to your door.
Then you try them on pay only for what
you love and return the rest.
Shipping exchanges and returns are
always free.
There's no subscription required.
You can sign up to receive scheduled
shipments or get your fix whenever you
want.
Stitch fix styling fee is only 20 bucks
which is applied towards anything you
keep from your shipment and that's how
we do it.
Guys going to the store and all that.
You don't get to do that.
Okay?
All you gotta do is go to [inaudible]
dot com slash hp and you'll get an extra
25 percent off when you keep all the
items in your box.
That stitch fix.com/hp
to get started today,
stitch fix.com/h
three.
Give it a shot.
Thanks for watching and we are back.
You know in the spirit of uplifting you
all this podcast and keeping spirits
high.
I will not talk about the fires.
Devastating this state until we've asked
a funny video first.
Okay,
now,
fair deal.
Do you want to watch a wedding dress
explode or.
My new favorite show now on to Tlc is
the best network on television.
Every show is an absolute golden
nuggets.
You know what we're watching like a
wedding,
Jessica.
So 90 Day fiance,
as you guys know,
is my new passion in life,
but I have to wait a week and spending
time on the fabric.
Dude,
I'm in so deep and that is like gun a
ula,
Larissa and they are in jail and I'm
like,
who are you talking about?
And there's like 90 day fiance.
Oh,
okay.
It's fascinating.
Right.
But you talk about them like it's a
because it's,
I'm really mad,
so freaking amazing.
And like there's this really vibrant
community on Reddit of 90 day fiance and
they've got all these great memes and
discussions and it's fantastic.
It's so good.
But I need something to watch in the
week between.
And so the new show that I've found is
called extreme cheapskates.
Now these people are cheap on a level
that is probably should be classified as
a mental ill because in real it's not
like I'm getting what's on sale at
Ralph's.
It's not like getting these guys like
there's a guy and they're like proud of
it too.
It's very interesting.
They're all,
they're all,
they all have significant others that
are super embarrassed by them,
which I find.
But yeah,
and marriage and they seem exactly,
they all seem to be in really healthy
relationships.
But like for example,
there's this one guy,
he's like 40 and he's retired.
He's like,
I have financial freedom.
I'm retired from being a cheapskate and
none of my other friends have this,
uh,
this freedom in life and this guy spends
his whole day biking around for 12
hours,
not because he loves biking,
but because gas is too expensive,
I'm checking phone machines for money,
going to diners and checking the
cushions for coins and it's like,
that doesn't sound like financial
freedom.
That sounds like you could just get a
job and work less hours,
but they have got like this need to save
money in any way.
I think it's,
it's this need to feel like.
I think they got it.
They,
yeah,
they got that one up and I'm the result
of some of this stuff is absolutely
bananas.
So this is one of my favorite guys here.
This guy's such a legend.
He's a legend that during the first
season they only had six episodes of sky
was in two of them.
By the way,
on Amazon videos you can decide to buy a
season hd or SD and I went super in the
spirit of this.
Oh by the way,
it's going on there.
We were going to make a video and it
didn't work out and all this left is a
stupid fucking Erica that was going to
say you've got to show them.
Yes,
I love that the video didn't work out,
but you're keeping the haircut.
We had this whole idea for video was
going to be so good and I cut my hair
for the reaction and all these sketches
and we're sitting down editing it
yesterday and I'm just like,
we're both like,
this isn't good.
I just cut my hair for nothing.
You know?
Sometimes I'll walk outside because I
feel completely normal and I'll forget
them.
My hair looks like this and I'll walk
outside without thinking a walk shredder
and you just.
You're just that guy.
I know that.
Some days I'll look in the mirror like
last night and I'm like,
kind of a good luck.
Oh No.
I'm almost a kind of a good look.
Yeah,
if it was a little more symmetrical.
Yeah.
The way we kind of have your head tilted
to the camera,
that side looks okay,
but then you know that it's a problem.
Madmax cool.
Hipster.
Fall out a $5,
coffee,
coffee.
So you know what's been interesting
because I buzzed my whole head and I
took a fricking razor blade and razor
blade my scalp and that was gnarly dude.
But it was actually kind of amazing.
I have to say.
Oh yeah.
It was painful.
It was bad.
I have a new appreciation for people
that shaved their heads with razors,
but it was kind of Nice.
I think I'm going to buzz it all off and
bic my whole fricking head.
It's like it's such a freedom in a way
because your hair's gonna grow back all
beautiful and healthy and like how often
do you get to see yourself?
Just like bawled.
Everyone at home is also like,
fuck you dude.
Every day,
every day as well.
It's not being bold is not a meme.
I'm appropriating bulbs,
culture.
Um,
where was I?
Oh yes.
Extreme cheapskates.
Let's see what we have here.
So yeah,
I was saying this guy only had six
episodes the first season.
Oh No.
What I was saying is that on Amazon you
can buy a season hd or you can buy an SD
and save $1 and you have to dig.
They have a more options button.
You have to go in there.
And in the spirit of extreme cheap
skating,
I saved a dollar on this season.
I was very proud and honored with these
guys.
Most people consider the paper towels
and disposable,
like reusing spruce it up,
bring it back to life through set up.
Eva could reuse these paper towels three
to five times.
Roy estimates that over the last 10
years he saved nearly $2,000
just by reusing paper towels,
but he also went down to a federal
savings,
totally the truth,
which are kind of flimsy on these
disposables.
They get dull.
I sharpen them on the striking part of a
book of matches.
Give them a whole new life when you
can't squeeze anymore out.
Finished to be emptied.
That's the end.
And they just toss it away and there's a
week's worth still left in there.
I buy cheap to ply toilet paper and I
get two rolls out of one
that I have that I said you need those
two plys buddy.
Especially at your consumption level.
We've seen.
Well,
what did he eats too in that?
Do we have the clip of him at the
restaurant?
Because I need that one.
No,
but we haven't done one in the deal.
We got to watch that one.
This is nothing
price.
I do not enjoy two ply toilet paper
being separate.
I just kind of threefold it so that it's
a little thicker.
His toilet play third is a lot like life
in general.
The closer you get to the end,
the faster it seems to go.
That's a pretty well.
The funny thing about that I've noticed
about these cheapskate,
these,
uh,
cheapskates is that they spent so much
time,
it cannot be a worthy investment of
their time.
I guess they don't work.
That's the thing.
But like the guy will spend an hour d
flying and then re rolling a roll of
toilet paper to save like,
I don't know,
twenty five cents or something.
And it's like,
man,
these guys have.
But you've got to see this guy at the
restaurant because that,
that really ain't ain't nothing.
Um,
let's see here.
Extreme cheapskates,
why don't I look for it?
And you watch that clip where I got it,
it's too late and that it's a clip of
the movie day.
You've got this one.
I can't believe Roy brought me to the
movies.
I haven't been to the movie and I don't
know.
So she's begging him this whole episode
to take her on a date night,
which I guess they do once a month or is
it once a year?
Once a month.
And so she wants him just to buy them a
soda pop and some popcorn.
And he's like,
well come on baby.
What are you crazy?
So he has a novel idea that some of you
could use at home and yourself.
So are you hungry?
Yeah,
I've told you I wanted something to
pass.
So Mike could,
I haven't been at a big waste of money
to buy food at the snack bar with
concessions in any movie theater here.
Keep it low here.
People smuggled food into the movies
theaters all the time.
I don't like it,
but they do it by bringing my own
snacks.
I save at least another $10.
Eating a banana and moving.
There is a sad shit.
I can imagine.
It's like a banana and he's begging him
the whole time.
I want a and popcorn.
You said you didn't want the apple to an
apple.
I told you what I wanted when I came in
and I want to pop corn candy or drink
for instance.
Well I made a movie like what is even
going on in that theater?
I think they went to a crazy matinee.
They did go.
Yeah.
They went to like the cheapest show of
course.
Just completely empty,
you know,
probably it's like 3:00
PM on a when,
I dunno Tuesday,
who knows?
But here we go.
Lucky Day popcorn,
there were the garbage.
She grabs a bag of popcorn is literally
rummaging through the garbage.
Okay.
He does the decency of out at least
judgement.
The either gives free refills with
popcorn and soft drinks.
So I found a few containers in the
Trish.
I appreciate it.
That surprised my loving wife.
So how this isn't theft by the way.
Can't beat that.
Yeah,
pretty much.
I like,
uh,
he,
he pocketed a bunch of straws.
Destroyed too.
It's just going to ask you for this dry,
but you probably wouldn't come on.
Oh,
nice.
Thank you.
Wow.
You know,
this lady at after being together for
how long as they have,
she knows not to ask questions.
She's just like,
thank you.
You made it happen.
It's not probe to deep.
Here I am.
So they didn't show up,
but at the end,
on the way out,
he fills up the popcorn and the sodium
again.
The restaurants.
Shit is crazy.
He goes,
I don't,
I couldn't find a clip of it.
But.
Well there's the other family that does
it.
I saw this is important.
You guys might be,
I might be a,
he's like a borderline freegan.
Freegan yeah.
Have you ever heard of that before?
No.
Tell me about Freegan.
Freeganism is,
uh,
is people that um,
I don't know if they exclusively are
always vegetarians or vegans,
but they,
they have this philosophy that it's okay
to eat anything as long as it is being
thrown away.
So it's like a whole diet based off of
dumpster diving consensually.
Here was a guy like that in the show?
No,
I think this guy is down for anything
that's cheap.
So this family,
is it going to last one?
I show you guys,
but I urge you all to buy this on SD and
save that dollar.
So this guy,
their house was so wild,
so he takes his family out once a year
with change.
He saves all year to treat them for
enduring.
Um,
so he takes them to a buffet.
And uh,
this is wonderful.
You can imagine the dismay on everyone's
faces up to a Chinese buffet.
I couldn't believe it.
All I could see was food stacked upon
each other.
We work with fine dining live in the era
of the table.
What the legend news.
You're going to have whatever you want.
You guys don't seem very lumpy.
You want to sit and talk and you want to
leave.
We want to leave.
Want to go to at least give it a try.
We at least agree to give it a try.
I guess we're hearing his wife's pond
showed up at the last minute thing to
always help them out I guess,
and they're like,
oh,
guess I'm aunt Auntie.
He's coming with us.
And he was like,
yeah,
this guy's a legend.
Lack of appreciation and I'm going to
make sure that everybody's happy.
Alright,
cool.
What is that?
That's our food.
The plates on it was going to pay
for three people,
but there were six of us.
Pay for three.
Delicious.
I know I got your favorite three plates
if I have more than this number of
places that you pay for each of us to
get the band is the band.
That was unacceptable.
I was so mortified that he would even
suggest it.
So the guy we just washed and this guy
does the same thing,
so at the end of the meal they sharp
taken out doggy bags and then everyone
in the restaurant who hasn't finished
their food,
they start hitting them up and saying,
can I take this home?
That to me was the best part of the show
and I don't know why this guy paid in
coins too,
right?
Yeah.
And they don't show them pink.
He whips out like a panty hose full of
entities is so good.
You guys gotTa Watch this show every
day.
Started that Youtube trend of like,
huh,
they're Bradbury's.
We're buying Gucci store with pennies.
That guy's like,
dude,
that's just my life.
I'm not even trying to make.
What's the prank?
Oh,
I highly recommend.
This show is so entertaining guys.
There's so many more great clip.
These clubs don't even do.
They show justice if I'm being honest,
but enough about the funny light hearted
stuff.
Let's bring it down now.
Actually,
I do want to talk about the California
fires because I have a lot of incredible
footage that I want to show you guys.
It has been so nuts out here like I want
to emphasize how was just one day all
good and then in that evening on the
news,
it was like the whole freaking state was
on fire.
I heard a stat that up north.
That's the campfire,
right?
Yeah.
That this fire was spreading at the rate
of one football field.
A per.
I don't want to say it wrong.
One football field per second.
What's really?
Yeah,
that sounds well maybe.
Well,
well I mean no,
it's just hard to fathom it going that
fast,
but I guess that's probably.
Well it explains then why up north
especially there's 631 people missing
that there's a good chance that their
dads,
because this fire was moving so fast and
so furious that people were chilling at
their home or in their car in the
mountains and didn't even realize they
were in an evacuation zone and then all
of a sudden you see some ambulance
coming over the ridge and by the time
you're packed up on your car,
the fires consumed the whole.
Yeah,
I mean,
so there's a town up north paradise
paradise.
I do ironically named,
so this town,
it was really beautiful.
I love them though with California.
Yeah.
I mean it's really beautiful and
foresty,
but the state is so dr from a lack of
rainfall that basically everything's
just ready to go up,
which is what makes these fires so
severe.
Um,
the population was $27,000
and in this city nearly 12,000
homes and other structures were burned
down.
12,000.
Yeah,
it was at 6,000,
like the whole city.
I mean,
like a whole city was burned down.
12,000
homes in other structures and 631 people
on accounted for.
Seven people died in their cars and
paradise.
The boys was so hot that aluminum wheels
melted.
It burned.
It burned in paradise up north of
142,000
acres.
I have no way to fathom what that means,
but I have some videos I want to show of
kind of some of these people survived
and were unharmed and we had the,
there woolsey fire going on in our area
and that one seemed crazy.
And then once we heard the numbers of
the one in the north,
it's like,
oh my,
it was way worse.
Destruction there was unbelievable.
I think here,
because La is so densely populated,
the evacuation here was way crazier.
There was a hundred and 70,000
people who were under mandatory
evacuation.
Um,
there were 600 structures destroyed and
a three fatalities and this fire and the
one in La and Ventura County.
Um,
I want to show some some footage again,
all these people that were more.
Well here,
that's,
that's what it was.
According to the stats I have in front
of me,
correct me if I'm wrong.
Then those were,
uh,
I pulled that from CBS News and they
published it around noon today.
So it's about as up to date.
Let me see here.
So this is,
this stuff is,
so it's like out of a movie,
like I can't believe this stuff.
How does that fall for you,
Dan?
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Perfect.
Right.
So this is just,
where was this from?
The,
this is the Paradise Campfire,
the one up north.
So you can imagine like,
describe it for the,
uh,
cell.
It's that guy.
Thank you Dan for reminding me.
So this is a guy driving down a road and
I mean it's hell fire.
She's hell.
Fire up in hell.
Fire on both sides.
Amber,
when smoke and it's the highway to hell
man.
And this fire was so,
like I said,
spread so fast and so furiously because
it was so windy all of a sudden.
Yeah.
The Santa Ana winds,
which is like pressure from hot.
I don't know how the science works,
would,
it gets really windy and really dry and
so this guy could very well just be at
home not knowing anything is going on
and then all of a sudden he's trying to
escape.
And here this is what it looks like.
You can only imagine how hot it would be
in that car.
A lot of people have met their end when
from the car.
Literally.
That's so horrible.
So this is one look here,
retard can also just stop at any moment
because of the lack of oxygen.
It like turns off and you get,
you're just stuck there.
Yeah.
Um,
that's all fine.
Really horrifying.
Um,
well also trees could fall on the road.
I mean,
I never thought of lack of oxygen.
No,
that's crazy.
I don't know which one.
Oh,
I think this was from Canaan.
This is right in hills and move.
Drove up and down this road a million
times.
So how does that frame up?
That's okay.
Yeah,
looks good.
She's driving what is usually a really
beautiful and scenic road down to the
beach,
down to Malibu and it's just.
Oh yeah,
that's the Canon tunnel that drive some
of the time.
So she's going through a tunnel on the
ground and as she emerges on the other
side,
you can see the amber red go low stretch
through a merge.
She comes out of the tunnel and it's
just like,
that's such a scary drive to do it in
such a time because it's like you drive
to the mountains.
There's already they started going to
them.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
My.
It's just smoke and fire.
Amber asked the visibility's lift one
foot.
You're going to hear the.
You can hear the crackling.
Wow.
How the hell did she record this?
That blows my mind that she was able to
drive and recording the wheel,
you know,
and got her phone in the same hand.
I mean,
um,
and then so it looks like she's out
because she's in another tunnel and
she's coming out and then once again on
the other side of the tunnel,
it's just endless fire and ash and
smoke.
She opens the window.
You hear that
that is the worst road to be on at this
time.
So,
so scary driving on a regular because
it's so twist and turn and mountains.
And
I'm amazed that she was able to record
this.
I mean,
how can you.
Yeah.
I haven't watched if,
but yeah,
that's what she makes her.
Right?
She's fine.
I saw an interview with her afterwards.
She's laughing about the experience.
She's totally fine.
Okay.
But I,
I don't wish that experience on anyone.
I mean that is so terrifying.
Um,
but my God,
she is a hero for.
I mean,
imagine you're driving for your life and
holding a phone,
recording it on one hand.
That's something she needs to be like a
professional camera lady or something
because she's got it.
She's got potential.
Yeah,
incredible stuff.
Canaan is a landmark in Los Angeles,
is beautiful,
really beautiful canyon road that goes
down to Malibu beach.
So it's weird to think of it from a
beautiful scenic route too.
A hell fire.
So there's more yet.
Um,
we'll have we here.
Uh,
I just thought this was so crazy.
Here you can see that the freeway full
of cars,
fire creeping up the side of the cliff
and then a helicopter dumping water on
the freeway as cars are still on the
freeway.
I mean the fire spread so fast.
They didn't even have time to shut down
the freeway and evacuated.
So you can see these people.
You'll see I'm playing.
It's unbelievable.
I mean,
that's crazy.
Look at this.
Helicopter is literally dropping water
on cars on the freeway.
I think if we're going to stay from
getting hammered,
we probably want to imagine being in
that car.
You're just like,
whoa.
Right.
And the worst part is that people are
stopping the look.
So there's traffic like stop and go
traffic or right next to the fire.
Why would you stop?
Would you stop?
It's good.
I think it looks like what you see this.
They're all,
they're all right next to the fire.
Just stop and go traffic.
It's just because they've always done
the.
Yeah,
right there.
Who that is so fucking scary.
But that's just a testament.
Thou fastest thing.
A spread.
Like look at this just on the fricken
freeway.
Oh my God.
You have a guy actually splashed,
drifted.
He could see where it was going to drift
because of the wind.
Crazy.
Huh?
And I do want to say I was up at 5:00
AM the night that it broke.
And these firefighters are freaking
amazing.
Like being a firefighter in California
or any firefighters are amazing.
I have a lot of respect for firefighters
in general,
but these guys were grinding it out.
Five am,
I'm raging and Friday and they're out
there.
Uh,
all Doug,
24 hours just fighting this shit.
I had an,
an,
a profound appreciation for them.
And there was a lot of police involved
and a lot of
I saw a clip of,
and dude I know they say you're supposed
to evacuate and everything,
but I saw a dude,
he had like a,
it looked like a pretty poor house and
you'd like a farm and animals and shit
and his whole neighborhood.
I was watching this live last night,
not last night when it was happening and
his whole neighborhood was engulfed in
flames and the dude is just there with a
garden hose putting out ambers and it
looked like he saved his house man.
I mean he was just there with a fricking
garden hose,
like against this force of nature.
So I'm a huge respect for these fricking
amazing people out there.
And even now the fire is still going,
you know,
I don't know.
It's still,
it's still I,
I could be wrong band.
It's like what?
Sixty contained or something.
The one close to us.
And uh,
yeah,
I mean the one up north is still raging
as well.
So that's what you,
it's hard to appreciate it.
Like now the kind of the dust has
settled in the city as fires still
raging on and these guys are still
fighting it.
I just can't imagine that moment you
come back to your house and it's gone.
Where do you start in?
Okay.
It just look it up.
Was he fired?
That is 70 percent contained.
Uh,
the one up north,
the campfire.
A only 45 percent contain still.
Gosh,
Gee Whiz.
Um,
many really luxurious,
huge,
expensive houses burned down la,
like architecture and art and um,
and whatnot.
Like crazy.
I heard that.
I hadn't heard if uh,
if it had been confirmed whether or not
his house survived,
but the director,
Guillermo del Toro,
which you'll,
I know you're a huge fan of guy,
but he,
he has a,
a huge,
uh,
he has a huge private collection of
artwork from a lot of really famous
artists that in his house.
And last thing I thought about when I
heard about all day,
like I think it burnt.
I think I heard of Brian,
did he not?
That's me.
That's crazy.
Because he had,
he had a bunch of really awesome pieces.
I might be wrong about that.
Maybe you guys can fact check that.
I'm curious.
I'm gonna.
Look it up.
Yeah,
I know.
That was like,
as of a day or two,
it's only minor smoke damage.
Okay.
You miley cyrus lost or have a lot of
super rich people,
which is good in a way that because
these are people that can take it,
but on the other good,
but they can.
Well there their lives are not ruined,
but that's not to dismiss the suffering
that they'll surely endure from losing
all of their worldly belongings.
Horrible.
Yeah.
Can you imagine?
Um,
and Kanya Kanya hired private
firefighters to watch his house and
protect his house,
which was interesting.
God bless him in his neighbors to
evidently which,
which is the neighbors were thankful for
him,
but it was his own.
Yeah,
that's what I meant is that he,
he not just to protect us but to protect
his whole neighborhood.
Yeah.
I didn't know you could do that,
but I mean that's a little private
firefighters.
I don't know.
That seems 30 old thing.
There was saying his house is worth $6
million.
So I think when you have found much to
protect,
well you're saying,
you're saying what other people's houses
are burning.
Well,
it's just,
you know,
you can't afford the private
firefighters see your house burns.
Is that really fair?
I mean,
uh,
well world isn't fair and army of
firefighters.
Goddammit.
You go for it apparently though,
saved this whole neighborhood.
Yeah.
No,
that's.
I mean that is good.
That probably helped the firefighters a
lot because they didn't have to come.
That's true.
Fucking waste
resources on.
I guess my thought is just how these
private firefighters,
if nobody pays them,
do they just stay at home?
And I'm like,
well I'm in bed.
They're probably not necessarily
firefighters just like I'm right now.
It's probably like ex military kind of,
you know.
But uh,
I had the same.
It does sound weird.
I'm trying not to be cynical about it
because my first impression was like,
uh,
no.
Yeah,
exactly what,
you must be nice.
But on the other hand it's like,
you know what,
if you got the money,
if you got,
if you've got it,
flaunt it.
Oh for sure.
I don't blame Kanye for doing it.
Hell yeah,
but I,
I bet you in the end it probably did
help the firefighters a lot because they
don't have to worry about saving that.
He's like,
start with my house.
But then you know,
help other people if you can,
you know,
I got to say I don't like talking about
politics and I don't like talking about
trump and I'm not a forest ranger
obviously,
so I don't know how to analyze this
statement,
a,
the validity of it.
But trump's first response and,
and as someone that lives here,
I want to read this to you,
there is no reason for these massive
deadly and costly forest fires in
California.
Oh,
thank you.
There is no reason is this better?
Much better.
There's no reason for these massive
deadly and costly forest fires in
California except that forest management
is so poor.
Billions of dollars that are given each
year with so many lives lost all because
of gross mismanagement of the forest
remedy now,
or no more federal payments.
This was his first statement.
He did end up saying a lot of Nice
things and encouraging stuff,
but you know,
again,
I'm not a park ranger so I can't assess
his statements.
Uh,
all of that might be completely and
perfectly valid.
Right up to that last sentence where you
suddenly threatened pulling funding,
like,
you know,
have that fight after work where we've
stopped the fires maybe.
Sure.
Yeah.
My,
my,
my problem was just like,
as someone that lives here is like,
I dunno,
I feel like the world needs a little
more tenderness,
more compact,
a little more compassion right now.
And especially in these times when we're
so divided and everything.
So political and I don't know,
I just felt disappointed that our
president was making a political point
or using it to make a point or to attack
people when people's houses were still
borrowing the bore.
Dying and fires.
I was just like,
man,
I mean,
you,
you might be right.
I'm not even going to get until trying
to analyze who's right and who's wrong,
but I just wish that there was more
fricking tenderness and compassion and
the planet for each other.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean,
if there may be a lot of validity to
what he's saying about mismanagement and
you know,
things that can prevent it,
but when it's an ongoing disaster,
it's not,
it's not over like people are still
dying and it's
like,
just,
you know,
next month,
let's talk about that.
Let's talk about what we can do better.
And Donald trump really is a role model
for a lot of people,
a lot of people look up to and the
ambulance came and I just think,
I dunno,
it'd be nice to see more compassionate
in the world unless of whatever this is.
That's all.
And so I thought it was relevant,
just a little disappointed by buyer
leader.
I mean he's,
he leads all of us,
not just his base.
He's still the president of California
even though Californians hate him in
general.
So
yeah.
Um,
I definitely am going to donate to
support the people that have been
affected by this.
I was trying to research the best place
to do it.
The mayor of Sacramento,
which is the capital of California and
just south of um,
this really incredible fire up north,
um,
straight from the horse's mouth.
Is that derogatory?
Is that a relevant thing?
The horse's mouth gets horses shit
straight from the mayor's mouth.
If you want to help the victims,
please don't send supplies as the
evacuation center.
Say they have been in undated.
Those working on the front line and say
that giving to the Red Cross or habitat
a.org
is the best way to help.
So these are some good recommendations
from someone directly involved in this
to give you some ideas if you want to
help.
I'm definitely going to donate myself.
So there you go.
I've just feel awful for everyone.
Yeah,
it's just,
uh,
you know,
this,
this thing going on a coffee.
These wildfires are just.
So they've gotten so out of control
every season.
I was watching a documentary on Netflix
that was really interesting about it,
about the guy who's been following.
I forget the name of it.
Maybe you can look it up for me when you
guys and out.
It's about a documentary crew that
follows firefighters over the course of
like a whole fire season and the
firefighters are saying that in the past
like 10,
15 years,
it's been getting progressively worse
and the season's been getting longer
because there's the change in weather
and the changing climate has a produced
the less rain in California and so
everything's more dry and it's just
making the fire is way worse.
There's a lot of dead trees.
There's a lot of dry trees and
California,
a ton of wilderness.
Um,
so it's incense from due to the change
in weather.
Just a huge matchbox,
just a huge,
uh,
so every season like this,
this one now la.
Yeah,
fire chasers.
Thank you Dan.
On netflix.
It was really captivating.
Watch.
I gotta watch it.
Incredible footage.
Last year the one in Ventura was the
worst in history.
It was the most destructive in
California history.
And now this year the one up north beat
that record already and it's still
burning Ventura county.
I don't know what's going on.
Those poor guys,
man.
I'm from Ventura originally.
They're just getting crushed.
Man.
I feel so bad for them to fires
shooting.
They had that shooting and the next
night before they can even mourn for the
loss of like 11 lives.
I think it was 12 lines that,
uh,
the,
the fricking counties on fire,
same people that needed to more and had
to evacuate.
Exactly,
man.
Rough.
Probably if I had the guests are a
result of all the gay people bringing
the wrath of God.
I like this.
No,
there's,
there's like all these preachers that
say all the fires and everything bad
happening in the world is because of gay
people.
I swear to God,
go Westborough Westborough.
I mean people like,
um,
more reputable than that.
Like people with actual.
I'd have to look into the specifics of
it because I don't want to say anything.
Not True,
but I've seen lots of clips of preachers
being like,
oh,
all the fires out here in California is
because of the gays.
Eh?
You know,
when you rub dicks together,
what do you expect to happen?
When you rub two sticks together,
it causes more than just semen to erupt.
It causes sparks like sticks,
two sticks rubbing together.
God said,
no.
I rub two big sticks and a whole fire
burned estate down.
If that ain't the got gazed and I don't
know what it is.
That's why God says use Lube,
because if you rubbed Dick Dry,
you could burn the whole state.
Oh,
that's a good point.
We're talking about.
I said something.
Oh,
Ilos got where it is.
Pastor.
Blame scalpel all over this.
Let's see.
A pasture blames California offers on
states embrace me of Lgbtq Center.
A reasonable stance right there.
Now trump says that it's because of the
poor forest management and the liberal
ses because of climate change,
but I have an alternate theory that it's
a that gaze when two men rob dix
together,
it can cause more than just ejaculate
known for inflammatory claims.
A pasture.
Kevin Swanson,
a little subtle upon their inflammatory
claims.
Maybe it is a little fun with it.
Yeah.
Pasture.
Kevin Swanson is drawing a link between
California's devastating wildfires and
the states embrace of same sex
marriages.
Well,
it sounds foolproof.
Wrap it up with God's punishment of the
Golden State for legitimizing the sin of
homosexuality.
Imagine being God and you hate gay
people that much.
The Gay God must be really closeted or
something because he hates gays like way
too much.
The first gay pride March occurred in
San Francisco in 1970,
and then San Francisco legitimize
homosexuality in 1972.
He said in 2005 California state
legislators became the first state in
the nation to pass the same sex marriage
law.
Two thousand 18.
Well,
okay,
you got to have to draw more correlation
than that.
What is Jim Baker's?
Zach priest was similar views.
Other one.
You guys find a video.
I want to watch a video of one of these
guys.
Sure.
Now,
now a lot of people say that climate
change is making the state dry,
but what I say is that it's drag
butthole that's causing a fires.
What I say is that the gay people,
I haven't way too much fun and it's
causing all these Dang fys.
Please donate to my church because I
needed another private jet.
Uh,
what else we got here?
Folks?
We got,
um,
what the F we got,
men with beards are more attractive than
those who are clean shaven,
really real.
And who study finds hung.
Dan,
have you found that to be the case?
You seem shocked by that.
Well,
you know,
all of us as having a beard that helps
you.
There are statistical outliers I guess.
Well,
just imagine how bad,
how rough it'd be if you were shaving.
Well,
that's true.
That's a good point.
I mean,
have you gone,
have you been beard lists?
Uh,
in the past and uh,
to be honest,
very rarely,
not since I was a teenager.
Basically I've,
I've had a beard while I was
continuously.
I've had a beard pretty much since I
could.
And I'll tell you that when I clean
shave I feel like a monster.
I feel good.
I also really like,
if you'll come to kiss me or something,
it feels horrible too.
You don't want your perfectly,
it becomes like sandpaper.
I hate it,
but the thing,
I think the real ticket from it,
well this guy's handsome as fuck with or
without a beard.
So I mean,
you know,
a guy like me on be like,
here he is with no like,
but for me personally,
they did a study and they showed how
much are you likely to want to fuck this
guy?
They just showed people probably,
you know,
random guys.
But I do think in my case,
the beard,
it just hides my face and I'm going to
be honest and it's fine.
I'm not that insecure about how ugly I
am.
That is one thing I'm comfortable with.
But if you criticize me I'll shut down.
But um,
I don't know if that's what it is.
Covers my face.
I to,
I,
my details are not that good.
I've got a tiny chin.
I've got chubby cheeks.
Everything going on here is not
beautiful.
Chiseled.
I don't look like superman or wherever
this ass.
That's the 50 shades covered as much as
possible.
You can see my nose,
my eyes,
my eyebrows.
That's okay.
I don't know if that's what it is,
but I agree with the.
Went to stay with the premise of this.
Don't you think I look better with a
beard?
Yeah.
And it looks horrified when I shave.
No,
I think that about everybody.
I think I do think that it looks better
not,
and I don't like a longer beard though,
that I know there's a certain point.
Well,
that's actually what the study found to
right,
that,
uh,
they,
they check about that.
I will.
Let me,
let me read.
There's,
there's,
there's four tiers.
There's like clean shaven,
a little bit of stubble,
a decent amount of stubble.
And then like a full beard and the
decent amount of stubble,
which I think was 10 days.
No shaving.
That was the sexiness.
Let me read this for you guys.
Men who have full beards are seen as
more attractive than men who have just a
light stubble according to results of a
new study that don't say what this study
is.
So I don't know if it's a reputable in
any way,
but it makes sense.
Researchers found the widely celebrated
attractiveness of bearded stars like
Jamie Dorman,
Jake Gyllenhaal,
and Chris Hemsworth is apparently no
coincidence.
Doesn't hurt that they're incredibly
handsome as well.
Exactly.
The most beautiful men in the world are
found a track,
although could that be a cultural
phenomenon because I feel like in the
fifties,
having a beard was seen as kind of a
trend.
Right now.
You know,
I think it's a beards are.
That's kind of like a new thing to come
back if I,
if I'm not mistaken,
you know,
it definitely became like super hipster
guy with the long beard to buy like
beard oils.
Let's see.
As part of the experiment,
Male subjects were photographed clean
shaven five days after shaving 10 days,
and then after a whole four weeks
without shaving a 8,500
women were asked to rate them in on
attractiveness
as a longterm romantic partner.
Heavy stubble 10 days was found most
attractive while fold.
Beard's grown over four weeks came
second.
Oh Wow.
They like the full even more than the
light stubble stubble was third while
clean shaven was ranked the least
attractive.
Margaret.
No.
Shaving is so annoying.
I hate shaving to the skin on my face
and a lot because it irritates your
skin.
I feel like that's part of why I don't
like it too,
because I know that it's,
it doesn't look comfortable.
I like,
like you shaved your legs.
Imagine doing on your face.
I mean,
Geez Louise.
I'd like raising like some parts,
like my neck and the back.
I use a razor for the back of my neck in
the shower.
That's changed my life.
But the,
this is so.
The reason I grew a beard to begin with
is because it's so irritable.
I keep getting like pimples and cried
out and oily.
The whole God damn thing
river.
Uh,
I know this weird question,
but have you ever had a professional
shave where they use like a straight
razor and somebody does it for you?
I don't know that I have Dan.
And that's so strange that you would ask
that.
No,
I'm kidding.
That wasn't that weird of a question.
It's honestly,
I did.
It was nice.
It was awesome.
And it doesn't irritate you.
I mean that's the biggest thing is the
razor is so sharp that it doesn't make
you break out the way a normal radio.
I do have a fear during that procedure
that they're going to slit your neck.
Yeah.
Sweeney todd style.
Just fucking down the rational fear that
they'll just be like,
whoops.
Got Him.
I was nervous.
It is freaky.
I mean,
I've got a guy with a razor sharp
utensil to your neck.
It's a.
it's a little uncomfortable,
but seems nice.
I would go for that.
This article is on Yahoo style blue.com.
Yeah.
I love all these tech companies trying
to like exist in the shadow of Google.
Yeah.
Was style.
Um,
but the research paper concludes that
beards consistently render men with an
older,
more masculine socially dominant and
aggressive appearance.
Oh Damn.
Girls are fucking crazy.
I want a man that's aggressive and
dominant beers maybe more attractive to
women when considering long term than
short term relationship.
I'm looking for a man that's socially
dominant and aggressive for a longterm
relationship as they indicate a male's
ability to sex successfully compete
socially with other males for resources.
I think you're looking way too much into
this.
Yeah.
That time.
I think it's a fad.
Of course not everyone can grow a full
beard.
It all depends if it suits you.
Okay.
Whatever.
Tell him,
uh,
what else is google style?
Got To tell me about the word.
Do we have any clips of those crazy
preachers?
I was trying to find this Jim Baker Guy,
um,
but can't seem to find any evidence.
So Jim Baker,
if we've,
if we've a solid your name unfairly,
we apologize.
You may or may not
gave people.
Now many think that,
uh,
whatever,
it's such a stupid.
And even many people think that you
don't think I should continue with the
whole preacher thing or no els hitting
the board on that one.
In the crickets.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hit me with the crickets.
Yeah.
Many people think the blame.
I say being gay is fine.
Just as long as you lose you loop.
When you rub your sticks together,
you can hit me with the cricket on you.
Bended.
Tom and Christina were at the thought of
cricket.
They were like,
so they were both had this visceral like
what?
It's funny too,
because I,
I don't have that problem.
I know.
It's funny.
It's amazing to see they both really
like recoil at the sound of the
crickets.
That's amazing.
I love those guys.
They're so freaking awesome,
aren't they?
Yes,
they are.
What else we got here?
Oh,
we got some.
Should we go onto fan submissions?
We're at an hour 45.
Yeah.
It's time.
Uh,
Joshua mccardy says hi.
I'm a big fan of the show and thought I
would suggest showing this gem of a
video.
I'm from eastern Kentucky and my local
news station had a segment about a
robbery.
I won't say anymore,
but encourage you to watch and enjoy.
Thank you josh.
Wall for thinking about it.
Getting some really great clips from.
Yeah.
I want to say guys
keep sending shit to podcasts at h three
h three productions because there's been
some absolutely great stuff there.
I want everything.
I want questions you want to advice you
have any reaction,
any suggestions for a reaction?
Videos you like,
what you see?
Um,
it always looks good on that.
I was saying when I looked in the mirror
last time,
I was like,
damn boy,
I have you turn your head all your hair
like that.
No,
you wouldn't.
no.
I don't know what you think I could walk
down.
You agreed that it almost looks good.
So what I mean is that it looks like a
style.
Yeah.
I think I could get away with it.
Honestly.
It's just not.
Not,
not the side you're showing us right
now.
Not that one.
And yeah,
maybe not that.
It looks like you evacuated.
Well getting a haircut.
It's just not my style.
I'm not,
I'm not.
I'm not slamming the style.
It's just not my style.
Yeah,
that's all.
But I actually,
it was,
I swear to God,
it felt so good to do it all the way
down.
It's really,
really amazing.
It grows so fast,
so it's already like it was the skin two
days ago.
Yeah.
Huh.
I wonder if there's a research about the
hair stubble research found that men
were more attractive when they weren't
completely bald to the skin.
Zach just pointed out,
you actually looked like the dude from
the dude,
from his Robert Deniro,
from taxi driver.
Yeah,
I know.
We wrote out a bunch of them.
We had a bunch of hair.
That was one of the insults.
I have my,
we had a,
I looked like Mr.
Cleans inbred cousin.
And then how do you look like a,
how do you look like a Jew and a Nazi at
the same time?
Yeah.
But that was really.
And they were,
it looked like it when it was super
skinhead.
Um,
we had a lot more.
you look like a
definitely taxi driver reference at the
end there.
God torturing people.
People are going to be demanding this
video now.
In the end it was really bad.
You're not missing anything folks.
The haircuts,
the best part.
You're getting all the good names.
Um,
what else?
There were so many.
Let me just,
I'm going to look like where we got
nothing to do.
We're at the end of this video.
Our fans.
We have this video.
No,
I'm going to wash that.
I just,
I want to at least,
uh,
enjoy.
What little jokes I want to salvage,
whatever I can from this.
There wasn't much more than what we
said.
Let's see.
Uh,
you look like a 90 villain extra.
Yeah.
A little bit.
Those were all meant for me to say to
you look like a dollar store.
Zurich from Fifth Element.
I think my favorite is how do you look
like a Jew and skin at the same time.
And Mr.
Cleans inbred cousins.
Yeah.
That's all.
I got guys,
great video that I just gave you the
highlights.
We can just clip this and putting this
on our main channel,
but hopefully we're going to start over
and why couldn't you have video,
new subject,
new everything and hopefully I can
leverage this haircut into a new joke
because I don't want to waste a broccoli
assassin.
Cut for now.
I was calling this the carat cut because
the Broccoli was more about the crown.
Carrot is more about the stem.
It's like a carrot cut.
If I had spray Tan,
it could be a real character,
but like a nice orange.
You.
What could make that happen?
All right,
let's watch this.
Thank you too for your submission.
Uh,
Joshua,
your home is never a good idea of floyd
county man found that out for himself
after having a gun pointed at him when
he did.
Just that way.
Empty Sean Allen talk with the victim.
In that case we'll say math is on the
rise.
Math as a result.
So it must've been a bad batch around
here called forward.
Counties went crazy in the last four
days.
Neighbors notify Mason Tackett that his
cousin,
Phillip,
Matthew Higgins was seen carrying items
from his house
when I finally got down here and for the
house to look.
So you walk out the door was standing
wide open.
It looked like he was packing up for
yard sale.
You got my fan by the way.
They wanted hagans
cracks me up.
What is he like one inch tall?
It's like a chase through grant.
It's like from his perspective,
no,
it's not that everybody else wants
Tackett found items belonging to him.
Pull a gun on me when I got back around
the house because I guess he thought I
was upset with him.
Items not normally.
The target of the would be burglar who
steals a cheese grater.
She's got the worst.
He stole the empty bottle of was my soap
stone massage.
I still feel the pagans is charged with
receiving stolen property and being a
convicted felon with a firearm in Turkey
creek.
Sean Allen,
way empty mountain.
New Tech.
It hard to believe that it's not a
sketch.
Still be stolen.
Who steals a cheese grater?
That guy's awesome.
His accent is amazing.
It's amazing.
What did you say?
Kentucky.
Go lead.
I feel like that deserves a golly.
I feel like that deserves a jimminy
cricket
and really you could say anything with
that.
Excellent.
And it would be fun and amazing.
I'll tell you what.
No thank you.
Say hit me with that cricket.
You got to just using it after he hit
me,
like I really don't mind that either.
Can't use it anymore.
So I'll lead jimminy cricket.
Who steals a cheese grater?
He stole my Nana's.
I gotta find something,
you know,
a boo just Bu.
Um,
this was an interesting story.
Taylor swift apparently used to travel
in a suitcase to avoid hopper Razzi.
Now Taylor swift is one of the most
famous people in the world.
And so I can understand that,
uh,
trying to avoid popper Razzi was
probably a source of great discomfort
and a and annoyance to her to say that
lead,
but the,
the level that she went to to avoid them
was amazing.
And I want to say is a testament to how
annoying these people are.
Rather than that,
it should reflect poorly on her.
That being
said,
it is incredible.
Uh,
Zane,
this was the one direction.
Confirm.
Keep confronting winter.
So this guy from Zane says Taylor swift
was traveling around a suitcase during
the summer of 2007.
Um,
and so he,
I love the heat.
So here it is.
Here's the alleged suitcase
the other day explained to me that this
was actually a rumor at the time and was
like,
dismissed as just being kind of a meme,
but it's just way too over the top to be
real.
But now evidently this guy saying,
no,
you don't.
This is all really happening.
Taylor swift.
So when they were dating or they were
friends,
I know you're super famous and now he's
funny.
He's an outing.
Elaborated.
Yeah.
I mean imagine that.
Imagine that she's in that sick also.
It's such like an undignified thing for
someone like Taylor swift.
All right.
Now curl up and getting the suitcase.
I wonder if it's like,
well,
pad it.
If it's nice and cool.
I was wondering.
That's what I like or know of it.
Or is it even like form cut to her.
You know what I mean?
Like it's a little like fetal position.
Taylor swift slot that she just doesn't
have that much space in there.
Taylor swift being transported in a huge
suitcase from our tribeca apartment in
to her truck fleet of cars,
including two large cadillacs and three
suv is arrived at Taylor's apartment,
Tribeca to move a large suitcase from
her apartment.
Also dozens of Taylor swift security
guys were present to move this package
carefully as Taylor swift remains to be
unseen for a long time.
Now I went and there's a bunch of other
photos of this suitcase
and for the audio listeners,
stay understand this suitcase is not
that bad at all.
Well,
you would have to be smaller than a
person for sure.
She definitely laid
barone all crunched up in a ball cannon
ball into a swimming pool.
So
here some detectives have a little
bigger than a regular suitcase.
I feel like.
Well,
it looks like a mute for use for
musical.
That's what it looks like.
You can see here.
I mean if anything,
this is kind of a testament to help
FDIC.
This Papa Razzi imagine you're willing
to do crawl into a fricken suitcase to
have.
Well,
do you know what she's doing?
She probably wants to go do something
private.
Maybe she wants to fly somewhere,
go to a beach without everyone knowing
what she's doing all the time every day.
So if like I get it.
If you're trying to go hang out with all
these filters like filming you and
recording you,
it's like,
you know,
you got to do what you can.
I always see videos of Justin Bieber and
the proprietor people driving him crazy.
Yeah,
they're pretty aggressive with Justin.
I've seen that shit too.
It gives them shipped back though.
I like watching those,
but there's a lot of videos where he's
nice at first and they really push it
and then they start asking him really
inappropriate getting in his way so he
can drive away.
Yeah.
Yeah,
man.
Fame on that level is really.
It's so.
It's so cheap.
People need to appreciate how
challenging and
I mean those aspects for sure.
People are paid to try and piss you off
literally,
like they're just there to piss you off,
so you flip out and then it's a story
story,
right?
Yeah.
Just imagine that everywhere you go in
public,
people are paid to Piss you off and
record it.
Yeah.
I mean,
so I hope that people have a more of
appreciation for what ultra famous
people go through on a day to day basis
is that it's not all just because
there's.
I always hear this kind of sentiment of
like,
Oh,
you have no right to complain once I
tell that to somebody that crawls into
side a suitcase.
I mean obviously the riches and the fame
that,
that's nice and I'm sure they enjoy
but you're right,
it comes with baggage.
Comes with some serious bag,
a lot,
a lot money doesn't buy you happiness,
I guarantee and promise you that buys
you a one way ticket in a freaking
suitcase in this case.
Um,
I thought that was wild.
I was frankly shocked by that.
What else?
Uh,
what else we got?
What they forgot.
What else do we got?
People showing an explosion.
Ian,
do you have anything to say about this
Kanye Ego?
Like of the dance group?
You want to come in here and watch it
with us?
He's like chickens.
I please know really does not much to
watch.
I in,
in here like Ben and he's nice.
He's sweet,
he's a great guy.
He's got a good presence,
you know,
but if you don't want to,
I won't force you.
I may not understand that.
Uh,
you have a choice.
I'm not going to podcast rape you,
but you are fired if you don't come.
Yeah.
Let's,
uh,
let me find it.
There's a new meme now about,
uh,
what else?
Me saying what else there is.
Yep.
Used to be fascinating.
Now it's what else?
That's funny.
It's been a long,
long pot.
Okay.
Where is it?
I got a whole list of things here.
What else do you see it in this document
that I'm looking at it right now.
You can do.
Highlight it for me.
Why don't I see it?
There it is.
Okay.
Kanye has gone on stage,
dressed as the joker.
A,
correct me if I'm wrong.
Not intentionally.
It looks like the joker.
I hate to say this and I don't want to
offend anybody,
but he kind of looks like the guy that.
I hate to say this.
So don't say you shouldn't.
The hair and the joker is reminiscent
of,
okay,
I'm not the guy that shot up the theater
on the Batman.
It's not saying yes shooter,
just saying it looks like the guy.
Is that awful to say?
I mean,
it's just the orange hair.
Right?
Right.
So
yeah,
he looks like he's doing the elaine
dance kind of thing.
How people have speculated that he's on
drugs.
Is that substantiate or you think he's
just having fun?
I think once the power of that music
just takes over your soul.
You can't do much,
but just let it possess you.
Like that's the drug.
The beauty of his music.
Thank you.
He very much reminds me of in though
then a little bit of a goober just in
general,
like fun.
What am I talking about?
Why maybe you such an asshole.
He's having a good time,
man.
He is letting it go.
Dance like nobody's watching.
That's what they say.
They going to judge the guy.
We're having a good ass time.
Why?
People got to say it looks like the
shooters shot up Batman Theater.
Who's saying that?
Ignorant.
He's having a great time.
Yeah.
I wish I could go out and dance like
that.
Get it.
I heard that people were really happy
with his performance.
Actually
having a good time.
Dude.
Look at me being a.
let's see what they think.
Somebody aunt,
whatever.
I don't need to re imagine reading
reddit comments on live on a podcast.
Well,
it's been two hours less.
The wedding dress is very short,
so let's wrap it up here.
Texas woman declares a tech was woman's
celebrates or divorced by blowing up her
wedding dress.
Well,
I can see that.
That was a healthy relationship,
man.
What the hell did that guy do to you?
There's like a whole party here to
celebrate.
Why?
Oh my God.
That was a lot more than I expected.
Just be like a little mad or something.
That's a real explosion.
What that guy did to her man,
but whew,
that's a good.
It's a good thing.
You guys got divorced.
Yeah.
Alright guys.
We're thinking of doing an extra episode
on Tuesday now.
Me,
a fan of the Howard
stern show,
they have this segment called cleaning
out the computer,
which is all the segments and all this
stuff they had planned that they never
got time to do on the show.
Thinking of setting up a panel here with
Ian and Dan to join us and to go over
all the great things of the year that we
never had time to get to do an extra
episode on Tuesday.
Let me know what you guys think about
that idea.
Not that,
uh,
wow.
Who Watches the steep anyway?
If you're watching type in the comments.
Um,
uh,
what should they type in the comments
for the frog loves a Ms.
Dot piggy is big titties,
right?
Yeah.
That's the classic.
That was the big one.
But I want to know.
Um,
did you know that I read this?
That farts used to be to actually a
danger to public safety before people
started wearing underwear because you
actually fart out aerosol shit.
Particles and people could breed them
and get sick.
I swear it.
That's what I read.
That's why people wear underwear.
They invented it back in the day.
So how much just underwear do,
did you read this?
I read it.
I don't remember,
but it seemed credible.
But that your farts obviously our permit
or passed through the fabric.
So the ship particles are not allowed to
freely enter your,
your neighbor's face.
You.
But look that up.
I swear a faculty commando is like a
public health nuisance.
Well,
no,
I think through the pants you're
probably fine,
but if you're like bare ass farting,
I don't know.
Look it up.
I swore a fact.
Check me right now.
Yellow.
He was all fucking day.
I think that whole,
that whole statement about being
dangerous.
That's what people should type if
they've stuck around this data type.
This did,
you know,
farts are dangerous if you're not
wearing underwear
done deal.
And then if I see that,
I'll know that you want an episode on
Tuesday.
Well if you watch this deep,
you probably do want app.
So on Tuesdays,
this isn't a good sample size
necessarily.
Let's end this guys.
Have a blessed beautiful Friday.
Thank you all so much for watching.
And again,
I want to thank you guys too for all the
nice comments.
The episode before last was an amazing.
Yeah,
no,
I mean there's spent a lot of criticism
which I'm happy that I've acknowledged,
but there's also been a lot of love and
support and understanding which I have a
tendency to focus on the negative and
this semester positive,
but that's so messed up.
And everybody who takes their time to
show support and love it means so
it's so important to me.
So appreciate it.
Thank you.
I mean truly.
So with that being said,
I didn't mean to do that one.
I'm sorry.
You guys know the audience loves that
one.
I meant to do that.
Well,
I'm not going to touch the sound.
Um,
thank you all.
Have a blessing.
Beautiful Friday.
Wonderful.
Productive,
happy,
wholesome weekend.
There's a good chance we might be her on
Tuesday and Friday.
And then the week after Bill Wirtz,
which I'm also.
Was there any progress on getting a.
What was his name?
The comedian.
I love.
I'm blanket.
You weren't in touch with them.
Oh,
uh,
yeah.
Um.
Oh God.
Ryan,
A.
Brian.
Brian Regan.
There you go.
I love him so much.
So he might be coming home.
There's no plan.
We are also planning to do what?
Charity stream like last year.
Yes,
and that might be the last episode of
this year.
Right?
That's what the heck was that cheering?
I don't we.
We've officially run out the outro song.
It's looping.
Oh Shit.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go.
We got plenty of time.
We talk about that.
We'll have time to talk about it.
That was going to be on December.
Well,
hey,
thanks for watching guys.
We love you.
Wish you all the Cape Creek watching.
Will some of you on Tuesday?
I might.