Five four,
three,
two.
Well,
hello everybody and thanks for joining
us today on the HD podcast joined by the
wonderful Jack Black and kyle gas yes,
of tenacious d of whom we are all we all
love and appreciate.
Uh,
today's episode is sponsored by me,
Andy's Vince Zero Robin Hood and meant
mobile.
Now you guys are here.
I can hear myself Dan,
but that's okay.
Do you guys have a new animated series
posts apocalypto that is on youtube
right now for free.
Yeah.
Why isn't everyone closing this and
watching that?
Well listen to what they have to say,
right?
I think it's kind of hard to find,
but I'm an old man.
I think the best way to find the full
movie post apocalypto is to go to
tenacious d.com
and just click on it there for free.
And if you also go to tenacious d.com
you can find out that these two
wonderful men are touring all throughout
this month.
So grab some tickets and catch the d
live.
The best one to see of all the shows
were playing is a December 30th in Las
Vegas.
We're doing something very special,
like it's,
I can't say what we're doing there,
but that's the one,
if you can,
you should get on a plane and fly to see
tenacious d in Las Vegas on a lot of
people are gravitating.
Yeah.
Towards our New Year's eve show in Las
Vegas.
And that's the natural show.
But the good show has nothing to do with
the tickets.
Tickets left.
It's a little well,
and also variety for your consideration.
Tenacious d did you guys see that
though?
I don't know who put that in there,
Huh?
Well,
clearly I watched em
loved so much this,
this,
uh,
is it a movie or Shell?
Because it's six parts and then you've
got it all together in one slot.
So do you think of it as a movie or a
show or a show?
Well,
we have found that the best delivery
system is actually on a big screen in a
movie theater and just see it at all at
once,
sharing it with the fellow fans.
And
it's more of a movie.
So we didn't know we,
I think we accidentally made a movie.
We're making little episodes.
You're making little five to 10 minutes
episodes.
And then when we got,
when we got to the sixth episode,
the finale,
we realized if we took away the intro
outro and,
and ran them as one movie,
it actually played the best.
So yeah,
we think of it in a lot of different
ways.
It's an album,
it's a TV show.
It's a movie.
It could be a broadway play,
could.
It is.
Yeah.
Well the live show is very a rock opera
ask presentation of
the material as well.
Yeah,
that sounds Super Fun.
Yeah.
Now I can maybe one up and you know
Bruce springsteen's on Broadway right
now doing his show.
I don't think he has any,
any lights and magic.
He's an old singer songwriter.
So I thought,
why don't we just,
you know,
well,
I think you're kidding,
but I would,
I would watch the heck out of a post
apocalypto Broadway show.
Well,
you know,
part of the reason why we did,
part of the reason,
part of the reason why we did post
apocalypto as we were jealous of a book
of Mormon are our arch enemies in south
park.
Did this incredibly funny musical
comedy.
If you get a chance to see it,
it's probably playing near your town
now.
A Super Raunchy,
uh,
politically incorrect,
a broadway musical.
And we were like,
yeah,
we,
we want to party in that sphere.
Genre rock the dramas.
Well,
there's isn't really a rock opera.
Yeah,
you're true.
It's actually classical classic.
It was a broadway,
it was so hard to see.
And I was living in Israel at the time
and there was so much hubbub about it.
I really wanted to see it.
And the only thing I was able to find
was a gentlemen recording it on his cell
phone the best way,
one of the back isles.
And I have to say,
I don't remember much,
but I think it was good.
Yeah.
We should still like,
yeah,
we should catch it.
Yeah,
but so you guys did everything on this
and it's a very unique style you've got.
It's a cartoon,
but it's what,
it's like one frame every 10 seconds.
So you guys kind of,
which I find charming.
It's not like I wouldn't consider it
like it's,
it's just a style.
And I think it's very charming.
Was this some like a style that you guys
chose four or was it kind of an
expedient thing?
Well at first we were thinking this is,
we're just going to do a real rough
version of what our fully animated show
would be.
You know,
we're,
we were making our rick and morty
basically and uh,
nobody wanted it on any other network.
So then we were like,
oh,
we're going to just do it our way.
And it was,
uh,
just the cheapest way to do it.
Right.
But at the end of the day,
it ended up being in a way funnier than
it is here.
It is charming.
Yeah.
I,
there wasn't any point where I was like,
oh,
I wish I had more frames.
Right.
Cause you get it.
You totally got it.
And I mean this,
I totally understand.
As I watched that robot vagina suck and
swirl on that cough,
I Scott boiler alert in a way.
It makes it less than a graphic while
it's just frame.
You know what I mean?
I don't know.
I was,
I was stopped up.
I never,
I never wanted to fuck a robot before I
watched your guys's go.
We're ahead of the curve for,
Hey,
when we're done with this youtube
series,
we're going to like release it on apple
tv with an apple was like,
well wait a second,
you have to get a rating from the
ratings board,
the MPA ratings.
And we're like,
fine.
We went to the MPA,
we paid them the thousand bucks or
whatever it costs to get the thing and
then they said this is nc 17 and it
cannot be shown anywhere ever drawing of
a penis.
And it's like a badly drawn drawing of
it,
but it's not like real photo realistic.
And at the end of the day,
I think it's like the sweetest
pornography I've ever seen.
It's like it's got a,
it's got a real message of love.
It's not coming from a place of a
exploitation.
Absolutely no expectation at not at all.
Everyone is enjoying themselves.
There is,
I mean it's,
there's a scene of will the robot does
put a finger on the but yeah,
and also,
spoiler alert,
take the balls and guys the penis into
the vagina.
Oh Gosh.
But um,
I had,
I was free.
I was like,
wow.
Well in a way it's,
it's very uh,
educational.
That's true.
It saves you a conversation about the
birds and the bees.
If you want to just show parents,
well you guys,
you guys gave a warning beforehand,
but through,
I noticed the only,
so on Youtube you've got these six
episodes in the movie.
The only one that is an age restricted
is the first episode.
And I don't know if you guys know about
how youtube works,
but when a video gets age restricted,
they share it less.
Yeah.
Oh,
we know.
All too.
Well,
I think there's bots flying around
looking for shapes of penis chariot.
Hey,
it's not the craziest that they don't
share it.
It's like,
it's impossible to find the full movie.
If you type in tenacious d post
apocalypto full movie,
it still doesn't come up.
And if you have not signed Daniel can't
watch it.
That's okay.
But I just want people to be able to
find it.
That's why I'm only telling people to go
to [inaudible] dot com is the best way.
But,
um,
if you go to the channel,
you'll see it all there.
But yeah,
Youtube does it.
They bury stuff.
They,
they'll just bury it because they're so
afraid of it harming their platform and
scaring advertisers away.
But it's just a little,
what about this for promotion though?
The show youtube did watch.
That's excellent.
It doesn't that always have to watch it
then.
Well,
I'm telling you,
you,
you're going to wash this robot,
swirl this vagina around a cock and
you'd be like,
damn,
I can't wait for the future.
Yeah.
I mean,
the future is already are robots.
They're talking about robot and draw
falls now.
Yeah.
So I heard of a sex doll bronco,
but I don't know that there's mechanics
in the vagina because we're always just
a sloppy plastic is just around the
corner.
That sounded really appealing.
Now would you guys fuck a robot that had
like a super badge?
Um,
I must admit in my youth,
I think there might've been a doll
experience.
Tell me about that more.
Well,
I might've continued in the early days
of experimentation when you want to
practice.
I think that the adults can be a great
educational tool.
I fully,
first of all,
no judgment on my side.
I mean,
I put at that age,
you put your Dick in just about
anything.
Yeah.
I mean,
tell me about what did the doll look
like?
Kind of like a,
where do you get those because you'll
have to be of age or do you get those at
a six shot?
It,
there might've been some shoplifting
involved.
Like I should go into all the detail.
There might've been a crazy night out
from a ucla that's in the theater
department.
Uh,
yeah,
I might've been like 19 years old.
So it's like,
wait,
that's a little old for,
for uh,
needing a doll.
Well,
no,
there's no age limit on when you need a
dog.
Well,
apparently you are not,
you can't even buy it until you're 18.
So the people that need it the most
don't have access to it.
Right?
Yeah.
In fact,
I think maybe the target audience is,
is uh,
men in their forties for the dog.
Huh?
It could be.
Absolutely.
Thank God I'm too old for that.
I think I just,
depending on a large pillow,
I think with that vivid imagination,
um,
I have,
I want to expand on this further and I
don't know,
I'm taking it too far.
But if you fuck a robot sex doll,
is it cheating?
Oh,
if you're married and you have,
and then you're like,
oh,
I want this vagina can swirl and soc and
do all of them do everything.
But I mean it's just a robot.
Is that cheating?
Uh,
I think it depends on the,
the,
the secrecy of the act.
If,
yeah.
Um,
hmm.
Maybe,
maybe you're going on the road,
uh,
to do a job and your wife would actually
give you a doll or like a little,
a little flashlights,
something that would fit in the,
isn't a fleshlight basically,
or a sex robot.
Well,
it's not a robot,
but it is a sex flush.
Like,
well,
let me show you a flash.
A flashlight.
Can I kill the question?
I don't understand what you think.
Oh Wow.
There's a,
there's a lot there.
Well here,
this point is not very graphic.
So let me show you this one.
Christ sake.
It's on Amazon here.
Wasting my time with my hand.
This all these years.
Well,
so,
so let's start here.
Ila is a fleshlight,
uh,
infidelity.
Hmm.
So here,
this is a fleshlight usually shaped more
like a vagina,
but I don't want to think you can see it
on the screen there.
Oh.
But it's a basically,
and I love that they make it look like a
flat,
like a flashlight
of all things.
Like put your Dick in this flashlight.
Any,
any kind of sphere or any kind of,
does it light up?
So there's no light.
There's,
Oh wow.
Does this only when you're doing it.
But here we have a video.
Please don't be a penis.
Okay.
We'd better know.
It seems like the light could create
some warmth.
Hmm.
Wow.
So can I use a fleshlight Isla without
consulting with you?
Um,
I guess it would just be a little weird
if you did.
Okay.
So if it doesn't have a face,
it's not cheating.
I don't think the parameter just have to
be decided on together.
But what's the fleshlight and
masturbating and sorry doing include you
guys on this conversation.
It's all right.
No masturbation.
Well maybe.
Yeah.
Is Masturbation shooting?
No,
no,
no.
Especially if you're like,
ah,
get outta here and go masturbate.
Yeah.
You don't want to see that.
Exactly.
I think I was reading though you,
it's important that you should
masturbate together though.
You should be.
Not all the time.
Well no,
but comfortable enough with that contact
laser.
We need to try that cow.
I assume you guys had done that.
That was a Howard Stern interview.
I heard that.
Yeah.
And Ringo claimed he wasn't there for
that session,
the band,
yet he had the perfect alibi.
He was there finally.
I find it funny how people made such a
big scoop out of it.
Well,
it's funny besides that,
it's funny,
but like people started trying to draw
the conclusion that they were like
lovers and all this,
you know,
and it's just a couple of dudes jerking
off in the dark.
I mean,
right.
They're young.
They're all up the early Beatles and
maybe,
yeah,
maybe that's why they kicked out the
drummer if they didn't like the way he
masturbated with them was a snare and
all the ladies though he was an American
and apparently he was very good looking.
Is he still available for drumming?
Curious.
You've got Sasha?
No,
we got,
we got great drummer.
Um,
so you guys did the voice,
the art,
the music,
the writing.
This is your baby post apocalypto yeah,
you're saying tour De Force?
I was,
I,
that was coming next toward him from
wars and who was the art director
because there is a very distinct art
style throughout art direction.
All Art Times,
man.
I actually tried to draw a cell just to
show Jack what it would be like if he
wasn't drawing it and it was really bad
burns.
Did you actually draw it?
I did draw it,
but we got uh,
uh,
how probably too we got a colorist is a
amazing Michael Molina to do all the
color with his computer and uh,
yeah,
we were going to hand over the reigns to
some other animator and artists at some
point.
But that was back when we had dreams of
having a Netflix or hbo series and then
we were like,
it's better this way.
Anyway,
we were laughing until late version,
but butthead isn't well drawn,
but it's great.
It's someone or to draw beavis and
butthead a style.
It's because they're badly them.
So hilarious.
So nobody wanted to show,
I mean I find that a pure insanity.
Well I would love spicy somebody's neck.
What was that one?
Yeah,
the color was interested.
Well,
I forgot.
I know none of the major players,
but where are you guys uncompromising on
the penis and set like very graphic sex
shots.
We presented what we wanted to put on
the air.
We weren't saying,
hey,
we want to do something like this.
We were like,
we want,
we want to do this.
Yeah.
No one wanted to go with us down that,
that,
uh,
crazy a half.
But,
um,
in a way we were kind of glad about that
because,
uh,
it gave us an opportunity to really go,
it seemed kind of liberating.
It's like,
yeah,
no,
it's just kind of a fun project to do it
with your friends.
Exactly how we want to do to make it
well,
I loved it and I urge everyone to go
watch it now.
You guys,
do you guys watch youtube?
I know.
Oh really?
I do.
Could you do,
you're like,
Oh yeah,
I'm sorry.
Oh Man.
Thank you.
Well,
I'll just go down and strange wormholes
as we call like a wow.
I wonder if thin lizzy played a live
concert in the UK in 74 or something and
I'll just find myself watching fold
concerts or anything.
I mean,
where it leads and Youtube's got a
brilliant at leading you to the next
thing might be like,
oh,
that's where I would be interested in
that.
And yet their algorithm,
they know if there,
then we do.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
I find it,
yeah,
eminently entertaining.
That's great.
But I guess I'm,
most people don't watch it like I do.
Well,
there's different,
there's different worlds.
There's people that like watch youtube
for the personality or I don't know what
to say.
There's people that could produce
content on youtube and then there's,
I think a lot of people like you who use
it just because everything's on youtube
cause everything's going watch
tutorials.
You can watch music,
you can watch bands,
and then you just go down this crazy
rabbit hole of like endless content.
So there's two types of people and I
guess you're very much,
they'll,
well,
and there's the endless,
I mean,
how do I play of something on guitars?
It's like,
wow,
that's so easy.
Yeah,
it is.
Jack,
do you use,
I do go on the youtubes.
Uh,
mainly to like figure out how to make
potato lot because like that I'd be
doing today,
I'm having some family over this evening
for a Hanukah celebration though.
Let me see if I know I've never made the
potato lot because somebody else in the
family,
it would be in charge of those.
So this time,
how did you get stuck with luck?
QCA duty this year?
Um,
it's,
you know,
it's sad but my mom used to make the lot
just recently so I'm sorry.
But uh,
yeah,
so I think it's going to take a village.
We're all done.
I'm going to have,
I have a bunch of graders and a pile of
potatoes.
I think log cause is like poker as they
say.
It takes a day to learn a lifetime to
master.
Yeah.
So you will be a lot code kings like
you're always just one youtube video
away from making the perfect lots cup.
That's true.
That's my,
in this day and age.
Do you guys live,
do your light the Menorah and do the
whole thing?
Of course.
You say the prayer.
Are you ready for it?
Are you kidding me?
Tell me if I do this correctly.
I'll tell Ya.
Bottle.
Ha.
Yeah.
Hello.
Hey Dude.
This is the hard part.
I shed get a baby's photon.
The tiva.
Huh?
Very hard.
Ha.
That's impressive.
Um,
wow.
Rabbi black
music.
The savage beast.
Do you know any other Hebrew prayers?
Because I am just,
I bought it already.
I know some of the songs.
Oh No.
Give like a modern,
hey,
hey.
Well you know what?
It doesn't sound like that was written
back in the 18th century.
Oh pretty sure.
Jesus,
they had him in a chair and they were
doing the whole,
yeah,
I don't remember that.
A Jew.
The Jews,
in fact,
the king,
you actually pronounced everything
correct too.
Cause she's Israel.
Shalom.
How do you say thank you in Hebrew toe
down.
When in doubt I go Shalom.
It means so many things.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it is.
Um,
you are a,
a lot of us were surprised to learn that
you're Jewish.
I don't know why,
but that's came as a surprise to a lot
of us.
But you,
your father was born a Jew.
Oh my father was,
my father was born Protestant.
Right.
My mother was born a Jew,
which makes me full Jew according to the
Jews.
I,
man,
I'm not out.
I'm not questioning your doing.
And the idea is we know where you came
from because we have witnesses were not
positive if your dad was a Jew or not.
So true.
I never thought of it that you came out
of that vagina.
You are.
Yes we did.
We don't have DNA.
Right.
You are.
Is that the best show everyone,
they start break dancing and shit in
front of the baby.
That I love it.
I love it so much.
But your story is unusual because I'm
usually,
I find that it's the male or the female
that a convert to Judaism.
But your dad converted to Judaism,
right?
Yeah,
I find that fascinating.
Well,
it wasn't just because he loved my mom,
but also because uh,
he was into Judaism.
Wow.
But since they divorced,
he is now no longer a practicing Jew.
He drunk.
It's like when you lose certain friends
in a divorce,
you lost.
He left the dude.
But uh,
yeah,
so,
so I was raised you,
I got my bar Mitzvah and then I
immediately sort of a bales you taking
the chance or price.
Exactly.
They'll do the,
but now you're back.
They'll do the bar Mitzvah and then
they'll stick around until 16 or let it
sit around for the confirmation hearings
or whatever it is that I booked it at 13
I know what the calls from hr then
officially adult.
Well you get the check,
you got the check,
right.
Get the big pay that I would expect.
That's the socks and an intellivision
cartridge.
Somebody got the money,
somebody.
And a lot of times the parents will be
like,
thank you.
Repaying all those years of tourists
school.
Cause I know my parents got thousands
and all they bought me and I was
grateful at the time.
But in retrospect I'm like,
Holy Shit.
They bezels my bar Mitzvah money and
this is a,
yeah,
I'm calling you guys out.
All I got was a [inaudible] 64 and I
know they got like 10 Jews and 64 C.
I'm a little older than you because
Nintendo wasn't even out in 1982 when I
got my bar Mitzvah.
You got socks?
Yeah,
Emma and television cartridge.
It was,
it was a sad turnout,
but,
uh,
it was a celebration because as you say,
I no longer had to go to Hebrew school,
which was additional school.
I had school and then I had to go school
Tuesdays and Sundays.
You go in the evening.
Well,
it's so,
Isla doesn't understand but are
pressured by they,
they part of your life.
You didn't have to think about extra
Judaism.
Yeah,
exactly.
She doesn't understand what us,
American Jews have been.
She speaks Hebrew and she doesn't
understand that.
We just learned the Hebrew,
so we couldn't do the Bar Mitzvah and
that of us even know what the F we're
talking about.
Yeah.
That's pretty weird.
I still have a couple words.
Shalom.
Ah,
Ema,
Ema.
[inaudible].
Wait,
where did he say?
What was that like pesach,
Passover.
Maneesh Denalis some lyrics from a song.
I don't even know the painting goes.
Well,
my favorite,
if you guys want something to take away
from this is a by rule Hashem,
I'll root.
Which means you're like,
Oh man,
this is live.
We can't go back these rot.
Hachette,
which means it's like what God's house
with God's help.
When someone will say like,
let's say,
Oh,
you're going on tour.
That's cool.
You'll say,
but it's lots of shame.
Like what I liked about it.
Yes,
but let's not,
let's not get over our skis.
But what I like about it is when you use
it and very like trivial things like,
well,
I'm going to take a sh,
I got to go take a shit.
[inaudible] Hashem with God's help.
You know?
That's when it really gets a little more
humorous.
I love it.
Love it.
Just thinking about the prayer,
but real and ny,
it's blessed at our God king of the
universe.
Amaz yeah.
Could you use that in every day?
Like,
yeah.
Big Mac,
King of the universe.
I don't know.
That might not work.
Uh,
yeah.
That reminded me of flash can go for the
impossible.
Yeah.
Oh,
that makes me think I need to see that
queen movie.
Oh yeah.
Have you seen huge fan of Queen?
Very little desire to see it.
I know it was kind of the thing to see
and then it wasn't the thing to say.
It was weird,
like the opposite.
It was,
well,
it was the thing to see it and then it
wasn't the thing to see.
And then I think it is the thing,
not the thing to say no,
like it's become a worldwide phenomenon.
The good really,
I saw it all over the world when it
wasn't the thing to see.
And I was so pleasantly surprised
because it wasn't the thing to see.
And it was good.
It was like,
yeah,
I mean he'd go in his,
it's a Hollywood biopic.
Yeah.
They're going to fudge this,
that and the other and the details.
What?
It's like that guy's performance.
I mean,
imagine like,
okay,
you got to play Freddie Mercury iconic,
uh,
charismatic rock star of all time and
just nail it.
Work on that.
I mean,
he does.
Wow.
Kind of,
kind of amazing.
Well,
I guess I should see it because I'm a
huge fan.
There's a new phenomenon that one of,
uh,
when someone on Youtube pointed out
really funny,
Lee,
that there's a phenomenon of people
pretending they've never heard Bohemian
rap.
Oh God.
Oh,
I saw that.
I'd like the adults listen to that thing
we did.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
like people react.
Yeah.
People react to whatever the phone bros.
Why would they,
why would they pretend like they have
never heard?
Cause they're getting tons of views and
it's like related to the video,
but it's like everybody gets hurt.
Come on everyone's door.
They go and they go and they were like,
here's a song by a [inaudible] queen of
wrap Saudi.
Uh,
and they're like,
why?
Anyway,
Gus Johnson made a video about it and
he's like,
why are they all aligned?
They're all wine.
It's like the Jimmy Kimmel live witness
news.
Yeah.
It's getting people to say anything.
You can't.
Well,
they,
yeah.
So we're going to throw it to a quick
commercial break that we have
prerecorded for our convenience.
You can,
yeah.
But we'll be back after this short
commercial break with these two fine,
wonderful human beings.
See you soon.
Have you finished your holiday shopping
yet?
Well,
no worries because you can get
everything you need for you and your
loved ones over at me undies.
You have never felt a fabric so soft and
luscious before and the good news is
it's going to hold your genitals one way
or the other.
These smooth micro modal,
three times softer than cotton is going
to be rubbing up on your genitals and
that's where you want it to be.
Not in a sexual way,
but just that you want to take good care
of that part of your body and you're
going to have fun,
playful patterns like this Sushi
underwear.
Oh,
you can take a,
hey,
is that a chopstick or my penis and my
case?
It's hard to tell the difference.
It's not as long as the chopstick,
but it is as then why stop it undies.
Mandy's also has cozy lounge pants and
one disease and socks and the super soft
fabric.
Perfect for wearing on Christmas
morning.
Guys.
Mandy's has got a great offer for our
listeners for any first time purchasers,
when you purchase any of me on these,
you get 15% off and free shipping order
by December 16th for free shipping and
time for Christmas or you're crunched
for time.
You can't go wrong with a [inaudible]
gift card.
It's a no brainer.
You're going to get 15% off.
You can get the most comfortable
underwear you or anyone you've known has
ever worn.
I'm telling you,
it's all I wear now.
They get your 15% off your first pair of
free shipping and 100% satisfaction
guaranteed.
Head on over to [inaudible] dot com
slash hd that's Mandy's dot com slash h
three Vince Cyril watches has learned
that luxury is a process.
It's not about specs and it's not about
price.
It's not a marketing term to be thrown
around.
It's about attention to detail as step
by step process to craft.
Every product is this process that
separates us from the competition,
them from the competition.
I'm not associated with them.
They just pay me to read this.
It's a belief that you isla,
yes,
you deserve the best.
They are tired of cookie cutter designs
and mass produce mentalistic watches
that have flooded the market.
They want to offer a watch that was able
to stand out,
get noticed,
get your Dick sucked and set yourself
apart.
Rather than conform to civil design all
at an accessible price,
they are able to provide the look and
feel of bold luxury watches that are 10
times the price by selling directly to
the customer.
So the holidays are coming up.
Guys,
is the perfect time to get yourself or
your friends and family a gift.
And what's a better Gift Than Been Sarah
watches?
Get Your Dick sucked.
That's not their float.
I made that up.
Um,
but it is,
but it could happen.
Furthermore,
we are offering to engrave on the back
to create a personalized message,
to give a gift that makes the right
statement.
So go to Vince,
Sarah watches.com/h
three December and enter the Promo code
h three h three to get 15% off your
entire order.
Then Sarah watches.com/h
three December.
If you're like me,
you don't know anything about investing.
And that's why Robin Hood is such a
great investing APP.
It lets you buy and sell stocks,
etfs,
options,
cryptos all commission free.
They strive to make financial services
work for everyone,
not just the wealthy.
And it's a non intimidating way for
stock market newcomers to invest for the
first time with true confidence.
Here's why it's so great.
They've got a simple intuitive,
clear design with data presented in an
easy to digest way.
Now,
I don't know anything about trading
stocks,
but Dan learned how to trade using this
app and he says that they have tutorials
that show you and kind of take your hand
and tell you what you're doing so you
can learn as you trade.
Is that right then?
That is accurate now,
right?
Uh,
Robin Hood,
no,
no commission,
no fees.
Other brokers charge up to $10 for every
trade,
but Robin Hood doesn't charge commission
fees,
trade stocks,
and keep all of your profits.
Boom.
Learn by doing.
Learn how to invest as you build your
portfolio.
Discover new stocks and track favorite
companies with personalized news feed.
You're going to get custom notifications
for price movements and you never missed
the right time to invest.
And now you want to learn how.
Learn with a free stock complements of
Robin Hood.
They're giving away a free stock like
Apple Ford or sprint to help build your
portfolio.
Sign up@hdpodcastoutrobinhood.com
that's h three podcast dot Robin
hood.com
and get a free stock to get started and
learn.
How's it done?
There's nothing better about the holiday
season.
Then unwrapping a brand new phone until
you get hit with that brand new monthly
bill,
big wireless providers can really suck
the joy of the holiday.
So this year,
don't just upgrade your phone,
upgrade your wireless provider and
switch to mint mobile for limited time
mint mobiles offering the best holiday
deal and wireless you've ever seen.
Three months of service for only 20
bucks for limited time guys meant mint
mobiles.
Holiday deal is here.
You get $20 would get you three months
of wireless service of five gigabytes of
four g lte data each month plus
unlimited talk and text and you're gonna
use your own phone with any minute
mobile plan.
You can keep your old phone number along
with all your existing contacts meant
mobile runs on the nation's fastest,
most advanced lte networks and if you're
not 100% satisfied meant mobile has you
covered what their seven day money back
guarantee did Cheryl wireless bell and
start saving with mint mobile.
This is how it comes.
They send you a Sim card,
you pop it in your phone,
you're good to go.
These guys,
I love it so much.
I love this product and the Internet has
gotten way too expensive.
I we need a company like this to come
disrupt.
That's why I love mint mobile.
Give them a shot guys.
Take advantage of this mint mobile
holiday deal before it is gone.
Three months of wireless for $20 and get
the plant shipped to your door for if
our re by going to mint mobile.com/h
street.
That's meant mobile.com/h
street,
that's three months of service for just
$20 at mint mobile.com/h
three.
Welcome back guys.
So we've got a lot of a development.
It's over the break.
Uh,
my parents are listening and they have
some beef with what I said about that,
uh,
embezzling
my bar Mitzvah money.
So go ahead down.
They messaged me pretty much within a
minute of you saying that.
Ask Ethan if he forgot the Disneyland
trip with 20 of his friends for his bar
Mitzvah.
Stole his money.
Huh?
Okay.
I didn't realize I was paying my own
barbecue.
Great Book where there's more,
there's more.
I spent $5,000
on his bar Mitzvah and everything he
got,
which wasn't very much,
went into his own bank account.
His memory is a bit off using his
parents for a laugh.
Shameful.
Using the parents back down.
I want to thank God used.
Your parents were alive and where are
we?
Yeah,
there you heard it from Kyle gas
himself.
Mom,
mom,
mom.
If I can retort real fast and this is
perfect because you cannot respond one
me,
I'm not supposed to pay for my own Bar
Mitzvah party.
Yeah,
I'm off on a madness.
Is that Oh I paid and then the money in
the bank.
Uh,
she says it went into my college fund,
whatever that that's what they always
say when they take your money college
fund.
Okay.
You stole my money.
Well we got a lot to deal with.
Did you go to college after all?
I did.
Did you graduate?
Barely.
Cause Jack and I were in your graduating
class.
I barely graduated and all the only
reason I did it was because I went to
ucs.
See the most forgiving Santa Cruz world.
Really?
Yeah.
No grades.
Remember?
Well they changed that.
They changed that.
Some classes are still pass,
no pass.
But for the most part you get grades.
Oh.
But they are very not only liberal in
spirit but also in their forgiveness of
the grading system.
Yeah.
Learning.
Okay.
Yes.
Was it all teacher?
All the professors?
Hippies.
Yeah,
cause that's what I imagined.
Santa Cruz University.
A lot of a hacky sack.
Ultimate Frisbee.
That's well I will tell you a jack that
they had the number one ultimate Frisbee
team and the nation.
That's no joe and you're right,
there was a lot of hacky sack as well on
the sidelines.
That would have been me.
Yeah,
I want to see it.
Do you have any video of a frasier
falling off stage?
You do.
So coincidental that you asked me that.
Um,
I would love to see that as these guys
were walking in,
the God vape is right outside the door
and we had the ipad of Kelsey grammer
falling off stage and so they hadn't
seen this video.
So I,
I absolutely adore this.
Is he like giving a Ted talk here or
something?
He's giving a on recovery.
Let's talk about acting.
He's very,
see he's being very serious and uh,
well without further ado,
enjoy Kelsey grammer falls off stage.
Sure.
We have to smile world pretending I was
a UN interpreter.
I think.
There you have it.
Do that one more time.
And my favorite way goes,
oh dear Lord.
I know cause I was laughing on top of
the Oh dear Lord.
I think let's see it again.
Nasty problems like in character as
frazier.
Wait,
you did it again.
I go back a little bit.
Yeah cause I really want to get,
I'm going to get with an interpreter.
You went interpreter.
How did not hurt him?
He just took a lot of town hall stage
looks treachery.
Yeah.
We didn't like the front of the stage
looking like it has jagged wouldn't fell
in between the wooden teeth.
Have you guys ever had any stage
malfunctions or any issues on stage was
we were recently watching a collection
of artists falling off stage and there's
a lot of help there by the look of it.
Well occasionally a fan will run up and
and try to Hug Jack.
I think that's happened a couple of
times.
Don't you remember the one though where
I did have one?
You did and I think it was when we were
out on tour with the beastie boys.
We were doing like uh,
we were rocking the vote.
Oh,
they were rocking the vote and we were
just sorta coming along time around,
we were opening up for the beast is an
ena and I was like stomping across the
stage and then I just like stopped in
between too big.
Like you can also walk on top of the big
speakers that are out there.
Right.
Yeah.
And I like stopped in between speakers
and I went down all the way to my hip.
No,
but uh,
the adrenaline bounced me right back up
and I just,
I kept on rock and I'm pretending as
though nothing happened.
And I think that might've prevented it
from going viral was that I recovered
too quickly,
but it was pretty intense and I came
very close to breaking my hip.
One of the great,
you remember cones and one of the great
falls we had during a show was our
guitar player and he was shredding,
he was shredding the Electric Guitar.
So look to the heavens melting phases
and he's walking back and many trips all
over again is just a direct kind of,
he had a,
he had to get right back up though and
continue rocking.
He was,
do we have video videotape of that?
We should might be on youtube,
but luckily there's been no serious
injuries on a tenacious detour.
That's good.
And when you fell,
were you,
were you like,
uh,
injured or you were just,
he came right back.
I was sore and bruised,
but now the show must go on and we had a
show the next day.
I think it was fine.
But yeah,
I felt it.
The dings and there's like,
there's this one video of Justin,
like there's just a straight up whole
yeah,
on the stage.
And this poor guy,
right?
The biebs went down the hall.
Yeah.
Let me show you went down the rabbit
hole and whole,
and I feel so bad for him because it's
like,
what can you do?
Oh,
wearing a kilt.
He's wearing a lot of layers.
I don't know if it's really cold in
there.
It's kind of got an axl rose thing go on
Yup.
Yeah.
And so Bob's your uncle in bye bye
birdie.
Oh God.
The anticipation.
Oh God,
no.
Why would there be a hole there?
Why would there be a hole
guy?
I fell so bad,
man.
Cool.
Like he never had a chance.
He's got to get an accident lawyer for
that cause he's got it nick deep though.
Play that for you again.
But yeah,
he goes all the way down.
It's never quite as serious when you
weigh 112 pounds.
Dot.
Right,
right.
Nothing really hurts.
That's not the normal stage.
And then,
oh man.
That last step was a doozy that had to
be like for an effect or something like,
well these dancers popping up through
the hole,
but there's the best of clothes.
That's how you got it.
You got to cloquet.
Yeah,
you've got to close the hole.
How often?
But he knows the clothes,
the whole,
everybody knows.
Everybody knows.
There's something I heard about you that
I,
that I found was interesting.
I was thinking about,
as you said,
we,
we both had this experience.
We turned 13,
and we said smell your later to the
Jews.
Yeah.
But since you've had kids,
I've heard that you've returned to
synagogue.
Well,
I did feel like it was important for
them to feel part of a community and I
wanted them to have that experience.
And uh,
we did have them enrolled in a school
that had Hebrew studies as part of the
curriculum so it wouldn't feel like they
had to go to extra school afterschool.
Hmm.
Um,
but it wasn't a good fit for the boy.
We were there for a few years.
This is a good school.
But,
um,
God,
uh,
Dan actually so much stress dude is
figuring out the right school for our
kids.
I've spent so much time and energy and
just like anxiety over this part.
I had no idea being a parent could be so
hard.
You thought it was going to become a
public school,
public school just,
well,
what's wrong with the public?
Well,
what's wrong with public school?
Um,
it doesn't feel like our society puts
enough energy towards public education.
Well,
there are tragically,
I feel like even though it's not fair,
I feel like I have to use the resources
that,
that we have at our disposal to give our
kids the best possible education.
And that unfortunately does not include
public school ad this time.
So,
and is it a problem for your kids being
a,
does it cause issues for them being your
son?
Does that ever,
yeah,
that is a factor too.
Interesting.
It's,
uh,
you know,
when,
when everybody knows who your,
your father is,
that's kind of a weird situation for
them to be in.
And then to not know if like their
friends or friends because they're,
yeah.
That's complicated for it.
It's hard enough for an adult.
I mean,
yeah.
But,
uh,
I think my boys are,
are relatively well adjusted and it was
actually my son Sammy,
who turned me onto your show.
Oh yeah.
Low three h three.
How old is he?
He's 12,
but he's sharp.
Very advanced.
Tammy,
thank you so much.
I always take sam his advice and he's
given me,
he's given me lots of golden nuggets
over the years.
And,
uh,
and uh,
and Kyle's always like,
Hey,
wait,
how did you hear about this thing that
we're doing today?
It's always Sammy,
Sammy,
you've been on,
you've been on good mythical morning and
you've been on hot.
Were both,
were those all families?
Examine Samsung is giving you good.
He needs to be your manager.
The best shows.
Well,
I believe that children are,
well,
hold on,
back up.
My glasses have a tendency to fog up.
I'm a hot and steamy guy by nature and
sometimes it bothers me and I'll just go
up here for a little while and let them
cool off and then I'll bring them back.
You did it kind of without your hands,
which I thought was pretty cool.
Yeah.
Well I can bring him down without my
hands.
I can't get them back.
Get them up there.
That would be something that we then had
really business,
well,
the reason we've been thinking about it
is because I'm pregnant.
Oh really?
Yes.
They got a little thing happening.
Yeah,
it's exciting.
So we know.
Do we have any idea what's,
uh,
what's coming up?
We think we haven't said that yet,
but I don't mind saying we will that the
person who did the ultrasound,
they go,
if I had to guess do,
they said,
do you want my guests?
I was like,
Oh yeah,
it says I love that move and you do it
so casually.
There wasn't also,
there is a button on it.
Did you see that?
So it was like boom,
look at that.
It's like I'm ready for business.
Wow.
I felt like they were default enough but
I was wrong.
I actually need like some sauce and a
cloth because they're,
they're being on.
You need to defrost or like a little fan
inside or something.
I'm going to use the phone crazy.
Someone rescue our little,
our little troublemaker.
Um,
the ultrasound guys?
Yes.
The ultrasound take a guess.
I'm not sure.
But uh,
it looks like a,
it looks like a girl really.
Well that is not what they said.
Oh,
they said they saw little tiny little
baby penis and they thought it was a guy
that's a tip off.
But I don't know.
I,
cause she's like,
well technically the next ultrasound is
when you find out,
but if you want my opinion at one angle
I saw a little penis,
which was kind of at another angle.
You saw your angle.
I couldn't tell what I was looking now.
I mean the ultra stays early.
Ultrasounds are so crazy because there's
like so much space and the babies just
like floating around and she's doing
this thing where she's putting on
pushing on the stomach and the baby's
like,
like uh,
an eight ball and an eight ball and has
shaken the eight ball and it's like
constant around.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
So it's a little boy.
We think Theodore Theodore already know
you already met him.
How do you know?
I feel it.
Yeah,
I feel that I'm would call him theo.
We were okay with it.
Yeah.
I like,
yeah,
I'm fine.
I'm great with that.
I like Sierra.
There it is.
So we've been wondering what we would do
as far as Jewish,
the whole Jewish thing,
because we're not like religious,
right?
But it is a way of growing up during the
holidays and also a barn.
They speak Hebrew cause your family,
but the extra,
the extra schools is just so brutal.
I didn't know it's extra because they
don't teach,
they don't teach Hebrew with public
school.
I tell you that.
No Sir.
I felt like there was something to be
gained also from the,
the,
the moral fabric that you get with,
uh,
with,
with Judaism.
And just in general when you have that,
uh,
that cradle of,
it's a culture that's,
that's an identity.
And I very much identify,
I think I come from the same.
Yeah.
I'm very much a cultural Jew,
you know,
it is.
What,
what,
what is your,
what's going on with you?
What are you,
are you well,
I think my mom tried to cover all the
bases.
I think I was a,
what do you call it when you're a
Christian,
you get baptized and she just sorta go
Kevin to do that.
He's been case fine circumcision in
there.
That's good.
So she mutilated my genitals.
Thanks mom.
No.
Um,
yeah.
And then at quickly,
uh,
and then nobody was interested in,
in church or anything and it was just
evolved into an atheist household
evolved until eight.
Yeah.
I love that.
It's just,
yeah,
I gave up.
Do you regret being circumcised?
Because that is a debate that goes on
today is that people are angry at their
parents for circumstance.
Yeah.
Here's one right here.
You,
you wish that were made were made fine.
All the parts are working fine.
You don't do that whole like cleaning
business.
It's just such a pilot who it is it,
but you don't know.
You don't have 40 miss it.
Yes.
You don't remember having,
I'm going to just take a chance on
mutilate it sexually mutilating babies
is not a good idea.
It's going to call it a leap of faith
there.
I mean,
let's,
let's not do that at that one.
How can do that anytime on my own when I
make teen,
oh,
I don't want that for skin anymore.
Let me remove that.
I think it looks a little nicer.
Oh,
merry go.
Aesthetically I can,
I think my opinion,
I haven't noticed a drop off.
I don't have anything to compare it to,
but the quality of orgasms has been all
good.
All light baby.
So wait a second,
maybe there's something maybe there.
Well,
do you know what a lot of people get?
So for scan is complicated business.
I've heard a lot of people who end up
having to get there for skin removed and
their adult life.
And that can be one of the most painful,
awful like a circumcision apologists,
frankly.
Because yeah,
the debate rages on because now we have
to decide if we're gonna do it right.
You really decisions.
Have you asked your parents what,
what they think about it?
Oh,
I'm sure.
That fucking thing.
I know Jack do well.
I don't know,
but I just,
I liked the exuberance.
Yeah,
you're a wild man.
Um,
I say cut it off,
right?
I say cut it off.
But uh,
I want to ask you guys about,
first of all that hbo show,
you guys did his beloved to me.
Still one of my favorite shows ever.
Thanks man.
How do you,
I mean you guys,
I mean,
it stands the test of time.
It's hilarious.
It was at the time.
How do you,
tell me about your guys' experience
making that show.
Think that we were ranked like 36 best
hbo show by I think Hbo.
Well it has 100% on rotten tomatoes to
this day.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Well,
how could you not like,
so it was like the Sopranos.
Yeah.
Game of thrones checkout.
You're,
you're the only real question is where
were we ranked in relation to flight of
the conchords cause our whole blank gun
is great.
Somehow compete with the new generation
of tenacious d,
right.
Ceiling Heights.
Are you friends with those guys?
You know those guys?
Yeah.
We are friends with them.
Even though we do,
I think there was a pretend rivalry.
Yeah,
that's what I try.
I think I was trying to stoke those
flames be the greatest thing.
It's good for business.
If you can get a rivalry garden,
the more popular Burchard to fight off
and then I think they took it,
I think they might've taken it the wrong
way.
Yeah.
So,
well friendly beef turned to real beef.
Well in their,
uh,
in their first show,
they had a thing,
a little sort of inside joke.
We don't know that this was flight of
the conchords that put this joke in to
their episode.
It could have been an art director.
It's such a small thing.
But Kyle,
with his powerful lasers,
scope eyes noticed that they had like a
newspaper,
right?
Is there an advertisement in a newspaper
that someone's reading in an episode?
What does it say?
It says tenacious done.
D Oh,
walkodile dial done before except
tenacious d.
And if you read into that,
it's like tenacious is done.
And we've took that very personally and
ever since then.
And then we spent the next 10 years,
I'm trying to get to do our festival,
but we do,
we do.
We do love the conchords.
Like they're uh,
uh,
a subtler cuter younger.
He killed like,
you guys are horrible by,
can I say thank you?
Sort of give a vibe like a,
we're wizards.
You've arrived.
I'd love to see the earth searching.
We're very furry.
I love many furries.
Furries.
It seems to be sweeping the nation.
Can you tell me army and here,
let me,
well this,
this first is best presented with
photos,
but a furry think it's either go to
flaming lips,
concerts.
Nope.
Anybody.
So this might weird you out because
again,
people are sensitive.
So these are people that dress up as
critters.
It's a sexual thing though,
isn't it?
Isn't it part of it?
As far as I know,
it is a sexual thing.
So the aiding other furries,
they dress up as critters and they just
have orgies.
Really.
As far as I'm aware,
that seems very,
very me.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
I may be representing them.
So Dan and Ian,
please fact check me.
But it does seem to have a sexual
component.
I don't know what's the origin,
but the faces and I and I got a cute
group there.
You got to say that's,
and I think that they creep me out.
There is a sexual component from what I
understand.
I don't know about orgies happening,
although,
I mean we'll explain this Dan.
Yeah,
I need to know what you don't know.
What is know why their,
the bases have to be like Toronto.
It doesn't seem like their faces are a
little creepy.
Yes,
thank you.
You will.
But if it's sexual,
it's just a dry humping,
right?
No,
they cut a hole.
There's a hole like the Mormons,
like it's more like,
it's gotta be like a Velcro flap now
that sex,
but I guess,
you know,
I guess it's kind of Nice if you're
attractive as a whole bunch of them
there thing and you don't know who's
black open and who's fights flaps closed
and there's a photo you don't know.
I guess if you're real ugly,
like uh,
you know myself and you've gone a Fox
outfit and you showed deck and maybe
you've got a good one and your face
isn't that good,
then all of sudden you're like king of
the furries.
It works to your advantage.
Right?
You think that's like 50% of the reason
why people go for maybe what you're kind
of hiding your identity.
You can't really see everyone's kind of
equal.
And just in Nicaragua it's kind of like
eyes wide shut but ridiculous if you
have to adopt a furry voice,
you know like her pet boy.
Oh good.
They do that then do you guys know if
they talk [inaudible] I mean I know that
there is a role playing aspect so I
imagine that that Dan is saying,
yes,
you're going to this length zoom.
You would assume the voice as well.
Right?
Well I think we should go under cover.
Well you paint your Dick reade like the
red rocket.
Not Often Jesus,
you know,
awesome.
But they might just looked it up.
I mean on their wikipedia about for
these the sexual aspect,
it's fairly far down in the article
there.
There's quite a bit to the sub culture
other than the sexual aspect.
Although I will note that the sexual
aspect,
that is the biggest part of the article.
So there you go.
These guys fuck like crazy.
I think it's more about the cuddling
really.
I mean I think that's what that's about.
You want to get snugly?
Yeah,
I got to get hot.
And I think all the first watching her
and being like,
thank you jack.
Understand man.
So ignorant.
Don't understand.
Yeah.
Have to get their message out.
So you guys created that show with,
um,
I didn't know this until recently.
David Cross and Bob owed and Kurt,
I mean,
what an incredible lineup.
How'd you guys get a,
they should have,
well,
they took us under their wing.
Wow.
Our first ever show was a at a little
club that no longer exists in downtown
La in [inaudible] 94,
somewhere around there we played a place
called Al's bar and there was like 12
drunk hipsters in the audience and one
of them was David Cross and he was like,
you guys are Rad.
Com,
uh,
open for our thing.
We do a thing called Mr Show live at
clubs in,
in,
in La comedy clubs and stuff.
And we're like,
you know,
Oh yeah,
let's do it.
That sounds good.
We had never heard of them,
but they,
they had come out,
they had just finished working with Ben
Stiller on the Ben Stiller show and they
were starting this new thing called Mr
Show.
And,
uh,
and then they had already made a deal
with hbo to have their show,
Mr Show on the air.
And,
and they finagled a way for us to be on
Hbo too with short films that they
helped us.
Well,
Curtis,
we were going to be part of their show.
Right.
I remember.
And it's like,
wait a minute,
these guys don't really fit into our
show.
They should do their own little after
our show.
Little specialty.
But first they,
I remember they took us to Aspen for the
Hbo Comedy Festival and that was very
exciting.
Yeah.
Amazing.
Owed.
And Kirk is like,
has a rep.
I mean he also kind of gave Tim and
Eric,
they're big.
Yeah.
Well,
which is just incredible.
Yeah.
That's a great,
uh,
mentor.
Both of those guys are huge forces in
comedy,
but they're kind of like under the
radar.
Yeah.
But a great like,
well,
that was great.
Great advocates for people.
I find that so awesome.
Totally.
It's great to see Bob just bust out in
the,
in the sole role.
I now take over the famous for being on
better call Saul,
but he was before that,
it was like,
oh,
bob.
I mean,
he's always doing so many great things,
but yeah.
How was that watching him have a
breakout and like the breaking bad
world?
I mean,
he's,
and he's so good.
Yeah.
I think he's just a dramatic actor now
really.
I mean that he's just taken in onto that
so amazingly and he's,
he's getting other parts to left and
right.
Well each rose,
but for me it's,
I always think if that is like a little
side thing that he's done,
I don't think of that as the main part
of him.
The main part of Bob Odenkirk is genius
comedic.
Mine came out of SNL.
He was one of the riders staff on,
on snl just as a rider.
And uh,
and uh,
uh,
yeah,
everything that he touched seemed to
turn to gold.
He and,
and uh,
we were really lucky to cross paths
with,
with him and David Cross.
They we in a way they,
we owe them everything.
They gave us our big break.
They gave us the big break.
So I recommend if you are trying to
break into the industry or in the 90s
and you're trying to break into,
I'll just try to help me.
How impressed Bob and David Jack as I
understand it from a mutual friend of
ours,
you are also an advocate.
I have.
So I have a surprise,
somewhat of a surprise.
I'm like,
God is,
am I going to be surprised by someone
from a blast,
from my past going to enter the room?
I think so.
No,
I'm really excited.
A friend of mine reached out because he
heard you were going to be on the show
and I don't know that you've seen this,
he said,
but I think that you will be,
you'll be joined by it.
Wow.
You will be joined by,
you will be joined by.
It's like,
it's never been like this is an issue.
So hang on.
Here we go.
Tell me if you've ever met.
Recognize this.
Oh my God,
it's Justin reuland.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
So speaking of genius,
so Justin Reuland,
Jack Black helped Justin reuland pitch
and sell his first show as eap.
Wow.
Jack helped Justin get his foot in the
door.
No.
Well,
and by the way,
well Justin reached out and he's like,
Jack is amazing.
He helped me and he believed in me and I
just want to say hi and thank you.
Ah,
and that he loves it.
What a mench.
Well,
let me see because you did a little
cameo in this.
His,
this is the first show he ever sold.
Here's your little cameo,
but she says the funniest part of the
show.
It comes up after this.
This is unfair.
This is juicy threat drag.
Hey Mitchell has a zone and coming along
over here.
What the Hell's going on?
I ride,
I ride.
Mitchell.
This isn't the jingle.
He winks time.
It's a job.
Now get back to weight plates that
accent.
God,
I love eating maggots out of dead
animals.
I love it.
I do it all the time.
I'm proud of it too.
I show it off.
It makes me unique comp.
Nobody seems to care that I do it at
work.
Either.
You'd think they would consider when I
work in a grocery store,
but they don't let me do as I please
listen to me.
Go on.
Tara and I are character.
I should get my own spinoff show.
I'd be huge.
Everybody had loved me.
Pull,
pull,
pull.
I forgot all about that.
Got,
I think was from,
I think
it was from the early two thousands am I
right,
but really he had shows coming out his
ears.
He was creating amazing content all over
the place.
I,
I don't really think that was a stepping
stone.
It was the first show he ever sold
thanks to you.
You went around with him.
He,
he peed it.
Oh we did.
We did a little tenacious d thing with
Justin when Ireland time fixers,
but justin had tons of people that
believed in him and we're looking for
opportunities to work with him.
By the way,
another photo I want to show you,
you're being modest,
but he's,
this is what he told me.
Okay,
look,
I couldn't you leave.
He sent me this photo last night,
blow doors down while he's a saver saved
stuff like that horse.
But I can't believe how young this is,
like history.
I mean this was a beautiful,
brought us together.
It was all about Dan Harmon and rob
shrub.
They do that.
They did that thing.
A Channel One o one which was a
competitive short film,
uh,
Charlotte thing that they did once a
month on the youtubes and a yeah,
all kinds of creative types.
Like Justin all came out of that.
Yeah.
But he told me this was at a,
um,
Mr show.
He was just there in the audience at Mr
Shell.
Yeah.
And this,
he just got to meet you randomly as a
fan.
Yeah,
no,
those were the places to be.
Back in 90 11,
you wanted to be at the tapings of Mr
Show.
It felt like,
uh,
you know,
they were the nirvana of the alts comedy
scene thing.
They,
they,
and at least to see it'd be seen.
That's right.
Well here you have it.
I love this photo.
This,
I mean,
this is amazing.
Amazing.
I got to frame this and put it on the
wall.
So,
um,
that was hard.
I wanted to ask.
We have questions from fans.
Oh,
nice.
Yes.
We have some questions from our fans.
Noise,
take them live.
We do not take them live.
You vet them.
They were posted on our,
on our subreddit,
on a fan forum.
So let me allow me to read some to you.
This one comes from pj four,
two,
four,
two.
Uh,
this one's for you,
Jack.
What was the Eric Andre interview like?
Did,
did you know what you're getting
yourself into and were there any
surprises?
Well,
yeah,
I knew what I was getting into in that
I'm a huge fan of Eric Andre and I knew
it was going to be some sick shit.
And I was a little nervous about it
because I was like,
is he going to treat me bad?
But he,
he,
uh,
it was what you'd expect.
It was about 112 degrees on the set by
design to make me uncomfortable.
I was sweating profusely.
Uh,
it smelled horrible.
And then I found out why later they were
boiling hot.
Rodding a squid carcasses underneath the
floor boards.
Uh,
and there was also some,
uh,
some surprises.
Uh,
here's a little bit of a electroshock
therapy.
Every time we did a lie detector tests,
in a way it was torture,
but it was also like a rite of passage.
I felt like it was a late Bar Mitzvah
for me if I could survive the Eric Andre
experience.
And,
uh,
I loved it.
It was so funny.
It was really weird.
Like the soda come in or the coffee
coming out.
That was pure surprise.
My plan was to try to just approach it
like any other talk show.
Like I'm going on Conan O'brien now and
do like a funny little entrance like I,
I usually do.
And then just descend into hell.
Yeah.
Oh Man.
It's great.
I highly recommend it if you get a
chance to,
to embrace
the madness.
Yeah.
That is eric on.
I love it.
And I was so happy to see you there.
Uh,
this one comes from incendiary war pig.
Oh,
uh,
which tenacious d song do you guys most
enjoy performing and how many cockup
Cock pushups can you do today?
Often asked.
Oh,
off to ask questions in there.
The cockroach up.
And the answer,
the real answer is you only need to do
one.
That's right.
Yeah.
Can you still do one though?
I'm afraid I,
uh,
I can't have,
you cannot have more out there.
Uh,
I can,
I can do a partial,
but it's like a granny pushup there has
to be there.
It has to be from the knees and I do all
that little hub,
but I can still get there.
What song do you like to play the most?
You know,
it's always fun to,
uh,
to,
to play the crowd pleasers,
but it's one of the deep cuts that I
enjoy the most.
I think it is a throw down.
I know that in the funnel and it's got
a,
it's got some biblical references in
there.
We kind of go deep and it's about the,
the dangers of,
of blindly following a organized
religions and about how it could,
it could end up being the,
the end of the world for all of us.
The Battle of the three major,
uh,
you start with the Judaism.
Moses came down from the hill and then
you go to Jesus and then you go to the
one that you can't say,
did he say his name,
his date in the song?
The three of them end up battling in the
rain.
The world is completely insane sounding.
Alarm bombs.
Crazy.
Wait,
fuck.
I said what I wrote down was what was
that song about originally?
Remember we kind of tweaked a little
bit.
I remember,
Oh yeah,
no,
we had the jam for,
for,
for months and we didn't know what the
lyrics would be.
And then we finally realized this.
Champions.
So have,
it's important.
It's an important jam is his needs toss
to hit that we leave with the big guns
we're going after.
What was it about before that?
One line is we're clowns,
but we do like to get serious sometimes.
And maybe that's that those are the most
fun ones when we tackle real issues,
you know?
Yeah.
Well I that makes me think,
cause I was watching post apocalypto
sorry.
Yeah,
fair for me to ask any question was
spreading that swollen too and yeah,
I want that dog part of the flavor,
but I don't think he's hypoallergenic.
One of my book that's not first,
that's like,
Hey,
fair.
He gets hair.
Oh my God.
What a come home he has.
He doesn't shed.
He's a Yorkshire terrier.
Hypo allergenic.
Should we,
should we get a Yorkshire Shampoo?
Sammy,
if you,
if you trust my word at all.
Are you allergic to the Dander?
I'm not,
but,
but the non shedding is like beautiful
because they're so clean.
He literally shares a pillow with us at
night and I have a good place I can
recommend to,
if you want to get a similar breed,
I'll tell you off there.
That'd be great.
They're close by.
Yeah.
Let's not say that on the air because
then there'll be all save the puppies.
Yeah.
You don't pick up the litter.
I'm swear.
I need to get a rescue.
Do you know how many dogs need homes?
Oh,
this guy needs a home.
Well,
I'm just saying,
I'm just preparing you.
Kyle's right,
there will be some hate mail back.
I talk about like,
you know,
not getting it because I've talked about
it a lot in this because I listen,
we're listening.
I thank you now I'm now I feel stressed
that everybody's listening.
This dog needs a home.
Yeah.
What about the dogs that need homes?
Need homes?
All right.
You can keep a thank you.
Well,
you know I love him.
He's like my son and when people,
you know,
they're,
they're all are people that are get a,
I crawl into your heart.
They didn't strange about but,
and I do think adopting is wonderful,
beautiful thing.
But I've got an ultimate hookup of pure
bred,
beautiful paper,
paper papers.
They got papers,
real allergies.
You,
you gotta you gotta be careful.
So,
but uh,
you were about to ask us.
Yes,
my dog,
uh,
interrupted.
I was asking cause you were saying you
like to get real about certain things
and I was wondering,
well while I was watching post
apocalypto,
do you guys think that we are on the
verge of a apocalypse here?
Is that some kind of reaction to
something you're seeing in the world?
One hopes not sure.
Of course.
We're one hopes.
Yeah.
Oops.
Oh
yeah.
I mean that,
that was,
uh,
that was the impetus to do post
apocalyptic.
We felt like,
Hey,
this is,
this is going south real fast.
This,
this guy who's our,
uh,
the leader of our country is,
is the spew and a lot of hate.
Weird.
It's scary.
And it feels like this is what happens
right before some kind of a worldwide
catastrophe.
This is the kind of talk that you hear
right before World War.
And,
uh,
so we were like,
we need to do post apocalypse
to,
to save the world.
That's what we were thinking as we see.
We're still here.
So you're welcome.
You're welcome.
Well,
there was a scene where you guys cut off
Donald Trump junior's penis.
No,
not true or no,
you're right.
It was a,
you're right,
you guys were very delicate about that
actually got a tremendous Bj,
he got it to reach a so good that it was
removed from him or we're,
no,
the Bj,
Bj is just like the best Bj of all time
and we use that as a distraction so that
we can
get the source of all of his power.
The crystal of Gilgamesh,
right.
Uh,
and then we are discovered and then he
sends his attack dogs.
He sends a Nazis KKK and a demon from
hell,
of course,
known as the Gorgonzola.
What's his name?
The goal God.
And then a spoiler alert.
I'm not going to tell you anymore,
but what happens then?
But there is no penis removal,
but there is.
Oh,
right.
His penis is intact.
Yes.
His penis and his penis is,
is well featured in the episode.
It does turn into a mushroom cloud.
Spoiled.
Oh,
I do.
I pause it as like Isla,
we have to wash this again.
There's one dissolve in this feature
film that you guys need to watch.
Is that when a tip of a penis dissolves
into a mushroom cloud?
Yes.
Wow.
You know,
the Academy Awards and there are going
to use that as part of the montage.
Well,
and of course just a reminder what,
let me just borrow your magazine.
Oh No.
That tenacious D and post apocalypto is
in consideration for best picture.
It's just an honor to be nominated.
It's an honor to be considered
considered.
Well,
I mean that's all.
I don't know who took that out of,
but thank you.
Whoever that was,
uh,
yeah.
Honor to pay for your own,
for your consideration.
Yes.
Well,
I'm considering you guys you're
considering,
um,
but you know,
we,
uh,
we drew that,
that sequence before we even knew that
donald trump's penis was shaped like a
mushroom.
And that was in a way,
it was like a no,
sir.
Domus moment.
Art Imitating life because it's not on
senior.
Oh,
it's life and it's hitting all right.
We didn't know he was imitating,
I don't know.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But all the penises were very lovingly
crafted in this series.
Elon musk was Ilan glass.
Danielle is
it?
Yeah.
Is featured in there.
I don't know why we talk so much about
Ilan Musk and that third episode,
it's just a,
well,
of course he got highs.
If you're talking about who's going to
survive the lock lips,
of course,
the super wealthy and the super to
Branson Genius engineers,
we'll find a way to end up on the hill
who would end up there.
But,
um,
you know,
a big part of it also when we're making
it was that,
uh,
we felt like we understood the psychosis
that is donald trump's the,
the,
the phenomenon that is his astronomic
rise to power because we have a little
seed of his disease too.
It's called,
what is it called,
Kyle.
Oh,
a grandiosity.
Narcissism,
narcissism,
narcissistic,
egotistical,
uh,
disorder.
Uh,
because we,
we,
uh,
have made our whole careers on this
thing about saying we're the greatest
band in the world.
Uh,
everything flows through us.
We are the best band ever.
And our,
our biggest hit song was the first song
we ever wrote,
uh,
the greatest song in the world tribute.
And so when we see this guy coming out
and he'll go,
oh,
good winning,
I'm in the best of movement of we know
that scam,
that he's planned,
that Shell,
but he's not joking.
That's the only difference.
And,
and then I,
and then I started to think about other
people in the industry who have made a
huge career out of this.
And you think of like Howard Stern,
the king of all media and he's the best
and he's kind of joking,
but he's also kind of Nice,
kind of got the narcissistic looking in
the mirror all the time,
talking about how great he is.
And then you look around at other
people.
You need to see like Kanye West,
he's the greatest and he's,
you know,
creating and you see different people in
pop culture that I have this disease and
are succeeding because the world that we
live in now embraces it.
And they love it.
They love a narcissist.
Hmm.
Uh,
and,
uh,
it seems like particular to these times
right now we are vulnerable to Psychos
who think they are the greatest thing.
People are so accepting of this
grandiose that people are like love that
larger than life figure.
Is it all?
Maybe it's always been like that.
But you had said like today people are
more accepting of it.
I wonder why that is.
What do you think kyle?
Kyle knows all the answers to
everything.
It's true.
I do.
I just doing a nicorette piece of gum
with this down over here.
Don't pay on the camera.
He stole.
I'm just trying to think of an answer we
talks about as nicotine gum.
I think that a celebrity is a,
I'm kind of the uh,
the uh,
the cachet of,
of modern society.
It seems like it's overly valued and I
think,
uh,
I think Donald was spent 14 years being
branded over and over again.
Is this kind of a super smart business
guy self made.
And I think unfortunately that can
really work.
And just repetition.
I mean there's certain just kind of
dynamics at work that,
that we know that if you just keep
repeating something over and over again,
the pinnacle can marketing.
It is,
I like the best marketing campaign ever.
So anyway,
we thought it would be good to go.
Flash forward to the whole world has
been destroyed by this mega maniacal
demon beast.
And uh,
we have to pick up the pieces because
all of the great movies in,
in our opinion are the post apocalyptic
science fiction masterpieces,
road warrior,
uh,
terminator,
[inaudible]
wizard of Oz.
These are the movies I think we can all
agree objective are the best movies ever
made and they are warnings.
They are like look out for the future.
And we wanted it,
we wanted to jump into that sphere
because not,
not only because we love those movies
but also because it seemed like what the
world needs now and only a narcissist
could think that they could save the
world.
And that's where [inaudible] comes in.
We are the antidote to the demon because
we are the demon.
Well I don't know where I'm talking
about but it is court jesters.
Sort of pointing up.
Rice was very much like a road warrior,
rock opera and it's on youtube.
It's at tenacious d.
Dot com.
You should definitely go watch it
because you do bait happen.
So make sure to go link in the
description by the way.
Oh,
watch it.
You can watch it in episodes.
You could watch and movies and of course
make sure to go,
why don't everyone just go to tenacious
d cause you can get tickets there.
You can watch the shows.
They're tenacious.
d.com
that I should throw in a caveat.
Apparently it's NC 17,
so,
uh,
well there's a couple of animated penis
as a company.
Come on.
There was a lot of love bacon and I
loved it.
It was hilarious.
Um,
so guy,
I think you got,
I mean it was such a pleasure to be here
with you guys.
The pleasure was mine.
I mean really,
we're all such big fan.
I just want to get it.
Oh,
he's doing something very sweet.
C'Mon you guys.
You're not in.
We got it.
Um,
yeah,
we're all,
and I know you have a lot of lot because
to grind.
Oh,
I hear you.
Thank you for having us come down to our
pleasure when we play your town,
please.
All right,
good.
Yeah,
I'd love to meet your son or if he wants
any like merger.
Okay.
Is it okay for me to say lifetime
backstage pass for the,
oh my gosh,
whoa.
Lifetime.
Oh my God.
Are you kidding?
And I just want to say if,
if any fans out there want to see the
greatest tenacious d show ever.
Yeah.
December 30th in Vegas.
It was the one to see that's the one
before admiration society.
It's not just my son who loves your
show.
I have since become a huge fan.
I appreciate the bravery of your
honesty.
I think you guys really go deep and I
and I picked it.
You keep up the good work as well.
Thank you God.
Thank you guys.
God bless you.
God bless God bless them.
Or as they say,
the rot.
I Sham Wally,
go back where you go.
Thank you so much for watching.
Have a blessed weekend Friday.
Hey,
have an awesome time guys.
We'll see you next.
[inaudible] shout out to your parents
also Shabbat you mom,
I love you and thanks for the Bar
Mitzvah.
You guys are the best.
We got a lot to talk about though.
So he was on the next week.
Who Do we have on next week?
Uh,
is it,
uh,
[inaudible] Jack and Eric.
All Boys,
the Jack and Eric next week.
That's awesome.
Can't wait.
So we got it.
We're all hooked up.
We'll see you next week guys.
Have a great weekend.
That tough,
Huh?
Sorry.