Okay,
I started,
I started the beginning of the class
three months ago talking to you about
what it,
what the problem was that I was trying
to address
and the fundamental problem was the
problem of belief systems and the issue
is was what precisely constitutes a
belief system and then a secondary
question was why are people so inclined
to even engage in conflict to maintain
and expand their belief systems and then
maybe a sub question of that and is
there an alternative to conflict with
regards to belief systems and then the
last issue was something like,
well is there a way of judging the
relative quality of belief systems?
And so those are all very,
very complicated questions.
I mean the first one is something like
how is it possible to understand the
structures by which we orient ourselves
in the world.
The second one is something like what's
the psychological significance precisely
of those systems?
What role does it play in psychological
health and maybe also in social health.
The next one is
can you make it non relativistic case
when you assess an array of different
value systems and then linked to that is
is it possible to hierarchically
organized value systems in a manner
that's justifiable so that something can
be reasonably considered in a superior
or subordinate position?
Now,
the last question drew my attention
because of the implications of the first
set and the last question drew my
attention because I was trying to sort
out the metaphysics in some sense of the
Cold War.
The question was,
was this just a battle ground between
two hypothetically,
equally appropriate belief systems which
could be a morally a moral relativistic
perspective,
right?
It's belief systems are arbitrary and so
combat between them is in some sense,
inevitable and even more to the point
there isn't any other way around the
discontinuity in some sense than combat
or subordination because there's no way
of adjudicating a victor because there's
no such thing as victory.
If there's no way of ranking value
systems.
It's arbitrary and it's a frightening
prospect because it means that if you
have a value system and I have a value
system and they're different and they're
different,
I mean we can talk or you can
subordinate yourself or I could do the
same,
but there's also no reason why we
shouldn't just didn't engage in flat out
conflict.
Now it's complicated in the modern
world,
obviously by the fact that conflict can
become so untrammeled that it risks
destroying everything and that doesn't
seem necessarily to be in anyone's best
interest and less your interest happens
to be in destroying everything.
And certainly there are no shortage of
people whose interests tilt in that
direction.
Alright,
so the first question was,
well,
what does it mean to have a belief
system?
And that's a very complicated problem
and I think
it's a subset of the question of being.
Maybe you can break the question of
being into two domains which we've done
in this class and you could say,
well you can assess being from the
perspective of what exists and then you
can assess being from the perspective of
how you ought to act.
So it's like you walk into a room and
you can describe the furniture or you
can determine how you're going to
conduct yourself in the room.
Maybe it's the difference between a play
and the stage setting for a play.
Now,
the modernist perspective,
roughly speaking,
is that the fundamental reality is to be
found in the description of the
furniture,
so to speak,
in that description of what is.
That's the scientific
process and the scientific process seems
to involve the stripping off of the
subjective from perception and to some
degree from action and the extraction of
the commonalities across perception as a
means of delineating the nature of
reality.
Now obviously that's a very powerful
process and it has many advantages,
but exactly what it is that science is
doing is not precisely clear.
One perspective might be is that we are
genuinely.
I'm discovering the nature of objective
reality and perhaps even the nature of
reality itself,
but there are some problems with that
perspective.
One of them being that
the scientific process seems to strip
the subjective from the phenomena.
It does technically,
right?
I mean you have a hypothesis about what
something is and you have a hypothesis
about what something is and you have a
hypothesis about some what something is
and we undertake a number of procedures
to assess what the fundamental phenomena
is and then we look across our
perceptual sets and we extract out the
commonalities and we dispense with
everything that is superfluous.
Everything that's merely subjective.
So what you feel about the chair is not
relevant to the objective existence of
the chair.
And so it eradicates subjectivity and
that's a very useful process because it
does seem to enable us to grasp reality
in a fundamental sense more profoundly,
but it leaves the subjective behind and
maybe that's a problem because they
didn't make the noise.
Okay.
Thank you.
I would have,
I just didn't want.
Alright,
appreciate it.
So.
So then the issue might be,
well it is something irretrievably lost
if you dispense with this objective and
and also how deep a hole you dig when
you dispense with this objective.
And I think that that's an intrinsically
associated with the problem of the
relationship between is an ot,
because that's an old philosophical
conundrum.
I think first put forth by Dave,
David Hume,
who made the claim that no matter how
much you know about something from an
empirical perspective,
you cannot use that as an unerring guide
to action in relationship to that,
to that empirical object or set of
empirical objects and people.
It's a tricky issue,
you know,
because obviously you can use empirical
information to inform your decisions.
But I think.
But the problem is is that there's
multiple pathways of action that are
implied by any set of data.
That seems to be the fundamental
problem.
It's something like that is that you
can't draw a one to one specification to
between the empirical districts
description and what you should do about
that.
And like maybe an example is where you
can gather a lot of information about
aids and you can gather a lot of
information about cancer and you can
gather a lot of information about
educational outcomes and economic
outcomes and so forth.
But it isn't obvious how you then use
that empirical information,
for example,
how to guide policy decisions because
you might say,
well,
how much money should we spend on
education compared to cancer prevention
and how much money should be spent on
cancer prevention compared to curing
aids and or or addressing disease in the
third world country.
What happens is that the set of
variables that you encounter while
trying to make your empirical
calculation get to be so massive so
rapidly that there doesn't seem to be
any logical way of linking them to a
behavioral outcome.
That's kind of associated with the
postmodern conundrum as well,
which is,
well,
if you have a set of data and it,
it could be a literary work for that
matter.
There's a very large number of that you
can derive from that set of data and
there's no simple way of deciding which
one is going to be canonical and so it
isn't it.
I think the reason that you can't derive
an ot from an ias is because you run
into something like competent tutorial
explosion.
It's like you have an infinite number of
facts at your disposal,
roughly speaking,
and then another infinite number of ways
that you can organize those facts and
that massive array of facts and and and
recategorized facts doesn't tell you
what to do in a given situation.
And so maybe the question of what to do
in a given situation is a different
domain of question and I,
I believe that to be the case.
I think it was Stephen Jay Gould who
talked about religion and science as to,
I think he called them different
magisterium.
Two different fundamental domains that
and that each had their realm of
operation and one was the description of
the objective world.
Obviously that's on the scientific end
and the other was the realm of ethics
and so you could put religion,
mythology,
narrative,
the humanities,
all of that history.
Even for that matter to some degree,
into the,
into the ethics category and because I
don't see a straightforward way of
taking a set of facts and then
transforming them into a behavioral
compulsion.
Then I do think that these two things
are reasonably regarded as overlapping
and intrinsically associated.
But,
but technically and philosophically
separable.
All right,
so then then the next question emerges,
well,
if they're separable,
if there has to be a domain of inquiry
into the structure of values,
what might that look like?
Like how is it that you would understand
the psychological and sociological
phenomena that are associated with a
moral stance?
How,
how would,
how would you understand the details of
that and then even more to the point,
is there any way of subjecting different
sets of ethical interpretation to
testing so that you can judge their
comparative validity because that's sort
of the way out of moral relativism.
Roughly speaking.
It's like first you make the proposition
that there are value structures and that
they're independent from empirical
investigation and then the next is that
you investigate the possibility that you
can compare and contrast different
structures of ethics and draw some sort
of conclusion.
That's not merely arbitrary.
Now it might be turtles all the way
down.
That's how the old joke goes.
Right?
But,
but maybe not.
And I was interested in that again
because I thought,
well,
are we fighting the cold war merely
because we're having an argument or is
there some manner in which one of these
systems can be just determined to be
wrong?
And of course there was more weight
behind that query because the Soviet
system and the system and the system
that's in place in North Korea,
we're not only predicated on different
assumptions than the western system,
but they were also extraordinarily
murderous.
And so that seemed to add additional
weight to the,
to the sequence of questions.
So
yeah,
I was reading young at the time and
young was Carl young was fundamentally,
I would say a psychologist of narrative
of story.
And and he,
he outlined this.
He outlined the idea for me that people
inhabited stories,
roughly speaking,
he said actually they inhabited myths
and even more to the point whether they
knew it or not,
they inhabited archetipal myths or even
that they were possessed by them.
And so it was the first time I'd really
come into contact with the idea directly
put that there was a direct relationship
between the structures that you use to
orient yourself in the world and
stories.
And so then I started to assess the
fundamental elements of stories,
what might a story looked like,
and while I was doing that,
that was informed by a number of other
things that I was reading about,
including a set of.
I read the neuroscience literature with
regards to information processing fairly
extensively.
And that introduced me to a whole set of
other ideas including cybernetic ideas
which have been incorporated into what I
was describing to you in this basic
cybernetic system is a system that has a
starting point in a system that has an
endpoint and a system that has a
subsystem that monitors progress or
deviation from progress along the
pathway to the end point.
And I thought,
well that looks a lot like a story or
map.
That's another way of thinking about it.
And I thought,
okay,
well that's where the overlap is.
And the fundamental story is something
like.
It's very straightforward.
It's,
it's also the frame that you inhabit
when you conceptualize the world and
narrow and narrow and simplify the
world,
which you have to do because it's so
complex because you have this infinite
number of facts that are laying around
you.
So what are you doing while you're a
mobile creature,
living creature,
not a static information processor and
your targeted.
You're a targeted creature and otherwise
you wouldn't move.
Right?
To move is to be a targeted creature
because you have to move towards
something or away from something so the
targeting is built right into the fact
that you're a mobile creature and then
you might say,
well,
what do you target?
And the answer to that is,
well,
you target your target.
You could say you target what you aim
for,
but then you could say,
well,
you,
you aim for what you want.
You target your desires and then that
leads you into a discussion of the
underlying neurobiology.
Essentially you bring to the table a set
of inbuilt desires and the targets that
you pick have to address the fact that
those desires exist in the desires are
actually grounded in necessity.
And this is,
this is,
this is a sidebar,
but this is where I think piaget's
theory is weaker than it should be
because piaget and you know I'm a great
admirer of piaget,
believed that the human infant came into
the world with a fairly primordial set
of reflexes,
mostly sensory motor reflexes,
and then boot strapped him or herself up
on the basis of those reflexes in the
sociological,
in the in the social surround,
and so it's a constructivist view point
that the child comes in with a few basic
elements that can get it going.
Elements of exploration and memory
essentially,
and then it builds itself as a
consequence of its exploration in the
social community.
Now I think that's true except that it's
too empty because what it fails to take
into consideration is the fact that,
and I think this is.
This is an observation in some sense,
philosophically that was first made by
Emmanuel Kant when he criticized pure
reason so that you can't come into the
world structureless.
You have to come into the world with an
inbuilt structure and then it's the
interaction of that structure with the
world that provides the information that
you can use to build yourself,
but the structure has to be there and I
would say that's the same mythologically
speaking as the idea that the great
father is always there,
right?
There's the great mother is always
there.
That's chaos itself.
The great father is always there.
That's order,
that's the interpretive structure that
you use to interact with the chaos,
and then of course the individual is
always there at the same time,
and piaget in some sense re retold that
story except he didn't give enough
credence to the fact that the infant
comes into the world far more fully
formed than his theory.
His theory presumes now the problem.
See the problem with that is that
without that additional underlying set
of,
let's call them biological constraints,
the interpretation universe gets too
large.
You need constraints to narrow the
domain of phenomena that you're
contending with and and it's in the
analysis of the constraints that the
answer to how do you stop drowning in an
infinite number of potential
interpretations emerges.
The interpretations are subject to
constraints and that's also the way out
of the moral relativist paradox as far
as I can tell.
Now.
One of the things I really liked about
piaget was that he described some of the
constraints was one of the constraints
was as well,
all right,
if I'm going to exist in a social world
and I'm going to because I won't exist
at all.
If I don't exist in a social world,
then there are constraints on the way
that I have to interact with other
people and and Psj is essential point
was I have to organize myself to play a
joint game with you,
but the game has constraints and one of
them is you have to want to play because
you have other options and then there
are other constraints.
You and I have to be able to play in a
way that other people don't object to or
maybe even that you and I have to play
in a way that other people will be,
uh,
will support.
And then you can imagine another
constraint which is you and I have to
play a game in a way that other people
would support that will last more than
the moment.
So it has the law,
it has to work today and tomorrow and
next week.
It has to work across the span of times.
It has to work not only for you and I,
but it has to work for our future
selves.
And so the dam constraints are starting
to pile up.
That's just on the socio cultural side.
That's on the constructionist side only,
but there's the biological constraints
are equally important because not only
does the game that you and I have to
play have to satisfy those emergent
sociological constraints,
but the game also has to be organized so
that the internal polity that that's
composed of,
let's call them the fundamental
motivational and emotional systems that
make that,
that,
that constitute us.
They have to all find satisfaction
because otherwise the system grinds to a
halt and so this seems to me to be the
beginnings of an answer to the
postmodern conundrum.
It's like,
okay,
any set of facts is amenable to an
infinite number of interpretations.
Fine.
Got It.
That makes deriving an is from analog to
a very difficult endeavor,
right?
No problem.
All right,
but that doesn't mean that any old
solution will work.
Why?
Well,
first of all,
it's merely because we introduced work
into the conversation to begin with.
The interpretation has to be functional
and again,
that's what it seems.
That's what seems to tie it back to the
story.
This is also what got me interested in
pragmatism technically speaking and so
because if,
if your conundrum is here you are and
there you have to be and and how to get
there.
Then one of the constraints on the
manner in which you interpret the world
is when you apply your interpretation,
do you end up moving from the point
you're at to the point you want to be,
and if the answer to that is no,
then the solution is insufficient.
Now you could call the solution untrue,
but I it's dangerous to to to introduce
the truth or falsity dilemmas because
because it isn't it's functionality,
more functionality,
more than truth.
Although I think you could say that in
the final analysis,
truth is integrally linked to function,
but I'm not going to touch that question
for the time being.
The point is is that your interpretation
of the world carries within it
implicitly a theory about its own
validity and the theory about its own
validity is that if you enact it in the
world,
it will produce the result that you
desire and then the consequence of that
is that if it doesn't produce the result
that you desire,
that it isn't good enough theory period
and that's how you grapple with the fact
that although you don't know everything,
you still have to orient yourself in the
world.
You lay out partial theories that,
that make partial predictions and if
they do a good enough job,
then you don't worry about it anymore
and you go onto the next thing.
Okay?
So then you think there's a lot of
constraints piling up on your
interpretations.
Number one,
they have to work for the creature that
you are and so you know,
we can lay it sort of like maslow's
hierarchy of needs.
Something like that's not exactly the
same because I don't think that he got
the hierarchy right for,
for very complex reasons,
but it's,
it's reasonably obvious to,
to observe that well,
you're not going to work out very well
if you don't have anything to eat and
you know,
you you've got about a week and you if
you don't have anything to drink and
obviously you need shelter and you know
you need,
you need companionship and by need.
What I mean is that if you don't have
these things,
then you die.
The whole game comes to a halt so we can
ground that in self evident reality
without any real problem.
And you might say,
well what's the list of human
necessities?
And that that's,
that's a difficult thing to parameterize
because you can argue about the degree
to which something is necessary,
but there's some things that we know
about.
Well,
we covered the basics,
temperature regulation,
elimination,
food,
intake,
shelter,
right?
But then there's more subtle things
like,
well,
children,
for example,
die without touch,
so there's.
There's something integral about tactile
interaction with other people,
so we could call that love if you want
to do that's.
It's not optional,
right?
Play is the same thing.
Children do not develop properly unless
they played,
and I would say that adults also can't
maintain their mental health or physical
health unless they play too.
And so you can say,
well,
there's a core set of necessities,
and then off of that there's a secondary
set of like,
what would you call them?
They're not ultimate necessities,
but they're pretty high.
They're going to be pretty highly valued
by people and more or less universally
pain avoidance.
For example,
under most circumstances,
most people don't really like to be in
terror.
Most people really don't like to be
disgusted.
You know,
you can lay out the basic emotions,
you can lay out the basic motivations
and you can say,
well,
the game that you're going to play has
to operate within this space that's
defined by that set of a priory
constraints.
Fine.
Now things are getting pretty
constrained here.
So they had the game,
you play house to satisfy that set of
biological demands,
intrinsic biological demands,
and it has to be something that you can
utilize with other people voluntarily
and it has to be something that will be
playable across multiple iterations and
I would say there's a very limited
number of interpretive interpretive
structures that are going to satisfy all
of those preconditions simultaneously.
And to me that just blows out the the
two things.
It blows out the claims of moral
relativism and it it,
it also demotions and this is the same
thing in some sense.
It demolishes ideas that the manner in
which people organize themselves in the
world as individuals and as societies is
somehow arbitrary.
It doesn't look to me to be arbitrary at
all and so in is genius.
I think in some part was observing that
in children's spontaneously in that when
children past the egocentric phase,
which means after they were about two
years of old or they're maybe they're
what?
They're approaching three years old,
they've more or less got their internal
mechanisms organized so that they're a
unitary being.
Roughly speaking at three.
They start to develop the ability to use
fictional frames of reference,
so and that's an interesting thing
because I would say that the fundamental
biological systems come armed with their
own frame of reference,
so if you're hungry,
poof,
up comes a frame of reference and within
that your perceptions are shaped,
the action proclivities are
rr primed and the world lays itself out
around that particular biological
necessity and you can lay those out.
Same if you're thirsty,
same if you're too hot,
same if you want to play all those
systems come built in,
but then the problem with that is that
they compete because it isn't obvious
which one should take priority and then
it's not that easy to organize them in a
social space.
And so what seems to have happened to
human beings is that we've been able to
replace the frame that's predicated on
motivational necessity with abstracted
frames that are more voluntary,
voluntarily constructed that incorporate
multiple motivational systems
simultaneously.
And that's in some sense.
That's also what it's the same thing as
we've learned how to think abstractly
and so the frame that you're going to
lay out on the world,
if it's a good frame,
is one that solves a whole set of
problems at the same time and so that,
and you can slot different frames.
You can.
You can experiment with different frames
and that's a precondition to being able
to play because one of the things that
Piaget pointed out,
you can see this when children pretend
play is like for an even more clearly in
in games that have rules,
but let's say they're in pretend play
and they're going to say,
well,
we're going to lay out a little
fictional schema here.
We're going to play out and you can be
the cat and I'll be the.
I'll be the dad,
and then you negotiate a bit to see if
those rules are acceptable and then you
run it as a simulation and that's what
kids are doing when they're playing and
they're experimented with different
super ordinate frames of reference that
are accessible in the world and they're
in there.
They're learning how to develop those
perceptual schemes and also how to
interact in a manner that allows the
scheme that they're using to find it
social acceptability and it's
successful.
The child assumes that the scheme is
successful if both children have fun
while they're doing it,
and so that's the volunteerism and so
piaget made a very interesting point
about that that I think is absolutely
brilliant.
He said that
there's a difference between a game that
people will play voluntarily and one
that has to be enforced and so then you
can imagine an environment where gay may
is played voluntarily,
it has a certain end and game b is
played by force,
but both of them are moving towards the
same end and Piaget's claim was the game
that's played voluntarily or even more
to the point.
The set of all games that are played
voluntarily will outcompete the set of
all games that are played by force if
they're put head to head in a
competitive environment.
I thought,
God,
that's such a brilliant observation
because there you have the basis for a
pragmatic grounding of for the
evaluation of ethics.
It's like you can pick the target,
it doesn't matter whatever target you
pick.
If the game is voluntary and aimed at
the target,
it will defeat a game that's imposed by
tyranny.
Now it's a proposition,
but it's a pretty good proposition.
I would say there's a fair bit of
evidence for this proposition and a fair
bit of it is actually derived from
observation of animal behavior because I
ran you guys through the emerging
literature on this stability,
say of chimpanzee hierarchies and the
chimpanzee tyrant hierarchy isn't very
stable and the reason for that is that
to subordinate chimps who are three
quarters as strong as the dominant
tyrant can take them out and they do,
and so then the question might be,
well,
how do you have to conduct yourself as a
high dominance chimp if you're not going
to be torn apart by those who are
hypothetically your subordinates and
answer to that is,
well,
don't be too much of a tyrant.
Formulate some social connections.
Engage in some reciprocity with regards
to your social relationships.
Don't oppress the females,
don't torment the children,
et Cetera,
because that makes you unpopular and
then you'll get torn to shreds and so
there are practical limits on the
expression of tyranny that are a
consequence both of biological
limitations because people are going to
object if the system is set up so that
their fundamental needs aren't met and
they're also going to object if the game
that's being played isn't functioning
socially and so this is very,
very tight set of constraints and then
the question might be,
okay,
if you take that set of constraints,
what sort of systems can operate,
what would you say?
Well,
just that what set of systems can
operate within those sets of
constraints.
Then you might say if you take that set
of all systems that might operate within
those constraints and you look at what's
common across them,
then you could extract out what's
essentially a universal morality.
It's something like that and I don't see
how that proposition is precisely
questionable.
It seems to me that all of that's built
on rock.
It's like there's no doubt that infants
bring biological necessity to the table.
I think that's fully established and
it's established physiologically.
It's established behaviorly.
It's established with regards to
evolutionary history because we can take
the motivational systems that are part
and parcel of our being and we can trace
their development back in some cases,
half a billion years,
so.
So the idea that the infant is a blank
slate when it's born and thus subject,
infinite sociological manipulation is a.
it's a.
it's dead in the water.
That's just not the case,
so okay,
so far,
so we've got that nailed down hard and
then the idea that your identity is also
shaped sociologically.
While I don't think anybody disputes
that,
it doesn't matter where they are on the
interpretive framework.
They might dispute the degree to which
that occurs and the mechanisms by which
it occurs,
but the fact that it occurs that's.
That's close enough to self evidence so
we can just leave it there.
Well then the question is what are the
consequences of the,
of sociological,
of associate,
of socialization,
and
once you admit to the existence of the
realm of biological necessity,
you instantly put a set of constraints
on how society is constructed themselves
so that they will not be
torn down and overthrown with that.
If you look at how kids are socialized,
I think that Piaget's developmental
observations are buying by,
correct the first two years.
It's mostly interactions between the
infant and the parents.
Um,
it's,
it's bi-directional though because the
infant has to come to terms with the
mother,
but the mother also has to come to terms
with the infants.
So it's not even top down at the level
of infant maternal relationship.
Quite the contrary.
If you watch a new mother adapt to a
baby,
you can see that the mother is doing as
much adaptation to the baby as the baby
is to the mother because the infant has
this inbuilt character already and has
to be charmed into a relationship that's
love.
Does that and,
and detention.
It's very little different than
establishing a relationship with someone
who's older.
It's,
it's lower resolution and it's harder to
make the observations because of course
the infant is only capable of behavioral
display count,
can't speak,
but nonetheless,
the necessity for establishing the
individual relationship is there to
begin with.
So even in the early stages of the
infants socialization,
the process isn't state downward.
It's not great father downward.
It's mutual and then of course by the
time the child is old enough to be
launched out into the social world than
all the constraints that are associated
with the playground are immediately
placed on that child and that's a very
unforgiving landscape,
right,
because the last thing a child wants
really the last thing that child wants
is not to have any friends or even
perhaps equally seriously not to have a
best friend.
Huh?
Not read something so idiotic the other
day that I couldn't believe it.
So the newest prince,
so Queen Elizabeth,
I guess great grandchild is off to
daycare and in the UK and in this
daycare,
they don't let the kids have best
friends because that's unfair.
I thought,
you know
something times you see something that's
so stupid you can't even believe it.
It it,
it exists.
And that was one of those examples
because it's been known for quite a long
time that one of the developmental
milestones that children attain
somewhere between say the age of five
and 10 is they pick a best friend and so
they and,
and you know the hypothesis well that's
unfair to all the other children.
It's like,
well first of all,
you can't be the best friend to everyone
because you then maybe there is a
billion children,
so each of them gets one second.
It's like that's just not a very deep
relationship.
So the idea that you can be equally
friendly with everyone is.
It's a preposterous,
but even worse.
The thing is,
the thing that the child is doing is
actually becoming.
They're stepping out of their
egocentricity because they're best
friends becomes more important than they
are.
And that's a precursor for adult
relationships where you know if you're
married while your partner should be at
least as important as you are and the
relationship should be more important.
But then when you have children,
it's like they're more important than
you that that's that.
It's unless there's something wrong with
you,
you come second in.
Your children come first and they're way
first.
They're not just a little.
I mean you're necessary because without
you,
they're not going to manage,
so you have to take care of yourself,
but you're not number one anymore.
Once you have kids and less seriously,
unless you didn't learn the lessons in
the playground and when you have a best
friend,
you're not number one.
They are.
And so,
so anyways,
there are these constraints that emerged
in the,
in the social landscape,
you have to have friends and also you
have to single someone out as
particularly unique among those friends
and establish a genuinely reciprocal and
caring relationship.
I can't remember the psychiatrist who
studied this so intently.
Unfortunately he was the first person to
do a detailed analysis of the best
friend relationships that children
established.
It's,
I'd like to give him credit for his
ideas,
but unfortunately I can't remember his
name.
So.
Okay.
So what are the proposition so far?
You inhabit a.
The door emc in the
world,
it has something that's akin to a
narrative structure.
I'm here,
I'm going there,
and this is the way I did it.
It's narrative,
if you describe it,
it's based in biological necessity,
but it's shaped by social socialization
and the fact of of that base and that
shaping means that the set of
interpretive Schema that you can lay out
in the world are bounded.
Those would be functional hypothetically
functional systems and maybe they
compete over over the evolutionary time
span,
but there's something in common across
that set of functional interpretations
and if you extract that out,
you can get the initial images of what
you might describe as an archetype.
Lee,
universal morality.
That's what archetypes are fundamentally
so and to say all that is no more than
to say that people can obstruct across
instances and we can obviously do that.
So then the question is can you start to
develop an articulated picture of what
that archetipal
structure of universal morality might
be?
And so my answer to that was basically,
well,
let's look at old stories,
as many old stories as we can collect,
and if the stories are stories that have
survived for a very long period of time,
so much the better because it,
it,
that indicates that they're peculiarly
memorable and peculiarly functional,
because if they weren't memorable than
they'd have been forgotten.
And if they weren't functional,
they wouldn't have managed to be the
foundation stories for,
for cultures that lasted for thousands
or even tens of thousands of years.
So,
and then we could say,
well,
let's collect a whole variety of these
stories and see if there's patterns
across the.
Now the danger of that is,
have you collected an unbiased set of
stories?
Danger number one.
How do you know that you're not just
reading into the stories that's the
postmodern problem,
reasonable,
reasonable objections.
And so that those objections have been
laid against people like,
um,
he wrote the golden bough Fraser,
who was the frazier,
who was one of the first anthropologists
to collect stories from all over the
world and to start to look for
commonalities.
The same objection has been laid at the
feet of people like Richard Lee or Carl
young or Joseph Campbell.
It's like,
how do you know you just how do you know
you're not just cherry picking your damn
interpretations?
Perfectly reasonable,
perfectly reasonable objection,
and I would say that the reason I don't
believe that I'm Cherry picking my
interpretations is because I used a
method.
It's a method that's akin to the
multitrack multi-method method of
construct validation that that clinical
psychology and other disciplines of
psychology rely upon,
but it's also akin to a process put
forward by Eo Wilson that he called
consilience,
and the process is something like,
well,
pick your level of analysis.
Does the phenomena manifest itself at
that level of analysis?
Yes.
Pick another level of analysis and
another level of analysis and another
level of analysis and see if the same
phenomena manifests itself at every
single level and then assume that the
probability that that will happen by
chance decreases with each additional
level of analysis that fits that where
there's concordance and I thought,
okay,
that,
that makes sense.
So it isn't only that you can look for
patterns and stories because you know
what?
If you're a hyperactive pattern
detector,
which basically means like there are
people like that,
people who tilt towards paranoia,
people who tilt towards conspiracy
theories,
you could see it manifest itself in new
age thinking all the time.
Then because new age thinkers are very
high in openness but not very good at
critical thinking and so they see so now
I'm going to a and B and c and d,
they think pattern.
Then they think universal pattern,
but they don't attempt to disconfirm
their pattern prediction.
And so what I tried to do when I was
starting to see patterns emerge in the
stories in informed by people like you
and Eliana and so forth was to see if
what they were describing manifested
itself at any other levels of analysis.
That we're independent intellectually
from that stream of thinking.
And I found it in two places.
I found to cybernetics and I found it in
neuroscience and so and and that,
that and the neuroscience element.
That includes the physiology,
but also the behavioral analysis that
was done by by people most particularly
like like like Jeffrey Gray and the
animal experimentalists who were
brilliant,
brilliant scientists and who've done a
very good job of laying out the manner
in which interpretive frameworks exist
within the realm of animal cognition and
and,
and to describe how they manifest
themselves in the world.
So I thought,
okay,
that's not too bad.
You've got.
We've got maybe four different levels of
evidence all pointing in the same
direction.
And so that's why I walked you guys
through the neuro psychology.
It's like a story is you're going
somewhere,
you're somewhere and you're going
somewhere and you're tracking your
progress.
Okay?
That's the story.
Well,
what,
what happens when you look at how people
lay out there called cognitive maps,
while it's the same thing you specify a
target and endpoint is you specify a
beginning point,
which is just where you are,
and then there's a mechanism,
a comparative mechanism that operates or
multiple comparitor mechanisms that
operate neuro physiologically.
To Orient Yourself towards that goal and
the emotions basically emerge as a,
as a consequence of that positive
emotions indicating that you're moving
forward properly negative emotions
indicating that you've encountered some
kind of obstacle.
It's like,
well,
that's the basic.
That's the basic structure of a
narrative.
Okay,
fine,
so now we can see how it's instantiated
neurophysiologically.
That adds a fair bit of credence to the
to the entire process,
so
now normally when you look at the basic
cybernetic work,
there's a hypothesis that the system is
oriented towards a goal and that it's
comparing what is manifesting itself in
the world to that desire to instate as
the system moves,
but it's too simple because people don't
precisely have gold.
They have nested hierarchy of goals and
so the issue of emotional regulation
becomes more complex than are you
proceeding happily towards your current
goal because your goal is composed of
micro goals and it's a constituent
element of a set of macro goals,
and so that makes the problem of error
far more complex than it would be if you
only had one frame of reference and you
were only adjudicating your error within
that frame of reference.
The question starts to become what does
it mean when you make a mistake?
And the answer to that,
the behavioral answer to that was,
well,
you encounter a stimuli that's a threat
or maybe a punishment or an incentive
reward or a conservatory reward,
something like that.
It's very,
it's a.
it's a unit dimensional and
oversimplified answer,
I'm not complaining about it has great
utility,
but there's the problem,
there's a problem and the problem is it
doesn't take into account the nested
structure of this,
of your goal hierarchy.
And what that means is that it
underestimates the difficulty of
responding to an error.
Because the problem with an error is
that you don't know what the error
signifies and that's a huge problem and
that's part of what I want to delve into
even in more depth today,
and so this is like Alice in wonderland
going down the rabbit hole.
It's exactly the same thing.
That's the hole.
The rabbit hole is you made a mistake,
right?
You made a mistake.
You've got your oversimplified
representation of the world laid upon
it.
It validates itself in its execution.
If it executes properly,
if it executes improperly,
then what does that signify?
And the answer isn't precisely that
you've made a mistake.
The answer is it signifies that there's
something in the world that you excluded
that shouldn't have been excluded,
and that's a big problem because when
you've laid out a simplified schema on
the world,
you've excluded virtually everything.
And so what that means is that as soon
as you make an error,
the search space for the error
immediately tends towards the infinite
and you experienced that and it's,
it's,
it's part of it.
Human existential experience and the way
you experienced that is,
especially if your mood is shaky,
is you lay out a small plan,
like maybe you go out for coffee with
someone that you're romantically
interested in and they're,
they're,
they're not,
uh,
they're not pleasant to you.
And,
and so that scenario it means,
well,
what does it mean?
Well,
you've construed yourself wrong.
You've construed them wrong,
you've construed the opposite sex wrong.
You've construed human beings wrong,
you're a walking catastrophe and you
might as well not even exist.
It's like,
well,
that's,
that's pretty extreme,
but it's not that extreme.
I'll tell you like it's,
it's not that uncommon for people to
have exactly that set of catastrophic
responses to even a minor setback.
Now it's not good for them.
And I would say no,
just because you scraped your foot
doesn't mean you should dig a grave and
jump into it.
Pull the dirt on,
on top of you.
You know,
so you don't want to start by taking
yourself completely apart,
but that doesn't mean people won't do
it.
They do it all the time.
In fact,
to me,
it's always a mystery that they don't do
it every single time because the logical
inference for why didn't you get someone
interested in you could easily be
because you're a failure as a human
being and at some level that's actually
true.
Now it's,
ah,
it's true in a way that's not that
helpful,
right?
Because it's just too catastrophic,
but it isn't obvious at all how people
can defend themselves against that
cascade of,
of,
of Ka,
Ka,
catastrophizing.
I mean,
after all,
if you are everything you could be,
then maybe everyone would be attracted
to you.
I mean perhaps not,
but you get the point and no and no easy
rationalization is going to let you just
brush that away,
especially if you actually happen to be
interested in the person because that's
even worse because then not only are you
rejected,
but you're rejected by someone who's who
upon whom you've projected an ideal or
perhaps on from whom you've actually
observed an ideal.
So it's worse.
You're,
you're rejected by someone that you want
to have be attracted to you to validate
your own miserable existence.
It's not a trivial problem,
so you're in this protected space that
I,
you know,
I made an analogy between that and the
garden of Eden or the city that Buddha
was raised in.
It's all protected and everything inside
of this beautiful and functional,
and that's by definition because if your
frame of reference is working properly,
then what's within it is things you
control,
that are functional and,
and,
uh,
and they are serving your purposes.
So
when you're successful,
you're in the garden of Eden.
That's one way of thinking about it.
When,
when the things that you're laying out
in the world are delivering what they're
supposed to deliver,
that's what you inhabit.
But the problem is,
is that there's always the snake inside
the garden and it's,
that's the story that's echoed in the
story of Buddha.
In that case.
It's Buddha's own curiosity that happens
to be the snake.
And you could actually say the same
thing about human beings.
Maybe it wasn't the snake.
Maybe it was eve's curiosity.
They're the same thing in some sense.
And so it's Buddhist curiosity that
drives them outside the city to find
disease.
And death and to blow apart his
paradisical conceptualization of the
world.
And so when we're looking at you for
universality,
the first thing we might say as well,
if you have a frame of reference that
you've laid on the world,
it's a story.
You live inside a story and the second
thing we could,
and that's universally true,
the content of the story can differ.
That's okay,
I don't care about that.
It's the structural equivalence that I'm
interested in.
You live inside a story and you have to
do because you have to live in something
like that because you are goal directed
and you have to be and you have to
simplify the world because you're just
not enough of you to take into account
everything at once.
In fact,
you could hardly take into account
anything at once so you don't have to
narrow things unbelievably and by
narrowing and including only certain
things,
you exclude virtually everything else.
So you're always in the problem in this
situation where you have this little
bounded universe that you inhabit,
but outside of it is chaos itself.
And,
and so that's the existential landscape
order surrounded by chaos,
right?
It's like a tree.
It's like the,
the,
the evolutionary home of primates,
the tree with the snakes on the ground.
That's,
that's our landscape or it's the fire
for tribal people and the terrorists of
the forest that are beyond the,
that are beyond the.
The light that the fire casts.
It's explored territory versus
unexplored territory and that's,
that's an archetype as well that,
that you can't not be in a situation
where that's the case.
Even if you're among friends,
you know,
you think that's explored territory.
That's not exactly right because what
happens if you're among friends is that
they carefully reveal new parts of
themselves all the time.
So it's like they're blasting little
elements of unexplored territory
territory at you constantly.
And if they don't,
then what happens?
You get bored and you look for New
People and we know there's empirical
data on that with regards to intimate
relationships because there was a nice
study done awhile back showing that
looking at the ratio of positive to
negative emotional experiences that were
most predictive of long term
relationship success.
And the answer was,
now obviously it depends on how you
would measure an event and how you would
measure positive and negative emotion.
But that aside,
the finding was something like if you're
in a relationship and you only have five
positive interactions to one negative
interaction,
then the relationship will land.
It's too negative.
But if you have more than 11 positive
interactions to one negative
interaction,
then it also ends and you think,
well that's pretty bloody peculiar.
Why?
Why in the world would that be?
Don't you want like a 100 to one
positive to negative interactions?
And the answer to that is what makes you
think that you wanted to relationships
so that you can be happy or at least
happy moment to moment.
Why do you think that it's not?
It's certainly not the case is that you
know that too.
Because I'm,
I mean I bet you there's not a person in
this room who hasn't rejected someone
because they were too nice to them.
Something like that person's no
challenge.
It's something like that.
You want someone who you know you can
get along with them,
but now and then they bite you and you
think,
oh,
that's,
that's interesting.
You know I didn't really expect that,
and then you go and puzzle over it for a
while.
You get tortured yourself about it,
and that's one of the things that keeps
you really linked into the relationship
and the reason for that is that part of
the reason that you want the
relationship isn't so that you're happy
right now.
It's so that you can live a high quality
life across multiple decades and so
you're looking for someone that you have
to contend with who's going to push you
beyond what you already are and who's
going to judge you harshly often for
your limitations.
Now that'll make you angry and all of
that you'll know and resentful and maybe
you'll take your revenge and all of
that,
but you don't want someone who thinks
you're perfect in your current forum.
Partly because why would you want to go
out with someone that diluted?
So okay,
so you've got this interpretive Schema
laid out on the world and it excludes
the entire world and because it excludes
the world,
the world tends to manifest itself
inside that protected space on a in an
uncontrollable manner,
and that can take you down and it takes
you down the rabbit hole and down the
rabbit hole is where everything is
because when you make an error,
what that is is the manifestation of the
excluded world and the problem with that
is that's too much,
right?
Because if you step out of the lifeboat
into the ocean,
then you drown and that's,
that's not any good.
You can't drown every time something
manifests itself that you didn't expect.
There has to be a mechanism for
orienting you in the face of error.
All right,
so what exactly does that imply?
The question is what you discover when
you go down the rabbit hole.
I was thinking about that a lot today.
I showed you that diagram that I thought
was like a map of the phenomenal logical
world.
The lowest resolution category is
something like the dragon of chaos.
And so you might say,
well,
what do you discover when you make an
error?
And the answer is,
first,
it's a brief manifestation of the dragon
of chaos,
and that's no more to say than when you
encounter the incursion of unexplored
territory into explored territory.
The circuitry you use is the same
circuits that we use to to respond
instantaneously to the presence of
predatory forces.
We use that circuit and that makes
perfect sense because the Predator is
almost by definition,
the thing that lurks beyond the safe
confines of the community.
And I told you I believe a story about
rats raised in naturalistic
environments.
The rats are.
It's got the burrows on one end of the
little field.
They're little rat hierarchy.
They're doing their little rat social
things.
They're playing and they're laughing and
they're tickling each other and they're,
they're,
you know,
raising the rat families.
And that's all working out just fine.
Rats in that situation,
by the way,
are very difficult to get addicted to
cocaine.
If you want a dick,
the rat to cocaine and you have to put
it in a cage at isolated,
it's not really a rat anymore than any
more than you're a person if you're in
solitary confinement,
right?
I mean you're sort.
You're mostly,
you're just misery.
Anyways.
In solitary confinement,
you'd be after cocaine nonstop and maybe
under other circumstances,
but like a normal rat.
It's not that interested in cocaine.
So that's just a side note.
Anyways,
the rats are doing their thing and then
they've learned that they can go out to
the other side of the field and they can
get food and so one day the
experimenters,
instead of putting food out there and
put a cat out there and the rat goes out
and gets a whiff of the cat,
which they do not like.
And then the rat runs home and pokes his
beak out of the borough and screams for
like two days ultrasonically and all the
other rats are like frozen stiff.
Because of that.
They're not going anywhere.
And so a two day rat screaming fit is no
trivial thing that be.
I calculated that'd be the equivalent of
use screaming for two weeks,
so you have to be pretty upset to scream
for two weeks.
Right,
so this is hard on the wrap,
but the reason I'm telling you this is
the route doesn't expect the cat to be
there.
The rat goes out and there was a cat and
what it uses its Predator detection and
alert systems to signify the presence of
the cat and what we've done with the
dragon imagery,
roughly speaking,
is making a Mailgun of predatory bond
stirs and state.
That's a symbol for what lurks beyond
safety because we're.
We're observing our own responses in
some sense and it's not only that we're
observing our own responses,
but we also have a category categorical
set of responses to Predator and we,
again,
there's no speculation about this.
We already know this,
like if you go studied monkeys,
for example,
they have distinct sets of vocalization
that are associated with Predator
detection that have distinct circuits.
We know that there are Predator
detection circuits and it's not
unreasonable to also presuppose that
they underlie the phenomena,
for example,
that human beings are very good at
learning fear to snakes.
Snake fear might be innate like that's
pushing the argument,
but at minimum psychologists have
already concluded that even if snake
fear isn't an eight,
and it probably is,
that it can be learned like that.
So you can condition people to be afraid
of pictures of snakes way faster than
you can condition them to be afraid of
pictures of electrical outlets are
handguns,
so that's well documented.
I don't think anybody disputes that at
all.
So the first assumption is when
something unexpected emerges,
so we'll call that the snake in the
garden that you're prey and Predator in
the monster has come to get you.
It's something like that.
Now the representation of the dragon is
more complex than mere monster because
the dragon,
the mythological dragon also is the
thing that hoards treasure.
And I really liked that symbol.
I think it's.
I think that's also why it will never go
away.
It's such a great symbol because it
says,
well,
the unknown can take you down,
it can,
it can bite you with its fiery breath,
like a poisonous snake,
and it can burn things like fire and
it's an aerial Predator that can take
you from the air and it's a carnivorous
Predator that can take you from the
ground and it's Reptilian.
It's the sort of thing that can pull you
down into the water and it's easy to see
that as an amalgam of of the threats
that have been laid forth for human
being since the beginning of time and
and monster is an amalgam of Predator,
and you might say,
well,
there's no such thing as a dragon.
It's like,
yes,
there is.
It's just a loose category.
What's common across all predators
equals dragon.
It's not like it's not.
They're not real.
They're hyper real.
They're more real than the phenomena
themselves.
Just like an abstraction can be more
real than the phenomenon of themselves,
and then the canonical dragon for human
beings isn't just a predator.
We're not rabbits.
You can imagine that the dragon for a
rabbit is just a dragon.
There's no damn treasure there at all,
but for human beings it's ambivalent
because the thing that you don't know
about is also the thing that holds the
greatest gift and why is that?
It's because the unrealized world
manifests itself when you make an error
and the unrealized world is something
that can take you down obviously,
but it's also the source of all new
information.
It's an infinite source of information
and that's a really useful thing to
know.
Error is an infinite source of
information and that's one of the things
that can help you recalibrate the way
that you interact with the world.
You think,
well,
we're interacting.
Let's say we're having a conversation
and it's flowing melodically and all of
a sudden I say something and there's a
disjunction,
right?
You're offended by it.
There's some negative emotion that comes
up or or,
or,
you know,
maybe I've said something to impress you
or to be arrogant and you respond badly.
It's like we've got this melodic thing
going on.
It's a conceptual frame and something
pokes itself up to put a disjunction in
the conversation.
It's like,
well,
that's where the inflammation is.
It's like something went wrong,
something didn't work out.
I'm not looking at the world properly or
I don't know you well enough for as well
as I thought there's something there and
if I have any sense,
I'm going to focus my attention on that,
like not obsessively or anything like
that,
but that's where all the information is
because as long as what we're doing is
working,
then we both know enough already.
As soon as what we're doing together
isn't working,
then that's instant evidence that
there's something about us that needs to
be updated and you might think,
well,
that's a terrible thing,
and the answer is yes,
of course it is.
It's a terrible thing,
but it's also the thing,
and this is the next stage of the
development of this,
let's call it universal morality.
It's like the universal morality might
be found in the answer to the question,
what should you do when you make a
mistake?
Now,
one answer is catastrophic disillusion.
That's,
that's a collapse into chaos.
While that's no one is going to pick
that voluntarily,
let's put it that way.
It's an unbelievably unpleasant,
terribly anxiety provoking,
shameful and painful all at the same
time.
Worse,
it can mean the absence of positive
emotion because if you really collapse
into chaos,
not only are you overwhelmed by negative
emotion,
but the positive emotion system shut off
and that's what happens to someone who's
extraordinarily depressed and also hyper
anxious at the same time.
Not only are they suffering from an
excess of negative emotion,
but they've got no incentive movement
forward whatsoever.
Okay,
so that's not an optimal solution
because it takes you out the other
possible,
and so I would call that a nihilistic
solution or a chaotic solution.
It's not a solution.
It's a disillusion and you can think
about it as a precursor to a potential
solution,
but it's very easy to get stuck there
and that's why Jonah could have stayed
in the belly of the whale along with all
the other people that were eaten by the
whale and never got back out.
And you see people like that all the
time.
Their error has come along,
blown out their frames of reference.
They've collapsed into the underworld,
into the chaotic underworld,
and they don't know how to get out.
They have posttraumatic stress disorder
or they're depressed or they're hyper
anxious or or they're.
They're resentful and aggressive and
destructive like there's any number of
states of being that can overwhelm you
when the bottom has fallen out of your
life,
so it isn't something that people are
going to.
It's not an optimal solution,
let's put it that way.
Well,
the,
the other,
that's a nihilistic solutions a
collapse.
The other solution is
we're talking and I don't get what I
want from you,
and so I say,
you better not do that again.
I don't want to see that from you again
and starts a tyrannical attitude,
right?
What I'm going to do is I'm going to
take my universe of order and its
predictions and I'm going to say,
you go along with this or I'm going to
punish you,
and that's,
that's a.
Now there is an element in society like
society is made up of threats like that.
To some degree.
It's an erotica bowl in eradicable part
of society.
That would be the tyrannical aspect of
the Greek king,
let's say,
you know,
we we've organized a set of punishments
and threats that keep each of us in
alignment.
However,
generally speaking,
in a society that's functional,
we've decided to adopt agreement with
that set of principles more or less
voluntarily and we say,
well,
you have rights and responsibilities and
I have rights and responsibilities and
I'm willing to pay a price for years,
including the acceptance of punishment
if I transgress,
but you're going to do the same for me,
so there are.
There are intelligent ways that
punishment and threat can be used and
bound it so,
but that could easily degenerate into
tyranny and one of the methods that I
can choose to use if I don't want to
encounter error is just to enforce my
will on everyone else and I think when
that happens personally and in the
family and in the community and in the
state all at the same time,
then you get the emergence of a tyranny
and
so I would consider those to
counterproductive
reactions to the emergence of the
unrealized world.
It's like you say something.
I do like a collapse completely.
Children don't like other children who
do that by the way.
Right?
Something that's very interesting to
observe,
so let's say kids have organized
themselves to play a little game of
baseball with a plastic bat and a ball
and you know one child pitches and the
other child hits the ball and the child
catches it and puts the,
puts the batter out and the batter
bursts into tears.
Well,
what happens is the other kids,
you know the first time that happens,
they'll be sympathetic.
The third time that happens,
they won't invite that kid out to play
baseball anymore,
so the answer to we're not getting along
is not you get to burst into tears and
and,
and manifest extraordinary emotional
distress because if you do that,
no one's going to want to play with you
and that's a lesson that many people
could stand learning.
Again,
one of the things I think that's really
destabilizing our society right now
maybe is that I'm not sure that kids
have been encouraged or allowed to play
enough in the last 25,
30 years and I think a lot of this
identity stuff is actually fantasy play.
It's delayed fantasy play because it's
sort of what you do when you're seven
years old.
It's like,
well,
I'm going to be this identity.
That's what you're doing when you're
pretend you're going to go along with
that because we're going to play this
out.
It's like,
that's fine.
You don't impose that though,
right?
Not Not.
If you're a kid that has a clue,
you invite people to play.
You don't insist on your identity and
their compliance with it.
It's not a playable game and you don't
burst into tears and runoff when someone
won't play your game because then they
won't play with you and then you have to
turn to force and that's.
That's fine if that's what you want to
do,
but you better look out because you
better be ready to use it.
This creating universal morality through
responsible making sure because this
search or a better this structure being
from a programmatic perspective,
the does come with responsibility of
making sure that people are trapped.
Perhaps the medical leave structuring
somewhere else,
but we have a responsibility that
against.
Good question.
I mean that's part of the question that
in some sense motivated in some sense
motivated the American incursion into
Iraq.
Right?
So what's our responsibility in
relationship to tyranny?
That's a good question.
Feminists are getting this for
protesting about the petition of human
and say Saudi Arabia.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that's.
I think that criticism is more emerging
because of.
Because it's apparently.
It's apparently paradoxical in they've
laid out a set of principles to which in
principle they they adhere and one of
those principles is to reduce the
destructive power of the patriarchy.
It's like,
okay,
there is some destructive patriarchy for
you radio silence.
It's like,
hmm,
now what am I supposed to do about that?
Am I supposed to question your adherence
to those principles?
Which is exactly what should be done.
So I think it's a.
it's,
it's a,
it's a criticism of performative
contradiction.
You say you're for this,
but when it comes to act it out,
you don't selectively in this situation,
so if there's something wrong,
there's something about your game that
you're not being straight about.
That's the criticism and maybe there's
rejoinders to that,
you know?
Well,
okay,
well responsibility.
Well,
you know,
then you'd have to look at,
at,
at different levels of,
of analysis with regards to
interactions.
You definitely have a responsibility to
your partner and your children.
Okay?
So your responsibility to your children
as far as I'm concerned,
is don't.
It's twofold.
One,
don't let your children do anything that
makes you dislike them and there's a
corollary to that,
which is don't be an idiot.
You know?
So that's partly why you need a partner
because your partner has to tell you
when your demands on your children are
excessive because you're kind of,
you know,
you're not 100 percent oriented
properly,
but still you're their target adult.
And so it's up to you to help them
choose a path that makes you want them
to be around.
Right?
And that that's your critical
responsibility and hopefully your enough
of an an analog of the broader community
so that if they can figure out how to
get along with you,
it radically increases the probability
that they'll be able to get along with
everyone.
So for example,
if you're playing with your children two
years old,
you,
you help them,
you encourage them to play in a manner
that's fun.
And if you get that down,
then you know when you introduce them to
another child,
don't know how to play in a manner
that's fun and so great.
You've solved the problem.
The problem is to get your child to
enter into the collaborative social
world.
And so yes,
you have a primary responsibility for
that.
And then with regards to your,
here's something to think about with
regards to roles.
So my wife and I have had this
discussion many times,
one of the discussions as well,
how are we to treat each other in
public?
And it isn't.
Her name is Tammy.
The discussion isn't how should Jordan
treat Tammy in public?
Or how should tammy treat Jordan?
That's not the discussion.
This isn't personal.
It's how should a wife treat her husband
and how should a husband treat his wife?
It's impersonal and it's partly you
don't put your partner down in public.
Why?
Well,
it's not because you're hurting that
persons feelings.
That's not why.
It's that you're denigrating the
relationship that you are in
voluntarily.
You know,
some of the most painful days I've ever
spent.
One in particular I spent with a group
of men who had been in therapy for their
marriage and who bloody well needed it.
I can tell you that.
And they spent their whole day
complaining about their wives.
Like it just made me sweat the whole
day.
I thought,
I can't believe I'm here with you guys.
I can't tell you.
Why was it,
you know,
it was just happenstance more than
anything.
And I thought,
how can you be so damn dump?
It's like,
it's certainly possible that you
marriage barbara married barbarian
witches fine,
but you don't have your so lacking in
sense that you would discuss that in
public.
Not noticing that you pick them.
So basically all you're doing is holding
up a sign and waving it constantly.
That says,
I'm an idiot,
I'm an idiot.
Right,
and so well,
Dr.
Responsibility,
you have a responsibility to those whom
you love and are obligated to,
to ensure that they manifest themselves
in a manner that's most beneficial to
them over the long run.
Now you have the same responsibility,
I would say to yourself,
but you'll have blind spots.
Other people have to help you with that,
but so the rule is you know,
you don't let your,
don't you help your wife figure out how
not to make a fool of herself in public
and she extends to you the same courtesy
and it's partly maintenance of the
sacred nature of the relationship.
It has nothing to do with you or her.
Precisely.
It's broader and wider than that.
Okay,
so then that's two levels of
responsibility.
Child,
partner,
next level of responsibility.
You're asked at your workplace to go
uncaught to undergo unconscious bias
retraining new say yes.
It's like,
okay,
you've just admitted that you're a
bigot,
right?
Because you're acting it out.
It's like I'm a racist bigot.
Obviously I need to be retrained and so
you might say,
well,
I'm not going to make a fuss about it.
Right?
Or I've been told to do it.
Or maybe you agree with it fine,
and if that,
if you agree with it,
no problem,
you can make a case for it.
I think it's a week and appalling case
personally,
but you can make a case for it.
You could say,
well,
you know,
I am interested in my,
my biases and how to rectify them and
like,
fair enough,
you know,
people are biased,
but if you object to it and you don't
say anything,
then you're complicit and then it's on
you and you know like a causes B and C
and b causes c and d and so forth.
The thing tends does noise,
but it has this tendency to expand and
you'll come home angry and upset and
you'll go to the training program and
you'll think this is ridiculous because
that is what you'll think in all
likelihood and you won't say anything
but it eats at you.
Well,
you've abrogated your responsibility.
And so,
and then you might say,
well,
so then,
then that's how the community becomes
corrupt.
That's how the community starts to be
corrupt,
is that people turn a blind eye to
emergent pathology when they know it's
pathological.
That's exactly what the Egyptian story
says.
Oh,
cyrus is overcome by Seth because he's
willfully blind,
which means he knows,
but refuses to.
He knows quote his Predator detection
systems have gone off monster while then
you're supposed to look okay,
exactly.
What sort of monster is this?
Well,
it doesn't have wings.
It doesn't have a tail.
You know,
you cut it down into the.
You cut it from the monster that it
could be into the monster that it is.
That's the first step.
And then you take the appropriate steps
and then you also noticed the other
monsters.
Because here's something to think about.
You're going to pay a price for speaking
up,
but you're gonna pay a price for not
speaking up.
So it's like monsters on the right
monsters on the left.
Pick the ones you want to battle with.
If you decide not to make your stand,
you weaken yourself.
If you do it 100 times,
then even if the monster was only this
big,
now you're this big,
it's going to eat you.
You know when it was this big,
you probably could have kicked it across
the room.
It's too late for that.
You have capitulated and capitulated and
so what you've done.
This is a way to think about it from a
union perspective.
This is what young was trying to get at
when he was talking about elk alchemy.
It's like the thing that pops up to
object to you is this incredibly complex
entity.
It's,
it's the entire world encapsulated in
the event.
If you interact with it,
you unpack it.
You differentiate your sense of the
world and you and you gather new skills.
So for example,
let's say there's something going on at
your workplace and that you need to
object to it because it's driving you
crazy and you talk it over with your
wife so that you've got your head
screwed on straight and say,
well,
I've got to say something.
And you go there and you say something
and you're stumbling and awkward and all
of that.
But,
but you watch the response and maybe you
get what you're aiming at.
Maybe you don't,
but you've learned a bunch.
You've learned.
While I'm not as coherent as I could be,
I'm not as good at putting my arguments
together.
My boss is more of a son of a bitch that
I,
that he thought he was.
This is a worst problem that I knew
about.
It's like differentiated,
differentiated.
So now the landscape is higher
resolution and so were you well,
so good.
So maybe you're a little bit next,
better prepared the next time you have
to do that.
And so the issue here to some degree is
don't lose an opportunity to grapple
with something that objects to you,
especially when the object objection is
rather small because that's something
you can say,
well I can put up with it.
It's like fair enough.
Like you don't want to make everything
into a war.
I usually use your rule of three.
If we're interacting and you do
something that I find disruptive,
I'll note it.
It's like potential dragon.
Go on and I'll leave it be.
And then if you do it again,
I think,
oh yeah,
that probably wasn't merely situation,
but I'll leave it be because that's
still not enough evidence.
But if you do it a third time,
then I'll say,
hey,
I just noticed this and you'll say,
no,
that didn't happen.
And I'll say,
yeah,
no one really did it happen,
but it happened here and it happened
here and I'm not making this up.
So there's something going on here like
I'm not ignoring it and we can get to
the bottom of it.
And then they'll come up with a bunch of
objections about why that isn't
necessary.
And you push those aside.
Now come up with a few more objections
and then push those aside.
And then usually they'll get mad or
burst into tears.
And if you push that aside,
then you get to have a conversation,
right?
And then you can solve the problem.
But man,
it's,
you got to be a monster because first of
all,
you need six arguments about why their
objections aren't gonna stop you.
And then you have to not be intimidated
by the anger.
And you have to not be swamped by
compassion about the tiers and then you
can have a conversation and people don't
do that.
They won't do that.
And so they don't solve the problems.
And so then the problem's accrue,
right?
And if they accrue over 15 years of a
relationship,
they end up,
then they end up fat,
ugly,
end in divorce court.
So,
and that's,
you know,
that's not a,
that's not a great outcome.
It's a divorce court and cancer are
similar in their,
in their seriousness,
not always,
but,
but sufficiently often.
So when that error emerges,
it's a,
it's a glimmering.
Now,
you know,
we talked a lot about the hierarchical
structure of goals,
you know,
and so here's,
here's something that,
here's something to think about.
So the thing that analysis itself is
error has a twofold nature.
That's because it's chaos in order at
the same time,
or it's because it's all the archetypal
structures at the same time,
it's the dragon of chaos.
It's the great mother,
positive or negative.
It's the great father,
positive and negative.
It's the individual hero and adversary.
All of that manifests itself in the
moment of error,
right?
The architects come forward.
Did you make an error because you're a
bad person.
Could be now.
So,
so one of the things to think about with
regards to that is,
you know,
in the Mesopotamian creation story,
when,
uh,
when time comes flooding back,
it's so interesting that story.
Think about what she does.
So she's the archetype of error.
Let's say the error that can take you
out,
they can dissolve you in salt water
tears.
Well,
she's irritated because apps,
it was destroyed.
So the structure is gone.
Carelessness is destroyed.
The structure up comes,
tie or not.
She's not happy.
What does she do?
She prepares a phalanx of monstrous
monsters.
It's exactly what the story says.
She produces a whole horde of monsters
to come at you and she puts king you at
their head.
And Kenya was the king of the monsters
and later,
so he's the ultimate bad guy.
He's Satan,
for all intents and purposes,
in the midst of Damien version,
it's out of him that makes human beings.
It's out of his blood.
But mark makes human beings.
That's a critical issue,
man.
The Mesopotamian said,
imagine the worst monster you can
possibly imagine the king of all the
monsters.
That's the blood of human beings.
Wow.
So what.
What does that mean?
Well,
it means that one of the terrible things
that lurks,
let's say that you've been in the
longterm relationship and it collapses.
Let's say you were,
you know,
he had a tendency towards alcoholism.
You weren't so great with regards to
your drug use.
You don't have that conscientious and
you had like four or five kinda low ran
to affairs and you know it.
Your marriage collapses bank.
Well,
who do you first meet when you fall into
chaos?
You meet King of the monsters and he's
you like,
why did my marriage fall apart?
What did I do wrong?
Bang,
Bang.
I did all these things wrong.
Why?
Because of that thing and habits me.
What is it?
Well,
that's the most horrifying question,
right?
Well that's why.
So down there in the architectural
space,
all these things lurk the heroin,
the adversary,
but you've just met the adversary,
right?
Well,
maybe you were tyrant.
That's certainly possible.
Maybe everything around you was chaotic,
so what do you encounter when things
fall apart?
Even counter the adversary you
encountered the tyrant,
you encounter the catastrophe of nature
and you encountered the dragon of the
chaos and they're all intermingled.
You have to sort that out.
That's what happens to Ellis.
When she goes down the rabbit hole,
she meets the Red Queen.
The Red Queen is always running around,
off with their heads off with their
heads,
and she says,
in my kingdom,
you have to run as fast as you can just
to stay in the same place right down the
rabbit hole you meet the archetypes.
And so,
okay,
so back to responsibility.
Well,
one of the things,
soldier and incent detailed,
you know,
he said,
well,
how does society go?
Corrupt said it's easy.
One little sin at a time.
You go to work,
someone's Lording it over you.
You know that they're tyrannical.
You don't have the wherewithal to stand
up.
It's like,
okay,
you're a slave.
And so if you continue to agree to be a
slave,
you will continue to generate tyrants.
Right?
And the only thing that can stop you
from doing that,
I think is the right kind of terror.
It's like,
be careful what you give up because now
it's this logo.
So.
Okay,
so,
so.
All right,
so that's this logo.
The logo is the thing that enables you
to mediate between eight,
between order and chaos.
And maybe you have to have some faith in
that.
It's like,
well,
what should you do with someone who's
harassing you?
Well,
you should fight back.
Okay,
what does that.
What's the most effective way to fight
back?
Well,
sometimes it's physical,
but that's not necessarily for the best.
Maybe it's through articulation.
Maybe it's through analysis,
right?
You want to be sharp,
you wouldn't be able to decompose a
problem.
You want to be able to formulate an
argument and a counter response and
maybe you want to be so good at that,
that people don't mess with you to begin
with.
And then you're a perfectly articulate
counter monster and you never have to
take your sword out.
That's,
that's the place that you want to be.
It's like people should know after three
seconds of interacting with you that
harassing you will be a seriously bad
idea and then you'll have a perfectly
fine time with them,
so and that's part of you know,
so there's some utility in meeting the
devil in underworld,
right?
Because maybe he's got something to
teach you that's certainly possible that
and one of the things that you can be
taught is that your normative morality,
which is basically your harmlessness and
your naivety masquerading as virtue is
completely insufficient to protect you
in the world,
especially against the sorts of things
that you're talking about,
which are tyrant tyranny.
Tyrants will push until you push back.
It's in their nature.
They don't have internal controls,
so they just push and push and push and
push and push and push.
Even kids do that,
like little kids do that all the time.
They'll just push you until they hit a
wall.
They're actually quite happy when they
hit a wall because the last thing a
child wants is a universe without walls.
It terrifies them,
right?
They want to see while I'm in a swimming
pool,
there's an edge.
They don't want to see,
oh,
this isn't as important.
This is an ocean.
I'm in the middle of an ocean.
I'm going to drown.
That's a terrible thing for children.
That's why they need discipline and
structure because it's consistency and
predictability and routine and all the
things that are extraordinarily helpful
to them.
Okay,
so now think about that hierarchy that
we talked about so you're not in a
story.
You're in nested stories,
and the nest is stories ground
themselves,
inaction in actual embodied action.
So if you're going to sit,
if you're going to be a good a partner,
maybe you help prepare the meals and to
help prepare the meals means you pick up
a plate with your hand and you move it
physically through space and you put it
on the table.
That's where it stops being an
abstraction.
So at the bottom of an ethical hierarchy
of value,
our actions,
not things that's the scientific world,
but actions and then you can label the
actions with abstractions as you move up
the hierarchy.
So you're good at setting the table so
that means you're good at making dinner,
so that means that you've got one
element of good being a good partner in
place and being a good partner is one
element of being a good person and so
you you're not so good at setting the
table and you say,
well I'm not a good person.
It's like,
well no,
you should go down to the higher
resolution levels of the hierarchy and
start there and that's what you do when
you're arguing with people.
But there's another thing that's really
useful about conceptualizing the
hierarchy in this manner.
So don't miss it.
So I think what we'll do is we'll stop
now for 10 minutes and I'll,
because I want to bring up this diagram
because what I want to do next is it's a
bleak story at the moment because the
story is something like you're going to
lay out over simplifications in the
world and they're going to be prone to
catastrophic error and then you have to
encounter what's terrifying in order to
progress.
And so what that means is that
progression is always dependent on
terror.
Something like that and there's some
truth in that and that's why people
don't progress,
but it's not a sufficient truth and I
want to unpack that when we come back.
So let's come back in 10 minutes and
then I'll,
I can unpack that.
There's this parable in the new
testament that just came to mind.
Um,
I'm going to mangle it a bit because
it's not one that I have well memorized,
but,
and I'm probably going to conflate two
or three stories together,
but I think.
I think I've got it right.
Christ is walking down the road and
someone picks them up and if the person
is rich and wealthy and he has a talk,
they talk and the wealthy man basically
tells him all the things that are wrong
with his life.
And then he asks him what he should do
about it.
And Chris says to him,
you have to give up everything you own
and follow me.
And that's often be read as a criticism
of wealth.
And that's actually not what the story
means.
What the story means is this,
this guy has a lot of wealth,
but he's still miserable.
And so that means that what he has is
the obstacle to what he could be.
And so that's the message of the story
is that if you're miserable with what
you have,
then you have to let go of what you have
so that maybe you could have something
else.
And so and then there's some commentary
on that story.
I think other people are listening and
they say,
well,
if that's the price to be paid,
then no one is ever to pay it.
And I think that's where the statement,
it is easier for a man to go through the
eye of a needle for a camel to go
through an eye of the eye of a needle
than for a rich man to enter paradise.
I believe that's the derivation of that
story.
And like I said,
that's been read as a critique of
wealth,
but it isn't.
It's a critique of attachment.
Now,
you know,
in the Buddhist doctrine,
one of the
impediments to enlightenment is
attachment.
And people read that as saying,
well,
you shouldn't care for anything in the
world.
And that's,
there's a nihilism that's associated
with that.
There is a strong nihilistic tendency in
Buddhism that has to do with abandonment
of the world.
Do you see that in Christianity to some
degree with people going off to lead
ascetic lives in to,
you know,
it's.
It's part of multiple religious
traditions.
That idea of asceticism and there's some
utility in it.
If it is your attachment say to material
things or status or whatever that's
interfering with your psychological
progression.
Now the idea is that you should let go
of whatever it is that's interfering
with your psychological progression
because no matter how valuable what it
is that's interfering is it's not as
valuable as what you're giving up.
Okay.
However,
that criticism still stands and the
criticism was,
well,
if the task is that difficult,
then no one's going to do it,
and so in in the brothers Karamazov,
there's a famous story called the grand
inquisitor and it's a story told by Ivan
Karamozov to his brother Leo,
and Ivan is a very high status,
intelligent,
attractive,
tough minded soldier and Lee.
Osha is his younger brother and he's
kind of softer and less rational,
a more spiritual,
and also training to be a novitiate at
the local monastery and Ivan likes to
tear strips off it because he's a cynic
and an atheist,
and and,
and in Dostoyevsky's normal,
brilliant manner.
He makes Ivan and incredibly powerful,
articulate and admirable character.
So when Dostoevsky wants to take someone
on and his literary investigations,
he doesn't take his enemy and turned
them into some sort of weak puppet.
He takes his enemy and turns them into
the strongest possible enemy he can
imagine.
And then goes to battle against that.
It's a hallmark of great literature.
It's what distinguishes dusty ask,
for example,
from Ayn rand,
because what Ayn rand does is she takes
her.
She's a darling of the,
I would say libertarian slash,
right?
She takes her enemies and they're all
the same.
First of all,
every single one of her negative
characters is exactly the same as every
other one,
and they're all bad.
You know,
there's,
there's no redeeming qualities
whatsoever in them.
And they also,
I would say,
make their weak characters who make weak
arguments.
That's not the way to progress.
The way to progress is to take your
enemy seriously and to even inflate them
into something beyond their capacity to
inflate themselves and then see if you
can hammer out a solution to the genuine
problem that's being posed anyways.
So dusty,
he does that brilliantly always.
And that's what makes him so absolutely
remarkable.
But anyways,
I even tell Lee Osha this story,
he calls it the grand inquisitor and in
the story,
Christ comes back to Earth in the
Spanish inquisition and he's,
he's out by a fountain and people sort
of notice him and he starts performing
miracles in a big crowd,
gathers around and it's like happy days,
you know.
Um,
but then the inquisitor's shows up this
old harsh tyrannical guy and he has his
guards arrested and throwing them in
prison.
And so now Christ is in prison.
And the inquisitive it comes down and
says to him,
well,
you're probably wondering why we throw
you in prison.
You know,
especially given that we're the members
of the,
you know,
where the representatives of the church
that you hypothetically founded and,
and Christ remained silent through this
entire episode.
And uh,
the inquisitor basically says,
look,
you know,
you laid down this ethic.
That's,
it's wonderful,
but it's superhuman.
No one can do it.
It's asking way too much.
And so you're,
you put the burden you put on people was
just far too great.
And so what we've done in the Catholic
church in the centuries since the church
was founded is lightened the load.
We said,
well,
we'd take ordinary people and say,
there,
here's some things you can do to be a
little bit better.
And you know,
we've instituted confession and
repentance and all that.
We've kind of toned it down so that the
average person has some hope of progress
and we're making headway.
And the last bloody thing we need around
here is you coming back and like
screwing up all our,
all our good efforts is.
It was nice to have you around once,
but once was plenty,
man,
we don't need you around anymore.
And so Christ listens to this,
doesn't say anything,
and then the inquisitor turns to leave
and Christ grabs him and kisses him on
the lips and the inquisitor turns white
and then leaves.
And when he leaves the door,
he leaves the door open and that's the
end of the story.
And it's an amazing store.
It's an absolutely remarkable story in
every possible way.
And,
and you know,
dusty was objecting to some degree to
the tyranny of the Catholic church,
or even if the Christian church for that
matter.
But the thing that he did that was so
damn brilliant is that he even made the
inquisitor leave the door open now.
And as a balanced critique of
Catholicism,
even during the inquisition,
it's so brilliant.
It's so emblematic of Dostoyevsky's take
on the world that he criticized the
inquisitorial aspect of Christianity.
And it's,
of course,
it's the tyrannical aspect of any belief
system,
but noted that they bloody well left the
door open.
Right?
So it's brilliant.
It's brilliant.
It's,
it's,
yeah,
it's remarkable.
So anyways,
the whole point that I'm making here is
that there are terrible impediments to
enlightenment and the light,
the impediments are the necessity of
sacrifice and the necessity area of
necessity of the voluntary acceptance of
suffering.
I mean,
you see that in Buddhism,
you know,
because one of the canons of Buddha,
one of the fundamental principles of
Buddhism is that life is suffering and
that attachment makes it worse and well
it isn't,
it isn't precisely attachment.
It's an attachment to things such that
you cannot release the things when it's
time to let them go.
Right?
So like you're a phoenix,
you're 100 years old,
your feathers,
they're not working anymore,
right?
You're all wrinkly,
you're done.
It's time to burst into flames and be
reborn,
but you don't want to burn off your
feathers.
You want to clean to them.
And that's not good because you have to
be willing to undergo that
transformation process.
And that involves like,
you know,
if you,
if you take your self apart because
you've made a mistake and you find out
what it is about you,
that's not set up properly.
And that's why the mistake occurred and
that's really going to happen.
For example,
when an intimate relationship breaks
down,
then you have to be in a position where
you're willing to let the errors that
are part of your character that define
you,
right?
They might even be part of your
identity.
You have to let you have to be willing
to let them go.
You have to be willing to let them burn
off and that's a hell of a thing to ask.
And so then the question might be,
well,
is there a less radical solution to the
problem then then then crucifixion and
resurrection or that the total emulation
and regeneration,
because that's the archetype will.
What's that?
That's the archetype will and point that
if you want to put your self together,
you have to die and be reborn.
I mean that and that motif comes up all
the time in,
in,
in popular popular stories and
mythology.
And so they,
here's,
here's how I think that problem can be
resolved.
So let's go back to the UN story
momentarily.
So what happens?
And the Pinocchio Story to me is
analogous in its structure to the sermon
on the mountain.
So I'm going to make a parallel between
those two things.
So basically what the sermon on the
mount suggests is that you should
conceptualize the highest good that
you're capable of conceptualizing and
orient yourself towards that and that
having done that,
you should live in the moment.
So it's not like you should live in the
moment.
It doesn't say that because that's often
Christ the Hippie,
you know,
so they,
the hippies who have adopted that or
the,
that sort of,
that,
that element of Christianity say,
well you live for the moment,
you know,
and,
and in meditation and other practices,
some of the attempt is to get you to
live in the moment,
but you know,
just to tell people to live in the
moment,
it's like,
what the hell kind of advice is that?
What about the future?
You know,
that it's not helpful advice.
Somebody comes to you and they're
suffering dreadfully because their
mother has Alzheimer's and they're
unemployed.
Well,
live in the moment.
It's like,
that's just not helpful.
It's because it's even worse than that.
It's judgmental.
You say,
well,
the only reason you're suffering is
because you haven't oriented yourself.
Property live in the moment.
It's like,
no,
you're suffering because your mother has
Alzheimer's and you don't have a job,
so like it's not because you aren't
living in the moment,
so living in the moment isn't the right
answer.
The right answer is something more like
Orient Yourself towards the highest good
that you can imagine and then act in the
moment.
That's a whole different story.
Now that's what happens in the Pinocchio
Story.
Basically what happens is that Japan
sees the star that cutting in the
distance and he orients himself towards
the highest good he can imagine.
He wants to take this creation of his
and so this is manifesting itself
conceptually at multiple levels
simultaneously because there's a.
there's a story about the destiny of
humanity in relationship to God nested
in the story.
It's like take your fallible creation,
your puppet and
set up the pre,
set up the conditions such that it's
capable of taking on full functional
independence.
It's something like that,
so that's what you do.
If you're a good parent with your
children,
you don't protect them,
you don't offer them safety,
you know,
do any of that except insofar as it's
necessary to facilitate their
development as fully competent and
courageous beings that the purpose of
the protection is only to allow that
developmental process to,
to continue.
So you,
you've Orient Japan himself and so the
father orients himself and then the sun
undertakes the voyage.
And so.
Alright,
so let's say that that's the case.
You Orient Yourself first,
then you can start to rely on your.
Then you can start to concentrate more
on your orientation to the moment.
Now
I'm going to tell you another story.
So you know,
I was just watching Harry Potter the
other day,
the first one and I was watching the
quidditch game and the quidditch game is
very interesting because there's a game
and a game going on at the same time.
So the game is just the standard
quidditch game.
It's kind of like basketball played on
Brooms,
right?
You have to throw balls through hoops
and if you get enough points you win.
But at the same time,
so there's the normal players and then
there's two seekers,
one from each team and the seekers
aren't playing the same game that the
game is nested inside the secret game
actually,
because if you're a seeker and you
perform your task that everyone wins,
you win.
But everyone wins.
And so you're not even playing the
normal game.
You're playing the seeker game.
And the thing that,
that,
uh,
Harry Potter chases is this thing called
snitch and the snitch.
This is one of the things that I can't,
I don't know how the hell jk rowling
figured this out.
I cannot figure it out because that
snitch is a winged ball.
Right?
And there's,
there's actually a symbol of that wing
ball called the round chaos,
which [inaudible] describes in his works
on alchemy.
And his works on how it could be,
are really,
really difficult.
It's not easy to figure out what he's
talking about at all.
But the round chaos,
which is a wing ball is,
is it's a manifestation of the spirit.
Mercury and mercury is an emissary of
the God.
So you can think about mercury has the
unconscious manifesting itself in your,
in your field of experience,
something like that.
In any case,
the round chaos is the container of the
primordial material from which the world
is made.
And I think about it like this.
It's this thing there.
It's that.
So when you encounter an normally an
error,
it's a container that's a way of
conceptualizing it.
And what does it contain?
Well,
it contains in some sense it contains
the whole world.
But,
but here's an example.
Like look,
let's say,
Oh God,
let's say that you've had repeated
fights with your wife about how domestic
duties are going to be arranged among,
around meal time,
and you believe me,
you're going to have those fights.
And so and so what's happening is that
mealtimes are unpleasant because there's
a war for power going on in the kitchen,
right?
And so then you think one day while
you're gonna you're gonna note that,
and you're going to do an archaeological
investigation and find out just what the
hell is going on.
And so you start unpacking the fact that
mealtimes are not pleasant.
And so what's in that little thing that
you're unpacking that package?
Well,
the entire power dynamic between men and
women in the modern world is inside that
dispute and you might find that part of
the reason that your wife is upset about
the way that mealtimes are arranged
because because her grand mother was
beat by her grandfather and that's
playing a role in it played a role in
determining her unconscious expectations
and that's pathologizing one of the day
to day rituals in the house.
And if you're going to unpack that,
you're going to have to unpack all of
that into the.
You take a little monster new,
decompose it.
You find out it's a hydrates,
got 50 heads and then you have to work
through every single one of those.
It's really,
really difficult and so it's a container
that contains everything,
but the thing is if you want packet
successfully,
let's say,
and you deal with it,
you negotiate a consensus,
then all of a sudden you get,
you get paced,
say around your meal times,
which is a major accomplishment man,
because you have to eat three times a
day and it's the center,
the household and all of that.
So,
but the thing is is that often when
you're,
especially in the context of a of an
intimate relationship,
things will emerge that produced
discontinuities and the question is,
what should your attitude towards that
discontinuity be?
While you can punish the person for
manifesting the discontinuity,
that's the tyrannical aspect,
or you can let it take the whole thing
apart and that will happen.
I mean that's often how relationships
and is that a discontinuity emerges and
people get into it and things go
sideways so badly.
The whole relationship descends into
chaos and people bail out of it.
So.
So it's no wonder that people want to
ignore it and it's also no wonder that
they want to tyrannized it.
It's like,
quit bothering me with that.
Well
possibly,
but probably not.
And also if my attitude towards you is
quit bothering me with that,
your attitude towards me when I have the
same sort of problem in reverse,
it's going to be exactly the same and so
we're not going to get anywhere with it.
All right?
But that still is painful.
Now let's go back to the quidditch
issue.
Now,
here's what happens is that
Harry Potter is picked to be the seeker.
So with that being,
t is the secret.
Whatever he represents is the seeker and
he's an interesting character because
he's touched by evil and he's a rule
breaker and he's also kind of a normal
kid.
He's not a hyper intellect or anything
like that.
That's her mind.
These role,
right?
So He's,
he's,
he's normal but,
but super normal at the same time.
And he gets picked to be the seeker and,
and then you think about what is it he
seeks and he seeks this thing that
glimmers,
right?
It flashes in front of it.
It's made out of gold and it has wings.
And if he grabs it,
then he wins.
And so the question is,
what does that represent?
Now,
it's interesting that when people watch
that movie,
they actually find that,
you know,
they think that that's kind of cool,
that it's a cool game.
Um,
and it is a cool game.
She laid it out very nicely.
And the idea is that,
well,
there's a game and if you play it,
normally you win the game,
but in that game is a metagame.
And if you play that properly,
then not only do you win,
but everybody wins.
So then the next rule is the metagame
supersedes the gate.
And that's the same idea that I'm
chasing here with you today about this
metta morality.
It's the,
it's the morality that emerges as a
consequence of the analysis of a set of
moralities or it's the morality.
It's the morality to which other all
other morality's should be subjugated.
That's another way of thinking about it.
And I said,
well,
that's a terrible thing because it,
it involves painful sacrifice or maybe
it involves confronting the thing you
least want to confront.
That's the union dictum,
right?
If your life isn't all that it should
be,
then you should find out the thing that
you least want to confront,
that you're avoiding and confront that
and that's easy to say,
but it's a terrible thing because it
means you're going to have to turn your
gaze to the place where you are weakest
and most vulnerable and that is asking a
lot of people.
So then you might say,
well,
is there an alternative?
And I think there is an alternative.
So.
So this is the anomaly,
right?
This is the ball that contains
everything.
I think there is an alternative.
I think it's associated with this idea.
So imagine,
imagine we have a.
We could have a conflict.
If we were in a relationship,
we can have a conflict that would blow
the relationship apart.
All right,
so we don't want to have that conflict
and then we could have no conflict
whatsoever,
which means that you would never get to
say what you wanted and I would never
get to say what I wanted because we're
either identical,
which is just not happening or we're
going to have conflict because you're
going to want some things that I don't
want and vice versa.
So if there's no conflict,
we are not in a relationship,
right?
So zero conflict is the wrong amount and
conflict that destroys the relationship
is the wrong amount.
And then you might say,
well,
okay,
what's the optimal amount of conflict?
Well,
so,
so then we can think about how people
respond emotionally.
So let's say if you go after the person
that you're arguing with and you say
you're a bad person and you really make
that case,
you bloody well hammered home.
You remember 50 things they've done that
were bad and you lay them out like,
I'm going to stomp you.
You're a bad person.
You really need to change.
Okay,
well first of all,
you're going to meet tremendous
resistance and that's like you've got
the hydrogen.
You're bringing the hydrogen bomb to the
war,
right,
and maybe unless you want to destroy
everything,
maybe that's not the most logical
solution,
but then by the same token,
everything's all right and we never have
any conflict.
That's not helpful either and you're
going to get bored of that and you're
not going to develop and so then the
question is,
well,
maybe there's some happy medium here.
Maybe you want to be repairing this
structure.
You know the structure that goes from
micro actions up to higher order
conceptualizations.
Maybe you want to be updating that on a
constant basis and you want to update it
in a manner that doesn't drop you into
chaos or place you in too much status
and then the answer is,
well,
how?
Then the.
Then the question is how is it that you
can calibrate your approach to error so
that you get the benefits of doing it
without the disadvantage of collapsing
into chaos and then the issue.
The answer to that is something like
it's something like once you have
decided to adopt responsibility for
being and will say that what that means
is that you have conceptualized a,
a good that you're willing to devote
yourself to and I think you,
you're perfectly welcome to do that on
an individual basis.
I think you should do it on an
individual basis.
You should consult with your ancestors
while you're doing that because
generally speaking,
the route to optimal,
the route to to quality of life and
productivity has been laid out by other
people.
We we kind of know what the parameters
are.
You need to do something that other
people find is useful and and,
and you have to regard it as useful as
well,
or at least you have to be entertaining.
There has to be something about you have
value to other people that you have to
pursue with a fair bit of diligence,
so you have to play a productive social
role.
Probably need friends,
probably need an intimate relationship
and if it could be medium to long term
infant intimate relationship,
perhaps all the better.
That's what most societies hold up as
ideal could assume.
Well,
there's probably a reason for that.
I think one of the reasons is is that
your life gets fragmented otherwise
badly fragmented because every time you
have a longterm relationship and and it
fragments,
it's like your identity is blown into
pieces.
You get fragmented across time.
It's,
it's not.
It's not good.
It breaks you into pieces and you don't
necessarily recovered that well.
It makes everything much more
impermanent and unreliable.
All of those things,
so it.
It introduces a tremendous amount of
uncertainty into your life and it also
means that you don't have anyone around
that you can really trust and that's bad
because if you have someone around you
can really trust,
then you have two brains instead of one
and like you probably need two brains to
to manage your way through life.
It's pretty complicated,
so you orient yourself towards some
good,
highest good that you can conceptualize,
and it has to be through a consultation
with your ancestors because you need to
do the things that people have always
done it and you need to do them properly
and you need to assume that that's the
way that you should live unless you have
a very good reason to change it
dramatically and maybe you do,
but you got to start with some axiomatic
set of presuppositions because otherwise
you have to invent everything on your
own and you don't have enough time to do
that.
So you have to use normative guidelines
and if you don't,
then people won't know what to do with
you.
That's another big problem is if you
live completely outside the norm.
I mean,
you know,
remarkable artists manage that to some
degree,
but of course they pay for the privilege
by being remarkable artists.
So if there's something truly remarkable
about you,
perhaps you could justify deviating from
the normative path.
But if there isn't,
first of all,
there's nothing remarkable enough about
you to justify deviating in every way
from the normative path,
no matter how remarkable or so,
so that's part of the rescuing of the
father from the,
from the depths is to to reunite
yourself with the traditional structures
of your community.
You can do that in a way that you feel
suits your needs best,
but I don't think you can not do it
because it makes you weak and then
you'll drown.
All right,
so let's say you have oriented yourself
but not perfectly because you're full
of mistakes and errors.
So then what do you do?
Because you have to fix those errors,
but you still have to be oriented.
This is why I started getting interested
to get interested in the phenomenon of
meaning as a,
as a phenomenological experience to
experience something as meaningful.
It's not exactly obvious what that means
to experience something as meaningful.
I think that you can.
You can approach it obliquely,
you know,
like if I said watch yourself for two
weeks and notice when you're doing
something that you regard as meaningful,
I could say,
well here,
here's some,
here's some markers.
You lose a sense of time.
You lose a sense of vulnerability,
you're deeply engaged in it.
It seems,
it seems worth the effort,
right?
You forget yourself while you're doing
it.
Maybe you forget your existential
concerns while you're doing it.
You're not ruminating or obsessing about
the meaning of your life.
Right?
So,
so there's markers for,
it's like the flow states that chicks at
my highly described,
um,
and then you can experience it.
You experienced it under a certain sort
of ritualistic conditions.
You might experience it when you go see
a great movie,
you might experience it when you listen
to music.
I think music is a very,
very standard pathway for people to have
that kind of experience because
virtually everyone gets intimations of
mute of meaning from music.
And I think music music is
hierarchically structured patterns that
are representative of being laying
itself out properly.
It's something like that.
So it's an abstract representation of
proper being and so we can,
we can grapple with the phenomena of
music and we can we can bark or
phenomena of meaning.
We can box it in a little bit and start
to conceptualize it.
W
we can start to conceptualize it perhaps
as the manifestation of a deep instinct
and so I would say well meaning is what
manifests itself when you are,
when you've oriented yourself properly
and when you've optimized the flow of
information between you and you,
between you and chaos.
That might be the right way to thinking
about it because you think about a piece
of music because you want it to be
predictable,
but you don't want it to be perfectly
predictable.
You want it to be predictable with some
interesting variations and predictable
with some variations that make sense.
And maybe you can conceptualize that as
something like this.
It's like it's predictable that this
order of of stability,
but it's.
It's varying down here from time to time
and so you've got stable stability
there,
but variability there and you can handle
that.
So you want
an overarching structure,
stability with some internal
variability,
and maybe that's the way that you update
yourself without falling apart.
And then I would say you can find the
pathway to the optimal rate of update by
relying on your sense of meaning.
That's what it's for.
What it tells you is that you're.
You're wandering your way through the
world between the catastrophes of chaos
in the catastrophes of order and now and
then you swing into the proper locale.
You're where you should be.
And what happens is you get engaged by
that.
You get meaningfully engaged by that and
it's fragile.
It'll move on you,
right?
Because it's very difficult to exist at
that point constantly.
Your bad habits,
all sorts of things.
Your situation,
there's all sorts of things that are
going to interfere with that,
but that doesn't mean that that isn't
where you should be.
And so then you might say,
well,
that's where you should strive to be all
the time.
And then the question might be,
well,
what would it be like if you were there
all the time?
And I think that's where intimations of
paradise come from,
being when words think of it was
wordsworth talked about intimations of
immortality and childhood people tend to
romanticize their childhood because of
the sense of intense engagement that
goes along with being a child.
And it's one of the wonderful things
about being around children.
Actually.
It's,
it's,
it's why they pay you for their care.
And the way that children pay you for
their care is that they turn normal
things into magic again when you're
around them because you've seen it 100
times before.
And so when you see it,
you don't see it,
you see what you already know.
But when a child sees it,
they don't because they don't know,
they see it.
And then when you watch them see it,
you see it too.
And so it's just,
it's tremendous fun leading a small
child around to do things that you've
done before because they're so,
you know,
they're like this,
they're like all the time and you know,
maybe that's too much and they cry and
they get upset and all of that.
But a good part of the time,
it's just wild eyed wonder and then you
can see the world through their eyes and
it's payment and so that's that sense of
being engaged like that is something
that people love about children and and
rightly so,
but it's also a marker to the proper way
of being.
You know,
there there's a dictum in the.
This is a union idea that there's no
difference between the archetype of the
wise old man in the archetype of the
child.
They're the same thing because the wise
old man is the person who found what he
had in childhood but lost,
right?
It's a very powerful moment.
Teeth is that the purpose of maturation
is to return to the state of childhood
as a mature b.
not to stay in the state of childhood,
that's Peter Pan,
but to make the sacrifices necessary for
maturation and then return so well.
How do you do that?
Well,
you do that in part by noting what it is
that's meaningful for you to engage in.
I would say it's your nervous system
reporting to you,
right hemisphere and left hemisphere
balanced.
The balance between chaos and order
produces an output that says you are in
the right place.
It's a perception.
The meaning is a perception of being in
the right place.
It's the genuine thing.
However,
because it can be pathologized.
That's the thing and that's why I think
there is a call to virtue in most great
religious traditions.
If you're going to rely on your sense of
meaning to Orient you,
you have to play a straight game because
otherwise you warp and twist the inputs
and then the mechanism won't function
properly.
You know?
It's like if you.
If you were only.
If you're.
If you blinded yourself to half the
world,
you can't use your perception story at
yourself properly because the half of
the world that you ignoring is gonna pop
up at you unexpectedly and take you
down,
and so if your relationship with the
world isn't pristine,
honest,
primarily,
then you can't rely on your own internal
orienting mechanisms and then you either
fall into chaos which is an absolute
catastrophe or you have to rely on some
kind of external authority and that
makes you prone to possession by
tyrannical etiologies.
For example,
which give you that sense of meaning
that you showed in fact have as a
consequence of your own action.
Sorry,
that's the question as best as I can,
but okay.
So if,
if all relationships are,
are sort of predicated on this balance
between no conflict and conflict that
destructs um,
then if we were,
if we were to look at this at a more
macro level,
we see this sort of manifest in,
in history in our world,
like with conflict in between countries
in between systems,
ideology,
etc.
But what if this sort of navigation
between the exact line of no conflict
versus conflict,
how does that not imply that some people
are inherently doomed to chaos?
It might imply that,
you know,
one of the things,
so look,
so sometimes,
right?
Sometimes you don't have an answer that
works.
You've announced that produces the
highest proBability of success.
And like I could view the archetype of
world from a religious perspective and
say that there's such a thing as
ultimate and final redemption.
That's a metaphysical claim.
I don't,
I don't want to do that.
I think it's independent of what I'm
talking about.
What I'm saying is that there's an
archetypal path that's laid out in,
in the mythology of the hero and it's
your best bet.
That's all.
It's your best bet.
It doesn't mean that if you apply it
that everything is going to turn out the
way you might want it to turn out,
but.
But I would say this,
there is a way of of.
There's an interesting twist on that to
mrs.
One of the things that I came to
understand about trying to speak the
truth is that you can make an
assumption.
You can make a fundamental assumption
based on your ignorance.
Let's say I'm the ineradicable quality
of your ignorance,
that you can't compute the best possible
outcome.
What you can do instead is make a
decision and one decision is,
well,
I'm going to say what I think and see
what happens,
and then you can define that as the best
possible outcome.
Now you might say,
well now and then that's going to lead
you into chaos.
It's like,
yeah,
it is.
It is.
It's a strange.
It's a strange inversion,
but regardless of all that,
I would still say human beings are
finite and limited in mortal,
you know,
and and death is final,
let's say.
I'm not saying that,
but we could easily say that doesn't
matter.
This is still the best pathway forward.
It isn't certainty.
There's no certainty
and it's very frequently in life.
You have poison oak or poison be like
you get to pick your poison.
You don't get to pick the elixir of
life.
But I would,
but I wouldn't say.
I would also say I don't think there's
any reason to be particularly
pessimistic because we don't know what
would happen if people really tried hard
to get their acts together.
Like if they understood the necessity of
that and really put it forward.
I mean,
I've,
I've had lots of experience with my
clinical clients now.
I've seen dozens and dozens of people
and we have tried jointly to get their
lives straight her and it works almost
inevitably.
Now.
That doesn't mean I've had clients who
died,
you know,
we were three quarters through a
wonderful process of psychological
renovation and they got cancer and died
so,
so there's,
there's no certainty associated with
this,
but it's the best solution available.
And,
and it's also possible that it's a good
enough solution.
No,
I was talking to my class yesterday
about this,
you know,
so you,
if you pursue the things in your life
that are meaningful once you've oriented
yourself and that means accepting the
challenges that come along with that
because one of the things that you'll
find,
you even find this in music,
if you know a piece of music completely,
then you tend not to want to listen to
it anymore.
There's still has to be some challenge
in it.
You still have to track it and sometimes
music is so complex,
you just can't.
It just sounds like noise.
Modern music is often like that because
it's so.
Well,
it tends towards the chaotic and so
it's,
I find it difficult to listen to because
I can't get a handle on it.
But then you know,
so it's too challenging.
And then there's other music.
Pop music is often like this,
it's catchy.
The first two times you hear it and then
you never want to hear it again.
It's too much.
There's too much predictability and not
enough chaos.
And hopefully you find a piece of music
that somewhere in the middle you can
listen to it 50 or 100 times and each
time you listen to it,
there's still some new nuance in it that
you didn't,
that you didn't expect before.
And so why don't you kind of want to set
up your life like that.
So that.
And I think you see that the phenomena
of meaning manifest itself at the area,
at the locale of optimal challenge.
So if the thing.
So one of the things,
for example,
I might say,
well let's say you want to set some
goals for yourself.
We say,
well they're remarkable goals,
but they're all there too unattainable.
You're just gonna find it frustrating to
pursue them.
It's going to be too punishing.
And then we might say,
well,
here's a goal and you think,
I could do that.
You know,
standing on my head,
there's nothing,
no challenge in it.
Well,
both of those two extremes are gonna
leave you in a state that isn't
characterized by the optimization of
engagement and meaning.
One is too difficult to punishing.
It's the judge and nothing else,
and the other is the ultimate unmerciful
mothers.
It's like you win no matter how you
play.
So then you calibrate it.
Say,
well,
you know,
I need,
I'm,
I'm up for a challenge at this level.
I wouldn't recommend that because that's
just a bit like people do that you might
want to investigate your character in
detail and decide you know what's going
on at this level of analysis.
That's pretty harsh,
but you can certainly continually retool
yourself at more micro levels and that,
and I think what you do is you pick the
level of retooling that optimizes your
willing to be engaged in it.
And then what's so interesting about
that is that I think is that you get the
benefits of perfection,
so to speak,
while still being imperfect.
The imperfect,
your actual imperfection has nothing to
do with it.
What's relevant is the journey is the
journey that you're undertaking to
rectify the imperfection.
So instead of aiming to be that entity
without flaws,
you're aiming to be the entity that
continues to realize its flaws and
overcome them.
Well,
that's a game you can play forever.
And that's maybe the ultimate in being
an unflawed entity.
It's something like that.
So.
So I want to show you some pictures that
are,
think are associated with that.
So this one to begin with,
this is an absolutely amazing picture,
I think.
So this is bert hold firt mayan tree of
life flanked by yves and mary ecclesia,
and this in some sense this,
this picture summarizes the biblical
stories in one picture,
which is,
that's pretty amazing that,
that a picture can do that.
And so I'll,
let me explain the picture a little bit.
So the first thing you see here is that
this is the tree.
This is the tree of life.
And so it echoes the tree of the
knowledge of good and evil,
but this is post fall.
So we interpreted that story of adam and
eve already.
He said,
human beings became self conscious,
they discovered death,
they discovered morality.
It was all a consequence of interacting
with the fruit and the snake,
something like that,
and you can read that as an as an
evolutionary tail.
You can at least read it as a
representation of the emergence of self
consciousness and human beings,
and so what does that mean?
Well,
It means that the apple in some sense
was equivalent to death and that's what
you see here.
You see this picking fruit from the tree
here,
but the fruit is.
It's on the skull side of the tree and
so eve,
it's the vulnerability of eve.
She's naked there and displayed to the
world.
It's the vulnerability of eve.
That's one way of thinking about it was
the vulnerability of eve.
That was the catalyst to the development
of human self consciousness and I think
that that's true.
It seems to be to be a reasonable
proposition,
and so eve eve's relationship with the
fruit and the snake doomed human beings
to the realization of mortality.
that's what this side of the picture
represents,
and so it's a catastrophe and it's
associated with here with the snake and
the fruit.
It's human beings attempts to understand
how it is that they emerged into a self
conscious world.
Okay,
so fine.
So that's on.
This is on the fall end of the story and
this is on the solution end of the
story.
Now what you see here,
there's a skull there and there's a
crucifix here and you see there's all
these little fruits on this tree,
so it's the apple of death that eve is
handing out on this side and it's the
host that that plays a role in the
cannibalistic,
right?
That's at the center of christian ritual
that mary,
as the church is handing out as a
medication for this.
So she's handing out the antidote.
Well,
what's the antidote?
it's a strange thing.
It's associated with this crucifix and
that's translated into this wheat and
host,
so you're supposed to eat that and that.
That is the incorporation of whatever
this represents.
Well,
the question then is what does that
represent?
It's assist.
It's a symbol of suffering.
Obviously it's a symbol of the ultimate
end suffering.
It's the weirdest thing because the
picture proposes that to ingest,
the ultimate in suffering is to
simultaneously ingest the antidote to
the catastrophe of the knowledge of
death.
It's very strange paradox,
but but it's the.
It's the proper paradox that's at the
center of this,
of the great drama that's represented by
this picture.
A little knowledge of death destroys
you.
Full voluntary acceptance of it is the
cure.
That's the idea.
Well,
that's a.
That's a hell of an idea.
It's not only to and to accept it is
simultaneously in some sense to take
responsibility for it
because you don't take responsibility
for things that you don't accept.
You only take responsibility for things
that you do accept,
say,
well,
the world is fundamentally flawed
because its fundamental nature is
vulnerability,
intolerable vulnerability.
I'm not going to take any responsibility
for that.
That that's really caden's attitude in
the story of,
of cain and abel.
He externalizes responsibility for the
catastrophe of his life and therefore he
doesn't make the right sacrifices.
And so the paradoxical injunction here
is except responsibility for the
catastrophe of your life and that way
you transcended simultaneously and
there's a,
there's an unbelievably hopeful message
in there.
And the message is you're actually
strong enough to do that.
You just don't know it and you won't
find out till you do it.
You can't find out till you do it.
But if you did it,
you'd find out that it was true.
It's a massive risk.
It's the ultimate in risks,
right?
You have to be willing to loSe your life
in order to find it.
It's like.
Exactly right.
So that picture,
when I started to understand that
picture,
well,
every time I look at it just blows me
away.
I can't say it's unbelievably,
it's an unbelievably sophisticated set
of ideas,
but I don't think it's much different
really than this idea.
I mean,
buddha finds his enlightenment under a
tree.
It's not fluke that that's the case.
That's his natural environment.
and he's sitting in the lotus.
The lotus opens up his thing that
springs up from the depths and he sits
there illuminated the same way.
He's got a halo that's the sun that
stands for higher consciousness and
he's.
He's transcended by accepting the fact
that life is suffering.
He's transcended the limitations that
are part of mortality.
You see that symbol there,
that swastika.
You see it there.
It's reversed.
The nazis reversed it.
Well,
think about that mean they weren't
stupid symbolism there.
SYmbols had meaning is what the swastika
were represented was what this
represents.
Reversed.
Well,
that's a very bad idea.
This is the thing that this,
this idea is what enables people to
transcend their suffering.
And buddha said,
well,
don't,
don't be too attached to things,
and what does that mean?
It doesn't mean deny the world.
It might mean deny the world if you're
too in love with the material,
like with material wellbeing,
let's say.
Then your pathway to transcendence and
meaning might be to abandon that because
it's constraining you.
It's making you less than you could be,
but the fundamental lesson,
the more fundamental lesson that's
underneath that is don't let what you
are stop you from being what you could
be.
Right?
And so then the question is,
well,
what do you identify with?
Do you identify with what you are?
Then you're a tyrant,
do you identify with,
with chaos,
because that's the opposite of order.
Say then you're nihilistic ball.
You don't identify with either of those,
you know,
that they're both necessary,
you know that you have to live with both
of them,
but you would,
you identify with the capacity to
continually transcend what you are and
then you seek out error.
That's what humility is.
It's like I'm error ridden
psych,
so I want to see,
I want to put myself in a situation
where I can discover one of my areas,
hopefully not in a way that's going to
knock me completely out of the game,
right?
I want to,
I want to seek out a challenge.
I want to find out where my limits are.
I want to find out where there's not
enough of me yet and I want to do it
that in a way that's engaging because
you know,
you can wear yourself out fighting
dragons.
So obviously you can exhaust yourself
completely.
And that's not helpful.
You know,
one of the things I learned,
for example,
when I was coaching,
when I was coaching lawyers who these
were people who had very high end
careers and so they had an infinite
workload.
No matter how much they worked,
flat out there was always way more work
that they should do.
It's very difficult thing to learn to
manage and so they were exhausting
themselves and I said,
well,
you know,
you have to work less per day.
It's like,
well,
no,
that's not happening.
I can't do that.
And so what I learned over time was,
okay,
so this is what you have to do every
three months.
You have to block off four days and go
have a vacation and you have to plan
that in advance so it's in your calendar
so that your secretary doesn't book your
time and then you need that because you
have to recuperate enough so that you
can work as hard as you're going to
work.
And of course they were nervous about
that and I said,
well look,
we can.
We can calibrate this.
Let's keep track of your billable hours
over the next year and see if they
increase or decrease because I bet you
if you take more time off,
you'll actually have more billable
hours.
You'll actually have your cake and eat
it too.
You'll get to have a vacation and you'll
be more productive and that inevitably
that was what happened and so that's a
matter of calibrating the game properly,
right?
You want to play a game that you can
play today,
but also one that you can play next week
and next month.
We're not tAlking about you know,
your,
your career this week.
We're talking about you having a career
that lasts 30 years that doesn't kill
you,
that doesn't make you hate yourself or
the job that doesn't make you better.
That doesn't where you to a frazzle,
so it has to be optimized and so I think
that you can in fact decIde to take on
the load that's optimally meaningful if
you want,
and then you get to have your cake and
eat it too.
You're on the pathway to continual
incremental improvement.
You only have to burn off a feather at a
time instead of having the whole bloody
thing burst into flames,
but it's a constant.
It's a constant source of renewal and
there's an idea that to be renewed,
you have to drink the water of life,
right?
That that's an old mythological idea and
what's the water?
The water of life.
Chaos is water.
Water,
water is chaos.
Water is what washes away.
Too much order and to stay continually,
let's say a refreshed by the water of
life is to take on exactly the right
amount of chaos to make sure that your
garden is properly nourished and I think
meaning is actually the marker of that
and as I said,
you know that I'm not.
I wouldn't consider myself either naive
or particularly optimistic person.
I don't think I'm either of those,
but this is an actually an idea.
This is one of the only ideas that I've
ever found that I really believe to be
rock solid.
I actually think that it's true and it's
very optimistic because it says you can
use your sense of meaning to calibrate
your progress through life,
but there's rules.
You have to aim at the highest possible
good that you can conceive now and
that's subject update because what the
hell you know,
but you,
they start by aiming at the star you can
see rather than the dimmer one that you
can't yet perceive,
and then you decide that you're going to
do that honestly.
Right?
There's that.
That's a big decision.
So the first decision I think in some
sense is a decision of love.
You're going to decide that being is
worthwhile and that you're going to work
for its betterment and that's a decision
that's based on law,
but in the second decision is based on
truth.
Having made that decision,
you're going to play a straight game.
Having made those two decisions,
I think that you can allow your sense of
meaning to calibrate your pathway.
And then what's so interesting is that
you hit a state that's as close to
paradise as you're going to hit right
away because being engaged like that,
it's better to be engaged in the
solution of a complex problem that not
to have a problem at all.
And that's,
that's no different than saying it's
better for there to be being the non
being because being is a problem.
and so if you want to have no problems,
then you have no being.
And,
and you could say,
well,
being so miserable that maybe that's the
route we should take and fair enough,
but maybe you can have your cake and eat
it too.
You can have the damn problem,
it can be a problem we're solving.
And you can be so engaged in solving the
problem that it justifies the fact that
the problem exists.
And then you get,
then you get to have,
you get to have the problem and the
solution at the same time.
And maybe That's better than not having
the problem at all.
And I believe that because one of the
things I have seen,
and I've seen this so interesting,
so interesting when I've been lecturing
to people especially more recently,
and this is also manifested itself on
cell phone,
youtube,
I'm talking to people a lot about
responsibility and it's young men in
particular that seemed to be responding
to that and I think that's partly
because I think that young women in some
sense have their responsibility map
already laid out for them.
It's also less voluntary in some sense
for women because they have more
complicated problems to solve in the
first part of their life,
right?
Take because they have to get the family
problem solved.
But whatever.
I've been talking very in a very
delineated matter about responsibility,
whIch is a strange thing to sell to
people,
but responsibility is what gives your
life meaning.
And so then you might say,
well then take on ultimate
responsibility and what happens?
You have an ultimately meaningful life
and then you might say,
well,
if your life is ultimately meaningful,
it doesn't matter if it's
punctuated by tragedy or even predicated
on tragedy.
It's worth it.
and I think that's true,
and everything I've seen indicates to me
that's true.
Every time I get my clients to take on
more responsibility.
You know what?
And it isn't an injunction.
You're a bad person.
You should take on responsibility.
It has nothing to do with that.
You can defIne the damn responsibility.
It isn't something that someone else
should impose on you.
It's not a matter of doing
what you should do in some abstract
manner.
It's not that it's the choice of what
game you're going to play and you know
you can play the game of the seeker,
I would say.
And if you play that game,
then everyone wins and it's the best
game you can play.
And so the,
the,
the answer in some sense to the tragedy
of life,
to the catastrophe of life to the fall
is to adopt the responsibility of
mortality that goes along with that and
to play that game maximally.
And paradoxically,
it's in willingness to do that,
that the solution emerges.
And I don't know.
I have done my best with every single
thing I've talked to you guys about.
I have done my best to do what
dostoyevsky he does in his novels,
which is I make a proposition and then I
spend months or years trying to figure
out if I can take the bloody thing
apart,
if there's something wrong with it
because I want to fInd out,
I want to hit it with a hammer and
seeing if it breaks.
And what I've been trying to do is to
tell you all the things that I've
gathered,
let's say,
or,
or laid out or articulated or discovered
over the last 30 years that I have not
been able to break with the biggest
hammer that I could take to them.
And I guess that's the fundamental one,
is that I believe that the,
the,
um,
the idea that lurks in these images
derived from very different cultures.
It's the same idea.
Life is suffering,
right?
Indisputable.
What do you do about that?
You voluntarily accepted and then strive
to overcome the suffering.
That's a consequence of that.
And you do that for you and you do that
in a Way that makes It better for other
people.
And then that works.
And one question might be,
well,
how well does it work?
And the answer is have.
The only way that you can find out is by
trying it.
That's it.
That's the existential element of it.
The proof is to be derived by the
incarnation of the attitude in your own
life.
no one can tell you how it will work for
you.
It's the thing that your destiny is to
discover that and you have to make.
You have to make the decisions to begin
with.
It's like because you can't do this
without commitment,
you have to commit to it first.
That's the act of faith that that
character guard was so insistent upon.
You have to say,
I'm going to act as if being as good,
I'm going to act as if truth is the
pathway to enlightenment.
I'm going to act as if I should pursue
the deepest meaning possible in my life.
And there's there's reasons to do none
of those.
There are real reasons,
so it's really a decision,
but you cannot find out what the
consequences of the decision is unless
you make the decision.
I think the same thing happens when you
get married by the way,
so if you think you might leave,
you're not married and then you think,
well,
the marriage didn't succeed.
It's like,
well,
maybe you were never married because the
rule is you don't get to leave and
there's a reason for that rule.
Now I'm not saying that there aren't
situations where there should be
exceptions made for that.
That's not the point.
The point is that there's some games you
don't get to play unless you're all in,
and the other thing that's so
interesting about being alive is that
you're all in.
No matter what you do,
this is going to kill you,
so I think you might as well play the
most magnificent game you can while
you're waiting because do you have
anything better to do?
Really,
why not pick the best thing possible
that you could do?
Why not do that?
Maybe you could justify you're wretched
existence to yourself that way I think
you could.
That's what it looks like.
You know,
people find such meaning in the
responsibilities they adopt.
It stops making them ask questions about
what life is for.
If you have a newborn child,
for example,
like unless you're really in a bad way,
psychotically depressed or or maybe your
personality really needs some retooling,
you stop thinking about
anything but ensuring that that baby is
doing well and if someone comes along
and asks you an existential question
about your commitment to that,
the right response is why are you asking
me such stupid questions when,
when the,
when this,
this is manifesting itself right in
front of your eyes,
like how blind can you be?
That isn't a time for,
for questions about the meaning of life.
The answer is right in front of you and
if you can't see it,
it's not because life has no meaning.
It's because you're blind.
I mean that's what they image of,
of,
of the virgin mother and the child is
all about.
It's like,
what's the answer to the meaning of
life?
Here's an answer.
IT's like,
well,
I'm going to criticize that.
Well,
go right ahead.
You know,
it's like,
it's like what?
What?
You're.
You're like a.
You're like a,
what do you call that?
A termite.
KnowIng on a temple,
there's no,
there's no utility and that sort of
criticism.
You're,
it's blindness and it's the same thing
with regards to the path of the hero.
It's like it glistens in front of you
and you can criticize it.
It's like
fine.
Put the cart before the horse and see
how far you get.
So I thought to bring full closure to
the class,
I was trying to solve this terrible
puzzle that confronted me for and many
other people about how it was that human
beings got themselves in such a tangle
about what they believed,
such a tangle that we were pointing the
ultimate weapons of destruction at one
another,
which by the way,
we are still doing.
I thought,
okay,
well I understand that we need to are
belief systems.
They orient us and that means there will
be conflict between belief systems and
that can be a catastrophe and that's
being played out everywhere.
Again,
in very many ways.
What's the solution to that?
Well,
one possibility is there's no solution.
It's just mayhem all the way around.
Could be the case,
but it seemed to me as I delved into it
that the proper solution to that was to
live properly as an individual because
you're more powerful than you think way
more powerful than you think.
I mean god only knows what you are in
the final analysis.
You're blind to your own weaknesses,
but you're also blind to your own
strengths and so then I think,
well,
if you've got your act together and be
better for you and instantly it would be
better for your family.
Assuming they wanted you to get your act
together and not everyone does,
but.
And then it would be better for the
community.
It's like how far could you take that if
you stopped wasting time and if you
start lying and if you oriented yourself
to the highest possible good that you
could conceive of it and you committed
to that,
how much good could you do?
Well,
I would say,
why don't you find out?
So that's what I think you should do.
You should find out you don't have
anything better to do and there's
nothing in it.
As far as I've been able to tell,
there's nothing in it but good,
so
maybe you could sort yourself out so
that you wanted nothing but the good and
and then maybe you could help make that
manifest in the world and maybe we
wouldn't have all these terrible
problems.
Then at least we'd have fewer of them
and that would be a start.
So it's the.
It's the answer to the problem of
humanity is the is the is the integrity
of the individual.
That's the answer.
So and states that are predicated on
that realization are healthy,
so in states that aren't,
are doomed to stagnation and
catastrophic collapse and personalities
that are predicated on self tyranny and
the tyranny of others are doomed and
them to collapse.
So and then you think,
well,
what's the barrier?
The barriers are you willing to accept
the responsibility and part of the
answer to that is reduced the damn
responsibility until it's tolerable.
You don't have to have to fix everything
at once.
You could just start by fixing the
things that you could fix or you could
even do it more.
You can do it with even less self
sacrifice.
you could start by fixing only the
things that you want to fix.
God,
you can get a massive way that way,
so do it.
See what happens.
That's what you should have been taught
in university right from the beginning.
It's like aim at the highest good tool
yourself into something that can attain
it and go out and manifested in the
world and everything.
that everything that comes your way will
be
everything that comes your way will be a
blessing and so,
oh,
you have to do is give up your
resentment and your hatred.
I know that's a hard thing to give up
because he had plenty of reason for it.
That's probably a good place to stop,
so it's a pleasure.
Thank you.