Okay,
so one of the propositions that I set
forth for you last week was that the
most real things are the things that are
most permanent across time and that
manifest themselves in the largest
number of situations and those are the
things that you have to map successfully
in order to survive,
survive as individuals but survive as a
species over a very long period of time.
And so the question is,
one question is what are the constants
of experience if you are a follower of
the evolutionary psychologists and to
some degree the evolutionary biologist,
but I would say more the psychologists
like to be and caused me these.
They have a very afro centric view of
human evolution.
And the idea basically is that
after we diverged from the common
ancestor between chimpanzees,
Bonobos,
and human beings,
we spent a tremendous amount of time in
the African environment,
mostly on the velt.
Although we're not absolutely certain
about that.
We're also very good in water human
beings and we have some of the features
of aquatic mammals.
So,
um,
while hairlessness being one of them,
women have a subcutaneous layer of fat
or theater quite nicely adapted for
swimming.
And so buckminster fuller,
who I wouldn't call it mainstream
evolutionary psychologist,
hypothesized back in the seventies that
we spent some period of time in our
evolutionary history living on beaches
near the ocean.
And that idea really a echoes for me
because we like beaches a lot and it's a
great place if you want to get easy food
and we're pretty damn good at swimming
for,
for terrestrial mammals,
and we are hairless and we do cry salt
tears and there's a lot of evidence that
we end our feet.
If you think about our feet,
they're quite slipper.
Like I know we have stand up and all
that and walk.
So that's part of the adaptation,
but we're pretty good at swimming.
So anyways,
the classical evolutionary psychology
view is that we spent most of our time
on the African Veldt in the critical
period of our evolutionary development,
let's say,
after we diverged from this common
ancestor and that were adapted for that
environment.
And one of the consequences of that is
the idea that we're,
that things have changed so much around
us that we're really not adapted to the
environment that we're in anymore.
And I don't really believe that because
I think that the idea that the primary
forces that shaped our evolution shape
them during that period of time call it
us roughly a 7 million period,
year period of time,
something like that.
And that that was somehow a special time
for human evolution that's set our
nature.
I don't believe that,
um,
I mean it's true to some degree,
but it's more useful to view the
evolution of human cognitive processes
over the entire span of evolutionary
history and not necessarily give
preference to any particular epoch.
And I certainly believe that the idea
that we're no longer adapted to the
environment because of our rapid
technological transformations,
it's simply not true.
And the reason I think that it's not
true is because the fundamental
constants of the environment,
let's say,
or it's more of the fundamental
constitute constituent elements of
being.
I think that's the right way to think
about it.
They're the same.
They haven't changed a bit and there is
no way of changing them as far as I can
tell without us being radically and
incomprehensibly different than we are
and you know with with the rapid rise of
artificial intelligence and robotics and
all of that,
it's certainly possible that in 500
years will be completely will be so like
unlike the way we are now,
that we won't even be the same
creatures.
I don't think that's a particularly
great outcome,
but it's certainly possible.
So what are the fundamental constituent
elements?
While they're expressed in mythology,
but they're.
They're not merely symbolic.
I think it's the wrong way to think
about it.
There are symbolic,
but they reflect a very deep reality and
they actually reflect the reality that's
not easily apprehensible directly by the
census.
Now your senses are tuned for a
particular duration.
That's roughly,
excuse me,
that's roughly the duration that you
live,
let's say,
but more importantly,
it's the duration.
Whatever that duration is across which
meaningful actions take place and we
kind of have some idea of what that
duration is.
You know,
if you look at us,
a computer screen,
if it has a refresh rate of less than 60
hertz,
you can see it flickering,
but above 60 hertz you can't,
it's uniform.
And with movies,
um,
anywhere between 20 and 50 frames a
second,
is it enough to give you the illusion of
continual motion?
So,
you know,
we live in a universe that's above the
10th of a second domain or maybe the
hundredth of a second somewhere in there
anyways.
And I mean it's not like time isn't
almost infinitely sub dividable at
higher levels of resolution than that,
but we don't operate generally speaking
at higher temporal resolution than that.
And then,
you know,
we're,
we're our,
our,
our feeling of the,
of the felt moment seems to be,
I would say something approximating half
a second to a second,
you know,
I mean it's an estimate obviously,
but a second is a meaningful unit of
time for a person and 100th of a second
really isn't in certainly a billionth of
a second isn't then you know,
we can think across hours and days and
weeks and months,
but we really can't.
Once you start getting out into years,
it gets kind of sketchy and it's hard to
think more than five years down the
road.
And the reason for that is that the
particular is upon which you're basing
your predictions are likely to change
sufficiently over a five year period.
So that extending out your vision past
that just exposes you to accelerating
error.
Right?
And that of course that's the problem
with predicting the future period.
So we live in a time range that's about
say a 10th of a second,
two,
three,
three years,
something like that.
Now I know it can expand beyond that,
but that's,
that's kinda where we're set in.
Our senses seemed to be tuned to those
durations and,
and to be operative so that we make
proper decisions within those durations
and,
and also from,
from a particular spatial positioning
and so forth.
You know,
how your eyes see what's roughly,
maybe we could say a walkable distance
in front of you,
something like that.
So,
and you didn't detect things and in the
locale that enables you to immediately
interact with things,
but it isn't necessarily the case that
senses that are tuned to do that are
also tuned to inform you directly about
what the most permanent things about
being itself are.
I think that those things have to be in
third and there's some,
there's some supporting evidence for
that kind of thing from a,
from psycho linguistics.
Um,
there,
there is a level of,
of categorization that we seem to
manifest more or less automatically or
implicitly.
So for example,
when children perceive animals,
they,
they perceive at the level of cat or
dog.
They don't,
they don't perceive that the level of
subspecies like cat or,
or,
uh,
or uh,
let's say salmonoid,
you know,
there's,
there's this,
there's a natural,
I can't remember what they call that
base category,
something like that.
It's usually specified by very short
words that are easily learnable.
And so the linguistic system seems to
map right onto the,
to the object recognition
characteristics of the sensory systems
that are built right into it.
And,
and if they weren't built into it,
we couldn't communicate easily because
our natural categories,
I think that's it,
but it's probably wrong.
Our natural categories,
they have to be the same for everyone or
it would be very difficult for us to
communicate.
Okay.
So having said all that,
then the question is,
well,
what are the most,
what are the most real categories?
And I think there's,
there's a real division in ways to think
about this because there's a scientific
way of thinking about it.
And,
and in that case,
the most real categories are,
well mathematical equations certainly
seem to be in the top category there,
the equations that describe the physical
universe,
but then then the,
the hypothesis of the existence of such
things as protons and electrons and you
know,
the,
the material elements that make up
everything,
that's every element of being with the
possible exception of empty space,
um,
but in the,
in the mythological world to categories
I think are more derived from Darwinian
by the effect of Darwinian processes on
cognitive and perceptual function.
So which is to say that we have learned
to perceive and then to infer those
things that are most necessary for us in
order to continue our existence,
propagate live well.
All of those things.
And that would be true at the level of
individual survival.
And maybe it's also true at the level of
group survival.
Although you know the,
there's a tremendous debate among
evolutionary biologists about whether
not selection can take place at the
level of the group anyways.
There are these basic level categories
that manifest themselves to you.
And then there's categories of the
imagination that you have to infer up
from the sensory domain,
and we do that partly in science by
comparing our sensory representations
across people.
But we also do it by thinking
abstractly,
conceptualizing abstractly,
and no.
One of the things that's interesting
about abstractions,
it's not clear whether they're more or
less real than the things they're
obstructed from,
you know,
this is a perennial debate among,
let's call them ontologists,
who were interested in the fundamental,
fundamental nature of reality itself.
In some sense,
independent of conceptual structures.
Our numbers more or less real than the
things they represent.
It's a really hard question to answer
because knowing like using numbers as a
representational system gives you
unbelievable power.
And there are mathematicians that
believe that there isn't anything more
real than mathematical representations.
Now,
it depends to some degree of course on
how you classify reality.
That's the problem with a question like,
is a,
a equivalent to be.
The answer to that always is.
Well it depends on how you define a.
and it depends on how you define be.
So generally it's not a very useful
question,
but you can still get the point that
there's something very real about
abstractions,
incredibly real,
because otherwise why would you bother
with them?
They wouldn't give you any handle on the
world.
So what's the,
what's the most useful or what's the
most,
what's the broadest possible level of
abstraction and is there any use of any
utility in thinking in that manner.
And I tried to make the case last time
that that in the mythological world
there are three categories or four
depending on what you do with the
strange fourth category,
because the fourth category is sort of
the category of uncategorizable entities
and so it's sort of the category of
everything that not only do you not
know,
but you don't know,
you don't know it hits,
or you can think about it as the
category of potential.
I actually think that's the best way to
think about it is that it's the dragon
of chaos is the category of potential.
And I do believe that we're.
Our materialist view is essentially
wrong.
I think that the proper way of looking
at the at being is that being his
potential and from that potential,
whatever consciousness is,
extracts out the reality that we inhabit
anyways.
That's certainly the mythological
viewpoint and and but it's not just a
mythological viewpoint.
It's,
it's the,
it's a sequence of ideas,
for example,
that deeply underlies the thinking of
your own piaget and piaget by the way.
It was very interested in reconciling
the gap between religion and science.
That's really what he devoted his life
to doing and so,
and there are other streams of
philosophy and I would say heidegger
that phenomenologists are,
are thinking along lines that are
similar to this as well because
heidegger was concerned not with the
nature of material reality,
but with being as such and,
and,
and so you can extract out the viewpoint
that I just described from,
from mythology,
but it isn't the only source of such a,
what would you call it?
A high hypotheses is probably the right
idea.
So,
so the idea,
you can think about this as a
bootstrapping process in some senses.
In order for anything to get going,
it has to bootstrap itself up and become
more and more complex as it does that.
So it's,
it's like this is the answer to the
chicken and egg problem,
right?
Which was first the chicken or the egg.
Well,
neither something from which both the
chicken and egg were derived,
right?
Because the,
the ultimate,
the ultimate answer to that is the
answer to how there are things at all,
who knows,
but at some point there were neither
chickens nor eggs,
but there were the things that were the
precursors to those things.
And so they spiraled upwards in some
sense.
And those,
those,
uh,
initial,
prodo entities,
single celled animals for,
we need to go back farther than that.
But we could say,
well,
single cell animals differentiated over
time.
Right?
And there's this looping process that,
that differentiates out into both the
chicken and the egg.
So,
but what the question is,
what do you need in order for that
process to begin?
And that's really the question of what
the fundamental constituent elements of
reality are.
And the mythological hypothesis is that
there are three or four.
One is the fact that there has to be
something that,
that,
that that manifests itself as an
observer.
It's something like that.
Some kind of observer now where that
process of observation starts in the
phylogenetic chain is very,
very difficult to tell.
No,
we might say,
well,
there's certainly no possibility of a
conscious observer until there's a
differentiated nervous system.
But then prior to the emergence of
differentiated nervous systems,
there were animals that were complex
enough to react with the environment in
a manner that,
well,
single celled animals,
they're quite complex.
I mean,
some of them are unbelievably
complicated.
You know,
they can move themselves through space,
they can orient,
they can follow chemical trails.
They're not,
they're not stupid by any stretch of the
imagination.
Now,
to what degree they have being,
you know,
as something they could represent.
Well we don't have to speculate on that,
but the elements of conscious being are
there.
So you need,
you need a being.
You need that.
The structure of that being through
which the the entirety of being itself
is interpreted and you need the
surround.
It's something like that and so I
conceptualize that is something that
knows that's the knower,
what it knows,
that's the interpretive structure and
that which needs to be known or you
could come.
You could conceptualize that as the
individual in explored territory,
nested inside unexplored territory.
That's another way of thinking about it
or you can think about it as the
individual inside culture and the
individual culture has nested inside
nature.
That's another way of looking at it or
you can think of it as the knower and in
order surrounded by chaos.
That's another way of thinking about it,
but all these things,
you know,
they're all attempts to articulate the
same underlying structure.
You see that in narratives continually
and I think Pinocchio is a very good
example of that because in Pinocchio you
have the culture that's Japan and Japan
always obviously creative,
but also insufficient and dad,
which is why he ends up in the belly of
the whale.
You have the blue fairy who's whose
mother nature.
For all intents and purposes,
the negative feminine doesn't Manifest
Itself Much in a Pinocchio story except
implicitly in the form of the whale.
The thing at the bottom,
the which is more like the dragon of
chaos than something feminine that
swallows up the the swallows up culture,
but you have nature or culture,
Japan,
nature,
the blue fairy,
and then the puppet Pinocchio and you
know from a strictly scientific
perspective,
we think of human beings as nothing but
the children of nature and culture and
that pushes you towards a kind of
deterministic view.
What causes your behavior?
Well,
it's either nature or culture because
there isn't anything else,
but that isn't how the mythological
story lays itself out because it says
there is something else and that's
whatever your consciousness is and that
consciousness seems to be able to work
with nature and culture in a non
deterministic manner in order to bring
well in order for what?
In order to bring itself forward.
I mean,
and that's really what's interesting
about that I think is that it isn't
obviously just the plot of Pinocchio.
It's virtually the plot of any story is
the story of the development of the
individual.
Now the story is order chaos,
higher order,
roughly speaking,
so you can get variance of that.
You can get order,
collapses into disorder and nothing is
resolved.
That's a tragedy,
right,
and and you can get so,
so you don't have to have the entire
story represented in this story,
but you get fragments of it.
It's a classic you shaped story and what
it is is the story of the development of
the individual across time as a
consequence of his or her adventures in
time and space and every story is
exactly that and those are
representations of the manner in which
you come to be in the world for better
or for worse.
It's differentiated so the individual
has a negative and a pause.
Development and culture has a negative
and a positive element to nature does as
well and that makes the potential for
plots much broader.
But,
and I think it's also very useful to
know that entire story because I think
it's one of the things that protects you
against ideology.
It's like,
okay.
Whereas if someone tells you a political
story or a story of any sort,
you can always ask,
well,
where are the missing characters?
Human beings are terrible.
They've erected a culture that's
destroying the planet,
and nature has been,
if you know benevolent and and pristine,
it's like,
yeah,
fair enough.
Accurate,
but you're missing half the characters
because humans aren't,
aren't just terrible.
Rip Patients,
creatures and culture is not just a
destructive force.
And nature is by no means on our side.
So where's the missing characters?
You need all of the characters in the
representation to get it right.
And I really believe this to be true.
So for example,
if you want to protect yourself against
trauma,
as you move forward in life,
you have to be very aware of the three,
three negative characters.
You have to know that the human
individual has an adversarial element
that's malevolent right to the core.
And if you don't know that and you will
run across someone who's malevolent,
you will end up damaged.
So because first you won't build it,
defend yourself.
You'll just be like a ripe fruit tree
for the plucking.
And second,
the mere existence of someone like that
will pose such a threat to the way that
you've organized the world,
that it might collapse on you,
that happens to people all the time.
So it really matters whether you know
these categories and it matters that you
know,
that culture can become tyrannical.
It really,
but that it's also your father that's
given you everything and it matters that
you know,
everything good comes from nature and
that we need to live in harmony with
nature to some degree,
but that it's also held band on our
destruction every second.
And it's very paradoxical.
It's,
it's a hard thing to reconcile with,
with,
uh,
a thought structure like modern science
that's based on a strict logic that
always says something can't be itself
and its opposite at the same time.
But you know,
human beings can certainly be something
and it's opposite the at the same time.
And anything truly complex can have that
and does have that bench.
Or if someone offers you a new job,
you think,
well that's positive.
It's like,
no,
it's not.
It's positive and negative and complex.
It might be the solution to your
problem,
but at the same set time it's going to
generate a whole host of other problems.
So lots of times we're,
we're,
we're encountering entities in some
sense that have internally paradoxical
structure and we have to deal with that
entire set of paradoxes or,
or we don't survive.
It's really a matter of survival.
Okay,
so,
so I'm,
I'm,
and then you know,
there's this overarching symbol which is
the dragon of chaos,
which is potential itself and it's the
potential from which all of these
categories emerge.
And so the,
the,
the most abstract category of our
imagination is that which is beyond our
understanding the category of that which
is beyond our understanding.
And that seems to me to be represented
because we can only use the
representational structures that we
evolved,
is that it's represented in our
paradoxical representation of the
Predator and the treasure that lies
beyond the perimeter.
That perimeter perimeters of our safe
societies.
So what's out there beyond?
Well,
we don't know,
but we need to know because we need
always to deal with what we don't know.
So weirdly enough,
we have to come up with a category of
what we don't know in order to start
formalizing a theory about how we might
progress towards it and interact with
it.
It's very paradoxical idea and there's a
paradoxical answer,
right?
It's,
it's the terrible Predator that lurks in
the unknown that also harbor is
something of great value.
Perfect.
That's exactly right.
And,
and I think that that is a reflection of
the fact that human beings are Predator
animals and prey animals at the same
time.
So what's out there in the,
in the terrible darkness,
something that can destroy you but also
something that you absolutely need.
So how do you,
how do you prepare yourself for that?
And that's the ultimate question of
life.
It's not how do you deal with death,
although death is a sub component of the
terrible unknown,
I would say it's how do you deal with
that which is beyond your understanding,
which is constantly manifesting itself
in the world and that,
and that manifests itself every time you
categorize something and the thing
escapes from the category.
And that happens most in interpersonal
relationships because people are so damn
complicated,
you get them figured out,
boxed in,
you even make a contract that neither
review,
we'll jump outside the box,
but you jump outside the box
continually.
And that's why a relationship requires
constant negotiation and
reconceptualization because you do not
exhaust the person with your perceptual
categories.
And of course you don't exhaust the
world with your perceptual categories
ever.
This is partly why the existentialists,
they have this concept called
alienation.
And the idea was that human beings
become alienated from their creative
products.
So,
and that is,
and here's why it happened.
So imagine a Henry Ford makes the
assembly line,
right?
So for it has no idea what's going to
happen when he makes the assembly line,
like because he's just trying to figure
out a fast way to make cars or he thinks
that what he's making his cars.
So he thinks he's making an assembly
line for cars and he thinks he's making
cars.
And you think,
well,
what's wrong with that?
Well,
first of all,
the assembly line absolutely transformed
the entire planet,
right?
Because it,
it brought in the era of mass cheap
manufacturing.
It's like it just,
it was way more than he thought it was.
And then did he make a car?
Well,
a car is something that hypothetically
takes you relatively effectively from
point a to b.
It was really a replacement for the
horse and buggy.
I mean,
they have the first cars looked like
that.
They were horseless carriages.
Well,
did he make a car?
God is God.
It's hard to tell what Henry Ford made.
He made a very effective way for
transforming the atmosphere.
Right.
And the fact that it also happened to
take you from point a to point b might
be completely irrelevant compared to the
fact that it was the internal combustion
engine and its rapid distribution
completely changed the constituent,
the,
you know,
the fundamental chemical structure of
the atmosphere itself.
It completely transformed cities.
It blew out the rural community.
Everyone moved to the cities,
right?
It made all the cities built around the
automobile.
But then it had this tremendous
political and economic significance too.
So I mean,
part of the reason that because you
think,
well is a car is a way to get from point
a to point b,
but no,
no,
it's not a machine.
It's also the embodiment of an idea and
it's a very strange idea.
A collectivist society would have never
invented the car because the car is
predicated on the idea that you could
own a conveyance that would get only you
and only you from somewhere to somewhere
else without ever asking anybody for any
permission.
And so the funny thing is is when you
build something like that,
those presuppositions are built into it
and then when you export that say to
Soviet Russia,
you don't get to.
They can't just take the car and leave
the political implications behind the
car.
The mere fact that you step into one and
drive it is an indication that you're
accepting the political ideological
presuppositions that are part of the
fact that that thing even exists and so
well that's alienation.
It's like even something you make,
you think what you have control over
what you make because you've made it.
You understand.
It's like,
no,
you don't.
You understand a tiny fraction of it.
You launch it out in the world man and
the snakes inside of it,
the Hydras and high inside of it
multiply their heads massively
constantly and you and you and you can't
really keep track of it,
and so,
so even even in your relationship with
created entities,
you still see the reemergence of this
underlying fundamental substructure,
right?
Even inside it's the,
it's the garden of Eden.
There's always a snake inside the thing
that's walled in always,
always,
always.
Even God himself could not get rid of
the snakes in the garden.
And partly what that means is that,
you know the garden is a conceptual
system.
It's the conceptual system within which
people exist.
That's Eden is a,
is a walled garden.
Paradise means walled garden and it's
walled because a walled garden is where
people live because the wall is culture
and the garden is nature natured.
We always lived in a structure that said
Amalgam of nature and culture,
so we set it up so it's paradisical as
long as we're unconscious,
but we can't manage it because there's
always something chaotic that's coming
in that we will interact with.
That's human beings.
You put a snake in the garden.
It's the first bloody thing we're going
to talk to,
and for better or worse,
it makes us conscious and awake.
It makes us aware of our mortality.
It does all sorts of terrible things to
us,
but it doesn't matter because that's,
that's the path that human beings have
what chosen,
because that's the implication in that
story and it's,
it's very difficult.
It's a very difficult thing to answer
because we certainly choose each other
for self awareness and consciousness and
intelligence.
And I don't know if you're,
if you're choosing a mate,
there's an arms race in human beings.
We're choosing intelligent mates.
Especially that's especially the case
for women in relationship to men.
So,
um,
so that,
the idea that that's a choice.
Well,
that's partly why it's eve that makes
out himself conscious in the garden of
Eden,
right?
She offers him the apple,
she's the one that makes him self
conscious and I think that's actually
accurate because the evidence from the
evolutionary biologist is that human
sexual female sexual selection was what
are the driving factors that
differentiate us from chimpanzees.
It's a major factor.
Chimpanzee females are not selective
maters.
They go into estrus,
they'll mate with anything.
What happens is the dominant males
chased the subordinate males away and so
they end up leaving more offspring,
but it's not a consequence of selection
on the part of the females in human
beings.
It's completely different.
Concealed ovulation and intense
selection pressure from women on men.
You have twice as many female ancestors
as you have male ancestors and people
could never have have a hard time
working that out arithmetically,
but it's not that problematic.
You just think on average,
every woman had one child,
half of men had none,
and the other half had to.
And that's approximately correct if you
average across the entire history of
human sexuality.
So human males in particular are subject
to a vicious selection,
pressure on the part of females,
and I also think that's partly why
nature is represented symbolically as
female among human beings,
because after all,
nature is what selects.
There's no better definition of nature
then that which selects so now.
So.
So here's,
here's why I want to talk to you about
the brain a little bit,
because if you make the radical case,
let's say that these are actually the
categories of reality and we're going to
say,
well,
reality is what?
Select for this,
for the sake of,
for this,
for the sake of argument,
then the than our,
our neurological structures and our
physical structure should be adapted to
that reality.
It's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a necessary conclusion from that.
So then the question is,
well,
are they,
and as far as I can tell,
the answer to that is yes.
And so we'll,
we'll go through the,
the neuropsychological evidence quite
rapidly.
The first bit of evidence is that you
have two hemispheres.
Why?
One deals with the unknown and the other
deals with the known that sale Conan
Goldberg.
That's,
that's hypothesized completely
independently of any of this underlying
mythological substructure,
which is really important thing to note
because if you're trying to determine
whether
or not something is true,
valid,
if the constructs upon which you base
your thinking are valid and true,
there's rules for doing that and one of
the rules is you have to be able to
detect the existence of the categories
using multiple methods of,
of,
uh,
of what using multiple methods.
It's the multi-method multitrack Matrix,
technically speaking,
it was established as a technique by two
psychologists named crone,
back C,
r o n b,
a,
c h and meal M,
e e h l Paul Meehl back in the 19
fifties when psychologists,
we're trying to figure out how do you
determine if something actually has an
existence like anger or anxiety as
something that you could study
scientifically.
And the answer is,
well,
you have to be able to measure it
multiple ways and all those measurements
have to read the same way.
And then the question is,
well,
what do you mean by multiple ways?
Because his sight and vision is sight
and hearing different.
While somewhat and somewhat the same,
but you know,
you do,
you make them as different as you can
manage,
let's say,
and our sensory systems are quite
different.
Smell,
molecular signature,
sound is auditory are you know,
auditory pressure,
you need a,
a gas around you or some liquid in order
for that to occur.
Site uses light,
you know,
we're,
we're using different inputs that
converge and allow us to say,
well,
if we get convergent information across
these multiple measurements,
then we'll assume that the thing we're
perceiving is real.
We even extend that in science because
we say if you take your multiple
measurement system and you take your
multiple,
multiple measurement system and then you
compare them will only allow what's
constant across both those comparisons
to be real.
And so that's the multi-method multi
trade matrix process essentially.
And my sense is that the.
So I think that the pattern that I'm
describing to you,
it's manifested itself evolutionarily.
It manifests itself at the mural in the
literal logical space and it manifests
itself in the conceptual space and the
probability of all three of those things
happening at the same time.
Without there being something valid,
there is lessons with each level of
interpretation you manage to stack on
top of one another.
So that's the,
that's the method.
Well,
so let's think about the brain a little
bit and I'll tell you a little bit about
how the brain works and uh,
and you know,
a lot of this stuff I'm telling you
right now is quite old.
Actually.
Most of it was,
worked out in the 19,
in the 19 eighties,
but it's been remarkably stable as far
as I can tell.
In some sense we're filling in the
details and not in every sense,
but in some sense we're filling in the
details.
Okay.
So you take,
this is from Alexander Luria,
who was the,
the greatest,
perhaps the greatest neuropsychologist
who ever lived.
He was a Russian,
a more work mostly after the second
world war,
mostly on people who had brain damage
and he was interested in trying to
outline the,
the,
the overarching picture of
brain function.
And so he did that partly by looking at
its function,
but also partly by looking at its
structure,
trying to get both of those things
working simultaneously.
And so we'll,
we'll go through a brief picture of how
the brain works.
And so one of the ways of so you can,
you can look at the brain from front to
back and you can divided roughly into
two sections and one section has to do
with sensory processing and that's
roughly the back half and one section
has to do with motor output.
Now those things aren't as clearly
differentiated as you might think
because you.
There's very little sensation without
motor output.
Maybe the,
the part that closest to an exception is
smell,
I would say.
But you at least have to breathe in,
you know,
and when an animal is actively searching
out a scent trail,
it's breathing in.
So it's,
it's using its motor output constantly
to modify the sensory stream.
It's really difficult to dissociate the
two.
And when you're looking at something you
know,
it kind of feels to you like you're a
passive recipient of sense data,
but you're no such thing.
Your eyes are moving back and forth in
multiple ways all the time,
including the ways that you can control
voluntarily.
So there's multiple involuntary systems
that are moving your eyes in multiple
ways.
And really what you're doing is feeling
the,
the array of,
of electromagnetic,
of the electromagnetic spectrum with
your eyes.
You're feeling it and you're actively
exploring.
If you're not a passive recipient at
all.
So even in sensation,
you can't purely pull sensation out for
motor processing and say I'm getting
untrammeled unbiased sense data because
you can't look at something without
focusing and you can't focus without
wanting to look at something.
You can't just lie there with you while
you could,
with your eyes have crossed.
But you know,
that's sort of like,
imagine you dropped a video recorder
from an airplane and it just spun around
in an unfocused manner.
Well that's the world sampled randomly.
You know,
why?
What are you gonna do with that?
Nothing.
And you know,
you're,
you're concentrating on the,
on the,
on the auditory stream constantly and
segregating out some things and
suppressing others.
Like if you listen in the classroom,
you can hear
probably four or five different types of
mechanical noise going on at the same
time.
Most of the time in the classroom that
silent,
you don't hear it like you don't hear
your fridge,
except when it turns on or off,
right?
Is Zero that out.
And so you're very selective in your
perception.
So you can't really technically separate
out motor output from sensory input.
And that's really useful to know because
it destroys the idea that you're just a
pat,
you know that there's a world of
sensation out there that's imprinting
itself on you and that's how you get
your information,
which is really the.
That's the fundamental presupposition of
the empiricists of the raw empiricists.
There's a world of sense data out there.
You sample it randomly and that's what
informs you.
It's like,
yes,
except that you're always an active
harvester of the information so you
can't get rid of the interpretive
structure a priority.
That was a manual count by the way,
who first established out in his
critique of pure reason.
You can't get away from the fact that
you're actively harvesting the data so
you can say,
well,
where does human structure come from?
The census data,
that sort of the blank slate idea.
It's like no wrong because a blank slate
cannot process information.
You're actively engaged right at the
beginning,
so that's another example of the knower
and the unknown,
you know,
working in a cyclical manner because you
interact with something you divided up
into you,
you and the world roughly speaking,
and I mean you really make it that way
because you build yourself out of the
information and then of course that
makes you a more differentiated
processor with a broader range of
skills.
Then you interact with the unknown.
Again,
you gather more information at
differentiates the world.
It makes you a more differentiated
harvester and then so it's just
continually cycling and that
consciousness,
the logos,
the knower is that thing that's doing
that harvesting and you can never say
it's not there.
Now what happens is that it's in it's
nascent form to begin with,
low resolution,
nascent for low resolution knower,
low resolution category system,
low resolution world,
but that's enough to kick it and to
start a differentiated and that happens
as you develop as an individual because
you start out as a single celled
organism for all intents and purposes,
a very low resolution thing in a very
low resolution world.
And that differentiates itself across
time.
But exactly the same thing happened over
evolutionary time.
So,
so there isn't a time when those three
elements aren't there.
For all intents and purposes,
they're always there.
They're permanent.
Okay?
So anyways,
back to the brain,
since century unit,
that's the,
uh,
the back half,
roughly speaking,
huge chunk of that is devoted to visual
processing in human beings,
right?
Most animals organized around smell,
not us,
somewhat stale because smell is a very
powerful evoker of memories and it has a
direct relationship with emotional
systems because you need to know if
something is edible or inevitable,
terrible or,
or good very,
very rapidly.
But human beings are organized around
vision.
So we have a massive,
massive amounts of our cortex devoted to
differentiated visual processing.
Now the motor unit,
so what you have is each of these little
zones here.
So for example,
look at the back here,
that's the primary visual area and the
secondary visual area.
And then this is the primary auditory
area in the middle of the brain here on
the outside and the secondary auditory
area.
And then the,
uh,
the,
the uh,
this is for body representation,
the primary area and the secondary area.
And you can think about those,
those areas of primary,
primary,
secondary,
and then tertiary
primary does the base level processing,
tertiary expands that up into more
abstract representate or secondary
expands that up into more abstract
representations and tertiary are the
areas where the sensors come together.
And that's really what you seem to be
most conscious of,
right action in the tertiary areas
because you don't really see the world
as a separate.
You can think about the auditory stream
separate from the visual stream and all
of that,
and you can think about touch
separately,
but you attended it consciously
experienced things as a unity,
as a comprehensive unity of all the
senses simultaneously,
so consciousness seems to occur only at
most of the time at the highest level of
integration and you would have
associated consciousness more with the
tertiary areas where the,
where the senses are talking to one
another.
Now it's more complicated than that
because there's obviously subcortical
structures all the way down to the spine
that are involved heavily in what
consciousness is.
It's not merely a consequence of
cortical activity,
you know,
we tend to think that because human
beings have massively expanded cortical
structures and we think of ourselves as
the most conscious creatures and that's
reasonable,
but you can take an awful lot of cortex
off someone and they're still conscious.
In fact,
you can leave them with almost no brain
at all and they're still conscious.
So we really have a rough time trying to
figure out what consciousness is and how
it's related to brain structure.
So anyways,
so that's the sensory and the motor
unit,
you have the,
the primary unit,
the secondary unit,
and the promoter or the prefrontal
Cortex,
and the prefrontal cortex is
particularly in a huge human beings.
So imagine that it's this primary and
secondary areas that allow you to,
to first of all to act voluntarily and
then two,
and then to play around in some sense
with your actions,
you know,
like imagine that,
imagine that you're a child building
with Legos and you can think with the
legos without,
without really having to think
abstractly,
right?
Because you can play around and build
different sorts of structures and so you
can think at the level,
at a level of motor output without
having to depend on abstraction.
But if you develop the prefrontal cortex
here,
which emerged out of the motor and
premotor areas over the course of
evolution.
So it's a differentiation of those
structures.
So this is dealing with the real world.
This is dealing mostly with the real
world,
but starting to abstract and,
and experiment a little bit.
And then this one,
this part deals with abstractions,
pure and simple.
So you know,
I can,
I can lift this and then I can play with
lifting it and then I can put it aside
and think about it abstractly.
I can think about all the different
things that I might do with it.
I say,
well,
I could throw it,
I can take it apart.
I could throw,
I could toss it near,
I could juggle it,
I could use it as a doorstop,
right?
I could kick it across the room.
And so basically what I'm doing there is
I'm using my prefrontal Cortex to
generate an abstract representation of
the world and then to plot out motor
strategies before implementing them.
And that's basically what abstract
thought is very,
very fundamentally.
It's,
it's,
it's the hypothesis of abstract action
and then the analysis of the outcome and
then the implementation into action.
And I think that there's something about
that that actually defines the
difference between intelligence and
conscientiousness because weirdly
enough,
you know,
the correlation between intelligence and
conscientiousness is zero.
No relationship whatsoever.
Which is quite strange because
conscientious people plan and so forth.
But I think what it is is that
intelligence is an indicator of the
effectiveness of abstraction and
conscientiousness is an indicator of the
probability of implementation and those
are very,
very different problems and you don't
just go from abstraction to
implementation because if you did,
you wouldn't be able to think,
right.
The thinking has to be torn away from
the implementation or what you're doing
isn't thinking it's just acting so and
so.
I think that accounts for the
psychometric independence of those two
phenomena.
It's annoying because you can think up
something that you should do and you
won't do it because there's no
deterministic causal pathway from the
conception to the action.
So that's kind of annoying.
It seems to take something like
willpower in order to transform the
abstraction into an implementation and
we don't understand that very well.
It's easy to understand the resistance
to doing it because Mo,
the default position of your body should
be something like,
no,
it never do anything except eat,
you know,
because doing something requires the
expenditure of energy and resources.
And so unless you have a really good
rationale for it,
you should probably not do it.
And so the body is sort of intransigent
by nature.
It's an oversimplification.
You have to come up with a good reason
to impella it into motion and you
should,
because you have to pay for action,
you have to pay for it with energy and
resources.
So there should be resistance against
it,
but it's still annoying.
So,
okay,
so that's one way of thinking about the
world,
the world,
something to sense and the world,
something to act upon.
And so the brain has fundamental
divisions of sensing and acting upon.
But there,
it's a constantly interacting loop.
You can't separate them really anymore
than we are separating them
conceptually.
Now on the motor strip
here,
the body is represented and this was
discovered at the Montreal neurological
institute,
um,
when,
when brain surgery was been doing,
was being done on,
on,
on people generally who had epilepsy or,
or some other terrible brain illness.
You have brain surgery when you're
awake,
which is a rather horrifying thing to
know about.
But the reason for that,
generally speaking is so that something
isn't taken out that you need.
Now,
one of the things that happened while
people were having brain surgery done,
and this would have been,
I believe,
I don't remember the exact time between
the thirties and the fifties,
I believe,
um,
and I think it was hab.
If I remember properly,
who was one of Canada's great
neuropsychologists,
do brain stimulation while people were
having brain surgery and they could map
out the way the body was represented on
the cortical surface.
And so you imagine there's two
representations.
There's,
there's a sensory representation of your
body on the cortical surface and there's
a motor representation of your body on
the cortical surface.
Those are both called.
The representations are called
[inaudible].
Monkey will either.
They're like the body has been laid out
on this strange strip or the strip of
tissue.
You can look up the whole monkey lie
online and see what they're like,
but I'll show you a.
they're sort of stretched out weirdly
long here.
That would be the motor one.
And then along here,
that would be the sensory one.
And you can Kinda,
you can kind of detect with your own
consciousness how your body is
represented in your brain.
So for example,
um,
can I get you to stand up if you would
turn around?
Okay.
So how many fingers on your back?
Alright.
Why low resolution?
He's like a row on his back is like a
low resolution,
a array of pixels.
Right?
And so it's virtually impossible.
You just don't have enough sensory
tissue on your back to make that.
You could tell I was pushing,
but it could have been a bad.
It could have been five fingers.
It doesn't matter.
Maybe your pixel is this big or
something like that.
Right?
And so,
but if I put a finger on your lip like
that,
man,
you've got it right now or on your
tongue because your tongue,
there's more sensory representation of
your tongue than your entire trunk and
well,
why?
Well,
you don't want to bite your tongue that,
that's a big problem.
You have to be able to talk.
You want to really differentiate what
you're eating.
If you're eating fish,
you don't want to eat the bones.
So.
And you know when your tongue is
unbelievably crazily sensitive and you
know that too,
that if you have a tooth pulled,
your tongue will investigate that area
for like six months.
You're,
you're sitting there,
your attention wanes and your tongue is
in there like mapping like mad mapping,
that little hole to update your body
representation.
Right?
And it's just this crazy thing that is
unbelievably well represented.
Set from the sensory perspective and
also from the motor perspective because
you could manipulate your tongue like
crazy.
It's like a quarter of your motor output
system is devoted to tongue
manipulation.
Right?
And so here's a,
here's a picture of the homonculus.
This is a motor homunculus.
So,
and that's how,
that's what your brain thinks of your
body,
that that's a good way of thinking about
it.
And so that's what a human being is like
in terms of his or her output.
And so what you see,
if you look at a sensory homonculus,
it's quite similar except the feet are
bigger.
The Genitalia or bigger.
Logically they don't have much motor
utility,
but they have a lot of sensor utility.
But the rest of it's quite similar,
so there's,
you know,
the motor and the sensory homonculus are
quite similar.
But I'm going to talk about the motor
homunculus because it's sort of the
action representation.
Well,
so what are human beings like?
we're all hands.
That's the first thing you know,
and if you,
if you do that,
there's no,
it's unbelievably high resolution and
your fingertips and,
and,
and the,
and the sensory.
But we can manipulate our hands like
crazy.
Like they're unbelievably articulate it.
Right?
And that's the thing that makes us able
to change the world.
It makes us what dolphins aren't.
And so a huge part of our brain is
devoted towards being able to move our
hands.
Now it enables us to take things apart,
put them together.
And then once we learned to take things
apart and put them together,
we can talk about how we do that.
And that's a lot of what we're doing.
And that's the hands in the mouth and
the tongue.
Roughly speaking.
Here's how I took something apart.
Chaos.
Here's what I made out of it.
Order,
here's how I did it.
And then you received that and you're
happy about it,
and then you can do the same thing.
And that's imitation facilitated by
language.
It's like,
here's what I did with my body.
I'm propagating the cross space.
You're taking it,
mapping it onto your body.
Now you can do the same thing.
Yeah.
And that's,
you know,
it might be simple like this is how you
pick up a rock,
but it might be complicated,
like here's how you go after the dragon
of chaos.
Right?
And so that's sort of maps onto that
hierarchy,
this thing that we've talked about in
some detail this,
when you're telling a story to people,
when you're informing them about
something,
you can talk to them at a very high
level of resolution,
which you do with your child.
Here's how you slice up some Broccoli,
right?
But then you move up the obstruction and
say,
here's how you act like a civilized
person at the dinner table.
Right?
And that's part of being a good person.
So you can tell stories about,
I just went and saw logan,
which I really liked.
By the way,
it's super violent,
but I really did like it.
It's,
it's got a very elegant mythological
structure,
which is not surprising,
but there's a scene in this logan movie.
He,
he,
uh,
it's not a spoiler.
He has this child with him who has not
been,
who's been raised roughly in the
laboratory and she has absolutely no
table manners.
And so they're sitting at the dinner
with some people that they've run into
and she's eating like a total barbarian.
And of course everybody's eyebrows race.
Like where did this person come from?
So the,
the fact that that high order behavior
isn't there is something that's of
extraordinary interest to everyone.
And so you know,
you,
you teach your children micro strategies
and you teach the macro strategies.
Some of the macro strategies you're
teaching them,
you don't even understand you because
you know,
you know the strategies they're built
into you because of an evolutionary
process,
roughly speaking.
And you say things like,
it doesn't matter whether you win or
lose.
It matters how you play the game and you
don't understand what that means.
Although you know it's right and you try
to act that out for your children and
they incorporate it in their action,
even though they can't represent that,
they cannot come up with a fully
articulated representation of what that
means,
and so they're like children,
the [inaudible] children.
Children can only play by themselves to
begin with while they're integrating
themselves internally.
Then they start to play in parallel with
other children,
so you'll you're to.
You play your game.
That child plays his or her gait,
little interaction,
but you can't unite the games.
Then you're between two and four.
You start to be able to unite the games
and you can either do that by acting
them out.
You can do this even with a younger
child,
they can catch peekaboo very rapidly,
but once you're between two and four and
you start getting linguistic,
you could start saying,
well,
let's play this game and that means
we're going to unite our attention
towards a particular goal.
We're gonna unite our motor activity and
maybe cooperate and compete towards that
goal.
So beginning of of the social structure,
so the beginning of the social
structure,
and you get really good at that between
two and four,
but you don't necessarily know what
you're doing.
You can't say it.
So Piaget's experiments indicated that
if you take children,
maybe they've got to the point where
they can play quite a social game.
Maybe they're five or six,
they're playing marbles.
You take them out of the game and you
say,
okay,
tell me the rules of the game of
marbles.
They give incoherent representations.
Why?
Because their behavior is more
sophisticated than their representation.
You see,
as soon as you understand that,
that is a wild thing to understand
because it answers the question.
For example,
how can you have dreams that tell you
things you don't know?
You think,
well,
how the hell can that possibly be?
You're coming up with the damn dream.
How can the dream tell you things you
don't know?
Or analogously?
How can people tell stories that contain
information that they don't understand?
And the answer is the information is
coded in our behavior.
Okay,
so we'll go back to a chimpanzee troop.
All the chimpanzees in the troop,
no,
the dominance hierarchy structure,
but if you take a chimpanzee out from
the truth and say,
what's the dominant structure?
The chimpanzee is gonna do whatever it
chimpanzee does.
It's not going to have a little
conversation with you about the nature
of the dominance hierarchy so it can act
out its knowledge and it might even be
able to represent it as an image,
but it can't articulate it.
Well,
why would we be any different?
We aren't obviously because we're more
complex than we understand,
so the fact that we're more complex than
we understand means that we contain
information that we cannot articulate.
Why can't that reveal itself?
It does all the time.
You have a revelation.
It's,
Aha,
I get it.
Well,
what is that?
It's you.
Maybe you're in psychotherapy and we
talk about some things about your past
and we say,
well,
this happened.
Then this happened.
I said,
look,
there's a pattern whap,
and it's overwhelming.
It's like now there's a concordance
between your knowledge and the things
that you're acting out,
and that's what comes as a revelation.
So one of the things that happens in
exodus,
Moses is leading his people through the
desert,
classic u shaped story.
They're in a tyranny to begin with,
right?
So that's the.
That's the insufficient present.
That's the old order.
And then they crossed the water,
the destructive water.
That's chaos.
Like the flood.
Then they're out in the desert wandering
without direction.
They start worshiping idols,
they're wandering without direction,
and then Moses goes up on the mountain,
which is by the way,
what happens in Logan,
just because if you're going to go see
it,
you might as well know that because it's
a journey up the mountain.
He goes up the mountain and he gets
rules revealed to him.
Well,
the way the story is structured is
stored nearly interesting because Moses
takes this people away from this tier
Annette tyrannical structure,
but they don't go from tyranny to
paradise to the promised land in one
move.
That isn't how it works.
They have to go from a tyranny to
absolute chaos where everyone is
fighting and killing each other and
having a terrible time of it and half
starving and and having to pass through
the Red Sea like it's.
They go from tyranny to catastrophe
before they go to higher order,
and Moses doesn't even make it to the
place of higher order.
If he dies before he gets there,
so it's,
it's quite the catastrophe and the
Israelites are all confused when they're
out in the desert because even though
they were in a tyranny and they were
slaves,
now they're nowhere and they don't know
anything.
It's not good.
And so a lot of them actually start
thinking about how good the damn tyranny
was compared to wandering around in the
desert,
which is exactly what happened to the
Soviet Union in Russia.
Now there's huge nostalgia for the
Stalinist era.
So these stories,
they are always true.
They're always happening.
So anyways,
what happens to Moses is that the story
is quite interesting.
So the Israelites start to fight amongst
themselves,
which of course they do because there's
no higher order authority.
And so then Moses sits and judges the
like literally like a judge,
he sits for hours everyday and the
squabbling Israelites come up and say,
you know,
he did this to me.
I know you did this to me,
and so then Moses has to figure out
who's right and who's wrong.
And he's doing this for like hours and
hours for days and days for weeks and
weeks for months.
It's like the origin of English common
law.
It's exactly what happened with common
law because in common law what happens
is that you have all the rights.
There are,
if you to have a dispute,
you go before the judiciary,
you sort out the dispute.
That becomes a precedent.
Now that's part of the body of laws.
The body of laws is what you act out.
That's why it's a body.
Well,
that's what Moses does.
So he's sitting there making judgments,
very,
very finely tuned,
discreet moral judgements.
You know how difficult that is when two
people have a dispute to try to figure
out how to mediate between that,
you don't know who's lying,
who's telling the truth.
You don't know exactly what an
acceptable solution would be like.
It's really ridiculously hard work.
So he walks through this entire process
of continual judicial intermediation.
Then he goes up the mountain and what
does he get?
Tablet of rules.
Well,
why?
he spent his 10,000
hours investigating the structure of
morality in a practical way and it goes,
Bang,
this is what we've been doing.
These are the rules.
It's not like there's no rules to begin
with and those are opposed because that
wouldn't work.
It doesn't work that way.
You have to take how people are,
extract out what the pattern of what
they are is reflect that back to them.
Well,
that's,
that's the story of Moses and it's,
it's,
it's a myth.
It's a metal story.
It's a story about how rules come to be.
We act a certain way.
We have certain kinds of expectations.
We have certain kinds of disputes out of
that,
a pattern,
a pattern way of being emerges.
Then we map the pattern way of being.
We say,
well look,
here's the rules.
There's 10 of them or however many you
want to extract.
Right?
I mean it's,
it's a moving target in some sense.
Don't kill other people.
That's a bad idea,
don't steal what other people have,
honor your parents,
etc.
Etc.
I mEan these are.
You could come up with a different basic
set of rules,
but there'd be some overlap and those
aren't bad to begin with.
There were far more rules than that,
but those were the central ones.
And so then you mIght say,
hey,
if you took all 10 of those rules and
you tried to extract out one rule from
them,
that would be at the top of the
hierarchy,
what would that be?
And in western culture,
the idea there is that do unto others as
you would have them do unto you is the
rule that it's the mega rule that guides
all other rules,
sort of like the one ring in the,
in the lord of the rings.
And so it's this consistent pattern of
abstraction of ethical guidelines.
So okaY,
so well and so that maps onto,
well there's a,
there's a micro,
there's a micro level that you instruct
people at and that then there's a more
abstract level that you instruct them
out and then there's a more abstract
level while maybe at that point you
can't exactly directly instruct them
your number in the pinocchio story.
Japan,
oh,
sits pennock or the cricket gemini sits
pinocchio down and tries to lecture to
him about what the highest level of
moral virtue is.
A sounds like a complete fraud.
He sounds like a propaganda artist.
He's a soapbox preacher and pinocchio
doesn't understand them at all.
why has to be acted out now?
Maybe as a parent you can be a model for
emulation,
which is so you're a mortal for
imitation.
What you say matters,
but it doesn't say as much matter as
much as what you do.
Maybe it would if what you said and what
you did were the same.
That's the ideal situation,
right?
That's what you want to do.
If you're a parent,
if you say one thing and act
differently,
your kids will torture you to death and
they're right to do it too because
you're confused and confusing them,
makes them anxious and aggressive and
they will go after you.
consistency,
consistency.
And if you can't provide it,
he will drive them crazy.
So you,
you,
you want to bring your words and your
actions into alignment.
Right?
And that's part of the development of
wisdom.
So.
Okay,
so back to the brain.
All right,
so there's,
there's the motor homunculus.
So now what I want to tell you about
that is you just think about what this
thing is like.
It's taking the world apart and it's
talking about it.
So that's what a human being is like.
And that,
to me that's kind of an image of the
mythological hero.
It's the thing that can speak magic
words and take the world's apart.
Take the world apart.
Now in one of the stories I'm going to
tell you today,
which is the story of the enuma elish,
which is the oldest written story that
we have.
It's a mesopotamian story and it's from
the same pool of stories that the
creation account in genesis was
extracted.
It isn't obvious what the temporal
sequence was,
but imagine there was a pool of stories
in the middle east that were of
indefinite age,
tens of thousands of years and in needs
of the more developed in a slightly
different way.
Although the themes underneath were
similar.
There are great parallels between the
mesopotamian creation account and the
first part of the creation account in
genesis,
so it was discovered in the late 19
hundreds and isis just destroyed a huge
treasure trove of that sort of
manuscripts.
So just so you know,
so at nineveh,
so we can.
We can thank the war in the middle east
for the destruction of a huge,
a huge treasure house of irreplaceable
human knowledge.
And a lot of that's happening that's
happening very,
very frequently.
It's an absolute bloody disgraceful
catastrophe.
So anyway,
so you know that that's the human being.
Lips,
tongues,
hands,
and the face.
Your face is also extraordinarily
amenable to voluntary manipulation,
so you can learn to move single neurons
in the tissue underneath your eyes.
That's how that's how high resolution
your faces and that's partly because
it's a broadcast screed,
which is why people are always looking
at it.
RighT,
and that's why if you watch a movie,
it's always concentrating on people's
faces because they're just broadcasting
what they're broadcasting their stories
constantly and we're looking at their
faces.
What are you looking at?
What are your eyes pointing at?
What are you up to?
What's your emotional expression?
What are you going to do next?
What do you think about me?
Where are you going and you're brought
like you find someone who has had too
much plastic surgery.
Uncanny because their face is dead
because you cannot tell what they're up
to there they've got.
This is all and be like aspect.
It's terrifying and people like that.
Look,
people like that got killed.
That's why we're not like that or they
didn't meet.
It's like you want to know what that
other person is up to,
and I told you already.
That's how the whites of our eyes
evolved,
right?
I don't you remember that story.
Gorillas don't have that distinction
between the irs and the whites.
Not like human beings and our eyes are
very sharp and one thing we really want
to know is what are you looking at and
why?
What are you up to?
And if I can tell what you're looking
at,
I can infer what you're going to do and
you want to broadcast that well,
except when you don't want to broadcast
it,
but you know,
most of the time you want to be pretty
transparent to other people because
otherwise they won't trust you and if
they don't trust you,
they won't cooperate with you,
they won't compete with you.
And the probability that they'll come
after you is extraordinarily high
because you'll be evil predator in no
time flat.
So,
okAy,
so we'll take a look at the brain from
another perspective.
Now,
a lot of this I got from alcoa conan
goldberg,
um,
well,
that's not exactly right.
I had laid up,
laid this out before that,
but I found out and goldberg's readings
afterwards and he was a student of
lyricists and he was trying to account
for the y.
We had different hemispheres roughly
speaking because it's not self evident
that we should.
They're actually somewhat separate
consciousnesses and they they,
they communicate,
but the communication isn't complete.
It's like our brain is modularized and
unified at the same time and you can
think about it like a meeting of people.
Why do you want it mod your mod
muellerized while so if one person goes
down,
all of them don't.
That's one one reason.
So at some separation of function,
why else?
Well,
each little module can do its own
creative thing independently of the
others and that's useful and then there
can be communication between them and so
there's,
there's utility in modularity and
there's utility and integration and part
of what we're trying to work out on the
global political scene right now is how
modular things should be and how
integrated they should be,
and the erp and the community rushed
into integration and that's bothering
people dreadfully because they feel that
the advantages of modularization have
been washed away.
You saw that and maybe they're right
because you saw what happened when
Greece collapsed,
right?
And Greece is very,
very corrupt,
incredibly corrupt.
and Germany,
whatever else you might think about
Germany is not corrupt,
and so the eec tried to bring Greece and
Germany together.
That didn't work.
There was no unity there.
The modularity was actually useful and
the fact that Greece was so destabilized
and Italy also very corrupt and Spain
also very corrupt,
was very shaky just about brought the
whole thing down.
It it.
The argument is the modularity would
have been better conserved.
Well,
who knows,
right?
Because modularity is useful and so it's
integration,
but full integration seems to be a
mistake and sodas,
full modularity.
How do you get that?
Right?
We don't know.
That's why we're arguing about it and
right now there's a backlash.
We're pulling away from the integration
and you you can see why too,
because in 2008 when the american
economy collapsed,
the world economy just about collapsed.
That seems like a bad idea.
You know,
you might want some,
some separate nest so that if one system
malfunctions and goes down,
the whole bloody thing doesn't go into
flames.
And so we don't know.
We don't know how to manage that.
It's a really,
really complicated problem,
so anyways.
Okay,
so how did the,
how does the brain work?
Well,
the left roughly speaking in
right-handed males and the reason that
I'm concentrating on right handed males
is because there are simpler in their
neurological structure.
Women have a more complicated
neurological structure and lefthanded
people tend to have a more complicated
neurological structure,
so we'll just say that we'll just go
with the standard model to begin with
and you can assume that the same systems
are there in every person,
but they're not laid out on the
hemispheric structure quite as neatly,
but they're still there,
so it's sort of like these are
tendencies.
So for example,
if you're a.
So there's a tendency for the right
hemisphere to specialize for what's
relatively unknown and the left
relatively mastered and you can think
about it this way too,
left,
right?
It's something like that.
Okay,
so
large scale,
low resolution abstractions tend to be
the province of the right high
resolution,
detailed knowledge structures tend to be
the province of the left.
The left is linguistic.
That's where the detailed structures
manifest themselves.
In articulation,
but the fundamental difference between
the left and right isn't language versus
non language.
The fundamental distinction is
relatively explored and mastered versus
relatively unexplored and not mastered,
and that's both in terms of structure.
The right hemisphere has a less granular
structure.
It's less differentiated.
It's also responsible mostly for
negative emotion,
especially in the prefrontal part,
and the reason for that is,
well,
how do you encounter what's absolutely
unknown?
Imagination and emotion,
right?
I told you that little experiment that
you could do if you're alone in a house
and you hear a strange noise at night in
a room,
turn off the lights and put your hand in
the room.
It's like your brain will just flash off
monsters like mad.
You know?
You'll be nervous because that what's in
that room,
something to make you nervous.
That's a very low resolution category,
right?
It's like it's a.
It's some indeterminant manifestation of
the category of things that might hurt
you.
Very low resolution,
but a very smart category.
It's like,
don't put your hand in there.
You put your hand in there and you watch
your imagination.
It's like monsters.
It'll generate monsters like matt and
that's what the right hemisphere is
doing.
It's saying what's in there is an
exemplar of the category of things that
are dangerous.
Here's a bunch of images of those things
and that thing in there is going to
partake of that essence.
That's a and that's a very low
resolution hypothesis.
That's kind of what horror movies do
with people.
You know.
They sort of lead them through that
initial process and so and so.
That's what the right way.
The right hemisphere seems to me to be
dominated by dominated by subcortical
processes was the left hemisphere is
reversed.
The cortex is more or less got dominion
and so the right hemisphere,
well we'll walk through this
neurologically,
but the right hemisphere is responds
rapidly to what's unknown and that's
subcortical is the hippocampus,
is is doing an awful lot of that.
Noting a mismatch and then it's using
the right hemisphere to to abstractly
represent what the possibility space is
in relationship to unexpected things and
then the right hemisphere is tracking
that continually.
What those unexpected things are and
coming up with models of what you
haven't yet mastered and that's kept
separate from the left hemisphere,
which already has functional models and
you don't want to blast the left
hemisphere continually with the
normalist information because you blow
out its structure and then you don't
know what to do.
So the right hemisphere generates new
models in some sense out of nothing,
and then when the time is right,
taps information into the left
hemisphere slowly so that it doesn't
disrupt its function too much and that's
a lot of that seems to happen when
you're dreaming by the way it happens at
night.
So and what happens with the dreams.
You think about how dreams work as you
might think of dreams as part of that
process where ideas come to be so
they're low resolution to begin with,
mostly a majestic,
really highly emotional and incoherent
less coherent.
Why you can't be coherent less.
You know what to do,
f if that's working,
you've got coherence.
But if you're dealing with something you
don't know,
you have to muck about with your
category structures.
And that's what dreams do,
and you know,
when you're interpreting a dream,
one of the things you watch for is the
dream.
The dream presents this.
And then this.
That's called metonymy.
By the way,
from a literary perspective.
And what that implies is this is related
to this in some way.
Why else would they be co activated?
You know,
people sAy,
well,
dreams are random.
That's the stupidest theory I've ever
heard.
Like white noise is random.
Dreams are not random.
They're hard to understand,
but they're anything but random.
They're more random than real life.
Well,
that's because what you don't understand
these really random and you're organized
and there has to be an intermediary that
sort of quasi random between the more
you'll never get from one to the other,
and dreams,
fantasies,
myths,
all of that is part of that process that
it stretches you out beyond what you
know into the absolute unknown.
And so,
and you're hemispheres are
differentially specialized for that.
So roughly speaking,
right hemisphere operation and
unexplored territory,
that's a really good way of thinking
about it.
You need a system that tells you what to
do when you don't know what to do.
A huge part of the subcortical
structures of doing that to unknown
freeze.
Then what?
Imagine right,
freeze emotion.
Imagine then explore,
then differentiate,
then master.
That's the process.
That's the process of learning and what
you're doing is you're.
You're transforming low resolution
representations of what's frightening
into high resolution representations
that enabled you to master it,
to take the world park and to make
ingenious things out of it.
So there's this very cool part of the
mesopotamian creation myths so that the
major hero whose name is martech,
confronts the dragon of chaos.
Tiamat who's feminine,
and he cuts her into paces and he makes
the world out of her pieces and one of
his names,
there's,
he had 50,
60 names and I think that was,
those were amalgams of tribal gods and
one of the names was he who makes
ingenious things out of the conflict
with taya matt.
It's absolutely perfect.
That's exactly what human beings do,
right?
We confront that terrible predatory
potential that lies outside our domain
of experience and we make ingenious
things out of it and then we talk about
how we did it and then we model how we
did it,
and that's the basis of our ethics and
our morality and the way that that ties
into think about.
One of the things we talked about was
that the mythological hero was a
representation,
not of the being that was at the top of
the dominance hierarchy,
but of the being that was at the top of
the set of all possible dominance
hierarchies.
Okay,
so here's the cool equation.
The hero who goes out into the unknown
to who make contact with the dragon and
to bring back the treasurer is the same
thing that wins the battle across sets
of dominance hierarchies and that's how
the two things come together.
Right?
It's so brilliant.
It's so absolutely brilliant,
and so it's the mythological hero.
Mythological hero is the representation
of what's,
again,
not at the top of one dominance
hierarchy,
but at the top of all of them.
That's the eye that's above the pyramid.
Why the eye?
Because it pays attention and that's
what you do.
Like none of this is.
This is not fiction,
it's method truth.
It's a right way to think about it.
Look,
let's say you're socially anxious.
Okay?
So what happens when you're socially
anxious?
You go to a party,
your heart's beating.
Why the party is a monster.
Why?
Because it's judging you and it's
judging you.
It's putting you low down the dominance
hierarchy because that's what a negative
judgment is and that interferes with
your sexual success.
And that means that you're being harshly
evaluated by nature itself,
right?
So you are confronting the dragon of
chaos when you go into the social
situation.
And so what do you do?
You like this,
right?
You hunch over and that's low dominance.
I'm no threat.
It's like whoa,
that's not going to get you very far,
you know,
but that's a logical thing to do.
And in the,
in the face of a tyrant.
So I'm no threat.
You know,
you look at the king and your dad,
I'm no threat and hunched over.
And then what's happening internally,
howard,
what are people thinking about me?
What are people thinking about me or am
I looking stupid?
Am I looking foolish?
Geez,
I'm awkward.
I hate being here,
man.
I'm sweating too much.
It's all internalized,
right?
It's all self focused.
The isn't work.
the eye isn't working.
What do you tell people?
Stop.
Don't stop thinking about yourself
because you can't.
It's like,
don't think of a white elephant,
white elephant,
white,
elephant.
You can't tell someone to stop thinking
about something because they get caught
in the loop.
What you do with socially anxious people
as you say,
look at other people.
Look at them.
Right?
Why?
Because if you look at them,
you can tell what they're thinking and
then you.
Unless you're.
Unless you're terribly socialized and
some people are,
some people have no social skills and so
the reason they can't go to a party is
because they don't even know how to
introduce themselves.
Like they're just no one ever taught
them how to behave and so they're really
good candidates for behavior therapy
because you walk them through the
process of how you actually manifest the
procedures that are associated with
social acceptability,
but most people aren't like that.
They have the ability,
so if they're really introverted in high
in neuroticism,
they can usuaLly talk quite well to
someone one on one.
Why?
Because they looked at them on.
If I look at you,
it's another thing to do.
If you're ever speaking to a group of
people,
never speak to the group of people there
that doesn't exist.
You talk to individuals and then they
reflect for you the entire group because
they're all in trained.
You look At one person,
they broadcast what everyone's thinking
and you know how to talk to one person,
so it's easy.
So as soon as you focus on the person,
not you,
you push your attention outward.
Use your.
I push your attention outward and you
start watching.
Well then all your automatic mechanisms
kick in and you start being awkward
because if we're talking and I'm looking
here,
I don't know what you're going to do
next and I'm going to put disjunctions
into the like,
they're like a bad chords and the melody
of our,
of our conversation,
and the reason is I'm not paying
attention,
so that's why the I is the thing at the
top of the pyramid,
it's like the thing that enables you to
win the set of all possible dominance
hierarchies is the I pay attention.
Pay attention.
That's the critical issue.
That's why the egyptians worshiped
horace.
That's why horace was the thing that
rescued osiris from the.
From the depths.
it's the capacity to pay attention.
What do you pay attention to?
Most?
What?
Your right hemisphere signals as
anomalous.
It attracts your attention.
It's like this isn't going quite right.
I'm not looking at that wrong.
That's what you look at.
What's not going right,
because that's.
See,
that's the terrible monster that might
eat you,
but it's also the place you get all the
information,
so that's why it's useful to have
discussions with your enemies because
they will tell you things you do not
know and that's such a great thing
because if you don't know them well,
you're not very smart,
are you?
You know,
there may be a time when you go
somewhere,
that's the thing you need to know and
maybe your enemy will tell you why
you're such a fool,
a bunch of other things that aren't true
to,
but even one thing that's accurate,
it's like,
yeah,
thanks very much man.
Maybe I'll do Some work on that and I
won't have to carry that forward.
So.
And then that's part of the reason again
why the terrible predator.
It's always the terrible predator that
has the gold.
It's like it's the person who delivers
the message you do not want to hear.
So it's rough,
it's rough,
but it doesn't matter.
Life is rough.
Okay,
so how are these specialized?
The right hemisphere operation and
unexplored territory and that unexplored
territory emerges whenever what you're
doing doesn't work.
You know,
you can conceptualize it as that which
is beyond the walls of the city,
but the city is a category structure
abstractly,
but there's no difference between the
barbarians that invade the world's city
and the things that happened in the
world that damaged your category
structure there.
They're the same thing from a,
from a practical perspective,
okay?
Right hemisphere operation and
unexplored territory,
negative emotion,
inhibition of behavior.
That's this.
That's anxiety.
That's what happens when the medusa
looks at you.
You turned to stone,
right?
That's the basilisk in Harry Potter.
It freezes you.
Why?
You're moving forward according to a
schema.
If you're moving fruit forward,
property you're getting to where you
want to go,
and the schema is being validated
simultaneously.
I'm moving forward and the map is
correct.
Something happens that's unexpected.
What should you do?
Stop.
What else are you going to do?
He stopped first.
Then the predator can't see you,
right?
That's the freezing reaction of a prey
animal,
so it's.
It's,
it's,
it's built very,
very deeply into very,
very old circuits.
Do that fact,
if it's a real orienting reflects to
something that's normal,
she'll go like this and that's to stop
the thing that will jump on your back
from carrying out your throat and that's
really,
really fast.
It's almost as fast spinal snake
reflects circuitry extraordinarily fast
and that you know that's conserved over
and evolutionary span.
That predator defense system is at the
bottom of your cognitive apparatus.
Everything's been built on that.
It's a low resolution pattern,
a higher resolution pattern.
That's the same pattern is built on top
of that.
Then a higher resolution pattern.
That's the same pattern is built on top
of that and so on,
but that initial architecture is
duplicated across the levels of
differentiation of the nervous system
and that's partly why these symbols can
be so archaic and still be accurate.
it's still the way the world works.
negative emotion,
inhibition of behavior,
image processing,
right?
Because image hang about images is there
fast,
you know,
a picture is worth a thousand words.
Okay.
You get the picture,
you know,
get the picture is actually something
you say to someone.
If you say,
do you understand?
Right?
To get the picture is very,
very fast.
So the right hemisphere managers,
that holistic thinking,
that's that low resolution thinking that
generalizes across instances,
pattern recognition,
pattern generation and gross motor
action.
Yeah,
freeze and get the hell out of there.
That's gross motor action.
The right hemisphere is very good at
that.
That's why if you're right handed,
use your.
If you're right handed,
you use your left hemisphere to manage
the really fine motor details,
right?
You write with it,
you write with it,
and because that's very,
very.
If you're right handed,
you tend to use your left hand to open
the top of jars,
right?
You use your left hand.
That's a gross motor action.
I mean sometimes people are more
lateralized than not,
but the left hemisphere specialized for
the fine grain.
Things that you know very well.
that's exactly yet.
okay.
The left hemisphere,
well the left hemisphere,
which is associated with positive
emotion by the way,
that's specialized for operation
unexplored territory.
So now what we might say is that you
spend your whole life trying not to have
the right hemisphere turn on
because why would you want that?
That's where the monsters pop up.
So you stay in explored territory,
but maybe you also tentatively expand
its borders and the left hemisphere
seems to be involved in that too.
So if you're curious about something,
it's usually something usually something
minor enough so that it won't blow your
entire category structure if you explore
it.
Now,
sometimes you get unlucky and you're
like,
eve in the garden of eden,
you go have a little chat with this
little snake that seems to be of no
significance whatsoever,
and it feeds you something.
The apple,
it feeds you something and bang,
everything falls apart,
right?
You claps and you're,
you're out there in history.
You're no longer in your old paradise.
So activation of behavior.
Yeah,
well that's because positive emotion is
associated with movement forward.
like if you're where you want to be and
things are going well,
then your behavior should be activated
so that you go and get things.
Now,
one of the negative consequences of that
is that if you're really in a good mood,
really happy,
you're going to be impulsive and make
mistakes because you hear these dough
headed.
that's a very minor word.
people who are always pushing happiness
as the as the key measure for for
successful existence.
It's so
ill informed that it's embarrassing that
that even happens.
Positive emotion makes people impulsive.
Maniacs for example,
which is really if that's mania,
right?
Bipolar disorder.
If you're manic,
you're one happy person,
way too happy.
Everything is great.
Nothing but wonderful things that are
beyond your imagination.
You are going to happen to you and
they're going to happen fast and so
you're down to the mall to buy
everything you can possibly get your
hands on because you have 100 uses for
everything and then a week later,
you know you crash into your depressive
episode and you realize that you're
$150,000
in debt and you've alienated everyone
that you know.
It's like that's untrammeled positive
emotion.
So how about no,
you're the appear index of positive
emotion is no way of determining whether
or not a system is working properly.
Even your own system,
you need a balance between positive and
negative emotions.
Plus positive emotions are absolutely
exhausting because if you're in a manic
episode,
it's like it's time to get everything
good right now,
fine,
but you won't sleep for a week and then
you die because you just burned yourself
to a crisp and so to be overwhelmingly
enthusiastic about everything sounds
like a real blast and I've seen full
blown mannix and they're having plenty
of fun,
but it is not a pleasant thing to
behold.
They're just all over the place and you
know,
yeah,
it's really not good.
It's really not good.
You need a balance between these two
systems because the whole world isn't
explored territory bursting with nothing
but promise.
That's not the world.
The world is that the bounded space a
little bit without absolute horror show
going out around the periphery and both
of your both systems need to be active
in order to keep you balanced.
People do unfortunately sustain damage
sometimes to the left Prefrontal cortex
responsible for positive emotion or the
right prefrontal cortex responsible for
negative emotion,
and if you sustain right hemisphere
prefontal damage,
it makes you inappropriately happy and
impulsive and your and your life just
goes.
You just spiraled downhill because you
make nothing but impulsive decisionS and
you know what the world world
consequence of that is.
you know you get drunk and be impulsive
for one night.
You can learn what the bloody
consequences of that are.
You try living like that for a month
independently of iq.
That's the other thing that's so
interesting.
You can blow out your left prefrontal
cortex and not much of a decrease,
especially in crystallized intelligence,
but the fact that you're running on
nothing but sorry,
your right hemisphere,
you're running on nothing but positive
emotion is going to argue.
You write it into the ground and then if
you're perhaps even more unlucky and you
lose the left prefrontal cortex,
then you're permanently depressed
because there's nothing but
the unexplored manifesting itself.
We know that if you take depressive,
depressed people and you do eeg
analysis,
that they have predominant lifting,
predominant,
resting right hemisphere eeg activation,
and so,
so that's roughly.
So why is this well unknown territory
known territory you think,
well,
is that real?
Well,
it's real enough.
So that's how your brain evolved.
That seems pretty damn real.
So then we can think about it.
Sub cortically and we might as well do
that.
This is mapped out on the hippocampus
more,
most particularly by Jeffrey gray who is
influenced by soul glove and vinegar,
dover,
who were also students have luria,
Jeffrey Gray used cybernetic theory that
was developed by norbert wiener and
which has an ai,
uh,
which he was the father Of artificial
intelligence.
And some of that was actually integrated
as well into peer jetty and thought
because piaget and white wiener,
norbert,
wiener and luria,
if I remember correctly,
all went to the same conference back in
the early 19 twenties,
mid 19 twenties and heard norbert wiener
speak.
So that's how cybernetic theory got
built into some of these underlying
theories and sort of manifested itself
everywhere.
So gray gray uses a model very much like
this derived from cybernetic theory,
and so here's the idea,
how does the brain work?
You have a target in mind
and you aCt too to manifest the target,
you act to transform the world into the
target and then you compare the
consequences of your actions to the
target.
And if they match,
then that's a good thing.
And if they don't match,
then that's what they were negative
emotion comes from.
Okay,
so how does that work?
The hippocampus seems to be central to
that.
So it detects mismatch.
So.
So in the classic behavioral theory,
no.
So this would be Grazed theory.
You have your expectations of the world.
So that would be your model and you have
your sensor input,
which iS the real world.
And then the hippocampus is mapping one
onto the other,
one from a top downstream,
one from a bottom uPstream and saying
match,
and as long as everything matches,
then the hippocampus.
This is an oversimplification,
keeps the subcortical emotional systems
inhibiteD because you don't need them
except for maybe my mild positive
emotion to keep you moving forward.
If there's a mismatch that's anxiety,
the anxiety system gets disinhibited
because it's on.
It doesn't get activated,
gets disinhibited,
that freezes you,
and all the other motivational systems
are prime.
God only knows what you're going to have
to do next.
Okay,
so then if you make a mistake,
given that scheme,
you have to modify the world in order to
rectify the mistake.
You have to modify your motor outputs so
that you put the world back in order,
and that's basically grays model,
but gray model is insufficient because
gray presumes that what you're comparing
your expectation with is the real world,
but you don't have access to the real
world.
What really happens is that your brain
compares the model of the world that you
want to have happen,
so it's desired,
not expected with the model of the world
that you think is happening.
There are both models.
There's no direct contact with the
truth,
and so what that means,
and this is what's horrible about this,
is that if your model fails,
it doesn't only mean that you have to
adjust your expectation and change your
motor activity.
It means you might have to bloody well
retool your perceptions well,
that's a lot more horrifying than just
having to change your motor output.
If you will be trained me,
then I have to see you differently and
you know I've.
If we've interacted a long time,
I've built up a hell of a model of you.
You know,
it's taken a tremendous amount of effort
to generate and I may have used that
model as a predicate for all sorts of
other plants,
which is what you do with an intimate
relationship.
And so then if you do something that
indicates our true mismatch,
it isn't only that I have to adjust my
actions.
God only knows what I'm going to have to
retool.
I may even have to retool my perceptions
of myself.
I'm a lot more gullible than I thought I
was,
for example,
and god only knows what the implications
of that are.
If you,
if you're close to me And you could do
this to me,
is that my flaw and environment?
Am I carrying that into other
relationships?
It's an absolute catastrophe and so gray
actually underestimated the degree of
severity of mismatch because he only
said,
well,
it was motor output and and and re and
re world adjusting.
That would have to be repaired.
Not perception because like most
behavior,
see the behaviors had this idea of
stimulus,
right?
The stimulus produces the response.
It's like,
okay,
what stimulus?
Well,
they never went there.
They just assumed that the stimulus
spoke for itself,
but it doesn't.
That's the fundamental weakness of
behavioral theory is that the reason
they could get rid of the mind was
because they hid it invisibly inside the
idea of the stimulus,
which is all of a sudden,
not just something that was a sense,
like a piece of sense data,
but that had motivation built into it.
Well,
no,
you know you can't do tHat.
The motivation.
You can put the motivation into object,
but then it's no longer an object.
It's something completely different.
Okay,
good.
Let's stop there.
When you come back,
I'm going to tell you a bunch of
stories.
Okay,
so we'll break for 15 minutes.
So imagine what happens.
The civilization
develops and develops out of an amalgam
of tribal organizations,
and so each of those tribes has their
own god,
which has their own sort of imaginative
universe and their attempt to make sense
out of the moral landscape of being and
underneath all of those representations
is a pattern and the reason there's a
pattern there is because all of those
tribes are made up of people and so
there's going to be.
It's like there's a domain within which
variation is going to occur.
So if we're going to set up a structure
that works across time,
it's going to at least be roughly
predicated on the same structures that a
dominance hierarchy is predicated on.
It's going to be predicated on tHe same
patterns of interactions that would
characterize a chimpanzee troop.
You know,
there's,
there's this basic biological,
what would you call it?
There's a realm of biological necessity
that constitutes the boundary space
within which human interactions that
have to take place.
I mean,
I can't be so violent that I kill
everyone in my tribe that's not gonna be
very helpful because I'm in tribal
creatures,
so without the tribe,
what am I going to do?
And so I have to be vaguely acceptable
to other people because otherwise
they'll kill me even if I'm really,
really powerful,
they'll take me down.
And so because I have to deal with you
and you and you and you and you were
going to modify each other continually
and,
and within parameters.
Now the parameters are wide,
but they're not nonexistent.
And you know,
you can see what those parameters are.
Genuinely if you look at something like
a wolf pack or a chimpanzee troop,
because those are stable across really,
the structure itself is stable across at
least hundreds of thousands of years,
if not millions of years.
And so there's a,
there's um,
so frans de waal shows,
for examPle,
that with the chimpanzee troops,
if you have a pr,
he studied them mostly at the arnhem zoo
and I would recommend his writings
highly diwal d,
e,
w a l,
m.
He's interested in the prototypical
moral behavior among chimpanzees.
It's a very interesting study and what
he's showed for example,
is that if you have a particularly the
the dominant dominance hierarchy and
chimpanzees is male,
a female dominance hierarchy to that
overlaps the mail and some of the
females are more dominant than many of
the males,
but the fundamental structure looks like
it's patriarchal,
roughly speaking among chimpanzees.
If you put a really rough,
tough barbaric,
brutal dictator,
chimpanzee at the top,
his,
his reign tends to be unstable and
violent because he isn't good at
negotiating social support and so he
doesn't have any.
And so that means two chimpanzees that
are friends can take them out.
And so that's what happens.
And so the desk bought chimp is an
unstable leader and they've all shown
that the more stable chimp leaders are
more chimpanzee.
Attarian I guess Would be right word.
It's not humanitarian.
They,
they,
they do know they have friends and you
know,
friendship is predicated on reciprocity
even among chimpanzees.
And so if a predicate of power is
reciprocity,
then that's one of the things that
alleviates the dictatorial tendency.
So anyways,
so my,
my point is when a great civilization
emerges,
it emerges from the amalgam of tribal
groups,
but,
and each of the tribal groups has their
own ethic.
But that ethic is,
isn't the ethics aren't entirely
separate from one another.
That's why tribes can trade because they
do trade,
they,
they interact with one another.
It's kind of half.
I remember,
here's how here too,
for separated tribes begin to trade
because you don't know,
you meet each other,
cross the river and it's like you got
your bows and arrows and someone makes a
mistake and it's like warfare and so,
but you don't want to start the damn war
because maybe you'll die.
So you're sitting there with your bow
and arrows watching these guys and now
you know they're there and so then you
go back to your tribe and you think,
oh man,
what the hell are we going to do about
this?
And one solution is,
well,
let's find out where they are.
And then we'll go in there at night and
we'll like,
we'll kill a bunch of theM are will wipe
them out or something like that.
Or another solution might be did you see
all the neat stuff they had?
And so then what do you do is you find a
border area and you go and you put some
things out there that are valuable and
you run away and then you watch from the
trees and you see what happens when
these other people discover these
valuable things that you left there.
And if they're like little under
psychopathic side,
they pick it all up and giggle and run
away.
And that's the end of that.
But if they have any sense,
what they do is they leave some cool
stuff on the ground too and then they
run off and then you can go pick up
their cool stuff and leave.
And then it's like step one in the trust
process and then maybe you do that,
you know,
for a year.
And it starts to fall into a cadence.
And then maybe you know,
you get a little closer when you're
washing,
watching in the bush.
And then maybe one day you have enough
courage to kind of,
you sending your biggest ugliest guy out
there.
And you know,
they do the same and you know,
they look at each other and finally they
shake hands or something like that and
trade and then well then you've got a
trading relationship established and so
you can see in that the emergence of a,
what would you call it,
negotiated consensual moral structure
that allows trading to take place.
And there's gonna be rules emerge right
away,
which is well,
you better leave me something that's of
approximately equal value or I'm not
going to play the game again.
That's the thing that's so cool is that
if we only play a game once,
I can do whatever I want.
And so that's,
that's what psychopaths do.
They play with game once and then they
go play with someone else.
But if we're going to play the same game
over and over and over,
it's like the dominance hierarchy across
time.
There's a different rule for playing a
game once.
Then there is for playing a game a
thousand times
and if we're in a relationship,
the game we want to play is one that can
be duplicated a thousand times and
there's really tight constraints on that
and so that's the origin that you could
consider that the biological,
it's not even biological exactly.
It's predicated in biology,
but it's a consequence of continual
interaction.
The ethic emerges.
It's like the rats that I told you about
that you knoW the,
the rats that play with each other,
the big roundhouse to let the little rat
win 30 percent of the time or the little
rat won't play anymore and so because
the little rat,
that's the biological,
the biological framing,
the limitation is the little rat doesn't
want to lose all the time.
That just produces negative emotion.
It's not fun.
It's not motivating.
So why would the little rat go play
again?
So the,
the,
the constraints on our interactions are
our biological constraints and they
manifest themselves in a patterned way
across time and there isn't any
difference between you and me
interacting across time.
Then there is between you and me acting
say in the next hour or so with everyone
in this room,
it's the same thing.
It's just continual human interactions
and the ethic emerges from that.
Now different groups are going to code
that ethic differently,
so they're going to come up with
different images,
stick representations,
and different stories.
Now,
one of the things they're trying to
figure out is,
well,
let's do,
let's do it in the tribal way.
You have to do this inside the tribe to
you have 100 people and 10 of them are
leaders in one way or another,
and then out of that 10,
you think,
well,
who's the who's the best person?
So you have to have a hierarchy of value
to determine what the most important
aspect of the ethic is,
and it's going to be something like
trust because that's the predicate for
continued interaction.
Trustworthiness,
it's not any real,
really,
really any different than honesty.
It's not really any different from
telling the truth.
So there's a really powerful necessity
for honesty to emerge as a,
as a canonical value carrying might
emerge,
um,
power might emerge,
right?
The ability to exert physical power,
especially in places where war is a
continual,
uh,
is continually likely.
And in lots of tribal landscapes,
it's just nonstop tribal trade in
warfare.
So,
but,
but you can see how different ethics
would eMerge as,
as canonical depending to some degree on
the situation.
But trust is a really crucial one
because without that there's no
relationships.
Okay,
so you've got tribe and it's got its
tribal gods and its and its traditions
and all of that.
It's representation of the,
of being in its images and stories.
And then you've got try b and you've
tried seeing,
you've got tribe d and now they're all
coming together.
So what happens exactly?
Well,
the tribes can go to war or they can
talk and we're,
we're thinking about a communication
that might be extending across
thousand years.
You have your beliefs.
I have my beliefs,
I can overwhelm you,
I can subsume you,
but even then I'm likely to get
indigestion from doing it.
It's very,
very difficult to wipe out a set of
beliefs without wiping out all of the
people and that kind of nullifies the
utility of unification.
The more there are a view,
the better you can defend yourself
against other organizations that are
trying to be larger.
So there's a powerful self preservation
impetus to cooperation and so one of the
things you see happening in the
development of the stories in the old
testament,
for example,
we know this about genesis in particular
that there were at least this is.
This is relatively recently,
so say for 3000 years ago,
not 50,000
years ago.
There were two different stories.
There's two different stories in,
in the genesis account told by two
different storytellers and people who
are very good at textual analysis of
being able to separate them and they
were put together.
I don'T remember when.
again,
it's probably about something between
2000 and 3000 years ago.
They were put together by what appeared
to be a single editor and so he took
these disparate accounts and tried to
organize them into something that looked
like a logical narrative and that was
part of the process by which different
tribal representations of the world were
brought into something under which the
tribes as you as a unit could
simultaneously exist so you can think
about it as a competition between
images,
stick representations across time,
and then the emergence of some unifying
narrative that that captures the key
elements of all of them well enough to
bring them into some sort of union and
it has to be a story with motivational
power because otherwise no one will call
it non to it and it has to be a story
that keeps uncertainty at bay because
otherwise it doesn't have any utility.
So it has to be a functional story.
So I'm going to tell you a story like
that and just the story of marduk and
it's the mesopotamian story.
And mesopotamia is one of the earliest
civilizations and it emerged as a
consequence of the amalgam of.
Of middle eastern tribes.
So the over a very long period of time,
you could thank the gods of all of these
tribes were worrying in an abstract
space,
in a conceptual space,
and that would be the space of
argumentation and conflict.
And out of that a,
a story emerged and this is the medical
story and it's one of a host of similar
medical stories that came out of the
middle east,
one of which is the account in genesis.
Okay?
So here's The story.
So there are two primary day at east to
begin with,
app suit and tie I'm at now.
In order to understand that,
well,
here's how the mesopotamians
conceptualize the world.
There was a,
let's call it a disc that salt water.
Well,
why?
what happens when you go to the end of
the continent?
Salt water everywhere,
right?
So wherever you go,
you run into salt water.
So that's the desk that surrounds
everything.
Now,
why Is it a disk?
The world is a dome on a desk.
Why?
Well,
say you're standing in the middle of a
field.
What does the world look like?
Dome on a disk.
So it's a phenomenal logical
representation.
So the bottom of the dome is the ground
on which you stand.
What happens if you dig deep water,
fresh water.
So the dome of the land is on a disk of
What happens if you go to the edge of
the land?
You run into saltwater.
The dome of the land is on a disk of
fresh water,
on a disk of salt water.
Okay?
Those are the two gods.
Timeout is god and salt.
Water and absolute has guarded
freshwater and it's.
It's happened stamps in some sense
because that's the masculine and the
feminine and they could be attributed
all sorts of different geographical
areas.
So for example,
see if I can think of a good example.
It doesn't matter.
We'll just leave that for now.
Okay?
Okay.
So the two primary gods are absent,
and timeout.
Timeout is female and absolute is male
and there are locked together in an
inseparable embrace.
Okay?
So how do you understand that?
Easy yin and yang?
It's the same idea.
Here is,
here's another representation.
This is a cool one.
I've got a couple of them here that are
really cool.
This is from China,
so this is.
So this is foxy and new.
I think I've got that right,
but I,
I just love that reference is so
insanely cool.
This representation.
So you see sort of the primary mother
and father of humanity emerging from
this underlying snake like entity with
it's tails tangled together.
I think that's a ripper.
I really do believe this,
although it's very complicated to
explain why I really believe that's a
representation of dna,
so and that,
that representation,
that entwined double helix that is
everywhere.
You can see it in our australian
aboriginal art and I'm using the
australians as an example because they
were isolated in Australia for like
50,000
years.
They're the most archaic people that
were ever discovered and they have clear
representations of these double helix
structures in their art.
So.
And those are the two giant serpents out
of which the world is made.
Roughly speaking.
It's the same thing.
You see that in the staff of asclepius,
which is the healing symbol that the
physicians use.
Although usually that's only one snake,
but sometimes it's too.
So,
so,
so that's,
uh,
that's a chinese representation.
And then there's a,
there's this,
that's the representation.
We talked about the egyptian story the
other day,
right?
We talked about isis and those cyrus.
So there they are cobras.
Their tails are twined together because
he,
they emerge out of that.
That's the dragon of chaos that
manifests itself as culture in nature.
That's the representation.
That's unbelievably cool.
So,
okay,
so anyways,
back to back to,
uh,
to the mesopotamian story.
So absent entire amount or they're
primordial deities,
nature and culture there in twined
together and they give rise to the,
to the,
to their first category of children.
and those are the,
I think you could think about them as
the elder gods.
Now what do they represent?
Well,
the question is what did the gods
represent and they represent.
They represent sort of like primary
modes of being.
It's something like that.
So think about aries or mars' the god of
war.
Well that's,
that's a representation of single minded
aggression.
And then you can think about error oss
or venus,
which is a primary representation of
sexuality.
And you might say,
well why are those deities?
Well,
that's simple.
They live forever and they control you
and their personalities.
So that's that for that.
It's like,
yes,
obviously you know and you know that
you're under the sway of anger.
You're not in control of yourself.
If you're under the sway of of erotic
possession,
you make a fool out of yourself.
you're a tool of the power that drives
the,
the continuation of the species forward.
Hunger is the same thing.
Any primordial motivational drive we've
conceptualized in this class as a
personality,
but those are transcendent personalities
and their returnal.
They there forever.
And so that's why the greeks,
for example,
thought that human beings were just the
play things of the gods.
And the idea is echoed in the
mesopotamian story.
So then you can think about it sort of
neuro developmentally as well,
is that out of out of nothing,
out of culture and nature emerges.
Say the two year old two year old is a
battle ground of primary motivational
forces and something like that is being
hinted at in the mesopotamian creation
story.
The first,
the first progeny of the fundamental
union of chaos and order app suit and
tie math is the proliferation of these
primary motivational forces.
They're sorta like the titans or the or
the,
uh,
what did what it was that the greek gods
kept in the,
in,
underneath the mountain.
That's zeus.
What's the name of that?
They're like prime.
There are earthquakes and fires and that
sort of thing.
They're primordial forces.
Okay.
Anyways,
so these children are produced and what
happens?
They're very noisy.
They run around doing all sorts of
things.
You could think about them as grown up
to year olds causing all sorts of
trouble.
The first thing they do is kill appsu
and make their home on his corpse.
That's brilliant.
Now the story doesn't say much about
aps.
Who?
Other than that,
the culture,
daddy,
a prop primary culture data is not
elaborated up that much in the
mesopotamian story.
And I think that's probably because at
the time of the mesopotamian
civilization was new enough so that we
really hadn't mapped the mythology of
culture.
The egyptians did that much more.
And I know I told you that story first,
but that's just how it goes.
So the elder gods make their,
their home on the corpse of absolute
well,
what does that mean?
Well,
that's,
that's sort of how he is.
You inhabit the corpse of culture,
right?
It's the dad passed and,
but,
but it's not just the dead past.
One of the things that's very cool about
the mesopotamian story is that the elder
gods are foolish enough to kill it.
It's the death of god by the way.
It's,
it's no different from what nisha
pronounced.
This has been going on for a very,
very long time.
This collapse of belief systems,
they kill it carelessly because they
don't understand what it is that they
need to survive it,
kill it carelessly,
carelessly,
and then they try to live on the corpse.
I think that's what the postmodernists
do,
by the way,
because they assume we have this,
this tremendous system of value.
That's been built up across time and it
sustains us and everyone is criticizing
it and criticizing and trying to destroy
it as well.
We live in it's corpse and that will
nourish us forever.
It has to be replenished and there's
nothing in the postmodernist philosophy
that can act to replenish anyways.
They kill app.
So what happens when you kill order?
Chaos comes back.
Tie a math.
Now this is time out
here,
feminine,
but also the dragon.
So it's,
it's,
it's you think out of this fundamental
reptilian treasure bearer culture and
nature emerge and they can pull back
into that very rapidly.
So here's an example.
You've all seen sleeping beauty.
I presumed the.
How many of you have seen sleeping
beauty?
The disney film?
How many of you haven't?
Okay,
so there's a couple that habit.
There's a scene in sleeping beauty where
the evil queen has,
has imprisoned the prince who's going to
wake sleeping beauty up.
So he's the logos so that he's the,
he's the heroic individual or he's that
element of her consciousness that wakes
her up.
You can read it either way.
She's got him trapped in a dungeon.
So she's the kind of ultimate,
ultimate eatable mother,
you know,
she's the mother that has her 40 year
old son in the basement who's overweight
and unhealthy and watch and watching
video games and being covered with
cheeto dust and she always liked feeds
him sandwiches so we won't leave,
you know.
And she says,
oh,
it's good thing you didn't go out in the
world and make some poor woman
miserable.
So anyway,
so that's the evil queen.
He's got the hero trapped in the
dungeon.
So he goes out,
he escapes,
and then she goes after them to try to
bring them back and turns into the
dragon.
That's what happens in sleeping beauty.
So that's that reversion of the,
of the arChetype into it's even more
primordial force.
so anyway,
so timeout.
Matt is kind of an amalgam of feminine
nature and also this more underlying
primordial assemble.
So anyway,
she is not happy.
She is not happy that these,
her children killed her husband.
And so she thinks,
oh well enough for these creatures.
We're gonna,
we're gonna do the men.
So flood myth,
it's the same idea.
So what happens in the story of noah,
this happens worldwide,
is that human beings get all corrupt and
make a lot of racket and break all sorts
of rules,
and god thinks,
oh well,
you know,
now for you,
we'll just bring in a flood and wipe it
all out.
That's chaos returning.
You destabilize order too badly.
There's a flood and that brings with it
all sorts of new things because it's
water,
but it just drowns you,
drowns you.
Now noah is a good man so he can ride
out the flood.
He's the hero that can go down into the
chaos and then back up because he,
he hasn't let go of his morality despite
the fact that the entire society has
disintegrated.
So he sAves everything.
So it's like moses crossing the red sea
and then coming out the other side.
Same,
same sort of idea anyways,
so tie amount.
She's a,
she's not happy and these gods are
careless to it.
Impulsive.
They're making a lot of noise and their
activity disturbs her.
You know,
when you can see echoes of that fear,
that mythological fear in modern
consciousness,
because we tell ourselves the same
story,
right?
The story is if we keep running around
making enough racket,
mother nature is going to take offense
and wipe us out.
And that's the story that's at the
bottom of the sort of apocalyptic
element of the global warming.
Um,
uh,
apocalypse.
It's like if we,
if we mock about badly enough,
nature will take its revenge.
Okay,
fine.
It's true.
It's so,
it's a story that's always been true.
So anyways,
the gods are making a lot of noise there
being impulsive and then they make the
fatal error of killing app suit.
And that's a big mistake.
And so taya,
matt,
thanks all right.
Now for this,
she wakes up and she thinks I'm going to
wipe them all out.
Now the,
these gods,
they are gods say,
I mean they're not trivial characters,
but they're pretty worried because there
are gods but tie.
matt is their mother.
She gave birth,
she is mother nature.
And if she's angry about it then the
jigs up.
And so what time does is she prepares
this army of monsters and that they're
described,
there's,
I think,
13 different kinds of monsters in their
chi,
merrick images,
they're images of,
you know,
they're,
they're like dragons,
they're half snake and half bird,
half animal,
and they're monstrous images and there's
sort of the mesopotamians attempt to
images typically represent those things
that might come forward as an onslaught.
And so generates a whole
13 major monsters and then puts a whole
army behind him and she elects one of
them king who is his name as had
monster.
So he's,
for all intents and purposes,
he's an early representation of sate and
he's like king of the bad guys.
And it's,
it's important to know about him because
if something happens later in the story.
So,
so timeouts,
preparing her army of monsters to chi
maris to wipe out the,
the gods.
And so they're like shorting out about
this.
But while they're doing it,
they're still making a lot of rocket and
living the high life and absolutes
corpse and,
and propagating.
And while they're doing that,
they send out one god after another to
combat time out and they all come back
failed.
So whatever these elder gods are,
whatever they represent,
they're not whatever it is that can
confront chaos successfully and prevail
there powers,
but they're not whatever that is,
that ultimate power.
And that's what the mesopotamians were
trying to figure out who or what is king
of the gods and king of the gods is the
thing that confront chaos and regenerate
order.
So,
so they keep producing new gods and one
day they produce martin,
he's bored in martech is a whole new
category of god and every one of the
gods knows it and he's got some very
strange attributes.
One of them is he could speak magic
words and so when martin speaks,
the night sky transforms into the sky
and vice versa.
So he's,
he's the verbal capacity.
It's a massive discovery.
It's a massive discovery by the
mesopotamians because it's the first
time we know of that,
the idea that it's the capacity for
communicative speech as the primary
daddy should be at the top of the
dominance hierarchy.
It's one of the most remarkable
discoveries of the ages,
and he also has eyes all the way around
his head.
So martech is the thing that can speak
and see,
and it's the thing that's.
So all the gods think,
wow,
well this is a whole new thing,
man.
How about you go out and combat tie
matt?
Well,
it doesn't sound like much of a picnic.
You know the logical thing for any
sensible god to say his.
How about no,
but marta doesn't say that.
He says,
look,
I'll make you guys a deal.
You get yourself together in a whole,
you know,
and you have a vote for all intents and
purposes and you vote me king of the
gods and allow me from here on end to
determine destiny's.
That's exactly what the rest of the team
and say,
he gets the tablet of destiny and he's
now in control of it.
So the mesopotamians are working out
this idea that it's the thing that can
see and that can talk.
That should be the thing that guides
destiny.
Especially if destiny involves having to
go into combat with chaos itself and
restructure the world,
and so martin says,
those are the terms,
I'll do it,
but I'm king of the gods and they all
think,
well at the fool is going to go up there
and get killed anyway,
so you know,
what do we have to lose?
And so they agree and so martin goes out
to combat
time out and he takes a net and a sword
and he,
if I remember correctly,
he fills her with a wind,
which is I believe,
part of the manifestation of this voice,
this voice idea.
He fills her with a wind.
He encapsulates her in a net.
Now think about what that means.
You know,
psychologists even used this word
phrase,
normal logical net and a normal logical
net is this is the network of concepts
that you use to encapsulate something
new in idiation structure.
And so the idea of putting something in
a net is to put boundaries around it,
right?
And to constrain it.
And so some of that's actually,
well you can capture a predator in a net
and then cut it up,
but there's no difference between that
there.
There's a,
there's a tight analogy between that and
encapsulating something novel in a
conceptual network,
which then enables you to cut it up into
something useful.
Okay?
So that's what happens.
Martin goes out,
he,
he confronts timeout,
he overcomes the monsters and he kills
king.
And so and then he makes,
he cuts time,
hit into pieces,
and he makes the world.
And that's the world that human beings
live on.
And he makes the human beings to serve
the gods.
Okay?
So that's the first part of the story.
Now we also kills king knew and he makes
human beings out of the blood of king
knew.
Now that's a hell of a story,
right?
Cause king who was king of the demons
and human beings are the creature that's
made out of the blood of the king of the
demons.
And it's a very similar idea to the
idea,
the later sort of egyptian and judaeo
christian ideas that there's a satanic
element to being that is also
characteristic of human beings.
And part of that is,
well,
what's the difference between human
beings and every other element of being?
And the answer to that is,
human beings can deceive you,
right?
We're the only creatures that can do
that.
We're capable of deception,
voluntary deception.
We're capable of malevolence.
And so that's echoed as well in the
story in genesis because when adam and
eve eat the apple,
they wake up,
the scales fall from their eyes.
They recognize that they're naked and
they know the difference between good
and evil,
which means they can do evil.
And I took me a long time to figure that
out.
Why?
What that meant?
So imagine because there is a causal
sequence,
say the snake offers you something that
you ingest,
it wakes you up.
The scales fall from your eyes.
So now you can see the first thing you
do is you realize that you're naked.
What does that mean?
Well,
human beings stand upright.
They're the most vulnerable part of us
is front and center to be hurt,
but also to be judged right.
To be naked is to be.
That's terrifying.
You want to not die.
You want to cover yourself up,
and so that's the recognition of
nakedness.
but then you might say,
well,
why does the knowledge of good and evil
emerge from that?
As soon as you know you're naked and
vulnerable,
you know how to hurt other people.
You're not a predator anymore because
they'll just tear you apart and eat you
like they don't want you to suffer.
Although they don't care.
They don't want you to suffer.
They just want to eat you.
But once I know what hurts me,
I know what hurts you and then I can
turn that into an art and people have
done that,
and so that's,
that's why the knowledge of evil comes
immediately as a consequence of the
knowledge of,
of nakedness,
and that's associated with the same idea
that human beings are made out of the
blood of kengo nasty stories,
but very,
you know,
they're,
they're messing with the fundamental
structure reality.
They want to get this right.
Okay,
so one of the cool things about this
story,
so okay,
so that's martin.
Now,
here's what's so interesting about that.
The mesopotamians,
they've got this story about the deities
and how they organized themselves to
respond to the emergence of chaos and
how to master you.
You go after it.
You declare yourself the thing at the
top of the dominance hierarchy,
your eyes and speech.
You go out there voluntarily,
you encapsulate the chaos,
you cut it into pieces and you make the
world that makes you talk.
God brilliant,
bloody absolutely phenomenally
brilliant.
So what happens?
That's what's happening in the heavenly
domain.
Let's say what happens in the eaRthly
domain,
the the emperor of the mesopotamians is
martin.
He's the.
He's the manifestation of martech on
earth and he has to be a good marduk.
That's this because he might say,
well,
why should you be king?
Well,
the Answer to that is,
well,
your most powerful.
Now that's not going to work.
Some other weasels will take you out.
Why should you be king?
Well,
because you pay attention and you speak
properly and you keep chaos.
At bay,
and you make ingenious things happen as
a consequence.
So that's what the bloody mesopotamians
were trying to work out.
What should be sovereign and why?
Okay,
so what did they do in the new year's
ceremony?
So imagine that there are there.
They're the king is in a walled city,
right?
So that's the kings at the top of the
dominance hierarchy.
He's the eye at the top of the pyramid
in a walled city with chaos outside.
Chaos is outside.
That's the domain of tire.
Matt at the new year's ceremony,
the old year,
we know about that.
We still have this idea.
The old year is an old man.
The new year's about to be born.
There's an intermediary period of chaos
that's new year's eve,
right?
That's the intermediate period of chaos
where all the rules are temporarily
suspended,
which is why you can go out and party
like there's no tomorrow,
new year's eve,
and before the new year is born,
the mesopotamian emperor and all of his
rent knew and the people go outside the
city on new year's eve and they take
statues that represent the gods and they
act out the,
the,
um,
the story that I just told you with the
statues.
And aS part of that,
the emperor has to take off all his
garbs,
his garments that make him king and
kneel in front of the priest.
And the priest,
if I remember cOrrectly,
slaps him with a glove.
It's something like that and tells him
that he has to tell everyone why in the
last year he wasn't a very good marduk
and how he's going to do better in the
future.
Which is exactly by the way,
what you do when you make your new
year's.
Um,
what do you call those?
Yes.
The ones who immediately break the next
day.
But it's the same.
It's this renewal idea and it happens
that it happens in the depths of
darkness in the middle of the winter
before the light comes back.
Right?
That's why it's set up that way.
So,
so anyways,
and so that,
so as long as the emperor is a good
mark,
then that's why he gets to be emperor.
and if he's not a good mark,
then,
well,
someone else should be emperor.
So,
so thAt's how that works.
And there's some representations of it
day.
So there's,
there's a time out there,
sort of a spirit matter combination.
Winged dragon,
right?
The thing that we've seen so many times,
and there's marduk,
he's got angel wings.
Um,
uh,
why the wings?
I don't know exactly why the wings,
I mean he's obviously being assimilated
to the idea of a bird.
I don't know if the idea of
the far seeing capacity of the bird was
there for the mesopotamians it's highly
probable,
but also the bird is something that
flies up above everything else.
And that can see for long distances.
So it's an aerial spirit.
It's close to god and all of that.
So,
so there is a very primordial
representation of the same thing.
Look how much imagination does it take
to see that that's the story of human
beings in countering the unknown.
You know,
when you know the code,
it just seems self evident.
Yes.
Well there is.
he's got his bow and arrow,
you know,
and he's out there fighting the monsters
of the unknown and that's part,
that's how human beings have survived.
You see?
Yeah.
That's.
And then see here,
he's writing this great big snake.
So that's another representation of the
same kind of thing.
Okay.
So let me just think for a minute and
figure out what I want to do next.
If I want to go somewhere next.
I guess what I'll do right now is I'll
just show you some additional pictures.
So we've laid out the conceptual world
to some degree right on,
and I mentioned that you can think about
it as the,
the potential itself.
That'S the dragon of chaos.
And then nature,
which has a positive and a negative
element creation and destruction and
culture,
which has a positIve and negative
emotion element.
They're reversed a because it's the
positive element of culture that
protects you against the negative
element of nature and the negative
element of our culture can be destroyed
by the new coming in from the,
from the natural world,
and then the will individual positive
and negative as well.
That's the.
That's the entire story roughly speaking
and I showed you it's manifestations and
figures like this,
so you have this is called the open
virgin or they're opening virgin because
that those two halves can be closed,
so there's mother nature,
roughly speaking or the mother of god
and depending on how you look at it and
inside her nature culture,
the patriarchy,
the culture supports the suffering
individual who voluntarily accepts death
and mortality as the price to be paid
for being.
That's what that image represents.
It's.
It's absolutely unbelievable.
And then you see all these people at the
side here are gazing uncontrollably at
this image,
which is of course exactly what's
happened over the last 2000 years,
at least in part of the world because
there's.
There's a tremendous idea encapsulated
inside that image and the image.
The idea is something like the voluntary
acceptance of suffering is key to it's
transcendence and that's,
that's a,
that's a crucial psychotherapeutic
truth,
right?
Things that bother.
You need to be confronted voluntarily.
You have to accept them.
You have to accept that.
You think,
well,
how far does that go?
While we don't know,
it works in small things that works with
phobias,
it works with traumas.
Traumas are usually associated with
death or disease or malevolence.
So that's pushing it pretty far.
There doesn't seem to be a limit to the
due to the idea that the voluntary
confrontation with the things that are
terrifying is curative.
There doesn't seem to be a limit to
that.
There's an example in the story of
exodus when moses is leading the
israelites through the desert,
um,
they fragment because while they're out
of tyranny,
so they don't know what to do.
It's all chaotic.
And you know,
this moses character,
yeah,
he got them out of Egypt,
but now they're in the desert and
there's nothing to eat and like why
should they listen to him?
And so they start worshiping all sorts
of idols and that's kind of like the
fragmentation of what holds them
centrally together.
And so what does god do?
He is not very happy about that.
So he sends a bunch of poisonous snakes
into the desert to bite the ball.
Any thanks enough for these people.
And that's chaos returning right in the
form of these poisonous snakes.
And so the,
the israelites are kind of sick and
tired of being bitten by a poisonous
snake.
So they go back to moses and they say,
well,
you know,
I know we've wandered off the path here
and we didn't think you were the
greatest guy there for awhile,
but you know,
maybe you could have a little chat with
god and see what he could do about these
poisonous snakes.
And so,
so moses in treats god to do something
about the snakes and what god tells
people to do.
It's the strangest thing.
He says,
make a snake in the image.
Make a broad snake and put it on a post
and have everyone look at it.
And everyone who goes to look at the
snake won't be bitten by the poisonous
snakes anymore.
It's so,
it's,
it's crazy.
That idea.
It's crazy.
So,
and I'll tell you something else else
that's very interesting.
So in the,
in the christian story,
christ assimilates himself to that snake
that was put on the post in the desert
says exactly the same thing that,
that,
that has to be looked at because that's
the pathway to salvation.
Roughly speaking,
it's exactly the same idea.
It's the worst thing that can possibly
happen.
So you look upon it and meditate upon
it.
And that's the key to transcending it.
Well.
So that's the idea that's encapsulated
in that image.
So it's,
you know,
it's no wonder that these ideas had to
be expressed in images because they're
so unbelievably complicated that they're
almost incomprehensible.
So they'd come out first in the image
and they come out first in the story
because they're just.
And plus,
they're so difficult to believe what the
last thing you would think if you are
being bitten by a poisonous snakes was
that you should make a bronze image of
one and put it on a stick so that you
could go look at it.
I mean,
there's a magical element to that,
but it's psycho therapeutically.
Exactly right.
So I had this client and she had a dream
about what she was.
She was having a really rough time and
she,
she was a pretty good dreamer.
She had this dream that she was walking
down a road by,
there's a ocean on one side and there
was a sort of sand dunes on the other
side.
And she looked up and there was this guy
with a huge python that had,
that had been out there showing it to
everyone.
And uh,
she took a look and he invited her to
come and take a look at the snake.
But she refused and walked on.
And so she told me that dream.
She was also quIte imaginative.
So I said,
look,
let's,
let's try something.
First of all,
tell me about the snake handler.
And she said,
well,
he's kind of a charlatan.
He's a show off.
He's a,
he's a fake.
And I'm afraid that if I went up to the
crowd and where the snake was,
that they would force me to touch it.
And so I,
I thought,
okay,
so that's why you walked by,
said,
okay,
so let's play a game.
So you sit there and bring that dream
image to mind.
Close your eyes,
bring the dream image to mind,
but let's play with it a little bit.
It's like young technique of active
imagination.
Let's play with it a little bit.
So go up there,
you know,
imagine that you go up there and you
kind of have to do this like you're
daydreaming,
you know,
you can't force it.
You have to play with it like you would
when you're daydreaming,
which is you're kind of half doing it
voluntarily and it's half manifesting
itself.
It's kind of a gateway between you and
the collective unconscious.
That's another way of thinking about it.
And anywayS,
I said,
okay,
so go up there and the first thing we're
going to do is figure out what are you
going to do if the crowd tells you that
you have to touch the snake or get close
to it because she needed a defense
because it isn't up to other people to
force her to do that.
So we,
we practiced what she might say,
no,
I'm,
I'm comfortable here.
I'm just going to stand in the
background.
Just didn't look at it and get
accustomed to it.
I don't need you to push me forward.
And so she felt pretty good about that.
So that kind of armed her with a
defense.
So then she could pretend to go up And
take a look at the snake.
And I said,
well,
the first thing you should do is take a
look at the snake handler and see if
he's who you think he is.
And so she did that in her imagination.
She said,
no,
he's,
he doesn't seem to be sharp at all.
He's got this snake that is is,
you know,
something he takes care of.
And he just has come out here to show
the people,
let people look at this snake.
And so she said,
son,
I said,
well,
is he,
is he someone that you can trust or
someone you shouldn't trust?
You have to ask both those questions
because otherwise you're leading the
witness,
right?
You don't want to tell people what to
think.
You have to let them figure it out for
themselves.
So,
and she said,
no,
I think he's somebody that that can be
trusted.
And I said,
okay,
well,
so what do you think that you could go
up there and,
and,
you know,
maybe lay your hands on the snake and
touch this.
And she said she wasn't sure about it,
but we went through it and she was able
to do it.
And so it's the same.
So she had to,
she had to make contact.
She had to voluntarily make contact
with,
with the terrible snake that's at the
bottom of being.
that's at the bottom of the tree of
existence.
Right?
That's where the snake is.
It's wrapped around the tree.
Well,
why?
partly because we lived in trees and
that's where the damn snakes were down
there on the ground where we didn't
know,
right?
And that's the divine tree of being that
and so,
well,
you have to get the hell out of the tree
and go confront the snakes.
And then that's the,
that's the way out,
at least in principle.
So that's kinda what that means.
Um,
show you.
Here's another image of the same thing.
What I like about this.
See the fact that the,
the,
the culture of the patriarchy,
god,
the father will say here is,
is holding the,
the suffering individual in his arms and
that's encapsulated by nature.
It's,
it's very much like the story in
pinocchio where Japan auto pinocchio
wasn't able to go down into the depths
to confront the terrible monster at the
bottom of being without having support
from his father.
Even though his father ended up trapped
inside the whale.
If he wouldn't have been supported to
begin with,
he wouldn't have been able to do it.
And you know,
I've really seen this and I've really
seen this in people.
It's a hell of a thing not to have the
confidence of your father.
It's really,
really hard on people.
You know.
If your father is someone who says to
you,
you can do it.
I really believe that you can do it.
I'll support you in what you're doing.
I think that you can sort it out and
then alex towards you in that way.
That's a gift that really almost no one
else can provide you with.
Mothers obviously provide.
I think they provide the same kind of
gift,
but earlier you know because the mother
has to take care of the infant when the
infant is just completely dependent and
so,
and this is erickson's idea to Eric
Erickson is the mother is,
is the person who establishes the
relationship that allows the developing
person to manifest trust.
Real truck while you're being carried
for crying out loud,
you know you can be dropped and the
mother is also the source of food,
but the father seems to be something
like the.
And I'm being.
I'm obviously parsing these things
farther apart than they can be need to
be because the farther can play a
nurturing role in the mother complained,
encouraging role,
but we'll.
We'll keep it simple for now.
The father seems to be the thing that
supports and encourages.
It says,
well,
yeah,
you know,
you're little and small and all of that
and you're subject to destruction and
and,
and bullying and social pressure and all
that,
but I know you can do it.
I know you can do it and there's a force
in that that's unbelievable and people
who don't have that half a have a hell
of a time.
IT's actually one of the things that's
quite fun about doing psychotherapy
because you get people who have damaged
father figures.
It's harder with a damaged mother figure
a because it's so bloody deep.
You know?
I had a client who I just,
I just thought she was a remarkable
person,
but her relationship with her was really
disrupted.
That was really,
really hard to.
She say she would.
She,
she told me it was like something had
been torn out of her at an early age
that couldn't be replaced.
It's because you just can't be someone's
mother,
you know,
it's really hard.
You're just Not there enough for that,
but you can sort of be someone surrogate
father that's a,
that's a role you can play later and
that's what educators do at least to
some degree,
although now they're trying to be
mothers and providing safe spaces and
all of that,
which is not really all that appropriate
so that.
So the father is an encouraging figure
and allows the Individual at least in
principle to support the catastrophe of
being voluntarily.
And so anyways,
so those,
you know,
those images,
they're just be are brilliant beyond
belief.
Absolutely brilliant.
Beyond belief.
Okay,
well that's probably a good place to
stop.
And so,
so we've got through the,
the to fund these two fundamental
stories,
remembering the egyptian story.
You have much more development of the
figure of cyrus who's equivalent to
absolute and the egyptian sort of walked
through how the state becomes corrupt
and deteriorates and what the individual
has to do in relationship to the state
as well as in relationship to the chaos
itself.
So in the mesopotamian story,
it's mostly ab.
Sue's dad and marta makes a new society
out of the pieces,
but it's pretty damn implicit.
It's not detailed.
Whereas by the time the egyptians come
along,
they say,
well,
oh,
cirrus was great.
He's corrupted by seth.
He has an evil brother,
so that's the tyrannical element of the
state.
He's overcome by the evil brother,
which is the tendency of every
bureaucratic system.
EverywherE things fall apart.
Chaos comes back up.
The hero is born,
takes on the corruption of the state and
it goes into the underworld,
which is like confronting matt,
but I likE to have the stories in
parallel because one of them is the
confrontation with absolute unknown
tire.
Matt and the other is the revivification
of the state.
Even though the stories also overlap and
so in the egyptian story,
so just like marduk was the,
uh,
the mortal for the emperor,
the combination of osiris and horus was
the model for the feral and then there
was an idea that emerged out of Egypt.
This was called the democratization of
osiris and it's,
I think part of what gave rise to the
entire judeo christian idea set of ideas
because the jews hypothetically came out
of Egypt,
right?
So their thinking is very deeply
influenced by Egypt and ideas.
the pharaoh was the amalgam of osiris
and horus and they amalgam of osiris and
horus was his immortal soul.
The pharaohs immortal soul.
And the pharaoh was allowed to use the
symbolism of the conjunction of osiris
and horus.
But as the egyptian society is
developed,
the aristocracy started to get to use
that symbol.
So it started moving down the hierarchy,
the idea that it wasn't only that the
pharaoh was osiris and horus,
it was then it was the aristocracy.
And then by the time the greeks came
along,
it was all men who were part of the
political structure.
And then by the time the christians came
along,
it was no,
no,
wait a minute,
this applies to everyone,
men,
women,
and not only male and female alike,
but also not just star work,
upholders of the state,
but criminals,
tax collectors,
prostitutes,
outcasts,
everyone had this,
oh,
cyrus,
horace,
soul inside of them,
and we're entitled to be treated as if
they were intrinsically valuable as a
consequence of that.
And that's the bedrock as far as I'm
concerned.
that's the bedrock idea upon which
western civilization is predicated.
It's the sovereignty of the individual
and the individual is sovereign.
Why?
The individual is the eye that's up
above the pyraMid.
The individual is the thing that can
dominate sets of dominance hierarchies.
The individual is the thing that plays
the game,
but the metagame,
the individuals,
the thing that revivified the dead
culture,
the individual is the thing that that
goes out to combat chaos and generate
something valuable as a consequence.
And that's why it's sovereign.
Invaluable.
Now it's the foundation of our legal
system and our culture.
So,
so I think about it as the,
as a new emergence,
as an emergent property of
enlightenment,
ideals is dangerous because that's 400
years.
Who cares about 400 years.
This is forever and forever is a lot
more from grounding than 400 years.
It's not a set of rational ideas.
It's way,
way deeper than that out.
So.
Okay,
good enough.
We'll see you in a week.