Okay,
now that you've had an opportunity to
walk through a narrative,
then hopefully some of the things that
I'm going to say that are more technical
will make more sense and so what we're
going to do today,
at least in part,
is to deal with,
to start to deal with conceptualizing a
solution to the fact that the world is
too complex to properly perceive.
So what the problem fundamentally is,
is that there's a lot more of everything
else then there is of,
you know,
especially if you include in that
everything else,
all the parts of you that you also don't
understand.
And so,
um,
I want to walk you through how I think
we solved that at least in part.
And we do that by essentially by
simplifying the world.
But I think mostly that we simplify.
It has a place in which to act rather
than a place in which to perceive
objects.
And I really believe that there's a
critical,
critical distinction between those two
things.
I think that part of the reason that
there's been a continual,
that there's been continual tension say
between the claims of science and let's
say the claims of religion is because
the idea that the world as a place of
objects and as a place to act,
have to be considered separately isn't
properly understood.
Um,
I don't know.
So I'm going to try to straighten that
up to the degree that that's possible.
So I'm going to talk to you about
stories and met a stories.
And the story is this.
I would say it's the simplest unit of
useful information with regards to
action and perception that you can be
offered at a Meta story is a story about
how a story like that transforms.
And I would say we'll concentrate on the
structure of the story and then we'll
get into the structure of the Meta
story.
And that'll constitute today's today's
class.
So the first thing I want to show you,
I know many of you have seen this,
but I'm going to show it anyways.
For the longest time,
it was presumed that the longest time
say,
at least in the 20th century,
it was presumed that we make a pretty
complete model of the world and then we
act in the world and we compare what
happens to that model and as long as
it's our model and the world are
matching,
then roughly speaking,
we believe that everything is okay and
our emotions stay under control.
But if that model mismatches,
then we knew that something's up.
Now,
a lot of this work was done by Russians,
especially in the early sixties,
um,
by two Russian scientists,
vinegar,
Dova and Sokolov who were students of
Alexander Luria,
who was arguably the greatest neuro
psychologist of the 20th century.
Larry has spent a lot of time studying
soldiers from World War II that had
received head injuries and of various
sorts.
And because of that,
he could draw inferences about how the
brain worked and some of what we're
going to talk about over the upcoming
weeks with regards to brain function.
Much of it is predicated on Lauria's
work and Sokolov and vinegar Dover where
his students and they were interested in
this phenomena.
They were interested in
psychophysiological measurement,
right?
So as a,
as a way of inferring brain function.
And so psychophysiological measurement
is measurement of those physiological
parameters,
say like pupil widths or or skin
conductance or eeg that are in some ways
directly reflective of how the brain
works.
Now,
if you measure skin resistance,
skin resistance changes with the amount
that you swept and that that can change
very,
very rapidly and it changes in response
to physiological demands placed on your
body.
So for example,
if your body assumes that you're going
to leap into action for some purpose,
that it's going to open up your pores to
prepare you to keep yourself cool and
you can measure those transformations
quite accurately by measuring the
electrical resistance of the skin.
And so what you see,
if you put someone in a lab chair and
you expose themselves to different
stimuli,
you find that,
for example,
if you expose them to something that's
threatening,
say,
like a picture of a snake,
than their skin conductance will
decrease because there or sorry,
their skin conductance will increase
because they sweat a little bit more.
And it's quite a rapid response.
It can be a very rapid response.
Now,
one of the things that,
so [inaudible] or uh,
so yeah,
that's right noted was that if he is,
if I sat you down,
for example,
I put some headphones on you and I
played a tone to you that repeated
exactly the same tone that repeated at
predictable intervals that the first
time you heard the tone,
you'd produce quite a spike and skin
conductance.
And the next time a slightly smaller
spike.
And then the next time a slightly
smaller spike until after maybe you'd
heard it three or four times,
you would not respond to it at all.
And that was often regarded as
habituation.
And habituation is the same thing that
you can see in snails.
For example.
And I'm using snails as an example
because they have very,
very simple nervous systems.
So if you take a snail and you poke it,
then like it comes out of its shell and
you poke
it,
it'll go back into a shell and then
it'll come out than if you poke it again
and go back into its shell and it will
come out.
But if you keep doing that,
sooner or later,
the snail just stopped going in and you
might think of that.
It has been conceptualized as the
simplest form of learning habituation
and the behavior has tended to presume
that if a human being manifested,
a response that could be modeled by a
simple organism,
then the human being was using a
response that was analogous to that of
the simple organism.
And sometimes that's true and sometimes
it's not.
So for example,
you have simple reflexes that you know,
if you put your hand on a hot stove,
you'll jerk back and that's quite a
simple circuit.
You move your hand back before the
message gets to your brain because the
spinal cord is smart enough to mediate
reflex like that all by itself,
so you know your brain is actually quite
distributed throughout your body.
It's not just in your head like people
tend to think and so we have conserved
fast acting reflexes at various levels
of our nervous system.
They they aren't capable of
sophisticated response.
It's pretty much stimulus response
thinking about it from the behavioral
perspective,
but they have as an advantage,
incredible speed because there just
aren't that many neural connections
between the stimulus and the response
and so we have layers of response at
different timeframes that help us match
with the demands of,
of the external environment.
So Charles Darwin,
for example,
used to go into the think was museum in
England.
I don't remember the name of it.
They had a snake in there,
I believe it was a cobra and he'd stick
his face up at the glass and the Cobra
would strike Adam and he jerked back and
he tried many,
many times to master that reflexive
response to the snake.
But there was no way,
every time that thing struck at him,
he,
he jumped backwards.
Well,
you can imagine the survival utility and
a reflex like that,
but in reflexes in general.
Okay,
so back to socal off.
Now,
what he decided,
he thought if you took that tone and you
did anything to it,
that was perceptible,
right?
Because there are certain gradations of
tone that you're not capable of
perceiving,
but let's assume you took the tone and
you adjusted it enough so that it was
perceptibly louder or it was
perceptively a different frequency or
something like that.
Or even that.
The spaces between the tones,
because I said they were predictably
spaced even though if the spaces between
the tones were changed,
then when the change occurred,
the orienting reflex would be
reinstated.
You'd respond to it again and socal have
tried to vary the tone on many,
many parameters.
But no matter what parameter he varied
on,
as long as you could detect it,
perceptively,
you'd produce an orienting reflects.
So socalgas idea was that you must be
producing a complex internal model of
the world that's in concurrence with the
world and across pretty much every
perceptible dimension because if you
weren't doing that,
how in the world would you know that the
tone had changed from what you had
already learned about it and so for the
longest time,
and this was also true for people who
are investigating artificial
intelligence,
we had this idea that what people did
was make a complex model of the world
and hold it in their in their mind,
so to speak,
and then they'd act in the world and
they compare what they expected to
happen in the world with the model and
as long as there was a match,
then there was no orienting reflects.
Now the orienting reflects turns out to
be quite a complex reflex.
It's not merely an alteration in skin
conductance.
What it is in,
in,
in essence,
is the manner in which you start to
unfold your response to the unknown and
the initial stages of that are very,
very quick.
But it's hard to tell when the orienting
reflex stops and when more complex
learning begins,
they sort of shade into one another.
So the initial stages of the orienting
reflects,
are quite reflective,
but the later stages can be
extraordinarily complex.
So for example,
um,
well,
I,
I always think the example of betrayal
is the best one because it,
because it's so complex.
So imagine that,
you know,
you come home and you find evidence
lipstick or something like that.
Evidence that the person that you're
with is betraying you.
The first thing that's going to happen
is that you're going to orient,
there's going to be a real shock and
that's a reflexive.
It's very much akin to the response that
you're going to,
that you would manifest if you saw a
Predator or a snake or something like
that.
And so that's very instantaneous,
you know,
um,
and then that'll prepare you for action.
You'll get,
you'll get ready to do whatever it is
that you need to do next would be very
unpleasant thing.
But then it might take you even years to
fully manifest the learning that would
be necessary in a situation like that
because there's so many things that you
have to reconsider.
First of all,
the person might now appear to you as a
threat that's pretty immediate.
So there's a biological physiological
response.
First your body reacts first,
then you respond emotionally.
That's gonna take awhile and you know
that emotional response might extend
over days or weeks or months or even
years.
And then as you're doing that as well,
you're going to try to start to resort
out your interpretive Schema so that it
can adjust to the transformation that
this,
um,
this error on your part,
say,
or this catastrophe or this betrayal,
it'll,
it,
it has to adjust to whatever information
that event contains.
And so the orienting reflex can,
can manifest itself over an
extraordinarily long period of time.
It's best to think about it as the
initial pro part of,
of what can be a very complex learning
process.
Now that was standard.
That was a standard idea in psychology
for the longest period of time that we.
We created a detailed internal model of
world and we watched how the world was
unfolding.
We compared the two and the physiology,
the neurophysiology of this was even
understood to some degree even by the
Russians in the early 19 sixties because
they basically localized.
You could use complex eeg,
electroencephalogram technology to
localize where the orienting reflex was
occurring in the brain and basically it
appeared to occur roughly speaking in
the hippocampus and the theory of that
your brain,
your cortex,
let's say,
produced a very complex model of the
world,
an internal model and your senses,
and we're producing a model of the
external world and the hippocampus was
watching those two things to see if they
matched and if they didn't match,
there was a mismatch signal and that
would be the orientation reflects and
then your body would start to prepare,
would prepare itself for whatever that
mismatch meant,
and then you would engage in exploratory
behavior to try to update your model.
That was the standard theory.
It was very well accepted theory.
It has elements of cybernetic theory in
it,
but it was well accepted enough so that
when people first started to experiment
with artificial intelligence,
that's how they tried to make
artificially intelligent systems.
They tried to make ones that would model
the world and then act and then compare
the changes in the world to that model,
but that didn't go anywhere as it turned
out because it.
It turned out that it's so.
It's so difficult to see and model the
world that people had.
People had no idea how complex that was.
It was impossibly complex as it turned
out,
and so that's part of the reason we
don't have robots wandering around doing
apparently simple things like walking
with a walking in an environment like
this.
Now when we look at the environment,
we think,
well,
it's not that much different.
It's not that hard to look at.
It's full of objects and they're just
self evident.
There they are and we can just wander
through it,
you know,
and we don't even do that consciously to
any great degree because so much of that
perception is presented to our
consciousness without effort.
In some sense,
but the ai guys learned pretty quick
that perceiving the world was way more
difficult than anybody had guest and
then this experiment really in some sets
put a phenomenal logical put a
phenomenological punch behind that
observation because one of the
presuppositions of the orienting reflex
theory that I just laid out was that you
were very good at detecting changes,
that your nervous system would
automatically detect change anomaly,
right?
Any mismatch between your model and what
you expected.
And then while the AI guys I think
figured out first of all that that was a
big problem,
that the problem of perception was much
more complicated than that.
You know,
it's actually,
it's out of that same set of
observations in some sense that
postmodernism emerged in literature
because in literary criticism because,
well it turns out to be hard enough to
see a normal object like a chair and
part of that is,
is,
you know,
if you just do that to the chair,
it's really different than it was
before.
You could imagine how different it would
be if you tried to paint the chair under
both those conditions.
Right.
And if you were really good at looking
at it,
you'd find that even though if I asked
you what color this is,
you'd say white,
if you were actually painting it,
you'd find out that the colors of the
chair when it's in that location and the
colors in the chair when it's in that
location,
just because of the difference in
lighting are substantially different.
I think it was monet,
I think who painted a very large series
of haystacks in the French countryside,
right under in different seasons and
under different conditions of
illumination,
just because he was exploring how
radically different the same object
could be as it moved through contexts
and so it isn't even obvious why we
think this is the same object when you
move it and the answer is something
like,
well,
you can sit on it in both positions,
which is not a description of an object
by the way.
Right?
That's a description of something that's
useful.
Something that's a tool,
something that exists in relationship to
your body.
It's not an object.
And so if you think that just looking at
something like a chair is almost
impossibly difficult and subject to
interpretation,
they'd imagine how difficult it is to
perceive something like a text,
you know,
like a novel because a novel object
obviously is subject to multiple
interpretations of the interpretations
are going to depend on who else,
at least in principle on the intent,
conscious and unconscious of the author
of the time,
of the place,
of the culture,
of the language.
Then that's just on the side of the
production itself.
But then there's the reader.
It's like I've read books when I was 16
and then reread them,
say when I was 40 and the book was
almost completely different as far as I
was concerned,
partly because I knew it.
I knew what was in it the second time
and I didn't know what was in it the
first time.
And so the,
the meaning that manifests itself out of
a book is a consequence of all the
complexity of the book.
Plus all the complexity of the reader.
And so you know,
if you,
if you're reading Russian literature for
example,
and you've already read 50,
50 Russian novels,
you're going to be in a much more
difficult different.
You're going to be in a different
interpretive space than you are if say
the Russian novel is the first novel
you've ever read and so and the
postmodernists were grappling with this
w as as well as with many other ideas
that I think contaminated their thinking
and their conclusion was,
well,
you can't extract out a canonical
meaning from a text.
It's so dependent on the situation that
to say that the text has a interpretable
meaning is actually an error.
Now,
just because it's difficult to do
something doesn't mean it's impossible
and there's massive holes in the
postmodernist view as far as I think
it's an unbelievably pathological view
personally,
but.
But the thing is is that there are
reasons why it emerged and the reasons
were analogous to the reasons that the
AI project initially failed and
analogous to the reasons that this
experiment turned out the way it did.
So I'm going to show you this.
Many of you have seen this already,
but as I said,
it doesn't matter.
So the,
the,
the job,
your job here is to count the Times.
He,
there's a team of three people here
dressed in white and there's a team of
three people here dressed in black and
your job is to count the number of times
the white team throws the basketball
back and forth to the white team
members.
Okay.
So we'll just run that.
Well,
so obviously are perhaps not.
So obviously the,
um,
the number of times,
I believe that they threw it back,
they threw it back and forth with 16,
if I remember this correctly.
But of course that's not really the
issue because what happens in the middle
of the scene is that a guy wearing a
gorilla suit comes out into the middle
of the screen and pounds his chest three
or four times as credit.
He comes out quite slowly as,
as you saw.
How many of you.
Is there?
Anybody here who didn't see the gorilla?
No.
Well,
you and I presume all of you knew about
this video.
Anyways.
So,
uh,
Dan Simon who produced this video has
got a couple of other ones where he
shows that,
uh,
you know,
even if you're smart enough to see the
gorilla because you've seen the video
before,
you've heard about it,
if you make other changes in the
background,
you'll,
you'll count properly and you'll catch
the grill,
but you'll miss the other changes in the
background and they're not trivial
either.
And it's really quite remarkable.
He's produced other,
uh,
short videos,
for example,
where you'll be looking at a,
like a field and a road will grow in it,
occupying about a third of the
photograph space.
And you'd think,
well,
yeah,
you're going to see that.
Like,
you don't,
you don't.
So,
okay,
so this,
through this,
through a big spanner into the works,
this sort of experimental along with the
Ai Failures.
And we could even say the postmodern
dilemma.
It's like,
well,
everyone,
virtually every psychologist would have
predicted before this series of
experiments that there's no damn way
you'd miss that gorilla because your
nervous system was actually attuned to
change in the environment.
And like that's a big change.
And it's also a gorilla,
it's something you would really think
that you couldn't miss,
you couldn't possibly miss,
especially when it's occupying the
center of the,
of the visual field.
And so,
well this is part of a phenomena called
changed blindness and it helped
psychologists who had been studying the
visual system for a very long time
figure out,
well mostly figure out exactly how blind
human beings are because we're way
blinder than we think.
And,
and so we actually focused on much less
of the world than we think.
And we do that partly.
It's not exactly obvious how we do it.
It's Kinda like we,
we hold a still picture in our
imagination and then fill in the details
by using our central Fulvio Vision,
which has always dancing around like a,
like a pinpoint or a laser beam moving
back and forth.
And we're assembling those little
snapshots from the phobia into a
relatively coherent picture.
Maybe what happens is that a lot.
I look at you and then I look at you and
I've still got the information from
looking at you so my brain can sort of
infer that,
that that's remained stable,
but like if I look at you and I and I
pay it,
I've tried to learn how to do this
because you could look at something and
then pay attention to the periphery.
It's annoying,
but so if I'm looking at you,
I really can't make out your eyes.
I can more or less make out the fact
that you have a head.
I can see that you're an eye,
especially if you move it and so that's
what your periphery sorta like frog
vision or dinosaur vision,
it's much better at picking up movement
than it is at picking up something
that's staying still and that makes
sense because well if it staying still
then and it hasn't already hurt you,
then it's probably not going to hurt
you.
But if it's moving then you know that's
a good thing that you might pay
attention to.
And so if your periphery catches
movement,
then you'll focus your phobia on it.
It's like you go from really low
resolution to really high resolution,
so the center of your vision is
incredibly high resolution,
but then it fades into low resolution as
you move towards the periphery until
it's out here,
which would say it'd be about 170
degrees.
I really,
if I concentrate on this hand,
I can tell it's a hand mostly when it's
moving.
I have no idea what color it is,
this one I can't see at all,
and then I can probably see my fingers
now and then I can clearly see them if
I,
if I look at them with my phobia,
and so your vision is a very,
very,
very strange thing and it focusing on
something very specific and so you're
pointing your eyes at something very
specific and that's what you seem to
see.
And so,
so then that opens up a whole new
universe of questions.
It's like,
how do you decide what to point your
eyes out that that turns out to be an
insanely complicated problem.
John Burbank,
he talks about that all the time as the
problem of relevance,
but the issue is,
well,
there's many,
many things in the world.
There's an infinite number of things,
let's say,
and you're not going to be able to see
them.
That's for sure.
Even if they happen to be changing as it
turns out and so out of this mess.
First of all,
how do you pick what to look at and
second,
even if you do pick it,
how do you see it?
Because it's so crazily complicated,
so that's the problem that we're going
to try to unpack.
Now,
roughly speaking,
what seemed to have happened with the
gorilla video is you have to take that
first theory that you make a complete
model of the world and then a complete
model of the world,
which is the objects in the world and
how they're interacting,
and you compare that to the objects in
the actual world and how they're
interacting.
You have to modify that model.
You say,
well,
no,
you're certainly not making a complete
model and people should have known
better anyways,
even subjects to the limits of your
perceptions because there's all sorts of
things in the world that you cannot
directly perceive,
but what you're doing instead is it's
something like you're making a partial
model of the world,
but you're only making a partial model
of the world that you're currently
operating on that on on with some goal
in mind and you're also comparing that
to a model of the world as it's
currently unfolding.
Because the other thing that was
implicit in this is really tricky.
This is where you have to watch your
implicit assumptions.
The other thing that was implicit in the
original cybernetic theory was that you
have a model of the world that's
complete and then what you're watching
is the actual world as it unfolds,
and that's not a model.
That's just your perception of the
objects,
but that also turns out to be wrong
because your perception of the world as
it unfolds is also a model.
And so what's happening is you look at
the world,
the world you see as a model and a very
partial model at that,
and then you compare it to the model
that you expect or desire more
accurately desire.
Although the initial models were
expectation,
because if you're in the lab listening
to tones,
it's not like you desire anything,
but mostly when you're acting in the
world,
you have desires and so the experimental
constraints skewed the data in some
sense by making people assume that what
people were doing when they walked
through the world was expecting instead
of desiring anyways,
you have a model of the world that's
generated.
As you look at it,
you have another model of the world
that's something like the world that you
desire.
Then you compare both of them and they
can mismatch and they can miss match in
a way that upsets your current pursuit.
That's the critical issue.
You don't see the anomaly unless it
upsets your current pursuit and you kind
of know that too because when you're
like,
while I'm lecturing to you guys,
you know,
it was mostly you're sitting still,
but people are moving their arms and
they're moving their glasses and they're
shifting their feet and generally I
don't see any of that because what
difference does it make,
you know as it's not relevant to the
ongoing,
the ongoing,
what ongoing contract,
the an ongoing series of interactions,
it,
something like that.
So as long as you keep your movements
bounded within a,
within a range that doesn't interfere
with whatever it is that we're doing,
then I'm going to be as invisible to me
as the gorilla was when you were
counting the balls and the cool thing is
about the gorilla experiment or one of
them is that the reason you were blind
to the gorilla was because you were
counting the balls.
And so what?
That's so fascinating because what it
shows to a huge degree in unfathomable
degree to to to to an unfathomable
degree is that the value structure that
you inhabit determines what you
perceive.
It doesn't just determine what you
expect or want it bloody well determines
what you see and that that makes the
world a completely different place.
No one really expected that,
and so if you watch the basketballs you
see or the basketball,
you see the basketball.
If you stop watching the basketball,
well then you see the gorilla and so the
first question that arises from an
experiment like that is,
well,
just exactly what is it that you don't
see in the world?
And the answer is all of it.
You see so little.
It's unbelievable.
You see that tiny amount that's
necessary for you to undertake the next
sequence in your plotted movements.
Something like that,
but then that becomes very complicated
too because it isn't obvious how you can
conceptualize or how you can determine
what your next movement is because it's
not like you just add up movements and
make up your life.
It's not that simple and it's related to
the to the novel problem,
the problem of meaning in a in a
literary work,
so you imagine you're trying to specify
the meaning of a literary work.
Well,
there's meaning in the word and then,
but the word is dependent meaning of the
word is dependent on the phrase within
which it's embedded and then the meaning
of the phrase is determined dependent on
the sentence that it's embedded in and
the sentence in the paragraph and the
paragraph in the chapter and the chapter
in the book and the book and the Corpus
of books of that sort and then within
the culture and then within whatever
you're peculiar personal experiences,
all of those things nested our operative
to some degree.
When you're extracting out the meaning
at any level of analysis.
They're all operating simultaneously.
So you might say,
well,
what are you doing in this classroom?
Well,
the answer is sitting in a chair,
but that's obviously.
That's a very short term and context
independent answer,
but you're also attending to what I'm
saying hypothetically,
and you're attending to some of it and
not other parts of it.
You're thinking about some parts of it
and not other parts,
and you're also attending a class and
the class as a sequence of lectures and
that's embedded within your desire to
finish up the semester and then to
finish up the year and then to get your
degree and that you nest that inside,
whatever it is,
whatever the reason is that you're
getting your degree and then maybe
that's nested inside your career goals
and that's nested inside your life goals
and that's nested inside your ultimate
values,
which you may or may not even be aware
of,
and so I could say,
well,
you're sitting here because it serves
your ultimate values.
Well,
that's true.
It seems a bit abstract to be useful,
right?
It's.
It gets so vague out at the out at the
outermost levels that it doesn't really
have much specificity.
Right?
So it seems to lack information,
but by the same token,
if I said what you're doing is sitting
there,
it has the same problem of too
restricted meaning because of over
specificity.
And so there's some level in there that
you would,
that you would interpret as meaningful.
God only knows why,
and that's the level.
There's a natural level of perception
for that sort of thing.
So for example,
um,
when children learn to name an animal,
for example,
they'll name cat,
they don't name this species of cat or
the sub species of cat and they don't
confuse cats with dogs even though
they're both in the category for,
you know,
four legged furry mammal.
So why not call a cat and a dog?
Furry mammals.
Well,
children don't do that.
They go there,
you go to cat and dog.
And people who've who've studied the
acquisition of language have found that
there are basic level categories that
children pick up first.
And they're are often represented with
short words and the words are short
because they've been around a long time
because they seem to reflect the natural
level at which people perceive the
world.
But none of that's obvious,
you know,
it's,
I mean,
you could just lump pull at animals
together for that matter and just call
them animals,
which we do sometimes.
So anyway,
so it's very difficult to specify the
meaning level and it's not very easy at
all to figure out how we do it.
And so that's partly what I'm,
what I'm trying to unpack.
So here's,
here's part of the issue.
So let's say that you're,
you have a computer.
Yeah.
I have a story for this.
So,
um,
one time when I was in Montreal,
I was using my computer,
it's in my apartment and I was typing
out an essay and it crashed.
And so what happens when your computer
crashes?
Well,
you know,
usually you have some sort of curse and
it's interesting that you do that
because the circuit that you use to
curse with is the same circuit that
monkeys used to detect eagles or
leopards or snakes.
And so when,
when there's a bunch of monkeys
together,
you know,
they're not all preyed on by eagles and
leopards and snakes,
but you know,
there's usually a Predator in that
category for every single monkey
population.
And so when the monkeys are watching,
they have an,
an emotional adherents that the most
nervous monkey might utter first that
basically says,
you know,
hide from the Eagle,
get out onto thin branch so the cougar
can't eat you and look the hell out for
the snake.
But there's a circuit that's linked to
emotions that produces an instinctive
honor that represents that category.
And that's the same circuit that you use
when you curse and it's not the same
circuit that used for normal language.
And we know that because that circuit is
activated and people who have to Rett
Syndrome because they preferentially
swear,
you think,
well,
how,
why in the world would you have a
neurological condition that makes you
preferentially curse?
Well,
that's the reason why you don't just
have one linguistic circuit.
You have one for,
oh my God,
there's a predator.
And that's the one that will get
activated when something happens.
Like your computer crashing because you
know you're an evolved creature and so
those old circuits that were there say
30 million years ago to deal with
exceptions are the same circuits you're
using now to deal with your computer.
Why else would you want to hit it?
Right?
Because that's what you want to give it
a whack.
It's like it doesn't behave whap
aggression right away.
Well,
that's some clue as to the categorize,
categorize category system that you're
automatically using to encapsulate the
event.
Okay,
so fine.
What do you do when your computer
crashes?
Well,
first you curse and then you do the
stupid things that idiot primates do
when they're trying to deal with
something that's way too complex and
maybe you turn it on and off,
right?
And that doesn't work.
It didn't work.
And so then I thought,
well,
maybe the power bar went.
So I checked the power,
barred it.
I turned it on and off and nothing
happened.
So I brought a light behind the
computer.
The light wouldn't go on,
so I thought,
ah Ha,
I must have blown a fuse.
So I went to the fuse box and took a,
took a look,
but the fuses were fine and so I
thought,
oh,
the power's gone out.
So then I went outside and the power was
out.
None of the street lights were working
in.
The power was out everywhere and it was
seriously out because this was the time
that the almost the entire northeast
power grid in,
in Quebec collapsed.
And the reason it collapsed is because
there was a solar flare that happens
reasonably often and the solar flare
produced a huge electromagnetic pulse
because it's basically,
you know,
like a billion high million hydrogen
bombs going off at the same time.
Ninety 3 million miles away produces
this tremendous electromagnetic pulse
passes through the years.
Sat atmosphere produces a,
a spike and current in the main power
lines and blows the whole system.
And so just so you know,
assist an event like that happens about
every hundred and 50 years.
And if we had what now it would take out
all of our electronics,
like one of the big ones,
there was a big one back in the late 18
hundreds.
Everything,
satellites,
computers,
cars,
everything gone,
and so that's a big problem and no one
knows what to do about it.
One misdose by about nine minutes I
think two years ago.
So.
So that's something else to worry about
if you're inclined to worry about those
sorts of things.
Um,
okay.
So what,
what did I conclude from that?
Well,
the function of my computer was
dependent on the stability of the sun.
It's not the first thing you check out
when your computer crashes,
right?
You don't run out and go,
hey,
well yeah,
the sun still sudden still there,
no product.
I can cross that off the list.
But to me it's an extraordinarily
interesting example of the invisible
interdependence of things.
You know,
when our tendency to fragment,
what we seem to do is to look at things
at the simplest level of analysis that
actually functions.
So for example,
when you're interacting with your
computer,
you're not interacting with your
computer at all really.
You're interacting with the keyboard,
sort of one key at a time and you're
interacting with the symbols on the
screen.
But as long as the computer is working,
you don't care about it at all,
you don't give it a second thought and
you certainly don't care about the fact
that it's dependent on.
Well,
the electrical power for example,
and the electrical power is dependent
on,
you know,
I don't know how many men are out there
right now or we're out there last night
when it was freezing rain,
fixing power lines and freezing to death
while they're doing it so that your
stupid computer doesn't malfunction
while you're watching cat videos.
You know,
I mean there's this incredibly dynamic
living system that social and economic
and political that has to remain dead
stable in order for us to have access to
functional and like pure non fluctuating
electricity 100 percent of the time
because he also don't think,
well,
the stability of your computer is
dependent on the stability of the
political system.
But of course it is because if the
political system mucks up and the
economic system goes,
then people don't go work to fix things
and things are breaking all the time.
That's their normal state is broken,
not,
not working.
And so,
and that's all in some sense,
fold it up,
not only inside your computer but
actually inside your conceptions of,
of your tiny conceptions of the computer
while you're using it and you want to
get a glimpse of what the computer is
really like.
When it doesn't work,
then it's when it becomes a complex
object,
right?
As long as it's working,
then you're stupid.
Perceptions are are perfectly fine to
get the job done and that's another
indication that what you're using your
perceptions for is to get the job done
and how you specify exactly the level of
resolution that you should be operating
at.
I haven't sorted that out,
but it's something like you default to
the simplest level that moves you to the
next step.
You know?
So for example,
and generally that is what you should do
if you're having an argument with
someone that you have a longterm
relationship with.
You can start by arguing about what the
little argument is about.
Or you can immediately cascade into
whether or not you should have a
relationship with this person at all,
or even into whether or not you should
even bother with relationships,
which is,
you know,
every time there's an argument that
question is a reasonable question to
have emerge,
or at least it's in the realm of
potential reasonable questions,
but it doesn't seem useful to jump to
the most catastrophic possible
explanation.
Every time some minor thing goes wrong.
That's what happens to people who have
an anxiety disorder.
And that's what happens to people who
are depressed,
right?
They can't bind the informally.
And so what happens is it tends to
propagate up the entire system until it
takes out their highest order
conceptualizations,
you know?
So if you're seriously depressed,
maybe you'll watch a news article about
something stupid and you'll think,
Jesus,
why should I even be alive?
You know,
and,
and I'm dead serious about that.
If you score 60 on the beck depression
inventory,
which puts you way the hell up and the
depressed range,
anything that happens to you that's
negative will trigger suicidal thoughts,
roughly speaking.
And sometimes even positive things.
We'll do it because there are very few
positive things that happen that don't
carry with them some threat of change or
transformation.
So you know one mystery.
It's a big mystery is why don't you fall
into a catastrophic depression every
time something goes wrong because it's
not.
That level of analysis is not self
evident and you see this with people who
are high in neuroticism too.
You know there are trivial fluctuations
at their workplace or in their
relationships or in their health will
produce a disproportionate negative
emotional response,
but it's.
It's part of the range of normal
emotional responses.
Some people are very,
very high in neuroticism,
so everything upsets them.
Some people are very low and the reason
that whole range exists is because
sometimes you should get upset when some
little thing happens to you because it's
an indication that the whole damn
environment has got dangerous on you and
sometimes you should just brush it off
because you know it's,
it's net consequence is low,
but how do you calculate that?
Very,
very difficult question.
So you know when your computer goes
wrong.
Well,
you have to pick the proper level of
analysis to fix it and you could say,
well,
there's something wrong with the circuit
board and maybe you know,
there's a crack in one of the,
uh,
and one of the US somewhere that it's
soldered and,
or,
you know,
sometimes now when people are building
microchips,
they've run into a crazy problem.
Intel microchips keep getting smaller
and smaller and smaller.
Right?
And so the little wires,
now we're down to atomic weight or you
know,
the width of maybe 20 adams or something
like that.
But really,
really they're really getting thin.
And so that produces another problem
which no one would have ever.
No,
no,
you wouldn't expect.
And that is,
you know,
that at the quantum level,
there's uncertainty about where
electrons might be normally out.
Doesn't matter the degree of uncertainty
about where your electrons are small
enough at your size so that it's
basically irrelevant.
But down at the subatomic level where
these microchips are starting to be
produced,
sometimes electrons will be outside the
wires and that means that they're
getting so damn small that they'll short
circuit by themselves because the
electrons aren't stable enough to be
where they're supposed to be in the
wires.
And so,
well the reason I'm pointing that out is
because a problem that exists in the
system can exist at any of the multiple
levels of that system.
And it isn't obvious where to start.
And a lot of political arguments are,
are like that,
you know,
it's like,
well maybe a company goes bankrupt and
its shareholders get,
maybe a bank fails and so people can't
withdraw their money.
And one response is,
well that just shows you how rotten the
capitalist system is.
It's like,
well maybe that is what it shows.
But it seems there's,
it seems like that might not be the most
appropriate level to start.
And so again,
it's [inaudible] razor in the scientific
world,
right?
You want to use the simplest explanation
that it's not that fits the facts
because you don't organize your
perceptions by facts.
It's kind of like you want to use the
simplest tool you can possibly manage to
fix the problem so you don't.
When your car has a flat tire,
you don't buy a new car,
you,
you fix the flat tire.
If you can figure out how to do it and
so you go for the thing that will put
the tool back together with a minimum
investment of time and effort.
It's something like that and you care
about that because you have limited time
and you have limited resources and so it
makes sense for you to conserve them and
I'm telling you that partly for
practical reasons too because this is a
very useful thing to know.
If you're arguing with someone you want
to argue about the smallest possible
thing that you could argue both that
might fix the problem.
You want to really specify it.
It's like what's going on at a micro
level and what's the minimum that I
would require to be satisfied with
outcome.
And if you're.
This is especially true in intimate
relationships is like if someone's
bugging you and you want them to change,
you think,
well,
how can I be minimally bothered by this
and what's the tiniest amount of change
I could request that might satisfy me?
Because otherwise the argument will come
unglued and every time you guys try to
discuss a problem,
you'll start talking about whether you
should even be together and then you're
done because you'll never solve a
problem and then you won't be together
because you'll never solve a problem.
So okay,
so here's a way to think about
perception.
So let's say that this is the thing
you're trying to look at.
I called that the thing in itself.
Now that's a schematic of a thing in
itself.
So the thing in itself that's an old
philosophical,
a concept and I think it came from,
but I'm not sure about that.
It might be older than that.
And the thing in itself is what you
could see if you could see everything
about something,
but you can't.
So it's a hypothetical entity and maybe
who knows,
if I was looking at you like the thing
in itself,
maybe I could see every level of your
being from the subatomic up to the up to
this level of perception and then
beyond.
I could see your family relationships.
I could see how they were nested in your
societal relationships,
economic relationships,
political relationships,
the ecosystem as a whole.
Like I would see all these levels at the
same time.
Of course I don't because I can't.
What I see instead is first of all,
you're radically simplified by my senses
because they're just not acute enough to
say see you at a microscopic level and
they're not comprehensive enough to see
your connections across time.
So my sense is filter a bunch of you
from me right away and then I'm also
filtered from you by my,
by your willingness to act like I want.
Well,
we're together because that's because
you could be doing all sorts of strange
things at the moment,
but you're not.
And so you're helping me simplify my
perceptions of you by agreeing to play
the same game that I'm playing.
Well,
we occupied the same space and that's
basically politeness.
That's the mark of someone who's well
socialized.
You walk in somewhere,
you get the game,
you play the game,
and you don't scare the hell out of
everybody and that's.
That's partly how we keep our emotions
stabilized because if you're like a
Friday and you think,
well,
as long as your ego as well constituted,
you can keep your emotions under
control.
It's like yes and no.
Mostly No.
I like the Piagetian idea better,
which is if you're well socialized,
you're awake enough to identify the game
that's going on wherever you go,
and then you play that game immediately
and so to all the other socialized
primates and so then you can just
understand the game.
You don't have to understand them.
Thank God.
You could just understand the game and
as long as the game continues,
you don't have to be nervous because you
know you at least know what's going to
happen and maybe you even know how to
get what you want in that game.
And so.
So that again,
that's really we're thinking about,
because we talked about this before,
about why people want to maintain their
culture,
it hasn't just because their culture is
a belief system that helps them orient
themselves in the world.
It's because I believe system is a game
that everyone who shares that belief
system is playing and the fact that
everybody's playing means nobody needs
to get upset.
So it isn't like the belief system is
directly inhibiting the emotions.
That isn't how it works.
So and,
and it's,
it's not like the culture is just a
belief system.
It's only secondarily a belief system
man.
Mostly it's a game that people are
actively engaging in.
Now.
It's way more important than the beliefs
that go along with it.
You don't even need the damn beliefs.
That's why walls and wolves can live
with each other.
They don't know what the.
They don't have a belief system.
Exactly.
Mostly they have a set of,
they have a game.
It's the wolf game,
roughly speaking,
and all the wolves know how to play it.
And so that's that.
That's how they keep themselves
organized in their packs.
A lot of it's externalized and so
okay,
so anyway,
so the thing in itself out,
it's a very complicated thing.
It's got multiple dimensions,
multiple levels,
and then it's worse than that because it
doesn't only have multiple levels,
but all of those levels move across time
and every one of those levels shifts as
it moves across time.
And so I like to think of the thing in
itself like a symphony.
I think that's a good moral.
I think that's why we like music in
fact,
because music shows you a multilevel
reality that unfolds and Shay shifts
across time within some parameters,
right?
Because it's not just chaos.
The music has an element of
predictability and an element of
unpredictability and it has these
multiple levels and that's sort of what
what everything in the world is like.
It's what the world is like,
so this is a even.
That is just a conceptual model of the
thing in itself.
First of all,
that's only got two dimensions instead
of three because it could be a cube and
then it.
It has even a cube has three dimensions
instead of four because if that was a
cube,
adding the third dimension,
then it would also be a cube that would
transform and shift as it moved across
time and that's what the thing in itself
is,
but that's too damn complicated.
So then the question is when you look at
it,
what do you see?
And the answer is to some degree it
depends on what you want to use it for.
And so I would say,
well here,
look at the different ways you can look
at this.
You might say,
what is this?
And somebody could say,
well it's a rectangle and would you say
that's correct?
It's like,
well
it's not correct because there's not a
one to one correspondence,
but it might be a useful
conceptualization.
If you think about that as a box,
it could contain that and if you were
carrying the box you'd only have to be
concerned about the box and so that
would be fine.
That's a good functional simplification.
That ones a little higher resolution
because it says,
well,
yeah,
it's actually four rectangles and that
one says,
well wait,
think about that as an orchard that
someone's looking at from the top.
You want to figure out how walk from
south to north.
Well,
you got a little map there because you
can think of those as bars instead of
collections of dots.
Piaget showed that children will
automatically do this,
so for example,
if you take six dots and put them in a
row and you take the same six dots and
you stretch them out,
so the rows this much longer and then
you ask the child where there are more
dots.
The child will say that there are more
dots where it's longer because they're
flipping in some sense between the
perception of the individual dots and
the perception of the shape that the
array of dots makes and so the shape is
longer because you could see it as a
rectangle and so they think well longer
is bigger,
bigger.
It's more,
there's got to be more dots so.
Well what?
Then there's this one which is sort of
an amalgam of this one and this one,
and then not one.
There's that one and that's the highest
resolution model of that.
That still a simplification.
And you know,
what I like about this diagram is that,
you know,
people say,
well,
the facts are the facts and what we're
disagreeing about is your opinion about
the facts.
It's like,
no,
yes,
you have an opinion about the facts,
but the world is so horrible lead
complex that you can actually disagree
about the facts themselves.
And I think an etiology does that to
people very,
very commonly.
So I saw this movie once that Naomi
Klein made.
If I tell you the same story,
tell me.
Okay,
because I don't want to tell you the
same story,
but I might.
So she went down to Argentina after a
bunch of money had gone out of Argentina
because of financial collapse.
And she went to a factory that had been
padlocked and it was heavy machinery
factory and the workers had decided they
were gonna,
undo the padlocks and go build machines,
you know,
tail with the owner who shut it down.
And so she went down and made this movie
and follow these workers around and
showed how catastrophic their lives had
been because they'd lost their
livelihood in this big financial crash.
And so that was really interesting.
But then she went and interviewed the
Guy who owned the factory and she
treated him like he was like a cipher in
some sense.
Instead of asking him how he got the
factory,
what he wanted to do with it,
how it fit in with his life plans,
why he,
why he shut it down instead of
continuing it,
you know,
he,
she didn't get the backstory on him.
She just left him in the evil
capitalists box and went on with the
film.
And it was,
it was like,
it wasn't like what she did wasn't true,
but it was only half true.
And it was half true because she could
perceive the complexity of the workers
having sympathy for them,
but as far as she was concerned,
the the enemy,
the owner had no complexity.
He was just bad capitalist and that's
how it was left in the movie.
I found it profoundly unsatisfying
because I wanted to know,
okay,
it's like you know that these workers
are suffering.
It's not self evident that you want your
damn factory closed.
You'd think you'd want it open.
So you could be building things.
It's like,
who are you?
What are you doing?
Why is this justifiable?
Have a question about it.
Well,
you can take this infinite set of facts
and then you subject it to your filters
and you let some of the facts through
and their fact.
But what about all the facts that you
don't let through?
That's the thing.
And that's what the gorilla video shows
too.
It's like,
yeah,
you got the basketball account,
right?
But you miss the big primate.
And you might say,
well,
your priorities were a bit skewed in
that circumstance because you were
rearranging the deck chairs as the
titanic sank,
you know,
as the.
As the old joke goes,
and so it's very much useful to to think
always while you're.
It isn't just your damn opinion that's
biased,
although it is,
it's your perceptions that are biased
so
well in with your words.
It's even more so.
You say,
well,
you can't see the thing in itself
because it's too complex,
so you perceive it simpler than it is,
and some of that perceptual
simplification is dependent on your
aims.
So that's a vicious one because it pulls
the,
the value structure that you're
ensconced within,
into your perceptions.
It pulls it into the realm of facts
itself.
And then you do another.
I think about this as a compression.
You know,
you can compress a photograph by getting
rid of redundant information.
That's sort of what you're doing here.
So you're like one of these squares,
little black squares here,
black rectangles compresses all of
those.
It's like we're going to treat those as
if they're a grayish black.
Same thing happens here,
so we're blurring across them so we have
a much less hire,
much less high resolution image here,
so you take the thing in itself,
if you perceive it as a low resolution
representations and then you take that
low resolution representations and you
replace that with a word and so the word
is a twofold compression and then when
someone tosses you the word,
you unpack it into the low resolution
perception and then maybe into the world
itself.
If you can do that,
probably not.
So that's what we're doing.
We're taking the complex world,
we fold it into a simple perception.
We fold that into a word,
we throw the word to someone else and
they unpack it and the only way you can
unpack it of course is if you've had
enough similar experience so that you
have the reference for the word already
in your experience.
So which is why you have to use
simplified language with children,
right?
Because there's no point in tossing a
child a concept that he or she can't
unpack.
So
we,
we compress a very complex reality and
to have a very,
very small keyhole that's basically,
that's basically our cognitive
processing.
Okay.
So then here's the next kind of
argument.
This goes along with the science
religion argument that I was making
earlier,
which I want to unpack a little bit
more.
I think that fundamentalists and
atheistic scientists have the same
problem,
the fundamentalists.
So we could say the Christian
fundamentalists in the US make the
proposition that biblical stories,
we'll call them mythological stories,
are literal representations of the
truth,
but,
and that might be true depending on what
you mean by literal,
but what they mean by literal or what
they attempt make literal mean is that
they're in the same category of
scientific facts because they don't have
the idea that there are different ways
of approaching truth and the truth's can
serve different purposes.
They don't have a sense that your
definition of truth is actually
something like a tool rather than an
ontological statement about the reality
of the world.
And so the fundamentalists basically
make the proposition that the idea that
God created the world in six days,
5,000
years ago is literally true and they get
the 5,000
year estimate by the way,
by going through the genealogies in the
Old Testament and adding up the
hypothetical ages and figuring out,
you know how long before Moses Adam
lived and some bishop did that back in
the,
I think it was in the mid 18 hundreds.
I might be wrong about that,
but it was somewhere back about that
time and more or less that's been
accepted as canonical fact ever since.
And then the scientists say,
well yeah,
those are imperial truth.
They're just wrong.
And that's the only difference there is
between the fundamentalists and the
atheist scientists.
The fundamental say those are
fundamental scientific truths and
they're right.
And the scientists say,
while their scientific truths,
they just happened to be wrong.
Well,
I think that's a stupid argument
personally.
I mean for a bunch of reasons.
One is that the people who wrote the the
ancient stories that we have access to,
we're in no way shape or form
scientists,
you know,
modern people tend to think that you
think like a scientist and people have
always thought that way.
First of all,
you do not think like a scientist.
Even scientists hardly even think like
scientists.
But if you're not scientifically
trained,
you don't think like a scientist at all.
So one of the things for example that
characterizes your thinking is
confirmation bias.
And so if you have a theory,
what you do is wander around in the
world looking for reasons why it's true.
And the scientists does exactly the
opposite of that in the little tiny,
narrow domain where he or she is
actually capable of being a scientist
and what they have is a theory and look
for a way to prove it wrong.
But believe me,
you don't run around doing that.
I mean you,
you can train yourself so now and then
you can do that.
You know when you can learn to listen to
people,
for example,
on the off chance that you might be
wrong,
but that is by no means a natural way of
thinking,
and of course the the,
the fundamental philosophical axioms of
the scientific method weren't developed
until descartes and Bacon and who else?
Descartes Bacon.
There's one more.
Anyways,
the name escapes me at the moment,
but you can argue about when science
emerged,
but you,
you,
it certainly emerged in it's articulated
form within the last thousand years.
I think you could say even more
specifically that it emerged in the last
500 years.
Now you might argue with that and say,
well,
what about the Greeks and other people
who were fairly technologically
sophisticated or who invented geometry
or that kind of thing,
but yeah,
yeah,
bear precursors to the idea of empirical
observation.
Aristotle,
for example,
when he was writing down his knowledge
of the world,
it never occurred to him to actually go
out in the world and look at it to see
if what he assumed about it was true and
it certainly never occurred to Aristotle
to get 20 people to go look at the same
thing independently,
write down exactly how they went about
doing it,
compare the records,
and then extract out what was common and
that's a that seems self evident to us
to some degree,
but you know,
it was by no means self evident to
anyone 500 years ago and people still
don't do it,
so it's not even.
It's not plausible.
If you know anything about the history
of ideas,
it's not plausible to posit that stories
about the nature of reality that existed
before 500 years ago were scientific in
any but the most cursory of ways.
So why we have that argument continually
is somewhat beyond me.
Part of the reason is though,
that everyone fundamentalists included
really believe in scientific facts.
Even though they hate it.
They'll use computers,
they'll fly.
Computers won't work,
wouldn't work unless quantum mechanics
were correct,
like the fact that you use a high tech
device indicates through your action
that you actually accept the theories
upon which is predicated,
right?
Same as flying.
Same as anything you do in it too.
Complex technological society.
You're stuck with it.
You're reading by the lights.
Do they work?
Yeah,
they work well,
so it's really hard for people who are
trying to hold onto a way of looking at
the world that appears to contradict the
scientific claims when everything they
do is predicated on their acceptance of
the validity of the scientific claims.
It's really problematic for people and
it's problematic in a real way,
I think because one of the problems with
the scientific viewpoint is it doesn't
tell you anything about what you should
do with your life.
It doesn't.
Does it solve the problem of value at
all?
In fact,
it might make it more difficult because
one of the fundamental scientific
claims,
roughly speaking,
is that every fact is of an equal
utility,
at least from a scientific perspective.
Right?
There's no hierarchy of facts.
It's not exactly.
It's not exactly true because you can
think of one theory is more true than
another,
but that boils down to saying that it's
more useful than another,
so I don't think that that's a really
good exception.
Okay,
so fine.
You got the scientific atheist,
so on one end and you got the religious
fundamentalists on the other and what
they both agree on whether they like it
or not,
is that there's so much power in the
scientific method that it's difficult to
dispute the validity of scientific facts
and they seem to exist in contradiction
to the older archaic stories.
If you also accept them as fast fact
based accounts,
so what do we do about that?
Well,
your own scientific atheist end of
things.
You say,
well,
those old stories or just superstitious
science,
second grade,
barbaric archaic forms of science,
you just dispense with them.
They're nothing but trouble and if
they're on their fundamental aside,
you say,
well,
we'll try to shoe horn science into this
framework,
and really that doesn't work very well.
It doesn't work very well with the
claims of evolution.
For example.
Fact,
it works very badly and that's a problem
because evolutionary theory is like,
it's a killer theory and it's,
it's,
it's really,
really hard and like it's not a complete
theory and there's lots of things we
don't know about evolution,
you know,
trying to hand wave that away.
That's,
that's not gonna work without dispensing
with most of biology.
So.
So that's a big problem.
So here's another way of thinking about
it.
You don't just need one way of looking
at the world.
Maybe you need two ways of looking at
the world and I'm not exactly sure how
they should be related to one another,
which should take precedence under which
circumstances,
but one problem is what's the world made
of,
you know,
what's the world conceptualized as an
objective place made of.
And the other is how should you conduct
yourself while you're alive?
And there's no reason to assume that
those questions can be answered using
the same approach.
I mean,
physics has its methods and chemistry
has its methods and biology has its
methods.
So a method for obtaining the truth can
be bound to a domain.
So why would we necessarily assume that
you could use the same set of tools to
represent the world as a place of
objects and to represent it as a place
in which a biological creature would act
in anyways?
I'm suggesting that we,
that we don't view it that way,
that we have two different viewpoints.
Maybe they can be brought together,
although it's not obvious how,
but that it's not a tenable solution to
get rid of one in favor of the other,
and I think the reason for that is
you need to know how to conduct yourself
in the world.
You have to have a value system.
You can't even look at the damn world
without a value system.
It's not possible.
Your emotional health is dependent on a
value system.
The way you interact with other people
is dependent on a value system.
There is no getting away from it and
you'll say,
well,
there's no justification for any value
system.
From a scientific perspective.
You're going to draw that conclusion
that no value system is valid.
Where the hell does that leave you?
There is no down.
There's no APP.
There's no rationale for moving in any
direction.
There's not even really any rationale
for living.
And so people say things like that,
well,
why?
Why the hell should I care what happens
in a million years?
Who's going to know the difference?
It's like,
yeah,
true,
stupid but true.
And the reason I think it's stupid is
because it's just a game,
you know,
I can take anything of any sort and find
a context in which it's irrelevant.
It's just a rational games like
who cares if a 100 children freeze to
death in a blizzard who,
what differences is going to make a
billion years?
Well,
what do you say to someone who says that
you say,
well,
seems like the wrong frame of Reference
Bucko that's what it looks like to me.
You know,
because at some point you question the
dam frame of reference,
not what you derive from it.
And it certainly seems to me that
situations like that don't allow you to
use that kind of frame of reference.
There's something in humane about it and
that trumps the logic,
or at least it should.
And if it doesn't,
then all hell breaks loose and that
doesn't seem to be a good thing.
Okay,
so I have this quote from Shakespeare
here.
He says,
all the world's a stage and all the men
and women,
merely players,
they have their exits and their
entrances and one man in his time plays
many parts.
While it's the sort of thing that you'd
expect to dramatists to pant,
but that's how we looked at the world
and we still watch Shakespeare's plays
some hundreds of years later because
there seems to be something essential
captured in something about how people
do act.
But more importantly,
I think how people should and shouldn't
act.
Because what fund is it going to a play
that doesn't outlined how someone should
and how someone shouldn't act.
You want a good guy or a couple of them,
maybe they can be complex,
intermingling of good and bad,
you know,
that makes it more sophisticated and you
want a bad guy or a bad.
You know,
you always want to see that contrast in
either within a character or between
characters.
And it's because you want to know how to
live properly now it's how to be a good
person and you want to know how to live
in properly,
how to be a bad person so you can watch
out for people like that are so you can
figure out what that means for yourself.
It's compelling.
And that's another thing that's worth
thinking about.
Why is it compelling?
And it's compelling everyone.
That's the thing that's so cool is that
there aren't that many phenomena that
you can point to that are compelling to
everyone.
Music is close is a very rare person who
doesn't like at least some genre of
music,
no matter how narrow.
But the other one is stories.
You're hard pressed to find someone,
especially if they're younger,
who doesn't like stories.
Why is a waste of time?
Or is there something going on?
Well,
I think it's not only not a waste of
time,
it's actually the most fundamentally
important thing you can possibly do
because there's no difference between
understanding stories and figuring out
how to get along in the world.
So.
And there's a tight relationship between
the story that you inhabit that
structures your behavior and the games
that Piaget talked about that organize
people's behavior,
you know,
to some degree,
the reason that we can all sit in this
room together like this is because a
huge chunk of the value system that
guides our behavior is shared.
So I am lecturing and you're sitting in
the classroom and that distinguishes us
to some degree,
but you know that that's partly merely a
consequence of the difference in our
age.
It's the same trajectory we just
happened to occupy different positions
in a value hierarchy that we both
accept.
And so as long as you feel that that's
fair and just then you're not going to
object to it.
But I'm here in the classroom for many
of the same reasons that you're here in
the classroom.
If you look at the higher order parts of
the value structure and maybe right out
at the end of that,
because I've tried to figure out if you
push why you're doing what you're doing
right now to its ultimate limit so you
can't get a story that superordinate to
that.
It's something like,
well,
you believe that the investigation of
the world to acquire knowledge is
worthwhile.
Otherwise,
what the hell are you here for?
And even if you know 80 percent of your
motivation is to get a good stable job,
fair enough.
There's still something outside of that
because the whole culture says,
well,
you're more likely to be able to
function properly in a good stable job
if you're the sort of person who knows
how to go out in the world and forage
for information usefully.
And I think that's very much analogous
to the hero's story.
It's like you'd go out and you search
the unknown to find something of value,
and so fundamentally that's what we're
doing in the classroom and the reason we
can all organize our behaviors because
we accept that framework consciously
consciously would be,
we know how to articulate it
unconsciously.
It's,
well,
it doesn't matter.
We know how to act out the patterns,
whether we know that can say the rules
or not,
doesn't matter.
Same as a wolf pack.
We know the dam,
we know the procedures,
and you could describe them with an
articulated value structure.
Let's take a break.
Okay,
so let's go back to the complexity
problem.
See,
I actually think it's the.
In some sense it's the fundamental
problem when when you read about the
terror management theorists types and
they think that death is the fundamental
problem and that's a good argument
because it's definitely a fundamental
problem,
but I think it's a subset of the
complexity problem.
And,
and the reason I think that is because
sometimes people's lives become so
complex that they'd rather be dead.
So.
And the reason they seek death through
suicide is to make the complexity go
away because complexity causes
suffering.
If it's an controlled,
you know,
things beyond your control.
And that can happen.
You know,
if you're hit by three or four
catastrophes at the same time,
you know,
maybe you have,
oh,
the political system collapses,
there's hyperinflation,
you lose your job and you have someone
that you love or two
people die and maybe you get cancer or
something like that.
Like that.
Those things happen to people and they
just think,
well,
there's no getting out of this.
Like it's just too much.
And you know,
one of the things that's very
interesting about being a psychologist
is that what you learn if you're going
to be a psychologist,
is that people come to you with mental
illnesses.
And that's almost never true.
People come to you because their lives
are so damn complicated,
they cannot stay on top of them in any
way that doesn't make it look like
they're just going to get more
complicated.
And so then that causes the symptoms.
You know,
it's like there's this old idea.
It's sort of a metaphor for genetic
susceptibility.
Take a balloon and blow it up until it's
beyond.
It's tolerance,
it's going to blow out at the weakest
point.
Well,
that's sort of what a genetic
susceptibility is.
If I just keep adding complexity on top
of you,
at some point you'll blow out at your
weakest point,
you know,
maybe you'll get physiologically ill,
maybe it'll start drinking,
maybe we'll develop an anxiety disorder.
Maybe you'll get ocd,
maybe you'll get depressed,
whatever.
There'll be something about you that's
the weakest point and if I just push,
that's where you'll blow out.
So that's a mental illness,
but those things are almost never just
happen sometimes,
but not very often.
Usually people have just been hammered
like two or three different ways and
then they collapse in the direction of
their biological weakness and then maybe
you put them back together,
but it's almost always a complexity
related phenomena rather than a mental
illness related phenomena.
Not always,
but almost always.
So okay,
so now you've got this complexity
problem and you think,
well you deal with it conceptually and
that sort of akin to the idea that it's
belief systems that protect you from
death anxiety.
The ideas are roughly comparable,
but again that's,
that's wrong.
It's the sort of thing only a
psychologist could think about,
thank God because psychologists think
that everything about you happens inside
your head,
so to speak,
in your psyche.
But that's not true.
There's a huge chunk of you that's
outside of you completely.
And so this is a really good example.
Like,
you know,
we know the oldest cities,
this is a medieval city in France,
beautiful old city.
All cities were walled and the reason
for that was because they were places of
wealth and if you didn't put walls
around them then other people would come
in and steal everything and kill you.
So like having some walls was a good
idea.
Like the same as having walls in your
house is a good idea.
Walls between your rooms are a good idea
or borders between categories are a good
idea.
And so part of the way you simplify the
world is by building walls,
walls around your space because then a
whole bunch of things can come in and so
you don't even have to think about them.
It's not conceptual,
it's practical.
And so,
and you know,
one of the things I think I figured out
recently is the fundamental political
difference between people.
And it looks to me like the fundamental
political differences.
How many walls should there be around
your stuff?
And the ultimate liberal answer is zero.
And the ultimate conservative answer is
bring on those walls,
man.
And what's interesting about both those
perspectives,
first of all,
is that there's temperamental
contributions to them and second,
that they're both valid.
So one of the mysteries I believe that
permeates psychometric psychology right
now is why the temperamental factors
that influence politics are those
particular temperamental factors.
So there's five,
let's say,
right,
this classic,
Big Five,
extroversion,
neuroticism,
agreeableness,
conscientiousness and openness.
Well,
the biggest predictors of political
allegiance,
forget about the politically correct
types for a minute,
but on the liberal to conservative
access is that the liberals are low in
conscientiousness and high in openness
and the conservatives are high in
conscientiousness and low in openness
and so then you think,
well why those two traits?
That's the first question and the second
question is why those two traits
together,
given that they're not very highly
correlated,
right?
They're really quite independent,
so why do they co-vary along the
political oxys and I think this is the
reason I think it's exactly that is that
open people like to live on the
periphery of boundaries and they like to
break boundaries between things because
interesting things happen when you,
when you think a different way,
when you think outside of the box,
so to speak.
That's what opened people do.
They always think outside of the box,
no matter what box you put them in,
you know,
and sometimes you meet people that are
so open that they're completely
disorganized there.
Their thought process is almost
completely association like a dreamer.
They just jumped from one thing to
another and they're very interesting to
talk to.
It's very hard for those people to get
their lives together because they're
interested in absolutely everything and
their attention just flips all over the
place and so they're open and that
actually does go along with higher
intelligence generally speaking,
so and then if they're low in
conscientiousness,
they don't see any utility in order and
order like orderly people because that's
part of conscientiousness and the
biggest determiner of political belief
in the conscientious domain.
The orderly people like to have
everything in its separate place and
properly structured and so you know
their world is box inside a box,
inside a shelf of boxes and then that
shelf of boxes inside another box and
all those boxes are nice and neat and
tight.
Nothing inside the ms dot touching and
everything in every box is the same
thing and you know,
you can see that,
that you can see the utility in that and
that as far as we'd been able to tell,
is also associated with disgust,
sensitivity and disgust sent.
People are disgusted,
generally speaking,
when things that shouldn't be touching
are touching like something horrible
stuck to you,
for example,
that that produces a very visceral sense
of disgust and it's a boundary violation
because that's what disgust is.
It's indic in index is a boundary
violation and you can you how separate
people should be from one another as
individuals or in groups is an entirely
debatable issue because there's huge
advantages when people mingle and mix
and there's huge dangers when people
mingle and mix and so at some point you
say,
well,
the dangers are overwhelming.
The positives,
and then another point you say,
well,
the positives are overwhelming,
the dangerous,
and you have a continual argument about
that with yourself,
but more importantly with people have
different temperament than you know,
when the terrible temptation is to
assume that only those people who have
your temperament are correct and that's
just those other temperaments wouldn't
exist if that was true.
I mean,
if you look at it from,
just say if you look at it from a
strictly biological perspective,
so anyways,
one of the things we do to simplify the
world is to frame it physically and so
you look at this,
you've got wall number one,
and then you have wall number two,
but then inside the walls you have walls
around everything.
All these houses are walls and inside
the houses there are walls as well,
and so everything is and what you do
when you put walls around things as you
make part of the world simpler,
right?
Constantly.
If the reason you have houses so that
every buddy and his dog isn't in your
house.
You just want those few people that you
can barely tolerate in your house and
not all those other strangers and God
only knows what they're gonna do.
You'll still invite people in now and
then because maybe you're sick and tired
and bored of the people that are in your
house and so you want a little bit of
new information,
but you want those barriers to be there
so that you can voluntarily modulate the
information flow.
Okay,
so that's the first thing you do and you
know,
then you set up rules with everybody
else.
It says,
well I'm going to have some walls so you
can't come in,
but what I'm going to do is pay you for
that privilege by letting you have some
walls where people can't come in.
And so I think that's analogous.
I was thinking about the issue of
discrimination in relationship to sex
because I've been thinking a lot about
discrimination lately because everybody
thinks discrimination is a bad idea,
which is a very stupid proposition
because you're discriminating all the
time and the most fundamental form of
discrimination is choice of sexual
partner.
And so you might say,
well why should that even be allowed?
Because it is the most fundamental form
of discrimination.
So for example,
almost everyone is racially prejudice
when it comes to sexual partners.
So you think,
well,
is that,
uh,
what about,
are you,
do you use age as an exclusionary
criteria?
Probably do use physical attractiveness
only in so far as you're able,
right?
You use it completely.
If you could get away with it roughly
speaking,
but you can't because the most
attractive people aren't going to be
anywhere near you,
so you can't do it,
but you'd like to.
Health.
Yes.
Strength.
Wealth.
Yes.
Education,
definitely.
So it's unbelievably discriminatory.
And so you might say,
well why is that justifiable?
And it seems to me that it's something
like,
well,
you get to say no to me if I get to say
no to you.
It's something like that.
We've agreed that everybody gets to
discriminate on that basis and because
everybody can do it then it's fair.
It's something like that,
but it's very much we're thinking about,
you know,
I don't know if you know this,
but in Huxley's brave new world where
the family had been completely
demolished rate in children were
conceived in bottles and given an
produced in factories.
So the whole idea of the relationship
between sex and procreation had become a
taboo.
One of the Mantras,
the slogans of the society was everyone
belongs to everyone else and so it was
actually a social photo,
Paul,
to refuse to sleep with someone just as
it was a social for Paul to have any
exclusionary relationship.
Because another thing you might notice
is that there's nothing more
discriminatory than falling in love with
someone.
It's like you're special and all the
rest of you know,
so it's the ultimate exclusionary act.
Right?
And yet we presume that that's an
acceptable,
not only acceptable.
We demand that as a,
as a right.
And while that's where thinking about a
lot anyways,
okay,
so what you're doing is by,
by agreeing to this segregation and
boxing,
what you're doing is carving off little
bits of the world that are simple enough
so that someone like you can live for
some amount of time there without too
much danger and everyone agrees to do
that.
Roughly speaking because everybody needs
to engage in that process of
simplification and safety provision.
And so,
so we have towns and the towns are
nothing but boxes but inside bolt inside
boxes.
So there's a good,
a good schematic of a little little
house and you can see that even inside
the same place,
we segregate off rooms for different
purposes.
And then what's interesting too is that
we set up those rooms as a little
dramatic spaces,
right?
So you furnish them and you furnish them
with things that tell you how to behave
in that room.
So table and chairs tells you that's
where you're going to eat and that's
where people are going to sit and
they're roughly going to.
They're going to sit facing each other.
That has certain implications because
the chairs don't face the walls,
they face each other and you have a
living room where it's comfortable and
there's a fire and you know,
you're setting up little stages
basically.
So that just like kids do when they
pretend,
you know,
they all assign each other roles and
then they lay out a little drama and
that's what you do when you invite
someone over for a while.
Let's sit in the living room.
Well,
you'll probably get a drink if you sit
in the living room and hypothetically
you're going to have some conversation
and so it's a bounded place.
There are rules that apply and then you
get to have a little exploration inside
that set of bounded rules and if you're
open and you're going to discuss all
sorts of things and if you're
conservative and closed,
then you're going to discuss a very,
very small subset of things.
And so and so,
hopefully everyone will agree on that.
So that's one form of,
of binding.
Then another is while we,
we put boxes around each other when it
comes to groups.
And so this is,
I think this is a picture from the,
um,
from the Democratic convention when
Obama was elected,
if I remember correctly.
But anyways,
what happens is that people segregate
themselves into little micro groups like
Democrats and Republicans,
and they basically do that on a
temperamental grounds,
right?
Fundamentally.
And they,
and then they produce these,
these games that everyone knows how to
play.
And that's another form of
simplification.
So when you bring all these people
together at a,
at a political convention,
it's not like they all have the same
ideas,
they don't and it could degenerate into
chaos and sometimes that happens.
You get big demonstrations at these
places and sometimes people throw tear
gas and all of that,
but mostly speaking it's pretty peaceful
and the reason for that is that there's
a set of procedures in place that have
some historical justification that are
embedded within the shared cultural and
belief system and everybody goes there
and agrees to play by the rules roughly
speaking,
and so then they can elect a candidate.
It can kind of flip it down to a binary
choice for the election,
right?
Yes or no,
something like that,
and nobody gets killed usually.
So Hooray for that.
That's a hell of a thing to pull off to
be able to generate out of 300 million
people,
two people to run for the highest
office.
Then let everyone play a game to
determine who they're going to be and
then to have the bloody thing function
stable.
He through power transitions like that
never happens.
Right?
That's a complete bloody miracle and
hardly any societies have ever pulled it
off the power transition being the
really important thing because a tyrant
can be stable for awhile,
but usually what happens is he dies and
all hell breaks loose.
So I think George Washington,
I think it was George Washington that
said or had said about him,
the reason that he was a great leader
wasn't because he was president,
but because he stopped being president
and that's really worth thinking about.
So then the next thing that sort of
simplifies your world is actually your
physiological structure,
right?
And we talked about that a little bit.
Well,
you can only see things there in front
of you,
not things that are to decide or behind
you.
You know,
you can only see a very narrow.
You can only see a very narrow chunk of
the electromagnetic spectrum,
roughly that chunk that enables you to
see by sunlight and to detect ripe fruit
and that sort of thing.
So it's very evolutionarily determined
and
you see things of a certain size quite
easily because they're handy,
right?
So objects manifest themselves to you as
things because they have some
relationship to your capacity to use
them as tools and that's dependent on
your size.
You have a certain strength and not a
different strength.
You have a certain degree of
articulation.
There's some things you can represent
language.
So you have limitations that screen out
from your consideration.
All sorts of things.
And that's bad because for example,
before people discovered germs,
there was a lot of them zipping about
killing people and the fact that we
couldn't see them wasn't such a good
thing.
But by the same token,
we're also not as overwhelmed with
complexity as we might be if we could
detect everything.
And you know,
one of the problems with being connected
so much is that it's easy to drown in
information and that's rough information
for Jersey can't stay off your damn
computer because there's,
you know,
it opens up your senses far beyond their
normal limitations.
And so where should you stop?
Well,
you don't,
you know,
you're on the damn thing like a,
like a pensioner on a slot machine and
for many of the same reasons.
So your body also filters out the world
for you and provides you with access to
some information and not access to
others.
And then the same thing as the case with
your nervous system.
And I do read.
I put the first picture there of the.
This is the central nervous system that
controls voluntary movement.
For example,
I put it there because people like to
think that their brain is in their head,
but it's.
It's stupid way of thinking about it as
far as I'm concerned because you have an
awful lot of neurological tissue
distributed through your body.
Like your autonomic nervous system,
if I remember correctly,
which is mostly distributed through your
body has more neurons in it than your
central nervous system.
And so you.
You aren't a brain and a in a body.
You know your,
your,
your brain is really,
really distributed through your whole
body.
And I think the idea that you have a
brain in a body is kind of a holdover
from the idea that you have a soul in a
body.
And not that I'm necessarily criticizing
that idea,
but I think they kinda got grafted onto
one another and so,
but the problem with that is that it,
and this is the so it's the soul body,
brain,
body,
mind,
body dichotomy,
which I think is the same dichotomy.
And the problem with that is that it's
easy to think of thought as something
that's abstracted away from the body.
And I think that was an enlightenment
idea.
You know that,
that,
that just like the sole shouldn't be
contaminated by the demands of the body.
If you were going to be pure
spiritually,
so your thought shouldn't be
contaminated by your subjectivity and
your emotions and your motivations and
all of that.
It should.
Your abstractions should be independent
of your subjectivity and rationality and
emotion are,
are,
are construed in that manner as enemies.
You know that the purpose of rationality
as to dispense with the irrationality of
emotion and motivation.
And that's Freud.
Freud's idea of the property functioning
ego is something like that too,
because the Ed is this place of
compulsion and and drive and the ego has
to basically suppress that in the
service of the Super Ego.
There's no idea of integration really in
Freud now.
I don't want to be rough on Freud and I
think part of the reason that he thought
that way is because the patients he had
were precisely those who weren't very
well integrated because of their
pathological past and so they didn't
know how to get those subsystems up into
the overarching game and so their only
alternative was something like
suppression or repression.
Because if you.
You know,
if you don't know how to be aggressive
in a sophisticated way,
you're still going to be aggressive,
but you're going to have to inhibit it.
Control yourself because you cannot just
be aggressive around people.
It just won't go well for you.
So even if you can't do it in a
sophisticated way,
you're going to repress it or you're or
you're gonna get in trouble.
Those are the options,
so okay,
but if you start thinking about the
brain,
the nervous system as part of the body
as an inseparable part,
well then then the function of thinking
starts to become something different.
It's not so much the object of abstract
representation of the world,
which is kind of what you're pursuing if
you're a scientist.
It's more like it's more like
conceptualization of and practice the
practice of the proper way of being in
the world and I think that's what you're
more interested in any ways.
I don't see how you can't be since
you're living thing and you're.
You're overwhelmingly motivated,
too
successfully manifest those actions that
are living thing has to manifest in
order to continue and it's complicated
like you can boil it down to survival
and reproduction.
It's a good overarching simplification,
but there's nothing simple about
survival and reproduction.
I mean all sorts of complex monsters
emerge out of that even simple
conceptualization,
but it's not unreasonable to assume that
one of the things that people generally
want to do is to continue living in as
pain free manner as possible.
It's something like that.
That's a simplification.
So now the reason I'm,
I'm making that case is because the fact
that you have a body and yet the fact
that you have a nervous system is
another set of limitations on how it is
that you're going to interact with the
world.
Okay?
So now we've got the nervous system.
We can go to higher resolution.
You say,
well,
you have a brain and the brain,
see if I can.
So that's the prefrontal.
That's the frontal cortex there.
And that's the temporal cortex there.
And that's the pridal cortex there.
And that's the sensory cortex there.
And these were,
if I remember properly,
these were divisions that I think we're
first,
while they were first thought through in
the late 19th and early,
early 20th century,
um,
they're slightly specialized.
So this cortex back heres is,
does a lot of the elaboration of vision
and that one there helps you with your
sense of embodiment and your knowledge
about where your body actually happens
to be localized.
And then that one helps for,
for example,
in some elements of language output.
And then the frontal cortex,
especially the prefrontal part,
which is up here,
is concerned with the organization and
implement the Organization of motor
action,
and that's a good way of thinking about
it.
You got part of your brain that deals
with the sensory world and the and the
integration of the century world,
which seems to happen about there are
these places meet and the prefrontal
cortex grew out of the motor cortex.
Motor cortex helps you plan and plan out
voluntary auctions.
The prefrontal cortex grew out of that
in the course of evolution.
So you might think,
well,
the there's reflex auctions and they
happen when something happens to you,
you respond and then that elaborates up
into the motor system and that enables
you to act voluntarily in the world and
then not elaborates up into the
prefrontal motor system,
which helps you plan how you might act
in the world.
Right?
So it's the prefrontal cortex that's the
home of,
let's call it.
It's complex,
sophisticated,
voluntary thought,
which you could think about as a way of
representing the world,
but which is more accurately a way of
generating avatars of yourself.
In hypothetical worlds to figure out how
they would survive if you did implement
them into action.
And so I think that's why.
So one of the weird things that you
discover psychometrically is that
there's no correlation between
conscientiousness and intelligence.
And that's a weird one,
you know,
because people think about intelligence
as planning and forward thinking and all
of that.
But that's also how they think about
conscientiousness as planful behavior
and,
and the consideration of future
possibilities.
But intelligence and conscientiousness
have zero correlation.
And so you think,
well why is that?
Well,
I guess it has to be that way because
you couldn't think abstractly if you are
prone to act out what you thought you'd
just go and act it out.
And that like when I mentioned this to
you before,
when you dream you're paralyzed and you
can take that little part of the brain
that produces that perilous paralysis
out of a cat or out of person.
But we haven't done it with people out
of a cat.
And then when the cat falls asleep and
hits Rem Sleep,
it'll run around until it runs into
something and then it'll wake up.
Oh.
So the dream thinking is so tightly
aligned with action that there's no
separation between them.
So there's no real abstraction there.
If you couldn't abstract,
you wouldn't be able to think.
And the fact that you can obstruct means
that you can separate your thinking from
your auction.
So that's why as far as I can tell,
there's very little correlation between
conscientiousness and intelligence.
It's like it has to be that way because
you have to be able to think about
things that you wouldn't do if you're
going to think so.
And in generally we think of people who
act as soon as they think as impulsive.
So
okay,
well,
so there's a huge part of the brain
that's devoted to sensory processing and
there's a huge part of the brain that's
devoted to planning and the whole
prefrontal part of the brain is devoted
to planning.
And that's again.
So what that indicates is that in large
part,
as far as your evolved body is
concerned,
the reason is that you think is so that
you can act better and of course that
makes sense and you can think about
memory from that perspective too,
because if you think scientifically,
you think that your memory of the world
is something like an objective record of
events,
of objective events,
but it's really not very much like that
at all.
And besides who cares?
You don't need an accurate
representation of all the facts about
this room.
In fact,
all it would do is weigh you down.
Who cares what color the walls are,
what kind of the ceiling is,
or what color the paint is.
All of that's not worth remembering,
partly because it has no relationship
whatsoever to what you need to do in
order to continue to act.
And so what you're doing when you
remember as far as I can tell,
is that you're mining your experience
for information that you can bring
forward into the future.
It's purely pragmatic and so you know,
my team treat people who have
posttraumatic disorder or symptoms of
posttraumatic disorder and so let's say
they got posttraumatic stress disorder
because again,
because their relationship collapsed on
them suddenly,
which is quite common.
You know,
they get betrayed or someone leaves them
suddenly and then they don't know what
to do because especially if they're
conscientious because then they just
tear themselves into pieces trying to
figure out what they did wrong to bring
about that event and the reason they're
doing that is because they want to
retool their perceptions and their
actions so that the probability that
they'll have the same experience again
is minimized and their mind won't leave
them alone until they do it.
And no wonder.
Right?
Because if you fall into a big pit and
you get really hurt,
the first thing you should figure out is
how to not fall into big pits anymore.
And your mind is set up exactly for
that.
And so what you do with someone who's
having problems like that.
So maybe they're waking up at the middle
of the night or obsessing about what
went wrong is you walk them through it.
You do a situational analysis first
because one of the oversimplifications
that people make,
and this is especially for conscientious
people,
is if something bad happened to me,
I must've done something to deserve it.
Now,
that's actually a pretty functional idea
because it suggests that there are
things about your behavior that you
could change that would make the future
better.
But the problem is is that say if it's
the collapse of a relationship and
you've been with that person for eight
years or longer,
well you did so many things with them
that the idea that you did something
wrong pretty much extends to every
single thing you ever did with them.
And that's how are you going to fix
that?
And so that's part of the trauma
actually,
that the trauma is $80,
million snakes all at the same time.
It's like,
well,
forget it.
You don't have time to go through all
that material.
And so partly what you do is with
people,
and this is what you should do with
yourself too,
is you do a situational analysis.
It's like don't be assuming necessarily
that the thing that happened to you only
happen to you because of what you did or
didn't do.
There's all sorts of factors at play.
So one of the things that sometimes I do
with clients as if they were in a
relationship and I can get some
reasonable personality information about
both of them,
I can point out where they were
temperamentally incompatible.
You know,
like if you're a highly conscientious
person and your partner is very,
very low in conscientiousness,
it's like,
well good luck to you too.
How the hell are you ever gonna work
that out because you want everything to
be exactly where it's supposed to be and
you're working all the time and your
partner could care less whether things
were were they supposed to be and
they're not going to work.
And you can butt heads about that
forever.
The probability that you're going to
shift it,
you know,
except to some minor degree is very,
very low.
And so sometimes you end up with someone
with whom you get along very well on one
temperamental dimension and you're an
absolute catastrophe on the other four
and the probability that you're going to
be able to mediate a huge temperamental
differences extremely low.
You wouldn't expect yourself to mediate
a huge intellectual difference,
right?
You're going to make the other person is
smarter or maybe you smarter depending
on who you're with.
It's like no,
probably not bit maybe.
So you do a situational analysis and so
what you're trying to do is to extract
out information from your past and your
present that will enable you to conduct
yourself properly into the future.
And so that's another example of the
pragmatic element of,
of thought.
Well then within the brain itself,
apart from the major subdivisions which
which,
which we just described,
there are minor subdivisions,
and here's a bunch of them listed,
the caudate nucleus,
the cerebral cortex,
the huge newest part of the brain that's
about a square meter.
If you unfold it,
it's all folded up and most of the
processing occurs right on the surface.
That's the idea.
Anyways,
the Thalamus,
that's a place where a lot of the
inflammation in the brain appears to be
integrated.
I'm the cerebellum helps you with
balance and the sequencing of complex
motor activities,
the hippocampus,
that's the one we talked about before.
One of the things that the hippocampus
does seems to do is compare your model
of the world as it's unfolding with the
model that that you desire to be
occurring and then keep track of
mismatches and if it detects a mismatch,
then it disinhibit other emotional and
motivational centers and that's the
beginning of your response to the
unknown.
So
one of them is the hypothalamus.
I'm going to concentrate on it for a
bit.
It's a little tiny part of the brain
that's pretty much it at the top of the
spinal cord.
C,
it's really small compared to the rest
of the brain.
Now it turns out that if,
imagine this is a cat brain for a minute
and you take off the whole cat brain,
except for the Hypothalamus,
which,
which people do you take off?
The whole cortex for example.
Um,
and then the cat still live.
If you do it carefully but it doesn't
have much of a brain and so you might
think,
well that cat would just do nothing but
cats actually pretty functional.
If it's reduced,
just do it's hypothalamus and that's
because the hypothalamus is an
incredibly important part of the brain
and it provides what I would say
constitute the major frames,
the major psychological frames and so so
I like a decorticate cat can still eat
and drink and regulate his body
temperature and engage in defensive
aggression and if it's female it can
still meet male can't because the male
mating behavior is more complicated and
as long as you keep it in a bounded
environment,
it can function reasonably well.
It's hyper curious though,
which is very weird because you wouldn't
expect a cab with no brain to be curious
about anything but a cat with no brain
is curious about everything and that
seems to be because part of the reason
that you aren't curious about something
anymore is because you've investigated
it and you've built a representation of
it that's functional and that functional
representation then stands for the thing
itself and then you can ignore it and so
you learn to ignore things there.
They're interesting to begin with and
then you learn to ignore them.
And so one of the things that I think
artists do,
if they're great artists is remind you
that there's more to things that you see
now that you've learned to ignore them.
So you get a kind of a hallucinogenic
painting of flowers like Van Gogh might
produce like his famous irises,
which I think sold for $220,000,000
or something outrageous.
It's like what Van Gogh is trying to
show you is what those flowers looked
like before you thought you could see
that because now you flower and you walk
by.
You know,
you don't see it at all because you're
off to get a peanut butter sandwich or
something.
You don't have time to glory and the
wonder of the world,
you know you've got something practical
to do,
so.
All right,
so we're going to zoom in on the
hypothalamus here and what you see of
course when you zoom in on the
hypothalamus is that it's not a thing.
It's a whole bunch of things and then
it's one of those horrible whole bunches
of things that are made out of even more
bunches of things and they're made out
of more bunches of things.
And what's really interesting about
going down the body from an analytic
perspective,
it doesn't seem to get less complex as
you go farther down.
You know,
like some of the should actually show
you that
I haven't showed you that little video
of DNA fixing itself a Oh,
I better show you that.
It's so cool.
It's ridiculously cool.
So you definitely need to see it.
Until I encountered the artworks of
David goodfellow and it was a molecular
biologist at the scripts institute and
his pictures are old.
Everything's accurate.
At all to scale and his work illuminated
for me what the molecular world inside
us is like,
so this is a transection through blood.
In the top left hand corner you've got
this yellow,
green area.
The yellow green area is the fluids of
blood,
which is mostly water,
but it's also antibodies,
sugars,
hormones,
that kind of thing,
and the red region is a slice and a red
blood cell and those red molecules or
hemoglobin,
they are actually red.
That's what gives blood its color and
hemoglobin acts as a molecular sponge to
soak up the oxygen in your lungs and
then carried to other parts of the body.
I was very much inspired by this image
many years ago and I wondered whether we
could use computer graphics to represent
the molecular world.
What would it look like?
And that's how I really began.
So let's begin.
This is DNA and it's classic double
helix form and it's from x Ray
crystallography.
So it's an accurate model of DNA.
If we unwind the double helix and
unzipped the two strands,
you think see these things that look
like teeth,
those are the letters of genetic code.
The 25,000
genes you've got written in your DNA.
This is what they typically talk about,
the genetic code.
This is what they're talking about,
but I want to talk about different
aspect of DNA science and that is that
the physical nature of Dna and it's
these two strands that run in opposite
directions for reasons I can't go into
right now,
but they physically run in opposite
directions which creates a number of
complications for your living cells as
you're about to see most particularly
when DNA is being copied.
And so what I'm about to show you is an
accurate representation of the actual
DNA replication machine that's occurring
right now inside your body.
At least 2002 a biology.
So DNA is entering the production line
from the left hand side and it hits this
collection,
this miniature biochemical machines that
are pulling apart the DNA strand and
making an exact copy.
So DNA comes in and hits this blue
doughnut shape structure and it's ripped
apart into its two strands.
One strand can be copied directly and
it's conceivably seen spooling off,
down to the bottom there,
but things aren't so simple as the other
strand because it must be copied
backwards.
So it's thrown out repeatedly in these
loops and copied one section at a time,
creating two new DNA molecules.
Now you have billions of this machine
right now worrying and right way inside
you copying your DNA with exquisite
fidelity.
It's an accurate representation and it's
pretty much at the correct speed for
what it's occurring inside you.
But I've out error correction,
a bunch of other things.
This was work from a number of years
ago.
Thank you.
This is where from a number of years
ago,
but when I show you next is updated
science.
It's updated technology.
So again,
we begin with DNA and it's jiggly and
wiggling their.
Because of the surrounding soup of
molecules which are stripped away.
So you can see something.
DNA is about two nanometers across,
which is really quite tiny.
But in each one of your cells,
each strand of DNA is about 30 to 40
million nanometers long,
so to keep the DNA organized,
regulate access to the genetic code.
It's wrapped around these purple
proteins I've labeled in purple here.
It's packaged up in bundles up all of
this field of view.
It's a single strand of DNA.
This huge package of DNA is called a
chromosome and we'll come back to
chromosomes in a minute.
We're pulling out,
were zooming out out through a nuclear
pore,
which is sort of the gateway to this
compartment that holds all the Dean I
called the nucleus.
All of this field of view is about a
semester's worth of biology and I've got
seven minutes,
so we're not gonna be able to that
today.
No,
I'm being told,
no,
this is the way a living cell looks down
a light microscope and it's been filmed
under time latches.
Why?
You can see it moving.
The nuclear envelope breaks down these
sausage shape things are the chromosomes
and we'll focus on them.
They go through this very striking
motion that is focused on these little
red spots within the field cell fields.
It's ready to go.
It rips apart the chromosome.
One set of DNA goes to one side,
the other side gets the other set of
DNA,
identical copies of DNA,
and then the cell splits down the middle
and again,
you have billions of cells undergoing
this process right now inside of you.
Now we're going to rewind and just focus
on the chromosomes and look at its
structure and describe it.
So again,
here we are at that equator moment,
the chromosomes line up and if we
isolate just one chromosome,
we're going to pull it out and have a
look at its structure.
So this is one of the biggest molecular
structures that you have in Lisa as far
as we've discovered so far inside of us.
So this is a single chromosome and you
have two strands of DNA in each
chromosome.
One is bundled up into one sausage,
the other strand is bundled up to the
other sausage.
These things that looked like whiskers
that are sticking out from either side
are the dynamic scaffolding,
the cell.
They're called microtubules but means
not so important,
but we're going to focus on it.
This red region,
I've labeled it right here and it's the
interface between the dynamic
scaffolding and the chromosomes.
It is obviously central to the movement
of the chromosomes.
We have no idea really as to how it's
achieving that movement.
We've been studying this thing.
They called the Kinetic Corp for over
100 years of intense study and we're
still just beginning to discover what
it's all about.
It is made up of about 200 different
types of proteins,
thousands of proteins in total.
It is a signal broadcasting system.
It broadcasts through chemical signals
telling the rest of the cell when it's
ready,
when it feels that everything is aligned
and to go for the separation,
the chromosomes.
It is able to couple onto the growing
and shrinking microtubules.
It's transiently,
it's involved with the growing of the
microtubules and it's able to translate
couple onto them.
It's also attention sensing systems able
to feel when the cell is ready,
when the chromosome is correctly
positioned,
it's turning green here because it feels
that everything is just right and you'll
see there's this one little last bit
that's still remaining red and it's
walked away down the microtubules.
That is the signal broadcasting system
and sending out that stop signal and
it's walked away.
I mean it's that mechanical.
It's molecular clockwork.
This is how you work at the molecular
scale,
so with a little bit of Molecular
Icandy,
we've got kinases,
which are the orange ones.
They're a little molecular Korea
molecules working one way and here are
the dining.
They're carrying that bray broadcasting
system and they've got their long legs
so they can step around obstacles and so
on.
So again,
this is all derived accurately from the
science.
The problem is we can't show it to you
any other way.
Exploring at the frontier of science at
the frontier of human understanding is
mindblowing.
Discovering this stuff is certainly a
pleasurable incentive to work in
science,
but most medical researchers,
this is just discovering this stuff is
simply steps along the path to the big
goals which are to eradicate disease,
to eliminate the suffering and the and
the misery that disease causes and to
lift people out of poverty.
Thank you.
So like that's just so ridiculously
mindblowing.
It's almost unbearable to think about
that as clockwork even as pretty strange
idea because all those little things
walk over obstacles.
It's like how the hell does that happen?
They're just molecules.
So it's so cool because when you go down
you'd think simple,
but you know,
and you know,
he said at the beginning when they were
taking the little machines,
we're taking that DNA apart that he
didn't show the error correcting.
You know,
they have these other little machines
that go along and see if everything's
okay and if it isn't,
they cut it out and put it right pcn.
It's like,
yeah,
things we don't understand.
There's no shortage of them,
that's for sure.
Okay,
so what I'm doing in some senses walking
you through a psychophysiological or
representation of Piaget's developmental
process,
I would say.
Um,
so I wanted to zero in on a hypothalamus
because it seems to me the thing that
sets the most basic frames and so we'll
go head with that.
So you see that it's made up of all
these little parts and so it's called
the hypothalamus more for convenience
than.
Because it's a homogenous set of
structures because it's not a homogenous
set of structures and this is something
to consider very carefully when you're
thinking about the terminology that
psychologists use or that you might use
to describe your own behavior.
Because you know you can roughly.
There is a psychology of motivation and
there's the psychology of the emotion
and you might think,
well,
emotion and motivation are categorically
different entities,
but they're not.
In fact,
there's no such thing as a uniform set
of motivations and there's no such thing
as a uniform set of emotions.
And the distinction between a motivation
out an emotion is unclear to say the
least.
And that's partly because the
physiological substructures that subsume
what we call motivations and what we
call emotions and it's not like there's
a motivation center that's,
Whoa,
that's a margin is the closest is the
hypothalamus,
but it's made of structures that are
qualitatively different.
And then the emotions,
because I have to use that descriptive
terminology because we have to
communicate about it somehow.
There's all sorts of different
structures in the brain that contribute
to emotional expression and they're not
even in the same place,
much less,
much less composed of identical
structure or function.
So you know,
we have these shorthands that we use to
divide up the world,
but they're,
they're awkward and untenable as the
level of resolution increases.
But anyways,
I'm still going to go with motivation
and emotion because it's a useful
simplification.
But you can see with the hypothalamus
that there's all these complicated
little subsystems in there.
And then I showed you that video to show
you just how complicated this subsystems
are all the way down to the relate to
the molecular level.
How those little machines manage what
they do is completely beyond me.
You know,
to call it clockwork when those little
things that walk and walk over
obstacles,
it's like clockwork does one thing,
you know,
only click,
click,
click.
That's all it does.
No exceptions.
This thing walks over.
Obstacles to get where it's going.
It's like who knows what's going on down
there,
but it works well enough.
So here we are,
weirdly enough.
So motivation seems to me to be the
initial framing process and you come,
you come into the world with the
motivational systems roughly ready to
go.
You know,
babies are hungry,
babies get cold,
babies want something to drink,
you know,
so.
So the world already comes in some sense
they come into the world with
prepackaged categories for existence and
those are the categories that are going
to aid their survival.
And you know,
they're not simple either.
It's not so simple.
It's a hunger,
thirst,
pleasure,
pain,
anxiety,
you know,
the classic,
sort of the classic emotion,
sadness,
joy and so forth.
Those systems are already there,
but babies or have more complicated
systems too.
Like the system for exploration has
already in place in the system for play,
which is really complicated.
It's already in place and so you know,
you come into the world with a,
with a human nature and the nature seems
to be distributed across these
subsystems.
That's.
That's one way of thinking about it and
it's also useful to think about the
operation of those subsystems as
something like you could think about
them as games with a with an aim.
You can think about them as stories.
You can think about them as frames of
reference.
You can think about them as action
patterns,
all of those,
and you can think about them as
subpersonalities,
which I actually think is maybe the best
way to think about them because if
you're hungry,
it's not a deterministic drive fits the
sub personality that has a goal and then
it has a bunch of action patterns that
are going to work in reference to that
goal.
It has a bunch of perceptions that that
suit that goal and it organizes your
emotional responses around that goal.
And so to think about it as a
personality is a much.
It's a much more intelligent way to look
at it.
One of the thing about skinner's rats,
you know,
skinner could get rats to do almost
everything and he would reward them with
food and so he had a simple rat model,
but his rats were starved down to 75
percent of their normal body weight.
So not only were they know it's social
gregarious,
rats,
rats are because they were isolated,
they were genetically altered from wild
rats,
but they also weren't as complex as a
real route because they were starving
and so,
but you know,
a starving rat is a pretty good model of
a rat and a rat is a pretty good model
of a person.
But are a lot of our models have simple
behavior learning were based on starving
isolated rats.
So anyways,
how to think about motivation will think
about it from the hypothalamic
perspective.
So we could say one thing that
motivation does is set goals.
We could say that emotions track
progress towards goals and I'm going to
use that scheme.
I even though it's not exactly right.
So you say,
well,
motivation determines where you're going
to aim.
So if you're hungry,
you're going to aim at something to eat
and then that will organize your
perceptions so that you zero out
everything that isn't relevant to that
task,
which is almost everything you
concentrate on those few things that are
going to facilitate your movement
forward.
When you encounter those things that
produces positive emotion,
as you move through the world towards
your goal and you see that things are
laying themselves out that facilitate
your movement forward,
those things caused positive emotion and
if you encounter anything that gets in
the way,
then that produces negative emotion and
it can be like threat because you're not
supposed to encounter something that
gets in the way.
It can be anger so that you move it
away.
It can be frustration,
disappointment,
grief.
Those would,
if you had a response that serious to an
obstacle,
it would probably punish the little
motivated frame right out of existence.
You know,
so you walked downstairs and I don't
know the contracting company,
instead of wrecking ball through your
kitchen,
it's like that's going to be
disappointing.
You're not going to keep eating the
peanut butter sandwich and the rubble,
that little frame is going to get
punished out of existence and some new
goal is going to pop up and it's dead
and you know,
one of the things we're going to try to
sort out is how do you decide when
you've encountered an obstacle that's so
big that you should just quit and go do
something else because that's not
obvious,
you know,
and you can.
You can get into counter productive
persistence pretty easily.
So we don't know how people solve that
problem.
It's a really complicated one.
So anyways,
we're
going to work on that scenario.
Your hypothalamus pops up micro goals
that are directly relevant to biological
survival that produces a frame of
reference.
So it's not a goal,
it's not a drive and it's not a
collection of behaviors.
It's a little personality and the
personality has a viewpoint.
It has thoughts that go along with it.
It has perceptions,
it has action tendencies,
all of that.
You can see this in addiction most
particularly.
So one of the things that you find often
with people who are alcoholic is they
lie all the time and that's because when
they're.
They built a little alcohol dependent
personality inside of themselves or a
big one might,
maybe it's 90 percent of their
personality and one of that,
one of the things that consists of is
all the rationalizations that they've
used over the years to justify their
addiction to themselves and to other
people.
And so the addiction has a personality,
you know,
and so when the person is off or maybe
they're addicted to meth or something
like that,
where we know the addiction is more.
It's more short term powerful than I
would say,
than an alcohol addiction.
They'll say anything and the.
The words are just tools used to get
towards the goal and if they happen to
be deceptive,
whatever,
it doesn't matter.
They're just practical tools to get
towards the goal.
And then when you get towards the goal
and you take a nice shot of meth or
something like that,
you reinforce all those rationales that
you use to get the drug.
And then the next time you're even a
better deceiver and liar.
So okay,
so we're going to say motivations one
way of thinking about as they set goals,
but it's not the right way of thinking
about it.
They produce a whole framework of
interpretation.
And so we're going to think about that
framework of interpretation.
And then emotions emerge inside of that.
So that's it.
So the world is framed.
Motivations,
set goals.
You could say the world has to be
framed.
So motivation sets that frame,
cruise goals,
emotions,
perceptions and actions and inactions
track progress.
So positive emotion says you're moving
forward properly towards your goal.
And if you encounter something you don't
expect,
you stop.
That's anxiety.
It's like,
oh,
we're not where we thought we were.
And so we don't know what to do,
so we should stop because we don't know
where we are,
what we're doing.
Stop frozen.
And then the more powerful negative
emotions like pain they might make you
get out of there.
So emotions forward,
stop,
reverse.
That's your emotions within that
motivated frame.
So,
and that's another example of how your
mind is embedded in your body.
Your emotions are in like their,
their offshoots of action tendencies.
That's,
that's the right way to think about it
because action is everything
fundamentally.
So what are some basic motivations?
Uh,
most of these are regulated by the
Hypothalamus,
by the way,
that that tells you just how important
the control system it is.
The other thing that's useful to know
about the hypothalamus is that it has
projections going up from it that are
like tree trunks and inhibitory
projections
coming down there.
They're like grape vines.
So you can kind of control your
hypothalamus as long as it's not on too
much,
but if it's on,
in any serious way,
it's like it,
it winds.
So partly what you do to stop yourself
from falling under the dominion of your
hypothalamus is to never,
ever be anywhere where it's action is
necessary,
right?
You don't want to go into a biker bar
because you might find yourself in a
situation where panicked.
Defensive aggression is immediately
necessary.
You probably don't want that.
You don't want to panic,
you don't want the terror,
you don't want the frenzied fight,
you don't want any of that.
You don't want to have to run away in
absolute panic,
so you just don't go there,
and then a huge,
a huge part of how we regulate our
emotions is just by never going anywhere
where we have to experience them and so
that has very little to do with internal
inhibitory control and everything to do
with staying where you belong.
So okay,
so basic motivations,
hunger,
thirst,
pain,
pain is not regulated by the
hypothalamus.
That's a different circuit.
Anger slash aggression,
thermoregulation,
panic and escape,
affiliation and care,
sexual desire,
exploration play,
and you can kind of break those in.
You can kind of break those into a,
the classic Darwinian categories to and
say,
well,
there's a set of motivations that go
along with self maintenance.
That'd be your survival,
ingestive and defensive.
See,
I've sort of coded them there.
So the self maintenance,
there's an adjustive set of basic
motivations that go with self
maintenance.
You say that's hunger,
thirst.
There's a set of defensive motivations,
pain,
anger,
thermoregulation paddock and escape,
and then there's,
there's motivations that are associated
with reproduction,
affiliation care and sexual desire.
And then I put exploration in place sort
of outside of that,
uh,
I would say because those two things
serve both of these approximately
equally.
So what I tried to do is take the basic
motivations and then nest them inside up
fundamental Darwinian framework so that
you could see how the biological process
of evolution has manifested itself and
then sort of differentiated into these
fundamentals fundamental biological
systems.
So,
okay,
so this is a rat brain flat map.
And so it's basically what you would see
other routes brain if you flattened it
out,
unrolled it,
flattened it out,
and then made it to dimension when you
can see here,
so this is the hypothalamus and you can
see that it's made out of these
different nuclei.
That's what they're called.
And they started correspond to those
shapes that I showed you in the human
hypothalamus earlier.
And you see that there's different
systems.
There's the system for eating and
drinking is outlined in green and the
reproductive system.
There's two of them and they're outlined
in in,
I think it's red.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Reproductive is red in the defensive
ones are in Magenta and so those are
the.
You can think about those as the three
fundamental value systems of living
creatures with complex nervous systems
as far as the hypothalamus is concerned,
and then given what I told you about the
hypothalamus switches,
you hardly need the rest of your brain
at all.
As long as you have the hypothalamus,
it's worth thinking that those are very
fundamental to value per se.
Now you might think if you only need the
damn hypothalamus,
why bother with the rest of the brain at
all,
which is.
That's a very useful question,
especially because most creatures don't
have much of a brain so,
but it seems to be something like,
well,
you've gotten your eating and drinking
system,
your reproductive system and your
defensive system,
but the problem is,
is that those things,
first of all,
can conflict.
You know,
are you too hungry to sleep or to sleep?
Eat,
eat is.
That's a pretty simple kind of
contradiction.
You know,
are you more angry at your partner or do
you want sexual relations more so
there's an so they can conflict in the
present,
but then they can conflict with other
people doing the same thing and they can
conflict across time and so partly the
reason that you need the rest of your
brain is to solve the problems that
emerge from the solutions that the
hypothalamus offers and so because you
don't want to just eat and drink and
reproduce and and and defend yourself.
You want to eat now later,
tomorrow,
next week and next month.
While you're able to engage in
reproductive activity and defend
yourself in multiple contexts with a
whole bunch of people for as long as you
can possibly manage it.
And so you need the rest of your brain
to calculate that.
And so what the rest of your brain has
to do roughly speaking,
is regulate these and also elaborate
them up into like,
like into something that's integrated
inside you which might roughly be your
personality.
And then so that that personality is
integrated with the personality of other
people.
And so you can think about it as an
emergent process.
This is one of the things I really like
about piaget.
He's so damn smart because piaget is the
only thinker I know really who really
addressed the problem of the evolution
of value systems.
Now,
he never nailed it down to the
physiology because there wasn't enough
known about physiology when he did his
work,
but it maps very nicely onto the
physiology.
But you know,
he said,
well,
but he got it right.
Anyways,
he said,
you come into the world with a handful
of of a preestablished reflexes.
Okay,
we're going to complicate that up a bit.
No,
you come into the world with a handful
of micro personalities that are centered
around these fundamental motivational
axes.
Okay?
And then that gets you started and is.
And that has motor output as well as
perceptions and all of that that's
associated with it.
And then as you interact initially,
let's say with your mother,
you start to learn how to integrate
those things in some sort of social
context because you form a relationship
with your mother right off the bat and
so you're starting to figure out how to
to to produce patterned and stable
interactions between those motivational
systems on a day to day,
week to week,
month to month basis.
And one of the things you do with kids,
it's really important to do this with
kids is you want to get them onto some
sort,
some sort of a routine.
Because what the routine is actually is
the beginnings of the system that
integrates all of these underlying
biological systems into some sort of
unity because they have to sleep in,
they have to sleep and wake up.
So you want to get nailed that down.
So it's predictable,
you know,
they have to eat,
they have to stay warm and they need to
do that in a manner that's,
that's stable.
And so it's to your great benefit as a
parent that you get islands of stability
planted in the life of your kid.
So that some of this gets simplified so
that the kid isn't constantly
preoccupied with domination by these
different motivational systems and so
it's a useful thing to know because you
might think,
well,
you don't want to impose any structure
on your baby.
It's like no,
wrong.
You don't want to be a tyrant about it,
but there's no difference between that
structure and the emergence of the
child's adaptation to the world.
And to some degree what you're trying to
do is free them up from arbitrary
domination by these underlying
motivational systems.
You know,
because if the baby gets too tired,
it's a horrible little thing to just
scream at you nonstop and it's not happy
about it.
It's like it's not good for anyone for
that to happen.
And so the faster you have to do it in
relationship with the child,
even if some will sleep right away in a
schedule almost immediately and other
kids are harder to to to get their
circadian rhythms regulated.
So you have to attend to the individual
differences that characterize the child,
but you're still trying to establish
some stable harmony out of this mishmash
of initial of initial systems.
So
all right,
so,
so that's sort of a physiological look
at that.
This is more of a conceptual look at it.
So I said that each of these systems you
can think about in a bunch of different
ways.
You can think about our best,
something that sets a goal.
I'm,
I'm hungry and I don't want to be
hungry.
Point a point b.
So the hunger and the vision of the
satiation,
of the hunger,
all part of the same frame.
And so if you're hungry,
you go into the kitchen,
you know that already,
that's part of your
procedural knowledge about how the world
works and then what you're going to look
for are only those things that are
relevant to what you're trying to do in
the kitchen.
Everything else is zeroed out.
You won't even really see it.
And why would you?
You want to see the things that are
relevant to the task at hand and so that
that's the.
That's so cool,
I think because what it means is that
you see the things that are relevant to
the task at hand and so here's something
to think about.
Let's say that you see a whole bunch of
things in the world that you don't want
to see know that make you constantly
miserable and unhappy.
One thing you might ask yourself is,
are you sure that your goals are proper
because your goals determine what you
see now,
not 100 percent.
Obviously you can be thinking about the
homework you're going to do and step off
a curb and be hit by a van.
It's like you're going to get hit by the
van regardless of how you've oriented
your perceptions,
likely in all likelihood.
So I'm not trying to argue for pure
solipsism,
but it is very interesting to consider
that since you see in relationship to
what you want,
that a very large amount of what you see
is dependent on what you're aiming at.
And so one issue is if your life is
wretched and miserable.
One thing to think about is whether or
not what you're aiming at is the right
thing to be aiming at,
and so it's and nothing is exactly the
wrong answer to that.
I'm aiming at nothing,
so okay,
you're going to experience a tremendous
amount of misery and not very much joy.
So anyways,
you've got this little frame.
You're somewhere and it's not good
enough and you're going somewhere else
that's going to be better.
And what better depends upon is the
state of these underlying biological
systems and then more complex Lee,
as those biological systems get
integrated into a personality and into
the social world,
then the frame and the goal is going to
be dependent on that more complex
hierarchical organization.
So you're not in here because you're
hungry.
You're in here because if you get a
degree,
maybe you don't ever have to be hungry.
So.
So the hunger is properly incorporated
into your.
You don't want to be cold.
You don't want to freeze to death in the
winter.
You don't want to be on the street,
you know,
so your higher order goals are longterm,
socially negotiated solutions to the
problems that are implicit in your
being.
Not that might be one way of thinking
about it.
So,
so,
and the micro elements of this.
So you could say I'm hungry.
That's a physiological state and it
conception.
I have a vision of how I'm going to
solve that,
but then,
and those are,
that's an abstraction,
but what you do to transform point a and
point b is not an abstraction.
You Act,
you know,
so if you're hungry,
you actually move your body,
say down from the second floor into the
kitchen and you arrange things so that
there's transformations in the world and
that's a good way of thinking about the
relationship between the mind and the
body.
Your hypothetical solution to your
problem.
That's the mind.
But the manner in which you incarnate
that solution,
that's no longer abstract.
So you know,
people are always trying to solve the
mind body problem and that's as far as I
can tell,
that's how you solve it is you have
abstractions,
but they're not abstractions that are
representations of the world.
There are abstractions that are
representations of action patterns and
the way those are implemented in the
world is that you act them and so it's
strange because you've got this weird
level of control,
you know,
I can move my arm and I seem to be able
to do that voluntarily,
but I really have no idea how I'm doing
it.
Like I don't have conscious access
exactly to the musculature except
technically and I certainly have no idea
what I'm doing chemically to make those
muscles muscles transform,
but my,
my soul,
my abstractions ground out in this
movement and I can observe the movement
and and modern and modify it,
but I have no conscious access
whatsoever to the microprocessors that
are making that possible.
I have no idea why that is.
Probably because I'm not smart enough.
That would be my guess right?
Is you're only going to.
Evolution is only going to allow your
mind to control those elements of your
being that you're smart enough to
control and so you don't get voluntary
control over your heartbeat,
for example,
because you just forget and then you'd
be wandering around and then you'd
forget to beat your heart bag and you'd
be dead so you don't get to do that.
So all right,
so all these different classified,
these again is self propagation and self
maintenance motivations and so if you're
too hot while you want to go somewhere
cooler and if you're too cool,
you want to go somewhere hotter.
Same if you're thirsty and hungry and
for self propagation while you're get
lonesome and maybe you know you have
some sexual desire and and each of those
different systems competes for access to
this central frame and that's something
like the contents of your consciousness
at any given time.
So up pops a desire,
but it's wrong way of thinking about it
because a desire sounds like something
that's pushing you forward,
but the desire is goal,
framework,
emotion perception,
action pattern,
all at the same time.
It's a little personality or it's a
little story actually,
when you describe the operation of one
of these things,
that's when you're telling a story,
so I was somewhere I needed something.
I went and got it.
It's boring little story,
but that's the basic unit of a story,
right?
Because I don't care to hear what you're
doing unless you had a reason for doing
it.
I just say what's the point of the story
and the point of the story is the point.
It's directional,
right?
It says,
I went from here to there.
That's the point.
Here's how I did it.
That's the point,
and you're interested in that because
maybe you want to know how to do it too
and you won't have to struggle through
it like I did.
You could just listen,
and so we're always throwing these
little units of information back and
forth to each other and for good reason.
I.
I want to know what your point is
because better I learned it from you.
Then make all the mistakes that you had
to make when you were learning it and
human beings.
We've got that figured out.
That's for sure.
So okay,
I'm
going to just explain this and then
we'll stop.
All right,
so we're in one of those frames now and
we're going from point a to point b and
so the question is how does the world
lay itself out?
Okay.
So the first thing to understand,
and this is partly the reason I showed
you the gorilla video,
is that the first thing a frame does for
you is make almost everything irrelevant
and that's so great because that's what
you want.
You want almost everything to be
irrelevant because otherwise you're
going to be so flooded with information
that you.
That's what hallucinogens do,
at least in their initial stages,
is they take away that filter and make
everything relevant.
You can read about that in Huxley's
doors of perception.
He does a great job of describing that
initial stages of a masculine experience
and what happens is that all of the
memory in some sense that regulates is
perceptions is stripped off and so he
sees everything glowing and alive and
magical like,
like he'd never encountered it before.
Which is exactly how you would see
something.
If all your memory about it was gone and
so he sees things as way more complex
and interesting than he normally sees
them,
while that's fine,
but if you're like that all the time,
then you end up in a ditch starving to
death or something like it's not
commensurate with normal life.
That's what it looks like,
and so your perceptions or just shrunk
and restricted to the bare minimum
necessary to keep you moving in the
direction that you're moving.
All right,
so the first thing you want to do is you
want to make things irrelevant.
Now,
if you're with someone in a
relationship,
partly what you want them to do is to
help you continue making most of their
possibility irrelevant.
It's polite because one of the things
you so,
so you say,
well,
we have a friendship.
Let's say we have a friendship.
Okay,
so that means you're going,
you've agreed to act in a friendly
manner towards me and to support me.
There's all sorts of other ways you
could act like a myriad of them and I'm
going to do the same for you.
So were simpler to each other than we
would normally be and then you go and do
something that betrays me.
It's like bang,
that whole simplification has gone and
all those parts of you that were
supposed to be irrelevant because we
were playing the same game,
they're dead relevant and I don't know
who the hell you are.
And so that's really rough and people do
not like that.
It's this emergent mismatch between
their desires and the way the world is
manifesting itself.
So one of the issues of complexity is
that when you hit an obstacle,
everything that you have agreed with
other people to make irrelevant,
irrelevant.
And that's generally a disconcerting
experience.
Now you can,
you know,
you might want a toy a little bit with
that interrelationship,
you know,
so maybe you encourage your partner to
dress differently or you go do different
things or something because you don't
want to be stuck in exactly the same old
rut.
And so what you'll agree is how you can
both deviate and interesting amount,
but that's
voluntary and controlled.
It's not the same at all.
It's having that little massive 80
million snakes pop up right in front of
you,
which is the last thing you want to have
happen and so it's so weird because one
of the things that we're striving to do
constantly is to keep most of the world
irrelevant and our cultural systems are
designed precisely for that purpose and
part of what you do when you disrupt
them is you force people to consider a
far more range of relevance than they
are even vaguely comfortable or vaguely
competent to manage and it just burns
them to a Chris.
Because what your body does is if all of
a sudden everything around you is
irrelevant.
Like I could say you're stripped naked.
I take you to helicopter jumped,
drop you right into the middle of a
jungle at midnight.
It's like you're not bored standing
there,
frozen,
paralyzed.
Everything is interesting.
Well too bad for you because to
interesting is very little different
from terrifying.
And so you know,
your heart rate's going to be at one
slash 60 for like two days and then
something will eat you and your problems
will be over.
So.
Alright.
So this diagram basically suggest this
is,
this is how you break up the world when
you're going from point a to point b,
you read,
it renders almost everything we
irrelevant,
hooray.
And then what happens is the rest of the
world is broken up into obstacles that
get in your way and tools that
facilitate your movement forward.
And that's actually what you see when
you come into a place like when you come
into this room.
These are obstacles in so far as you
can't walk through them and those are
tools in so far as you can sit on them
and watch the class.
This is a tool and these are tools and
this is a tool and I'm a tool for,
although I'd never admitted,
but anyways,
um,
I'm a tool of because you need to take
this class in order to advance towards
your,
towards your degree.
And so basically what you see in the
world or entities that functional
significance and those are not objects,
they are not the same thing.
So,
and that's,
that's very much worth considering
because see,
we're trying to build up a case,
at least in part,
for analyzing the nature of the
structures within which you organize
your perceptions and we tend to think
that those are predicated on object
perception.
It's not true.
They're predicated on relevance.
Conception.
Does it help you?
Does it get in your way or is it
irrelevant?
That's what you want to know.
If it helps you,
you're happy about it.
If it gets in your way,
you're,
you're negatively predisposed towards
it.
If it's irrelevant,
it's invisible.
And so if you're,
if your little scheme is functional,
your little frame is functional than
most of the things that you encounter
are mildly positive.
And that's how you know that you know
what you're doing.
That's how you validate the entire
frame.
So.
Okay,
good.