So today we're going to delve a little
bit more deeply into the realm of
symbolic representation and I'll,
I'll tell you what I think I'm doing and
then we'll show you a bunch of examples
of it.
Then I want to tell you a couple more
stories and so I'll tell you the stories
in the second half of the class.
So you know,
it was Carl Jung who popularized and
differentiated the idea of archetypes.
They weren't his idea platonic forms or
an I are,
are archetypes essentially.
Ideals are an archetype.
And so,
but young,
the thing that I think he did that,
that hadn't been done before was to
suggest that he as well as suggesting as
Freud did,
that human beings are composed of sub
personalities.
You pointed out as I did to some degree,
that some of those personalities have a
universal character and so that they can
be thought about as transcendent
entities.
And you could think about those while
they have been thought about it,
even put forward as gods of one form or
another.
Um,
now when you talked about archetypes was
never clear what he meant and
everything.
The reason for that was because the
archetype is a very complicated idea and
a very complicated phenomena and you can
think about it biologically and you can
think about it socially and you can
think about it as something that the
individual participates in creating,
so it's not that easy to localize it and
and as well it's not that easy to
localize it and as well
[inaudible] was never clear about what
the universe of archetypes look like at
some time.
He spoke as if they were a relatively
small number and then at other times he
spoke as if they were innumerable and I
think the reason for that is in part it
depends on the level of analysis,
right?
The more transcendent the archetype,
the fewer there are.
They are,
but they differentiate because you might
say,
well,
how many hero archetypes are there?
And one answer could be one,
but they differentiate all the way out
into the diverse range of works of
fiction that we have.
So you could say there's as many
variants of the hero archetype roughly
speaking as there are works of fiction.
So you think about it as a hierarchy
with the ultimate archetype at the top.
So then another question might be,
what does the landscape of ultimate
archetypes look like?
And I think that that's.
Well,
that's what I tried to lay out and
that's what I'm trying to lay out in
this diagram.
So now why do you want to know that
there's a practical reason or way?
There's a number of practical reasons as
well as intellectual reasons.
One of the most relevant practical
reasons as far as I'm concerned,
is that integrating narratives and so
those would include political
narratives.
Integrating narratives have their forest
because they draw on universal
archetypes,
otherwise they wouldn't have any power,
right?
Because they're basically stories,
an integrating archetypes like the story
that people that Hitler sold the Germans
or that the Germans and Hitler
cocreated,
which is a much more accurate way of
thinking about it that had motive force
because it had an archetypal essence.
And so political stories derive their
power from the underlying archetypal
representations that obviously because
they have to be concerned with the
things that people find important.
Right?
Well,
how can you sell a political message to
someone if it isn't about something they
find important and if it's important to
them,
it's going to be grounded at least to
some degree in their biological,
uh,
in,
in their biological substructure,
mean if you're talking to hungry people
about food,
it's a story that you can tell,
right?
Because it,
it,
it hooks them deeply,
it hooks them in,
hooks deep into their motivational
systems to talk,
to use a narrative of Utopia,
which is the land of milk and honey,
roughly speaking a very,
very old idea.
You're also tapping deeply into
intrinsic human longings.
And so the idea that political
narratives incorporated archetypal
themes is,
is not really,
it's not an idea that I would consider a
particularly controversial.
Putting it that way might be okay.
So the problem with political narratives
in my estimation,
is that they can rapidly transformed
themselves into a theologies and
ideologies are dangerous for variety of
reasons,
but the primary reason for their danger,
I think this is a hypothesis,
is because of their one sided nature.
What happens is that they capitalize.
Paris.
Otitis,
I think is even a better way of thinking
about it,
a,
a profound underlying narrative,
but they don't tell the entire story and
so then if you're looking for
orientation in the world because you are
fragmented and chaotic and somebody
provides you with a partial story that's
going to serve an integrating function
and it's very.
One of the things you see in
psychotherapy is that if you're chaotic
and confused and you go see a therapist
who has a particular kind of practice
Friday and behavioral,
cognitive rigidity and whatever,
there's a high probability that
undergoing that course of therapy is
going to be good for you and that you
might even come to view your life in,
in the,
uh,
in the terms of that therapeutic
practice.
You might say,
well,
why?
Why is that therapeutic practice right
for you?
Maybe,
maybe it could have been Rogerian
instead of Freud and say,
and the answer to that is,
yeah,
well,
it probably could be,
could have been because roughly
speaking,
any coherent ordering principle is
better than none.
And so that's also a good way to think
about human development from a
intellectual perspective is that partly
what has to be provided to individuals
as they mature into an adult adults.
It's some kind of ordering structure,
and this is one of the fact that people
who criticize the dogmatic element of
religious belief don't really
understand.
They don't understand that you can't.
You have to provide people with a
determined that structure of support of
some type,
even if it's constricting and
restricting and crushing for that
matter.
You have to pass through a disciplinary
structure before and even in principle,
you could be free before you're
disciplined.
You're not free,
you're just chaotic,
and so you have to practice some set of
routines and rituals.
Now you could say,
well,
they don't necessarily have to be
religious and they could be secular.
You could become a lawyer,
you could become a plumber.
You can become a carpenter.
And I would say yes,
that's far better than not becoming
anything,
but the problem with an identity that
isn't rooted into the archetypes is that
leaves you incomplete because the
archetypical routing of the identity is
what helps you grapple with the
fundamental existential problems of life
and whether you're a carpenter or a
plumber or a lawyer,
they're still going to.
Your soul is still going to hunger for
some deeper form of identity and you're
not going to get that without being,
without having your practical identity
encapsulated in something that's that's
greater from a philosophical perspective
and perhaps even deeper than philosophy,
which is I think the archetypal stories
are there.
The.
There are the structure within which
philosophy itself is embedded and
outside of that as a behavioral
structure,
we've talked about how those evolve.
You know there's there's behavioral
evolution of something approximating a
consensual morality and then stories
about that consensual morality emerge
and that inside that the structures of
philosophy,
nest and all of those things have to be
addressed by your identity to some
degree or you're weak.
That's the problem.
You'll be sent by doubts.
You're be by anxiety,
your easy to stop and you don't have
much motivation and none of that's good.
It's not good at all because life
presents you with enough real obstacles
in the fort,
in the face of genuine suffering so that
unless you're strongly grounded and have
a real mood reason for moving forward,
you're going to get stopped and as soon
as you stopped,
you are one miserable thing because
it's.
It's almost like the definition of human
misery is to be paralyzed by anxiety and
emotional pain and also have no motive
force forward.
It's a terrible state and so you don't
want to be in that state and you have to
have an identity that's powerful enough
and deeply rooted enough,
so the most profound doubts that might
emerge about your life are met by
something of equivalent force.
Okay,
so we're going to review the symbolic
domain and briefly and then I'm going to
show you a bunch of different examples
of how it plays itself out.
Partly architecturally and symbolically,
but also partly politically because I
want to show you how both of those
things,
how those things parallel one another
and partly what I'm hoping
is that understanding the full domain of
archetipal symbolic representation will
also inoculate you against ideological
possession because you'll know when
you're told a half sided one sided
ideological story,
you'll know that there's something
missing in the story.
There's,
there's,
there's paces that aren't being told or
there's part of the story that isn't
being revealed.
So if it's a story about his tout
tyrannical modern culture is and how
oppressive you think.
Well yes obviously,
but what about the beneficial aspect of
it and how is that being represented and
dealt with and and so.
And it's the same story about the
negative element of the human being
which you hear stories like that all the
time because I think perhaps more
intensely since the 19 sixties,
but,
but because I wasn't around before then,
I don't know what it was like previous
to that.
There is this idea that people hold and
it's promoted that there's something
fundamentally no cancerous about human
beings.
The it was the club of Rome.
I think when they pronounced it,
everyone on the planet was going to die
of starvation by the year 2000.
That human beings were no better than a
cancer on the planet.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
you know,
there's lots of things about us that
could be improved,
but when you,
when you portray the human only as
negative,
the question should arise.
It's like,
fair enough,
but what about the positive part?
Why aren't you telling that story and it
doesn't take you,
you know,
all you have to do is be sick once and
go to a hospital where you get competent
care to understand that you know,
and you can get in competent care to,
but sometimes you get really competent
care.
You think?
Yes,
it's really good that there's some
people out there who have their act
together and are trying to put things
together.
You know,
when you can't forget that in your story
and you,
you don't want to forget that in your
story about yourself either.
So,
so what is the fundamental landscape?
While the basic idea is that it's,
it's,
it's predicated.
You can look at it multiple different
ways.
It's predicated on the contrast between
explored an unexplored territory or the
contrast between the interpretive
structure,
but philosophers like Kant talked about
and the real world manifestation that
underlies under whose existence
underlies the validity of empirical
thinking,
right?
There's you and your structure.
You interpret the world,
but there's also the world informing you
and so that's the explored territory
versus unexplored territory,
something like that,
or it's order versus chaos or it's or
it's another variant of that would be
it's the hero going out into the unknown
to Qa,
to encounter the dragon of chaos and to
gather the information that is out there
in the unknown and,
and,
and I tried to make the case to you
because I'm often accused most recently
on Sam Harris's podcast of making up
post hoc stories.
You know,
you have a set of stories.
You can interpret them any way you want.
Of course that is a danger because you
bring an interpretive structure to bear
on every set of facts.
How do I know that this isn't just an
arbitrary post hoc analysis and my
answer to that,
it's a technical answer is it manifests
itself at multiple layers of analysis
simultaneously and the probability that
it's merely an imposition of an a priori
interpretive structure is decreased by
the number of different levels of
manifestation that you can detect the
phenomena.
It's,
it's an.
it's axiomatic.
That's why you have five senses.
That's why,
because they need to report a different
level.
That's why in science use multiple
methods to detect the same thing.
So one of the things I tried to point
out is that you can map this archetipal
structure onto brain structure quite
nicely even onto hemispheric structure
and the function of the subcortical
systems,
but even more particularly,
you can map it onto the function of
specific neuro psychological systems
within the.
Within the,
within the biological neurology,
we do have an interpretive structure,
right?
That's your map,
so to speak,
of of expectation and desire in the
world.
That's your model.
There's a brain area of roughly the
hippocampus.
Although this is an oversimplification,
it compares that with incoming sense
data,
which is also a model,
but we won't get into that for the sake
of argument,
so that's explored territory,
unexplored territory and the thing in
the center doing the comparison,
that's the knower and so,
so it's strikes me as a highly unlikely,
although you're welcome to criticize a
way that you will see that kind of
stacking of evidence across multiple
domains of inquiry without there
actually being a pattern there,
so it's not merely post hoc analysis and
even the people who derive these
patterns like young to begin with.
Let's say look cross culturally at least
to say,
well,
here's,
here's a manifestation of a pattern and
here's a separate culture and you can
see the same pattern.
So there's some attempt there to be
methodologically rigorous.
He did the same thing with people's
fantasies and dreams and then again,
by mapping those onto people's behavior
and therapy also had them test out the
ideas in the world.
So these aren't just trivial
methodologically as people make them out
to be.
And especially that's the case when you
can put a biological underpinning
underneath them,
so the proposition is explored
territory,
unexplored territory and the explorer
roughly speaking,
and then a differentiation of those two
things into positive and negative.
Why?
Because everything complex has a
positive and negative element and so
explored.
Territory explored territory can become
stultifying and crushing.
That's tyranny,
but it's also provides the structure
that informs and protects you and
unexplored territory.
Well that that can kill you obviously,
but it's also the place that you need to
go when you're static and dead and you
need new water and you need new life and
you need new information,
so it's constant movement out into the
unknown and back out into the unknown
and back,
and that's what human beings are like,
right?
We're information foragers and then the
individual is both positive and negative
and you know that
because you know yourself and you know
other people and you know yourself,
you can be.
There's parts of you that are that are
good classically speaking or good even
by your own definition and other parts
that really could use to say the
minimum,
a tremendous amount of work and you also
know that about other people and if you
get truly unlucky with yourself or other
people,
it won't merely be that you're not
trying hard enough.
You'll encounter something in you or
someone who's absolutely malevolent and
bent on destruction,
and that's also not a hypothesis.
You know,
the the literature on post traumatic
stress disorder reveals quite quite
clearly that people typically develop
posttraumatic stress disorder because
they encounter some form of malevolence
and if it.
If it's ever happened to you,
you know that it's no joke.
It's not some figment of your
imagination.
Quite the contrary.
So and then that entire world that's
sort of the world that can be
comprehended is nested inside a broader
symbolic network and that seems to be
the symbolic network that's made up of
the dragon of chaos,
which is something like our
representation of the set of unknown,
the set of all currently unknowable
things.
It's a very strange category,
right?
It's like the category of zero or the
category of infinity and the reason that
we formulated that category is because
we don't only want to know how to solve
a problem,
just like we don't only want to know how
to win a game.
We want to know how to win this set of
all possible games and we want to solve
the set of all possible problems.
And so what human beings have been
trying to do for the last forever is
trying to figure out how to solve the
problem of the set of all problems.
And we actually have some ideas.
One is playing to win the metagame and
not the game.
That's one solution.
Another solution is go out into the
unknown voluntarily and gather the
information that lies there because that
continually updates you.
Um,
the other one is to make sacrifices.
And that was discovered in an articulate
form not very long ago.
And the idea of sacrifice is something
like,
well,
you don't just have to solve the problem
of how do you survive in the present,
which is roughly the problem that
animals are always trying to solve.
You have to solve the problem of how you
survive in the present,
given that you also have to survive next
week,
next month,
next year,
and among other people and answer that
in part is the answer of sacrifice,
which is to give up something that you
desperately want now that would even be
useful right now so that you accrue more
benefit across a broader span of time.
A very,
very difficult lesson for animals to
learn.
Animals have a terrible time learning
that,
but even human have a terrible time
doing it because there were some real
intelligence in getting while the
getting is good,
but it's a sub optimal strategy.
If you can stabilize the environment and
spread out your adaptive capability over
wider spans of time,
while so much the better you get what
you need now and you get what you need
later and you get what you want and so
does your family and other people at
much better solution.
But that requires.
It requires precisely sacrificed because
it requires sacrificing the present for
the future.
And that idea of sacrifice emerged like
all of our ideas,
first in in action,
in acting these things out,
and then conceptualizing them with our
bodies like Indorama,
just the way that piaget described
children first,
assimilating the structure of their
parents' actions by imitating them
rather than by breaking them down into
systems of rules,
understanding the rules and
incorporating the rules.
That isn't how we work,
react and figure things out in action.
Then we imitate our own actions.
And to imitate your own actions is to
act yourself out or to act other people
out.
You can do that without having explicit,
articulated knowledge and that's it's so
crucial to understand that because it
it,
it explains great mystery,
which is how can we tell the stories
that have meanings that are deeper than
we know?
And the answer to that is we have
information encoded in our behavior that
transcends our understanding well how
well we're constantly modifying each
other constantly and the world's
constantly modifying us and there's no
reason that wellbeing modified.
We should also be able to track how it
is that we're being modified.
We have to figure that out afterwards
and it's extraordinarily difficult to
look at a whole culture or even a single
individual and to say,
well,
what is that person?
Or what is that societal structure?
It it.
It supersedes our conscious capacity for
representations were always playing
catch up.
That doesn't mean that we don't act out
things.
We think sometimes you know,
the,
the causal pathway can't go the other
way because it can,
but more,
more frequently.
It's bottom up rather than top down,
which is how everything works in the
biological world.
Animals do and have wisdom,
but they don't know what they do and
they can articulate their wisdom,
so it's self evident that a process like
this must've occurred.
I mean,
I was talking about wolf dominance
behaviors online the other day and
somebody tweeted and said that it's the
only captive wolves that dominate each
other through aggression.
It isn't necessarily the most aggressive
males that are dominant in the wild.
And I thought,
well,
yes,
I know that that's what the wall has
already documented among chimpanzees.
The thing that emerges as as appropriate
to lead and then to be imitated as
leader isn't untrammeled aggression.
It's some process that is a kin to my
interests and your interests matching
over some period of time with all of us
considered simultaneously,
right?
That's some equilibrated state of social
behavior embodied even in the behavior
of wolves,
the behavior of rats,
who,
who knew how to play fairly.
The behavior of chimpanzees and
certainly in our own behavior,
much more complex be in no small part
because our social structures are much
bigger than those of animals,
so therefore much more complex.
Robin Dunbar has indicated,
for example,
that one of the best predictors of brain
size predictors or correlates more
likely what are the highest correlates
at brain size,
especially at.
I think he only looked within primates,
is group size and that makes sense,
right?
Because the complexity of the social
organization increases dramatically as
the number of individuals involved
increases,
and I wouldn't say it's group size,
brain size,
that determines groups.
How is it's brain size determines group
size,
determines brain size,
determines group size in a loop,
and and many other factors are involved
in expanding cortical representation as
well.
So as far as I can tell,
there isn't anything contentious in
those claims and it gives us,
gives us a basis out of which the
archetypal stories can emerge and it
explains why we can see revealed truth
in them so to speak.
Because the truth was instantiated in
the behavioral realm,
not in the conceptual realm and through
the you know,
you,
you see this in your own life.
You Watch yourself and one day you go,
Aha,
that's what I've been up to this whole
time.
That happens to people in therapy all
the time.
Or you're dealing with some other person
and they tell you something.
It's like,
it's like the last piece fell into
place.
He said,
Oh,
I had you completely wrong.
Now I get what you're up to.
And what's happened is my representation
has become more complete,
but it also matches your behavior
better.
There's a concordance between what I've
observed and what actually manifests
itself and so while so for the
derivation of of wisdom,
from the observation of behavior,
you do the same thing when you analyze a
shakespeare play,
you know Shakespeare play never
happened,
but Shakespeare extracted out patterns
that happen all the time and if he
hadn't extracted the out,
no one would watch the plays.
The plays are interesting precisely to
the degree that the play is about
something that's about you and something
that's about you and something that's
about you.
It has to be something that's common to
everyone and you watch the play and you
partake in it through invitation.
Even though you're sitting down,
you partake in it through invitation and
then maybe later you go for coffee with
your friends and say,
well,
what was that all about?
And that's your attempt to take the
behavior wisdom that's coded in the
story and make it articulate and we're
doing that all the time.
Whenever you discuss a movie,
you do that and that's how educated
people actually interact with
literature,
right?
Because if you're uneducated,
roughly speaking,
you go see a movie and you just go it,
you never think about it as as something
that was produced.
You never think about it as a cultural
entity and you never do that higher
order analysis and when you're full,
your first encounter,
the idea of even doing that,
you might be resistant to it because it
seems in some sense to destroy some of
the magic of that,
of that pure immersion in the form.
So,
but that doesn't mean that people who go
to movies and don't talk about them
afterwards aren't learning anything.
Quite the contrary.
They're just learning.
They're learning using a very abstracted
form of imitation and then you might
imagine you don't go to a movie,
go to 100 movies and you imitate
something that's clean,
common across all the movies.
Well,
what's that?
that's an archetype.
The archetype is what's common across
stories and so we're trying to get to
the bottom of what's common across
stores and this is the best I've been
able to do.
It also maps quite nicely onto
heidegger's representation of the world,
which is something I only found out
later.
He has three domains of reality that
correspond to this very,
very precisely,
and then Freud's conception is also very
similar.
Id Ego,
Superego,
right?
The end is the natural force within you,
positive and negative,
because Freud was smart.
He knew there was always that dichotomy.
Then the ego,
that's you,
the individual positive element,
negative element,
and the superego which controls you,
represses you inhibits you in civilized
as you,
but is also can also be a complete
tyrant.
And so part of the reason Freud's theory
obtained such purchase so rapidly was
because it filled a it filled in a whole
and architect will hole that needed to
be filled for psychotherapeutic
practitioners who in some sense had
taken the place of priests and ministers
and that Sorta then rabbis and that sort
of person.
So okay,
so that's the representation.
And then while we've talked about the
representation of chaos,
and I would think about that,
and this is a radical thing to think.
It's sort of predicated on the idea that
what you confront in your in your
experience is not so much the material
world,
but potential as such.
It's the potential that you're
constantly contending with that can
destroy you and bring you down,
but also has has as part of its nature
that which you can extract and use to
build and grow and and we don't think of
ourselves as interacting with potential.
We think of ourselves as determined by a
material substrate,
but I don't think the idea that were
determined by a material substrate is as
powerful an idea as the idea that we
interact with potential and I also don't
think that the idea that were determined
by a material substrate is a more
scientific idea.
Then the idea that we're interacting
with potential.
Because I think that,
and I do this with hesitancy because
anytime you delve into the quantum
realm,
the hypothetical quantum realm to ground
your arguments,
doing something very dangerous,
but the quantum view of the world seems
to be something like being as a field of
potential from which forms emerge.
It's something like that and some of the
physicists like wheeler,
for example,
believe that consciousness plays a key
determining role in that whatever that
role might be,
so it's not reasonable to think of these
ideas that somehow outside of the realm
of scientific conjecture,
not,
not in the least,
especially because they can also be
given a deep evolutionary grounding,
and that is why do we represent
potential with assemble like this?
Well,
it's because that's a great symbol for
what lies outside our field of
competence.
What is that?
Predators,
dangerous predators,
snakes,
raptors,
carnivores all amalgamated together in a
monster and the monster that well,
it's also the monster that even offers
fruit.
That's the story in in the.
In the story of good and evil.
Well,
or in the story of Adam and Eve,
well obviously because you always hunt
for nourishment in the face of
predation,
obviously always,
and that's a paradox,
but it's a paradox that's embedded in
everything that you do.
The strange thing about these categories
is they're not exactly logical
categories there paradoxical categories
and those sorts of things aren't
supposed to exist because generally the
rule for a category is it can't contain
itself and its opposite at the same
time,
but if you've ever dealt with a person
on an intimate basis,
you know perfectly well that the
category indicated by their name
contains many paradoxical elements and
they might be paradoxical enough so you
can't even live with the person,
right?
They're not homogenous enough so that
you can plot a path forward with that
entity to many things pulling both you
and them apart,
so some things are a and only a and not
b,
but some things are a and b at the same
time and complex categories have that
nature.
I showed you some of the representations
of Osiris and isis emerging from the
conjoined serpent and that's what this
diagram represents.
To some degree.
It's,
well,
what does the Kale,
what does the pimp chaos of potential
first differentiate itself into get to
say,
well,
it differentiates itself into Yin and
Yang.
That's the right way of thinking about
differentiates itself into chaos and
order and those and those are the father
and the mother of everything that comes
after them.
That's one way of thinking about it and
they each have their symbolic realms and
so I've listed some of the common
symbols that are associated with these
two realms.
Now it's a difficult thing to pin down
because what one of the symbols mean has
to be defined in relationship to the
other.
So for example,
if you think about the sky,
the earth in relationship to the sky,
it's easy to make the earth feminine and
the Sky Masculine.
That's a common symbolic representation,
but if you contrast the earth with the
water,
then the water tends to be represented
as feminine and the Earth is masculine
and so the symbolic representations can
shift depending on the literary context.
Let's say the broader literary context,
and that means you can't just do a one
to one mapping of the symbolic entity on
onto the underlying,
onto the underlying archetypal
structure.
You have to be attentive to context and
nuance.
Of course,
because we're talking about literature,
you know,
it's not like you can use a dictionary
of symbols to get your way through
something as complex as Shakespeare,
but you can see,
you can see the underlying patterns and
use them.
Especially I think if you know the
fundamental map.
But anyway,
so here are the more common symbolic
representations.
A chaos transforms itself into the great
mother.
That's the queen,
can be the evil queen or the queen.
It can be the fairy godmother or the
queen that provides the poisoned apple
to snow white or those or the queen that
locks the prince.
What's his name?
I don't remember the prince in sleeping
beauty and the dungeon and tries to
destroy him.
The queen them out.
We've talked about time out.
Um,
the material world,
material matter,
mother,
right?
So the material world is the mother of
all things and matter.
His mother,
the land of the dead,
dark water,
unexplored territory,
nature,
mother nature.
Obviously the night sky,
contrast it against the day sky,
Isis,
queen of the underworld,
the womb,
the forest,
barbarian lands,
anomalous occurrences in the grave.
And the great father,
the king,
the emperor APP,
sue and tie a matte look together as we
discussed in the Mesopotamian creation
myth,
the ancestral spirits,
the family,
the city explored territory culture,
the day sky,
oh Cyrus God,
the father,
the village,
the nation,
the predictable,
the monument stone,
anything that's built in stone to last
is this representation of the great
father.
That's why there were monolithic
religion spread across the northern
hemisphere for thousands and thousands
of years.
Those people were building things and
carving things in stone to make
memories.
That's what their monuments were for,
to bring the past into the present and
future on a permanent basis and try to
instantiate something solid that
everyone could stand apart.
Well,
sometimes solid isn't what you need.
Sometimes what you need is fluid and
liquid,
but the solidity is there to give you
something to stand on even though it can
become something arid and dry.
You see in the story of exodus is Moses
is a master of water.
And the Pharaoh is,
uh,
is the king of desert stone.
Roughly speaking in the and the Egypt,
Egypt is portrayed as a tyranny because
it's nothing but dry stone and Moses
brings water to that.
That's chaos.
That's partly the Red Sea story and
partly Moses ability to to get water out
of rocks and not and when that's
necessary and part of the reason that
he's found to begin with floating on
water when he's an infant,
which is also something that almost
killed him,
right?
Because while you don't want to put your
infant in a basket of rushes and put
them to float on the water,
so that's a brief overview of the manner
in which images and stories can be used
to represent the first division of this
underlying reality.
You know nothing.
What do you do?
You establish a center,
you explore from the center.
It's a domain of safety and that's
surrounded by the unknown.
So and that's what children do.
We already know this.
If you watch how children explore,
it's more evident if you look at
children who are somewhat inhibited
because really extroverted and
emotionally stable children,
they'll just explore.
They will recede,
but children that are sort of balanced
in their emotional response badge,
do you bring a 18 month old to a new
playground?
All mothers standing there,
she's the pillar at the center of the
world around her is explored territory
and the reason this explored is because
the child knows how to interact with the
mother and so one thing you want to know
about kids is you can have multiple
caregivers for your kids.
You can have a nanny,
you can put them in daycare,
but they do not like having their
primary caregiver switched.
It's like it's like everything
transforms when that happens and it
destabilizes been badly.
So if you're going to have other people
take care of your kids,
it's better that it's the same other
person.
Well obviously,
I mean they're going to form an intimate
and loving relationship with them with
any luck and if that disappears,
it's like a death,
but it's worse than that in some sense
or or the reason that the death is bad
because the child's conceptual world,
they're familiar world familiar family,
they're familiar world collapses,
so children hate that.
Now they can bond to multiple people.
That's not a problem,
but they do not like having their
caregivers shifted because that defines
their territory,
so the child is adapted to the mother's
presence and has been ever since birth,
if everything's gone well,
so it's a place of security and
stability,
partly because the child knows how to
act around the mother,
but also partly because if the child
encounters anything that he or she
doesn't understand well in the presence
of mother,
the mother will instantly intervene to
provide the knowledge necessary to
encapsulate the unexpected occurrence.
Okay,
so the child is by the mother and the
baby he's holding on and that gives him
ventral contact.
It's sad.
It's.
It's comforting.
It's produced is opiates.
It decreases pain.
It's directly comforting,
and so then the child is maybe they're
shy and they're going to take a few
looks at what's first and start to their
frozen clinging to something secure,
and then if nothing negative happens,
they start to relax.
Just like a rat that's been put into a
new cage.
They start to relax and they'll start to
look and that's the first manifestations
of voluntary exploratory behavior and
maybe if there's other people around,
they'll look and smile and then they'll
hide,
right,
and the smile is an invitation to play
or interact,
but so it's.
It's a foray out into the world,
smile,
eye contact and hide.
Maybe they'll do that multiple times and
get a game going,
not establishes something stable going
on between them and the stranger.
Does the stranger know how to play and
then maybe they'll loosen up and they'll
start to explore and then they go out
away from the mother and start
interacting with the world until
something happens that overwhelms the.
Then they'll run back,
get a hug,
maybe half asleep because maybe they
processed enough and then you can
encourage them to go back and so what
they're doing is they have the flag
planted on unknown territory.
That's mom the flag,
right?
They,
they circulate around there because it's
secure.
Make forays outwards where the dragons
are gathered what's of interest and if
it's too much,
they run back and then they end.
The mom says it's okay.
No problem,
well you know,
or gives them a little,
you know,
rock or maybe feeds them something or
and lets them have a little rest and
then off you go play again.
Now they go again,
and so what the child is doing is
continually moving out,
extending it's explored territory into
the unknown,
just like the Star Trek voyagers and
then moving back to security and then
moving up farther and then moving back
to security and hopefully at some point
they carry with them their own security
once they become competent,
like once you've incorporated all of the
competence of your parents,
you don't need to go back well,
and even if you do,
it isn't going to help you.
You've that.
You've transcended the security and
that's what makes you an adult.
Hopefully that happens.
So.
So that's why the,
the hero archetype is the central human
story.
It's because that's how we learn.
It's,
it's an images stick representation of
the process by which we make sense out
of the world.
So of course it's redemptive because by
definition that's the pattern we use to
expand our competence in the world.
How could it be anything other than
redemptive and it's tied in with the
here's how it's tied in with the idea of
sacrifice.
Every time you learn something
especially painfully,
which really means you learned it,
there's a bunch of things that you
already knew that you had to let go of
because they're wrong and so there is no
learning without sacrifice,
and now that means is that there is no
learning without the retooling of
structures that you've already been
using and that's because you actually
have a complete map of the world always,
but it's low resolution.
It's low resolution,
and then if you go out there and into a
particular area that you've only mapped
in a low resolution way,
you'll learn that force you to update
the low resolution representations and
sometimes that can mean abandoning whole
pieces of it because they're just wrong.
You think this is like this.
You think your girlfriend is like your
mother.
Well,
you may find out that that's absolutely
wrong,
and the degree to which you use this low
resolution map to map her,
you're going to experience nothing but
trouble.
So in fact,
in all likelihood,
that's what you'll experience because
your girlfriend is not your mother,
or at least she shouldn't be.
So when you go out and you encounter
something new,
it always means the demolition of parts
of you that are still uninformed and an
incomplete.
And so there's a sacrificial element to
exploration.
That's partly why people don't like to
talk to.
People have ideas that are different
than theirs because you might think,
well sure we differ.
Why can't we just talk?
If you know things,
I don't all the better,
but no,
if you know something,
I really don't know what's going to
challenge something I already presumed
and if it really challenges,
it will disintegrate and all do a little
trip into the underworld before I can
read structure myself.
And if you really challenged me,
it might be almost complete dissolution.
So you who wants that?
Well,
here's how you want that.
The only circumstance under which you
will want that is if you know that the
alternative is worse.
Continual small updates.
Hm.
Differentiate you and make you strong.
You shy away from that.
Your map stays low resolution and you
make yourself weak because you're not.
You're not practicing that process of
letting go and transforming and letting
go and transforming because you want to
become a master at that.
You don't want to be a master at
guarding your territory even though
that's extraordinarily useful.
You want to become a master of taking
the walls apart and extending them and
building them up and taking the walls
apart and extending them and building
them up and that because you'll never
run out of utility for that and that can
mean that unknown becomes something
that's your friend instead of your enemy
and that would be a wonderful thing
because of course people respond to the
unknown as if it's their terrible enemy.
It's like,
don't be so sure about that.
What you know might be your enemy.
What you don't yet know might be the
best friend you have and it's highly
probable because what do you know?
And there's an infinite number of things
you don't know,
so you might as well make friends with
them.
And then you also start to understand
that you are precisely the thing that
can move into the unknown,
as if it's welcoming and grow and
develop as a consequence,
and that makes you a much different
thing than the thing that has to be
terrified of everything.
It doesn't understand you're just in a
permanent state of existential horror
under those conditions and you're
dangerous to other people too,
especially if they don't agree with you
as another way of representing it.
The dragon of chaos stands for the
potential that surrounds us.
Inside of that,
there's the unknown.
They are knowing that you actually come
into contact with,
right?
That's the unknown as it actually
manifest itself in your world as
something you don't understand,
instead of just the potential for that,
because we say,
look,
you know perfectly well that as you're
sitting here,
there's all sorts of things you don't
know everywhere,
but where are they?
Well,
they're not manifesting themselves at
the moment.
They're only in potential,
but you could.
We could have a discussion that that
became argumentative and then all of a
sudden it would be as if emissaries of
that unknown had entered the space and
that's the unknown that's defined in
relationship to what you know.
That's what you actually experienced.
Instead of it only being potential.
It's a tough thing to get because
they're both unknown,
right?
You think,
well,
how can there be two different
categories of unknown?
Well latent and manifest.
That's a good way of thinking about you
know,
you in a relationship,
it's going stable,
but you know that sooner or later
something will come up.
Okay,
op from where?
Why?
Up from?
From beneath?
Well,
what do you mean beneath?
While it's from.
It's from your complex,
the person you're in a relationship with
in,
in width is complicated and complex
that's implicit in you.
It's,
it's inside your conceptual structure.
That's,
that's the way of looking at it now and
then when there's a disagreement,
it will manifest itself and you know
that you know that they're still trouble
brewing ahead.
Interrelationship always,
and that's part of what keeps them alive
was an interesting piece of empirical
work done on this a while back,
so you might think,
well,
what is the optimal relationship look
like in terms of positive and negative
emotion?
You might say,
well,
Utopia,
nothing but positive interactions.
It's like no.
Now again,
you get people to code the interactions
they have with your partner during the
day,
you know,
you sample it,
you say,
was that interaction positive or
negative?
And then what you're trying to do is
predict the longevity of the
relationship.
Okay,
so here's the data.
If it falls under five positive
interactions to one negative
interaction,
the relationship doesn't continue.
Fair enough.
Too much negative.
That's easy to understand.
If it exceeds 11 positive to one
negative,
the relationship doesn't last.
Why?
New Challenge,
right?
What do you want from your partner?
Bless.
No,
no,
no.
You don't.
You want periods of peace punctuated by
a good fight and that because that means
you respect them,
means you have something to offer each
other and it means that you're both
growing and so you don't want the fight
to be too dramatic because,
well then you retreat.
You can't settle it,
but the person that you can completely
map and who only does positive things
for you,
it's like a.
You don't know that person,
but they're not communicating with you
nor you with them.
Maybe they're just subordinating
themselves to you or you to them and
you're not growing.
You want someone who can.
It's a real relationship is a wrestling
match.
It's a grappling,
grappling phenomena that you both
emerged,
transformed from,
and that's what people want.
They don't want to push over.
Not Not unless there's something wrong
with them,
and when narcissistic person who never
wants to be challenged will want a
partner who does nothing but deliver
exactly what they're told to deliver,
but they will mistreat them beyond
belief and perhaps deservedly so.
All right,
so here's some symbolic representations.
The two on the left are Jonah,
Jonah,
and the whale.
So the story of Jonah is an interesting
one.
I'll just go over it very briefly.
There's a city and the city is full of
people who are sinful.
What does that mean?
Well,
to sin is an archery term.
It means to miss the mark.
So these are people who aren't oriented
properly and so the city is in a chaotic
state and God tells Jonah that he's
gonna.
Go to that city and tell them just
exactly what's up with them.
And Julie,
thanks.
No,
I'm not going to do that.
And why?
Well that doesn't require much
explanation.
It's like how popular you are going to
be if you go to a city full of chaotic
people and tell them why they're stupid
and wrong.
It's Joanna,
thanks.
No,
I'm not going to do that.
I don't care if God's telling me to do
it.
So his conscience is telling him to do
it or his destiny is telling them to do
it or,
or his orientation with higher morality
is telling them to do it.
You can read it any way you want.
And so he thinks,
no,
I'm hopping on this boat and I'm getting
as far away from that city as I possibly
can.
And so he does that.
And then the storm comes up because God
thinks,
no,
you're not getting away if I told you to
do something,
you're not getting away from it.
A storm comes up.
Well,
what does that mean?
it's easy.
Betray your destiny and see how long it
takes you to be drowning in a storm.
It will happen immediately.
And of course it will,
because what?
What's calling you to be your best is
exactly the thing that's pushing you
forward,
to manifest yourself most fully in the
world.
It's what you need.
You run away from that.
The boat's going to start to rock very,
very quickly.
Well,
you all know that.
You know that perfectly well.
It,
it,
it's hell.
All you have to do is not study for an
exam that you know that's coming up to
see everything start to the storm.
Water start to rise and everything start
to rock.
It's pretty bloody obvious.
So anyways,
he's on this boat and there's a storm.
And all of the people on the boat who
who can't quite discriminate chaos from
whether because they haven't
differentiated the world to that degree,
thank.
Oh,
the boat wouldn't be about to be swamped
if we hadn't.
Some of us had done something stupid and
wrong,
and there's logic in that.
You know,
you might think,
well God has nothing personal against
you because of the storm,
so you're confusing levels of analysis,
but you've got to give these people some
credit.
It's like maybe they did do something
stupid.
Maybe they didn't cop the damn boat
properly.
Maybe the ropes aren't in as good as
shape as they might be.
Maybe they weren't paying attention to
the weather when they went out on the
ocean,
you know?
Or maybe they haven't made peace with
their brother and so their hearts are
bent,
twisted out of shape so they don't make
particularly good sailors.
It's like the idea that you encounter
restoring because you're stupid and
wrong is a really good idea.
Even though it's not an infinite
applicability anyways.
They draw lots.
It's a primitive thing to do.
It's like,
wow,
it's one,
it's someone's fault.
We don't know who we're going to throw
someone overboard,
the worst sinner,
obviously that's what God wants.
Some kind of sacrifice,
so they all draw lots and someone loses
and then Jonas stands up and says,
well,
sorry guys,
like I know that I've got a problem with
God at the moment so it's probably me.
You better throw me over and they don't
really want to,
but he finally convinces them over Egos
and the storm settles.
Well,
you know,
sometimes if you're in a group of people
in an organization,
there is someone in the organization
who's head is screwed on exactly
straight and they know exactly why it is
and what they've done wrong and what
puts them in that position and they are
poisoning the entire enterprise and if
you throw them overboard or better,
if they agreed voluntarily to leave,
then this storm will abate and
everything will be okay.
So anyways,
they throw joe job over or Jonah
overboard and a whale comes up and
swallows them and takes them down to the
bottom of the ocean.
Well,
we already know what that means because
we watched Pinocchio.
It's like when God abandons you because
you've abandoned your destiny and the
storms come up,
the probability that you're going to be
taken down to the,
to the depths is extraordinarily high,
and that happens in people's lives all
the time.
Also down there,
Jonah repents.
Well,
what do you do when you were in not
underworld,
where you've been there before,
when things fall apart on your friends
have abandoned you and you're not as
popular as you could be.
You can't stand to look at yourself in
the mirror into the underworld.
You go and you think,
Geez,
I've done a lot of things wrong.
You know,
maybe I should reconcile myself with the
world that I could get out of this.
We'll also.
That's what Jonah does.
He thinks,
all right,
I've got this destiny.
I better go do it.
God says,
so the whale spits them out onto the
beach and off he goes to the city to
tell them what's wrong.
Well,
that's what that represents,
that these symbols,
you know,
it's so cool.
The second one I really,
I really like.
It's so interesting because you see joan
and reemerging from the whale and he's
got a halo around his head.
You say,
well,
what's a halo?
Have you ever looked at a quarter?
Well,
think about a quarter.
A quarter is the moon and who's on the
quarter?
The Queen,
the queen is surrounded by the halo of
the Moon,
the Queens Queen of the Queen of the
night gold coin.
That's the king's head on the sun.
That's the halo.
Well,
what comes out of the belly of the,
of the fish?
It's the illuminated human being.
It's the spirit of the illuminated human
being.
That's what that means.
Well,
what does that mean?
what else would come out of chaos,
you know,
if you,
if you fall apart and then you put
yourself back together,
what is it that comes back out?
But at least you're in better shape than
you were before.
You know,
and then maybe you do that 20 times in
your life or 50 times and you do it
voluntarily.
Every time you do it,
you're more like the thing with the halo
and less like the thing that's,
you know,
being thrown overboard by your friends.
And then you see this representation on
the right.
This is a very complicated
representation.
So in this one you see Christ who's
carrying his cross with the sun behind
them.
That's the halo that I was talking
about.
He's the person who's voluntarily
accepted the necessity of death and
renewal.
That's what the cross represents.
And so it's an,
it's an,
it's a,
what would you call it,
an abstracted representation of this,
uh,
further developed idea of this.
And then you see in the back,
this is a feminine symbol,
right?
It's a,
it's a symbol of birth.
And you'll see,
you'll understand more when I,
when I show you the symbols later,
this is the eternal opening in the world
from which new forms emerge.
It's the place from which babies emerge.
And you can tell that if you look
carefully because you see all these
little heads there with wings on them,
those are all spirits waiting to be
born.
And so the hero emerges from the,
from the eternal feminine,
willing to die and suffer.
And in doing so,
this defeating the snake,
the snake's down there,
and the adversary at the same time.
While it's no wonder we don't understand
those images,
I mean there are so unbelievably rich
that how could you possibly articulate
them?
That's why they emerged in images,
stick form to begin with.
The artists get there before the
philosophers,
long before the philosophers,
the dramatists get there way before the
artists even.
And so we figured it out,
we represented it in art and literature
and music and drama.
And then we're on the cusp,
so to speak,
of understanding it in a fully
articulated manner and not a moment too
soon.
So what does it mean for this symbol to
emerge from the feminine symbol,
let's say,
to emerge from chaos?
Well,
this picture,
this is a picture of Venus,
the goddess of love,
right?
And so I cut this picture out of a
larger picture and it's Venus
manifesting yourself in a transcendent
space in the sky in the same way that
Christ did in the previous
representation.
And she has raised coming off her and
there's all these men who are nights
kneeling in front of the image.
Well,
what does that mean?
it means that men use the image of
female perfection to motivate
themselves.
And that's exactly right.
That's precisely what they do.
You see that in the Tom Sawyer story.
So Tom Sawyer is about 12 years old and
he's still hanging around with his
friends like huck Finn and this one girl
moves across the street,
becky and she comes out and he's struck
by her for the first time in his life.
Something's changed.
And the first thing does is hot pop
on a picket fence and show off and
balance in front of her.
And he's saying,
well,
look at me,
look at me.
I'm like the male bowerbird building
something beautiful.
So the female will approve of it.
And it's,
it's motivation,
you know?
And that's something that I think modern
women don't really understand about men.
They don't understand that at least to
the degree that males are uncorrupted
and not better because of being
rejected,
they're doing everything they can to
kneel before the eternal image of the
feminine
and try to make themselves worthy as the
chivalry story.
Right?
That's what you should encourage in your
partner so and so out of chaos emerges
this first form.
It's the feminine form.
It's partly the form that represents
novelty as such,
so on one hand it's promise.
On the other hand,
it's threat that you wouldn't believe
and I don't know because I don't know.
I don't understand the situation with
women as well as I understand the
situation with men.
Obviously being a man,
but I don't know if women had any idea
how paralyzing they are to especially
young men.
A large,
very large number of my clinical
clients,
but also young men I've talked to in
general,
are absolutely terrified of women
because they're terrified of being
rejected and the terror exists in
precise proportion to the attraction to
the woman,
which is a horrible paradoxical
situation.
To be an insult and why men make such
fools of themselves in front of women
that they're attracted to,
it's because first of all,
they don't see the woman that they're
attracted to because what the hell do
they know about her?
They don't see her as an individual.
They see her as the manifestation of a
judgmental ideal and then it's only in
establishing the relationship with the
actual woman that they can start
differentiating between the judgmental
ideal and the actual individual woman,
and that also requires the sacrifice and
the sacrifice is
you never can have an ideal woman,
so to have a relationship with any
woman,
you have to sacrifice the relationship
with the ideal woman and you have to see
the individual woman and separate her
from the ideal and that's the same thing
that happens to the hero in sleeping
beauty,
right?
He sees the evil queen who actually
turns into the dragon of chaos and it's
not until he can,
he can defeat her,
that he can establish a relationship
with the actual princess.
And that's exactly the case.
I had a wonderful my clients who ran
this men's group,
which was quite interesting.
One of the things they had initiates do,
which was very intelligent,
was to go out and ask 50 women in one
day for their phone numbers.
Why politely,
properly you don't want.
It wasn't.
It wasn't a.
It was a game,
but it wasn't a stupid game and the idea
was get over your fear of rejection and
how do you do that by encountering it
continually and continually
and continually so that you're no longer
paralyzed by this.
Here's,
I love this cartoon.
This is from a underground comic for,
for people who smoke way too much
marijuana and it's called a.
These people are the fabulous furry
freak brothers and they were created by
Gilbert Shelton who was one of the first
underground cartoonists and one of the
least pathological ones with the best
sense of humor.
And he writes these stories about these
stupid hippies.
Three of them,
the fabulous furry freak brothers.
You see two of them there and all they
do is smoke pot and avoid responsibility
and and run away from the police and it.
But,
but it's a nice satire and so and they
have this cat and the fat one fat Freddy
has the cat and they're too lazy to even
give her the cat in name.
So it's fat Freddy's cat and it has its
own adventure is mostly with an army of
cockroaches that that lives inside.
They're like horrible slummy hell hole
of living place.
And so anyways,
it's quite comical and so the.
The hippies have stumbled across a small
fortune and stoned out of their minds on
cocaine.
They go out to set up utopia in the
countryside.
They buy this terrible piece of property
but they're so diluted that they think
it's like a mansion and they bring their
cat and I don't know if you've ever had
a cat,
but cats don't like to move.
It really bugs them and so they're not
comfortable.
When you bring them to a new place,
they're like the rat that's been taken
out of its comfortable cage and put into
a new cage and the cat.
You put a cat in a new room and it
depending on the cat obviously,
but generally they'll retreat into a
corner and be and now pityingly and be
very unhappy for quite a substantial
amount of time.
And so the cartoonist actually map this
out quite nicely.
So the hippie takes the cat out of the
box and says our new home,
it's there out in the forest.
This is an urban cat.
It's never been in the forest.
It doesn't know what the hell is up in
the forest and the cat's looking rather
dubiously and things.
So this is the country.
And then it's put on the ground and it
starts to slink as he says,
slink,
slink out into the forest.
And that's actually what animals do.
It's,
it's a predator,
evasion,
crouch.
And so if they're put in a new
territory,
they'll hunker down and freeze first and
then they'll slowly unfreeze and start
to explore.
They sniff first and then they'll start
to move it.
But they do it like with trepidation and
slowly and tried to hide it.
So that's what the cat is doing and the
cat goes out into the unknown,
far enough sniffing and all of a sudden
pow.
It goes underneath the house.
It's like the toddler running back to
the mother and the other,
another hippie there.
Uh,
I think that's fineas says,
where'd the cat disappeared?
You now and the fats ready character
says under the house.
And then the cats onto there in the dark
with big eyes looking terrified saying
you'd hide too if you'd smelled what I
did.
And so what it smelled was this thing
that has like the head of a wolf and a
and antlers,
like a deer in the tail of a skunk and
the feet of a,
like a chicken and horrible clause.
It's like,
well,
what is that?
Well,
it's a monstrous amalgam of that which
lurks and not known.
And so the cartoonists,
the comedian got it perfect.
Said,
well,
what is there?
What is out in the unknown while you
need one representation,
not a thousand.
And so you take pieces of what's out
there that are relevant and you create a
single image out of that and you say,
well,
this is what's out there.
And you might say,
well,
no such animal as that exists,
and that's actually incorrect.
An animal,
very much animals,
very much like that exists.
It's just a super ordinate,
low resolution category.
It includes all those weird animals that
might hurt you,
that are out in the forest.
That's a useful category,
weird animals that might hurt you.
And that's a real category.
You might say,
well,
there's differentiated things within
that category.
It's like,
yeah,
every category has that nature can still
be further differentiated,
maybe not protons,
you know,
they could even be differentiated with
regards to location at least.
So every category can be further
differentiated.
The question is whether the category has
some functional utility,
or at least that's one of its questions.
It's like that's the thing to be afraid
of.
Okay,
good.
Now you got it.
This is the category of all things to be
afraid of.
What do you do in response to that
category?
All right,
so then we'd go to the next
representation.
This is Kelly gay ally,
Hindu goddess of destruction.
She's the thing that you encounter.
She's the thing that makes things go
bump in the night.
What is that thing?
Well,
let's take it apart a little bit because
you can't see this image until you,
until you understand it,
you wouldn't be able to if you're Hindu,
because you'd be in the culture and
you'd know what the image represented,
but some people in here might be Hindu,
but not very many people.
So.
Okay,
so let's talk about this image.
It's horrifying image and so you.
Here's how this image emerged.
It emerged in the imagination of people
who were tormented for Millennia about
just what the hell lurked out there in
the unknown and some heart.
Some artists was seized by a revelation,
a horrifying revelation of just what
that was.
Okay,
so what is it?
Well,
first of all,
she's in a,
a container of fire.
Why fire?
Well,
fire is useful and destructive,
right?
And you also cannot look away from fire
and so it's a really good symbol of that
which you cannot look away from.
It's eternally meaningful.
Fire is eternally meaningful.
Why we can't keep our hands off fire,
right?
We're descendants of the first insane
ape who was so obsessed by fire that he
couldn't stay away from,
from a burning landscape and learned how
to master it.
And he's our forefather not.
We're obsessed
by fire.
It's magical to us.
And it transforms.
It Burns and transformed.
So from a symbolic perspective,
it's very useful.
Useful source of,
of images.
Stick representation.
Okay.
The fire's there.
And then inside the fire,
these are skulls.
You see them all lined up there.
So it's not just fire,
it's the fire of death that consumes.
So that's where Kelly lives.
So that's fun to start with.
And then there she is with her,
with her hair,
hair on fire because her hair's on fire
in case she isn't frightening enough
just because of where she lives,
their hair's on fire.
And her head dresses made out of skulls.
So that's nice.
And then she's like an insect like a
spider.
See,
she has all these legs and why is that?
Because we don't really like insects and
you know,
they set off our bug detectors and they
can bite us and they're quite horrifying
and many people have spider phobias
particularly and a and no wonder and
then she's got a weapon and one hand
here and,
but and then her,
you see she's eating something and you
see here her belly is concave.
Well,
why?
she's in a birth position.
She's just given birth to this
unfortunate character who happens to be
low.
She who she happens to be standing upon
and he's disemboweled and she's eating
him intestines first and that's Kelly.
It's like that's horror.
It's a representation of horror and
death and destruction and
transformation.
It's feminine as well.
What do you do in the face of his mother
nature?
That's another negative element of
Mother Nature.
What do you do with something like this?
Well,
that's the eternal question and the
answer is quite straightforward.
You make sacrifices to her and if you
make the proper sacrifices,
then she turns into her beneficial
counterpart and that's exactly what you
do do in life.
If in the face of horror and death,
you make sacrifices so you transform the
terrible destructive element of nature
into that thing that continually offers
you what you need and it's,
it's,
it's of that discovery is one of
unparalleled brilliance and you know we
don't get it.
We think it's primitive.
It's and no wonder you know you,
you can understand human sacrifice.
That sounds pretty primitive,
man.
It's terrifying,
but the idea of sacrifice,
it's inactive.
The,
the idea itself is a conceptualization
of otter genius and why do you expect it
to come forward first in its perfect
form,
it's not going to do that.
It's going to come forward in perfectly
and roughly and brutally and then
hopefully be refined across time,
which is exactly what has happened.
You see,
even in the biblical stories that
transition from human sacrifice,
sacrificed animal sacrifice,
and then with us now it's the transition
from animal sacrifice to psychological
sacrifice because we're sophisticated
enough to do that,
we can let go of concepts and
abstractions and things that were
holding onto that we should no longer
hold onto and progress that manner.
It's increasing,
articulated psychological
sophistication,
but we still make sacrifices and we hope
that they'll be accepted and we hope
that they're of high enough quality so
that they work well.
That's a representation of Diana.
You can think of Diana,
there's an opposite,
a durga in Hinduism and she comes forth
if you make the proper sacrifices to
Kelly,
but I wanted to show you alternative
representations from different cultures
of these archetypes forms.
This is Diana Positive Feminine,
what?
Multi breasted,
right?
She's the thing that nourishes the world
and so that would be on one hand your
mother who obviously protects you from
the terrible aspects of fire and danger,
but also my nature conceptualized as the
positive feminine in general,
the source of all fertility and all food
and all beings and all good things.
Something that you want to have on your
side,
that's for sure,
and you might say if you acted
heroically properly and you played the
metagame and not the game and you made
the proper sacrifices,
then you'd never encountered Kelly.
You would only encounter her benevolent
counterpart and so then you might say,
well,
does she even exist?
Then that's something that's very
interesting is because the degree to
which the terrible part of the world
manifests itself in your life is
proportionate to how insufficient you
are and we don't know the full extent of
that.
If you got your act together completely,
maybe all the suffering would disappear
from your life or at least maybe all the
unbearable suffering and maybe all the
suffering or the unbearable suffering
from the lives of people around you to
and you already know that because there
are people that you'll go to in a crisis
that you can rely on and you know
they'll help you and you wonder what the
world would be like if you were like
that and everyone else was like that
too.
We'd have a lot fewer crises and the
ones that we do have would be a lot more
manageable and so when people say,
well,
why is the world so rife with suffering?
One answer to that is because we're not
yet what we could be,
and at least that's an answer that we
have some control over.
Right?
You're not going to talk God out of
making the world suffer.
That's for sure,
and you're not going to negotiate
directly with Mother Nature,
but you might be able to put yourself
together a little bit and see if that
works.
At least it's under your control and God
only knows what the upper limit of that
might be.
Well,
here's the decomposition of the of the
fundamental archetype.
The dragon of chaos differentiates on
the one hand into the feminine.
That's the unknown in the feminine,
differentiates further into the negative
feminine than the Positive Feminine.
The negative feminine is the reason for
which haunts.
It's the reason for.
You know,
there's a whole group online called men
going their own way.
G T o w,
that's a very interesting group to go
study.
There's lots them.
I don't know how many
of them there are and most of them are
older.
Many of them are men who have been
through a particularly horrifying
divorce for one reason or another and
there they've had enough of women so
they stay.
Tell that young men that they're
teaching never have a permanent
relationship.
Never share your territory with a woman,
never share your possessions.
Make sure you never lived together and
don't stay with one long enough to enter
a common law relationship because you
will be stripped of everything that you
have.
Well,
that's a hell of a thing to be telling
people,
but what's happened is that the female
has been manifested in their life only
as the negative archetype and they've
got that confused with all women and
that's partly,
you know,
you gotta ask yourself if you know the
mythological stories.
Maybe if you made the right sacrifices,
you wouldn't have so much trouble with
women.
It's a,
it's a good question to ask yourself
first and,
and I would also say,
you know,
if you're a woman who has trouble with
man or you're a man who has trouble with
women,
it's not the women and it's not the man,
it's you because the women are telling
you what's wrong with you and the men
are telling you what's wrong with you.
And if you don't listen then it's you.
It's either you are all men.
Well that's easy.
It's all men.
While that's certainly how it's played
out in the world right now,
it's like,
no,
it's not all men.
You can be by definition,
by definition,
and it's not all women,
that's for sure.
I don't want to have anything to do with
women.
It's like you're a pathetic weasel.
That's the same statement.
Here's some lovely representations.
This is Mary from represented in,
in,
in very different areas.
This is a very old witnesses about
twelfth century.
I absolutely love this image.
It's so profound.
So what you see here is Mary as in as
eternal mother of the infant.
Okay,
she's sitting on the crescent moon here.
She tweeted the night and underneath you
can't see this very well,
but underneath the moon there is a.
there's a reptile and she's got a nice
nicely underneath their feet and that
Satan in part,
which means protect your children from
malevolent,
from malevolence,
and it's the Predator.
And so what's the.
What's the proper orientation for
mother?
Protect your infant from malevolent
predators,
obviously,
right?
That's the holy image of the mother.
So she's holding the infant safely in
her arms.
She's queen of the universe and she's
coming out of this strange tunnel.
It's the same.
These are called Amanda by the way.
This tunnel,
and it's.
It's actually,
this is going to be very strange,
but I'm going to tell you what it is
anyways.
It's like a hole into the fabric of time
and space and it's revealing in the
image that's eternal.
That's outside of time and space and
it's outside of time and space because
it recurs all the time.
It never ages that it's,
it's,
it's an image that transcends
temporality.
Now you might say,
well,
is it real?
And the answer to that is,
well,
it depends on what you mean by real.
Something that transcends temporality is
pretty damn real.
And so that's,
that's what that,
that,
that hole in the sky represents.
It also represents the place from which
all forms
emerge.
So there's a biological component to it
too,
right?
So it's as if the,
as if these divine figures are standing
in front while,
I'll show you in a minute of what
they're standing in front of and you see
here the same thing with these little
poteat.
That's what they're called,
sort of embedded in the fleshlight folds
law around here,
and you see mary here holding the infant
again away from the terrible predator.
That's the serpent of chaos down there
in the,
in the ocean and that's again,
what does that mean?
Why would the servant of chaos be in the
ocean?
Well,
how many of our ancestral infants do you
suppose were eaten by crocodiles at the
waterhole and plenty,
plenty of them,
and so that's something to be terrified
of and to take precautions against.
And so and then this image here,
the older one,
see all these weird little figures in
the background here.
You can't see them,
but they're musical instruments there.
There are all sorts of archaic musical
instruments and so here's,
here's what the image means.
It means the potential from which this
figure is emerging is like a musical
construction.
So it's like a symphony.
It's this pattern layer.
It's patterns layer upon layers of
harmonious patterns that make up being
and out of that emerges this image and
that's what that image represents and
that's what music represents.
It represents this pattern potential
that we're constantly interacting with.
It's deeply,
deeply meaningful.
That's why we love music so much.
I've got a that's an absolute work of
genius to put those two things together.
It's,
it's,
it's remarkable,
remarkable image.
So
well,
let's stop there and we'll meet again in
15 minutes and then this.
So that's the positive feminine on the
left and then on the right,
that's the Gorgon and that's the thing
that fills you with terror.
When you look at it,
there's another representation of the
positive feminine.
It's another representation of Mary.
There are representations very much like
this.
If I assist with horace on your lap and
people often consider those precursors
there Egypt,
Egyptian statues,
precursors to the Christian iconography
and well,
I suppose in some sense they are in so
far as they predated them in time,
but the fundamental issue is that,
well,
that this image has to be held up as
transcendent,
and by that I mean it's,
it's got to be.
It's an image that's got to be at the
basis of a value structure that actually
works in so far as there's going to be
human beings because there aren't any
human beings without the infinite and
the mother,
and so if that's not held up as a as an
image of ultimate value,
then everything falls apart and it's
something our culture does
extraordinarily badly.
I had a client recently admit to me and
ashamed tones that she wanted to have
children.
I thought.
I said,
well,
you don't have to be ashamed of that.
Especially not if you're talking to me.
And she said,
oh,
that's such a relief because I can't
talk to anyone about it at work.
They seem to think that it's,
you know,
degrading thought that
you can hardly diagnosed.
The culture is more pathological than
then that that's so appalling and it's
so hard is one of the things I really
feel badly for young women because
they're not guided through this with any
sense whatsoever.
And I'll tell you what my experience has
been working with women and you can take
this for what it's worth.
And,
and I've worked with women who have
achieved the highest levels of their
profession.
I don't mean just in academia,
but in a number of different fields.
This is what happens will we'll take the
typical woman,
conservative woman because they're more
typical conscientious,
not particularly open.
So they're there due to fool people,
you know,
their existing within the structures of
their society.
So I'll take female lawyers is a classic
example.
So they're very good at high school,
very hardworking,
very intelligent but very but very
beautiful and often rather agreeable.
And that's important because it means to
some degree that they want to please and
they'll do what they're told.
And so part of the reason I think that
women are outperforming men in,
in elementary,
junior high school,
high school and university is because
they're more likely to be obedient.
And I know that to some degree because
we did analysis of students in Quebec
and found out that one thing that
predicted grades over and above
intelligence and conscientiousness was
agreeable nus.
And agreeable people got better grades
than their Iq and conscientiousness
would predict,
and that's particularly negative for
men.
So imagine this is what's happening.
So you're a borderline student and
you're also a bit rebellious and anti
social.
I'm going to fail you like you're right
on the cusp.
Don't like you much.
You fail.
You have exactly the same grade profile,
but I like you tick,
you move ahead,
you don't.
And so one of the things that's dividing
men from women as they progress through
school is the degree to which they
agreeable.
Now that works out to some degree for
women in so far as the agreeableness
moves them forward,
but they encountered the negative
elements of being agreeable later in
their careers.
Anyways,
there are women are very good in high
school.
Then they go to college.
They're very good in college.
They nailed their damn grades.
They do their studying,
they get their a's and they had the ace
their set,
so they're smart too.
Then they go off to do their articling
and they're really,
really good at it and then they get
offered an associate position and
they're really,
really good.
At it and then by the time they're 30
they make partner and let's say they're
in high pressure,
high paying jobs,
$250,000
a year.
$300,000
$500 an hour.
Okay.
What's your life like?
You work all the time,
period.
Seventy hours a week,
75 hours a week,
flat out and you don't get to make any
mistakes and if your client calls you at
three in the morning on Monday,
on Sunday you say,
I'm really glad to hear you hear from
you because if you don't,
there's some hot law firm in New York
that'll take your client from you at a
moment's notice and the client is paying
you whatever the firm.
Seven hundred and $50 an hour of which
maybe you get 3:50
and what they want is an answer about
something really complicated right?
Bloody now.
And you can say all you want about the
fact that women have a difficult time
with that because it's a male dominant.
Patriarchy new.
Any female lawyer who's hit 30 and his
partner that has any sense at all knows
that's complete bloody rubbish.
It's market determined right to the
core.
What happens to the women when they're
in their thirties?
They all leave the high end law firms.
Why?
Because who in their right mind would
want to live like that?
That's the issue,
right?
Once you make about $60,000
a year for your family,
but let's say for you personally,
additional income makes zero has zero
impact on your quality of life.
Zero.
So why work 80 hours a week while men
will do it?
Some men,
very few,
a handful of hyper competitive men who
are obsessed with hitting the pinnacle
of the given dominance hierarchy there
in will happily work 80 hours a week and
they'll forgo everything else.
Relationships,
family,
children way in the second category,
and so those men are often very
difficult to live with too because
they're so obsessed with their career.
It's hard to have a relationship with
them and maybe they don't have much of a
relationship with their kids,
but they're damn good at what they do.
And part of that is is they're smart and
disciplined and they'll work nonstop all
the time.
It's like an obsession and that's the
sort of people who run things.
Those are the people who run things
while they're often also disagreeable to
because you want to.
You wrote a manage people really,
they're not going to like you,
you know when it's not an easy thing to
not be liked.
And actually if you're an agreeable
person and women are more agreeable than
men,
it's quite painful to be disliked.
But if you're in a managerial and
executive position,
the probability that people are going to
like you is quite low.
Now,
if you're a real son of a bitch,
then they're going to dislike you more.
But it's.
It's those sit in those positions are
very stressful partly because of the
interpersonal dynamics and they're also
incredibly,
incredibly competitive.
So the women hit that at 30 and they're
completely qualified in the law.
Firms are bloodied,
desperate to keep them because it's
really hard to find highly qualified
people,
especially once you've put all that time
into training them,
especially if they're also good at
bringing in business.
The law firm's trip over themselves to
try to keep them account.
The women think,
why in the world am I doing this?
Why when the world would anyone in their
right mind do this?
Especially because they're often married
by that point too,
and generally they've married a husband
who makes as much money or more than
them so they don't need the damn money,
and so they think,
well,
there's more to life than this,
which is exactly the right thing to
think,
and so they go and find a job that's
nine to five and controllable so that
they can hire a nanny and have some kids
and have a life and it's like,
yes,
that's the intelligent thing to do.
So we've got things backwards in our
culture.
We're thinking at least in part,
why aren't there more women in positions
of power?
Wrong question.
The right question is why are there any
minute all who want those positions of
power because it's not just positions of
power.
You have to be such a knothead to think
that,
oh,
it's a position of power.
It's like,
sure,
but it's a position of overwhelming
responsibility and if you make mistakes,
you're done.
Right?
It's not like you occupy that position
of power and everyone does what they're
told all the time in your life is easy.
It's like forget about that.
People are on your case to do exactly
the right thing all the time,
100 percent of the time and maybe you
want that.
Maybe you don't.
So the what I don't know what people
think is these people are all sitting in
their offices with their feet up on the
desk,
smoking cigars,
no pressing the world.
It's like that isn't how it works.
Those people,
they work flat out all the time.
So.
And that's fine if that's what you want.
And some people are like that.
They're hyper industrious people,
right?
From a trade perspective,
no matter where you put them,
if you put them in a forest with an axe,
they just wander around,
chopping down trees nonstop,
right?
Because there it's built into them,
but if you want to have a balanced life
and you should want that,
you know,
because the other thing you'll find,
and this is God's Gospel Truth,
is that the older you get,
if you have any sense at all,
the more important your family is to you
like that,
that the utility of your career,
maybe that peaks around 35 or 40 and it
starts to decline pretty rapidly after
that.
And what happens if you're fortunate,
you have someone in your life that you
love,
that you've woven yourself together with
and you have some kids so that you have
something to do from the time you're 50
till the time you're 80.
And so it's a real mistake.
It's a barren future without children.
Man,
I can tell you that it's a real mistake.
And so we do a terrible job of say,
putting that image forward and saying,
well,
yeah,
now you know,
because women have access to the birth
control pill now and can compete in the
same domains as men.
Roughly speaking,
there is a real practical problem here.
It's partly an economic problem now
because when I was roughly your age,
it was still possible for a one income
family to exist.
Well,
you know that wages have been flat
except in the upper one percent since
1973.
Why?
Well,
it's easy.
What happens when you double the labor
force?
What happens?
You have the value of labor.
So now we're in a situation where it
takes two people to make as much as one
did before.
So we went from a situation where
women's career opportunities were
relatively limited to where they were
relatively unlimited and there were two
incomes to wear and so women could work
to a situation where women have to work
and they only make half as much as they
would have otherwise.
And now we're going to go into a
situation.
This is the next step.
Whereas women will work because men
won't and that's what's coming now,
so we.
There was an economics economist
articles showing that 50 percent now of
of boys in school or having trouble with
their basic subjects and you look around
you and universities,
you can see this happening now.
I've watched it over decades.
I would say 90 percent of the people in
my personality class are now women there
will a damn man left in university in 10
years except in the stem fields and it's
a complete bloody catastrophe and it's a
catastrophe for women because I don't
know where the hell you're going to find
someone to,
to have to marry and have a family with.
If this keeps happening.
So.
And you think when you're 19 because
you're so clueless when you're 19,
you don't know a bloody thing.
You think,
well,
I'm not really sure I want children
anyways.
It's like,
oh yeah.
You tell how well you've been educated.
Jesus,
dismal,
dismal.
Without fail.
I got to tell you,
without fail,
I've watched women go through their
professional careers,
many,
many of them.
It's a very rare woman who at the age of
30,
doesn't consider having a child her
primary desire and the ones that don't
consider that.
Generally in my observation,
there's something that isn't quite right
in the way that they're constituted are
looking at the world.
Sometimes you get women who are truly
non maternal,
you know by temperament there.
They have a masculine temporary
disagreeable.
They're not.
They're not particularly compassionate.
They're not maternal.
They don't really.
They're not that interested in kids.
Fair enough,
man,
but there aren't that many of them and
there's plenty who will not admit to
themselves that that's what they most
desperately want.
Do you think women would be better off
if they had earlier?
Who knows?
Like it's like it really is a problem
now.
It's a really tough one.
I don't think anybody knows the answer
to that because
10,
11,
then you can go and get a bachelor's and
master's.
Well,
easy that way.
Having the career first and then trying
to raise young kids.
Yeah,
I,
I can't answer that because I've seen
women do a good job of it both both ways
and you do get the odd woman who manages
a high powered career and kids,
but Jesus,
those women,
man,
like they,
they,
they buy more powerful Mike Royce
because it'll take 45 seconds to cook
the food instead of a minute,
and I'm not kidding.
It's like they're,
they're up at five.
They exercise for half an hour.
They make breakfast,
they get their kids ready to work,
they go to work.
They worked 14 hours at 14 hour days,
flat bloody out.
They come home and work for another two
hours to get their kids organized.
They have a nanny to help them out and
then they work for two more hours before
they go to bed at like one and then
they're up at five and they do that
again and I'll tell you,
you better be tough if you're going to
do that physically too,
because you'll just burn yourself to a
crisp.
I've seen some women manage it,
you know,
but they're like,
they're tough and they're rare because
that's a hell of a hell of a regimen and
then if anything goes wrong,
you know,
you have a sick kid or something like
that,
or there's any sort of crisis in your
family,
it's just,
you know,
it then it becomes too much and I don't
know the answer to that,
you know,
I mean,
the advantage women have is they live
about eight years longer than men
because testosterone kills men so well
that,
that that's right.
They pay up front and gain on the,
on the,
on,
in the long run.
But how it isn't clear how our society
should sort this out,
we don't know.
And it's partly we don't know what to do
now that women have control over their
reproductive function.
It's a big mystery.
Yup.
But I think from a practical,
the workforce later on,
competition with people and that's
always.
People are always hiring joggers because
they'll have lots of.
Yup.
Yes.
Well,
and the thing is young,
stupid people have the advantage of
being young,
middle aged,
stupid people have the disadvantage of
being middle aged and so if you're going
to hire a young stupid person or a
middle aged stupid person,
you'll go for the young,
stupid person.
And I'm stupid.
I mean,
you know.
No,
not I'm being sarcastic obviously,
but I mean without,
without experience and just getting
started in the world,
you're much more likely to favor someone
young because there's an instant
explanation for their relative
cluelessness and it's a problem,
you know,
so.
So I don't know what the answer is,
but one,
one answer certainly is at least in
part,
is to start letting young women know
what being 30 and being female is like
because.
And also to disabuse them of the notion
that there's something magical about a
career.
First of all,
most people don't have careers,
man.
They have jobs and the reason you get
paid for a job is because you're being
asked to do things you wouldn't do
unless you were being paid.
And so it's not.
It's not some,
not some utopia of cigar smoking.
With your boots up on your desk,
that's for sure.
Not Hot that that would be such a utopia
to begin with.
But alright,
so.
So anyways,
so this is more differentiation of the
archetype fundamentally.
So you see the dragon of chaos here,
the potential manifesting itself into
this ambivalent feminine figure.
Both both promise and threat.
And then I've,
I've mapped this one out.
So the ambivalent feminine figure,
so sort of multi valence gives rise to
the positive mother and then the
positive mother gives birth to the hero
and that's Hercules there.
And this.
I like this image a lot.
So Hercules is in this container so that
you can interpret that both as something
feminine,
the container,
but also as a representative of culture
because it's a boat.
It's floating on the chaotic ocean here.
So that's Hercules.
He asked to be in a container that
sustains him in the murky water of chaos
and you see he's going out into the
unknown and he's got a lion skin on.
And that's partly because one of the
initiation rituals for,
for young men,
when the reliance say in the Middle
East,
and that wasn't very long ago,
was that you had to go out and kill a
lion with a spear and with a bow and
Arrow or something like that.
It's like that's impressive.
All things considered.
I mean you really think about that for a
minute.
You really want to go out and try to
kill a lion with a stick.
It's like,
it probably.
You probably wouldn't be quite the same
after you did that.
That would be my guess.
And
so anyways,
so there's.
Hercules has got his lion skin on and
that shows that he's assimilated to the
lion,
the dominant sort of animal and that
he's also mastered it and he's got his
bow and Arrow to.
So He's,
he's going to hit the target properly.
He's not.
He's someone who doesn't sin because he
can hit the center of the target and
he's got this club which I really liked
because it's covered with eyes,
just like Martech.
Mr Damian Hero.
Well,
what do you want to do when you go out
into the unknown,
it's like arm yourself and pay
attention,
and so that's what you're trying to
produce.
If you're a good mother is this figure
that can go out into the unknown,
armed,
accurate,
and able to pay attention and that's a
hell of a thing to participate in.
It's really fun.
I found having children incredibly
entertaining.
It's ridiculously entertaining thing to
do because for a bunch of reasons.
One is that it's the only relationship
you'll ever have in your life where you,
where you actually have a chance of
establishing something that's close to
perfect is with your kids because when
they're delivered to you,
so to speak,
they're there in some sense they're
perfect and your job is to maintain that
perfection.
If you can,
and you do that by being a good parent,
by being encouraging,
by being on their side,
by taking care of them,
and you can have an absolutely pristine
relationship with the child.
That doesn't mean it's not full of
trouble because it is,
but it's.
It can easily be the best relationship
you'll ever have in your life,
and in fact,
I think that's it can be the worst to
and you know,
sometimes you get unlucky in your child
is sick mentally or physically and
things fall apart and it's not your
fault,
but sometimes it is your fault,
but it's a real gift and you have to
play this game of protection and
encouragement,
right?
Protection and encouragement and get
that dynamic right?
And then you build,
you help someone develop into something
that's well exactly this,
that can take on the trouble of the
world forthrightly and man,
that's what you want.
That will make it worthwhile.
That's for sure.
Now,
let's see.
I got to figure out where I want to go
next.
Well,
I've talked about the dragon fight,
so I won't do that.
Oh yes.
We might as well look at some of the,
the,
we'll look at the same thing on the
patriarchal side of the equation so that
it's the great father and the great
mother that emerge out of chaos.
Let's say that,
um,
you can think about that over the
evolutionary time span to because it's
the fundamental differentiation of life
into one into two sexes,
in the fundamental differentiation of
being into two sexes that interact
creatively to produce,
to produce new being.
It's very,
very deep motif and so the dragon of
chaos differentiates itself into the
great farther and that's God the father.
That's an image there and you see he's
sitting in front of the sun and the sun
is behind him and the son is the thing
that comes up out of the darkness in the
morning and then shines the light on
everything with which we can see and
then collapses again into the darkness
at night.
Right?
And so and at night it fights.
It's battle with the forces of darkness
and chaos and emerges triumphant
in the morning.
And that's why we have solar gods.
Because the highest day it is
assimilated to the dominant,
the dominant phenomena in the sky.
And well no wonder because the sun is
also what gives life and that provides
light.
And that does send the darkness away and
to notice that there's something
symbolically useful in now that you can
also apply to the ideal person is
another active of conceptual metaphor,
genius and so behind God.
The father is the son,
son,
and you see he's ruling over a walled
city here.
And you can think about God the father
here as the spirit of the walled city.
That's a good way of thinking about it.
And so,
and why?
What is that spirit mean?
Well,
forget about the supernatural element of
this or the transcendent element of it.
Even.
How do you represent society?
Okay,
you've got your walled city.
why is it wall?
That's the fundamental structure of a
city.
Why is it walled?
Well,
because you have to have a border
between what's yours and what isn't.
So a border between your territory and
outside world,
right?
Otherwise it's not delineated and
defined.
So the first thing is it's something
that's walled off.
It's a,
it's a defined space inside that there's
a dominance hierarchy.
It's a masculine dominance hierarchy
because like chimps are fundamental
dominance.
Hierarchy is masculine.
Okay?
So the dominance hierarchy is what's the
same across all the men and then it's
more than that,
it's,
it's what?
It's what's the same across all men in
so far as they found their position in
the dominance hierarchy in so far as
they're supporting it in so far as
they're expanding it and in so far as
they're trying to strive up it,
so it's averaged across that,
but then it's more than that because
it's not just the man that lived.
Now,
it's also the men that used to live and
the man that will live and you think,
what are you relating to when you relate
to other people,
while in part you're relating to the
spirit of the man that will soon live
and that's what a contract is,
right?
You make a contract with the potential
society of the future.
It's embodied as a spirit and so you act
appropriately in relationship to the
patriarchal spirit because if you act in
accordance with that structure,
then you can extend your contractual
relationship with other people across
time.
It's brilliant.
It's a brilliant conceptualization and
that's independent of any supernatural
or transcendent reality.
I'm not saying it exists in in necessary
opposition to such things.
I'm just saying that you don't have to
introduce the idea of such things into
the conceptualization in order to
understand the symbolism.
Now,
I think it's more complicated than that
because if you think about this thing as
a spirit,
a spirit is an essential pattern of
personality.
Let's call it that.
To the degree that you're a well
civilized representative of the social
world,
you are actually inhabited by that
spirit and so what should happen as you
mature is that as you become older,
you shouldn't become God the father.
That's what you're aiming at.
You want to embody that central spirit
that characterizes the civilization and
that spirit is very complex and that's
why you see often see it in relationship
with the representation of God,
the son,
because the masculine spirit isn't the
spirit in general.
The spirit of civilization isn't
exhausted by it's patriarchal
representation.
That's the dogmatic form like Cyrus,
right?
It's only the structure that has to be
aligned with the thing that keeps the
structure alive.
So you want to be both of those things
at the same time,
the embodiment of the civilization and
the forest that transforms it and moves
it forward.
And that's what you're supposed to be be
being taught.
That's what university is for.
Well,
that's what he used to be for now.
It's mostly there to produce politically
obsessed idiots.
Oh,
anyways,
sorry about that.
But it gets very frustrating.
So.
Alright,
so that you'll get the picture.
That's what.
That's what that represents.
That's what he's trying.
That's,
that's an idea that's been trying to
emerge in the human imagination since
the beginning of time and it's not a
trivial idea.
It's an unbelievably profound idea.
And it,
it differentiates too.
And this is what makes it complicated.
What kind of relationship do you have
with your father,
your real father?
So often ambivalent,
right?
Because the earth,
there's an element of him that
encouraged you,
hopefully,
because without the encouragement of
your father,
man,
the world is a dismal place.
It's very difficult to be a courageous
person unless you have your father in,
in body and spirit behind you.
It's very dear,
demoralizing.
Like it really kills people not to have
their mother,
they just don't recover from that.
But,
and,
and I think people can recover from a
fragmented father relationship,
but it's the next worst thing you know,
because if your father rejects you or
doesn't form a relationship with you,
it says if the spirit of civilization
has left you outside the walls as of
little worth,
it's very difficult for people to
recover from that.
So the father should be an encouraging
forest but can be a tyrannical and
crushing force.
And so that's very,
that's a very difficult thing to get
right.
Partly because if you're my son,
then I should impose the highest
standards of behavior on you and I
should always be judging what you're
doing.
Why should be judging it with,
with the aim of making the best in you
come forward.
But,
but getting that balance exactly right.
It's very difficult.
And so it's easy to,
for a father to swing too much into
judgment,
let's say.
And then of course mothers can play this
role to,
to swing too far into the domain of
judgment and to be too harsh.
And to the degree that the father has
his own pathologies,
he's going to do that in perfectly,
you know,
he might be someone who's,
who's the father who devours his son
because he's jealous of the new
possibility,
the new potential that the struggle for,
for,
uh,
attention and love from the mother or
from the other children in the family.
There's all sorts of things that can go
terribly wrong.
So that's the farther as wise king.
And that's another symbol that's been
lost,
I would say to a massive degree in
modern universities because all we're
taught is to tear that down and to not
even notice that it manifests itself
everywhere,
especially in the universities which are
like,
there is close to an ideal environment
as you could,
as human beings have ever been able to
create.
It's as simple as that.
And if you can't be grateful for,
for the structure of the university,
with all its imperfections,
then then you're completely blind to
this element of the architect.
And that's the opposite of it.
That's the sun that devours the king,
that devours his own son.
That's a tyrant.
You know,
that's like the mother who's too over
protective.
It's the male version of that and the
mother that's too over protective says
I'll never let anything happen to you.
It's like,
well maybe you actually want to have
something happen to you.
You know,
it's a bit of an all inclusive
statement.
It's like,
no,
I'm going to make you strong so any
number of things can happen to you and
when you're,
when you need some care,
I'll be there.
But otherwise,
like out into the world with you,
that's the right attitude.
And for the father it's like get your
bloody act together,
but I'm on your side.
It's because not because I want to
destroy you or demean you or push you
down in the dominance hierarchy bit
because I want the best.
Didn't you?
To emerge.
And so you need standards.
It's like what are you doing wasting
your life?
There's way more than that to you get
your act together and bring it out.
And that's a message that people really
want to hear if they have any sense at
all.
And generally they do want to hear it.
So,
you know,
I was talking,
I've been talking to a lot of people
recently as,
as perhaps you know,
and what I was talking to one of the
leaders of the Conservatives this
morning and they're asking me about,
the person was asking me about bill see
16,
but more specifically about talking to
young people in because the conservative
leadership
struggle is going on right now.
I've been talking to a bunch of them and
I said,
well look,
one of the things you could do for young
people that no one's doing is to talk to
them about responsibility because
everyone talks to young people about
rights.
So like we need our rights.
It's like,
Oh God,
how many rights do you need?
You know,
really,
like you have more privileges than any
people who've ever lived anywhere.
Well,
it's so dull to hear that so dull.
It's so pathetic.
And,
and uh,
what would you call it?
It's so demeaning that you have to be
protected and have your rights.
It's like I said,
there's a huge marketplace for
responsibility.
That's what you want to talk to young
people about.
It's like get your act together and do
something worthwhile with your life.
For the first time,
my entire adult life,
the conservatives actually have
something to sell young people,
right?
They could sell them responsibility.
It's like,
well,
why?
Because that's where my life has meaning
with responsibility.
The more responsibility you take on,
the more meaning your life has and the
the higher degree of responsibility that
you agreed voluntarily to try to bear,
the richer your life will be and no
one's ever told that in the case.
You know,
it's like you have.
You have four kids say,
well,
that's plenty of responsibility.
You're going to have meaning.
It's going to be rough,
you know,
because it's complicated.
You have a complicated job and you try
to help the careers of the people around
you.
Do you try to solve tough problems and
aid suffering and do all of that.
It's like its weight,
its responsibility,
but it's,
there's glory in it.
There's real glory and there's deep
meaning in it and,
and,
and young people are starving for that
because no one ever tells them that.
It's like you're way more than you
think,
man,
stand up.
Do something difficult.
Do something difficult and heroic,
right?
Burst out of your barns.
It's like that's a good message.
That's a necessary message because we
have to be more than we are because if
we,
if we aren't,
we're not going to survive.
Well,
that's the sun devouring father,
that's a painting by Medina of Satan.
It's pretty horrifying one,
and that's Captain Hook.
I really liked the figure of Captain
Hook some of these popular mythological
stories.
Myths based fairytales.
Modern fairy tales have got things
really right.
Captain Hook.
Well,
he's a pirate.
So I think I told you that in the Google
engineers investigations of female
sexual fantasies,
the pirate played a large role werewolf
vampire pirate surgeon,
billionaire credibly comic comical.
Well pirate,
you know,
captain of the high seas and someone
willing to break rules.
There's a romance in that figure.
Well,
so the idea of the great father as the
pirate is a good one.
Well,
Kirk is kind of a pathetic pirate and of
course pirates are precisely that
because they're all also crooked.
And so what makes empathetic.
Well,
it isn't because he's got a hook
precisely because maybe that's just a
sign of adventure.
It's because he's being chased by a
crocodile with a clock in its stomach.
Well,
that's the dragon of chaos right now.
It's time,
tick,
tick.
Your life is going to end.
It's already got a piece of you and it's
coming for the rest,
and so hook is terrified of that.
He's terrified into resentment and and,
and the evil roughly speaking,
why he can prey on other people.
And so that's the father in the Peter
Pan Story out in Neverland,
which is the archetypal domain captain
Hook's the farther,
well,
why would peter pan want to grow up to
be Captain Hook?
Well,
he doesn't,
and so he stays.
Pan.
Pan Means everything,
right?
Like pantheism,
he stays everything.
He's the divine child.
He never wants to grow up.
Well,
why would you sacrifice the potential of
youth to become nothing but a death
obsessed tyrant?
Well,
that's the story in,
in Peter Pan,
and of course Wendy's in the story.
And so as Tinkerbell,
tinkerbell is the imagined feminine.
She's just,
she doesn't even exist.
She's just this perfect little thing
that's always around whatever peter pan
needs her,
but the problem with Tinkerbell is that
she's a fairy and fairies don't exist.
He has wendy there.
She's a real girl.
She grows up and actually marry someone.
Peter Pan stays king of the lost boys
forever and you know,
maybe it's better to be king of the lost
boys,
but not to be king at all,
but maybe not to.
King of the dam is not exactly something
to snort a dominance hierarchy to strive
for dominating.
So that's the Peter Pan Story and it's a
right.
It's the right story for the modern age,
that's for sure.
So that's a negative element of the
great father.
Here's the positive element of the great
father.
These are both read.
This is a representation of Moses
receiving the,
the rules for living from God on high.
What we talked about that already know,
and I see that that's a story of the
revelation of structure.
That's the story of mankind.
We're acting out a moral structure.
Well,
what is it now?
And then we get a glimpse of what the
moral structure isn't.
It hits people with the force of a
revelation,
then it can be articulated,
and that's partly what the story of
Moses lays out.
Then you see here,
this picture,
I really liked this one too.
This is a supplicant.
Basically someone who's who's hit hard
by a divine vision.
It's God in heaven.
Again,
very,
very similar to this with with a cross
in the background and it's something
like that to transcend your littleness
because look,
he's looking up.
That's what's at the top of the
dominance hurricane.
So what?
At the top of all possible dominance
hierarchies look up.
That's the father who supports the
sudden that's transcending his own
vulnerability,
right?
Willing to bear it voluntarily and not
too,
and not to shirk from that.
It's exactly right and it is what you
admire in people you know,
you admire people who are courageous and
they were strong,
and when you decompose that,
it means that they're able to act
appropriately and in a helpful,
compassionate,
wise and tough manner,
despite the fact that there be set with
all of the problems of mortality that
beset everyone else.
Well,
how does it go wrong?
that's all propaganda for Hitler.
Look at the imagery.
You know,
he's a night that's on the right.
He's the.
He's the night of nationalism.
Well,
that's God the father to,
you know,
it's a little bit one sided,
right?
Because there's more to the farther than
the state.
That's the thing and that's the problem
with nationalism and it's totalitarian
variance and we're moving in that
direction fast,
right?
You see Europe right now fragmenting
again because the European Union is too
amorphous and maybe not well enough
bordered and everyone is getting nervous
and they're saying back to the state,
back to the state,
it's fair enough.
Fair enough.
You need to be around people who are
like you,
so to speak,
what you have built a consensus with,
but to subordinate yourself to the state
and to make its head that the bearer of
the,
the archetype of the night without
having that element of individuality and
it is absolutely pathological.
We've already been down that road,
right?
Because the national socialists were
hyper national,
just like,
well it both in Germany and in Italy and
it's attractive.
Again,
it's interesting here.
You see hit the rest of the night and up
here there's a bird and that bird should
be the dove because that should be the
holy ghost if the iconography was
proper,
but it's not.
It's an eagle and an eagle is a burden.
Carry a neater,
right?
It feeds on corpses.
Well,
it's worth thinking about.
So that's the woman worshiping the
strong father.
Another representation of Hitler as a
night,
and then there's Hitler as wise father
you see is surrounded by people there
who focused in on him as if he's an
architect.
Archetype will import and then this is a
poster from,
from the Lis and anti Nazi poster from
the Allies and you see right there that
Hitler and the Nazis are assimilated to
a mess of predatory snakes.
It's like,
well,
why?
Well,
if you want to appeal to someone's
determination to destroy you say,
well,
here you are and you're all ready to go.
Let's go kill some snakes.
And everyone can say yes and then you
say,
well,
there's the snakes right there.
And the thing is,
it's true to some degree because you
have plenty of snakes.
Just like everyone else,
and so it's easy.
That's the first step towards
demonization and you can do it just like
that.
It's no problem.
The archetype will map perfectly,
especially if there's already tension
between the groups or if the other group
is identifiable in some manner or you
can make it identifiable.
Discussed is the best way to do that,
not fear,
disgust,
fear to fear someone.
You have to respect them.
You don't want to burn everything that
the person that you fear owns.
You want to burn everything that the
person who disgusts you owns,
and so you'll see people who are pushing
the nationalist agenda hard and Hitler
did this beautifully.
Everything that was outside of the area
in domain of purity wasn't to be feared.
It was disgusting.
It was contemptuous and it should be
destroyed and purified by fire,
and that was his message and Nazis were
unbelievably great at using fire of
purification as a symbolic message.
Well,
it,
it has an archetype will power.
Then you see here,
this is an English,
a poster from the World War II.
I'm asking people to buy bonds to fund
the American or the British war effort,
and you see these,
these talon like plause,
Japan and Nazi reaching out to the
virgin mother and her infant child,
right?
Deep,
deep use of deep subordination,
of archetypal imagery for the purposes.
While I hesitate to say propaganda
because world war in some sense was
pretty clear cut,
but you get the point and there's the
uniform reoccur.
That uniformity of the state,
right?
So the goose step,
everybody moves exactly the same way.
Everybody's put.
Everybody's turned into exactly the same
carbon copy of everyone else.
All the diversity is pushed out of the
state.
It's subordinated to the supreme leader
in the hierarchy becomes incredibly
rigid and,
and,
and homogenous.
So like,
well,
that's great for fast action,
but it's terrible if you don't know
where you're going.
You need some diversity,
needs some flaws in the cliffs
crystalline structure in case you're on
the wrong path.
And that's why you can't have everyone
being the supreme leader's acolytes.
The whole bloody thing wanders off in
one direction and because we don't know
the right direction to go wandering off
in a single direction is extraordinarily
dangerous.
You will eventually fall over a cliff,
so there's the Nazis use of of light at
night.
They were unbelievably good at there at
their.
This is one of the things that made
fascism so difficult to fight because
with communism,
because it was a fully articulated
philosophy,
you could attack it rationally,
but fascism never really did that.
What they did instead was used ritual,
right?
Huge mass rallies and highly emotionally
supercharged meetings and then the use
of light and fire and so Hitler built
the biggest parade grounds in human
history to host the Nuremberg rallies
and he would get in front of them on
this huge stage with,
you know,
with Greek columns.
Very impressive looking and have blocks
of thousands of people organized
perfectly orderly.
The Germans are good at order in order
is associated with disgust,
sensitivity,
incredibly organized,
orderly displays complete and then at
night with fire and behind him he would
have all of the search lights from the
Luther author lined up,
dozens of them shooting their light
straight up miles into the sky,
so we stand in front of these incredibly
impressive displays of light long before
there were rock shows and so forth doing
that,
you know,
it was unparalleled in history and and
addressed the crowd and it was very good
at addressing the crowd.
He'd say something and if people were
listening he'd say more of it and if
they were listening you'd say more of it
and because he was addressing the mob,
the mob God exactly from Hitler what
they wanted and we saw what that was
like $120 million people dead in no time
flat and the worst horrors that were
ever perpetrated on people.
Maybe because there's no shortage of
perpetrated horrors stolen.
Same thing.
Stalin the great father,
right?
Wise man at the helm of the ship of the
state.
This is after the wall came down,
some old man kissing a a gilded statue,
stellan before it's going to be before
it's going to be torn down.
There he is with happy children and not
the children that has policies starve to
death as you,
as you might well imagine.
Areas in his military uniform sitting on
what's all,
for all intents and purposes,
a throne.
And this is,
this is really an uncanny one.
It's very positive,
right?
That's Hitler is or still in his head of
state.
He's in this hellish Mandela of fire.
Perfect with God the father at his head.
That's Lennon.
You know,
who people still,
who people still revere.
You may know and perhaps you don't,
that I was nominated to be rector of the
University of Glasgow.
And so,
which is an honorary position.
And um,
today yesterday the different candidates
put up their manifestos and,
and the student newspaper paper put them
up and then wrote an analysis of the
manifestos which were biased and there
were appallingly biased in one sided.
And I wrote and told them that they
said,
well,
we have a perfect right to our political
opinion.
And I thought,
yeah,
well for sure,
but you know,
you are journalists after all and maybe
you could be just trying to tell what's
happening.
It's like,
no,
there's none of that.
And they said that one of the candidates
that they,
uh,
that they clearly recommended who seems
to be a person who's perfectly heroic in
his own right.
I mean,
he's taken on very many difficult legal
cases and,
and work for the oppressed and
downtrodden who clearly exist.
Um,
it was either him or another candidate
doesn't really matter that they
described as bolshy and an outspoken
Bolshie meaning Bolshevik,
like,
it's like,
well,
you know,
he's appropriately bullshit.
It's like,
it's no different than saying,
well,
he's appropriately not see.
Like,
like what the hell is that?
I mean there were 50 million people that
were killed in the Soviet Union by the
Bolsheviks and maybe twice that many in,
in China.
And that does,
it says nothing about Cambodia and all
the other places there were radical left
blood bass.
You think it's cute to call someone
Bolshie Jesus.
Okay.
It's appalling.
It's not some fashionable thing that you
do.
It's participation in some of the
deepest intellectual morasses of evil
that human beings have ever managed to
create,
and yet it's fashionable and shows you
what,
what
the universities are worth.
Well,
there's the downside of Stella.
Yeah.
Stella and his hangman.
That sort of cartoon would have gotten
you killed in the Soviet Union.
Stalin as st himself in a stain glass
representation.
There's a statue of Stella and covered
with red paint for the blood after the
wall came down there Astella as what?
It's very much like Medina's Satan,
right?
You look at that and it's exactly the
same.
Marketable idea.
There's the Americans going.
It had a cap in hand to get a little
large.
Yes.
From Papa stalad.
That's a painting of the Communists,
forcibly collectivizing,
the productive farmers in the Soviet
Union,
the early 19 twenties.
The kulaks right.
Everything from whom they stalled and
rape them and murdered them and ship
them off to Siberia and killed them and
wiped out the productive farmers of the
Soviet Union.
And then starved 6 million Ukrainians to
death and there is some poor kid in the
19 thirties who's ribs are showing,
you know,
taking a bath in this part with his eyes
wide.
And you know,
he's one of the fortunate ones because
he's still alive.
It's like bull sheet.
Yeah,
cute.
Pretty Fun.
Fashionable,
lovely.
Well that's the decomposition of chaos
into God.
The father,
half providing security in order and
half providing tyranny.
That's the archetype you have to put up
with it.
That's what your society is like.
You try to interact with it in a way
that enables the positive part of it to
come forth.
And then it does the same thing.
Chaos gives rise to the father who's
nurturing and,
and,
and encouraging.
And that gives rise.
That produces the son was very hard to
find that image I can tell you.
So.
And then that gives rise to the proper
balance of the proper attitude from the
father produces the same thing that
sutton,
who's the hero of the individual,
who's the hero?
The consciousness that conflict
consciousness of the child that's
willing to go forth,
eyes opened and voluntarily confront
chaos and turn it into order and that's
the proper pathway for human beings.
So here's a way of thinking about it or
showed you that diagram you know of how
you decompose the value structure and
you can do it right down to the level of
detail.
You know,
so you want to make dinner,
you go below that higher resolution,
you cut up vegetables,
you move your arm,
you it decomposes all the way,
differentiates down all the way to
skill.
You put these skills together,
represent them with abstract concepts.
I can make dinner,
I can take care of my family,
can undertake this job at work.
That makes me a decent father.
That's part of being a good pr.
That's part of being a good person.
The question is what's at the pinnacle
of that?
At the upper end of the abstraction
hierarchy,
because these things should be organized
all the way up into a complete
hierarchy.
What is it mean to be a good person?
Well,
it means we've walked through it.
It means you win the set of games,
you go out into the world and exploring,
you bring back what you've found and you
build yourself out of it and you share
it with other people.
That's an old,
old story that's no different than the
story of the collective hunt.
It's exactly the same thing,
right?
You,
you build yourself into someone that has
a low,
have a longterm relationship with
someone of the opposite sex,
generally speaking,
so that you can bring children into the
world and turn them into exploratory
heroes in stabilize the state.
That's what should be at the top and
that thing that's at the top,
it's the same thing.
It's integration of all
of those things into the same thing and
that's the same as the sun.
That's the same as the halo.
It's the same as the thing that emerges
from the belly of the whale.
It's all of those things and you also
know that because you know that you have
the capacity for admiration,
it's in you,
it's in you.
It's locked into your biology and it's
locked into your sociology.
You see what you admire.
Not to partial representation of the
ultimate ideal.
It's as simple as that.
So I,
I kind of nested this.
Hey,
so I should just explain this diagram
briefly.
So it was a map I tried to make in some
sense of my own identity.
I mean just using myself as an example
of someone typically situated in
society.
So now I have this role which is kind of
a high resolution role.
I'm a father and a husband and I also
run a business and so the father and
husband thing is sort of nested inside
of that because it's dependent on my
economic success to some degree.
And then that's nested inside a
capitalist structure and then that's
nested inside.
Well I said American personality,
but it's sort of that's good enough.
And then that's nested inside the
humanistic western personality and
inside the Judeo Christian personality
and that's all nested inside this thing
that's best conceptualized as something
approximating the exploratory hero.
And so that's a,
that's a value structure that's and you
know you can different.
You could differentiate that to a much
higher level than father and husband.
And we did that when we decompose things
right down to,
you know,
their motor actions and you want what
you want this and this is,
I think there's something that's
transcendent about this.
You want all those things stacked up so
they're all operating properly at the
same time,
all the way up and all the way down.
And I don't even know how far down
means.
Like if you get all those things
together,
your physiology be organized and
oriented properly to oh well,
you know,
and that means your organs work properly
in the micro elements of the board
properly and all the way down.
And then if everything is organized like
that to the society starts to work,
everything starts to organize itself
along the horizontal axis where each
level of the structure supports every
other lecture level.
And you can feel that.
I believe that's what you feel when
you're engaged in doing something
meaningful.
You can feel those things coming
together and you can also feel that as
a,
as a kind of strength.
It pushes you forward instead of pulling
you backwards.
So,
and it,
I,
I think that you're,
our nervous systems are very
sophisticated and they orient us in time
and space and they can tell us when
they're in the right place at the right
time and people love that.
And I think you experienced that when
you're deeply engaged in music as well.
It puts you there momentarily,
right?
Say you're in a cathedral and you're
listening to some remarkable music.
If the light pouring in,
you're in trees because that's what it
cathedral is.
That's what this,
that's what the arches is,
its light coming through the trees.
That's what's represented in the stones.
You're in there,
you're looking at the,
it's pouring down at you,
you're in this,
you're at the center of the world and
there's a great piece of music playing
and it's an indication that everything
is stacking up along this one poll.
That's what it's supposed to produce
that produces a religious experience.
If it works properly and you know that
you go to rock concerts,
you go listen to music.
So what the hell do you think you're
doing there?
You're not having a quasi religious
experience.
You think you'd go otherwise and just
because you don't know that that's what
happened,
that's what's happening,
doesn't mean it isn't what's happening.
People have been gathering together in
groups and transcending the limits of
their pathological individuality through
music and ritual since the beginning of
time.
Why would it be any different for us and
the lights there?
That's what the light show is for.
It's the same thing.
It's just that the religious element of
it is stripped away partly because we've
criticized that to death so carelessly
that we can't integrate it anymore into
ceremonies like that and I mean fair
enough,
but.
But it's not like that comes without a
loss.
People hunger for that more deeply than
anything else.
Questions?
Yes.
Sacrifice human sacrifice and a
psychological gratification and this
correlation between.
Exactly.
The question is,
is there a relationship between the idea
of sacrificed and delay of gratification
and is that related to
conscientiousness?
Yes.
Well,
the conscientiousness relationship is a
tough one.
You know,
we tested to see if conscientious people
were more likely to delay gratification
in classic delay of gratification tasks
and we found no effect.
We found Iq effect and we found a
reverse effect for extroversion and
positive mood,
and so what happens is that happier
people are more impulsive,
they're more likely to grasp what's
right in front of them in the present,
but conscientiousness is an
extraordinarily tough nut to crack and I
do think it's associated to some degree
with the proclivity for sacrifice of the
present to the future,
but finding ways of testing that has
proved very,
very difficult.
So but the,
the,
the relationship between sacrifice and
delay of gratification,
those are the same words,
right?
Delayed gratification is a sacrifice.
It's and you know,
there's famous experiments,
you know,
you may know the marshmallow experiment
and that is basically you take kids four
or so and you say you sit them in a room
and at a little table and you say,
here's a marshmallow.
If you don't eat that for 10 minutes,
we'll come in and give you another
marshmallow.
Right?
And so the kids and they videotape the
kids and the tapes are actually pretty
funny because the poor kids do
everything.
They can know what to look at that candy
or marshmallow like they sit on their
hands,
they hum.
They look at the ceiling.
It's like they try to distract
themselves and some of them just know.
It's like,
Oh,
to hell with it.
They eat it and then others can manage
it,
and those were the.
The.
The data showed.
You know,
I wouldn't say this study has been
replicated many times,
but the data showed quite clearly that
the kids who could delay gratification
out in early stage,
we're doing quite a bit better later in
life now.
I don't know to what degree that was
controlled for Icu because such things
matter,
but the point is is that,
well,
the point is,
the point that you're making is that you
can delay.
You can only delay gratification
intelligently though if the social
structure is stable,
right?
Because basically what if you delay
gratification,
you're making a bargain with the
potential future and the bargaining has.
Everybody's going to keep acting the
same way so that the future is the same
as the present because otherwise you'll
delay gratification and then everything
will fall apart and you won't get your
cake and you won't get to eat it,
and so society has to be quite stable.
It has to be stabilized by the
contractual relationship between people
before delaying.
Gratification is a useful strategy.
This is also why you see in chaotic
circumstances where the future becomes
uncertain.
People forgo delay of gratification
very,
very rapidly and and,
and perhaps appropriately so,
although you can get a spiral going in
the other direction.
So
yeah,
I would say it's a chicken and egg
problem because what happens as you
stabilize societies,
being conscientious,
conscientious becomes more useful,
and so then you're going to be selected
for as a consequence of being
conscientious and that's going to
stabilize the society even more.
These are,
these are roughly known as Baldwin
Effects.
So that's where,
let's call it a genetic transformation,
produces a behavioral transformation
that transforms the environment.
So the genetic transformation is more
likely to propagate.
You can get unbelievably rapid
evolutionary movements when when you get
a loop like that developing and and
they,
they happen frequently and that's,
that's also how in some sense of meaning
can be turned into a genetic can
manifest itself genetically,
so if you have an idea that spreads
through the culture and it tilts the
culture in a certain way such that those
who hold that idea are likely to be more
successful,
then the meme in the biology will align
themselves across time and and while I
think you see that happening,
that's that to some degree,
that's what's happened as religious
stories have propagated themselves as
well,
because as,
as the idea of the hero becomes clear,
so to speak,
and then it manifests itself more
clearly in the society,
then there's more rewards for doing it.
Then the selection pressures get more
positively related to that kind of
behavior in the whole thing loops
upwards.
So it's something like that.
In terms of treating mental health
disorders,
where do you think we should or have be
pharmaceutical interventions secretary?
At what point is depression and anxiety
should be treated with medicine?
That's what the.
Okay,
that's a good question.
So the question is,
how do you differentiate the utility of
behavioral slash psychotherapeutic
treatments for conditions like
depression versus medical treatments?
Okay,
so the first thing I would say is,
um,
don't underestimate the utility of
medical interventions.
Depression is a cat,
a catastrophe.
It carries with it a very high suicide
rate and it also levels people out and
it's really hard on their families and
so and it,
and it's physiologically extraordinarily
damaging.
And so if you're in a depressive state
and it's severe,
you can try an antidepressant.
You'll know in a month if it works,
if it works well,
maybe it'll help you get your life
together.
Like we could say,
well maybe you're depressed because your
life isn't very well together.
Could be.
Sometimes people are depressed,
their life is just,
it isn't fine because no one's life is
fine.
Everyone's life is a tragedy,
but sometimes people have their lives in
order,
as much as you could expect anyone to
have.
They have friends,
they have an intimate relationship,
they have a career that they like,
you know,
they're,
they're qualified,
industrious people working hard on what
they're doing and,
and,
and really playing a minimum number of
games with themselves and they're
terribly depressed.
Antidepressant man that's sometimes that
will just fix it.
And so hooray,
like you were biological entity if,
if there's something out there that can
help you strengthen yourself so that you
can prevail.
Great.
And you know,
people,
you hear,
everyone takes antidepressants,
you know,
everyone's taking them.
It's like no one takes those bloody
things without serious consideration.
Half the time I spend with my clients
who are depressed is often the two years
long attempt to get them to tentatively
try an antidepressant because there are
so guilty that they're relying on an
external crutch to sort out their lives
that they can't even tolerate it.
But you know,
I say,
well look man,
what if you had diabetes,
you know are going to take your insulin.
It's like you got stressed.
He blew out at your weakest point.
That's what happens when you get
stressed.
If there's something out there that
might help you,
it's like try it for God's sake,
you'll know in a month and you'd just
stop if it doesn't work.
Now having said that,
you want to do a multidimensional
analysis.
It's like,
well,
do you have any friends?
Do you have an intimate relationship or
are you pursuing one?
Do you have a reasonable career?
Are you as educated as you are?
Intelligent.
You have something useful to do with
your time outside of work?
Do you have a drug or alcohol problem?
Are there other behavioral issues like
sleep dysregulation and lack of eating
that are contributing to the pathology?
You want to differentiate all of that
and wherever you can make a behavioral
intervention so much the better,
but sometimes too you're dealing with
people whose lives are so rare that they
don't even know where to start.
There are different than the ones who
have everything in order to say and you
say,
well,
try this man.
Maybe you won't cut your throat in the
next month because if your dad it's
going to be hard to work with you and so
so medical interventions,
anything.
If you're sick,
you do what is necessary to get better
and you leave your pride behind if you,
if you have to,
and uh,
that that says nothing about the utility
of the behavioral interventions,
you want to hit the problem with
everything you have at your disposal.
But some antidepressants especially,
especially for people whose lives are
together and who are depressed,
antidepressants can be absolutely
miraculous.
So you know,
when you hear about the clinical
evidence in their favor being iffy,
and that's partly because the diagnosis
of depression isn't very well
formulated.
It's very different to have a terrible
life than to be depressed.
And antidepressants can only help you so
much if you have a terrible life.
So
yeah,
yes,
these activities that are meaningful and
consciousness would be very good at
identifying and I feel like some things
that are not as useful.
Sure.
That's what does some personalities,
for example,
video games are.
Okay.
So the question is can that sense of
meaning behind jacked?
And the answer to that is absolutely,
absolutely.
Because you could say that the ultimate
sense of meaning is composed of the
Union of fragmentary senses,
of meaning and the fragmentary senses of
meaning can be overwhelmingly powerful,
anger,
sexual lust and and,
and those sorts of things that you
experienced when say when you're playing
a video game which are very carefully
calibrated to keep you on the,
on the edge of exploration,
let's say now I'm not a full of video
games because games are complicated and
it isn't clear what people are doing
when they're playing them,
you know,
they may be expanding their cognitive
skills,
they may be learning to cooperate,
they may be learning to engage in
complex problem solving and so,
but part of it's also a matter of
balance,
you know,
50 hours a week,
probably not,
unless you're going to go pro,
right?
Because there's other things you need to
be attending to.
It's not a stable solution for your
family,
your society.
It's too one sided.
Yeah.
And you can get pulled down rabbit holes
of all sorts that are one sided pursuits
of meaning.
So it's something we're actually going
to talk about as the later classes
unfold.
The question is how do you stop yourself
from falling prey to a path or a sense
of meaning?
And I think one of the answers to that
is don't lie because what you're hoping
is that your nervous system is
sufficiently healthy and well program so
that what it reads out to you is
reliable and if you pathologize your
psyche by either through sins of
omission,
let's say or or outright deception,
you're gonna work that internal
structure and it's not going to read out
properly to you and then your sense of
meaning will lead you astray.
So like one of the reasons for speaking
the truth,
I shouldn't say that because you don't
know how to speak the truth,
but you do know how not to lie and it's
a game.
You're playing with yourself.
You can define the damn lies.
No one else has to do that for you.
You,
you try not to otter falsehoods because
you wore your neurological structure by
doing so,
and then it will read out pathologically
and then if you rely on it to guide you,
it will run you right off a cliff.
So that's why there's a moral element to
this is if you're going to rely on your
sense of meaning,
make sure that you don't pollute the
mechanism.
See,
this is.
This is partly why people go to
confession,
right?
Which is,
which is like a serious
psychotherapeutic technique.
It's like,
okay,
what stupid miserable wretched things
did I do this week?
That's a good thing too to make
conscious,
right?
Because maybe you cannot do them the
next week and you think,
well,
why would you bother?
It's like,
well,
you're in a ship sailing across the the
stormy seas.
If,
if you're,
if you're hacking holes in it with a
pick ax,
you should probably pay attention to
that before you sink,
so it's a good idea to keep,
to keep what you're doing.
That's stupid in mind so that you can
stop doing it,
and so then you can more and more rely
on yourself and your and your own.
You know,
your own conscience,
let's say,
as a guide to proper action.
You know,
in the Pinocchio story is that the
conscious was not an unerring guide for
Pinocchio.
It had to learn and so and so.
It's also partly pushing yourself into
new situations and differentiating
yourself so that you get wiser and so
it's courage as well as truth,
that those might be the two.
There's more beauty,
courage,
truth,
you know,
the fundamental virtues.
Yeah.
Why be virtuous?
That's the question.
And so that you can bear the suffering
of life without becoming corrupt.
Right?
It's practical.
If there's nothing more practical than
that,
so unless you want misery and
people do,
you know it's exciting.
Misery.
So other questions?
All right,
then.
See you next Wednesday.