Well, you wanted it and it's back.
That's right. Palm is back on Verizon.
What's Palm you say? I mean,
I didn't hear you say that,
but I'm guessing you said what's
Palm? Well, let me tell you, palms,
a small practical companion device that
syncs with your existing smartphone.
It doesn't replace your smart phone,
but it connects to it so you can leave
your phone behind and then you can take
palm with you. So f you phone. I got palm.
I think that's the idea of palm.
Go to palm.com to learn
more because clearly I'm not
helping run to your nearest
Verizon store to check out
palm for yourself and say
to them, Conan explained it,
but not very well.
Hello,
my name is Wanda Sykes.
Hmm.
And I feel uh,
somewhat trapped about
being Conan O'brien's friend
because he's right here in
front of me.
Back to
school.
Hey there,
welcome to Conan O'brien needs a friend.
This is a show where I Conan O'Brien.
I talked to celebrities and
interesting personalities,
basically people I've had
on my show over the years.
And I tried to see if we can become real
friends, not just on camera friends.
Um, aided in my quest by my
assistant sona. Hi. Hello. Hey Sona.
And now my producer Matt Gorley. Hi. Okay.
Today's guest is a comedian
who is brilliantly funny.
She's been coming on my
show for a very long time.
I love her Wanda Sykes.
Okay. So it sounds to me like you're not
doozy astic about the idea of being my
friend.
You're not sure how you feel about it.
You feel like this is a
contrived situation. Yes. Yes.
This isn't something that
would naturally come about.
Were you an IRF Froggert shop and we
bumped into each other. Right? Well,
you would never find me at a frozen
shop. So right there, you know,
absolutely nothing about me that's
Sydney would have said, oh, you know,
walked into this that we were in the same
bar or, right. Like Weirdos, dump junk.
It's that we have to do, yeah, we have to
get junk junk. It's old. And then if, say,
you know, we were at the, at the hotel
lounge or whatever, and at a bar,
that's more of it.
That's a situation that you could see
unfolding much more than I walk into a
frogger shop and you're there
having like a triple scoop cone,
right. With organic organic.
Know what, maybe if, if, if,
if I were with the kids, then you'll,
then you would catch me in a shot.
Yeah, I do. Maybe I know more
about you than you think I do.
Maybe. Maybe I knew you
have twins, you have twins.
That seems overwhelming to me. That
just was very, very overwhelming.
I mean, the, the first week I
really was thinking that, yeah,
I might have to take one
back. I know. I honestly,
I'm serious. I honestly
thought that, but I was like,
we have a boy and a girl and,
and I was just wondering which one would
my wife pick right to return. Right.
And uh, and then I was like, she's,
she's not going to be in on this.
I think I'm sold on this idea.
I don't think she would have gone
away with returning one. Nope.
Is the return policy. I don't even know.
That sounds crazy. They're gorgeous kids.
They're beautiful kids.
You know?
No one's stones were trained one hair.
I could've got a nice penny for one of
them. You thought about this, did you,
did you scout out what the prices are?
Inquiries.
I was pretty sure I can get six figures.
You know what? That's a great way
to say I love you too. A child.
I looked into it and you know,
worth six figures and
I kept you my mother.
I'm Irish Catholic, so big surprise
here. I'm one of six kids. Wow.
You fall in that line of sick. He, I
am in the middle now. A lot of people,
math nerds are like, how can you be
the middle of six? You don't care.
I don't care. But I'm the third from
the top and the third from the bottom.
So yeah, I think of myself as wait
for it from the, but that's not right.
Wait, that's wrong. That means
there's another kid in here somewhere.
The seventh he didn't make it.
We left him in the attic too long.
Supposed to crack a window anyway.
I,
I'm forced from the
bottom third from the top.
But my mom had a kid like every
six months. I don't know. Shit.
It's impossible. It's not. If you have
the Irish gene, you can have a child.
You can have up to two
children a year. Wow. Yeah.
And so my mom had litters then.
It's craziness.
Neil was born in 61 [inaudible]
62 Conan 63 Kate 64.
Gene 67. What happened there?
They waited a few years.
Then Justin comes piling along right
after that. I, it's insanity and,
and uh, it was the wild west
in my house. No one was,
no one was paying attention to us.
Winning around.
Your kids are both being doused with
love. I bet all the time. They are pretty.
That's nice. They get a lot of
attention. I need to be reparented.
I'd like to come to your house and be
reparented by you and your wife if that's
possible or reparented.
I'd like you to be my painful.
You don't want to deal with me.
No one wants full,
no one wants to deal with
me and you're so tall.
That's puts a strain on my neck. Cause
now I'm always happy to, you know,
also just to be friends,
you have to agree to it that we have
a lot of conversations and seed it.
I, I'm not going to be walking
around with your neck a neck.
What if I agreed to always be in a
wheelchair? Oh, that's even better.
One of those little scooter
ones. That's even, yeah.
You and I are walking down the
street eating frogger, a Wanda Sykes,
Conan O'brien and I'm in one of those
electric scooters and we have adventures
together. Yeah. Because what I've
noticed is that I've known you for years.
You came on my show very
early on, man. Yeah.
You were one of the people that came
on very early on in the show and uh,
we've known each other a long time and
I've always loved your comedy and I love
you as a person. I really do think you're
terrific and yet we're not friends.
Real friends. Yeah. And I'm thinking,
and that happens a lot on my show where
I can really connect with people on the
TV show and then, uh, TV
shows over and buy and we hug.
Right.
And then you get in a big black SUV
and you're dripping away and that's it.
And I don't see you again unless this sun,
another work thing.
G or so you only come on my show
to promote something? Um, no,
I've been on your show just to
like hang out again. Have to ask
some funny stuff to say.
Yeah, I'll go, I'll go.
But what I'm getting from this does,
you've never called the show and said, um,
you haven't called me and
I have nothing to promote,
but I just like to see Conan.
You've never done that? Nope.
Oh yes. It hotter in here. Good
Lord. What is going on? This is,
we're going to switch rooms
and this is, um, all right,
this is a former Brandon here.
Sweet Jesus.
We're making a Samurai Samurai Brad
in the back. It is warm in here. Yeah,
this isn't the best. Um, but we're
going to get a better place. Okay.
And so just chill and then you're
going to come back to the nicer place.
But when I come back, hopefully between
that time we would have, you know,
developed some type of a friendship.
I hope so.
It would maybe start with you
inviting me to your house. Yes.
That's a stretch, right? What do you,
what do you mean that's a stretch. Wow.
That is the really busy in
the most basic way. It takes
a while to get into the house. Since
the dawn of time, people have said,
come to my home.
That is how ancient people
showed friendship and
cordiality and I just suggest
it and you shut me down so fast,
but when you make it to my house and
I'm like, Hey, come over, you know,
hang out at my house.
That, that, that's like,
I'll help you had a body
friendship. Wow. Yeah. Okay.
That's a stretch for me right now.
Yeah. Right now we're still at the,
maybe just somewhere you'll
meet me in a neutral. Yeah.
Yeah. That's like your, that
goes well then it's like,
yeah, come on over man. Okay.
You just did. Basically, they always
tell someone who's meeting, uh,
you know,
a drug king pin meet in a public place.
So he can't tell you that's
how you're treating me.
You're treating me like
I'm a potential murderer.
Murderer. No, that's a
stretch. You know, we'll say,
well I'm just like, just getting
to know so one. Okay. Right.
Just make sure it's a public place where
there's a lot of people there do a lot
of people, but you want some people
there in case I, I start to flip out.
Other people were there to
restrain me physically. Yeah.
Yeah. We're going to be
really good friends. You know,
it's funny cause we just mentioned, I
just mentioned murderers. You and I,
and I've talked with
you about this before,
but we do share something in common that
we can talk about when we become real
friends. We both love murder, love,
murder shows you love them.
I love them. I love them.
To the point where I had to like take
a break from them because I was just,
you know, looking at
people as like, yeah bitch,
you probably got an body in this
trunk or really just poured.
Yeah. Or I'll look at couples and
I'll think like who's going to do it?
Who's going to kill those until yeah.
There and then,
and then cry on the local news and say,
I can't believe you can't. You can't,
you call it out. Now if someone goes
missing and if the spouse is on,
on the news, don't you know? Yes. You
can tell automatically right away. Yeah.
Right away.
I know from nine one one calls,
you can tell from a nine one one call.
Yup.
You can just listen to the timber
of their voice. And I go, oh man.
Yeah he did that. He said,
what is he talking about?
Cause he's usually forcing
it a little bit. Yeah.
Or given too much information. Yes. Yeah.
Oh
cause I was at Mcdonald's and I had,
and I have the receipt.
Did it, did it. That's so true. Yeah.
I watch every single murder
show and there's that show. Um,
is it investigative files? Uh, what does
that forensic files, forensic files.
Oh yeah. They take over a headline
news after a certain time. This is,
so what happens is I've stumbled upon
forensic files and I've watched maybe 18
in a row and I was upset
and I was supposed to like
pick up my son and I didn't.
And he's wandering in the woods alone
and I'm watching a show and I'm,
and I can't, I can't stop. I
can't stop it. And I'm just,
I'm fascinated by those shows.
And I'm always fascinated by how many
people murder for the smallest thing.
Like he had some butterscotch candies and,
and his friend wanted three of them,
you know,
so he went in there and just blood and
hair on the walls and mean just to cry,
you know, and he leaves with two
butterscotch candies. I don't know.
I would,
I love murder so much that I have said
many times I would love to murder or even
be murdered if I was murdered.
I'd be honored. Isn't that weird?
Because I'd be like,
I made it into the club.
I'm such a fan of murder that someone
murdered me. Yay. I made it out to murder.
Someone took the time to murder
me and now I get to be in the,
and now everyone gets to talk
about who did it. And uh,
it's probably a weird message to
put out there. It is. It is. Um,
we've talked about this a lot,
but I do think that you were in the best
named movie of all time and you know
what I'm talking about. You
can't get enough of it. I can't,
I can't get enough of it. Pootie Tang.
Yeah. Every time I'm on the show you,
the thing is,
it's been Pootie Tang and the thing is,
I don't know how long ago
that was now, Lord, that was
probably 18 years ago. Yeah.
2016 years ago.
Who knows?
Someone out there knows
exactly when it was. Yeah.
If I was interviewing you when you are
110 I would ask you about Pootie Tang and
it regardless of what else you would
done in your life. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
You could have just become the first
African American woman to be elected
president at the age of 110 years old.
And my first question to you would be,
let's talk about Pootie Tang
and then I'd be fired as an
investigative journalist. Yes. Yes.
Such a incredibly, yeah,
and it made me laugh though.
You'd lie. I would enjoy it if I can
make them laugh. That's all I want to do.
That's all I want to do. Do you
have a podcast? Cause if you don't,
you're the only person who does.
I don't have a podcast.
Would you like to have this one?
I'll give it to you.
It's so generous. Yeah,
they're not. It's really,
it's just a couple of microphones and some
guys I've ever met. I don't have them.
I'm happily going to give them to you.
They all come in one van
with all the equipment.
It really is like a dominoes
acme, like you can have, you know,
that's actually a good deal.
A good idea would be a company that you
call him up and within 30 minutes or
less they come up and they set up a
podcast and your house and then you do a
podcast and it is available
to automatically download
for all of your friends.
That's an idea. You could make some
money off of it and Matt would that work?
That's basically what you got here,
that that's already happened.
That's why it's so hot in here is
that we're in the back of a van.
Right back of a van. Yeah. But he's a nice
man. It's really not. It's really not.
It's mine. It's home.
Yeah. It's a nice fan.
I haven't seen shag carpet like this when
I got to sleep in it in quite awhile.
Carpet. Oh my God. But
you know what it is. Uh,
you probably get asked all the time
like people, cause you're funny,
you're great cats do podcasts,
do podcasts.
And I was getting asked all the
time to do podcasts. Then I thought,
I'm going to have a podcast just so I can,
that's my excuse to not do other
podcasts. Oh, I didn't think about that.
If you didn't want to come here today,
I could have just told you.
Coulda just said one of
them. I'm going to, no,
you don't have one. No,
everybody's got one.
Maybe that'll be my podcast and
basically all it is is it's your day.
You live in your life. You put no effort
into it. You were just might for the day.
Someone like this producer,
Matt chops it up into a podcast
and people listen to it.
They would,
people like you,
they would listen to it and then that's
your excuse for not doing a podcast.
It's your get out of jail free card.
All the podcasts that I got out of doing
because I'm doing this podcast. Yeah.
There's no awkward
conversation with Mark Marin,
dax shepard or Chazz Palminteri.
I mean literally everybody's got one
and now it's time for a segment called
Conan O'Brien pays off the mortgage on
his beach house. Yup. No reason
to get into this at length.
I have a mortgage on my beach house.
Got To pay it down.
So let's talk about erectile dysfunction.
It's a problem for a lot of guys.
Fortunately not me. I almost,
I think I have the opposite problem.
What I uh,
don't mean this to
sound creepy in any way,
but I am at attention 24 hours a day.
If it needs to stop right now,
please 24, seven, it's the worst.
It's a problem.
I've had to have most of my jeans altered.
Scientists are studying me to
find out how I'm able to do this.
A constant source of pain.
But anyway, for some men,
they have the opposite problem,
which is erectile dysfunction and they
don't want to talk about it and they
think, oh, I can fix this on my own. I
can buy some popsicle sticks or whatever.
You can't. Popsicle sticks
and glue do not work. Oh,
you're laughing a little too hard there.
SONA.
I don't know what you've experienced in
your life, but why me tell you something.
You need Roman in your life.
Romans a one stop shop where licensed
us physicians can diagnose erectile
dysfunction. And then he shipped
the medication right to your door.
If you don't have that embarrassing thing.
I've had to buy Sabz and ointments at the
drug store and it's tough because they
recognize me.
I'm quite famous and I'm asking for
something that I wish I didn't have to ask
for.
I'm purchasing a,
an adult diaper or something and I don't
wear them, not because I need them,
but for the comfort. And also they look
great. My wife thinks they're sexy,
but the point is, there's no waiting
rooms. There's no weird conversations.
You can handle everything online.
All you have to do is visit.
Get roman.com/conan.
Fill out a brief brief medical onboarding.
Uh,
you have a little chat with a doctor and
then you get FDA approved Ed meds and
they're delivered right to your door. And
you know, it's nice. The package says,
not erectile dysfunction meds on it.
That subtle. I made that up, that dust.
That's not true. I really
need this ad to end. Okay.
For free online visit,
go to get roman.com/conan that's get
Roman dotcom slash Conan for a free online
visit.
If I didn't believe in this,
what I let them use my
name and the Promo Code.
You know why I like me undies?
No,
it sounds like underwear that was named
by a pirate. That's why I love them.
I ain't got to me undies.
I'm wearing me undies.
I am and then the parents
like with micro modal fabric,
how the parent knows that the parent knows
all about cause they have micro modal
fabric.
That's what me undies has.
Plus as you know I'm always
wanting underwear that's
got different cuts for men
and women because we're built differently.
I'm actually,
I've been told I'm built a lot like a
woman but there are differences and they
just got a lot of cool stuff. Me undies,
they sent us a package. They did.
They came to the office to the day and
I tried on the me undies. Unfortunately,
I tried them on over my
jeans and that was a lawsuit,
but so they have a great
offer for my listeners.
First Time purchasers get 15% off and
free shipping when you purchase any me
undies you ordered by 1216 wait a minute.
I think it's past 1216 wow.
Okay.
Get yourself a time machine,
an order by 1216 to receive
your order before Christmas.
If you're listening to this now, it's too
late. God knows when they even run this.
All this Christmas stuff
is bullshit at this point.
If you're trying to get this for
Christmas, you fucked up big time.
That's right.
And if you've got a time machine,
you wouldn't go back and stop Lincoln
from getting shot at Ford's theater.
You'd go back in, order me undies
to make the Christmas deadline,
God. But anyway, it's a great underwear.
Get 15% off a pair of the most comfortable
undies you will ever put on free
shipping and 100% satisfaction guaranteed
when you go to [inaudible] dot com
slash Conan
did it take you a long time to get
here today? Do you live close by?
Please tell me it was,
this was this close by.
My biggest fear in show is putting people
out.
I hate when I feel like I've taken someone
out of their day if I'm imposing on
them. That makes me
nuts. It makes me crazy.
I hope you at least got to
run some errands on the way
here or on the way back.
I said did would you do?
Um,
I stopped and picked up my kids
from the bowling alley. Your kids,
they're old enough to go to a bowling
alley alone. They were with the AU pair.
Okay, Annie, for a second. I thought you
just left them at the bowling alley. No,
you like don't just leave you like
duct tape his colon and come on
money around like that.
That's 12 figures.
I think that's how it works. Again,
that getting, I'm not good at the math.
When they do boulder,
they put the guards up on either side.
You have those little guard rails
come up. They do. I worry about those,
but when they bolt with me,
I make them put them down good.
Because my son, my first son, I
took him bullying those rails,
came up and he took the ball
and he whipped it and it
caremed off each 15 times
way down and then accidentally knocked
over a couple of pins and he looked at,
he turned and looked at me like I did it,
I did it daddy.
And I thought this generation is done.
They're done.
Before the [inaudible] started,
this kid, a Turkey could have,
could have nudged a ball and it would
have knocked down as many pins as my sons
did cause it just bounced
off. And he goes, look,
if elation and then what is this?
This no put,
put the rail in his day and if
you're going to throw, you know,
20 gutter balls in a row. So
bid, learn now, learn now. Yeah.
That's the generation was a generation
that understood that and they fought
world war two. Yup. Well they
actually started World War II.
They told him the greatest generation.
I think it's bullshit.
He started as much as they, when they made
a mess and they cleaned it up. Anyway,
that's going to get me in trouble.
Two broke out here. Is that like Bro,
cause listen, fight podcast,
he probably has a plaque cas,
I don't think he has a podcast. No, he's
carving a radio out of wood right now.
Our raw rolling or Rio.
Um,
we talked about pornography last time,
but I forget what we talked about.
They have no idea it was that your
son knew the term pornography from the
Simpsons. And my son came up to me,
said what's pornography? And I said,
well that good, why do you
know that? And he said,
cause I was watching an episode of
the Simpsons where they talk about
pornography and it's an
episode that you wrote.
And that was an awkward dad
moment for me because once you do,
I said that's a different Conan O'brien.
I'll go to your room.
I did. I said that I believe in the
old school. I bet. I bet. I bet.
Did you ever have your mouth washed
out with soap as a child? No, I did.
Oh my mouth washed out with soap.
If you got a woman to look after us,
who's from Prince Edward
Island and even Murphy,
she was old school and my parents weren't
in the house and I said some word that
wasn't supposed to say.
I remember she took me into
the bathroom and she put dial,
she wet some dial soap and in
and out of my mouth. And what?
I remembered that it caked on
the back of my teeth. Oh yeah.
That really turned out okay.
You did turn it around, right?
Why did you write at the
end of the question mark?
You turned it around and then
you said, right, you only meet,
you don't want me to your house. You
only meet me in a public place and okay.
And you said that you'd like other
people to be there in case size suddenly
become physically crazy.
You said you'd like to be murdered.
So I'm pretty sure that
all the things I've said,
you can just throw those out the
window and let's just start with,
you said you'd like to be Merck.
That's true.
That's pretty few creepy dude.
Totally one. That's creepy. You one.
Okay. I'm just, you looked around the
room like other enough people here. Yes.
You're fine. This isn't a trap.
This isn't a trick. Won a Europe.
You're allowed to leave at anytime.
Okay. Let me use it anytime.
Horrifying.
I think that this podcast,
we may end up only doing like two or
three of these because my effort to find a
real friend is it's a mirror that I'm
looking into. That's what I'm seeing.
I'm seeing myself and I don't like what
I see Wanda. I don't like what I see.
A very sad and needy man.
What are the things that you enjoy doing
that you like to travel or when like
when you'd take, take the show on
the road and I love doing that. Well,
do you travel outside of show? Yes. Yes.
I do enjoy traveling. I do enjoy
traveling. What do you like to go? Oh,
I see what you're doing now. It
is your podcast. I like this.
Where do we like to go? I like to
go. Uh, I love to go to Europe.
I love to see things that are a
lot older than I am. They call.
It calms me down.
When you see like a,
when you're in a building that's like
800 years old, I just think, oh yeah,
I don't matter. In a good way.
Not in a bad way. I think when,
when I'm in cities that have been
around when I'm in Jerusalem,
I just think, what am I worried
about? This has been here so long.
We're all here for such a short time.
Relax.
I get a great perspective and it lasts
for about 18 minutes and then I'm right
back into, I can't make more of
my TV shows and that's not enough.
I need a podcast.
I need even more than that.
I must have more and so
it's, it's tough. It's tough,
but I love the perspective you get from,
do you travel a lot?
Go to Europe often France,
and know my wife is French so it's
quite to be with someone who speaks the
language. I had to be a nice
trip for the three of us.
You,
your wife and me in France,
not hearing anything from you.
This is the longest silence on a podcast.
It has been recorded.
Thank yet
I could stay in a separate hotel,
but we would meet in the morning and
we would spend the day with each other.
Now you're just exhaling what
a barge cruise in France.
Yeah. You and cause you
can hop on and off. Yes.
And you go through the whole country.
You can get off,
grab a bike just so you can steal it,
but you can take any bike.
It's not a crime and crime. As long as
you put a loaf of bread in the basket,
it's not crime. A loaf of
bread in the basket. And if,
if you're going to be gone with
the bike for like over three hours,
you got to put a bra on. You know they
have, but they have it all worked out.
That's what's great. Are you going to
do that? You can take a barge cruise.
We were looking into that. All right,
well I'll look into it. I'll let you know.
I'm going to wait by the phone.
Okay. Until you call. All right.
And I will go with you and we will
travel on a barge going all the way to
France.
Maybe let's just start small like
like maybe go to Canada first.
You know like, Oh, I thought you
were in Montreal. Montreal is nice.
I thought you meant they
do go there and test it.
See if we, you know. Right.
I was thinking when you said start
small that we would stay in La.
There is an La River
and we could find a place,
a part of it that has some water and we
could probably go as far as like 50 or
60 feet and then get out and spray paint
something on the tanks up there and
then all run in different directions.
But yes, I think you're right.
I think it's smart to test it out, test
it out and see if we're all copacetic.
We all get along. Yeah. Now I'm thinking,
oh we can just go down
to the all ball pawn,
you know and and grandpa croissant.
That's something I could do that.
Okay, let's try that first. Let's try
that first. We're going to do that.
You're not,
we're going to Wanda Sykes and I are
going to go to an all album palm.
Don't give him the address because which
one? Don't tell them which one. Right.
I don't want to see you get murdered.
Well that's weird cause it's actually
what I'm dreaming of to actually have all
those guys standing around me and saying,
wonder what happened. That's cool.
Thank you so much. Thanks for
coming in. Have you sometimes,
right when you only one of your, your
uh, investigation, Discovery Ryan there,
flip over to bt and
watch some black murder.
Really drama. What? Wait a
minute. I know. I always,
I don't know why, how we segregate
murders. Somehow murder gets segregated.
But wait a minute.
How is the BC murder channel
different call a fatal attraction?
It's just black people getting murdered.
But how would,
how do you notice what's the, is there
a cultural difference in murdering this?
Usually infidelity. Infidelity.
Like you're not going to see on,
on the black murderer,
you know,
somebody killed their neighbor because
the dog wouldn't stop barking. Best. Yeah.
That's white murder.
Murder.
Also white people love to murder
each other over insurance policies.
Yes. And it's all, we don't
have it. And it's, and it's,
and it's always have show pilots
and it's always for an incredibly,
like there was an $800 deductible that
he managed to get by killing his wife in
a murder. That costume, $10,000
a, I'm going to do that.
I'm going to start watching because
as a country we need to come together.
So I pledged to now start watching murder
on the bet channel and I'm going to do
that.
It sounds like you think about that.
I'll tell you when we're at the
elbow pawn. Okay. That's a date date.
Something you didn't think I
could do it one is a tricky one,
but I did it when it's like,
thank you so much. Thank you.
A pleasure and honor and uh, I
hope to see you very, very soon
and silence.
Oh,
and now it's time for another installment
of Conan O'brien pays off the mortgage
on his beach house.
Sony. You're aware that I've made some
questionable hiring decisions in the past.
Yes. You have. Would you consider
yourself one of those? No,
I would consider myself an
excellent hiring choice.
You were an excellent hiring choice.
How long have you worked for me?
Almost 10 years, right? You were great
assistant for a year. The thing is, um,
that's not nice.
No,
you were a great assistant and then
you are an even greater assistant.
There it is a nine.
I'm waiting for the joke
that inevitably follows.
You're terrific assistant. There was
no joke there. That was me being real.
I don't know what to do. Well, first
of all, you sure I'm being sincere.
I look in my eyes. What do
you see? Just pure evil.
Now you are a great hire,
but you have to admit there was a
chance that I wouldn't have found you.
It was just pure luck, right? I
just found you, taught you English,
brought you to this country.
It was like splash.
You were like the mermaid that
didn't know how to eat a lobster.
Remember you taught me how to be a human.
Yes.
Oh, you love yourself. Oh God.
If I could give myself an award right now,
I would.
The point is you don't want to leave these
important hiring decisions to chance,
which is why zip recruiter comes to mind.
I don't know why it comes to mind,
might be this piece of paper and in
front of me that says ZipRecruiter
read verbatim,
but ZipRecruiter comes to mind
because they find candidates for you.
That's what they do.
They find uh,
qualified candidates for you. They
have this powerful matching technology.
Ziprecruiter was rated number
one by employers in the US.
That's a true fat cause.
It's on this piece of paper.
And so when I go to zip recruiter,
now Sona,
God forbid I ever have to
replace you in a month. What?
But in a month I'll use
zip recruiter in a month.
I'm saying God forbid,
but you're seeing a specific timeline.
It's more like five weeks. I feel as
though you have planned something.
I have not,
but I've found ZipRecruiter to be
excellent at finding your replacement.
Should I ever need that person?
His name is Kyle.
I don't like Kyle. Well, he's terrific.
Thank you ZipRecruiter right now my
listeners can try ZipRecruiter for free,
for free.
Beat that at this exclusive web address.
Zip recruiter.com/conan if you like
the show, show your support to it.
And ZipRecruiter by going to
zip recruiter.com/conan that.
And it says spelled out C. O.
N. A. N. This is humiliated.
That's zip recruiter.com/conan C o.
N. A. N. Ziprecruiter is
the smartest way to hire.
That's not their slogan.
That's when I just thought of that.
I'm giving to zip recruiter
one. Uh, one followup question, Wanda,
on a scale of basically one to 10,
10 being best,
what do you think are your chances or the,
the likelihood of being
friends with Conan.
And after that discussion I would say,
and you can speak freely.
He's not in the room, right? Right.
Um, how would go and say like, uh, uh,
6.5 you feel safe with him? I
feel safe with him. Oh God, no.
Oh, I will have a weapon on me. Okay,
good. Alright. Yeah. So 6.5 with a weapon.
Well put that little asterisk,
6.5 with a weapon and then your weapon
of choice and he packing heat. Okay.
Thank you very much.
Huh?
Now it's time for Conan
gives a performance review.
Can I give a performance
review of how you just said,
now it's time for Conan to
give a performance review,
which I think is a better way to say
it then what you said. I'm impressed.
This is not your native language
and I'm an in very impressed.
It is actually my second language.
So yeah, this joke's on you.
I'm impressed that you note seven
languages. I know. Three. Okay.
How many do you know? Um, I am
impressed. I was saying I am impressed.
I only know five.
So good for you.
Now it's time for Conan to give
a performance review. All right.
I have a very good staff.
I want to start by saying that and uh,
but I think one of the reasons we have
such a good staff is that I'm, well,
I'm tough on them and uh,
I let them know when they've let me
down and uh, I also like to praise them.
So it's the whole rainbow of emotions,
but more putting down and praising.
I see the face from making, yeah. Today,
we're going to give a performance review
to someone who's been on my staff a
very long time. Aaron Blair. Erin,
what would you say is your title
on the show? I don't even know.
I don't know either. You're the web
guy. Yeah, I'll you when people ask,
I say web guy. You're a web guy. You
A, you've been with me a long time.
Anyone who's watched my clueless gamers.
That's a Aaron [inaudible].
Aaron, you've been with the
show. How long? Oh my God.
I started as an intern in 2001 that you
started in 2001 you were a young kid at
the time. It's still gray hair
though. Yes. You've always
had, you've had gray hair.
You look like Newt Gingrich when you
were 14 years old. That's true. It is.
It's incredible. Yeah. You know, I
felt like I made it work. You know,
you do. You make it. I wasn't
criticizing you in any way.
I was just saying it was striking that
you had this gray hair and I thought,
oh my God, Newt Gingrich's walking
around the office. Oh wait, no.
That's a 14 year old boy. You
have completely gray hair. Yes.
Okay. And you'll have a
completely gray beard. Right?
But then it is colored dark brown,
right.
Your mustache and right.
Just below where your chin goes,
it looks like you're a gray haired
person who stuck his face into a bowl of
cocoa to take a sip.
So my question is,
are you coloring that part? No. Why would
I call her this part? Because it's so,
I don't understand how this is
color, the whole thing. Why? Who?
Why would I'm asking you? Well
know to answer your question. No,
I'm not coloring that part.
That's just what God has given me.
But so do you know what you're talking
about? That a little unusual looking,
doesn't it look like he dipped down? There
was some, there was a hole in the ice.
He was walking through the woods
with completely gray beard.
There was a hole in the ice.
He dipped down and saw a chocolate
stream running under the ice,
but the whole would only accommodate
an area slightly larger than his mouth.
So he dipped down to sip it and it got
his mustache and the bottom of his,
his chin get beards. So let's talk
about you and your performance.
You have done a lot. I'll go on. Uh,
on the record and play was one of
the first people to push me to, uh,
to expand my foolishness onto the
internet and to shoot silly little things.
And uh, and you do a spectacular
job. You want us, uh,
an Emmy for your work.
So you would think too,
I want to settle down power of saying,
okay, I've got one of those too. No,
I got you two of them. I know. All right.
Oh, you got them from me. Well, I'm,
you got me. I didn't. You
got me using your work.
Why don't you touch my work is
in the clay that you have get.
Oh my got you to Emmy. No,
I got you two. Don't get,
I, you hell do you think you are?
You've won yourself too mean.
What do you want us, what do you want
me to say? Yes. How about despite you,
this is going despite you.
I just want it just, man,
I was about to give you such a good
performance review when you know you're
doing an amazing job. And I,
and I do mean that sincerely.
I have a few notes for
you. Oh boy. You know,
I think that you sometimes on camera are
way too loud and Jess and you clap your
hands a lot and you act like you are
running a children's show and you yell and
we do a lot of live streams together and
you really are sometimes acting like a
circus performer who knows that
he has seconds to live if he,
if he doesn't, uh, amp up the energy is
just a little more. So I'm telling you to,
as you've got to calm down
just a little bit. Right. Okay.
You comfortable getting that feedback?
I mean it's,
you've given me this feedback quite a bit
and in public many times. Yes. So, uh,
now can I just say, I realize
I'm being loud. Can I explain,
you know what I'd never get, and this is
great, I never get the chance to explain,
I to not talk back to you,
but whatever.
The nice way to say that is I
explained my position. Okay.
And I'm glad we have this form so I
can do this because what happens is you
realize if this starts to go south on
me at any point that we'll cut this off.
I'm s I will, I'll just
shop and go ahead. Go ahead.
When we're doing a livestream or
something, my voice sounds crazy.
You're yelling right? Cause
I'm very amped up. Okay.
They're adjusting dials all across
this building engineer's week. Yeah,
they're pulling levers.
It's like that scene where the Titanic's
just about to hit the iceberg and
they're,
they're turning giant wheels and they're
shoving huge levers into reverse to try
and veer us back into a normal
sonic level. But go ahead. Shouter
I uh, did a lot of choir when
I was younger I project. Okay.
Don't laugh at that. So I had
to turn away. Why is that funny?
Choir is a thing. You
know, he was the gray hair.
He was the gray haired boy
and the choir was tenor
second tenor. Yeah, that was the second,
second tenor here. It's like a time
and I'm just saying,
so I naturally project quite a
bit to do now to two live streams.
I feel like people are watching
on their phones very small.
You have to overcompensate really
to get it out. You know, look,
be like to do it right. So
bored. You're looking at me
with like dead eyes. No, I'm,
well first of all, I died
inside in a long time ago. Okay.
So I feel like I have to
overcompensate for that.
So I feel like that's what it takes.
It's all brute force.
I don't have your talents of being
hilarious, so I have to be just energetic.
I'm going to say you are a funny
fellow will second. And uh, I don't,
don't let yourself down.
That's my job. Not to put you
down a chocolate stream. Um,
I understand. And I also, I have
to say, I do appreciate that.
That always gives me something to start
with whenever we're doing something
right. And I come into a room and you're
doing a livestream and you're yelling,
that's the first thing I do.
And,
and it's so it's a little
like peanut butter and Jelly.
It works well together and then you punch
me for the next 20 minutes. I do it.
Here's another thing I do.
I punch a you often because you're a big
guy and you can take a punch just like
punch you a lot in the shoulder. Uh,
then your parents didn't like it.
That's true. He didn't like that
I was punching you. It's true.
And here's a negative performance
review for you. You commit.
You communicated that to me.
Now I think you should have
just kept that to yourself.
But I think you telling me that your
parents don't like it when I punched you,
I thought that was putting me in a very
uncomfortable emotional position as the
person punching
it was awesome.
This is the most ridiculous complaint.
I want to punch you,
but I don't want to hear any negative
comments from your family. Uh, well,
only what? My Dad didn't like it. My mom
says that like, do it more. She enjoys it.
Your mom likes it when they change.
She enjoys it. Yes. Uh, and I,
you want to explain to me, uh, that,
uh, coming from brothers very early on,
to your credit, you said, I'm
going to hit you quite a bit.
It's because I, it's because
I can't hit my brothers. Uh,
so I'm gonna hit you because
they're not within the arms.
Like there are certain writers that
I'm comfortable tackling fighting,
which is ridiculous and absurd. Yes. Um,
and I know that they're okay with it.
Yes. I think they're okay with it.
I may ask them someday if they're
okay with it. There was, there's one,
or particularly, I remember, uh,
I was either an internet just
started and I walked by and the old,
late night offices, he, he, he,
you had been fighting and you've have
his head whose head? Michael Coleman,
his head we used to play with a lot. Uh,
Oh, you're holding it down on the desk.
And as I walked by, you go, hey, hey,
come here. Come here. I was like, yeah,
you go hold his head here.
Just hold it here.
And if I walked by and his head is not
on the thing and you're not holding it,
you're fired. I was like, oh my God.
And so I held it for like 30 seconds
and he goes, he's just kidding.
And I was like, oh. And I love
Michael Coleman, brilliant writer.
But he had that coming. I
love Michael Coleman, but a,
and I fully admit to that kind of madness.
I'm an insane person.
And he ripped your shirt. That's
why that happened. He, he,
they can't wear my shirt.
Enraged me. Yes. Uh,
let's move on to areas that
won't get me in legal trouble.
Um,
you were ironic watches constantly.
That's true. Every day you were at
different. Ironic watch just is true.
This is a negative part of
your performance review.
Sometimes you wear a watch where all the
numbers are scrambled or you'll wear a
watch that has no numbers or your war
where a watch that has no information but
just a pancake on it. That's true.
Yeah. This is my grandpa's watch. I, uh,
that's a real watch.
It's ironic.
It's strange that it's weird that I'm
bringing this up today because this is one
of the only times I've seen you wear a
watch that isn't made to look like a mini
toilet seats or oh look,
it's a steaming piece poop and it
stops steaming at 1230 limited.
We'll show you exactly what
is the watch thing. Uh,
I don't know. You know, I'm a wacky guy.
Never say that. Well,
you know, I mean, okay.
I'm not a wacky guy. I enjoy, uh,
I enjoy color and I enjoy, uh, I think,
I mean a psychologically is probably,
well,
you know what guys don't get to a word
jewelry, we don't get no, it's true.
And guys don't really get to dress
up like I, you know, it's like, oh,
you wear like a time we
didn't do when you're older.
I have appreciated dressing up a little
more as I am wearing a tie right now.
We can't. You are, and you look, that's
all, that's all I'm wearing. Your kid,
you can't think on its long.
Anyway, the point is, you know what?
So I wear to ironic watch because I want
somebody across the room to be able to
see, see the kind of person
I am from far away. Okay.
Here's the next part of
your performance review.
We're doing very well on the
Internet, don't you think?
I would say so, yes. Okay.
Why am I not much bigger on the Internet?
And I think in your huge, no, no, no, no.
I mean I think there's a
lot you must not be doing.
I want to be the ultimate because you
know, we're not a car Dashi and levels.
Okay. Okay. And you know what I'm going
to say, let's be honest. Let's be honest.
You know,
this is going to be great.
I can't wait to hear what
you're about to say. Well,
all I know is every time I
turn on SONA, jump in. When I,
when I turn on my phone or my computer,
I see what the Kardashians are up
to or who they're dating or hold it,
who threw shade at Black China
and who does Travis Scott and who,
uh, got a new butt and stuff like
that. And I'm thinking I've got a new,
but you know why? Why are, why
am I not part of that discussion?
Anybody and I think I blame,
go ahead.
They show their boobs a lot.
And you that's what I was going to say.
Do not use saying that they are considered
sexier than I am. More sexual. Uh,
yes, they are definitely
sexier. They have, you know,
very voluptuous bodies
and they show it off.
I mean if you show like you're but
more often and like a thong, be honest.
Be Honest. Tell them that I about my butt.
Tell them you don't seem to have one.
They have, there's nothing. There
is literally nothing there. Yeah,
but you know what? It is a straight drop.
I had a carpenter check it out. My blood.
Not only does it not go out, it
goes in. Oh you can, there's like a,
an area where you can,
there's just a big carved
out indentation there.
I can't keep pants on. Why did
a carpenter check out? You know,
can I say one of the best things?
Not best things.
One of the very popular things we
did was when you were jeggings,
you remember that? Yeah, I remember that.
Yeah. If you were some tight like to Sona,
say if you showed that off, even if
you've got nothing, here's the problem.
Show it off. You know, like
here's the thing. Why did you say,
even if he got nothing. Well,
I'm saying if you, well,
I dunno, I'm saying, I'm saying
maybe it should be a little sexier.
You know, it might be just come out
and you come out in a suit every day,
you know, try, try maybe the jacket, no
shirt. Gold goes well, I'm just throwing,
I'm just,
I'm just spit balling.
He seen my chest prefer not if you've
seen my chest would really like not to.
I look like someone I don't
want. My chest is uh, you know,
a sunken chest.
Um,
it's the chest of someone who's been in
the coal mines for many, many years. Yeah.
So I don't know if you showed it off.
I guaranteed there is a
fetish for everything.
People would be into the sunken
chest, like Deron not, well,
they might not be the people you want,
but you know, sunken chest fetish.
Here's the good end of that.
You're in charge or uh, you know,
you are at the helm of my
web presence in many regards.
Why are you not figuring out a
way for me to break the Internet?
I think we've broken it. Guest is
doing well. What more do you want?
What would he be? Don't ever
ask me what more do I want more?
But would you want to be what
the head of a country like?
What are you looking
for out of the vendor?
When Kim Kardashian had that picture
that showed her opening champagne and the
stream of champagne was going up
in the air, do you remember that?
And then it made an ark in the air and
then it landed on her butt. Crack has a,
but you can't do that.
It goes straight to the floor.
You can't do this champagne on the buck.
You have nothing. Photoshop. Thank you.
She also shows off like on a
private plane and really fancy
leather chairs.
And here's my new book about the people
who live in bogs in 1910 and what they
ate. I took a, I took
a Selfie, to be fair,
I was in a on a u s air
flight that was fairly uh,
unoccupied and I took a self portrait
of me writing in my journal and I gave
that to,
to put on the Internet.
And then I waited for the
whole thing to blow up.
Remember US Air Flight? What is
that? Anytime. That's nothing.
Look where you were, you know you are
in business. You weren't even in first.
You know what? First costs on us,
but I'm just saying you weren't,
that's not like bling bling,
you know, life saying, but okay,
so you're saying I have to get on like
a southwest flight and be in the front?
Yeah. You should check in very
early for this point. You're misled.
He's missing them. You know what?
Here's what you need here. It's just,
it's the internet runs on everything
else. Its sex appeal. It's its popularity.
It's thrown at you. What was the last
time you threw shade at somebody?
So and don't you think he should start
a feud? Well, you need is, you need it.
You need a beef. That's what
you, how about I go after taiga?
You don't know who taiga is.
You know, you keep saying,
I don't know who target is, but I will
tell you I have a lot of beef with Tyga.
Well, what about like, who's
somebody who you like? Well, Hey,
you know Ruth Bader Ginsburg,
like who's somebody who you
know a lot about don don't
beef with, no, no, don't be,
but what about if you beef with like a,
but somebody who you know a lot
about who's still alive, who's cool,
who's still alive? Yeah, like somebody
like I know like Taf. Do you have,
don't you have issues with Taft? Who's
the, you said still alive, but no,
I was saying mean you're the first person
you lift. You just listed as, no, no.
I mean what if I'm the first person
to have beef with a historical figure,
but they can't be. They can't be if,
no, but I think this is the, hold on,
just settle down. Here's the
problem with you. You don't think,
what if I get into a beef?
You know,
I can't get into beef with Tyga because
I don't know who would tag is all about
and I can't get into a beef with black
machina and you know what I mean? And,
and uh, you know, Kendrick Lamar
and all these different people,
I can't get into beef with
them because no one's going to,
they're not going to know who I am.
It's the whole thing's not going to work.
But what if I'm the first person who
starts to have legitimate beef with,
you know, I've got a beef
with Hamilton fish know fish.
Exactly. Look it up. Everyone look
up Hamilton fish or look up, uh,
you know, Lsu route. I have beef with him.
He was in Theodore Roosevelt's
administration. No, I have,
I have beef with Czar Nicholas, you
know, or the people last czar of Russia.
I have may, you know, I have major,
he shouldn't have dissolved
the Duma then as ever.
Maybe the Russian revolution
wouldn't have happened.
I'm here in a future
segment for this podcast.
I know gold when I hear it and that
this blows up code because then we get
someone to start writing back to me.
Right. In the voice of that person. Right.
You know? Yeah. I just have a,
I have major beef with
Hubert Humphrey. Yeah. Uh,
and then he has beef with me back.
I have major beef,
it's called major beef, but major
feat definitely called major beef.
I have major beef with Secretary
of State Seward from the Lincoln
Administration. No. Yeah.
I don't think he should have purchased
Alaska and I consider it Seward's folly.
And this is the kind of stuff that,
okay,
I know what you're all thinking moves
stupid. You would learn from my beef,
my beef would educate educational
beef. Yeah. It's educational beef.
We want to learn from your major
beef from my beef. Would you learn?
Yes. You would all learn
from my beef. Okay.
But would think man Conan,
secretary of state's Seward or really
getting into it and then kids will just,
because they're into beef,
start to know about,
maybe Seward shouldn't have bought
Alaska. It'll be so big. The Kardashians,
we'll want to be on you and be like,
no,
you're not historically significant
enough. Exactly. Yeah, exactly. So I,
uh, we're going to do that
and that's going to blow up.
That's going to break the Internet.
Major beef like major beef. Okay.
Wrap up this performance
review. Yes, please play.
You are an excellent, uh, and
crucial part of my team. Thank you.
Sometimes you speak too loudly. I wish
you took your watches more seriously.
What would you,
what would you rate me?
What's the scale and how would
I rate on the scale of, of,
of your performance of the show? Yeah.
Like what is it? What do you rate?
What am I rated out of? Okay. Uh,
the scale is eight stars.
Okay.
And I'm giving you six stars.
Okay. Uh, plus half a moon.
Okay. It's confusing, but it works out
too. That's very good. Oh, well thank you.
It's not the perfect.
All right.
Conan O'brien needs a friend with SONA,
most [inaudible] and Conan O'brien
as himself, produced by me,
Matt Gorley executive produced by Adam
Sachs and Jeff Ross at Team Coco and
Collin Anderson and Chris.
Ben. And at Earwolf.
Special thanks to Jack White and the
white stripes for the theme song,
incidental music by Jimmy Vivino.
You can rate and review this show on
apple podcasts and you might find your
review featured on a future episode.
Got a question for Conan,
call the team coco hotline
at (323) 451-2821 and leave
a message it to could be
featured on a future episode
and if you haven't already,
please subscribe to Conan O'brien.
Needs a friend on apple podcasts,
stitcher or wherever
fine podcasts are down.
Yeah,
this has been 18 cocoa
production in association with
this holiday season.
Earwolf wants to spread some cheer.
Cheer, Wolf, if you will. We've got
special episodes all over the network.
Just for you.
Andrew t and tawny Newsome
talk to Kulapat delay.
I can't pronounce this about holiday
racism on Yo. Is this racist?
That sounds fun. Unspoiled takes a deep
dive into AFS. Favorite Christmas movie.
It's a wonderful life off
book. Has Not one, not two,
not four, but three holiday themes.
Musicals for you to indulge in. Surprise.
All the special holiday episodes of with
special guests are out from behind the
paywall as a gift to you.
You can also check out a very
special in proffered humans episode.
Best of the Bible on are
you talking Rem Remi?
Scott's talking about every rem holiday,
single released and nothing else.
Shannon Hayes hit the slopes with Adam
pally on a very festive episode of
Hollywood handbook. Beautiful
anonymous. Chris Gethard is,
they're taking calls from New Year's
resolutions to Nan on year olds,
Facebook page, December 21st
at 2:00 PM Eastern, and look,
get a special Listener Collin with
a heartfelt proposal on warp it up,
followed by the Christmas walk tacular
released from behind the paywall.
And if that's not enough,
checkout even more special holiday
apps from how did this get made?
Getting curious who charted three
dumb of course, comedy, Bang, Bang,
happy holidays, happy listening,
and a marriage cheer. Wolf to all.
So much stuff. So much
cheered sheer. Whoa.