Hi,
my name is Pete Holmes
and I feel frustrated but honored
to be Conan O'brien's Fred.
Yeah.
Ah,
back to school.
Hey there. Welcome to Conan O'brien
needs a friend. It's pretty simple.
This is the show where I Conan O'brien,
uh,
talk to people in the business,
a celebrities I've interviewed over
the years and trying to find out is it
possible we could be real friends,
not just fake show Biz pals.
Now I'm aided in my quest by
my assistant for now sona.
[inaudible] hello. Come on Sony. You know,
you're with me for the long haul. Yeah.
But it's hard to really believe that when
you constantly keep talking about how
my time's limited.
You see that often?
I like to dangle that because I think
that will inspire you to greater heights.
Do you think it's working? No, it is not.
No, I don't think so. Either. A Elsa,
someone who I give a shout out to my
producer, Matt Gorley. Matt, how are Ya?
I'm good. And I think because
you don't threaten my job,
it makes me actually worried that
maybe it is a short tenure here. Yeah.
Your replacement is standing behind
you. Oh, his name is Phillip. Hi Phil.
I call you Gourley a lot. I don't know why
you might not like that. You just fine.
Is it okay? I mean, he could call you
Matt. I have so many maps in my life,
but I only have one
Gourley I, yeah, I'm, I'm,
you're one Gourley I don't
like Matt Anyway. All right.
Gourley thanks for being here. You
do a great job. Well, that's nice.
I'm not sure that's true,
but uh, no, it's true. Okay.
I do think this podcast is doing very
well. You're probably a big part of that.
Uh, no, that's, this
is all you guys. Yeah,
I'm just putting it through filters
and shit. Okay. I think that's true.
[inaudible] Gourley is the magic spice.
He's the secret.
He's the colonel's secret recipe. We're
all holding hands right now. Oh No,
we're not. It would violate
somebody's hand. Right?
We were just told you're just
holding a severed hand. Oh my God.
Today I'm talking to someone.
Uh, have a lot of admiration for
Pete Holmes.
Oops.
What I'm liking about this so far.
You've been doing this a long time and
it's completely the way you and I would
talk. Yes. Uh, without
any interference, right.
Without, uh, and, and the show.
Do you feel like when you do the show
that there's levels of interference?
Do you think that's getting close? Yeah.
Cause you're quite relaxed on the show.
Well,
I really appreciate it.
It's one of the great thrills of my life
that I've done your show enough times
to be relaxed. Certainly the first time
I was, you know, Jimmy and my bridgies
trying to get some new freight and
new phrase is going, me and my, well,
there was a kid in my neighborhood,
Jimmy's,
how do we know that type
of narcissism I exhibit?
I make jokes that don't have any, I know
you don't know. How could you do that?
You just said, I'm Jimmy and
my bridges and I was like, wow,
I feel stupid because that's
clearly a classical reference,
a Shakespearean drama. And then it turns
out no, Jimmy from my neighborhood.
How could you not know that it's
all Baloney? It was just fun words.
My mom will do that though.
Oh wait.
Or I'll come like you and I will be
talking about the bread and won't be like,
Eh. The spreads pretty old and then the
waiter will come who wasn't privy to that
and she'll be like,
Laurie,
let's say we said the bread was
dry and then she's like the waiter.
I'll say to my mom, you want
some water? And she'll be like,
what am I the Brad to
him? I'm always like, mom,
he doesn't have the info. He doesn't
just a crazy person and was like,
what did I bread?
And then he calls an EMT and says,
women's having a stroke, a stroke.
This, no, let's not do stroke,
but it's too many people having
strokes. Really. Right. I don't know.
I'm going to keep doing them until
I have one. No, it is a funny Goto,
but I was going to say that a stroke
kind of sound like it's a stroke.
You stroke a cat. It's kind
of Nice. Nobody's like,
Hey, quit struggling my cat.
You stroke a cab or you stroke
your gentlemen lover. Okay.
Let me tell you something.
Give them a stroke if you're working
on a new honk and I sense that's what
you're doing. If you're gonna do
this stroke bit, stroke a cat,
what are you a stroke? A stroke. It
sound like such a nice thing. A Straw.
Oh my God, it is a Seinfeld
bit. You strong again. Hey,
I had a question on your boyfriend. This
is a bit I've wanted to do for awhile.
How are we? Great idea. It's a stroke
of genius. Yeah, I forced it. Yeah, no,
but she's the thing. Here's what,
here's a bit that I want to work on,
which is how are we going to know
when Jerry Seinfeld has Alzheimer's?
Holy cause.
He's going to come out on stage and go,
I just want to know who
all these people bad.
What is the deal with pizza?
And people are going to first
think that Jerry is working on,
they're going to think he's
working on new material.
No, sue, who are these big Cheri?
These are your loved
ones. Oh No, I'm scared.
I'm lost in the corridors of my own mind.
Who are these people?
Jerry. Jerry, calm down,
pump terrified,
everything around me.
What is this thing that,
that's a window. Jerry,
what does a window
and then it ends with it ends with you.
You see it's a window and then he
goes, that was a bit, no one was a bit,
you know Wednesday night I call those
playground bits where they're like you
have the premise,
you can do it forever but then no you
have to have that chord that you Paul and
then yeah I'm not telling you
what to do. I'm no, no period.
I just this my telling what to do or no,
I just did this 18 city tour and I have
this hump that I do up front and then I
thought of that on the road and working
it out in front of the comedians that
are like,
that's really funny.
But I never did it on stage cause I
thought I don't know yet. But I've,
but it might be because you don't, you
didn't know where the court is. Yeah.
The end.
I wonder if real like Vaudevillian Showbiz
is going to come back cause we're all
loose where the podcast generation of
comedy where it's like even your talk show
you can be transparent. People are
like we're seeing behind the curtain.
I wonder if the curtain is going to
make a comeback if our our kids kids are
going to be like it came out he
was partly, it's like John Malaney,
John Malania just does stand up. John's
not like, and that's how that one ends.
He doesn't, doesn't do
that. He is a throwback.
He is a throwback and that's
a high compliment. He is.
He's a very disciplined storyteller and
joke teller and he crafts his act in
this way. That's a little out of time
for today because, and again it's,
there are people that abuse the privilege.
There are comics that have their shit
together and then the ones that are very
brilliant but they,
they kind of wallow in,
I don't really know where this is going
and I am I really doing up here and
comment on everything and sometimes
it goes too far. Of course.
I think what we're talking about,
his podcast standup, it's like,
now that they know that we, we talk
about bits and these ways they left.
I can't speak for everybody, but
some audiences like it. You're like,
you go see Mark Marin who's, you know,
the pen ultimate. What does that mean?
Second to second to last?
I think he is.
Well now he is the next one. It's
over. Yeah, I meant the consummate.
Yeah. Podcast. Stand up. You know, he is
the Punam Bro. I know what you're saying.
It depends on person. He's Jimmy. And
is that just, yeah, he's the pneumatic.
I know what you're saying. Are
these the Paris, the populace? Uh,
I'm just going to say it like, Oh
God, how are we gonna you know,
this is a,
it's a disaster.
What I'm saying is when you watch him
80% of it, it's just like, I don't,
I don't know. You know,
like, and we love it.
Like that's what makes it
fun is that he's not doing,
because he's not supposed to be doing
what Malania is doing well and he's doing
what he's supposed to be doing, where
he's doing what he's supposed to be doing.
I do wonder if your kids,
kids will be like,
it came out from the cut and then he said,
well good evening ladies and gentlemen.
You know what I mean?
Like sitting at like lit up cocktail
tables and we just want to show up.
Be Nice.
Sometimes it is nice.
I'm gonna add some professionalism to
this. We do have something in common.
We're both from the Boston
area. We're both tall. Yes.
We are both bedeviled by our fathers.
Aye.
Come on. I've met your dad. Your Dad's
quite the character Carlo. Right?
His mother. That's my dad. I know
Gregory and giving me some wins
your cookie 10 minutes later.
I never had a,
when Joe called me,
well this is the thing about your dad
used to do an impression of him and I
thought it was a cruel exactly.
And then I met him and it's really not.
That is an accurate,
were you a bystander and you were
describing him to police and you weren't
related to him?
That would be an accurate description.
A sloppy Peter Griffin type. When you,
when I had the talk show that you did,
my dad was that you gave me,
my dad was in the audience
and I was interviewing rob
Corddry. My Dad by the way,
wore a red sox jersey. Yup. Tivas
and he has like, I love my dad,
but he's got some fucked up feet.
His feet look like,
who like wouldn't start at
Luke Skywalker was in that pit,
that Jabba the Hutt but have
been in the monster, came out,
they looked like a rang Gore ran core.
Why would you even know her?
I oh good. I nerd in the corner. He's got
rang core feet and he, and he was like,
I'm going to put a legion Kiva,
so whatever's growing on him and can
get some air and you know, grow better.
So he's got these nibs, the mangled kind
of white old man Bostonian Tivo sang.
Kelly's tell me that he was in a war.
He was never in a war.
Never in a war. Convenient. A war
is the good out for everything.
I was in the war if you're out. Yup. But
no, he was his feet never saw action. No.
So why are they mad? Did they get
dropped into machinery? It's no,
they're just there. They grew weird.
He has what's called a hammer toe.
Not Mc,
not MC.
No one thought of MC and everyone
thought of Mc, not a person in this room.
So a you're saying is he's in
the audience, I'm sorry. Yeah,
he's in the audience and I'm
interviewing Rod, Rob Corddry.
He's also wearing cargo shorts.
So this is kind of thin chicken legs.
He's got like Shrek Body, Big Dad bought
it, I'm sure of chicken legs. Yup.
Ran core feet. You basically,
you know that game.
Where will you fold a piece of paper
three times and you draw the defeat and
then you've hold it and then
someone else not seeing the feet,
legs and then you pass it and then
someone else draws the, the, the,
the mid body and then the final person
draws the head and then you unfold it and
you all made a body together.
You're saying that your dad is
the product of that game. Exactly.
Somebody's got stoned and drew my dad
with five friends and so I'm interviewing
Rob Corddry, my dad, my mom
and my brother both dressed up.
My Dad's dressed like he's just leaving,
not even a baseball game,
like a batting cage. Like he was
hitting some balls and that we're,
I'm interviewing rob Corddry and I
hear him. It made the show. He goes,
who is this guy? Well, I'm
interviewing nothing rod ropes,
not t crews,
but I'm interviewing rob Gourdie.
I'm telling the people who carry
crews carry crew or Tom Cruise.
Okay. God, you abbreviate
everything. He, he was humiliating.
Rob Corddry, rob Corddry ran
with it to hilarious effect.
These clips are available on Youtube.
I'm here to plug the
clips of our old doctrine.
You know what they'll live on
forever. That's the beautiful
thing. Isn't that fun?
Well, what happens too is you've gone
on, you've had this other success.
People know you. Yeah. Well
established guys. So then they may say,
I liked this Pete Holmes and then they
start looking and then people start
posting. Yes, your talk show,
which was very funny and so I'm
sorry if it was very cool about it.
They gave us a hard drive with all of it.
They were very cool about it.
And then Jeff Ross, your
Jeff Ross. Yeah. Pretty Nice.
Watch that fucking hat.
You'll look like you're going to go mop
up a bowling alley in the 1930s when
Oprah Winfrey,
bro,
you look like fair
hang a six shooter from now.
Why?
Why Berg Comedian Jeffrey Ross
never has to do with set again
cause she can just play that with a tape
recorder and hold it near his mouth.
That was amazing because you think about
Cheryl comedian Jeffrey Ross a lot. No,
not often. Okay. Wow. It's
amazing. I have texted,
tried to text your producer Jeff Ross
and texted Jeff Ross and I've tried to
vice versa.
Jeff Ross,
my producer at shares a name with
comedian Jeff Ross and Jay for years.
Jeff Ross would get comedian Jeff Ross
mail all the time and vice versa. Yeah,
it's, I knew it wasn't
him cause he wasn't right.
You fat,
lesbian route.
Hello? [inaudible] this
is Jeff Ross. Yeah. Yeah.
My Jeff Ross, a producer of
our show. Not a fan of comedy.
Do you think that's possible? I
think it is. Yeah. I think he is.
He's a great producer. One of
the things, he is professional,
he's an amazing producer. He's the
only producer. Everyone I work with.
I suspect sometimes he is
not a fan of comedy. Yeah.
Cause I'll be making sense from, I think
some pretty funny stuff. He's like,
this is just wrap it up. Let's go this
route. Okay, enough kidding around.
And then with your jokes,
let's get on with the ponytail.
Enzyme. Yes, he is in his,
your this. He's the thing that helps us
digest that. Yeah. Does that make sense?
Yeah. So you take a porn producer
that is an Intersex, he's just like,
and then the breasts come out and
then the asas shimmering. Right.
And it wiggles a little bit because people
seem to like that. And then they, they,
he is a born producer
who's not that into sex.
That's the only way that I understand
that they liked the jiggling breasts.
Right. And that he just
studying. And in that analogy,
I am a male porn star with
a massive penis. Yes. Yes.
Who is very good at sac.
Maybe some say the best at sex ever.
And sometimes in a rough spot would
call an Andy rector to help him finish.
He's got a feather.
Hey Andy,
shut that fan.
Ah,
you've completely derailed my
podcasts and I regret happening.
You have not derailed anything. I, yeah.
You know, here's what I gonna say. I,
it's something I admire about
you, Pete. Can I call you? Pete
said, all right, you're always
insisting on Dr. Holmes.
That's my brother's wrap bruiser
name. Is that true? No fool.
And Dr. Holmes 33 wait,
your brothers, what?
My brother John Holmes make a joke.
Go ahead and make a joke. Nope.
My father also John Home. Yup. Uh,
is one of the things that he does is he
produces beats for underground rappers
are used to do it more. He might still
do it, but you can look them up. Dot.
He's a white guy from Boston. He's a
white man from Boston. Yes. Says yes.
And he produces beats for rappers. Yeah,
he's good at it. You know what he does?
I think so. From what I can tell,
it's a, it's certainly a hard,
hard game to get into now.
Is there anyone in your lineage?
It's got the comedy thing. My uncle
Larry was hilarious. It was super,
super funny and my mom and my dad are
funding, but now nobody, they're like,
if my dad comes home filthy and I think
he likes that he's got like an old
school like you can
child like my back hurts.
Like he thinks that's great
and my hands are so soft.
Could massage a seal and it'd be like
mommy. Right. I think it was his mother.
He knows you're a hard worker. He told
me that. That's the city. He said, uh,
he said, I'm not going to do
your dad's accent, but he said,
because it wouldn't sound
right. But he said, uh,
I'll tell you one thing about Pete, no
one that no one can out work them. Oh,
that's very sweet. He said that,
and he was telling and I was like,
stop talking to me about Pete.
I actually don't fully relate to that.
I wonder how you are. I think,
uh, I would, will you describe me?
So now my, I think I'm a hard worker.
You're a very hard worker. Yeah.
Conan O'brien can't stop.
And I'm very different from that.
And that's how we clashed
a lot. Sometimes it's, I,
it's not that I don't work hard, it's that
I don't, don't care as much as you do.
Right.
I care so much about everything and can't,
and then I get mad because I care so much
about everything and I wish I didn't.
And I try not to,
but then I still care so much.
And Sona has always been the voice
of, Eh, I didn't do it. Well,
why didn't you do it? Well, this is the
Internet. I didn't care and I'll be like,
Woah, what do you mean
you didn't care? Right.
That I think when I watched the
documentary, yeah. Ryan can't stop it.
It doesn't make me a little bit,
it makes me a little bit sad because I
see myself in it. You know what I mean?
That part of us that's always sort of
chasing the next thing or whatever.
But you know, there's also part of me
that's like, I think neither of us,
cause I relate more to that than to sona
wouldn't trade it. You know what I mean?
Like if you could turn it off as a
pill you could take right now. That's,
well that's the big question is
if there was a way to turn it off,
I would turn it off and then quickly
turn it back on again. You know? And uh,
so I'm always signing up for way too
much work then complaining that I have so
much work.
I remember you saying
that and that is like
when I'm making the show,
I want to be on vacation when I'm on
vacation. I missed making the shout out.
Yeah. Oh Wow. That's a long time.
It's a terrible way to live your life.
I don't know if it is because it's
one of the cheaper fuels that runs the
machine and make no mistake that
work that sometimes we both dread has
incredible highs. Yeah.
He's incredible highs.
It's the addiction to the highs and the
lows. I think there's even a part of us,
I can speak from my experience that
enjoys when I'm like, oh you and said,
my job is putting my soul in the
wood chipper of show business.
And I think about that all the time. But
there's a, there's a, there's a beautiful,
it's almost like a French
like appreciation for like,
can you see what they make us
give? We kind of like it. Oh No.
That's the other thing too is that
they're not making us. That's right.
That's right. That's a
narrative. But comes back. Yeah.
To me is, um, there's this
moment of real clarity.
I think it's in the documentary,
which I haven't watched in years,
but there was this moment
where I come back stage,
I lay it on the screen.
Yeah.
I come backstage and I'm complaining
to my wife and I'm saying,
they make are making me do this
and they are making me do that.
And she said there is no they, there's
just, there's you, you're doing it.
And I realize that that's the,
the filmmaker who made that documentary
called it Conan O'brien can't stop.
And I,
when he told me that was the title,
I honestly didn't know what he
was talking about. Hilarious.
And then saw the documentary and it
was like, oh it's this, you know,
it's really strange to see
a mirror held up to you.
That's that accurate and not bad.
I'm not, I didn't think I was. Um,
but it was,
it was just interesting.
It's just interesting to
see the new England thing.
But maybe we were both probably raised,
I've thought about this.
You and I grew up in New England and it's
dark and cold in the morning and when
you go out to go to school,
the crappy car doesn't turn over
cause it's so cold and it's dark.
And my mom is making us say,
Hail Mary so that the car will turn over.
And she actually knew
the name of the saint.
You're supposed to pray
to WHO's good with cars,
which is ridiculous cause all the saints
existed 2000 years ago. But there's one,
there's like a saint Marcus or
something who's good with transmissions.
And my mom would make us pray to that
saint and then the car would slowly turn
over. And there's something
about growing up in it like that.
And I have thought to myself,
what if you could take a Pete Holmes in
a Conan O'brien and recast them so that
they're born,
uh,
in Santa Barbara and we serve,
we walked barefoot to school, we
walked barefoot, we, we chill,
there's a lot of wood. We, uh, we, we
maybe start smoking some weed like it,
is it possible that we
would be different people?
Like I always thought
if grew up in southern
California,
what I have had like a v shape torso in
a girlfriend when I was 14 and what I
have not had acne and what I
have just been this chill guy.
And what would I be doing now? I'd, I'd,
well I have pictures of me on the Cape
and I was like blond haired and I had a
10 like I don't Tan now. That goes a
little as felt. I've been soft ever since.
Like a svelte little boy. And I was
like, maybe that's California Pete.
But the question is, is California
peep funny? I don't know.
I could see you on Venice Boulevard.
Like not working out,
but maybe giving surf
lessons or something. No,
but I that wouldn't have worked either.
My center of gravity is way too hot.
I've got a disproportionate by all.
But,
but I have wondered
that is there's so much,
if there's a new England thing and
look at all the new England comics,
the real club comics. Yeah.
You know that it's so harsh.
I know you're really funny, but
it's, everything's fucked up.
It's a product of roads that were
designed for horse and buggy.
We had dinner one time around Christmas.
Yep. In downtown. But that's what I love.
That's a new Boston like a new, cause
that's not the Boston u and I grew up,
that's what I mean.
We didn't go downtown and that's right.
And eating a fancy restaurant.
When I was a kid, we went to,
we went to a place called Tony's Italian
villa on route nine and now I know that
is not an Italian restaurant,
but that's where we went and
we just got to have one soda.
And that was my brother
Neil always tricked me into
drinking mine really quickly.
He'd go,
let's have a race and,
and then I would drink mine really
fast and he wouldn't drink his at all.
And then he'd laugh at me the rest of the
meal. Oh Jesus. If ever I love the me.
And now it's time for a segment called
Conan O'Brien pays off the mortgage on
his beach house. Yes. I believe
in being honest with people.
Took out a big mortgage than
borrowed against that mortgage.
Then borrowed against it
again, mistake. But uh,
I'm an adult and I'm going to pay down
that mortgage and we're going to take
care of that right now.
There's some hidden little
chip in us that makes us,
we know we don't consciously know it,
but subconsciously we know
we're not staying here. Yeah.
That's how I felt about Massachusetts and
a lot of my family stayed there when I
go home, I don't feel like, ah, Boston.
That's right. My old home, it doesn't,
I like Boston. I really love
Boston. I love the people there.
It doesn't feel like home. And in
fact, New York never felt like home.
I don't know where my home is.
I am totally with you.
I think there's a feeling of restlessness.
I said to my family were kind
of rough with each other,
so they came to see the fan.
It's loving,
but they came to see the baby and they're
just, they're just sort of a nightmare.
It's a nightmare situation.
I told the story on chemo,
but my mom came in and it was like,
the first thing she said was, uh,
we got you a book for Leila.
We got her a book,
but we left it in the diner in Pasadena.
Will you go get it?
And it was like fucking no.
Yeah, no. That's not a gift.
That's an errand we have a baby
supposed to like out. So anyway,
they're kind of nightmares.
And I said to them,
if there was show business in Hawaii, I'd
be in Hawaii. But you know what I mean?
I was like,
if I could go further,
but there's something that sounds
cruel and I don't, I don't care.
I could explain to you
how we love each other.
No, no, I understand that
you can, I want to go away.
I understand that you can love your
family and they can also drive you crazy.
I think we can all sona you can,
you can relate to that.
Gourley I don't know what your
situation is. Of course, of course.
But I want you in this conversation.
Thanks.
You love your parents certainly and
your family really dearly. But you also,
uh, I mean you're routinely telling me
how much you also despise all of them off
Mike. Yeah, yeah. Off My, on a flow chart.
He's constantly writing notes
and pass them over to me during,
I despise slash love my family
and I'm like, you know what,
I'm trying to work here.
But you know, and my therapy
just hit me. He says,
Hey, your parents will,
which I think is what do you do it
intelligently and do it graciously and
lovingly. That and there is a way to sort
of be like, yeah, I don't, I love you.
That doesn't mean I like
everything about you.
Tell my, my wife is a
terrific, a terrific mom.
She's great. She's always, yeah,
she puts so much effort and thought and
love and to into being a mom and I'll
always remind her,
remember they're going to go to therapy
and they're going to complain about us.
Yeah,
we can do all,
we can base this Turkey with
love every five seconds,
but the Turkey when it's finally
done is going to go like, you know,
as a naive new parent and I'll
concede that might be what I am.
You're very early in the process.
I'm very early.
How far along are you? How old?
She's two and a half month.
She's two and a half months.
Right,
because you brought her to the
show seconds after she was born,
which actually blew my mind.
She was delivered in Jimmy
Vivino has dressing. Yeah.
You brought you,
you came to the show and I was like,
I can't believe you're
doing a show cause you just,
your wife just gave birth and
you said you and you said, uh,
what do you mean she's backstage and uh,
I walked into the dressing room and
your wife through the baby apnea.
I catch and uh, it was, uh,
very scarring for everyone.
But what we didn't know that when
people say like don't do that,
they mean that you're going
to get your baby's sick. Yeah.
Cause then we took our baby to Maui to
see Ron does because I wanted her to,
[inaudible] says my teacher, I guess
we can say, uh, who's also from Boston,
from Newton. Um, and I have a lot in
common with him because of that, I feel.
Anyway, I wanted him to her to meet him
and she got a cold and we were like,
oh, when people are like, you make
all your mistakes with the first one.
I was like, that's what they mean is
we're on a plane, everyone's coughing.
We get to the retreat.
Everyone has like literally people have
pneumonia and bronchitis and we were
like, oh, we'll be in the room.
Like we just, we fucked up.
Then like one day she got too
much sun on one side of her face,
but something I noticed,
I don't know if it was horrible parents,
I'm really terrible parents.
We need for the baby taken away.
But it wasn't a sun burn.
It was just like enough that it was
like she would go with tubercular ward.
We thought she should see
where tuberculosis is cure.
So she was about a day old and we
took her to show you lotus was,
who knows, you make those mistakes
with the first one you learn.
Bow felt horrible.
I notice a naturally occurring in uh,
in insurgence of what I call dad energy.
Women can have that energy to obviously,
and I can have mom energy,
but I started having like that dad,
like she'll be fine.
And I meant it like she got more nervous
than she normally did and I got more
self assured that everything is going
to be fine. And it was like, oh my God,
we're getting each other's yangs
right now and nobody asks for it.
I didn't read any book about it. I guess
exactly what you do. It's what happens.
Right? If your wife was super
chill, you freak out. That's right.
If you know what, we're gonna have
to take a break. We've talked about,
we've talked to you. I've got to wrap
up. We've been, how long has it been?
It's been like a close to an hour.
Jesus Christ tones.
Letting you guys roll the fuck.
I don't know much about this guy,
but all I've seen him do is
try to put this show in a box.
You can't contain this. I'm
lightening and he's the bottle. Yeah,
we're getting and yanging. I'm
father energy. He's a mother. Ah,
I'm going to pay you a
compliment. Oh, I will love it.
Not right now. Several years.
Several years from now. You're going to
get a letter and it's going to happen.
Compliment. That's just going to
say, uh, you, you drew tress. Well,
it's going to be much less
own yet and you don't, and it's going to
be in quotes. So you know, it's not true.
You know what I like is that
you,
um,
there is a very popular vein in comedy,
which is the comedian that is very unhappy
and miserable and I've always liked
that. You don't mind that vein. Do you
know what I mean? That you, uh, and, and,
and there's some other,
Ron Funches also talks about
things that make him happy.
Yeah. But he talks about
things that give him happiness.
And I think you're a the same
school, which I, I actually credit,
I think that is a harder path
to take. It's, um, it's a,
it's a more original or fresh or path to
take because I worry over the years of
the people that,
that come out and they just tell you
over and over and over the world and how
I'm sick, something's wrong with me.
I'm bad, I'm nearby, you know, and,
and I'm a disease and, uh, I dunno,
I weary of that.
I appreciate that. When, when
you're starting in the clubs,
it's 90% 95 maybe just like,
and I got up there, I punched him
in the face, and then I realized
there was a woman and people were whoa.
And then you have to go up
and be like, Kleenex. Hey,
there used to be facial tissue, now it's
clean. It, you know, like it's hard.
But I'm so grateful that like the taste
of comedy consumers shifted towards the
positive and that started happening.
You pioneered that in a huge way and
made a space for people like me too,
that want to be silly. They don't want to
be like, and I said, bubble my partner,
why am I doing it? Like a voice.
You know what I'm saying? Yeah.
It doesn't have to be against anybody.
Well,
I think there's it and I appreciate that.
You know what's interesting to me is that
it's that I think there's a lot of people
that conflate negativity with quote
the truth. Yeah. So it's that whole
school of if you're being negative,
that's right. And you're saying dark
things, you're telling the truth.
That's right. And, uh, if you're not,
if your comedy isn't right now railing
against what's happening in our country
and railing about, you know, who's
president and what's, you know,
happening, then you're escapist and you're
not handling the truth. And I think,
uh, I don't, I don't think
I agree with that. Yeah. I
don't think I agree with that.
I think it's possible to
be present in this world.
Understand that not all is right with
the world and then try to find a way
back at the dinner tip. Try to
find the silliness, right? Yeah.
There are people that confuse being
sarcastic with having a personalities or
hating everything is having a personality.
This is a real epidemic you'll see in
people's Twitter. Bio is it says like,
sarcasm is just one of
the many services I offer.
It's secure in the way bath. You
don't have to do those things. Oh,
bless you. I hope we got that on her.
That was a good one. We can solve that.
We can get money for that. Yeah. You
sneezing a lot lately. Use Nasal tracks.
I just made up that chronic.
Now we have to go find a company that
and make them get that name. Is that fun?
It's a podcast you can sing.
Live it or not for was not true.
No. Charles in charge of
our days and our nights.
It's like when your final
shows of the tonight show,
you can do what it the most expensive
show ever. Nobody's ever going to care.
You didn't found out you
couldn't pay for a song,
so you saying the total charge
that was, yeah, you could.
If you could have sing any. You know what
I did. It's also not true. You know what?
It is not here. I it, I
understand it is with yours,
but it is not here and I'm not
condoning that. I say do it crawl.
You had me for a second thinking I
could sing all of led Zepplin the most
expensive catalog next to the Beatles.
You think if we sing led Zeppelin,
they're going to, they get a letter. No,
but I think that the people in
this corporation will have words.
I say fan that fire. Go for
it. I'll do it with you.
Maybe I'm not to
back to school.
I'll give me your
no, no, no, no, no,
no man.
Now I sing it so strange. Yeah.
That melody is a vet,
a Charles in charge of
our days and our nights.
Charles in charge of our
wrongs and rights. Right?
Cy Want Charles in charge of me.
What a weird song.
Why is he in charge of bronze our age?
Well,
terrible song. Anyway, there's no
better way to get out on a podcast.
Then me singing a song knit Earwolf isn't
going to let come know what's going on.
No one's going to come after us for
the Charles in charge things I say,
let them try. Yeah. Whoa.
Gorley's throwing down. Yeah.
I couldn't fire wall later in
court. You just crying. No.
Can I? This is a fun way to plug
my, my standup special dirty clean,
which is out on HBO now. There's a joke
I couldn't do and it goes like this.
First I go, do you ever get things
that you're not attracted to children,
which is kind of a funny line, and
I go, but that shit is everywhere.
Like what's going on with that song?
Here's your little girl as you do.
Why am I hearing this at the dentist?
It's like someone took a knife,
baby edge and Dolan cut a six inch
valley through the middle of my skull.
Is that the next line?
He had not a wake up with
the sheets soaking wet head
[inaudible] now we're just
loving the song. That's a good
song. It is a good one. Great Song.
But all I said was like,
that's fucking weird.
Like nobody in the room recording booth
like this through the glass when he was
like, oh, go to bird desire. Yeah, it was
like a Bruce. It's fucking weird, man.
That's all I said. Don't do that Bruce.
And I never called him a pet. A fee.
I'm not an [inaudible]. We're not idiots.
We're just saying the song sounds.
Why did they cut that out? Because
I'm there. The lawyers, not of HBO,
because the Production Company would
get sued. Not Hbo. Hbo was fine with it.
The production company
wouldn't let me do it.
And understandably because you're
calling him a pedophile and then I'd say,
Neil diamond girl,
you'll be a woman's soon.
Wait for that transition to be
complete. Yeah, we're fucking ski.
He's just 16 years old.
Leave us alone. Yeah.
As a lot of name, you're beautiful and
your mind. There's a lot of 'em out there.
I know. But those two were like kind
of subtler. No, no, no, no. I, but I,
I'm surprised that yanked, I'm surprised
at that. Got Yanked. It was yanked, well,
let's make some money. Make sure I get
the name of the special correct. Jody,
dirty, clean, dirty, clean. And that's out
now. It's out now. That's how now and uh,
on HBO go or Hbo now and watch the
special, which is really funny.
But then imagine that honk in it.
I know it's even a little bit better.
I had another,
speaking of it went out like that.
I had a job where I go with sent,
this didn't make this special.
I got some songs sound unfinished.
Dad's man has a barrow at the market
place. Well, he has to say, okay,
that's a good start. And then they get
to the chorus. They're like, oh, blah,
or blah.
I just for now it goes on.
Obviously I couldn't get for led
Zeppelin and the Beatles in this episode.
This is going to podcasts already. This
is why I'm happy you're doing a podcast.
It's, it's still showbiz,
but like it's a dream.
I don't know if you've ever had a dream
of something that like requires almost
no preparation or effort,
but somehow impossibly produces a result.
I would say sometimes better than
something that we worked real.
I have calculated every question and
every response on this power hand and
you've said all the things that I
predicted you would say based on the
algorithms I was working
out long into the night,
so I don't know what you're talking about.
And I am old school and you've played
right into my hands. Pete Holmes,
an absolute desire.
I got a bad desire,
bizarre
terming out peaky. You're lying to
me. He won't sit on the edge of mine.
Neil, Pete, Pete,
you put that thought in my head and I
didn't think about it the rest of the day.
Calling Bruce Springsteen
cause we chat every day.
I'm sure not how he sounds
a terrible Bruce impression.
Oh Wow. Okay. Well that's what
is that him as a deputy in uh,
in an old cowboy west.
You're coming calm down.
Bad Bruce Springsteen. Impression of the
bad guy. If you're coming over to you,
we gotta get him. You know, we also got
to do something for the working man.
Marshall Dillon. All right,
I'm wrapping this thing up.
This thing's gone on way too long.
This isn't one of your nine hour bug,
just free flow.
A big believer.
It's after the first hour that you get
the good stuff. Who wants the good stuff?
Went not for hoop, but after, and
I say this, enter, he edits it.
Don't edit this out. I have that
control. So it's going ahead.
Who told us that podcasts
are supposed to be an hour.
I had had the experience of being on a
podcast and it's like our three. Nice.
Do start to feel like,
how does this stop bad
where I'm the guest and uh,
and I do think that they, if the studio
was on fire, they wouldn't wrap it.
I understand they're
trying to get a little,
a little more juice out of the
Breezy's. That's Conan. So breezy.
So that's your niche. That's right. Cause
no one knows what you're talking about.
Then I just say make it two hours. All
right Sonia, you got to end this thing.
Thank you for joining us.
That was Pete Holmes,
the heights dirty clean on HBO now and
Crashing Back January 20th 20th after
true detective after true detective
where the sorbet after the heavy on my,
someone in a cro mask. I was going to
shoot somebody and then I'll be like,
why am I doing it?
Right.
I won't be doing that cause I'm with
you. That's my girl in business. She,
Mr Rob Roy, do you think you
could put me on this show?
CHOMP chomp on gum.
Hands on hips.
Scrunchy on wrist.
Mr Robroy,
why could be a singer?
All right,
this is ed piece out Tupac
and now it's time for another installment
of Conan O'brien pays off the mortgage
on his beach house.
Okay.
Of course,
I'm sitting here with producer Matt
Gorley and some obsession is doodling
something.
Remember the time I caught you doodling
at your desk sona and it was a button
you weren't drawing everyone.
You were drawing a, but
remember this story, hold it.
You remember when you were drawing a,
but it's,
I'm going to tell the story right
now. There's no time who said, I know,
but you said you don't do
any work. I said, yes, I do.
And I flipped through and I have my
notebook and there was a drawing of a but
yeah. And where were you drawing?
Uh, but I uh, I didn't draw it.
Jason Chalami, our fueled
producer drew it on my notebook.
He was just very embarrassing because
I picked up sown as a book and see what
works she'd been doing and it was just
a drawing of a button is or notebook.
Well do you remember when we did those
Roman ed Ed's and you were drawing
erections all over the paper? It wasn't
drawing them. I was sculpting. Oh,
that's right. Um, Matt, we've
now released a handful yeah.
Of these podcast episodes and I thought
we should do a state of the podcast
where we assess how we're doing so far.
Why don't you give us your assessment
as a professional podcaster? Well,
I don't think it's any surprise,
but we're doing very well.
This podcast as an average of
five stars out of five stars.
The download numbers exceeded expectations
multiple times where they even upped
the ad sales and then had to sell more at,
so you're doing incredibly well.
Okay. So that's good. I don't have any
connection emotionally to any of that.
I, those are just, that's you
looking at various graphs and charts.
You probably go into a dark room and uh,
just look at all kinds of screens.
Yeah. My number's seller. Yeah.
And, uh, I what I know.
So I was in a foreign country called
Canada and I was walking down the street
and a car drove by and a guy road rolled
down the window on his truck and said,
God and I love the pod cast.
Now that's something when you're
reaching that just the streets of another
country.
I was in the streets of Vancouver.
Now granted it's practically
the United States. Yeah.
Vancouver is pretty much a suburb of yeah.
But I thought that was a good sign.
I'm hearing more and more people say they
liked the podcast and that's the only
thing I go by is humans telling me.
So your numbers and your graphs and
your charts and your telling me mm,
mm,
mm.
Yan retires areas quadruple
their expectations.
Is that a fair, you think it's a good,
first of all, I didn't use that voice.
And second of all, I am a person
telling you that. Oh, you're right.
How do you feel about it? Are you
feeling good? I am. I enjoy it. Yeah.
I totally go by how things
feel. I'm essential, man.
I'm a centralist too.
I feel like I know it.
So now it goes through on a day
to day and uh, I go a totally on,
I'm very tactile,
so the hell,
I'm like Jeff Goldblum I have to touch
everything around me. Oh, oh, oh,
that's Jeff. Jeff Goldblum. I, um, I,
it feels good to me. Yeah. I enjoy it.
It feels like a form that fits my,
a rambling mine.
Uh, so now what are
you doing? Why are you,
you're on your phone when I need help
over here. I know what I'm saying.
Can I just say something first of all,
when we're doing the podcast for doing
the podcast? No. And I looked over him.
Your paper please.
And you were drawing furiously
and you're drawing. Who is that?
It's looks like kind of a chubby girl.
That's very good. Little Chubby boy. Oh,
it's a little chubby little Afro.
Okay. And then you're drawing,
you drew all these weird
designs on the side, right?
So you're scratching and scribbling and
then I see you texting on your phone and
you're like the teenage daughter. I'm
trying to explain to you. We're at,
we're in Washington DC and I'm showing
you the Lincoln memorial and explaining
to you who Abraham Lincoln is and
you're on your phone. You know,
sexting with your finger gets,
yeah, put that down. Put it down.
The state of the podcast is
that the show's doing well,
but behind the scenes it's a mess here.
You doodle constantly.
Why can't I doodle a little
bit? I drew a little guy. Yeah,
but you're not in the moment.
I'm always present it in the moment
you have an attention problem.
You know what I do.
But you know in my defense I'm
answering emails for you cause I am your
assistant. So I'm an I do this.
I shut my phone off on my phone.
Doesn't exist because I'm only doing
this all. Here's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna do a doodle off.
Okay.
I'm going to tell you something to draw
and both of you are going to give it
your best shot. Go. Okay. A puppy
dog with a Christmas bow on it.
Thank God this. Cause I dropped puppy
dogs all the time. All right. Yeah.
Go ahead and talk us through your process
as well. I'm imagining the puppy dog,
they both have a very interesting, like
sodas just blazing this. Yeah. Well,
she draws puppy dogs all day long.
That's what I do.
They're both actually quite good.
All she does is draw your doctors like
Conan is like the New Yorker style
artwork. James Thurber, and
he's got a bow in his head.
It's a Christmas pepe.
One done. Whoa. All right, let's take
a please sign it. Please sign it. Okay.
Quite a signature
to wow. Yeah. I drew, I, I was under the,
we were drawing as quickly as possible,
so no one said that. Who said that?
No one did. But I, I just,
when I heard competition,
I just immediately started going really
fast and so on it please put your name
at the top.
So I'm going to put,
I'm going to put an extra
piece of flair on this guy,
both of these and precedent. Does
yours have a bow on it as, yeah.
He said a bow as oh, it
is. Okay. Right. Yeah. Wow.
Okay. So here's what we'll do. Uh,
go to earwolf.com to the page for this
episode and you can see the pictures of
these drawings and do you can vote amongst
yourselves or on Reddit or wherever
you want with friends,
whether Sona did the best dog with a
bone and drawing and the little Christmas
pop
and then keeping her name at the top
two as the assignment is clearly.
No, no. Okay. You're
taking a lot from Conan.
This is great for people
listening on the aisle.
And now what can I say something girly.
Oh,
you're the first podcast producer to
have people silently draw on the air.
Probably your downfall. You know, I didn't
know what eventually. What's that? You?
Uh, come on. Wow, that's not fair.
Mine's funny. Look at the dog is sad.
Should I?
Okay.
The dog is sad looking at a Christmas
tree with a thought bubble that says,
I'm too wish.
It's funny,
the owners didn't know his religion.
Yeah, they just assumed. Yeah. So anyway,
well you withdrew in sharpie. You have a
tree, you have a like a border. Oh God.
You know what? You and your
generation. All you do is cast blame.
It's beer, it's beer.
Where is my reality show?
Where's my billion dollars?
I put the work in and I reaped
the rewards. I don't know.
You're the one who started a show
cause you didn't get enough love in it.
Well it's working.
Conan O'brien needs a friend with sona
most Sassy and then Conan O'brien as
himself produced by me,
Matt Gorley,
executive produced by Adam Sachs and Jeff
Ross at Team Coco and Collin Anderson
and Chris van and at Earwolf special
thanks to Jack White and the white stripes
for the theme song.
Incidental music by Jimmy Levine.
You can rate and review this show on
apple podcasts and you might find your
review featured on a future episode.
Got a question for Conan,
call the team coco hotline
at (323) 451-2821 and leave
a message it to could be
featured on a future episode
and if you haven't already,
please subscribe to Conan O'brien.
Needs a friend on apple podcasts,
stitcher or wherever
fine podcasts are down.
Okay.
This has been 18 cocoa
production in association with.