Let's face it. Everybody wants to be
able to play a musical instrument,
but the problem is most people
that teach music are criminals,
murderers, just unscrupulous
types. That's just true.
Always be where someone who wants to
teach you a musical instrument that way
lies evil.
It's what you want to do is you want to
learn a musical instrument on your own
where there's no pressure.
That's where the musician APP comes in.
This is a great app and musician
APP can be your music tutor.
It's a great way to learn to practice
master an instrument you can play.
It gives you feedback.
It's great.
So become the musician you always wanted
to be without the interference of some
maniacal instructor.
Download [inaudible] for free and your
APP store today get 15% off using option
premium when you use the code word Conan.
Hi,
my name is Dax Shepard
and I feel very optimistic about
being Conan O'Brien's friend
on the fence.
Hey there, welcome to Conan O'brien needs
a friend to show her. I come to Brian,
speak to celebrities,
interesting personalities on
the hopes of finding myself,
possibly a friend and I'm talking one
that isn't on my payroll so it doesn't
work for me.
A real pal.
I'm aided in my quest by my trusty
assistant Sonoma of session.
Hi.
And my producer Matt Gorley.
Hi at today's guest is someone,
someone I have
a bone to pick with. We'll
talk about that later. Uh,
I do love the Guy Dax Shepard.
I know we've had some stutters steps,
but I'm not giving up on this.
You think it's possible? Absolutely.
There is a little bit of, uh,
an incident that happened between
us that we won't get into right now.
We're going to save that just a little
bit, which I think caused us, uh,
to uh,
fail a minute fire.
It was a misfire in our attempts to
get together and become real friends.
And I mean you a Christian and myself
and my wife lives a really getting
together as a foursome. Yes. A
double day. Proper Double Day.
I proper double date adults. Babysitters.
You have a whole nine valet parking.
Yeah. Then into the farmer's
daughter Motel on Fairfax. Exactly.
And then we switch it up.
We just pop on something exciting.
We'll see what happens.
No expectations.
It's a little Ang Lee ice party scene
where there's only four of us and uh,
we put keys in and so it's,
if we don't pick our own spouses, nothing
exciting has happened. Right. I mean,
if we do pick our own spices,
but spouses the best we fell
apart there will listen.
The best part about that scenario is
you and I would be on the are, you know,
respect of beds at the farmer's daughter
hotel and we would be so excited about
the possibilities in our wives
would be so bummed. Yeah, it's true.
It's true.
They both would be praying that we
got our own car keys in that scenario.
Yeah. Isn't that awesome? That's exactly
what would happen. It's exactly what,
what happened, uh, has a lot about
us. You and I, I think it does.
I think a women cringe,
uh, when we look at them.
But that's not true. You're
your real man's man. I'm
going to say this about you.
Oh, okay. You're a man's man.
And I say this because I visited a your
house not long ago when we recorded your
podcast where you had an incredibly
comfortable chair and I did not.
But I guess that's your thing. Well you
had a couch. It wasn't that uncomfortable.
It wasn't great. I didn't have
you on a, you know what it was?
I'm pretty sure there's a
foldout iron bed in that it's,
it's one of those kind of an iron
maiden. Yeah, there's a stick.
It was not a comfortable plush
couch. I didn't feel that
way. Well I, first of all,
I apologize and you though,
he's,
your chair was your chair is a lazy boy.
It's incredible.
Chair.
I gave it up one time on one episode
because if you interviewed David Harbour,
I have not. Do you know who he is from
stranger things? He's the cop. Yeah.
He arrived and I was like,
this guy's a fucking grizzly bear.
Look at this man.
He was just such a man then I felt it
would have been inappropriate to not give
him that lazy boy chair.
That's interesting cause I came in
and said this is an equal, I'll,
I'll put him on the couch and I'll keep
the proposal. That was a good safe.
I will say that you are,
you were the manlier of men because I
come to your house and I see first of all
this like all terrain vehicle parked
on in your compound on a trailer,
on a trailer. But it is one of
those things that looks like in the,
it's a mad max post apocalyptic vehicle.
It's an la of actuation
evacuation crisis vehicle.
Like when the 7.0 hits. Yeah.
My family and I will be in that.
It's a Polaris razor four seater turbo.
That's what I thought it was.
I saw it and it's like that's
a Polaris razor four seater.
I knew you were thinking
that and I appreciated that
you didn't try to embarrass
me. I think you knew what
it was and you were afraid.
He might not know what even owns, so
I'm not even gonna bring it up. Yeah.
Respected that. Yeah. There's
this great documentary.
I especially think you as the
owner of a boy should watch.
He was, uh, quite, uh, I purchased
a boy. That's correct. Well,
you made you have a
daughter and I have a son.
I think that's what you're trying to say.
Yes.
You have a daughter and his son and there
is a documentary called the mask you
live in. Have you heard
of this? No. Oh my God.
I have to bring it up because you're
talking about masculinity and it is all
about how we culturally,
um,
lay the foundation of what a boy or a
man supposed to be and pretty much how
cancer as it is for all of us.
And they've kind of lay out four criteria.
And as we were learning the criteria,
I was with Monica and my
wife and it became abundantly
clear what a cliche I am.
It was like sexual conquests.
That's, that defines manhood. Um,
fighting.
I'm consuming copious amounts
of booze or alcohol or drugs.
And then money got to make money
to be a man. And I was like, oh,
that's been driving me since eight
years old. Those four things all day,
every day. I am one on a four.
That's crazy. No. Yeah, I don't,
uh,
I heard you can suck down a eighth of
an ounce of kind kush weed in was single
toe. That's what I've
been told about you. Uh,
glad that that's out there about and
not true. I, it's an, it is not true.
I never, uh, I never dabbled
much. Never really dabbled
at all in drugs. I will say.
And uh, the Times I've tried sweet Mary
Jane, I think you guys call it. Oh yeah,
that's what we're calling it.
A or wacky cigarettes. Uh,
the time it was my uncle that told you
you would really benefit was the one who
Robert Smuggle it was my memory or no?
Uh, no, it was pretty recent. That, okay.
So the fact that you're
bragging about myths meant,
it makes me question your memory to the
fact that the fact that you're like, Huh,
I remember. I so Brian, right?
Brian. Right. Pretty good. Huh?
I shocked myself. That's why.
Yeah. Yeah. Robert's Michael,
a brilliant writer and uh,
insult the comic. Yeah.
Trying to insult comic dog and Blah,
blah, blah. And I've known him forever.
And when we were at Santa
and life together, he said,
you're the only guy I know who would
benefit from smoking because it would,
it would calm you down. You're
so tightly coiled that it, when,
if you smoked,
the cancer that you would get would
still be offset by the relaxation of the
cigarette. Yeah. Yeah. But, but you
know, you talk about masculinity.
I think I've done a pretty good
job with my son in setting.
I think in a lot of ways,
a low bar he gets to make,
he makes fun of me
constantly. And, and, uh,
I'm very self deprecating around him.
I'm not a big sports guy.
I'm not an incredible athlete. I work
out a lot, but I'm not a great athlete.
And so I have not set that expectation.
I'm trying very hard about the stuff.
Like, um, don't cry. Oh, I've
never told him not to cry. Okay.
And what about wished privately? Sometimes
he would stop, you know, uh, you know,
there've been times, there were
times when, uh, you know, when,
when he would lose it a over something
that I thought was kind of small and I
think like, Gee, you know, you're, you
know, my son is in his late thirties and
you know what, it'd be like,
okay, you dropped your donut,
but you shouldn't cry. No,
no, my son, uh, no, he
doesn't. I've never done that.
I've never shamed him for in any way.
I don't think. Well, how about this?
It starts with a very simple observation,
which I was definitely
true where I grew up,
which is we almost defined
boys in opposition to girls.
And so the worst thing you can be as a
boy is to be a girl, is to be feminine.
And in order of insults on a playground,
it is basically your sissy,
your a girl. Right? And it, and it's,
so the only thing topping the female thing
is then the homophobia. So it's like,
so it's tricky is when you're,
when you're introducing this concept
that to be a girl is bad and it's not boy
like you inadvertently are,
are basically establishing a hierarchy
of one's better than the other if you,
if you're supposed to avoid that.
So,
and then we get in these very insular
clubs cause it's very hard for us to emote
and to talk about our feelings
because we're told not to do that.
And then we get old enough where we start
drinking and now we'd say I love you
and that's why we drink.
So we can tell everybody we love him.
And now we're in this little pod and
we've been told our whole lives that being
a a woman or a girl is bad.
So then weirdly we feel superior to them.
I think it's all tricky. And I, I
found myself going like, oh yeah,
I got that software downloaded
into me big time. But you,
it sounds like you are a,
you are unpacking it. I'm
trying, but some of it is.
So I find this when I'm working on a
car and I hit my hand and I really draw
blood, like it's more, I'm already
frustrated. And then the wrench slips.
And then I cut my hand, my f,
and I'm ashamed to admit this,
but the first word out of my mouth is a
homophobic pejorative because it's like
in my reptilian brain,
like on the playground,
that was the worst thing
you could be called.
And you were trying at all times and not
be called that. And so it's just, it's,
it's cemented in there
and I can't get it out,
you know,
I know enough not to do that in real life,
but like in a moment where I'm,
I got really badly hurt and I'm
already frustrated that we're,
that word comes out and it's
cuckoo. I, cause I'm not homophobic,
I'm trying to relate to you.
Uh,
but I don't work on cars.
And the closest I can get to is if I'm
watching a PBS documentary on Emily
Dickinson. Great, great. Uh, and,
and they leave out the part where she
was in love with her gardener out the
window.
Exactly.
And they skip that part and they say
they're going to get to it later.
I usually shout out some kind of a slur.
Yeah,
it'd be it racial homophobic.
Right.
And I worry that my son will see that
and feel that I'm less of a man while I'm
watching the Emily Dickinson.
Yes. But it's very hard.
You do have that software.
I don't think I have that software.
You don't?
I don't think I have.
How could you have grown up in
Massachusetts or however you guys say it?
That's exactly how we say it.
You know that as a exceedingly tall,
redheaded kid and not have been called
names. You are all those names. No, no.
I was called names. I, uh, I, you know,
got into, uh, you know,
scrapes every now and then.
Uh, I was, uh, I had my nose
broken once that very badly,
and the north end of Boston. Uh, what age?
I was 18. And I was, uh,
a salted by a group. I believe they were
a young Italian men who didn't think, uh,
an Irish guy should be in there. I
swear to God. And so ironically, right?
It's like an 18th centuries wobble.
Yeah. It really was like, look,
and I had Ushman has come
into the Italian section.
What is this?
Is this 1820 well,
the saddest socio dynamic, if we're
going to use words like that. I'm not,
that's not even a word. I just kind
of, you're a strong guy and you've,
you've had a lot of experience fighting.
Yes. Okay. How confident are you that,
like right now if I whipped this podcast,
headset off and came across
the room and started swinging,
that you'd be able to handle me? I've
lived, I feel good about it. Yeah. Yeah.
What would my do you think I would be a
worthy opponent or, and just be honest,
I don't strike you as a goal. I'll be
honest. I'll tell you some things. Yeah.
You're, you're strong. I know you exercise
a lot. Yeah. I think you're strong.
You're bigger than me.
I think you outweigh me probably
by 30 pounds or so of debts.
Muscle weight. Yeah. You're thin. You're
whatever you have is muscle muscle. Well,
not all of it. Did you wrestle with
your brothers a lot growing up? Uh,
not effectively. I was quickly
overwhelmed by my oldest brother Neil,
who was much,
much bigger than all of us and we'll
just sit on me and then laugh as I was
underneath him. Right. Okay.
Well you know, much like, um,
uh, Tarzan grew up around
apes and he could break it.
He could swing from trees like yeah.
Yeah.
So my brother was five years older than
me and he fought me every hour of every
day and I think that made me
a very good wrestler. Yeah.
Cause I was fighting someone much
bigger than me, older than me.
So I feel like my wrestling
skills are really on point.
I fought my mother physically.
Okay. Uh, which didn't go well.
She also bashed me.
Okay.
So then I went after my grandmother
who lived in the House with us.
She also gets her, she also one which
did she employs, she was in her,
she was in her nineties.
Okay. All right. All right.
She know she used just brute strength.
So I think your price,
he also had a mouth, like a sailor too,
right? She had got a psychological,
don't get me started on that one.
You know,
my lived in the house with us when we
were growing up and she had grown up.
She's,
uh,
had lived a very long time and she had
grown up in Massachusetts during the
early 20th century.
I mean,
I think she was like 22 years old
when the titanic sank. Oh, real.
And show she on Saint Patrick's Day,
she pulled me aside and she told me,
now you're going to go to school today
and all the Protestant kids who are going
to tease you. And I
was like, this is 1975.
And you know,
I'm,
I'm going to this racially mixed
public school where, you know,
kids have Afros, there's Korean
kids. There's mean. It's just,
no one's thinking about that.
And she said,
go to school today and the Protestant
kids are going to laugh. He,
and I'm the laugh at you. I'll
never forget that. She said,
and they're going to try and, uh,
they're going to try and rile you.
And she said they're going to
put chocolate in your milk.
I thought like,
oh my God,
that's something that happened to her
in 1902 some protestants put a piece of
chalk and her milk and got the best
of muddy Reardon, you know, and,
and I was like,
what?
And then of course I went
in a bowl thermal and your
oil lamp and when you light
a smoke up the loud, yeah,
it's changed your whale oil
for seal oil and the light
will be dimmer than you expect.
So she, um, and then I
got to school and like,
people are wearing dashikis and you know,
but anyway,
the point sheet,
uh, it didn't happen. It didn't
happen to you. It didn't happen.
It was not mocked for being Irish.
I was mocked for being a,
I got hand me down clothes
early in my life and my pee,
my pants never fit cause
my legs grew so fast.
So I was constantly tormented. Where's
the flood? Okay, where's the flood?
Right? Where's the flood? And for
awhile I didn't understand it.
And then they said, [inaudible] someone
had to explain if there were a flood,
you would raise your pants.
And I was like, oh, okay.
Just put chalk in my milk then. Right,
right. Let's just cut to the chase.
Put the chalk in my mouth, but it makes
me think, did you read the first tycoon,
the Cornelius Vanderbilt?
I've read,
I've skipped through it and read
pieces of it, but I love it. I love it.
I've read all those, uh, where the
parishioner, what'd he say? Uh,
the class, those token the best, yes.
The rigging that golden age. Yeah.
They called parishioner clients.
I don't know at any rate of all those
guys. Uh, Carnegie, uh, you know,
uh, Rockefeller, Rockefeller,
the most fascinating is
Cornelius Vanderbilt because
he was just a tough son of
a bitch. And, um, he got, grew up just,
I think he had like one row
boat when he CRD. He did. Yeah.
He let on a little island.
It was all Dutch people and uh,
he grew it into this steam
ship empire. But, um, the, the,
the most famous fighter of the day,
some Irish men who was like
the champion of New York, uh,
said some stuff about him in the paper
and then they were having the Saint
Patrick's Day parade and Cornelius
was on horseback and the,
that fighter came out into the street
and he was pretty drunk and Cornelius got
off of his horse and punched
out the heavyweight champion.
And it's documented in the paper.
It's not like lore and uh, yeah.
Now that's the kind of tycoon
I want to read about. Exactly.
You don't see bill gates knocking anyone.
I'm not going to have Mike Tyson
Saint Patty's day. Exactly. If a, if,
if you know, Mark Zuckerberg
took out, you said,
what about my Gregor Macgregor? You
said, what about Facebook? How do I know?
Right? I'm Saudi. Saudi. No, come here.
I'm going to rip your ass publicly.
What's the rent? Take a break.
We're going to take a break.
Is that we take as a race on here.
We'd take breaks on this one.
Cause you know what? Okay, good. Let's
make some money. I have these cash cows.
Oh yeah, yeah. They are. Yeah.
To talk about that. Yeah.
We've been told it's a cash cow.
Just while you're sitting here,
put a ton of my own money into this and
I'm not seeing anything, man. All right,
we'll take a break.
Hold on.
Yeah,
and now for this segment, Conan O'brien
pays off the mortgage on his beach house.
Yeah. I hate to bore people with my
financial problems, but um, as you know,
I got a beach house but on a nice beach
and then took out a really big mortgage
and then took a loan on that mortgage
almost immediately then took a loan on
that loan. So, so many bad decisions. Yes,
I counted, uh, it's three bad
decisions in a very quick succession.
I'm okay.
Uh,
everyone's fine and kids are going to
eat and there's a roof over her head and
everything, but, um,
I need to get to work.
You need to make some money
and we must do that. Now,
Sony,
you're aware of how much I love to read.
You read constantly and you
kind of make fun of, you know,
the fact that I read a lot, I always
have like a giant book under my arm.
Call it nerd.
Okay.
It's a good way to mock someone for trying
to broaden their horizons. I do, I do.
I love books. I love reading. Uh, living
in Los Angeles soon your car a lot.
And for a long time I tried
reading while I was driving and uh,
just I was wreaking havoc just crashing
into things and that I don't recommend
that. Do not read novels and erotic
thrillers while you're driving,
but it's one of the reasons
that I truly do love audible.
I am a user of audible.
I,
I like audible because I love
listening to books while I'm driving.
Let's honest. You don't love reading
to you. I find it tedious. Um,
would you listen to an audible
book if I was narrating it?
Uh,
why you listen to your voice all the time?
What if you were listening to,
um,
like 50 shades of gray and I
was narrating it. That would be,
would it be like your nightmare?
That would be my absolute nightmare.
And it was so worse thing I could
ever subject myself to. Okay,
I don't see how any of this has anything
to do with audible. And I blame you.
And if you play back the tape,
you'll see that it was you
who brought up 50 shades
anyway. Yes, that's true. You do not love
to read, but you like to hear a book.
I do. I like information. Yeah. Well,
what's cool about audible is you can get
just an incredible selection of audio
books, bestsellers,
mysteries, thrillers, memoirs.
You can choose three titles every month.
You can listen on any device,
anytime, anywhere. You can listen at home.
You can listen at the gym was says at
the gym. I don't know how that works.
I don't know if I could listen
to a really intense book.
Um, while I was at the gym. Well, you
don't read light fare. You read like,
you know,
war and yeah,
I don't think I could read a detailed
account or listen to a detailed account of
the fall or are they the fight
for Stalin Grad? Say, um,
wow.
Uh,
I was doing a bench press or
jazzercise or sizing jazzers sizing.
That's my thing. No, anywhere you are,
you can listen to a audible check it out.
And uh,
they've got a great audio book library.
Get to keep that forever. So I'm,
I'm a believer inaudible.
I actually do listen to great
stuff while I'm driving.
So for a limited time,
you can get three months of
audible for just 695 a month,
six 95 a month.
That's very reasonable.
That's more than half off the regular
price of give yourself a gift.
Cause guess what?
It's that time of year,
the time of year when we think of
ourselves and give ourselves a gift.
That's the true meaning of the holidays.
Give yourself the gift of listening.
And while you're at it, think about
giving the gift of audible to a loved one.
A friend,
someone on that list from more go to
audible.com/conan O'Brien or text Conan
O'brien to 500 500.
And that leads me to this thought
that just popped into my head.
Everybody. Every business wants to
know what their customers are thinking,
what they care about.
And a,
if you've got a business you want to
meet my friends at campaign monitor,
I'll let me explain as best as I can.
Campaign monitor is an
email marketing platform.
It makes it easy to send emails
your customers care about.
I usually know I'm not tech savvy.
Right? What's an email? Okay,
so we're starting at the basics.
Yes. You're saying, okay,
so email is electronic mail.
You get on your computer. Okay.
I don't have a company so I don't know.
These are will you?
I don't think you're going to have
a company. What does that mean?
Why wouldn't I have a company? I
could have a company, I don't know.
You're way too laid back. I am laid back
here. Yeah. You're not starting a company,
but if I did have a company,
I would use campaign monitor.
Yeah. Well, campaign monitor. I'm,
I'm, again, this is what I'm told.
It's got helpful tools.
They have a drag and drop email builder
and they have a library of ready to go
templates.
So you can create a personal relational
email and automations and you can build
relationships with your customers leading
to more engagement and revenue for
your brand. I have a lot of
questions and if you have questions,
they have a friendly support system of
people who are available seven days a
week.
So I might just call them and say,
I just did an ad for you guys and I'd
like you to explain to me what this is and
you can sign up for and try out
their platform for free. No cards,
no contract.
So maybe the best way to find out what
this is is to just sign up and start
using it.
Well,
you know,
if when I opened my company and I start
my company and I want to send out emails
to my customers to market the
products that I will eventually have,
this is the kind of platform I
will use in order to do that.
So I a company would you have,
you'd have,
it'd be something real
chill like beanbag chairs.
I sit that would be a cool company. I'd
have a really cool company. I'd be really,
do I think you're a cool person? You
know that right? I could start a company.
It takes, um, what's it called?
Work to start a company.
It also takes a great email marketing
platform and so I would use campaign
monitor, which are very
successful company. Whatever
that is. Go ahead. You know,
the best thing to do is check it out.
Yeah.
For yourself and go to
campaign monitor.com/conan.
Okay.
Campaign monitor.com/conan campaign
monitor or make your emails unforgettable.
That's um, a slogan. I just thought of.
Rebecca,
can you
hear with Dax Shepard? You really do
think we could be friends? Oh, absolutely.
You know, I really do. I know that
this is like kind of a comedic premise.
I recognize that it's a
bit of a comedic premise,
but it has some grain of truth in it.
Yeah.
I would like to discuss the real
of it. Yeah. If you're open to it,
I am.
Maybe you'll have to save this to episode
100 where you have a breakthrough or
something. Yeah. But in your mind,
when you think about the fact that you
haven't accumulated a bunch of friends in
show business,
my assumption is you think their fault.
Is that accurate? Nothing
is my fault. Well,
I mean it's very human to assume it's
the other person doesn't want to be
friends with you. Yeah. Is that your
assumption? I mean, sincere, uh,
if we're gonna do this sincere thing,
I have to change my tone of voice.
Maybe a different shirt to
get a whole wardrobe they ran in for
sincere wardrobe right now, something,
uh, I need something made of hemp.
Um, yeah, I would say it's a,
mostly,
I would say it's mostly comedic premise
and then there's a grain of truth,
but it more, it comes out. I actually
do not blame other people. I don't,
I don't, uh, if we're going to be
sincere, I don't blame other people. I,
I know that I have,
I spoke with your wife about this.
I'm really busy and I have a a wife and
two kids and I'm really involved with
them.
I had come from a big family and I do
have a set of friends and it's very hard
to get together with them.
It's really hard to make it happen.
You and I also live on
opposite sides of this city,
which shouldn't be a big deal,
but it actually is a gigantic deal.
If you're listening and you don't
know about Los Angeles, uh, you,
it takes 90 minutes for me to get to
Conan's house at the wrong time of day and
it's only 19 miles and
that's in a Leer jet. I mean
you have,
you have post apocalyptic cars
that can drive over other cars.
I've thought about just going straight
over the Santa Monica mountains to your
house in the off road vehicle and I'm
not ruling that out. You do it. Well,
if that fucking p 21 cougar could get
himself from there over to Griffith Park,
I assume. I must be able to. Yeah,
you can do it in your vehicles
needs a mobile ramps and stuff. Oh,
that's a problem. There's a couple
interesting things to explore, which is,
one is that just might be you,
right?
You might not be ultra social and you
might be very satisfied being with your
family and using all the time you're not
at work for your family and then that
would be fine,
but even if you were fine with it,
you'd have to relieve yourself of this
expectation that people should have a ton
of friends. Like you couldn't just
peacefully go, Oh, you know what?
I'm just not that kind of person because
you inherently are innately just kind
of feel like, well, what's wrong
with me? Why don't I desire that?
But I wonder for you is do you desire
it or do you just not desire it?
I think two things.
I think one a,
and this is very hard
for people to believe,
but it's true of a lot of
people to get into comedy.
A lot of people get into comedy or
there's a strain of person that gets into
comedy.
And I think I fall into this category
where there's a bit of a shyness and
people don't believe that I'm
shy because I'm very verbal.
I really do like people, I like to talk
to them, but I am the kind of person who,
if I'm at home and I'm on the
second floor and the doorbell rings,
I'm really hoping my
wife gets it because I'm,
I need a little more,
like I need to ramp up to going
down and saying hi to someone. And,
and I don't think anyone listening to
this would believe that that's true.
But I do get a little shy.
And also when I'm,
when I'm in a restaurant and I see other
celebrities or people I've interviewed,
I'm,
I got to work up the nerve to a little
bit to go over there and say hi to them.
Right.
Because it's not my natural.
I always think people want to
be left alone. I, they don't,
I don't want to bother them. You
know, this is very Boston, have you,
but um,
what's kind of fascinating is,
um,
I two I didn't have social
anxiety my whole life. I'm very,
I was very social. I love going to
bars and stuff. Um, being famous,
uh,
resulted in me having social anxiety
weirdly enough because when I would meet
strangers I would feel,
and again I'm putting this all on myself,
they probably be just happy
to shake my hand that be that.
But I feel this obligation to deliver
something to them when I meet them.
I feel like from the
second we start talking,
it's on my shoulders to make this
a memorable, interesting exchange.
And quite often if we're at a public
place with a bunch of people, I don't,
I can't do that 45 times in one
night. And I start just thinking, oh,
that person left let down. Like, oh,
that guy isn't nearly as fun or gregarious
as he presents himself and Conan's
talk show.
So I feel like I have as a result of,
of being, you know what I mean? Like that
word. But yes, but being famous has, has,
eh, definitely increased my level of,
of social anxiety. That's interesting.
I don't, you know, you had it
on the same level before. Yeah,
I think I had a little bit of that. I
definitely had that shyness before. Um,
I do think to contrast myself with you,
uh,
I,
I do feel like people might expect me to
entertain them a little bit and I do it
for everybody. Sure.
I'm failing and Sonia,
you can weigh in on this,
but if the guy comes to change the smoke
alarm in the house because you know,
uh,
I want that person to have a satisfactory
entertaining moment with Conan O'brien
and, and uh, if I'm at a party
for the 150 people and uh,
and at some function where I'm
supposed to talk to, uh, you know,
I'm supposed to mingle and talk to
them at some function for the network,
I will get to everybody and
I will give them my full,
it's been just fine. The platinum package,
I, everybody gets it. Everybody gets it.
And it's not a status thing. I do
it. I am running for something,
I'm running for some high office and
I don't even know what it's for. Well,
I know for me it is,
and this is something that I've
had to like really work at is um,
the notion that someone would walk
away and not like me is so painful.
My own ego of like someone, like
someone's going to walk away and go, oh,
he's an asshole in real life. I
find that to be, you know, painful.
The thought of. Yes.
But through having kids,
it has helped move me a little
bit closer to a healthy place,
which is I am generally quite nice if
you meet me out in the rest of are a nice
guy. If I'm with my kids, I'm not
very nice because it's their time.
It's no one else's time.
So before at the airport and people want
to take pictures and stuff with us, I,
I'm, I'm not mean, but I'm very direct
in that this is their time. Yup.
And I have had to become comfortable
with the notion that, Yup,
some people on planet earth are going to
leave you and say that guy's a Dick and
tell people that I'll never meet that
I'm a dick and I just have to get
comfortable with that because my priority
is these two little girls and I got to
live with that and you can't control that.
And also you can give
them everything they want,
but if it's a better story later on in a
cocktail party that you're a dick. Yes.
Then you're a dick.
And so and so you just talk to the
person for 15 minutes to try and convince
them that you're a good guy, good
person. And then you bought them.
I'm going to try all airport, uh,
you know, and carried their bags,
gift shop and carry their bags. But then
they're like, yeah, I met him. I Dunno.
It seems like kind of a Dick.
And that's their story for the rest of
their life because frankly on her store,
it's a more fun story. Um, let's
get to this because really quick,
I just love when you were on my show.
He corrected my English like six or
seven times and I just said funner.
And as it was coming out of my mouth,
I go,
he's not going to roll with
that and just match my,
or he's going to say more fun, which
is correct. I don't did, I don't have,
isn't it crazy how lightening
fast these thoughts happen? Well,
from her and in the moment those
two syllables came out of my mouth,
I felt insecure. I thought about
what you were going to do a,
all this stuff happened.
That's where it,
cause I just instantly felt pity for you.
Same Shit.
Let's get to this. We just got to
get it out of the way. Oh, okay. Uh,
I made an attempt, a good hearted
attempt. I came out of my shell,
I reached out to and I said, let's,
uh, after he would suggested it,
let's really make this double date happen,
but oh, that's insufficient. Hold on.
That's not sufficient. Hold
on. Okay, go ahead. You, uh,
I, I put out there, uh, how
about three, four, no, none.
And I'm not letting you proceed.
Your, your, your, your timeline.
You've jumped way too far
ahead. Okay. So here's what's,
here's what really happened, which is
I've been on your show 350 times. Yeah.
We get along great on your show.
We have a great chemistry. Yes.
Some of my finest chemistry is
shared with you and my wife.
That is a very specific rapport we have.
Yes.
And I ran into you in Santa Barbara
at a party and we started talking.
Yeah. And there I discovered you
love history and I love history.
So we started really talking
about history. It was whole bunch.
It was fun to our wives.
Total erotic fantasy come true. Yeah. Um,
they weren't, they weren't
touching themselves as, as
we were discussing grants.
Second term. Yes. So in that moment, uh,
also that you ride bicycles,
you ride motorcycles, so
that now we discovered, oh,
we could be real life friends. Right.
I just, I think that's relevant.
It's not like on the 29th appearance
on your talk show. You were like, Hey,
let's hang.
No,
and we talked about maybe getting together
and we tried to make it happen a few
times and then I just get her to do a
real three dimensional human being that I
would be interested in hanging out with.
But those, is that a surprise to you?
Absolutely. I meet you on
a talk show. Yeah. Yeah.
You have a persona during the talk show.
Is it that different from who I am and
really you do a different voice like I
don't know, every two
minutes now if you imagine,
I mean someone over for dinner who's
going to do a different voice every two
minutes? Let me in. I can entertain you.
I'm one it those mashed potatoes I lesson.
That was my catch phrase for
94 those mashed potatoes.
That was my catch phrase in 94 slash
95 one of those mashed potatoes.
It was a big thing.
Then look it up.
It was just as that was during
friends for a season. Here we go.
I put out how about three 14 three
15 or three 24 you right back.
You're really excited.
And you say three 15 I love that
you're saying your exact sentences,
but paraphrasing mind.
I don't feel like this is just
at all cause I have the same,
I have the same shit on my phone
that I also brought. Okay. Listen,
I'm half of this print it out on pieces of
paper, which makes me better. Okay. The,
so we established that the date would
be three 15 now you're a history buff.
March 15th the ides of
March. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
What happened on the Julius Caesar
was stabbed by Marc Antony. Um, right.
It was a Brutus Brutus
stabbed him. Brutus. Yeah.
Brutus Stamp Mark Antony. I don't take
Mark Anthony. Like how I'm saying Antony.
Antony was his only friend, right?
Yeah. Well but Brutus was a friend.
March 15th is a famous state
that when it goes sideways,
when not just that when a man is betrayed
by someone he thought was his friend.
Yeah. Okay. The ides
of March. Okay, great.
So you write me back and here's,
you better read this shit verbatim
because I have it. I have it right here.
I actually was delighted.
So again,
I'm going to interject because
I'm the fucking did this.
Then I let you talk more when you were on
my show. So let me talk for one second.
Oh, here we go. Hold up. Let
a sense stones here though.
You're pissed. Order order.
So your pistol quiet. Clearly.
I've got him on the road. Okay,
go says I'm doing voices all the
time. A teen, true. Like Tatiana,
attain TrueCar. I'm secure. I
don't need to entertain constantly.
You say perfect.
I'll start fasting now.
Three 15 march 15 exclamation point.
Okay. Your friend is telling you to
flip the page. Uh, that's not my friend.
This is like watching your 90 year old
grandma kick your ass. It's laborious.
Then I reached out to you on the
15th and say, Hey, is this happening?
You get back to me and the only
reason I bring this up here as well,
or I insist you now go verbatim, which
I'm now holding the same script as you.
Okay, go ahead. Okay, let me do my
part. You read new because by the way,
when I looked this up to find out
who was right or who was wrong,
and you'll soon learn I was wrong.
I can admit that that's all I wanted.
I was upset to see that I was wrong.
But then it was delighted by our
exchange because it really delivered.
You're very funny in your exchange.
And I say one thing just before him.
The only reason I bring this up
and being so such a stickler,
is it an I did your podcast and I said
you canceled day up and you insisted that
it was impossible that
you would cancel day of.
So I went back into the files as did I.
And when I realized that
you cancel day of I dance,
I orgasm for the first time in four years,
mostly done mixing. Most mostly
dust came out some lint. Yeah,
Lynn and a a a Lincoln Penny.
So my friend Conan inquires,
whether or not we're on for that night.
And here's my response.
So when we made these plans
and I picked this date,
I knew I was shooting a Sitcom,
but at the time they told me we would
shoot live on Fridays in front of an
audience.
Then I got the schedule last night and
learned I will be shooting stuff tonight
as well.
For some weird reason I'm attaching it I
guess because it's very important to me
that you know,
I'm not lying,
which in and of itself probably d'oeuvre
deserves some exploration. At any rate,
I'm very bummed that this is the
case and I hope we can reschedule.
Don't give up on me. Dad. Interesting.
You made me your father. Uh Huh.
That's right. And I did attach
the, the, the, the schedule.
Would you by the way, literally did
come up the night before. So yes,
I couldn't have really done a better job
because I just found out basically when
you found out, I understand not to excuse
it, I still canceled on you day off.
But can I, are you gonna read
your response or can I read yours?
I don't think it's, yours is
great. So you say, you say Dax,
I called your line producer and
you aren't even in the cast.
He said you never got the role and haven't
worked in months. You need help man.
No problem.
Let's do it some other time.
It's not like I'm terminally
ill or anything off to the
doctor now Conan, right.
This is a brilliant response.
And then I respond Hahahahaha
I give you like nine hah. Aha.
You know how funny I thought it was quote,
I called your line producer.
I'm even quoting you. Yeah, you wrote
back, I was told that's a thing. Yeah,
a little self deprecation at the end.
Now I look at that as a big victory
for both of us. It wasn't a victory.
And you know what? I wasn't upset.
I wasn't upset. The only reason I'm,
we're talking about this now is that
you insisted by, we never had cast that.
You would never do that.
And I just had to set the record
straight that on the ides of March,
you stabbed me in the back.
I did once you bleed on the steps
and the vote on the Senate floor. Um,
but no, it is, you know, it is,
we're going to get together and you and
I are going to talk about history and
maybe the ladies can't be,
maybe the ladies can't be there if
we're going to talk about history.
Well that's the other most predictable
outcome of our night at the farmer's
daughter hotel is that you and I probably
will just start passionately rolling
around in the, in the binding of
a grant biography. Yes, exactly.
Marrying the pages on his said,
uh,
listen,
I gotta say that was probably my favorite
moment you and I ever had on your show
was I was going through
what I think I am out of 10.
Do you recall this? You probably
don't. I do. I'm a six but, but,
but lucky for us men,
women subconsciously average your
personality in your looks and that's what
they're seeing. So I was telling
you, well, my personality is a Tan.
It looks for a six. Thank God my wife sees
an eight when I walk in the door. Yeah.
And then you said to me,
what am I? And I said, well,
your looks or a five and you came
unglued. And I'm like, well, hold on,
I'm only giving myself six. Do you
remember that? And that was really cool.
It was a five. I still don't understand.
There's no comedy. If I say six,
there's comedy.
If I say you want to lower the whole
thing was that you're being sincere on
podcasts.
I am on your show.
I'm a liar and an instigator
and a provocate tour. Right.
But marriage challenge, all those guys.
What am I, we're on the podcast now.
I think you and I are very comparable.
I think you're a six.
I think I'm higher than that. Okay. What
do you think you are okay. I've got,
first of all,
I think if I got a few things fixed,
not the listen to me.
I have host makeover assessment.
I have fin, unattractive lips. Get those
plumped out. Okay. I have rat. Like guys,
I have BDI and I have an eye vein
that shows up on camera and uh,
and I, if I could get those things,
I have killer hair. I haven't,
I'm a 12 when it comes to, well, you
can't go over 10. Okay. I'm a 10 in hair.
Okay. Uh, I've got, uh, I've work out.
My body is in pretty good shape. It is.
Yeah. And I give myself from my age, I'm
going to give myself an eight on that. Uh,
but yeah, I got to get
ready out. Go Higher.
I'd say if we're just talking your
physique at 55, you're at nine. Okay.
Thank you. Yeah. Yeah. So you're
saying my grade down shit,
my face drags me down to a, well, no,
I'm not, I'm not averaging your body.
I'm just going with your face
and your personality. Okay.
What's wrong with the personality?
It's great. It's a 10. He's a 10.
Your looks are five key guilty.
It makes you a 7.5.
I've only got you by 0.5 in my scenario.
I don't,
you don't accept that it's good for you.
You've got a competitive flair.
I got to fix this thing. We got it. You,
I gotta really some fillers it
sounds like is what you want.
You want some fillers in your lips? I
want lips filler. I have to have the eyes,
uh,
opened up a little bit cause when I looked
from sign up to go to Asia for that,
that's a procedure that's done.
I, when I look from side to side,
I look like one of those.
I looked like a rat looking around to
see if the room is safe to enter and I
want that to go away. Okay.
We can fix that. Yeah.
And you can see my veins
through my skin because of my,
my Pale that we're stuck with.
Unless you want to wear an eye patch
because they can't make your skin thicker.
To my knowledge,
I was thinking of having the,
I moved but then I found out that it
supplies most of the blood to my brain.
Okay.
Then let's not do that.
Although you know what you could do is
you could use this great product Latiece
that women use to make
their eyelashes thicker.
I think if we got your
eyelashes so thick and powerful,
it could distract from that vein you don't
like. Okay. What do you think of that?
I'll do it. Okay, great. I think
what we took away from all of this,
and maybe this is why, I dunno,
you sorta gave away the ending too.
Maybe this whole podcast, which is
that I may not want a lot of friends.
I have a couple of friends who are
really good friends and I have, uh,
I have friends that go back 35 years
who I talked to all the time once,
twice a week. Yeah. I'm really
close with those people.
You're also someone who historically has,
uh,
remained friends with people you've worked
with think is a pretty good sign. Yes.
Oh No. I'm a loyal friend. I
just, I don't think I'm looking,
that's why you've ruined this
podcast. I try. I'm hoping to,
I don't think at the end of the day,
I would love to hang with you
whenever we can make that happen,
but I don't think I'm looking for a lot
of celebrity friends and I think we have
to change the name of the podcast. Well,
do they have to be celebrity friends?
What's the point of having a regular
friend while at celebrity front and bring
up, you bring up a good point. It's
going to sound terrible, but I'm,
I do very well with the common man.
Aw,
I'm sure that's what the guy who installed
your smoke detector told them in the
hallway. He was doing some
work here. So I said, hey,
they had common man.
I know you are applied.
Did you have any problem getting
your mule up the driveway? All right,
we got to wrap this right. You are a,
you're an ex new feel how much I like,
you know,
I keep trying to make this go longer.
Do you feel me trying to make this go
longer because it's more time with you.
I do and it's pushing me away. I'm going
to feel needy. Yeah, it's going to,
it's coming out. It's a
very neat. Okay. Um, but uh,
loved this so much. Also, I'm, I
can't believe this hasn't come up yet.
You are a, you have, you're
killing it in the podcast world.
So I am absolutely thrilled that
you and that you took the time to,
to come here and do this because
this is your, this is your main ta.
I don't know what that word means.
It's not French. She said correctly.
It sounds like Matt and Matt,
like the Latin format may be seen as
something I do in the afternoons. Okay.
No, this is just, this is
what you do. You've, uh,
you took to it like a duck to water
that hadn't been in water before,
but then immediately like the water. All
right. God bless you. You're a good man.
I love you Conan O'brien. I
love you too. Dax Shepard.
And now another segment of Conan O'brien
pays off the mortgage on his beach
house.
Give it's okay.
So now I'd like to talk about a sensitive
issue if that's cool with you. Um,
it's about guys in a
certain health problem,
but not going to say this as
delicately as I can, but, uh,
it's erectile dysfunction. You
know, that's something that, uh,
some men struggle with.
You know,
guys feel awkward discussing it.
I feel awkward discussing it
right now because we're, I mean,
first of all because I'm discussing
it here and you're my assistant.
That's strange. But also I feel a little
awkward debt in this room right now.
There's about 150 people. I don't know
why we have that many people in here.
It seems, it seems silly. You're also,
you're a repressed Irish Catholic.
Yes. And very repressed. I
don't discuss sexual matters.
That has never been my way and uh, but
this is something we should talk about.
It's something that's
healthy to talk about.
A lot of guys out there
have trouble with Ed and uh,
there's this product Roman that's created
an easy way to get checked out by a
doctor and then get treated for
erectile dysfunction on the line.
And let me just say something as a
guide and please let me be very clear.
I have not had this issue myself yet.
Could happen anytime now,
but it's hard to discuss
this with anybody.
There have been times where I've been
talking to a doctor and I haven't wanted
to bring up,
hey,
what if I someday need that a
drug for rectal dysfunction.
So what I try and do is pretend I'm
talking about a head cold, you know,
like I've got a really bad head cold and
it's really bad and I'm worried someday
the head cold might give me Ed and
then he says, do you want an Ed drug?
And I'm like, no man, I don't need
that. Just talking about my head cold.
So it goes through all these
different and I don't even have it.
You keep saying you don't have it.
It's me.
It's making me think you might
have it and I might have it. Well,
if I was a guy and I had this,
I wouldn't want to,
I would just want to do it like take
care of it quietly. Really? Yeah.
You wouldn't want to put
an ad the paper and said,
I have erectile dysfunction
is anybody know what to do?
And then a picture of yourself, is
that what you did? We didn't want,
she was mistake. Hmm. Point
is there's no waiting rooms.
There's no awkward face to face where
you say to the doctor or your dentist or
whoever you're going to,
I need an erectile dysfunction drug.
I had a guy fitting me for a ThoughtWorks
once the shoe store and I said,
can you get me, uh, an
erectile dysfunction drug?
I was escorted out of the shoe store
very quickly. Anyway, a handle,
everything online.
All you have to do is visit.
Get roman.com/conan that's right.
My dreams fulfilled.
Fill out a brief medical onboarding,
chat with a doctor,
get FDA approved,
erectile dysfunction meds
delivered to your door discreetly.
Maybe even could put
something else on the package.
Here's that drug you need to keep
you from having a constant direction.
Would that be great? Like, yeah,
man, I'm just ready to go 24,
seven and it's a problem because I work
literally around Hummel figurines and
I'm always smashing them,
man.
Even Gorley's laughing at this one
was hard to get too specific. I know,
but you work at, at Hummel figurines
store, you've got a constant erection.
You turn, what's that smash.
But is it to my rights smash?
You just broke 35 little Hummel figurines,
poor little alpine boy and
later hose and hiking up a hill.
He knew what he knew what he
was in for a and that's it.
That's an idea of Roman wants to use that.
Go ahead and use it,
but actually I'm all joking aside.
I think this is a, you know,
sounds like a good idea.
For a free online visit,
go to get Roman dotcom slash Conan.
That's get roman.com/conan
for a free online visit.
Get roman.com/conan it's time to
have an erection again.
Is that right?
Tried to think of a slogan. Roman,
it's time to have an erection.
I don't see what's wrong with that.
Roman,
can you imagine if we got like
James Earl Jones to say that Roman,
it's time to have an erection again.
That's a good,
I don't see anything wrong with that.
That tells you exactly what's happening
with this product. You're welcome, Roman.
You can have that for free.
God,
I don't understand how you
make money in this business.
He's drawing pictures of erections
on his head. Copy. In all fairness,
those pictures of erections were drawn
long before I read this Ad. All right.
You know, some artists
work in clay, some in oils.
I draw your reactions.
All right,
well you want some Clinton really happy
about right now my parents don't know
how to get a podcast.
Hi everyone.
This is Matt again.
So there's some things slightly unique
with this one and that you guys have semi
concrete plans to actually
hang out as friends.
Do you think that that actually
going to happen? Yeah, I do for sure.
I have a lot of shortcomings, but I
am an, again, March 15th excluded.
I am a man of my word.
It did seem like you took great pains
to show how stressed you are that I
included a document when I my
comment, right? Yeah. Yeah.
So I definitely think we will hang out
sooner or later he'll move east or I'll
move west. There's no way we'll
end our lives separated like this.
You'll do it for each other. No, no. But
just by some other set of circumstance,
you've gone deeper than anyone else
that's far, so thank you for that. Okay,
thank you.
Sana? Yes. It's time to play
a little game. We call true
or false with sona much.
[inaudible] y'all said not really. Okay,
here we go. We were just a on tour.
Of course, Conan working hard. I'd go out
and I do my, you know, 40 minutes up top.
Then I go out at the end.
I'm working hard going city to city,
18 city tour a year there do
help me out too. Or false.
You left me on the last leg of the
tour you took off. True or false?
True. Ben, did you leave me
with anyone to help me? No.
You left me alone? Yes. Would you
like to talk about that at all?
Did you feel bad about it? No.
Okay. I don't feel bad about it.
She took off and then it was up to me
to carry on by myself and it was tough.
I'm not trying to make you feel
guilty or anything, but if I were you,
I'd feel a lot of guilt.
At first. I liked how you, you
said a code and working hard.
I just have to get that
out to any of this.
Like talking in the third person
when I hear you talk about this,
I just here,
you're so valuable that when you
leave there's a hole in my life.
That's a nice way to look at it. And
you know what? You are valuable to me.
So when you left, um, I thought,
I hope this is for a good reason.
Where'd you go? I went to
a wedding. Whose wedding?
I went to my friend on I his wedding.
My friend [inaudible] and Roger
got married in London. In London.
She a close relative? No.
Oh no, she's a friend.
You just went to a friend's wedding. I
went to a friend's wedding. Yeah, I did.
Did you think at all?
Maybe I shouldn't go because I'm
with Conan on this important tour.
Do you want me to be honest?
Of course.
I didn't think about it at all.
I also,
I don't even know if I told you that I
wasn't going to be there until like you
did like a day before he
did.
And that's another point. You didn't
say anything to me like, you know,
a month from now because you had
to buy tickets to go to London.
You had to make big arrangements to go.
You didn't say anything to me.
You just day before like, Oh yeah, I'm
not here tomorrow. You're on your own.
Good luck getting all
of your shit together.
Good luck with your tour.
Laughy chimpy boy.
And then you took off and you donate.
Who is this person?
I've never even heard her name before.
Laughy chimpy boy. No, Nas. Who's nae?
So I don't even know her. Her. She's
a friend of mine every time. Oh God,
you have so many fives.
Real popular. I know, but,
but sometimes I think you throw around
the term friend a little loosely because
you're just like, oh yeah, she's my
friend. They got to go to London.
Did you really have to go right now?
Do you think you made the right call?
Yes. I don't regret it even for a second.
I uh, uh, yeah, I do. You
should. You should not be a lot.
So what I really did was you like
having rifts where you make fun of how
terrible I am at my job. So I just
stepped away from that for a few days.
So if you're asking me,
hey,
did you miss me making fun
of you incessantly for a
few days so you could go to
London for a wedding?
A Ah,
it wasn't a hard decision to make it
all. Okay. Quick question. You left,
left me in the lurch.
Uh,
but then you said that you were
going to be back for the next,
the show at the start of the next
part of the leg, which was in Chicago.
Were you there in time
to go with us to Chicago?
No, that's right. You weren't.
What, what happened there?
My flight got canceled.
Could you leave a little buffer there
for that flight back so you can get back
to you? Important job? No, I want
you to maximize my time in London.
So I booked the fight for
the morning of the show.
You booked the flight in London for the
morning of my show in Chicago that you
were supposed to be at and then,
oops. Oh, that didn't work out.
You're on your own again.
Chimpy boy.
But it my defense. Do you make fun
of me a lot? I do. I'm good at it.
It might be the thing I'm best at now.
Now listen,
let's make sure that we're honest here.
Do you make fun of me a lot? Yes I do.
It's what I'm best at.
I think we are both.
I think in each other we have the person.
Isn't it crazy that the person your best
make it making fun of in the world is
Conan O'brien and the person I'm best
at making fun of in the world is sort of
assessing and then we happened to meet.
Yes. And we happen to work together.
This is like Lennon Meeting Mccartney.
It's magical.
I don't understand that reference at all.
I'm sorry.
They were singers a long before
there were, uh, you know,
apps and spo that Lennon
and McCarthey McCartney.
Wait, did you think I was talking about
Vladimir Lenin and Joel and Joe McCarthy?
Yes. Yeah, you're right. You know what
you're like, you're like, you're like,
I'm Vladimir Lenin and
you were red baiting
redbaiting Cami Hunter. Joe McCarthy.
Yes. Perfect. It's perfect analogy.
We're the perfect analogy Carthy
and I was like Lennon, him,
Ricardo and understand that her leash,
oh my God,
this is great. I actually think
we're perfect as you know what?
Let's leave it that way.
Vladimir Lenin and Joseph McCarthy,
that's what we are together.
So one of us has a stroke at a pretty
young age and the other one dies of
alcoholism. I'm happy you're
going to be the stroke one.
Conan O'brien needs a friend with sona
most Sassy and then Conan O'brien as
himself, produced by me, Matt Gorley,
executive produced by Adam Sachs and Jeff
Ross at Team Coco and Collin Anderson
and Chris van and at Earwolf special
thanks to Jack White and the white stripes
for the theme song,
incidental music by Jimmy Levine.
You can rate and review this show on
apple podcasts and you might find your
review featured on a future episode.
Got a question for Conan and call the
team coco hotline at (323) 451-2821 and
leave a message it to could be featured
on a future episode and if you haven't
already, please subscribe to Conan
O'brien. Needs a friend on apple podcasts,
stitcher, or wherever. Find fine
casts are down.
Yeah.
This has been 18 cocoa
production in association with,
Hey, this is Arnie from the comedy
podcasts. Hello from the magic tavern,
a chat show I host from the magical land
of food with my cohost use at all the
blue wizard and chunk the shape shifter.
Most weeks we interview adventurers,
wedding planners, ambulatory trees, but
this week we have a special episode.
I am so excited to learn about the
Earth Law in pride and prejudice.
We're going to do a book
club up pride and prejudice.
And you said this is a well
of both on earth, right? Yeah.
It's one of those books that people love
or were forced to read or more likely
it's one of those,
I'm going to get to it,
and some of our most beloved of guests
are rich hurting to read the book with us
and enjoy some drinks and food. Have a
book club. We are flower. We have chrome,
the barbarian and girl.
You know who they are.
Maybe you don't give a crap about what
an academic thinks about Jane Austen,
but don't you want to know what a
wizard and a badge or think about it.
Not enough spells, not enough,
not enough sword fights.
Whether you love pride and prejudice or
have no interest in reading it and just
want to listen to a book club
going really off the rails.
You'll enjoy this week's hello from the
magic tavern. We shall defeat this book.