[inaudible] joining me today as a
professor of economics at George Mason
University,
the host of conversations with Tyler
podcast and the author of stubborn
attachments, a vision for a
society of free, prosperous,
and responsible individuals. Tyler Cowen,
welcome to the Rubin report. My pleasure.
Now I did your podcast once and I believe
that the first question you asked me
was do I like being on the interviewing
side or in the interview side?
So I'm going to start with
the same exact question.
I spent the first half of my life being
interviewed the last fifth of my life
being the interviewer for 58 segments
and now I'm being interviewed. So for me,
so we've come full circle and then
around halfway around again are saying
there's less preparation when you're
being interviewed. So that's easier. Yeah.
All right, so I'm, I'm
thrilled that you're here.
I wanted to have you on for for
quite some time. You are sort of for,
for so many of the people that have
influenced me, you have influenced them.
So I think there's a,
there's a certain beauty of this and
we're going to do a lot on economics and,
and,
and all sorts of stuff here,
but I always like to start with
sort of little bit of background,
just sort of where you're from and
history before we get into the meat.
So tell me a little bit about Tyler Cowen.
I was born in northern New Jersey.
I was a nerd growing up. I played chess.
It was that an economics and philosophy.
Now I teach at George
Mason and live in Virginia.
Travel a lot and I'm a kind of
information omnivore. Yeah, and you're a,
you're a big basketball fan.
We just did a whole basketball NBA fan
sprays a big difference. Yeah. So me too,
I'm not a huge college fan nor mine.
It's not good enough.
And so why not watch the best,
right? There's enough of the NBA,
especially with the Internet and Youtube,
and it's a way of thinking about
talent evaluation, rules of the game,
technical innovations,
conceptual breakthroughs,
how to get a group of people to cooperate.
It's a kind of economics in a way.
It's like a new laboratory.
Yeah.
So when did you get interested
in economics and economics?
I was 13 and my father brought home
like some magazines and periodicals.
I started reading them. I then went to
the public library. Never stopped. Yeah.
Yeah. You went to the
library, never said, and were,
were you always interested in sort of
more libertarian leaning economics or do
you read everything and then kind
of figure out where you fell or,
I read everything but early on I read
Hayak I read Milton Friedman, uh,
some of Vine Rand Henry Hazlitt. That
made a big impression on me. And uh,
I was, you know, then 13, 14. Yeah.
Was that a weird thing for a 13 or 14
year old to be into? Or I guess you said,
I think it was, and this
was pre internet, right?
So people were not exposed and I just
went crazy and I read all of Plato's
dialogues and I just thought, I'm going
to do this for the rest of my life.
How can I find a way of always being,
reading, writing, talking to people? Yeah.
What do you like more doing the
academic side of things? Teaching?
Or do you like podcasting?
More public speaking?
I don't think they're so different.
Podcasting is the new education, right?
So think of it as an educational
innovation and you reach people.
The discussions are often smarter
than in the classic classroom.
So I view it as one in the same really
kind of integration. Yeah. So, okay.
So let's just talk about your economic
beliefs in general. So basically,
basically you're a libertarian,
right? Is that smaller libertarian?
So what does that mean? Cause
people say that all the time. Let's,
I like defining terms specifically when
you say you're a small l libertarian,
I believe in freer markets,
social liberalism,
and I'm often skeptical of
foreign policy abroad. That said,
some libertarian simply refuse to admit
that government can never do good.
I don't think that's the case.
Antismoking campaign would be one good
example of something that did people a
lot of good. It was led by
government. So empirics come first,
look at the evidence.
But I think overall right now,
people in our society under a business
and over eight the government. Yeah.
So is there any difference,
any meaningful difference between a small
l libertarian in a classical liberal,
when people say classical liberal,
I think it confuses the listener.
Does the word liberal in there?
What does classical mean?
That reminds people of the 19th century.
I don't like any of these words.
I feel I've written and
done so much online.
People can use search and see
what I think on any issue,
but I'll still go with
small and a libertarian.
I won't deny I'm a classical liberal,
so I should probably be saying small
little libertarian by, by your definition.
I agree. It's gotten confusing. I'm
trying to clean up the word liberal so,
so deeply that it becomes hard to do
that because people have suggested
associations with the word.
If I could just call myself liberal
as you can in some European countries,
that would be my preferred approach.
But here it just won't work. Right.
That's the problem. Yeah. Well this
is listened to all over the world.
So in England, I'm a liberal. You're a
liberal know liberal that that's nice.
So light touch a government,
how do you figure out where the right
spot for government to do some things?
It's cause I'm sure there's libertarians
that may be our big l libertarians that
are going all right,
well even if the antismoking thing worked,
it's not the purview of
government to do such things.
I believe in the power of economic growth.
Uh,
the significance of just compounding
returns over time and the economy that
grows at 3% over time becomes much,
much wealthier than an economy
growing at 2%. So we need to ask like,
what are genuine public goods
the government should provide?
I think support for basic science or
basic social welfare state or safety net,
obviously foreign policy than there are
particular instances where governments
have done good. Uh, but the presumption
should be in favor of liberty.
People do have individual rights. You
just can't take all their money from them.
We way overregulate most of our economy.
We could be far more dynamic.
We've had wage stagnation in this
country for decades and we are complacent
about all that. I mean that, that's
my basic take on America today. Yeah.
And I think, you know, I'm, I'm
pretty much on board of all that.
Are you shocked at the
amount of individual liberty
that people sort of want to
outsource to the government?
As you said, they,
they want to trust government more than,
than markets. Right now on social issues,
I'm fairly hardened.
I don't think people should ever
go to jail for smoking pot say,
and we're moving in that direction. I
never expected that say 15 years ago, uh,
gay rights, gay marriage. Again, it wasn't
clear or a while ago that would happen.
And that's great. Yeah. In those areas,
people have been very protective
and fought hard for good changes.
But when it comes to economics,
I see too much resentment and too much
shrillness and just to believe that most
say billionaires out there and
somehow didn't earn their wealth.
And it's our job to take it from that,
which is becoming a huge theme right now.
Right. I mean, Elizabeth
Warren, just in the last week,
she wants a billionaire's
tax and she's upset that,
who's the guy that got the yacht?
Uh Oh, I forget. Yeah. You know,
he got a yacht and then she doesn't seem
to understand that a lot of people were
employed to build that yacht at all
the resources that went into that yet.
But she thinks she has a moral right,
that that seems to be coming out
to the left a lot these days.
Cortez is doing this,
that there's a moral right to take
people's money who have too much.
I think a lot of it is just
competition for the voters.
So everyone wants either the
nomination and more publicity,
so they put forward crazy ideas
to get traction on social media.
The net result is to help Donald Trump,
actually,
I call it the Donald
Trump reelection campaign.
The more Democrats talk about taxes,
it's ultimately a winning
issue for Republicans.
No matter what the Democrats say, voters
will never trust them more on taxes.
It's like healthcare. No matter what
your view is, when that's the topic,
Democrats are more popular in taxes.
A trip.
Publicans so it's this weird paradox,
democrats pursuing their own individual
interests and hurting their party.
Do you think that the,
like when Elizabeth Warren or one of
these people that always want to tax more
and more and more,
do you think they actually believe
it's the right thing to do or that they
believe it's cold,
calculated political move,
even though your argument is that
it doesn't make sense politically?
Like I don't imagine them doing things
that are against what they believe will
work politically. I think you're
probably right that it doesn't work,
but it's hard to know if they,
they know that it doesn't work.
It's a cold calculating political move.
In my view.
They don't quite think it's a disaster.
They just think we need to move the
debate in this direction about taxing rich
people more talking about this
for them will work in that way.
So they have a broader notion of work
than what an academic might have and more
or less coincides with
making a stink about it. Now,
does he drive you crazy when
politicians talk about economics? No,
I mean newer to that, uh, I think I'm
fairly detached as a personality type.
I don't like it, but at the end
of the day, if it drove me crazy,
I would be less effective
communicating myself.
So who would you say in the political
sentence is talking about economics in a
way that is roughly within a framework
that you like? Is there anybody?
It's hard to think. So I'm pro
immigration, but with limits, uh,
that's a pretty centrist position. But the
center is pretty empty right now. Okay.
But I'll,
I'll go,
let's lay it out for me and I'll see
if we can figure out somebody here.
The liberal have an earlier time perhaps.
So private immigration,
definitely pro free trade,
which is running against a lot
of the Republicans right now. Uh,
other than say climate change issues.
I would deregulate most of our economy.
I would have much more freedom to build
in San Francisco or Manhattan. Uh,
I would have radical reforms to k through
12 education with much greater choice,
just a lot more experimentation.
I would never send people to jail for
doing drugs unless they're selling drugs
to minors. Uh, I'm not sure are all
drugs should be totally illegal,
but just kind of in a safe
space off to the side.
And I would welcome a not so polarized
America where there's tolerance and a
very strong center and some real belief
about the importance of America's role
in the world, but more about building
alliances than being aggressive.
That means that those are
my views. Yeah. I mean, I,
I'm there I'd everything you just said.
Yeah.
And I do think that empty
center that you just referenced,
these actually starting to get filled up
with people that have had it with both
sides, which is I guess, heartening, but
we've got our work cut out for it. Yes.
Yeah. I don't know who the candidate
Israeli, yeah. Uh, you know,
I write for Bloomberg, so I'm reluctant
to say Mike Bloomberg of the Democrats,
but he is in fact my favorite with
the caveat that I write for Bloomberg.
So I appreciate the Gavi. Otherwise the
Youtube commenters would of went bananas.
You don't want to deal with their wrath
wrath. What do you think about that?
Just the two party duopoly
that we have right now and,
and how hard it would be for say, a
more centrist candidate. Like even now,
just in the last couple of days,
Howard Schultz of Starbucks is saying he
may jump in as an independent, and he,
it sounds like he'd be a little bit more
of a centrist Democrats say than the
really far left progressive,
but at you tile endeavor,
I believe in working through the parties.
Yeah.
There's much about Donald
Trump I disagree with,
but he was effective because he decided
not doing the reform party bid from the
late nineties, but he would work through
one of the two major parties. Yeah. So on,
on most of the issues that you talked
about in terms of regulation and freeing
the economy and things like that,
you've gotta be pretty pleased
with the trunk on regulation. Uh,
the administration has slowed the pace,
uh,
but on carbon and environmental issues,
I disagree with deregulation.
I think we actually need to be tougher.
So even there, that's a mixed record. Uh,
Trump hasn't rolled back that much
regulation. This is too hard to do.
But the pace has been slowed. I'm
happy about that. Yeah. Is there a way,
because our system is so huge and
our federal government is so big,
is there really a way to do a lot of this?
I think people sort of hear the
idea of let's roll back regulation,
let's you know, drain the swamp. All
of these phrases that, that sound good,
but then they get in office
and they realize that this,
this giant Federal Munster that is just
sucking money and employing all sorts of
people that probably it shouldn't. And
all of this that it just doesn't change.
It's just the system is sort of corroded.
Our best bet is to invent new sectors
more quickly than they can be regulated.
So let's say for instance that virtual
reality where to really work and people
would take to it. You could have
schools within virtual reality,
they would be unregulated. Not Out
of any government. Tolerance is just,
no law is set up to really regulate
virtual reality in any direct way.
So parts of the tech sector have
had a light hand of regulation,
not through anyone's wisdom.
They just started doing things
now and had been expecting.
And so there's a kind of race.
So do you believe,
so you basically believe them that self
regulations within certain parameters
does just happen.
It just sort of happens itself.
I'm glad we let Facebook and Uber happened
and that no one had to ask permission.
Do this company sometimes make
mistakes? Yes. Are they perfect? No.
Are we better off having them? Absolutely.
So if Uber had had to ask permission,
I imagine that,
oh like 10 years from now we'll do a
pilot plan where like maybe a fifth of the
drivers in Seattle do ride sharing and
most cities say no and they just did it.
I'm all for that.
Right.
And it always becomes a giant
government boondoggle anyway.
If you look at the New York City taxis
with the used to cost about a million
bucks just to get one of those
medallions and then it's like there's no
competition. So I'm worried ride
sharing will turn into that.
But then there's always the new thing.
And again,
it's this kind of race where
innovation has to outpace regulation.
The nice thing about government
regulators is there a bit slow, right?
They're very formulistic. It takes some
time. Innovators can be very quick.
So is that the silver lining
more than anything else?
That's the silver lining
up ugly aren't that great.
They're mostly conscientious. I mean,
they do the job, they're told to do.
There are countries with much worse
regulation than the United States.
We should appreciate what we have.
But that said,
if you look at say occupational
licensing for barbers and beauticians are
interior designers, in my opinion,
none of that should exist.
It should all simply disappear tomorrow.
So what would you say to the person
who would say, well, wait a minute.
What if I go to,
uh,
get my haircut and this person hasn't
been licensed by the state and now they
stabbed me in the head with the
scissor? Well, murders against the law,
but I'm not sure the licensing stops
that the more competition here,
it's not just the license,
it's stopping people from stabbing people
with scissors. Is that what you're,
there should be laws against tos or
stabbing in my humble opinion. So, okay,
so you talked a little bit about the,
the tech side of this.
Why is it that,
it seems to me that the people that I
know that are up in Silicon Valley and the
tech world in general is very,
very privately libertarian.
These people want to innovate,
they want competition.
They want to do exactly
what you're saying,
stay ahead of the regulators and figure
out new ways to do all sorts of things.
But outwardly,
these companies seem extremely left and
extremely controlling and centralized.
Many tech companies are in California,
a lot of highly educated California
employees are very left wing.
Those employees pressure their companies.
Also,
a lot of tech companies have big
contracts with the government,
which puts them in somewhat
of an awkward position.
And the ideal stands for
many companies tech or nod,
it's just not to be in politics.
And I think most people in business would
rather compete as a business or get a
favor from the government.
But the tech companies,
one of the miraculous things about
them is defense. Contracting aside,
their core model has been to supply
better products to users and not to curry
favor with the state.
And to me that's highly admirable,
but are we entering an odd place where
they clearly do have relationships with
the government at this point? Are we
entering a phase where this is where,
this is the great debate
right now in my world as a,
as a guy that's doing this on youtube
is have these companies gotten so out of
control that there is now a threat
actually to the first amendment because
basically there is government involvement
related to policing speech and are
they platforms or publishers,
that sort of thing.
If I look at youtube or
a fly look at Twitter,
I think they have supported far more
freedom of speech than they have hindered.
And if you even ask like which set of
views had been helped the most by youtube
and Twitter?
I suspect on average it's a mix of like
the right and some part of the radical
left. But I don't think
overall right wing ideas,
and that's not even the
correct way to put it,
but I don't think they've been harmed
by these media. Quite the contrary.
So I'm not as worked up about that issue
as some of my friends are. Yeah. But,
but either way you would, even if you
saw more of a threat there, you would,
there's no,
is there any situation where you ever
believe the government should jump in and
do something?
Any is a tricky word,
but I feel at current margins I would
rather the government not regulate tech
companies more. Yeah. So just
free them up and just keep,
so you believe in human ingenuity
more than anything else? I mean,
I think that that seems to be
the sure enforce rule of law.
I think the notion that, uh,
a platform is not liable,
say for everything that platform is used
for as we set out in law in the 1990s
was a fantastic idea.
It helped the Internet grow as quickly
as it did that equity capital could fund
a new ventures without being
obsessed with liability issues.
No one even knew at the time what
a smart thing that was to do. Uh,
so the genius of American government,
finally we did it kind of unintentionally.
Usually the good things
are done unintentionally, I
think. Yeah. But you know,
tech companies are vulnerable,
so people think Facebook has a lock and
young people don't necessarily want to
be on Facebook and a,
there's always competition.
So my space was once considered,
you know, untouchable.
They would rule social media forever and
American history is littered with the
corpses of corporate giants that seemed
untouchable and basically went under.
So if David can be Goliath
than Dave can be. Google. Yes.
All right. I've got my work cut out for
me. So I was on your website this morning,
marginal revolution.com which
I, first off, I love the name,
but I want to get the
tagline totally right here.
Small steps towards a much better world.
I thought that actually is pretty perfect
for a way of looking at the world that
we need to fix things,
perhaps in the west with some small
steps with some marginal things on the
outside.
But it seems like there's a movement
right now where people just want to rip up
everything as if,
as if nothing good has come out of the
200 plus years of freedom that we've had
here.
Was that a little bit of,
of why I'm slowly came up with
the tagline in the first place.
We need to start with where we are.
It's not about designing society from
scratch and the West tends the best
heritage, the best ideas. Um,
most effective religion that I think
our world has seen ever and we should
embrace and cherish those things and yes,
modify them when appropriate.
But the American constitution is one of
the great works of genius of mankind.
Yeah. So how do we then, so what, let,
let's say your Bloomberg or somebody
that's your guy, let's say, well,
there's no one who's mind,
but somebody,
somebody who roof roughly holds these
ideas is, is in office tomorrow.
Now I know you don't want to give
too much power to the executive,
obviously because you're into
the constitution and all that.
What does this look like?
Well,
I think the presidency of Trump shows
how little influence her president has.
Trump is in most ways a weak president.
Most of his policy agenda has not
happened. The courts have overruled him.
Our Congress won't act now.
The Democrats control the house.
So for me the key is her ideas
and broader society to change,
to try to be like a personal role model
for what you believe in and just to have
like your guy as president, you're a
woman as president, there's no such thing.
And if I were very happy
about intellection,
I just wouldn't feel that good about it.
I don't think it would matter that much.
It's more about the broad
sweep of history. Yeah.
So then is the key to
that that we have to stop.
I don't want people to become uninformed.
Obviously we need to be informed,
but that the key might be stopped.
This sort of endless obsession with
politics right now. Does that strike you?
It strikes me as dangerous that we've
turned politics into the national pastime.
It's a blood sport now and it's the way
you take people down and insult people.
So just the simple rule of how you would
treat people to their face or talk to
them,
to their face,
that politics should be done by all
those same rules and just being genteel.
I get that doesn't solve
our national problems,
but it stops some things from getting
worse and that's slipping away right now.
Yeah. What can we do?
So you think it's just,
just be nicer sort of at
least, well, different people
have different roles, right?
So maybe some people,
it is their role to be a kind of Paul
revere of sorts, but other people,
you know our role models and they should
conduct civil intelligent conversations
and that is catching.
I see that on the Internet.
So if you look at the best material
on the Internet, how smart it is,
including a lot of podcasts and youtube
shows compared to what people thought
was possible in the age
of Network television.
It's just astonishing
the intellectual level.
So I see right now even sort of within
my crew of of intellectual dark web
people,
whatever this thing is a,
that there is sort of a split happening
where there's a certain amount of people
that think we have to,
the institutions are changing say academia
and the media in New York Times and I
realized that they're going through these
massive changes and we're watching all
sorts of lay offs all over journalism
right now and there's a split where it's
like some people are just like,
let it burn. It deserves to burn.
It's time for it to burn and then
there's another version that's like,
well if we don't prop these things up,
you know who the hell knows what's
going to come on the other side?
What do you think about that?
I would go back to this idea of small
steps toward a much better world.
Like what can I do so I
can write on the Internet,
I can have my podcast series and I don't
have some big mega plan for what to do
with the New York Times
or the Washington Post.
I'm genuinely not sure those outlets
will have to evolve with competitive
pressures.
In any case,
I'm not like wishing for the
death of anything in particular.
And I think a the same set of people under
different circumstances can do a much
better or much worse job.
So like I root for institutions to
succeed and not for their death. Uh,
but again, I focus on the,
what's my comparative advantage,
what do I see is missing at the margin
and really hone in on that like a laser.
Yeah. I mean I liked that and I,
I think it's what I've tried to,
what you're doing to build here.
It's that I believe that usually the
things that I'm talking about here are the
right set of ideas.
And I don't mind having a difference
of opinion obviously with guests,
but trying to keep it relatively civil
and worse added on Twitter than I am in
here. Uh, and hopefully people
can start thinking for themselves.
So what if I ask you like, what should
we do with the Rotary Club in Houston?
I mean, you don't know, right? Not
specifically. Yeah. Tell me. Okay.
I don't know either. That's an
interesting point. What do you,
what do you make of that,
that everyone feels they have to
have an opinion on everything. Yeah.
The second something happens,
everyone knows everything
about the nuclear deal in Iran.
Everyone knows everything about what's
going on in North Korea and everyone
knows everything about, you know, the
tax margins and everything else. It's,
it's crazy. Actually, you know,
one of the themes in my book,
stubborn attachments is on most issues.
Yes. You should do what you think is best,
but the chance that you are exactly
right is actually pretty low. Yeah.
And Act and talk with that in mind.
So the first I want to get
the first sentence right. Uh,
the first sentence is growth
is good. Economic growth. Yeah.
Personal growth too.
But yeah. Well it sends,
you were talking about economic growth,
but in a way you are talking
about personal growth. Sure. Um,
when we talk about growth, so what
does, what does that mean beyond, okay,
you can say the,
the economy grew an extra percent
this year or that sort of thing. Like,
can you put that into some sort of more
layman's terms for the average person
that isn't particularly
interested in economics,
why growth is is the important
thing that that led off your book.
If you take a time period of like a
bout a hundred years and you have the
American economy grow one percentage
point lower over that time period,
we would today have the national wealth.
I've Mexico, not the United States.
So in any given year,
a percentage point of growth,
like maybe it's not that big a deal,
but over time as it compounds,
it's the difference
between riches and poverty.
The ability to have a job where
you're somewhat in control,
the ability to have more scope
for creative action in your life,
the near certainty your children will
not die when they're very young to take
care of your parents, better, to
have access to the best medicines,
to be able to travel the world.
All of these things and
people want different things,
but wealthier societies do a much
better job at giving us those things,
including sustaining democracy.
So economic growth in my view,
is centrally important.
Why do you think so many people believe
that that has not occurred here or
something like people
don't want to accept?
I see this at colleges all the time when
I go to talk to colleges and these kids
think that they're oppressed and that
something horrible is happening in the
United States right now and the only way
that I've been able to break through to
them. I always ask the same question and
I've had nobody argued with me. I say,
just anyone in this room have it
worse than their grandparents.
And it has yet to happen where
someone raises their hand. Yes and no.
I'm sure it has happened where somebody
grandparents were super wealthy and lost
it,
but that would also be an argument sort
of against leftist economics because it
would show that you can
lose a lot of wealth,
which they would want because they
don't want well to be accumulated.
But why do you think this idea that
somehow things haven't gotten consistently
so much better, which there is
so much empirical evidence of,
why do you think that hasn't taken
root say with younger people?
Some of it is Myopia.
Some of it of course,
is that younger people have not
been on this earth for very long.
Some of it is we have taught
too much egalitarianisms.
Some of it is I think our society perhaps.
Can you,
can you explain what you mean by that?
Again,
Lateri aneurysm is the notion that if
one person has something and the other
doesn't,
that may be that's automatically wrong.
Even if the other person's pretty well
off or well off by world historical
standards and I think that's
very often a harmful videology.
I would do more to teach like when we in
plus economic growth types of thinking
that America is a more secular society.
I think it just creates a vacuum.
I'm not myself religious,
but I think religion plays an important
role in giving us a framework and when
that framework has taken away a lot
of ideas enter the vacuum that can be
harmful. Do you see that happening
right now? I do. Quickly. Yeah.
I definitely see that.
And I say that is someone that's not
particularly really and especially on the
left,
which is less religious than the right.
So is that what's happening that they've
sort of traded religious thought or you
know an unmoved mover or some sort
of beginning of this whole thing.
They've traded it in for a series
of ideas that are just about,
I mean it sounds Cliche,
but how they feel now,
not enough about a higher purpose of some
kind and one can have a purely secular
vision of that higher purpose,
which is how I see myself.
But religion is a very easy persuasive
way for many people to get there and we
are secularizing finally in this country.
That's one of my greatest concerns.
Is that funny for you as a, as
a secular person? Absolutely.
Cause I've never been religious.
My parents were not religious.
But when I look at the actual data and
also religious people tend to have more
children, I believe in, you know,
a populous America that is not like a
tiny country compared to India and China.
And it's one reason why I would like to
make immigration work better and taking
more immigrants. I think we should
be a strong country of 500 million,
600 million if China and India
are going to be over a billion.
So I had a couple of weeks ago I had uh,
Heather McDonald in here who you're
probably familiar with. Sure. She,
she talks about being a secular
conservative. Now I know you're,
you're a small l libertarian, right?
If we're going with labels, um,
but do you think there is room on the
right for a secular movement to grow?
Because I think that
would be pretty powerful.
And I see some seeds of it
actually happening right now.
I don't libertarians generally or don't
care what your belief tend to be secular.
Yeah. I think there will have to
be right. And the secular society.
So, uh, I think there's right now more
intellectual ferment on the right.
It strikes me,
especially on Twitter,
but not only how much left wingers
attack each other, you know,
people who support different candidates.
This person's terrible, this one is evil.
Joe Biden did this. I think that's much
worse on the left now than on the right.
And uh, it's partly because they
have fewer ideas to talk about.
And I find a,
to bring up an unusual idea,
you will get further on the
right currently than on the left.
And that's actually a positive sign.
So what do you make of that positive sign?
Because if you, I mean I think,
you know, I know, you know,
you know a bit about my
political evolution. I mean,
if you would've asked me five years ago
that most of the people that I agree
with would be libertarians and
conservatives, or at the very least,
even though I'm still pro choice and I
know some of them aren't thrilled with,
with gay marriage and I'm against the
death penalty and a whole bunch of other
things that these people
would be extremely opening
open to always sitting down
with me. And on the other side
there's, there's almost nothing left.
It's a reason to be optimistic.
If you look, say at the 1960s,
seventies people on the right,
I think we're more open or maybe
even more talented than on the left.
And they were at that time losing.
But you then have the eighties
and nineties where some
of the classical liberal
ideas become much more powerful.
Communism falls. And then I think, uh,
some point in the 90s,
there's actually a lot more talent and
openness on the left and the right style
defies, wow, we beat communism.
What do we do now? Well,
that's when they went after
video games, right? I mean, yes.
And that was a big mistake.
The Republican is attacking video
games and Mccain and it's like what?
And they embrace too many politicians who
are intolerant or telling lies or just
being irresponsible. And a lot of
the right is still in that Rut.
But I think if you look at intellectual
discourse, it's better on the right.
That may well again, be a
historical leading indicator
of change. Maybe not soon,
but 20 years from now, I think there'll
be a payoff. Yeah. God, I, I, well,
I think it's happening. I actually
do think it's happening right now,
but I didn't ugly, twisted, painful ways.
Right. It's never easy or pleasant. Yeah.
Do you sense,
we're sort of in the death throes of
something right now that between the
institutions kind of wavering and with
all the free speech stuff on campus and
just so much tension.
You've mentioned social media a couple
of times that there's so many things
happening at once.
The way this is all speeding up
faster and faster and wherever you are
organizing discourse around the Internet,
which is a good thing and
will be a very good thing,
but it's extremely
painful for many people.
I think that's one of
the big changes going on.
I actually think America is depolarizing.
I'm not saying that's a pleasant process,
but if you go to someone in Congress
like what do you think about free trade?
And you hear their opinion right now
you can't necessarily tell if they're a
republican or a democrat or someone
who wants to increase, you know,
social security,
government spending.
They could be a republican or a Democrat
and that wasn't the case. And you know,
2011 or 2013 so what people are calling
polarization is the stakes are higher.
What is possible through politics
is becoming greater and grander.
So there's more hatred,
more mutual recrimination,
but people are just all over the map
in terms of what they believe. Yeah.
Well I do think it's a,
it's a rich ground for ideas right now,
but it's higher risk to, yeah. Yeah. So
it could, it could spin out of control.
Correct. I guess podcast host have a
lot of responsibility right now. Well,
we all do.
And some sense of personal mission in
the old standard American Protestant
sense,
even if you're totally secular,
to take that notion of a personal mission
upon yourself and go and do it to me
is just critically important,
isn't it? Like to me that's it.
It's your life. Grab it, go with it.
Demand as much freedom as you can possibly
build for out of this world and take
it. And yet that message
right now for young people,
unfortunately it's not catching it on the
way shit and it or maybe it is to your
point. Yeah. And also understand we
have some origins as a puritan nation.
I'm not saying be a puritan,
not at all,
but that has given America a cultural
strength and ability to support people who
do this in terms of openness and
resources and the culture surrounding you,
how much encouragement and you will
find how big an audience you can build.
So early things like
blogging and podcasting,
just how American those are we
take for granted. But it's a deep,
fundamentally important truth that
Americans are sometimes Canadians,
Jordan Peterson has been
the leaders in this area.
I don't think we appreciate enough.
Yeah.
Is anyone else doing
it better than America?
Is anyone else doing basics of,
of freedom and liberty and the type of
economics that you're talking about?
Is anyone doing it better?
Better is a tricky word.
I think Australia and Canada as
countries are in pretty good shape.
Uh, not with respect to political
liberty, but in many areas.
I'm a fan of Singapore.
They have done in economic policy very,
very well and they have become
overall freer than they used to be.
Uh,
you know,
western Europe in some ways
has a wonderful lifestyle,
but for me it's somewhat
deadening and not that innovative,
but for cultivating like quality of
consumption and how to enjoy leisure. Uh,
not really my thing in many ways,
but there are definitely ahead of us and
we should like value that and learned
something from it.
What are,
what are some of the economic ideas
or principles that we're not paying
attention to you that we
should, if you're, you know,
like there's people talking about ubi now,
there's people talking about all
this stuff with automation. I mean,
what should we be,
we're looking at the future now.
What are things that we should
be focusing on learning about?
What I'm seeing is people
forgetting a lot of basics.
So ubi I find attempting idea,
but I don't favor it. I want,
can you steal magnet for those
that don't know what ubi,
universal basic income, the notion,
there's different versions of the scheme,
but government sends everyone money to
support them as a kind of social welfare.
So just like a baseline everyone's
got and yes, go from there. Yeah.
Now I believe in some kind of baseline.
So if you're disabled,
I believe you should receive a significant
baseline if you need assistance.
I think for the most part we should pay
people to work, not pay them not to work.
So we have the earned income tax credit.
If you work and your poor,
the government pays you extra money.
I think that has worked quite well and
attract a better quality of immigrant
when you pay people to work rather
than paying them not to work.
Too Much of western Europe
pays people not to work.
So the forums of aid we give,
they are cultural symbols and they are
potent and the idea that it is automatic,
any eternal that you just get cash.
It's telling people the main thing of
importance in life is cash and you will
get it no matter what.
It's the wrong message to send and he's
it stealing the exact idea that you've
been talking about for the last half hour,
which is sort of you've
got to innovate in life.
It's stealing that idea
from the individual, right?
We're just going to give you something.
If you don't do anything,
you'll be able to subsist Dane at
the bottom of the tower forever.
Even though obviously there are always
going to want more and more for that.
Right.
That's not just going to get ubi day
one and then it's going to be like that
three years later.
Correct.
But that said we should find ways of
helping the needy. I'm all for that.
What's the right way to do it?
I don't think it's ubi. Yeah.
What else that we should be thinking
about that's popping up right now?
Like when you're,
when you're in economics conferences
and things and people are talking about
what's going on in the future,
which we be thinking about.
I'm not sure how to fix climate change.
I think it's a very important issue.
I very much favor nuclear power.
I hope nuclear fuel it. Let's,
let's do one at a time. So climate
change, do you think this could be,
I see a movement now it's coming
from the right actually. Yes.
Where there are people saying there are
ways to tackle this that could be done
through private enterprise and
not purely through the government.
And I know you said you want
some regulation that that
is a place where you see
the government doing something
related to the environment, right?
But do you see as some sort of partnership
there perhaps you also need to free
up energy competition,
so,
so you try to build wind turbines
in different parts of America.
Homeowners say not near my house.
Right.
There's a kind of Nimby mentality
that should be much easier.
I know it doesn't always look pretty.
You drive from La to palm springs,
you see all the wind turbines, but
it is cheap, clean, green energy.
And if you really think climate change
is a problem, you should jump on board.
Nuclear Energy, in my
opinion, can be safe. France,
Sweden have done it just fine.
I'm optimistic about the
prospects for nuclear fusion,
which can be safer yet
than nuclear fishing.
And this is a place where you think the
government should be leading? Correct.
Or leading is a tricky word
for nuclear power to operate.
I do think nuclear plant operators need
a special kind of liability insurance,
which we've provided under
the price Anderson Act,
and that has a role for government.
And I'm fine by that.
I think it's much better than dealing
with all of the secondary costs of higher
air pollution.
So I don't think it can be laissez faire,
but also you have to free up the market
so entrepreneurs can do this. Right.
Do you like, like I've sat
down here with a couple, uh,
and cat people that really just wanted,
you know,
disassemble the governmental altogether
and enter their mad max phase.
I really like the idea intellectually,
like I liked seeing how far you can take
an intellectual argument and how much
government could disappear.
Do you like entertaining those ideas just
purely for just purely for your mind?
If not for practicality,
it's very important to entertain them
or learn something from them. But again,
we have to start from where we're at.
There's a lot of things government does
that probably they're impossible to undo
even if they're unwise American.
And that's why I was asking you before
that we have this machine that is so big
that it's not like you should just come
in and something like social security.
You may not have designed it
from scratch the way we have it,
but I'm not sure there's a way to back
out and undo it all because you're caught
in a cycle where people have been
promised payments. Right? Yeah.
So maybe you know, just live with that one
and try to fix some other things. Yeah.
I'm sort of all over the place here,
but what do you think about crypto
related to all this in a changing economy?
I think there's a 20% chance crypto
will pay off big time, but not now.
Maybe in 2030 years from now.
Just the way quantum mechanics at the
time seemed weird and much later it became
a central for computers,
but right now it seems to me the
crypto revolution is failing.
What was promised has
not really come to us.
I'm not upset that the
price of Bitcoin is low.
I see a lot of potential for the notion
of self executing market contracts.
In a crypto system.
I just don't see that right now.
Consumers have problems where they're
clamoring for this as the solution.
So I could see us getting there.
Right? So in a bizarre way,
if the problems of today exacerbate,
then maybe that funnels this all to crypto
answers and also crypto may need more
infrastructure.
So you look at a possible use of Crypto,
well verifying individual identities,
possibly crypto is much
better at that than you.
You're with someone on
the phone and they say,
what are the last four digits of your
social? Right? That's crazy system.
But for Crypto, right? We've just,
we've just accepted that we're
giving it to all sorts of strangers,
most likely Asia, right? Every time
we pick up the phone and go crazy.
But it doesn't mean you can fix
it quickly just by having crypto.
Now there's a whole system built that way
with payments companies and government
bureaus and your personal data is
encoded with your social security number,
your tax returns.
Even if crypto is the answer there,
it will be such an awkward
roundabout route, just like
for cars to be a big deal.
Well, you needed roads, you needed
service stations, you needed spare parts.
And it took about 40 years for us to
put together like the network of cars to
revolutionize the world.
So I think a lot of people
are over promising crypto
in the short run and there
is a very real chance it just
dies out and doesn't work.
But I don't think it's all some fraud or
bubble. Uh, there's real potential there.
We don't yet know if it can work. The rest
of the infrastructure is not in place.
Probably in the short run it will fail.
But I still hold that hope.
I have to say there's a
certain pleasantness to
everything you're talking about
because you're sort of just telling people
to take a breath for a second. Right?
I mean that, that sort of economically,
but personally, everything,
I was just kind of slow down a
little bit for all of our problems.
The world is a hall has never been
in better shape than it is today.
2019 never ever. So just keep
that in mind. And you know,
gratitude is good for
your personal development.
Like people who keep gratitude
journals, uh, it seems they're happier,
they're more productive.
Uh,
my gratitude journal I guess is my blog
in a funny way or podcasts, but, uh,
try to have some version of a gratitude
journal in your life. Do you think as a,
as an interviewer, uh, that,
that you actually do learn every week?
I think one of the things I'm most,
I have most gratitude for is that
I genuinely learn every week.
And I forget that the average person
doesn't get to learn every week.
Or maybe it doesn't take time to learn
everything you could learn every week.
But I mean, I sit across incredible
people all the time and it's like, wow,
I learned something.
Or at least I sat with someone who
knows something that I don't know.
It's incredible. I mean, you
get that same opportunity.
We've had many of the same guess,
not over the years.
Prepping for interviews is right
now the main way I learned.
But most people now also have this
chance to learn every week. Podcasts,
other forms of the Internet.
Uh,
cable TV is much better than
television used to be. Netflix,
so there's a lot more access for learning.
How do you decide how much prep you're
supposed to do? Because I find sometimes,
occasionally I want to know a little bit
less because I find that it'll allow me
to explore during the interview more.
Sometimes I need to know a lot of
very specific factual information or
chronological information.
When I did your show,
I was truly impressed how deep you had
dug into my past and you asked me things
that nobody had ever asked me
before I go crazy over prepping.
So for Agnes calories, I read Plato's
symposium five times in a row.
That's a lot of prep.
Emily Wilson,
she just trained retranslated Homer's
Odyssey olive read that three times and
she did Seneca's plays and she wrote a
biography of Seneca and wrote a book on
over living and a book
about the death of Socrates.
And I'll read all of those and
reread some of the underlying texts.
And her sister, uh, wrote a
book on the history of the fork,
which I've already read and
has some other books on food.
I'm going to read some of the books that
her sister book on the history of the
fort.
And it's a wonderful book.
It's called consider the fork forks a
report in there that I thought you meant.
Maybe that's an economic term.
The flow, not crypto for,
I mean the fork dinner table for literal
fork. Yeah. So people's families,
if people, uh, have, you know, a sibling
or a spouse who have done things,
I figure we'll,
of course the person has thought about
this and they probably have interesting
ideas about it that are not
out there anywhere. Yeah.
So you'd rather talk about ideas more
than, than any. Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah.
Like the nitty gritty of the day to day,
that's when I see all these people
fighting over this policy, that policy.
It bores me to no end at this point.
It doesn't seem,
it seems meaningless or valueless.
It's overreacting to the
most recent signal in those
ideas, which are, you know,
eternal, uh, will be with us and actually
be more influential. Yeah. So that's a,
that's an interesting segue actually
to college campuses because you're,
you're teaching actually her,
first of all,
it has economics at least from your
position been infected by a lot of what
we're seeing in the wider sense on
college campuses related to free speech,
shouting down speakers. Cause even if
I find this all the time, if, you know,
people will come up to me after
events and they'll say, you know,
I want to tell my boss or something that,
or my spouse that I'm for low taxes.
But if I say that they're going to say
I'm racist. I mean really crazy stuff. Um,
so as someone that takes the small
l libertarian approach on this,
do you find that some of these
ideas are infecting not so much.
Economics is a much healthier field.
It has a tradition as being maybe more,
conservative isn't the right word,
but more market oriented.
A lot of people disagree with me,
so I'm an economist so I think
register is about 80% democratic,
but they tend to be more
conservative Democrats.
And I don't find that much just
outright bias. When I say things,
I feel mostly accepted and
indeed even welcome. Yeah, no,
I know George Mason obviously
is a certain specific thing,
but in general when I
visit other campuses,
I just spoke at University of
Michigan to the philosophy department,
but I spoke to them and bad economics.
I'm going to U Chicago.
I don't expect any trouble at all.
I don't think I'll say
anything incendiary either.
Just like my version of common sense.
Here's why you should have a
more positive view of the world.
Here's what we can do.
Here are the small steps toward a much
better world that we should embrace.
I think it's going to go fine.
Sounds pretty hate speech.
He to me. Wow. We'll see.
I suppose.
What would you say is the best to deal
then with what's going on on campuses?
Even if you're not getting it and maybe
it's not happening directly in economics
departments right now.
I mean we're seeing it leak into into
biology departments when we're talking
about gender and all
sorts of other things.
What do you think the best
way to push against this?
The sort of corroding of academic freedom.
And if I look up my own school,
George Mason,
we have a very good record in this regard.
We have the highest tree
speed trading from fire,
a group you know about and our school I
think has about more immigrant students
or children of immigrants than any
other major university in America.
And their attitude is so different.
They want to get an education to learn
something and to make a good living.
And they're very practically oriented.
A lot of them are very curious.
And to them this is political correctness
is often a form of nonsense and it
seems to me a disease of kind
of rich white kids' schools.
So I think we need to be more cosmopolitan
and just less provincial America has
a long history of being provincial
and this is the new form of American
provincial ism.
All right,
so let's back up a little bit cause
you just mentioned immigration but we
started there before.
Yeah.
So lay out what a sensible
immigration plan actually looks like.
I think that if you have a plausible
graduate degree from a real institution,
including from most other nations, you
should be able to get a green card here.
I think we should have completely
free immigration from Canada.
I would say we should have open borders
with any country that has a more
generous welfare state than we do because
then those people will not be coming
for welfare.
They'll be coming here to work and I
get you need to transition to that over
time. And then I would still let
in people from poorer countries,
you need some of what is
called unskilled labor.
It's not actually unskilled in fact,
but the more skilled people you have,
they need to work with people who
can ease the burden of their time.
So you have working women and they
want nannies or a, that's fine.
So I think we could increase both
skilled and unskilled immigration in this
country.
We've done a pretty good job
of assimilating immigrants
better than anyone in
the history of the world, I would argue.
Absolutely. So anyone that's even close,
I mean I guess,
I guess Canada perhaps or they do
a good job accepting immigrants,
but they assimilate the much less. So they
have a tradition like friend, you know,
Quebec is separate and maybe
always will be separate.
So they just let it be separate.
So if you're a Sikh Chinese,
he moved to Canada and maybe you'll
stay separated. It works well.
It's very peaceful. Uh, but
they assimilate much less.
I actually prefer a simulation, but
that's okay. So what do we do with the,
what do they always say?
It's 12 million people that are
here illegally right now. How do we,
how do we fix this?
Then I would cut a deal.
I think they should be
able to stay and uh,
if the restriction is, you
know, want more wall for that,
it's actually a deal I would do. I'm
opposed to the wall. But you know,
the wall will not stop people.
Most people who come come
by overstaying their visas.
The net flow from Mexico has actually
been negative by a small amount for a few
years.
I think Central America is a problem.
The notion that you can be safe from
Honduras and simply by virtue of the fact
that you made it to the border claim
refugee status because you know there's a
drug gang in Europe.
Weblo I think that's a bad system.
I do favor some version of refugee status.
My wife was a refugee from Soviet Union,
so I appreciate this,
but just because you know,
things are bad in my country,
I'm a refugee because I'm close to
the U S and I made it to the border.
I think it's a very bad system.
It's very bad incentives and it's
overwhelming our court system.
So some of what Trump says
about that is true. Again,
my goal is to find a way of taking more
of those people in an orderly manner,
but to encourage just rushing for the
border. I do think we need to change that.
Yeah, well that's why it really does seem
we've imaginating Hillary now, right?
You've got Trump wanting,
okay,
he wants a wall and I don't think a wall
is actually pretty much agree with it.
He said, I don't think a wall is
inherently racist. They may not.
Actually work and maybe there's all
sorts of other ways to deal with it. Uh,
but if the option that,
if the other option that people see is
that you've got people screaming for open
borders and I don't blame all the
people that weren't the bowl, the wall,
and we have a wall right now.
And if that's the way the argument's
going to be framed, right? Yeah.
So to enforce immigration more properly,
but letting many more people
would be my preferred solution.
So when you say cut a
deal on the people here,
so if let's say you're
throwing the Republicans,
the idea that you're going to get some
more of a wall or something, what's the,
what's the deal on the other side of that?
What these people,
the dreamers get to stay and we adjust
the quotas upward and say tech companies
can hire more skilled people on work
visas. And uh, we also Redo Nafta.
So Canadians have the
right to simply come here.
You might want to limit their ability
to claim welfare. I'm fine with that.
And over time,
think about with what other countries
can we have free movement the European
Union has does this,
has done this within the European Union.
I get that there's a political backlash.
I'm not sure we should have open
borders with Bulgaria and Romania.
I understand that probably doesn't work.
We've also got, you know, an ocean. Sure.
But to the idea that 15 years from now
we could have opened borders with France
and Germany. To me, we should be working
toward that. I understand it's not easy.
So I think when people hear
the phrase open borders,
they think that means that
you can automatically come
here and become a citizen.
But that's not, that's not what you'd be
calling for. Right. Well, work rights,
but we have a rapid path to citizenship,
which I favor.
It's one of the things that makes us
good at assimilation and you know,
both political parties at different
points in the past, they always go crazy.
Like, oh, all these
people are going to come.
They're gonna vote for the other party.
I don't think we really know 20 years
from now what immigrants are going to vote
for or why. So you know,
Asian Americans will,
they remain as heavily
democratic as they are right now.
I don't know that that one's gotta be
changing. Just the pure economics of it.
Same with Latino's.
I just say it's an open question.
So the partisan fear that like they
who come will be on the other side.
I think we just need to
relax a bit on that. Yeah.
Are there any topics that you shy away
from talking about because you have to
keep on asking, keep on asking
you because I've got a whole lot,
I haven't even looked at this, but I've
got a whole lot here about economics.
But it seems very obvious to me that
through an economic lens of looking at
things the way you do that you
really could talk about anything.
But also I interviewed
people a lot as you do.
And I'm used to talking about many topics,
so,
so what else is interesting to you right
now that that maybe isn't purely within
an economic lens or even a Political Lens?
What sort of peaking your interest
in these days besides Fords?
The question of how to find
more talent in the world.
So I think there's a relative surfy of
capital relative to talented labors.
My view of the world as if you have an
incredibly talented person who is good at
execution, that person
can get so much done. Uh,
the world as a whole is under
explored from this point of view.
So you go to Nigeria, how many
talented people are there? Well,
there are bad as talented
as United States,
they just don't have the opportunities.
Look at how much talent has come from
India in the last 20 years. Right? China,
phenomenal amount.
And so 40 50 years,
people like that didn't really
have a chance. Yeah. So how is it,
say you were to go to Nigeria and try
to mobilize and Nigeria and talent,
what should you look for?
What should you do?
What kind of cultural training is needed?
What ought to change in Nigeria?
How can we recruit that talent?
That's maybe the biggest
question in the world today.
And we're not good at it and we
don't really know what we're doing.
So I think what's keeping the twinkle
in your eye actually is the fact that
technology has led us to be able to ex
explore all of these ideas, right? Yeah,
absolutely. Yeah. And talk to people about
them. Yeah, that's pretty cool. It is.
Yeah.
I guess we are doing something fun and
these other countries there except maybe
in North Korea, but they're
connected to the Internet. Yeah.
So you go to a random place in Africa or,
I was just in rural real Ecuador.
A guy was driving me around and I
asked him, do you listen to Youtube?
Is that cash? Was speaking fellow.
I asked him in Spanish. He's like,
of course. Uh, I went to, uh,
my Ethiopian travel guide and Lali Bella.
I asked him, do you listen to Youtube?
He's like, of course. I say,
what do you listened to? He said,
I'm a big fan of Armenian church history
and he can speak articulately about
movements in the Armenian
Christian Church in Medieval Times.
Cause that's what he does on Youtube.
A guy in rural Ethiopia.
That's phenomenal. People don't get how
much of that is there? What a difference.
It's gonna make people a lot of outside.
Oh, youtube. That's like cat videos.
Well, yes, there's those two.
Some are pretty good actually,
but it's also a medieval Armenian church
history in, in rural Ethiopia. Yeah.
I like how can you not be excited by that
and just the amount of people that are
thirsty for a little of this
betrayed a little bit. Yeah,
pretty great.
And they're basically all smarter than
the mainstream used to think and the
innovators who just talk to them and
try to be like as smart as they can be,
they're attracting those audiences.
My goodness. That's exciting. Yeah.
I don't know how to end an interview
better than that with a little excitement.
That's pretty good. It is.
You feel good about it. I do.
How'd I do as an interviewer?
Wonderful. You did find as a guest,
thank you very much for more on Tyler.
Check out his website,
marginal revolution.com.