All right.
What's going on everybody?
It is our monthly patrion
exclusive live stream.
We're changing it up this month.
Uh,
so what we've always been doing here
with Patrion is I do this video,
this live stream where I take questions
from patrons and we only share the video
with Patrion people. But I realized, uh,
last month that when we were
doing this that it's like,
I think more of you want more people
to be able to hear the questions you're
asking. And here my answers. So I
asked everybody basically, I was like,
look, how about we let only patrion
members submit the questions,
but we'll post this video live to our
youtube feed as we're doing right now and
let everybody hear the answers.
That way it gets more people
hearing your questions,
more people here in my answers.
And hopefully for some of you guys
that haven't joined us, uh, on Patrion,
hopefully you will join us. So if you want
to get a question and to me first off,
uh, it's patrion.com/rubin
report and I think it's the,
a level one tier gets ya,
gets you right in on, on this.
And I've got a trusty iPad here.
My guys are sending me questions on the
fly and we're going to do about an hour
of Q and a totally uncensored.
Whatever you want to ask me.
I'm reading them right here.
I haven't even looked at them yet.
I've been doing patrion hangouts
all day long. You know, we,
for the higher tier members, we do small
group chats. We used to do one on ones.
Now we're doing them in groups.
So I've been going all day long.
I am wearing a hat, which people don't get
to see me in a hat that often. Uh, but,
uh,
I haven't even showered today because
it's been a crazy freaking day of Patriot
hangouts and just catching up on
life. As you guys know. I've been, uh,
last three weeks on the road with Jordan
Peterson and we were in Denmark and
Sweden and Norway and
UK and Ireland. And, uh,
definitely forgetting some other places,
but we've been all over the place.
It looks like we just signed
on for probably another 30
shows in Europe in March
and April. Uh, we got a whole bunch
of stops in Australia in February.
They're just great energy
behind what we're doing. I'm,
I'm so enthused and site and, uh, I just,
I just feel great at the moment and a,
and I'm looking forward to taking
some questions. Oh, just real quick.
Let me pimp out one, one event I've been
doing. So I got back from Helsinki. Oh,
Finland. I forgot about Finland.
Uh, I got back from Helsinki, uh,
two days ago and then I did stand
up immediately that night in Braya.
Uh, and then I did stand up last
night in Oxnard and both nights I a,
I brought two members of the intellectual
dark web. I always bring one.
So I do about an hour of stand up and
then I bring the guests from the IDW on.
Uh,
I bought,
brought both Weinstein brothers on stage
and we're just having a great time and,
and it's, it's totally different. So I
hope if you guys happen to be in a city,
Warren, I'm doing stand up soon and
I hope you'll come check it out.
I'll be in San Jose on November 28th at
the San Jose Improv and there will be an
IDW member, uh, with me and you know,
I do stand up but it's a lot of crowd
work and we do live Q and a and it's
really interactive and fun and I get
the crowd going at each other and it's a
politically diverse
group of people and it's,
and it's pretty cool and
I'm psyched about that.
And if you want to just check out some
more dates and tours and other things
that I'm doing a,
you can go to Dave rubin.com/events
and before I start,
I assume everybody
wants to say hi to Emma.
She's been hanging out all
day long and here she is,
14 years old.
A lot of you know the story about her.
She's a rescue from Hurricane
Katrina in New Orleans.
So she's lived in New Orleans then.
She lived in New York for about 10 years
and now we've been living in La for a
couple of years. She's been to the Grand
Canyon. She's been to the White House.
The girl has lived through a lot.
Okay.
Let's jump into questions cause
that's what it's all about.
So we will go right there. Uh, when
are you coming back to San Francisco?
So I've done a couple
events in San Francisco.
Well I will be in San Jose on November
28 that's pretty close to San Francisco.
So hopefully you can come check it out.
I think we're going to do some more
stuff in San Francisco and I just need to
spend a couple of days there cause there's
a lot going on on tech side of things
as you guys can imagine these days
with all the algorithm craziness and,
and youtube stuff and
Twitter shadow banning.
So I need to spend some time
in San Francisco. Um, so maybe,
maybe on the 29th I'll do like some sort
of public event there if I can figure
out a way to do it. But 20th, I'm in San
Jose, so do come and check it out. Um,
Dave, uh, after listening to the Idw,
I can no longer listen to conservative
talk radio. It seems shallow. Uh,
just like the mainstream media.
What have you done to me?
I've done something good my friend.
This is what it's all about. Look,
what is the IDW trying to do?
Uh, as Eric Weinstein said,
who I think is sort of the,
he was the sort of architect of this in
some ways and I've been sort of the main
facilitator and we've got all sorts
of people that are part of it.
It's like what do,
what do we agree on most of them?
What we agree on mostly is that
we're allowed to think differently,
but we agree on what a conversation is,
what a respectful conversation amongst
people who have different thoughts are,
which is why I can sit in my studio
with my own home across from Ben Shapiro
when he'll tell me that he wouldn't
attend my wedding anniversary. And we can,
we can agree to disagree on things.
So we can agree that we still want to
live in the same societies, each other.
I think what we've done
with the IDW is we,
we've shattered some of the notions that
media and the political establishment
has, has thrust on all of us
about how we should behave,
where everyone who
disagrees with us is evil.
And everyone who disagrees with this is
a bigot or a Lib tart or a racist or a
homophobe. All of this stuff, it's
not real. It's tearing us apart.
It's making people crazy. And I can
tell you guys, I just meant the,
the last three weeks
bouncing all over Europe,
I spent the two months before that
bouncing all over the United States. Uh,
we've done 70 plus shows
together. I think Jordan and I, a,
it'll be well over a hundred by the
time we're done. And people are good.
They're out there,
they want to solve problems.
And one of the coolest things is so
you right now, person watching this,
most likely you're watching
this alone, right? You're,
you're watching it either on your phone
or you're sitting at your laptop or your
desktop. Um, you're not
listening to this, right?
Cause we're only live streaming
this on youtube. We will,
I think we're going to put this up
on the podcast feed probably. Um,
but this is a sort of solo operation.
Like maybe you're watching it
on your smart TV, maybe your,
your husband or your wife or your
boyfriend or girlfriend is there,
but it's a pretty solo experience
ingesting all of this content. You know,
you can walk around listening to
these podcasts and it's a solo thing.
And what I'm,
what I'm really loving right now about
the Peterson events and now doing standup
again,
is that people are coming into these rooms
and they're looking around and you're
going, holy cow. You know,
for the standard shows,
there's hundreds of other people laughing
about the same shit that I'm laughing
about at the Petersen shows.
There's thousands of other people that
are as interested in ideas and getting
your life right before you fix the world,
fix yourself.
And they're coming together and they're
realizing, holy cow, I'm not alone.
And yes,
they disagree.
All the people that come there
disagree on all sorts of things.
And I have people that come up to
me after the shows. And you know,
a lot of people of course say Dave,
I'm sort of on the same political
journey is you? I used to be a big lefty,
but I'm a liberal and that has
nothing to do with the left anymore.
And people come up to me and say,
I'm a libertarian and I've been waiting
for some good liberals to join forces
with. Some people say I'm a conservative
and I disagree with you on some things,
uh, but, but you know, I support what
you're doing and all that. Um, so look,
if you can't listen to talk radio
anymore because of what we've done here,
I think that's pretty good.
You know,
I'm not putting down anybody and the
people can do what they want and listen to
who they want to listen to.
But I think we've offered up something
a little more and I'm really proud of
that and I think we're just
at the beginning again. So
it's, it's pretty exciting.
Um, okay. Let's see. Um, Dave,
have you followed the leftist attacks on
Peter but goes you unrelated to his pro
bound grievance studies? I have,
uh, first off, I love Pete.
Pete's been on the show twice
and if you haven't seen, uh,
particularly the second one.
So the first interview that I did with
Peter was the first time we met and we
did mostly a talk an hour
long talk about atheism.
And Pete wrote a book called a
manual for creating atheists.
We did that about three years ago.
I think it was three years
ago this month actually,
it might've been this week and it
was right before thanksgiving. Um,
and Pete was on again about
a year ago in this studio.
And we did, we talked about all
sorts of stuff. But what was great,
I think the first 20 or 30 minutes was
about the nature of friendship. Actually,
his father had just passed
away. And, uh, you know,
our friendship sort of blossomed because
I tried to be there for him during that
time. Um, he's, he's a really
good guy. Look, these guys wrote,
Pete and James Lindsey and Helen
pluck, rose wrote these, uh,
these fake academic papers
that got accepted by peer
reviewed journals and they
just freaking flipped
all of these nonsensical,
um,
all of these nonsensical ways that these
departments figure out what's real and
what's not real right on their head. I
mean, it's actually incredible. So anyway,
Pete is a philosophy professor at Portland
State University and the school paper
issued this statement all anonymously
signed by professors and Grad students,
uh, about how awful he is.
And it's like, man, you know,
he's put his butt and his career and his
life on the line to fight for what he
believes in. And you guys won't even
put your names to this paper, uh,
to this statement against him.
And it's like you're all cowards.
If you were on the side of truth,
you would stand up and be who you are,
but you won't. And this guy is
doing good work because what he,
what Pete I think
basically believes is that,
that the gender studies and these
types of disciplines that aren't pure
reviewed, that don't, uh,
that don't come from a place of
empirical evidence like say the stems,
uh, do, um,
Pete would say they are
infecting every part of academia.
And it's not just Pete that says that
it's plenty of other people at Jordan.
Peterson says it,
uh,
plenty of other people in academia or
realize what is happening. And, uh,
so I love Pete. I backbeat
and I hope that, uh,
what he's done will have wider effects
and will ripple for a long time coming.
And I do think they will. Um, what
do you think is the future of comedy?
Can it get back to being funny and not
just political watch the Adam Sandler
Netflix than recently,
even though I was not a fan and I enjoyed
it partly because the songs were funny
and weird and because there
was no political content,
so I haven't seen that thing yet.
You know, when I was younger,
especially in college, I loved
Sandler is comedy was off the wall.
That wasn't political.
It was completely ridiculous.
Then he had like five or six movies in
a row. There were absolutely horrendous.
And then those Netflix movies
have been pretty awful.
The Sandy Wexler on was sort of okay,
but some of the others are just terrible.
That one with David spade where
he's a secret agent or science,
it's not even a movie. They need another
word for it. It's so bad. That being said,
I haven't seen this yet,
but,
but if he got back to his
off the wall roots where he,
we know what's happening and this
is what your questions about.
It's like what's happening right now
is that these comedians have become the
same type of hectoring preaching blowhards
that they're supposed to be making
fun of.
So imagine if George Carlin,
who I think is the greatest stand up and
the most prolific standup comic of all
time,
if he was alive today.
Now first off he be getting booed off
college campuses because he'd be an old
white guy defending the patriarchy.
I mean, it's so stupid, right?
This is a guy who fought the his entire
life. Um, but what would he be doing?
He would be using comedy to
say what he wants to say,
but if you go online now and you
see what a lot of really famous,
far more famous than me comics are doing,
they're just yelling and
preaching and they're all,
they're all progressive activists and
Democratic Party members and all that
stuff and they're not funny anymore.
I mean the amount of people
who I used to like comedically,
who now like make me
kind of nauseous as sick,
but that's actually why
I'm doing standup again.
And we did great show in Oxnard last
night. We did a great show and Brian,
as I said,
I'm doing something that's like more of
like a crazy road show slash town whole
thrash interview slash Phil Donahue
Slash Jerry Springer show than anything
else.
And I'm treating my audience with respect.
We're doing some
politically incorrect stuff.
I hope people aren't a recording
all of this stuff because what,
what happens in accountability club
is kind of sacred and a lot of comics,
by the way, now the big, the big
time comics like Rogan in Chappelle,
who both are spectacular comedians.
They don't even let people bring their
phones. You have to give up your phone.
You put it in a bag before you even
go in. Um, because that, you know,
the comedy club is the place where
you're supposed to experiment.
And imagine if you were a scientist and
you're experimenting and things were
blowing up in your face, you wouldn't
want that out there all the time. Man.
You know,
I Albert eyes,
I didn't want all of his formulas out
there while he was trying to figure him
out. So I'm glad to hear that about
Sandler. I will check out the, the, uh,
the special one.
I have a chance and a,
and I do hope you guys will come check out
the, the standup that I'm doing. So, uh,
28th in San Jose at the Improv. I'll be
in the, at the, uh, the Improv in Irvine,
California in January and we're,
we're booking out a bunch of other stuff.
So yeah, there you go. Uh, love the Norway
Q and. A. I just posted on the channel,
I think yesterday, the Q
and a from Oslo, Norway, uh,
me asking Jordan questions.
It's the only public thing that
we've posted from the entire tour.
So if you haven't seen a dude check
it out. So thank you for that.
Just so that Jordan Peterson is
coming to Auckland, New Zealand,
will you be accompanying him?
I hope so.
So that's right after Australia and I
had something I have to do that week in
the states, so I don't think I
can, unfortunately. I'm sorry.
Believe me, I would absolutely love to
go to New Zealand for a million reasons.
Of course. I've got to try your lamb.
Uh, I get New Zealand lamb here,
but like, and then that's just one of many
reasons that I would love to go there.
And I get a lot of email
from a New Zealand also. So
don't count me out just yet,
but unfortunately I don't think it's
going to happen. Um, okay. Let's see.
What's your least favorite thing
about touring with Peterson? Uh,
we hear so much about how awesome it is.
I'm curious if there's anything
that bothers you at all. Wow,
that's a question.
Um,
okay.
No, there, there really
isn't. Um, you know,
the travel can be a little
bit exhausting at times.
Like I'm actually a little beat right now.
The reason I'm wearing a hat is I didn't
even shower today because it's been so
busy doing patrion hangouts today.
And you know,
I got back and I immediately went to the
standup Gig and then this other standup
Gig and I interviewed
Bret Weinstein yesterday,
which will be on our channel tomorrow.
And I had so much business to catch up on.
And, um, a mirror who's been our
director for three plus years, uh,
who's been just an absolute
all star at every level. Uh,
she actually accepted a new job, has
moved on. So we now have a part time,
part time or taken her job,
which is clearly a fulltime job.
It's many people's full time
jobs as we're hiring for that.
And I know a whole bunch of you have
submitted resumes and we're trying to
figure all that out so
there's just so much going on.
So I would say the only thing that's a
little sucky is that I feel like I'm a
little bit behind on things. And actually
one other thing related to the show,
which I mentioned in a
live stream last week,
the one thing that I think has suffered
on the show is that I haven't been able
to do direct messages because we've been
taping a lot of stuff in advance while
I'm on the road. I did do two
live streams last week. You know,
this is live stream right now and I'm
going to try to do more of these so that I
can keep that connection with you guys.
And so that I can,
I can speak directly to you and you guys
can ask and, and comment directly to me.
Um, but I do miss the
direct messages. I mean,
I think that's where I can
give you my most clear,
cogent thoughts because I write it out
and I go directly to camera over there
and do it. So I, I miss that
a little bit. Um, but we'll,
we'll get back to that kind of stuff.
And I also want to change what we're
doing and how we're doing it as,
as the years go by and always remain
fresh and all that good stuff.
But in terms of the tour itself,
nothing bad, nothing bad.
Jordan and I have hit
a nice rhythm together.
I think we're really bringing
out the best in each other. Um,
I honestly feel like a better person
than I was like five months ago. Like,
if you guys think Jordan has affected
you and if you think you've tried to
incorporate the 12 rules of life to,
to your life to fix yourself,
it's like try being on the road with the
guy for six months and try doing Q and
A's where we do 45 minutes together in
front of 2000 people and he's talking to
them, but then he'll turn and you
know, we're this close. Right.
And it's like there's powerful stuff
there. Um, and that's been, uh,
that's been very exciting.
So it's all good. It's very,
it's very cool. I see this,
there hasn't been one of,
actually the,
the running joke with our tour manager
John, who's also been wonderful.
It's like this guy is like, this is
the easiest tour ever. He's like,
nobody's doing drugs. Nobody's drinking.
Nobodys ripping up hotel rooms. He's like,
the two of you,
you know,
you have dinner maybe or you shoot the
shit after you drink some sparkling water
and then talk about philosophy. He's
like, this is the easiest thing ever.
The only screw up of the entire tour is
I think when we were in where the hell
were,
we were in like Ontario,
Canada and I said that we were in Toronto
or something like that, which is like,
that's like tour screw up one
oh one. So yeah, it's really,
it truly has been great.
It really has, uh, Dave,
many of us are such huge fan of yours.
Would you ever consider a patrion reward
where you would follow some of your
fans on Twitter? That's actually
kind of interesting. You know,
I wouldn't want to make it about like
that that feels like it would almost be
like bribery or something. Um, you know,
the Twitter feeds of just
become such a mess. Let me,
let me think about that one actually,
because I suspect too that if,
if you're a fan of mine and
you enjoy what we do here,
you probably treat Twitter with
the same sort of respect that I do.
So it probably wouldn't be such a bad
idea. Let me think that one through.
I think there might be something there.
Um, how much worse do you think youtube,
Facebook and Google have to become
before someone who creates a competing
service refuses to sell? And we
start to shift over? I mean, look,
this is the million dollar
question, right? Like,
we've been talking about this for months.
If you didn't watch my livestream with
Eric Weinstein from about six weeks ago
or so, uh, we got into a little bit.
There's no doubt that the billionaire
class a is now paying attention to this.
Um, there is a billionaire
that I had on the show
not too long ago who knows what he's
thinking about all this stuff. Um,
I can't tell you everything at the moment,
but yes,
I think perhaps finally, um,
we've hit critical mass with this.
We're just today I tweeted out that I
just don't see people's tweets anymore,
especially the IDW crew.
I never see Eric's tweets or Brett's
tweets or Sam's tweets. Uh, may maybe.
I see Jordan's every now and again.
Christina Hoff Summers, I never see ion.
I never see 'em a slew of them.
I never see them.
What I do see often is I see
the conservative commentators
that I follow like a
bill Kristol or no Rockman.
A couple of guys like that.
I see their tweets all the time,
but I never see my other guy's tweets.
Now we know that there's some
level of shadow banning going on.
There's something being manipulated
in the algorithm. Who the hell knows?
And again these companies can
do whatever the hell they want.
People just want some transparency.
So yes,
at some point will something
come in and replace them? Yes,
I do believe that.
Hopefully I'll be part of something
that that does do it and it's so funny.
It's like, man, all you guys have
to do, it's sort of like what I,
what I generally say about
the left at the moment,
which is all you guys had to do these
last couple of years was not be absolutely
terrible. Like you could
have been basically terrible.
You know like you could have just
been generically terrible and a lot of
liberals and left.
These would have kind of stayed with you
because they would have been like, ah,
the rights still is too scary for me.
Or something like that.
More the societal pressures to not move
politically or whatever, you know, or the,
the, the cries of racism
and bigotry wouldn't have,
would it stop people from moving,
but instead they decided to be really
awful and I kind of feel like that's
what's happening with the
tech companies right now.
It's like we don't know if
videos get out to feeds anymore.
I don't know how many of you actually are,
are watching this live at the moment
and did this get out to, you know,
we've almost 900,000 subscribers. How many
people actually got this notification?
People tell me they get unsubscribed
all the time. All of this stuff.
It's like there's gotta be a better way
to do this, to communicate information.
There's such a starvation for,
for good conversation and
enlightening thought and, and,
and not belittling and braiding everybody.
So I think it's coming together.
If you're not,
let's see.
I'd love to see your radical
feminist or SJW on the show.
How hard is it to get one to
accept an invitation? Look,
I think you guys know this.
I am happy to talk to anybody that will
have a decent, respectful conversation.
If there is,
there's a small crew of people out
there that are always attacking me and
mocking me and, and, uh,
lying and slandering me and all these
things and then demanding to come on the
show. And it's like, now I
wouldn't want you in my life,
but I wouldn't want you in my
home much less my show. Um,
but if there's someone out there from
that line of thinking that will honestly
defend their ideas and sit across from
somebody and not call you a Nazi or
racist, I'll be happy
to do that. You know,
I tweet out this list of lefties all the
time that I would love to have on from,
you know,
Michael Moore and Rob Reiner and
Chelsea Handler and Sarah Silverman and
obviously Bernie Sanders
and Elizabeth Warren and a,
and a whole slew of, uh, of other
people. So I'd be happy to do it,
but they have to discuss things. Um,
honestly and fairly, you know what,
give me one second because my dog wants
to get out of the studio and she's given
me to look.
Hold on one second.
Okay.
Sorry. That was, that was six
seconds. She gets, she's 14 years old.
She gets up the stairs a little slower
these days. Okay. Let's see. MMM,
yeah.
Uh, will you come to Cincinnati?
Bring Peterson please. Um,
actually Peterson did an event in
Cincinnati, but I was not there.
I had to go home for a, where was
I going, I think for a wedding,
so I missed that. Um, but I'd love
to go back there and I've never,
I've actually never been to Cincinnati,
so I would absolutely love to go.
One of the funny things he may,
it might crazy travels over
the last couple of weeks, um,
was that in the midst of the
whole European thing. Uh,
Bob Saget who's, uh, you got,
you guys all know Bob Saget comedian
from full house, Fuller House,
America's home videos and a good Julian
other things and a legendary standup. Uh,
I've become good friends with him and
his fiance at the time. Kelly Rizzo,
who's a great girl. And, uh, we,
they were getting married
and I left the UK.
I flew home for one day,
went to the wedding and then flew back
to Amsterdam in the middle of the whole
thing. But the wedding was,
was absolutely great and, uh,
at a great time and they're just
great. And it's like, you know what,
when you're in the thick of things,
it's like,
I just didn't want to like do this
and work this hard and then like,
just miss important things too. So
just doing my thing. Okay. Let's see.
Hey Dave,
a little worried when Jordan told the
pug story in one of your recent lectures.
So if you guys haven't seen this,
this was Jordan was referring to the
count dank yellow pug who made the Nazi
salute. Uh, and you can watch this
in our interview and from Norway, uh,
just a couple of days ago.
There are single lines out of that that
the left could use to further create an
alt right agenda.
I think you'd understand the lines that
could be edited out or combined with his
and the audience laughed or any concerns.
I'm not concerned about it even though
I think we made one or two jokes about
that. Um, look, here's the
deal. We cannot look, you know,
Jordan's not racist. Okay. Um, the
audience knows Jordan's not racist. Now,
could these people
selectively edit these videos?
Could they do this to literally any of
us at any time? Do they do it to me now?
Yes. I see people, these,
these awful Twitter anime avatars who
will quote me on things and they will
literally cut out the previous sentence
where I said, I do not think, or no,
this is not right. Can people do
all of these things all the time?
Yes they can.
And we just live in that time right now.
And I think the best thing
you can do is what we do here,
which is do not edit for content.
And,
and what I mean by that is we
don't edit for content in that.
If my guests says something that is
stupid or ridiculous or whatever it is,
we let that stand.
We do not add for content.
The only thing we edit for occasionally
someone like has a sneezing fit or a
coughing fit or if a light
blinks or something like that,
like maybe we would do an edit around
that. But we do not edit for content.
We've only edited for content one time
in the hundreds of interviews I've ever
done. I don't want to throw
the guest under the bus,
but it was somebody that really was
not in good shape for the interview.
And it was, it was just a train
wreck. And we, I didn't want to do it,
but ultimately my team convinced me
that that's what we should do just to
save. This person's a lot of anguish.
Let's just leave it at that. Um,
but in terms of that,
look, Jordan was mocking,
he was making the point that you
have to be free to express yourself.
You have to be free to make jokes.
And I think he could have even taken it
a step further that even if cow Dacula
was racist, which Jordan is
explicitly saying he's not racist,
but you're still allowed to do that.
And I would or I would argue that
you're still allowed to do that.
Now we have a stronger defense of free
speech here in the United States with our
first amendment than they do in Europe.
And further,
he talked in that Q and a about some of
the things that are happening in the UK
right now,
particularly around speech.
And you've got the Yorkshire for Yorkshire
Police Literally tweeting out saying,
you know, watch out for hate speech from
your neighbors and report them. I mean,
this is,
this is dangerous totalitarian
stuff that's spreading
all over Europe right now.
And we have to be very careful about this.
So I,
I get what you're saying that someone
could isolate one of that and then the
audience laughed when he said this, but
his intention, his intention was not, oh,
let's make fun of what the Nazis did.
The intention is to make fun
of the Nazis made, you know,
flip all of these things on their
head. And I think that, you know,
I think I said this to him in that
interview, but you know, comedy,
I think it's Mel Brooks,
it's in comedy is tragedy plus time and
you have to be able to look back and
make fun of you of these things.
And I think bart,
with partly as long as you know,
we're talking about this
in the context of Nazis,
that's why there's a lot of Jewish comics
because there's a lot of tragedy in
the, in the story of the Jews.
And it's like, all right, well,
you could either be dead or you can
learn to understand your history and what
happened and make fun of it
to sort of own it again. Um,
and I think that that's just
one way of coping and that's,
and if we don't have comedy, I don't
know what we have. Yeah. Uh, let's see.
Have you ever heard the song
politically correct by Sr 71 it's great.
20 years ahead of its time.
It read the social trajectory and speaks
uncannily to what is going on right now.
I haven't heard it but I will
keep this question up here guys.
Don't delete that one so that
I can check it out later. Um,
let's see.
Jordan Peterson is often mentioned that
the left is essential and important to
stem portrait, a potential tyranny of
hierarchies of competence. I'm wondering,
do you think that Jordan's audience can
acknowledge this is important to this?
A great question. Jordan has such
nuanced and compassionate perspective.
I'm curious if the audience,
his audience resonates with this nuance
or are they more attracted to the
critique of roasting the left? It's a
difficult question to answer I guess,
but interested in your
thoughts and perspective.
You might win best question of the day
cause that's, that's seriously good. Okay,
so in essence what you're saying there
is when Jordan critiques the left,
which is, which is sort of
the red meat for the audience,
is that what they're really into or is
it when he does this more nuance thing,
which is that we need a healthy left
the way we need a healthy, right.
Because as he would say,
they cause a tension between each other.
And that tension is,
is sort of where a society should live
so that it doesn't tilt one way too much
or tilt the other way too much. Yes. I
think they really, really are into that.
The red meat, he doesn't do things for
applause lines. Like, um, you know,
he doesn't do just the easy things
like get up there and be like
feminism or not. He never does
that. He never does that. Um,
as a matter of fact, one of the things
that I'll say to him sometimes is, uh,
you know, sometimes he'll get a
big laugh on something and I can,
sometimes it's intentional.
Sometimes it's not intentional. Um,
but he always will talk right through
it because his intention up there is not
to get laughs. And then when I
go up there and then I, then I,
my intention is to get labs and mess
with him and have fun with the crowd. Um,
but his intention is not for the audience
reaction is intention is truly to
expand what his thinking is. And I
watched this guy doing it every night.
It's pretty freaking awesome.
Um, so as your question,
one of the way he describes this is that
you need this healthy left and right
the way you would want a
relationship in a marriage.
You wouldn't want to beat your
wife and an argument, let's say,
because then you're the
winner and she's the loser,
and then you're married to a loser.
What you would want is that you could
prove a point so and then sort of offer a
handout and say,
we can fix this together,
and you would hope that that's the way
the other side would treat you as well.
I sense that a lot of people
are into that nuance. I mean,
I think that's sort of what's
happening with the IDW. It's right.
We're not just saying, look, we're
all frustrated with the left.
Most of us come from the left.
Some of us,
like Brett and Eric and Sam still still
believe they believe they're on the left.
I can't honestly say that anymore. I
see a much healthier center, right?
These days I see a much more interesting
and rich and politically diverse group
of Libertarians and conservatives these
days and former liberals or classical
liberals or former progressive that are
making a really wide tent and better
really interested in discussing ideas.
That's what I see and I'm,
I'm very comfortable with them.
Well,
I'd be glad to talk to those
people on their side, of course,
but basically that you need these
two healthy sides that have nuance,
that have tension with each other because
otherwise if you break this thing,
then you got one sort of tyrannical side.
And guess what? Look, I know that, uh,
you know,
most of you guys watching this right now,
you're at your other classical liberals
generally are your libertarians or
conservatives.
Um,
but you don't want to wing to the point
that there's no opposition because that
opposition is what is the sort of gestalt
of what a healthy society is made up
of. Um, so I do think people
are in on it for the nuance and,
and he's given it to him. He really is.
He's not doing the red meat stuff. Um,
let's see. Uh, do you ever
fear of the IDW being hijacked?
Example,
you can all have conversations,
but now what do you have conversations
about? Can the tolerance go too far?
A good question and there's a
little bit of a follow up. Uh, Dave,
I just want to tell you that you were
awesome and Bray at this week and it was
great to meet you. Oh, this is
a different question. All right,
I'll get to that one in a second. So do
you ever a fear of the ITW being hijack?
Look, it's, it's tough because
what are we exactly like,
you know, are we, are
we a political movement?
I think there's probably
some legitimacy to that,
but we're not a political party
or we a publishing company.
Are we a road touring group?
Are we a podcast network?
Are we a youtube replacement? Are we all
of these things? Are we a news network?
I mean,
who nobody really knows.
I promise you we're having a
lot of discussions about this,
but in terms of being hijacked,
look, I could see some,
I see sometimes now mainstream
trying to hijack some of these ideas,
but I don't think you can fake it.
We have,
we have been in the primordial stew,
uh,
with you guys for years doing this.
And I don't think you can fake it.
And the things that we see and believe
and talk about our real and authentic and
these people, I promise you
guys, these people, I look,
I've done plenty of TV shows.
Almost everyone that you
see on a generic TV show,
they are that on television and
there's something else in real life.
And you can even see it when the
cameras go on something changes in them.
And there are a different person, um,
these, this crude. It's not, it is,
it is the real deal. And maybe
look, maybe it could be a,
maybe it could be hijacked in some way
that, you know, who knows, maybe tomorrow,
like CNN announces they have a show
with their big thinkers and maybe they
grabbed one of the ITW people. And throw
a lot of money at them and whatever.
I'm just not that worried.
And it's almost like I just look,
I'm just doing what I think is right and
I'm going to keep doing it and I think
we can fix some of this stuff and I think
we are fixing some of this stuff so.
So that's it right there. Um, Dave,
just want to tell you that you were
awesome in Bray at this week and it was
great to meet you. I brought three
friends with me and we all had a blast.
The Weinstein brothers were great.
Also will probably come and again in
January to Irvine and bring a few others.
Keep it up. It's not a question,
but I appreciate it. Yeah,
I think we're really doing something
different and I'm so, it's awesome.
So I'm like,
when I meet you guys after,
and especially when I meet
the Patriot on people,
it's like you guys are
supporting what I do and I, I,
we showed you guys a great time and you
just laugh and it's not that serious.
And we make fun of all of this nonsense.
And I'm a little bit different, you know,
look, it's like when I do
these live streams with you,
I'm a little bit different than Dave
doing the interview and I assure you when
I'm doing comedy I'm a little
bit different than, than
Dave doing this right now.
It's just like a different,
it's like a different frequency that
I'm operating at. So I'm glad you came.
And thank you for, uh, coming. And
for those of you just tuning in,
I will be at the San Jose Improv on
November 28 and there will be at least one
IDW member, uh, come in.
Let's see. Uh, Hey Dave,
how is it that you were the one who ended
up being attached to Peterson and his
tours?
FYI,
my podcast partner and I made it to one
of the shows in Seattle months back and
of course, love every second of it. Keep
up the inspirationally profound work. Um,
so the way this whole thing started was,
you may remember last January I
had Shapiro and Peterson in studio.
And by the way, I'm doing a live
stream with Peterson and Shapiro again,
and we're going to cover all new ground
on November 30th. So keep that in your,
uh, in your pocket on
your calendar. But anyway,
I had them in studio last January and
that night Jordan was doing his first ever
theater show.
Uh,
the book had just come out and they
were just kind of testing it, like,
could he sell out a theater and
what would it be like and all that.
And as he was walking out the
door, I said to him, Hey Jordan,
do you want me to open for you
tonight? I'll, I'll warm up the crowd,
see what happens. And he's just
like, yeah, Dave, come on down.
I don't know what kind of
Peterson impression that
was. Um, but anyway, he said,
come on down. Anyway, we do the show.
It's at the Orpheum here in la downtown.
It's about 2000 people.
And I just did a bunch of jokes about
Jordan and about lobsters and all of these
things. And the crowd just absolutely ate
it up. And then we did a Q and a after.
So basically I do stand up,
Jordan does an hour and a half or so,
and then we do some Q and a together
for another 45 minutes. And uh,
Jordan's agents were there and
they immediately were like, Whoa,
we got to do something with this.
And I signed with them like two or three
days later, maybe a week later. Uh,
and then we decided to do this tour
and I gotta tell you it's, it's a,
it's freaking fantastic. It
really is. Um, let's see.
Have you invited Barry Weiss on the
Ruben report? She would be interesting.
I have invited her many times.
She has said she's going to do it.
We haven't been able to
coordinate the thing in La, uh,
partly because of my travels,
I think part of the cause of hers.
But we will make that
happen at some point. Um,
what do you think of attempting to brand
these folks that are attacking free
speech as illiberals in particular in
particular using that word whenever
referring that to them in order to
distinguish between them and classical
liberals that many of ourselves
consider us to be. That's interesting.
So that's like saying it's a little bit
of those sort of regressive left thing
like these people are not progressive
for progress because being for progress
would mean that you're for
equality for everybody,
not equity are for equality
of opportunity for everybody.
These people are regressive.
They want us to regress.
They want us to go backwards and
start looking at people based on their
immutable characteristics,
their sexuality and gender and
skin color and the rest of it.
And that is not progressive. That is
regressive. So illiberal it's good, right?
I mean I've heard,
I've obviously heard the word before,
it's good because they are not liberal.
Liberal in its,
in its essence means live and let live.
It means you believe in the individual.
You believe in individual rights.
You believe in a light
touch of the government.
This is the reverse of what progressives
are who believe in the collective.
And they believe that the
government has all the answers.
They believe that the
government gives you rights.
I don't believe that the
I believe you person watching
this right now, you are born free,
you are born free.
The government can protect your rights
and it can take your rights away.
But it did not give you those rights. It
is your human rights. This is where, uh,
someone on the more conservative side,
if I had Shapiro or Prager,
one of those guys, they would
say, these are God given rights.
I would say they are, they
are rights by the, by the,
the fact that you are a human makes
you free. You are born for human.
It doesn't matter if
it's God given or not.
You are free and someone can
take that away and lock you up.
They did not give you your freedom. No Man
gave you your freedom. You are free. Um,
and they don't,
they don't believe that.
They believe that the government
gave you those things. Um, so I like,
I like the word illiberal, you know, it's
like one of those things. It's like, look,
I had those two years when this was all
bursting forth originally where I said
regressive left all the time because so
many people realized there was something
wrong with the left.
And the and modularized came up with
the phrase regressive left and it's so
captured.
It was an easy way of explaining to
people what this segment of the left was.
Now I would argue that segment of the
left has no almost encompassed the entire
world cleft.
It's almost everything,
media and political establishment
and the whole thing,
but I don't say regressive left anymore.
It sort of was becoming a little redundant
and a bit memorable. Um, and, and,
and I didn't want it to be a pejorative.
I wanted it to be something
that identified something.
And I think we've really did that.
We really did do that.
And not only do we do that,
but I,
but I'm really proud to say that people
talk about classical liberalism now,
and I think I was one of the people,
if not the really the first person in
this space that got people starting to
talk about that again. And then of
course I did that Prager u video,
why I left the left and I am mapping,
I think it's their number
one video of all time.
And I think it woke up a
lot of people. So, you know,
I wouldn't want to use any of these
phrases as pejorative as to just mock.
But if it's, if it's a phrase,
if you say, if someone,
if you're in an argument with somebody
and they're telling you there are liberal,
but therefore all these illiberal
policies, you say, you know,
you're not a liberal,
you're in a liberal and here's why.
Well then I think that's a
pretty effective. Let's see.
Um,
for God's sakes,
how can we get Eric Weinstein to post
more on his youtube channel four posts in
eight months. There are squirrels with
Warren posts. What can you do to fix this?
I will,
uh,
well I've spent the last two days with
him doing stand up and some other stuff.
Uh, I'm sure I'll see him
in the next couple of days.
I will tell him this and he will
not out be out done by a squirrel,
I assure you of that much. All right,
we got about 20 minutes left guys. Um,
let's see.
Um,
do you enjoy studying science?
That's outside of politics,
learning for learning's sake. All right,
so let me do it with the second part.
I do like learning for learning sake. You
know, I think one of the coolest things,
if I've done anything right in this world,
um,
is that I get to learn every week.
So I just yesterday
interviewed Bret Weinstein,
which were posting next week and this
guy is a wickedly brilliant evolutionary
biologist and he was put on the map
obviously because of what happened at
Evergreen.
And he and his wife no longer have jobs
and had to move out of the town that
they love.
And I don't want to give too much away of,
of where they're at now because you'll
see it in the interview next week. Um,
but we did sort of half the interview
on what happened to him and what his
future is,
but then the other half,
and we did about an hour
and a half together on,
on evolutionary biology and explanations
of all of the things that are seemingly
out of whack these days.
And this recent talk that he had with
Richard Dawkins and what they think, how,
where they think that evolutionary biology
bread thinks they forked at a certain
point and what he thinks Dawkins gets
wrong and what Dawkins gets right. I mean,
the fact that I get to sit with these
people or get to tour with Peterson or get
to, you know, uh,
listened to Eric Weinstein talk
about mathematics or whoever it is.
It's like I learn every week. So
in a way that is learned it. Look,
it's learning for learning's sake.
I happen to be doing it on a show.
I happened to be doing it on
something that now has become a,
a small production company.
And that that is a profitable
business that I'm super proud of,
that it's allowed me to buy a home and
build a studio here in all of these
things. And, and we're completely fan
funded, which is freaking amazing. Um,
but I do consider most of it learning
for learning's sake if that's possible.
It's like,
it's really cool.
Like I get to be around really
cool people and not only that,
but then when I go out and I do these
public events and then I meet you guys and
people,
people give me books and they write
these incredible letters and all of these
things. And it's like, we're,
we're doing something guys.
Let's, let's keep doing it.
And, and what we need more of you
guys to do is share these videos,
is tweet about these things,
is get,
get your friends and families
to know these ideas. Um,
because that's how we really can change
these things. And I, and I think we're,
we're actually doing it.
Yeah.
Um, do you have a fear that
has tech companies veer left?
Do you think things will progress beyond
shadow banning and d platforming to
outright hostile advocacy
against competing views?
I mean this is sort of like the question
of like how much worse is it going to
get before it gets
better? And yeah, I mean
it seems that, you know, look, they can be
platform, they can screw with algorithms,
they can get rid of likes,
they can get rid of follower accounts,
they can do all of these manipulations.
But it's like,
what are the next hostile moves?
And what I would say here is it's like,
forget what you think.
I've said this before,
but it's like Alex Jones as
an example. It's like, look,
you may think the guy's
views are all horrible.
He said some horrible things about
Sandy Hook and a bunch of other things.
It's like, there are plenty
of horrible people out there.
Go look at Louis Americans Twitter and
tell me that what he's saying on any
given day in the videos that he's
posting aren't probably worse than uh,
what Jones was saying everyday or that
Hamas who is committed to the destruction
of all Jews on earth, uh,
has a Twitter account.
So those guys were allowed on there.
But Jones can't be on Facebook or on,
on youtube or on any of these
things. Again, I'm not even,
it's so boring to make this about Jones.
I'm not even talking about him
specifically, but it's like, look,
if they can take out one person, they
can take out anybody. And the Pete,
the type of people who want to take
people out are not people who ultimately
believe in freedom. And again,
this is not a defense of Jones,
but it's like of Jones specifically.
But it's like if the type
of people that do this,
it's not like they take one person out
and then they're suddenly like, wow,
we're good to go. We want to get dinner.
No, it's like, oh, we moved a lot.
And how can we move that
line a little bit further?
And then you see what happened to
bench pure or the last couple of days,
I think it was Ohio state.
He goes there and these
people are chanting that he's
a Nazi in this ridiculous
bullshit and he's an Orthodox Jew
and they're calling him a Nazi.
And then there's this great video by this
guy, I think his name is Joe Flakka, uh,
where he's interviewing these kids that
are protesting Shapiro and he gets the
Migraine. But well, what
don't you like about venture?
And they don't even know any of his views.
And it's like,
it's become this,
this leftist monster and I monsters the
only word that makes sense to me around
it as become an infection
in young people's minds.
Unfortunately where they're protesting,
they don't even know
why they're protesting.
They're protesting because
they believe that victim hood,
but it's not even just victim of
that perceived victim hood is virtue.
Edit is not virtue. Guys, what is
virtue? Every movie that you love,
think of your favorite movie right now.
Think of the great adventure
movies of all time.
Luke Skywalker didn't look for someone
else to blow up the death star.
He went ahead and did it. You know
what I mean? Frodo didn't be like,
oh we're doing is the ring.
Where's the ring?
You could somebody take this ring and
get it to your door and drop it in the
thing for me. No, he did it. He didn't
just sit there as the victim. He,
it's everything. Neal, what
a neo do you know an Eeo did?
All of these guys,
every movie it's like everyone comes
from something and some of us come from
shitty or things and some of us were
born with more and some of us were born
less than some of us got to limp
and some of us are this color,
that color and this sexuality and
that cause none of it matters.
Get you've got your free. If you live
in a Western society you are free.
And if you're afraid to say what
you think in a Western society,
and we were in a bunch of countries
in Europe and Sweden in particular,
where people are really
afraid to say what they think.
Well do you think that your silence is
going to somehow make it better? No.
There are plenty of bad people who will
take your silence and only use it to
make more people be silent. So you
better fight for what you believe in.
I don't think I'm anyone special other
than for some reason I feel like I can
talk about this stuff and it
hasn't stopped me yet. And,
and you know what? Yeah,
it's Shitty when, when
these awful journalists and
they're journalists, they're,
they're, uh, they're, well, it's Candizolv
and says their hit men. Um, you know,
when they, they're activists though, is
what they really are. They're masking,
rating or masking and masquerading
as journalists. Uh, yeah.
It's not fun having them
write these things about you.
And I know none of you
would ever want that.
And I don't like it when it happens to me,
but you know what?
We're all still here. Peterson's
still here. Everybody's still here.
That's been through this, this thing.
And you'd be through it too. Uh,
but everyone has to think
about their own life, how,
how they will and you responsibly
hopefully in seriously. Um,
but as Douglas Murray said, you
know, uh, when you get in the pool,
you might find out that the water is not
that cold. And I think that that is it.
Everyone's afraid of jumping in.
But if you actually just put your foot in,
you might find that it's actually more
okay here. And you might find that, yeah,
you're going to lose some friends,
but you're going to make better friends
and you might find that you feel better.
You physically feel better because you're
being more honest with yourself. Uh,
and I,
and a slew of other things.
So get out there and fight
for what you believe in.
Even if you believe in things that I
don't believe I would be all for you doing
that.
Um,
how do we begin to translate the important
message concerning individual liberty
that you and Jordan are doing to politics?
Individual Liberty is not represented
on the, on the traditional left, right?
Political scale. Yeah. Well
there hasn't been a great, um,
there hasn't been a great, let's say
stance for the individual in a long time.
Like Rand Paul talks about the individual
because he's basically a libertarian.
Uh, um, what's his name?
Paul Ryan would talk about the individual
quite a bit and I know he was really
influenced by Iran.
Um,
but there isn't a real fighter for the
individual the way that there should be.
Um,
you know,
as more and more of the left goes to
the identity politics thing and as the
Democrats won, uh, just two weeks ago
there they've realized, well, all right,
well this may be,
is a winning strategy now,
so they're going to only go in on it more,
which is why I wanted them to lose,
I wanted them to lose because I thought,
all right,
if they lose maybe then the
more extreme set of Democrats,
the Democratic Socialists
would be washed away.
And then some decent liberals
that used to exist would,
would magically appear again.
Maybe a JFK could appear again and then
that that could actually be a decent
democratic party against something
that I could probably be part of again,
et Cetera, et cetera. Um, but there is no,
as they've done that the Republicans
haven't done a great job or the
Conservatives or whatever on the right
have not done a great job of really
explaining why the individual is the
root of a free society and that we should
only care about individual rights and
we shouldn't be giving to this group and
taking from that group
and things of that nature.
This is a winnable argument
because it's a clear,
clean argument and it's the most human
argument there is because every one
watching this, everyone listening
to this, you, me, everybody,
we would only want to be
judged as individuals.
None of us are sitting
or no one sitting there.
If you're watching this and you're black,
you're not sitting there going,
I wish I could be judged the way
all other black people are judged.
They're a good,
bad black people.
There were bad black people there would
use bad Jews. Nice Muslims mean Muslims.
Everybody, you know, great gay people
or gay people, everything is out there.
And so that's why when these people say,
I'm for women.
So Mark Hamill, who's Luke Skywalker, and
you guys know my feelings on star wars,
he tweeted out this thing
the other day about this,
that we should have all women in politics,
but he doesn't really mean that because
you don't mean you want Nikki Haley and
Sarah Sanders, uh, Sarah Huckabee,
Sanders and Republican women.
You mean you want women who behave as
you want them to behave. And that's the,
the,
the silliness and the foolishness.
And the lazy thinking of
collectivism is that you can't,
if I'm for gay people really,
are you four Republican gay people
or you're for gay people who are into
firearms and who happened to be prolife?
No, you're not into those gay people.
So to say you're for gay
people is actually, that's
actually sort of offensive.
Say you're,
I'm for certain things and
certain individuals happened
to be for those things,
but I'm for women. And then the
new thing is that if you're the,
that there was this real push after the
election from the left against white
women and the women's march was teaching,
we're going to have to teach white
women and it's like, oh, really?
Do we just have to bow to you forever
because we have different political, uh,
thoughts. Oh, it's gross. It's actually
greets gross and racist guys. Um,
let's see here. Uh, we got
about nine minutes left.
I want to get to as many as possible.
I would love to have you interview some
of the climate change scientists who
would challenge MSM
mainstream media narrative.
Have you talked to Mark Stein about that?
You know,
we were in touch with Mark
Stein for awhile and I did
Gutfeld show with him once
about a year ago and then it
just kind of fell apart. Um,
so I don't know where that left off,
but I'll ask my guys after this and
I'm sure we can make that happen. Um,
let's see.
Uh,
do you think the increase in California
fires can be partly caused by the
numerous red tape regulations to protect,
to protect trees from humans? Uh, I
don't know enough about the specific,
I mean, I feel like this is a slightly
trolling question perhaps. Um, we,
we don't know exactly what caused these
fires yet. From what I understand.
I think one of them, maybe
it was a campfire. Um, look,
a little of this is just nature.
Nature does things now also,
we've been in a crazy drought here in la,
so I moved to La in February
of 2013 so it's not even that,
it's just about six years.
If I tell you guys that in,
in six years,
I don't think I'm exaggerating when I
would say we've had 20 days of rain,
like real rainy days. We've had, you
know, some drizzle here and there.
There was a couple of years ago,
we had like four days in a
row where it really rained,
but I don't know that we've had more
than 20 days of bringing ballparking.
It basically, I mean, we're in
a pretty dry, pretty dry, uh,
time.
We're in a drought and you know,
when you drive through the
hills here in Los Angeles,
there are times when when it's rained
a little bit and everything's green,
and then there's times when everything
is just dry and it's like, man,
you could set fire to everything
just like that. And then, you know,
there's so many houses in
these odd crevices and hills,
and then the way these Santa Ana
winds blow where once the fire starts,
it blows it on too.
I mean,
it's literally blowing embers
over there when this was,
when they talk about jumping highways.
Um,
I don't know enough about it specifically
related to regulations and everything
else, but I don't think everything can
just be solved by government regulations,
obviously. Uh, and I don't
think everything can be solved.
I think nature is pretty freaking
powerful. Um, so yeah, that's that.
That's my thought on that.
Um,
California seems to be at the
past the point of no return.
What do you think would have to happen
for a peaceful political remedy to the
left? This bottomless pit.
The state is in. I don't know.
It's weird. I mean, look,
we have super high taxes here. I don't
know that we get a ton for them. You know,
our, our mayor, our governor
now Gavin Newsome, uh, is uh,
is as far left as you can get.
He was the mayor of San Francisco.
San Francisco is kind of gross.
They have literally have an APP that
tells you where human poop is so you don't
step in it.
The last time I was in Berkeley,
our car got broken into on a nice street
and they stole my bag. When my, uh,
sister-in-law's,
or when my brother in law's parents
were visiting from out of the country
visiting Berkeley about a month ago.
They got mugged in broad daylight.
They literally tore his mom's rings
off her finger, broad daylight.
Um, so, and I can look, we
go to Seattle when I've been,
now that I've toured the whole country,
when we go to the cities
that are more progressive,
those are the cities where there are more
drugs and more crime and more homeless
people.
It just is.
That is just a fact when I've gone to
the cities that are more conservative,
Salt Lake City, Dallas, things like
that. They're beautiful. They're clean.
It seems like the economy's
you're strong there.
You don't see as many homeless people.
W I mean it all adds up to something,
doesn't it? So I, so what can
happen in California? I don't know.
I do know that there is a growing,
uh,
conservative libertarian
movement here in California.
I don't know that it's really
getting a lot of momentum,
but when I had John Casick on who's the
governor of Ohio who ran for president,
obviously he was meeting with Arnold
Schwarzenegger and a bunch of other people
and look arms. Schwarzenegger was
the governor, believe it or not,
of California not too long ago. And
he was a republican. So, you know,
these things ebb and flow.
Um,
but I do think it's possible
that eventually, you know,
California will tax out all
the good people who will
just leave and they'll move
to Florida and they'll move to Arizona,
New Mexico and Utah and Colorado and,
uh, and then who knows what will be
left here. I can also tell you this, uh,
just from living here,
there are way more homeless people here
now than there were when I moved here.
I don't know what that exactly means.
I don't know exactly how all of those
policies that have been put in by,
by democratic and left the politicians
of, uh, laid all of that out.
But you know, we shall see. Um, let's see.
You have an open invitation to the
weekly wake up county libertarian party
meeting in Raleigh. I will keep that
in mind. Thank you very much. Um,
let's see. Uh, Dave,
I keep seeing these new laws regarding
gender and sexuality and morality.
How can people keep track of what's
legal and what's illegal anymore?
Things could be changing
so fast. Um, I, well,
I'd want to know exactly what laws
you're talking about specifically.
What I will tell you is, uh, is,
is one of those interesting things that
happened to us during the tour was that
Jordan and I both had
sort of circled a den, uh,
Sweden as,
as sort of an interesting stop because
for us on my youtube channel here,
the fifth most watched
country, uh, is Sweden,
which is really interesting because
there are not a lot of people in Sweden.
I think there's around 12 million people.
So it's a pretty tiny country.
So us is number one, then it's UK and
then it's usually Canada and Australia.
They, they flipped between
three and four and then, um,
Sweden and I, you know, I've had a
couple of Swedish people on the show,
which I think is part of it.
Aaron flamme who is a very
popular comedian and I met
him there and he's a great
guy.
Uh,
and I've had a Tino Sanandaji who's an
economist who I had on mostly talking
about immigration. These are both a long
time ago. Tino is a couple years ago.
Right. Um, anyway, um,
we both sort of circled Sweden as cause
cause Jordan gets a lot of mail from
there. We thought what's
going on in Sweden, so a,
the shows we did two shows in Sweden,
they sold out in like five minutes each.
The crowds were phenomenal,
like endless, endless cheering.
They were so great. My need and
greets after were absolutely packed.
It was just such an interesting,
cool group people.
But the reason I bring this up,
it related to your question is I thought
that most people when we do the Q and a,
we use this app called Slido.
When people submit questions
and people can up vote things.
And then with Jordan's onstage,
I go through the ones that I think are
the best and I pick interesting ones.
I pick funny ones,
I pick off the wall ones,
they pick heartfelt one's
personal stories, whatever it is.
And I thought mostly we were going to
see things about immigration in Sweden
because they definitely have
an integration problem. Uh,
and there were a lot
about immigration but,
but the vast majority of
questions were gender related.
Um, and there's, well,
we'll have to do a show on this
and when I have Jordan and studio,
we'll talk about this a bit more,
but it's really,
really interesting because the Swedes
and the Scandinavian countries in Nordic
countries in general,
I've done egalitarianism really well that
men and women are equal and have been
equal for a long time.
Sweden right now has a supposedly a
self proclaimed feminist government.
Men and women are equal completely.
And as this has happened,
um, what they've realized is that
men and women are still different. B,
despite equality,
that women are more into people
and men are more into things.
So despite all of the equality
that you would want in a society,
and that's what they have in Sweden,
that there are still more female nurses
and there were still more male engineers.
So it's like they ran the
experiment of equality.
We're going to treat everyone equally.
Men and women can do whatever they want,
everyone can live as they wish. And
yet still there are, there are jobs,
vocations that women want to do and that
men want to do. And that just is so,
it's like the social
justice warriors of Sweden,
which are now very
embedded in the government,
aren't letting the experiment of humanity.
They did the experiment.
How can we do it? Let's keep
it, make everyone exactly equal.
That's what everyone should want. Well,
we did it and now they've got the result.
They've got the, they did the
experiment, they got the results,
but they won't let them have the result
because they don't like it because there
were still more women that are nurses
then and there are still more men that are
engineers.
So they want to engineer a society.
So you'd end up having people doing
things that they don't want to do.
So would it make more, would it be
a better society if you had 50, 50,
or exact proportion, uh, male nurses
and female nurses and exact proportion,
male engineers and female energies?
I mean,
does anyone think that would be
a better free or happier society?
Know that would very clearly be a worst
tyrannical, authoritarian society.
So it's really interesting
stuff over there. And I'll,
I'll talk to Jordan about
it when we have men. Anyway,
I didn't get to everything here,
but we'll keep some of these uh,
catalog and we'll get to them next
week or next month. Um, so yeah,
if you haven't joined patrion.com/ruben
report and if you join at level one,
I take all patrion on questions here.
We also do group chats,
which I was doing all day,
small chats.
Sometimes there's three
or four people in groups.
Sometimes there's 15 or
16 people in, um, uh,
there's all sorts of other rewards you
can get free meet and greets to my stand
up events and all that good stuff.
I will be in San Jose at
the Improv on November 28th.
You can go to Dave rubin.com/events.
I'll be at the Irvine Improv in January,
um, at the Orpheum here in la on
a December 1st with Jordan, uh,
Jordan and Ben in studio on November 29th.
I'll be in Calgary and Vancouver first
week of December with Jordan. What else?
Hawaii with Jordan the
day before thanksgiving.
I'm literally flying there that morning
and leaving that night, which is bananas,
but you know, you're just do what
you've got to do. And uh, what else?
I think I'm at the University of
Montana first week of December also,
and a whole bunch of,
and then we're going to be in San Diego
and a whole bunch of other things in
January. Whew. That's a lot
of talking. All right. Thanks
everybody. Appreciate it.
Remember it's patrion.com/rubin report
if you want to get in on this and we are
fan funded and all that good stuff and
I'm not going to talk to the rest of the
day. All right. Goodnight everybody.