[inaudible]
alright.
Ladles and jellies spoons.
We are alive on
www.youtube.com/rubin report.
All right.
And there's a lot to do here and we've
only got an hour today because I've had a
completely bananas day. I feel like
my days are getting more and more.
I like to say bonkers, but I've gone with
bananas. I said Banana sometimes to, uh,
my days are getting crazier
and crazier these days. Um,
I've already taped three shows today and
I was up at the crack of dawn and I did
a 45 minute a radio interview.
I had about two minute breaks in
between everything. And here we are.
We're going live.
The second I'm done here,
there's already a car waiting for
me outside. I'm heading over to, uh,
to do Tucker Carlson tonight and then,
excuse me. Then I hear that that a,
that Trump fell has given a big speech.
I guess I'll have to tweet that thing.
So it's going to be one of those days.
It's all good. Uh, what I wanted to do is,
as you guys know,
I am departing Patrion Sam Harris
has already left Patrion uh,
Jordan Peterson will be
joining me on January 15th.
We will be deleting our patrion accounts.
This is all because of their treatment
of Carl Benjamin Sargon of a cod.
I'm sure most of you are well
aware of that whole situation,
so I don't want to repeat the whole thing.
Uh,
suffice to say that every now and again
in life I think you have to just take a
stand when it's not easy to do so
and maybe not popular to do so.
And maybe puts yourself at some risk.
And I just think this is the
right one for us to take.
A patrion has been amazing to us.
We've been on there for
about two and a half years.
You guys know all the stuff about youtube
demonetization and how hard it is to,
to make a living as a, as a youtube
creator. A patron has been awesome for us.
I built a business, I bought
a house, I hired employees.
Everything that we've done basically in
the last two and a half years has been
because of Patrion. Uh, but
we are deleting it. It's
time. It's time to stand up.
Jordan and I are working on a platform
that I think can be a solution to this.
There are many layers of problems that
we're going to have to deal with a,
but we're thinking them all through about
payments and crypto and the terms of
service and the whole thing. You've
heard me talk about all of that before.
So what we're doing today,
I'm only gonna do two more.
One today and one on the 15th on
January 15th. Uh, two more live streams,
uh,
doing a little fundraising because we're
getting everybody off Patrion and we're
trying to get people over
to Dave rubin.com/donate.
That removes some of the middleman we can.
We can control everything.
It doesn't solve all of the technological
or monetization problems yet,
but get everybody to
over to our website and,
and off of Patrion and stand
up to the man, so to speak. Uh,
so we're doing a little fundraising.
So here's the deal.
Anyone that donates@daverubin.com slash
donate for the next hour while I am live.
Anyone who donates $5 or above,
however you do it over there,
I'm going to give you a live shout out.
So I've got an iPad here and my
guys will be typing out names.
You will get alive.
Shout out if you do $5 or above.
If you do $25 or above,
you're going to get the Rubin report tee
shirt. Now this select member tee shirt,
this was the t shirt that we were given
to our patrons who were at the high
level that we're at the tee shirt level.
So we've got about a
hundred of these left.
They will never be printed again
because we're not on patrion anymore,
so select no longer exists.
So these are the last ones.
They are a limited edition collector's
item. Ladies and Gentlemen,
I'm wearing one of them right now.
Maybe I'll have to give away the one
right on my back. We we shall see.
So that's $25 or above monthly.
And you're going to get a tee shirt.
If you go to $50 or above,
uh,
during this live stream for the next hour,
I'm going to take the official
Ruben report mug and what
am I going to do to it?
I'm going to sign it. I'm going to show
you how, I'm going to sign it right here.
I'm going to sign it for Ya.
And you could get that mug.
So whoever does the first
50 and dollars Mug, uh,
the first $50 person monthly at a time's
up, Dave Ruben. Dot. Constellation donate.
You can get this mug that I just
signed right now. There you go. Okay.
Putting that down.
So we've got tee shirts,
we've got mugs and basically you guys are
funding our ability to keep this thing
totally independent. We have had, as I've
said, we have had offers from networks.
There's all sorts of advertisers that
want to jump on board, all sorts of stuff.
So none of this is Crimea river and I'm
not sitting here woe is me or anything
like there is plenty of opportunity.
I love doing what we've done the way
we've done it, remained independent. I am,
I am beholden only to you guys.
And there's a certain beauty in that
because I genuinely have, I can't say,
I have no idea. I have almost no idea
what most of you think about anything.
So it's like I couldn't really sell
out one way or another or any other way
because I get emails, people that are
conservatives, I get liberal emails.
I get some angry emails from
progressive's. I get a lot
emails from Libertarians.
I mean all of this, but I don't
even know exactly what my, my, uh,
patrons in the past and people who
are currently supporting us things.
So I can just do what I think is right,
which is what I've tried
to consistently do.
And just what I'll consistently
try to do. So, okay,
if you go to Dave
rubin.com/donate $5 and above, uh,
I'm going to give you a shout out,
25 bucks and above monthly
you're getting the Rubin report,
tee shirt and $50 or above monthly.
You're getting assigned mug right now.
And you're getting the t shirt and
I'll just keep talking to you guys. Oh,
by the way,
tomorrow I will be at the Ontario Improv,
not Ontario, Canada. I'm sorry
to those of you in Canada.
A lot of people were very confused last
time. Uh, it's Ontario, California,
which is, I think it's about an hour
away. Uh, southern California. Um,
I will be there tomorrow
night doing standup.
I do about an hour set and then I
will be bringing Bret Weinstein,
a professor in exile, Bret Weinstein,
formerly of evergreen state. And you guys,
I'm sure all know his story.
He'll join me for a sit down afterwards
and it's just like a fun night.
It's not normal standup like
you've ever seen before.
I mess around with the crowd a lot. We
got people screaming, I giveaway stuff.
We do a live Q and a. It's like, it's
like just a free for all. I think you'll,
I think you'll really dig it. Um, so
check that out. And uh, Oh and on, uh,
January, Twitter 30th, I will be
at the Irvine Improv in Irvine,
California,
Orange County.
And I will have an IDW guests with
not saying who that is just yet. Okay.
We've got a couple shout outs to Jared
and Andy, welcome aboard. Thanks guys.
And Garrett, you were the first one that
I saw. So Garret is getting this mug.
Let's make sure we put this mug aside.
That was a person when I signed and Brad,
welcome aboard.
You also are getting a mug which
I'm going to sign for you right now.
Thank you guys. You are a supporting
our ability to do what we're doing.
So as I said, I'm only gonna do one more
of these and then I won't, uh, you know,
promoter, whenever you're going to call
this fundraiser drive, whatever it is,
I won't do it throughout
the year. I, you know,
once a year I think we'll do it going
forward like one day where we're like,
all right, we're trying to raise
some funds to do this or that.
The next one that I'll do and then it'll,
we'll be done for all of
2019 will be on January 15th.
We're going to do one of these.
I'll do a little giveaway and
some fun stuff and all that.
And then I'm going to take my computer.
We have to figure out how this is
exactly going to work. Logistically.
I will turn it around and I'm going to
press delete on Patrion right in front of
you guys.
So you will watch me delete patrion right
then and there we will get rid of that
thing. Um, it's no hard feelings,
any of those guys in a weird way.
It's like you want to run
your business that way.
I'm not going to have the government
jump in and tell you what to do,
but I just don't want to be part of,
of what they're doing anymore.
So we're going to do that on January 15th,
Jordan and I also should have some updates
on things. Hopefully somewhat soon.
Things are moving. Trust
me, things are moving.
Just takes a little time to get
things done. All right, so, uh,
let me jump into some questions. We're
also take some questions on super chat.
I see a whole bunch of you guys
jumping in on that. So, uh,
from Patriot and I got a question
from Patriot about patrion.
Do you have any idea how much of a
financial hit patrion itself has taken
because of the exodus of you,
Jordan, Sam, etc. So I don't know,
I mean I could extrapolate if
I was to look at, you know,
sort of the amount of money that
I know we were making per month.
I have a general sense of what
Jordan was making per month.
I have a sort of sense but less so
of what Sam was making per month.
And let's say a couple other
people, patriotic gets, you know,
like 5% of each of us per month
plus some other fees and things.
Let's say it's 10% total. I'm, I'm
actually not totally sure. Um, it's,
it's a nice amount of money. Um,
but considering as far as I know,
Patrion got something like $450 million
dollars in VC funding in the last couple
of years.
It's a small amount.
So I don't think this is about while it
is hurting them in the pocket. Right.
And it's like they want to
make as much money as possible.
I think us taking the stand
is more important. So look,
if patrion crumbled after this,
that's not really my goal here.
But like if it started a chain reaction
of people inside there that suddenly
we're into free speech and don't like
all of this d platforming and are afraid
of the way the line is moving to exclude
people. I would be okay with that.
But this is more about us just doing what
we think is right. But by the way, look,
people like Bret Weinstein, who I just
mentioned, people I call them, I already,
I mean, people that I love and admire
are staying on Patrion for now.
And maybe there's an argument to
be said that if you stay and fight,
that could be more effective. But
I also liked the idea of, okay,
some people say stay, some people go,
some people write articles about it. Um,
some people talk about it on
social media, et Cetera, et cetera.
There were more than, there's
more than one way to skin
a cat, so to speak. So, uh,
I think we're all going to hit it from
different angles and see what happened.
But I do think that there is a,
a technological and business solution to
this and that's where I'm going to put
a lot of my energies,
although it's pretty bizarre.
I gotta I gotta show it around here,
which is a job unto itself, a tour.
We just got an offer last night to do
a live Reuben reports for all of April
taken me across America. I'll be in, uh,
Australia with Jordan for most of
February. I'm writing this book.
We're probably going to head back out on
the road in May and June with Jordan in
Europe. So there's a lot of
cooking and now I guess I'm
a tech guy as well. Uh, so,
you know,
we'll see what happens.
Shout outs to Jeffrey to gunner
and to Richard and a Mug for Jared.
You're getting a mug. Thank you very
much guys. Really appreciate it.
You guys are helping us do this thing
and uh, I hope, I hope it's, look,
if you care about these ideas, then I
guess it is worth it to you. Let's see,
a good luck on your endeavor of creating
a new platform. Thank you very much. Uh,
make a blockchain based payment service.
I can help hit me up.
So I'm talking to a lot of
people based on a well just,
I'm getting a lot of recommendations.
Let me say first about doing a lot of
this through blockchain and taking more
blockchain payments. So first
off, just on the blockchain front,
we are taking payments right now for uh,
we're taking bitcoin
payments@daverubin.com slash donate. Um,
and we've been doing pretty
nicely on there and you know,
it goes up and it goes down and it's
just sort of something to, to have. Um,
I think there were more options.
We're, we're looking into light coin,
we're looking into a theory and we're
looking into ripple and a couple of the
others, we're looking into some blockchain
based video stuff. I mean we're,
we're just scaling through all of this.
And I see when I do these videos now I'm
apparently a gajillion people that are
watching these things because then people
start slicing and dicing every word I
said. Reuben said this about that and
he said this thing about that thing.
And the other thing about
that, it's like, guys,
we're just trying to work this
thing through. You know what I mean?
It's a weird thing cause I have noticed
that the amount of hate that I'm getting
these days has really ramped
up and I don't really care.
It's like I mute or I
blocked these people.
I'll give you just going to
endlessly throw hate at me.
Like I don't care for you.
Really.
It's like if I was walking down the
street and somebody was like, Hey Ruben,
go fuck yourself. It's not like I'd
walk across the street and be like, oh,
should we talk about that? No. So I'm
not going to do it online either. Um,
but it's funny cause it's like I have
so much good stuff happening and show is
going great, like touring
and all this good stuff. Um,
and yet that isn't really what is
the marker of success in a weird way.
I see all these people writing about me
and doing videos about me lying about me
constantly. I'm like, Oh, if I'm somebody
that they're doing that stuff about,
I must really be a threat to these people.
I guess I am successful. So that's the,
that's actually a pretty good, all
right. Shout outs to Christopher, Joel,
David and Nicky and Alexander.
You're getting a mug. Here we go.
You've been signed Alexander.
Thank you very much. Okay. Uh,
good luck sticking it to the man. I closed
all patriots support. I appreciate it.
Are you coming to New
York City anytime soon?
So we just got this offer for live
Reuben reports as I said, uh, in a,
in April, basically the entire month. Um,
which will be pretty cool to be doing
the show in front of it would be theater
audiences, usually about a thousand
people. One of the shows is in New York.
I haven't signed on to the deal yet.
I got it late last night and I haven't
had a chance to fully dive into it,
but that could potentially
be in April. Um, let's see.
Just change my $5 to 25 bucks monthly.
Send me a medium.
Been funding for a few years and got
off the patriarch train before near.
Good luck. I appreciate
it. And uh, when you,
when you submit via paypal or,
or your credit card,
we have your email and then
we can figure out the sizes.
So that's how we do that. Greetings from
Argentina. I love what you're doing. Uh,
and what Jordan's doing.
My question is have you too
considered coming to South America?
So I don't know why the, the Jordan
toward didn't make it to South America.
I'm not sure. It's on the docket for what
we're thinking about in May and June.
I'll, I'll ask on that. I'm
actually not sure. Um, okay.
Shout out to Steve and to Maureen.
Thank you guys. Appreciate it.
Um, thoughts on Coinbase
economically, D platforming, Gab.
So yeah, I heard about this and
what's weird I guess, and again, I,
I don't know everything about Crypto,
but I know that Coinbase is one of
the places I have a coin base account
actually.
Uh,
Coinbase is one of the exchanges
where you can buy and sell crypto.
Apparently they booted Gab,
but not only do they boot Gab,
if I'm understanding this correctly,
they booted the private account of the
CEO of Gab, uh, Andrew something or other,
I think his name is. This strikes
me as, as particularly odd,
like unless they're doing
something illegal, but this is,
this is becoming increasingly the problem.
We're going to slowly watch all sorts of
maybe kind of potentially shady people.
And I'm not even saying that this guy is
a be pinned off and we're all going to
think, oh, if I don't say
anything, I'll be okay. I don't
say anything. I'll be okay.
But that's how it comes for
everybody because nobody stands up.
So I'm very proud to stand
up, uh, with Jordan and,
and see if we can figure this thing out.
Um,
so I'm not happy when I see any
of these d platforming issues. Uh,
I had lunch with Eric Weinstein yesterday
and one of the things that we were
talking about was that maybe
what the Internet needs,
and this is an interesting play on my, my
small government believes, is that, look,
I don't want the government telling
these companies to know, uh,
to telling them what they can do,
right? You all know that. Okay,
but maybe what we need on the
Internet is a public space.
So in other words, if everything's private
online right now, as it basically is,
you've got all these roads going in every
which direction everyone can be on any
of these platforms. The platforms can
get rid of anybody that they want,
but there's no public space.
And maybe what we need is a
public space that is based,
let's say it was made
in the United States.
The United States create some sort of
public space online that stands by the
principles of free speech and the
first amendment. And beyond that,
as long as you aren't doing anything
doing anything that is illegal in the
United States,
you can do whatever you want.
So think about it as like
just a public park, right?
So like if you're at a
cafe next to the park,
a crazy person can't walk in and start
screaming like they're allowed to kick
them out. And that's what
the private company could do.
If they don't want the person there,
they can kick them out.
But that at least we would have a public
space and public platform for people to
be able to do whatever they want.
That is based in American laws and,
and the free speech principles that,
that we all love.
I think there's some way that Pi could
actually sort of be for public funding
being for something like that.
That would actually be interesting
because in a weird way,
if we only have private things online
and then nothing's really private and I
think that that's what's
happening right now.
So there's something there I need to
think it through a little bit more. Um,
let's see.
Dave,
is there one particular rule out of
Jordan's book that helped you the most?
What are, that's a good question.
Um, man, well I tell you, I've,
you know, I've obviously heard Jordan
lecture about the book, you know,
a hundred some odd times. And you know,
some nights I've, I've said this before,
but some nights he does all the hill,
you know, lecture for an hour and a half,
about all 12 rules.
He'll hit all 12 some nights.
He picks three rules and he focuses
on them some nights. He does one rule,
some nights he does no rules and he talks
about what someone else that's on his
mind. Um, you know, I think
God,
is there one that's affected
me more than the others?
Well I, it's Cliche to say the one
about telling the truth. Right?
Cause like you should try to tell
the truth as much as you can.
I'm always trying to tell the
truth as much as they can.
So I don't think it's that, um, you
know, the one about petting a cat.
If you see a cat pet a cat, now I'm
allergic to cats. I don't like cats.
Don't pet cats in my estimation. But he
said, you can swap any animal for that.
I'm a dog guy,
but in effect,
what he's saying there is just
stop and smell the roses, right?
Just you know when things are going
well and you're in the thick of it,
like don't get so lost that
you don't remember to enjoy it.
And when things are going bad that there's
still some goodness out there kind of
and start, try to pause and remember
those things. So for me right now,
my life is moving very fast. I have very
little time to come up and breathe. My,
I tried to take a
vacation around Christmas,
the whole Patrion on thing happened
and I didn't get a vacation.
Like I haven't had a
lot of slow down time,
but try to take those little brief moments
when there's a little bit of quiet or
a little bit of something.
Uh,
I played my nine year old nephew and
NBA Two k on playstation four online the
other day.
Like just try to do some things to whether
it's petting a cat or petting the dog
or whatever it is to enjoy a little
of this, the craziness. All right.
Shout outs to bud, Rudy and Theresa.
David, you are getting a mug.
Thank you very much.
There you go.
David to David and Joe,
you're getting a mug.
Oh, I signed all these. Here we
go. Got Another one down here.
Thank you guys for the support.
It is really appreciated, uh,
on super chat. I found out about you via
Collin. Good luck on everything. Thanks.
So you're talking about column Moriarity
every uh, obviously I love Collin. Uh,
he's a great guy.
He's been through the outrage machine
and the mob and he has survived Collins
doing his podcasts,
sacred symbols with, uh,
with Chris Ragan who you guys may
know, who's also been on the show. Um,
and Collin staying on Patrion on. And as
I said, in no way do I judge him for it.
And in certain respects I think having
some of us on there and off their offers,
the best form of attack,
maybe having some of the guys stay on
there still allows for them to fight from
within. And maybe who
knows, maybe, you know,
between some of us go in and it's
almost saying that the Patriot people,
Jack Conti and Jacqueline Heart, the head
of trust and safety, there'll be like,
you know, maybe we should alter
the terms of service a little bit.
Not that I would trust them,
uh,
because obviously conti came in here in
lied directly to my face when he said
that, you know, you're not going to be
kicked off over speech, but you know,
it's just another way of
dealing with things. Everyone,
everyone does things a little
bit differently. You know,
unfortunately the way the
online conversation is,
it's like everyone wants to behave, force
everyone to behave the exact same way.
And if you do anything even a little
bit different, you're the enemy.
And it's just like, I don't think that
way and I'm not gonna live that way. Uh,
thanks to Alexander, to Douglas
and to David. Um, let's see,
uh, church, I'm Dave.
If Sargon had used actual slurs against
someone and not just use a slur to quote
someone's language back at them
and Patrion had banned them,
would you still have left?
That's a really good,
interesting philosophical
question. So, okay,
so the way for those of you that don't
know the wake Sargon was using the n word
in this specific video that was not
on Patrion and not even on his youtube
channel was he was basically using the
language of the all right against them.
He wasn't using the n word
as a pejorative. So your
question is a good one.
If he had used the n word in a,
in a racially offensive way,
would would this have resonated
with us the way that it did?
I don't know exactly. I don't. I, well,
I certainly wouldn't want to defend him
the way that I'm defending him right now.
Like let's say, let's think about it.
If it was a friend of yours, right?
Let's say you found out that a
friend of yours was truly a racist,
was running around calling people the n
word and it didn't like people because
of their skin color or
whatever that entails.
Like would you really want to defend them?
The answer's probably no.
You might want, you might want to
find out more about them and be like,
is this part of the person I knew
and whatever that is, but would,
would we have all,
I guess your question really is,
would we have seen this as the
opportunity to take a stand now if they,
if he had been using the n word as a
pejorative and in a racially offensive way
against specific people,
then it would have made this a little
more of a messy situation where,
where patriot, it would have more easily
been able to say, you're not on Etsy.
That would have not been on platform
also. Um, it would've made it messier.
I think that's the best I can say
short of being in the exact situation.
It would have made it
messier. Um, I'm for,
I'm for all people to be able
to say whatever words they want.
I'm not afraid of words. You can call
it. People call me all sorts of things.
You'd call me a faggot or whatever
you want to call me. I will survive.
I really will. It's crazy. Someone says
a word to me and I don't crumble. It's,
it's incredible. Um, but
at the end of the day,
the, I still believe that these
companies can do what they want.
What is the solution? Well, now I'm
coming around to this idea that a,
there's a technological solution,
that sort of decentralized solution,
but it's not just that,
it's also the fact that maybe
we need these public spaces.
So we're at an interesting spot to be in.
If you come from a classical liberal
or libertarian position where you don't
want the government doing things
that aren't within its purview,
that you might go, well, wait a minute.
This is actually a good use of government.
This is a good use of government dollars
to be. We are going to create spaces,
online platforms that allow people to
be involved in conversations that allow
people to be able to post video, to
interact. All of those things, uh,
that are public spaces that the only,
there isn't a 27 page terms of service
that you've got to look at with your
lawyer that nobody has before you clicked
accept that the only rules that you
will have to abide by are the rules
that you have to abide by as a citizen,
which are the rules of the constitution
and your local laws and things of that
nature. There's something to that and I
want to think about it a little bit more.
A reminder guys,
if you go to Dave rubin.com/donate
if you donate five bucks or above a,
I'm going to give you a live
shoutout 25 bucks or above.
You're getting one of the last
remaining monthly. By the way,
25 bucks or about monthly, you're getting
one of the last remaining Rubin report,
select tee shirts, which will never
be produced again and for $50 or more.
I will sign them up for you right now
and you get the t shirt. So there you go.
All right. Um, here have some money
since I'm no longer on Patrion.
Thank you very much. That was
from super chat. Um, okay.
Curious how you'll decide who will
be allowed to join the new platform.
Keep it open.
Verse limit extremists.
This is one of the many things
that we're discussing right now.
We are discussing all of this stuff.
Look, if we open it up to everybody,
well then you know what happens. You're
going to get all of the truly bad actors.
They're real racist and white supremacists
and Isis and all of the real bad guys
that everyone agrees are the
bad guys, you know, like that,
that are probably up to criminal
activity and all sorts of stuff.
Now as long as they're not doing
something specifically illegal,
I think there's an argument to be made
that they can be on there and express
their right to express themselves.
That may not be the platform
that we are going to build here.
We're really trying to
figure this out like that.
I'm not leading that
answer in any weird way,
like we're all having a sort
of internal debate about that.
Do we want to do something? Maybe the way
the Internet is the, the nature of the,
the future of the Internet is that not
everything should be so big and everybody
should be able to get on there and
fight with everybody. That may be,
it should be invite only or a sort of
white listed things, something like that.
So we're figuring out all of these things.
I think you guys know me,
my general position on this is I want
as little gatekeeping as possible.
I would rather have as
many voices as possible.
I would rather have for all the people
that have been banned on Twitter,
it's like I'd rather have all those
people back and if you don't like them,
you mute them or you block them
or you just ignore them. Um,
but this subjective way that they
do it is crazy. So it's like,
so it's like Sargon is also banned on
Twitter or Milo was banned on Twitter or
Alex Jones and his band on Twitter.
Okay fine. Twitter can do what it wants.
But at the same time say Farrakhan is
on Twitter, he said some he called Jews,
termites and what a Twitter do.
They took away his blue check,
but they left him on there.
So it's like you can stay on our platform
but we're not going to tell people who
you are. No, no, no. I guess
that's something or uh, you
know, Hamas is on there,
so you know,
like really awful groups are on there.
But we select basically if you're on,
if you're more on the right,
the groups that get booted. So it's
this selective enforcement and this,
this never ending a morphous terms of
service that seems to always hit people on
the right and not people on the left.
Look, if you're on the left right now,
anyone watching this or anyone
watching the test me right now,
anyone watching this,
go on Twitter and call whoever you want,
a white supremacist,
you will not be banned.
It's extremely damaging to call someone
a white supremacist. And, and it's,
and it's usually slander.
Um,
but you can do it and there's
no repercussions for it.
Now go on and call someone the n word.
Now I'm not saying do that.
I'm not saying do that,
but you get my point here is
that we've got a selected way.
We enforce these things.
These companies can selectively
enforce if they so choose.
But maybe we need an option
outside of these companies.
And that's what I'm saying about that.
Uh, shout out to Ryan and to Jord.
You're getting a Mug,
brother. Thank you very much.
Welcome aboard the future of the Internet.
Um,
okay. Um, let's see. Uh,
would you talk to Peter Schiff privately
about if and how to incorporate crypto
or a different payment system other
than cryptos? He's, uh, he's brilliant.
He's been on Joe Rogan's show a few times.
I think we've traded some emails over
the years and for some reason it didn't
work out. I'm not opposed to doing it. Um,
and I am exploring all sorts of
other financial options here.
We're trying to figure it out. That's,
that's what we're doing there. Uh,
get bitcoin, Jesus on the
show. I don't know who that is,
but seems like an interesting guy. Uh,
keep up the good work. Okay. Um, what,
what donated 25 on the website?
Need an extra large shirt.
Loved the content if they hate
you, you're doing good. Yeah,
I'm definitely coming around to
that one. It's like, all right,
you guys are going to spend all day,
like,
can you imagine somebody
like waking up and it's like,
why did Ruben do aren't alive stream?
What did he do? It's like, oh my God,
get a life. But that's more than
anything else. It's just like,
what are you doing with your life?
Um, okay. What are we doing here guys?
I'm giving away mugs $50 and above
monthly at Ruben [inaudible] dot com.
I'm going to sign it for you or a Dave
ruben.com/donate 25 bucks or above.
You're going to get a tee shirt. Uh,
we're going to send it out to you.
That's monthly and five bucks or above.
Uh,
I'm giving shout outs to anyone that
jumps in. I am at the [inaudible]. Uh,
I'm at the Ontario Improv tomorrow and
with Bret Weinstein and I am at the
Irvine Improv on January 30th
within IDW member. Tbd. All right.
Keep the questions flying in. Guys. A
shout out to Joshua. Thank you very much.
Welcome aboard. Uh, this is on
super chat. Shout out to CBD,
American Shaman of San Antonio.
Are you a or are they selling CBD
legally in Texas right now? Well,
I guess CBD can be sold.
This is where I'm always a little
confused about the CBD situation. Um,
but I haven't,
you know,
I have a friend who heard her shoulder
and she's been using medicinal CBD, but,
but out of cannabis.
And I think maybe if it's in Texas,
you're getting them out of hemp. Um,
I totally crossing this thing up. Uh,
but anyway, it had a really bad shoulder.
She had been used as in medicinal CBD.
It seems to be working. So there you go.
There's a little CBD, something for you.
Keep up the good work. Another one
of those. Okay. I will. Um, oh,
here's a whole bunch more. I
didn't scroll properly. Um,
which crazy lefty would you most like
to most like to interview and I'd love
among, all right, well you can get
a mug if you donate a over a day,
ruby.com/donate which crazy lefty.
Let's remove the word crazy for a second.
There are plenty of lefties I would
love to sit down with. Obviously,
I'd love to sit down with Bernie and
Elizabeth Warren and certainly Alexandria
Cortez. Um, I would love to sit, you know,
I offer it up to the
celebrity types all the time.
So like a rob rider or a Judd Apatow
or Sarah Silverman or Chelsea handler.
I'll talk to any of these people.
Look as long as you don't
attack me personally or,
or other people that I know personally.
Like if you're, if your basic, um,
behavior is decent and we can agree on
what a conversation is, I'll talk to you.
But if you're going to attack people,
if you're gonna lie about
people and all those things,
I just don't want to do it. It's just
not a game I want to be. I want to play,
go play that game with somebody
else. Um, okay. Where are we? Um,
I love that hyperspace painting behind
your couch. Keep it up. Oh yeah.
If you saw the, uh, was, did
I do both of those in there?
I think I did both of the conversations
with Jordan. That's in my, uh,
in my living room. It's a huge
five foot by six foot, uh,
hand painting of hyperspace. So
Millennium Falcon going into hyperspace.
That was done by Caitlin, Janet, by the
way. I think her website is Kaitlyn rose,
janet.com. She also did the
painting that's behind me right now.
The painting that's over there and a
whole bunch of other stuff in my house.
She's really phenomenal,
versatile actress, actress.
She's probably an actress to,
uh, artists who can do almost
anything. Let's see. Um,
what are your thoughts? Uh,
wait, have you heard of,
have you heard the beauty and the Beta
podcast where a caller mentioned is
making an alternative to Patriot
and he mentions you by name?
It might be a good idea to get in
contact with them. I haven't heard it.
I did that podcast once.
That's a Matt Christiansen, um,
who's been a huge ally in this,
in this Patrion, uh, fiasco. Um,
but I haven't heard of
that one specifically,
but I can't tell you that I've had a
bajillion people just reach out to me.
Here's a, you know, people are just coming
up with ideas too, which is also cool.
And it also shows you that this thing is
going to be solved by human ingenuity,
not by the government or not by
just like the same old people.
Like I don't think it's going to be the
same old tech people that solve this,
right? Like I actually think it's going
to be new people that are doing it.
And I wish I had time to
respond to everybody that's
reaching out to me and all
that other stuff. Uh, shout
outs, if you donate it,
Dave rubin.com/donate a.
Okay.
And there's a shout out for Brooke. I
made that. What happened quick. Okay,
let's see. Uh, this is from
superchat. Coinbase is problematic,
but you can still buy crypto on their
platform and then move it to another
wallet before sending it.
Sending to support to Gab.
Crypto is still the best option
for censorship resistance. Uh,
I also sent you $10 in Bitcoin.
Well, thank you for that. Um, yeah,
so from what I understand,
if I'm really grasping this all property,
you could properly, you could still
forget putting gab aside for a second. Um,
just the principle would be that you
could still use Coinbase because you can
use it as your wallet and then you can
put your crypto at wherever else you want
to put it. I got one of
these, it's called the ledger.
And that's where like a physical device
that I have where I'm now keeping, uh,
the crypto.
So we're truly were truly just trying to
figure this out alongside of you guys.
A mug for Zachary, you're getting
a Mug, Zachary. Here you go.
Oh, and somebody told me, but
please confirm this before I, uh,
before I ruin this way, somebody told
me that. So if you put these in the,
in the washing machine, sometimes
the signature is going to be written.
Even though I'm using,
I'm using extreme fade resistant sharpie.
Um, but it could wash off
in the, in the dishwasher.
Somebody told me that if you bake them up,
but I can someone confirm this for me.
If you bake the Mug, that the
signature, uh, will stay in there.
So I guess we will see about that.
Um,
the meaning of life is to give life
meaning therefore isn't the key to life
giving big love to you and Jordan.
That's very profound.
The meaning of life is to live it deleted
as I said it. All right, there you go.
Um, let's see. Yo Dave, crazy
idea. Invite Joe Rogan on the show.
He always does the interviewing.
So I think it would be cool
to have him as the subject.
Plus I think you guys would
get along for the most part.
Well I've been on Joe
Rogan's show three times.
I was on there the last time was uh,
maybe may or June or so.
I had just blown it, flown in from Atlanta
that morning. I think that was may. Um,
I love Joe. He knows he's welcome anytime
the guy is beyond, beyond, beyond busy.
He doesn't do that many shows. He did
do. Ben Shapiro is a Sunday special,
which I gave him a little shit for, uh,
because he hadn't done my show yet. Uh,
but I'm sure at some point it will
be here. So Joe, if you're watching,
cause I'm sure you're just sitting
around watching these. Uh, please,
you're welcome on my show anytime.
He knows he's on welcome.
Anytime a shoutout to Othman.
Thank you very much.
A patron and canceling my
Patriot on account. Now.
You were the only person I was
contributing to a, so thank you very much.
We'll start up on your website a very
soon. Um, another one on Patrion.
I set up a recurring contribution
directly on your website and I'm going to
cancel my account with patron.
Thank you for making me aware and leading
the way from my small act of standing
up to intolerance and oppression. Thank
you very much. Uh, another one on Patrion.
I just now canceled my pledge to the
Rubin report from my Patriot on account.
Okay. Did somebody already get
the old coffee table? Oh yeah.
So I mentioned in the live stream the
other day that we've got our, you know,
this is our new set, so we've got our
old set, which are the old chairs.
We've got to have the old guest chairs,
we've got the old coffee table,
we've got the old, a lot of the old
trinkets and things that are around here.
Some of the old artwork.
I thought maybe if people make us like
some really great offers on that stuff,
as long as we're raising funds right now,
people could do that.
So we did get a couple of offers.
They were, they were kind of low,
like it just wasn't worth parting
with them at that level. Um, so yeah,
if you want to make a great offer,
you could just email us
contact@rubenreport.com. Um, as I said,
we've got to have the guest chairs.
I'm not getting rid of my red chair cause
I still use that when we do the three
ways in here.
Um,
but we got the coffee table and a couple
of other things so you can check that
out. Um, we'll your old shows
be accessible somewhere.
I'm behind in my recent retirement was
going to afford me time to catch up.
That's from patrion.
I think what you're referring to is that
you watched the show in the Patriot and
feed. So to be clear, 100% of our content,
especially if you're
watching this right now, um,
you're watching this via youtube.
The video might be in the Patriot on fee,
but this is all on youtube.
100% of our content will remain free.
It will always be free.
I am not putting content behind a paywall.
The only thing we've ever done behind
a pay wall as a couple like behind the
scenes things or I ask our guests an
extra question or something like that.
We've never put any interviews behind
a paywall. I am not gonna do that.
I'm not starting a separate show behind
a pay wall or anything along those lines.
As long as we can afford to produce the
show as we're doing it and hopefully
expand a bit and keep doing everything
we're doing and I can keep working on
other projects, which can also
help fund all this. Um, you will,
you will be able to see
everything we've ever done.
So right now if you're watching this
person that asked me that question,
every video that we have ever posted
anywhere, it's all on youtube right now.
Every interview we've ever done so you can
catch it there. Uh, shout outs to Tony,
Charles and Gary. I appreciate it.
Thank you. Um, oh, I get this one a lot.
What are some books that
changed your life? Loved the
show and everything you do,
Dave.
So I,
I'll give the two books that I most give
and then I'm going to start coming up
with a newer answer for this on my bed
right now on my nightstand right now,
I keep a copy of on liberty by John Stuart
Mill. You can read it in a day. It's,
it's that thick and it's just a wonderful
explanation of the individual and what
liberty and freedom are.
And it's a great explainer of sort
of classical liberalism as I see it.
And then the other book that I would
recommend, which I should have on set, um,
but I don't cause all the books that we
have on set actually are our books of
former guests. And I wish I
could've interviewed this guy,
but he died about maybe 15 years ago.
No, he died. I know the year he died.
He died I think in [inaudible] 97 so,
wow. 21 years ago, if I'm not mistaken.
Carl Sagan,
who was the incredible scientists
who did a cosmos, the book and the,
and the television show. His last book
was called billions and billions. Uh,
he actually died before it finished.
And then his wife Andrea and
who's also a professor at Cornell,
she had to finish it for them. And it
was just sort of a broad explanation.
It was a, it was a little bit easier
to read than some of his other books,
which were a technical, although he was
an incredible explainer of science. Um,
it's a broad sort of explainer about the
way the world is and the way he sees it
and when he sort of sees
the future looking like,
and it really just like sparked so
much of the things that I care about.
I mean a shout out to Steven and a
Mug for Tom. Thank you very much guys.
Appreciate it. There you go, Tom. Um,
let's see.
Uh,
why do you think crypto would help be
specific? It's not a silver bullet.
If you can't convert tender into crypto,
it's useless. Too many hoops to jump.
I'm not totally sure I
understand the question.
If you can't convert tender into crypto,
it's useless.
But you can right now you
can buy crypto using tender.
So am I am I am not
understanding the question?
Maybe I'm not understanding the question.
If you want to clarify the question a
little bit more. Um, okay. Let's see.
Um,
Dave,
you should consider inviting the
author Robert Greene on the show.
He's in California would be a great fit.
I'm actually not totally sure. I who I,
who that is. So if you want to write a
little bit more, I will check it out. Um,
okay.
Let's see.
Here's a second emphatic load for
getting in touch with Peter Schiff.
A crypto currency backed by gold.
His thing is the most promising
political solution in my view. All right,
noted. I will, uh, let's, let's
put Peter Schiff on the list. Guys.
If he's not on there already, he
must be on there already. Um, okay.
How long do we got here? What time is it?
Three 37. I've got 23 minutes left guys.
Uh, this is, I promise you this is the
second to last fundraiser of the year.
Even though we're in the
first week of the year,
or when we're in a week of the day of
the year, a week and a day of the year,
we're going to do one more of these.
On January 15th I'm going
to take my computer,
I'm going to walk over to the camera
right over there and you're going to watch
me delete patron.
You know,
I shouldn't tell you something
about what's going on with
Patrion right now. So,
um, so you know, I've done obviously
a bunch of videos about leaving.
I have sent emails to my email
list about leaving. I have,
we posted on Patrion that we're leaving.
I've put it on Instagram. I mean,
wherever you can put it, I put it. Um,
but right now, despite all of that,
we still have about 2000 people
that are paying monthly on Patrion.
And I think if I'm not mistaken or
last I checked the day or so ago,
there was still about $14,000 a
month of paying people on Patriot,
meaning that if I didn't cancel patrion
they would all be charged again on
February 1st.
So it's sort of interesting because it's
like people buy into something and then
you may not pay attention to the day to
day. You may have unsigned for, uh, uh,
an email list,
let's say.
And if you're not paying attention on
Twitter and you don't check youtube for a
couple of weeks or this or
that or the other thing,
it's like you may not even know. So
it's such a weird thing. It's like,
I'm going to say goodbye to this money.
That in effect is like free money,
but obviously I don't think it would be
right to say I'm leaving and then not
leave just to collect on that.
So we're obviously not going to do that,
but it'll be an interesting
thing to see how much,
how many people and how much is
left in the account when I do this,
a week from today. Uh, that would
be a, that would be interesting.
Let's see. Um, shout out
Henrik. Thank you very much.
Appreciate it. Uh, all
right, 20 minutes left guys.
Dave rubin.com/donate get yourself a mug.
Get yourself a Reuben select tee shirt.
They're right here.
I'm wearing one right now. I'm
wearing a medium, by the way,
if that gives you any perspective on
sizing, they're quite comfortable.
It's not like one of
those crappy tee shirts.
You know those crappy tee shirts you
put on them? They feel like cardboard.
It is not that. It feels nice. I think
you'll like it. Uh, my dad often,
where's the t shirt? When he's wandering
around town and people say item,
I want to take selfies with my dad. That's
very weird. But people wanted to do it.
Okay. Let's see what's going on here. Um,
I got get bitcoin. Jesus is on the
show. I did that one already. Uh,
when you inviting Matt Christiansen
Christiansen on the show,
so that was mentioned already about
Matt. Yeah, we'll do it at some point.
I think he lives in like Montana
or Wyoming or something. Um,
I don't know how often he gets out to la.
You know,
we can do these things by Skype,
but I'm really trying not to do them
unless it's either like a s a really big
guest or somebody that's international
that really just can't make it here.
But if it's someone in the
states that's mobile or whatever,
I'd much rather do it in person.
Um, also right now, just Fyi,
um, we're booked out all through
January. We've got a good Julian shows,
we're taping a ton of stuff.
Um, so really cool stuff. Oh,
and tomorrow we taped this
already. I've got an interview, uh,
with behavioral scientists,
Jeffrey Miller, who is a really,
really site psychological behavioral
scientists. Jeffrey Miller. Really,
really interesting guy.
It was,
it was one of my favorite interviews I've
done in awhile and I think we've been
on a nice, a nice run here. So that'll
be a part one of that be up tomorrow. Um,
let's see. I'll donate a hundred
bucks if you answer these questions.
Do you think you will shave your
beard soon? The answer is no.
I do love the beard and
people love the beard.
Everyone that I meet everywhere I go,
they want to touch the beard.
They love the beard. So I'm not going
to shave the beard anytime soon.
Although when I got the beard,
which was not last August,
but the August before when I did my thing
off the grid and I just grew and grew
it and grew it, and then I trimmed it a
little bit before I came back on camera.
I thought I was going to maybe
have it for like a month or so,
but then everyone loved it and I really
like it. So I'm going to keep the beard.
And also, do you like Jordan Peterson
better with a beard or without a beard?
I liked him better with a beard.
I like them better with the beard.
I think there's something
about, you know, his,
there's something about his persona that
a beard fits it, like his grain beard.
Um, you know, he, he's, he's sort of
the older wise professor. Um, he's,
he's mentoring or helping a
lot of people, um, you know,
get their shit together and
get their lives together.
There's something that fits
with a guy in a beard. Right?
Like if this was a movie,
like he's the older professor with a
beard that's like teaching people some
stuff.
It seems like he would have a beard
that's like a Harry Potter or star wars
thing. He would have a beard. Uh,
when are you coming to Brazil?
No plans at the moment. Yeah. As I said,
I don't know why we're not doing much in
South America. Um, on the Jordan tour.
I'll, I'll look into that a little
bit more. I'm actually not sure.
Shout outs to George,
to nick and to Matt.
You guys sound like you could be a
boy band and a, and a mug for Dennis.
Welcome aboard, Dennis. There you go.
That's a fine signature right there.
You got it, Dennis. There you go.
Um, okay. What else is going on here?
So, wait, what else can I
tell you? There's been so
many things happening at once.
It's like, it's hard to keep my head on
straight in the midst of all of this. Um,
oh, you know, I got a question
for you guys actually,
because you guys often give me some
good advice on some things. So I've, uh,
I've shown her on video a couple of times,
but my dog, Emma, she's 14 years old.
I love, love, love this dog. Uh,
I got her when she was two years old.
She's actually from New Orleans,
from Hurricane Katrina. And when the
dog's got split up after the hurricane,
they were sent all over the country and
I assume all over the world actually.
They actually found Emma in a box.
Uh,
and she had given birth
during the hurricane and she
was nursing three puppies
and she was deathly sick because they're
drinking all sorts of oils and in the
water and all sorts of chemicals
and grow stuff that's in the water.
Though the puppies were actually
healthy. She was really sick. Uh,
the animals got sent all over the place.
She had a collar with no tags,
so they didn't know what her name was.
So she's actually had three names in
life because when she was in New Orleans,
she had a name.
We don't know what that was.
Then we got her at the humane
society of New York, um,
which is a great little non kill shelter.
It's,
it's not associated as far as
I know with the Ma, the uh,
national humane society.
It's just the one in New York City.
It's on 57th street between
first and second, I think.
And we got her there and they had named
her Paisley and then when we got her,
we named her,
Emma and I had had her the
first day I'm walking her,
I got her walking her first day in
central park and this woman comes up to me
and says, is that Paisley from the
humane society? I said, yeah. She said,
this is her son Bernard. And
they went crazy. They sniff,
bought like only a mother and son
could. And you know, there was at,
we used to get Bernard and
Emma together often. Anyway,
Bernard ended up moving to North Carolina.
But how bizarre.
Like they went all over the country and
Bernard and Emma both ended up on the
upper west anyway and it was about
14. Right now. She is the greatest,
happiest one, most wonderful
dog. We get people in,
all my guests come into my
home because my studio is here.
People that don't like dogs
end up absolutely loving
her. Uh, but at 14, she's,
she's not a a young pup anymore.
And I've noticed that she's a little
stiff in mostly in the back hips lately.
So I'm thinking that maybe she has a
little bit of arthritis or something.
So I'm looking at all sorts of, um, uh,
supplements and things
that we can give her.
And I know that they want you to take,
it's a little counterintuitive.
You'd think you'd want them to
rest more if they're in pain,
but they actually tell you that an older
dog should be walked more if they have
arthritis cause that keeps them
loose. Um, we can give them clues,
glucosamine and Chondroitin.
Try saying that three times fast and a
whole bunch of other stuff in massages,
heat pads. But if any of you
have any great ideas on that,
I would love to hear them, so
please let me know. Um, okay. Uh,
shout out to Pamela.
Thank you very much and a Mug for Mike.
Thank you very much guys.
Appreciate it.
You're keeping the Rubin
report totally independent.
I should mention actually what that
means when I say we're completely
independent.
We are 100% independent period.
I am the boss. The buck stops with me.
That might be good. That might be bad.
I think it's pretty good. Um, but we, we
treat all our, all of our employees great.
You know, we take care of 100% of
health insurance. We give Nice bonuses.
I try to let everybody be as,
as free as they can be,
as long as they're doing their job
and we get that respect back. We,
we've got a great little operation
here that I'm super proud of.
And when I say we're independent, we
have no, it's my production company.
We run it as we see fit. The chances I'm
ever going to fire myself. Pretty slim,
I guess anything could happen. Um, but
we're free to do what we think is right,
which is why when I'm getting
these offers from these networks,
it's like it would take something
crazy and I'm not even using this as a
negotiating tool.
It's like it would take something crazy
for me to have a boss and not be in a
studio in my home and all of the things
like we really did this thing right
somehow and knock on wood,
we can keep doing it.
A shout out to sh to Chaz
and a shout out to Louis. Um,
and just a reminder,
we've got about 15 minutes left that one
week from today on January 15th we will
be doing a live stream.
You will watch me delete Patriana alive.
I'm going to bring my computer right
up to that camera right there and we're
going to do it live a patriot
and really proud of you Dave.
There aren't many willing people willing
to stick their necks out the way you
and Mr. Peterson or doing 2019 is going
to be an exciting year to say the least.
We will definitely be
switching contributions over
Dave rubin.com/donate all the
best. Thank you very much. Um,
someone else on Patrion it's not so much
that we are not paying attention to the
day to day.
I am hoping that Patrion figures this out.
What they did for independent voices was
nothing short of amazing and I'd hoped
to be a creator myself.
The they're the only game in town sort of,
and I want them to come to their senses
and rethink their casual disregard for
free speech.
That's totally legit.
And that's why I said for my
friends that are staying on Patrion,
I get it for someone like,
like right now,
like the idea that let's
say Colin for example,
column Moriarty who's obviously been on
the show and it's a good buddy of mine,
for those of you that are canceling
patron patrion because of me,
the idea that some of you might fund
Collin as well and now he's not going to
get that. That obviously it
doesn't make me happy in any way.
It actually upsets me,
but I think everyone just has to do what
they think is right. Like at the end,
it's on you and you have to
decide what to do look like.
I suppose there's probably some people
that'll stay on there for Colin and then
donate separately for me.
You know, it's everyone,
everyone or screw both of us want or
whatever you think is right there.
There you go. Shout outs to Lucille, to
Robert and to Dimitri. Thank you guys.
Um,
beautiful story about Emma.
Dave also IX to explain my last comment.
Robert Green is the author of 48 laws of
power. You'd really love his stuff. Uh,
let's get the book. Can somebody write
that down? We'll, we'll get the book.
There we go and see what
happens there. Keep it up. Dave,
please donate my tee shirt.
Um,
I don't know if you're saying you're
donating a tee shirt to us or something
else, but thank you. Um,
I've spent a thousand plus hours
building a Patriana alternative with
anticensorship features in the past year.
What would be the best way to get
in touch and present it to you guys?
So getting all sorts of offers like this
and it's a little hard to track like
who's legit,
who isn't.
I've had some phone calls where people
that I think have been really interesting
and some kind of go nowhere.
Uh, contact@rubenreport.com
is the best way to do it.
My guys kind of go through it and the,
and the most important ones get to me.
And then if, if you're, if you're
really onto something here, I hope so.
And then we, you know, we do a zoom or a
Skype or take a call and go from there.
A super chat. I appreciate
your willingness to stand
up. Thank you very much. Um,
super chat.
The government slash payment processors
can stop you using crypto if they really
want to, especially the
ones with transparency built
in like bitcoin. So this,
I need to learn more about
this. I fully admit that. Like,
I don't fully understand
how the government,
if you were doing all the transactions
were on Crypto, were crypto based,
how would the government be tracking that?
And I guess they could track
if they had the specific, um,
bitcoin number or the wallet number,
Wallet Address,
they could track what's going in there.
I need to learn a little bit
more about this. Guys, I'm,
you're watching me do some of this stuff
on the fly. Like that's just the truth.
Uh, shout out to David. There
you go. Um, oh, you know,
speaking of doing some stuff on the fly,
something funny happened the other day,
so I did this live stream just like this.
And you know,
I'm taking questions right.
And you guys can see these
questions are just flying in, right?
And my guys color code them sometimes
if they think something's like
particularly important
for me to get to or,
or that I need to read it
quicker or whatever it is. Right.
Um, and so the other day I took, I don't
know, I took 50 questions. I have no idea.
And I'm just reading them on the
fly. I'm, they're not censoring them.
And then someone asked me something
about Brazil and I said one little thing
about how I need to know
about and I need to know more.
And then all of these
people started writing.
All these articles are doing these videos
about how I'm backing a dictator in
Brazil and I'm a fascist. And the rest
of it, it's like, man, like Bill Kristol,
formerly of the weekly standard,
which just folded,
he retweeted somebody saying
something about me. And it's like,
what are you people talking about? I said,
one sentence in a two hour live stream,
you're taking it totally out of context.
And I admitted I need to
know more about the topic.
Like this sort of desire to
destroy everybody. It's like,
it's going to destroy you guys.
It ain't going to destroy me.
It's going to destroy you guys.
And deservingly. So, um, let's see.
Um,
Dave,
is the new platform going to be 100%
geared towards free speech or is it going
to be an echo chamber? I promise you
it is not going to be an echo chamber.
As I've said, we're trying to figure out
what the parameters around that mean.
Is this an absolute place for everyone?
I mean,
I can be very clear. I don't want
people doing criminal activity.
I don't want child porn on there.
I don't want terrorist activity on there.
So an absolute free speech space
within the content confines of the law.
My goal is yes, but we have to
figure out exactly what that,
what that means and we're working
on it. Uh, all right guys,
we've got 10 minutes left.
So Dave rubin.com/donate you guys
are the lifeblood of the show.
You've already shown up for me
here today as you have last time.
I promise you we're only doing one more.
Are these this entire year we're knocking
them out by January 15th we will not
do any sort of fundraising for the rest
of the year. We're doing well. We've,
we've obviously, we took a huge hit on
Patrion and I'm, I'm now forcing it and,
but we're making up a nice
amount of it on our own website.
Dave rubin.com/donate I'm,
it's a short stop gap measure of
getting rid of the Middle Guy.
If you donate 50 in the next 10 minutes,
I'm going to sign the
Ruben Report Mug for Ya.
If you donate 25 monthly
in the next 10 minutes,
I'm going to send you this tee shirt. And
if it's you 50, you get the t shirt too.
Okay, let's see. Um, find a chiropractor.
It saved my boy's life. Oh, I think you're
talking about your dog. All right. Yeah.
Oh, find a dog. Find a dog
chiropractor. It saved my boy's life.
Yeah. Um, yeah, I read that there
are actual dog chiropractor,
so I may take her to one of
those. We'll see about that. Um,
Dr Jon Bergmann studies on reversing
arthritis may help you with Emma.
As a side note, Dr. Joseph
Dispenza is a great guest choice.
So I'll look and I'll look into both of
those. Can you guys write those down? Uh,
thank you guys for that. I really
appreciate it. Um, let's see.
I'm a conservative and
I just bought a Mug,
but I wanted to give the Mug to a liberal
teacher of mine because your show gave
us common ground. Could you
sign it for her? That's awesome.
I can email you the info. Yes,
I'd be happy to do that. Helen,
we'll keep an eye out. So
email us, contact that Ruben,
report.com remind us about this and I
will sign it directly to her and you can
give it to her. That's what it's all
about. That's what it's all about.
People don't hate each other for the
most part. Like there are good liberals,
there are good conservatives.
There are even good progressive's I
think their ideas are all terrible,
basically. Right? Like you
guys know that. I don't,
that doesn't mean I think they're
all terrible people are, are, are,
are many of them I think
confused sort of logically and,
and um, and morally at, at
a certain level. Uh, yes,
I think so, but I don't think
they're inherently bad people.
Do I think that they think that
they're doing the right thing. Yes.
I think those things are the wrong things,
but that's why we got to care about facts.
So it's like when,
when AOC the other day she said
this thing about, you know,
too many people get hung up on on facts
and making sure everything's exactly
right as opposed to what's morally right.
What,
that's a pretty dangerous thing to say
because we all have different morals.
One of the topics we've spent in
the last year talking about most,
here's where to morals come from
and the difference where, you know,
Sam Harris says morals can
come from facts that you,
that are sort of right in front of you
and we can figure out what we can derive
value and meaning from.
Fact.
Some people Ben say and and Jordan would
say that comes from a Judeo Christian
ethic.
It doesn't matter what the answer is,
but the point is we believe
different things or moral,
but I don't want politicians
who were on a moral crusade.
I want politicians who look
at the government, they go,
this should be as least intrusive as
possible and we're going to get out of the
way and we're going to
let people live freely.
And that's going to be a little
messy and it's going to be,
not everyone's going to
get whatever they want,
but we're not gonna keep taking from
everybody to give to some and we're not
gonna. Um, just, we're not
going to be involved in every
facet of everyone's life.
Most bad things that have happened in
the course of time have been done by
government and we have to really
remember that. Okay. Shout out to Elisa.
There you go. Um, all right guys,
we got six minutes left. Give me some
good questions to end up strong on.
Uh,
best
of luck, Dave and other best
of luck. We got a whole bunch
of best deluxe. Um, okay.
Do you like many are chasm in Libertarian,
political philosophy,
a nightwatchman state or mini are chasm
many or chasm I guess is a model of a
state whose,
who only functions,
who's only functions are to provide
citizens with the military. The police,
the courts, thus protecting
them from aggression, theft,
breach of contract and fraud and
enforcing property laws. I mean,
that's not that far from what an
ideal libertarian state would be.
So I would need to know what do you mean,
how is that different than what just a
basic libertarian state would be? I mean,
I'm for, I'm for and as much
as possible, the states,
each individual state
deciding what it wants to do.
If it wants to tax high or tax low,
and that may be,
that's going to either bring
in business or lose business.
I'm for states deciding whether they want
marijuana to be legal or not and maybe
that's going to bring people in and
help the economy or maybe it's going to
force certain people to leave,
um,
for states deciding how much tax money
they want to take to put into education
versus whether they want to,
uh,
put it into funding a baseball stadium
or whatever else. I want that experiment,
that incredibly beautiful American
experiment of testing this and that and
seeing what works and seeing where people
move and where they stay away from. Uh,
and where freedom prospers
and where people can make
the most out of their lives
and in what laws cause people to leave.
That that experiment is awesome to me.
And I'm for anything that
would lead to more of that.
So what you just laid out there for me
is pretty congruent with most of the
things that I believe. Um, but I, I
would need to know a little bit more. Um,
let's see. Super Chat. Yossi being a
patrion being a patron isn't enough.
What am I buying here?
I don't know that you're buying anything,
but it has been nice getting
to know you a little bit. That,
that is actually one of the things.
One of the things is that I've been
able to meet a lot of these patron, uh,
people and I've had dinner with some
people and when I was on the road with
Jordan, I would get coffee with
people and chat with people.
There's something cool happening here.
There's something cool. All right,
we've got four minutes left people.
These are your last chances right now
during this live stream to get the mug or
the t shirt. I'm going to
sign mugs. How many more here?
I've got four in this box right now.
Can we get rid of all these four?
I got a of your box right here, but I've
got four remaining. And you know what,
if you do it for these last four,
cause we got four minutes left.
I got four mugs for these law.
Anyone else that gets on until
we shut down in four minutes?
I'll actually put your name on it too.
There you go. Uh, rude. Uh, Dave Rubin,
[inaudible] dot com slash donate 50 bucks
monthly. You're going to get the mug.
I'm going to put your name on it and
you're going to get the t shirt and you're
going to feel good about
yourself. We should be selling
totes. Okay. Uh, all right,
Tanner and Eric, I'm writing your
name. There you go. Tanner and Eric,
I don't know if you guys were signing
up before I did it, but Tanner,
you're getting a mug.
Tanner,
I even put an exclamation point
after your name. That's exciting.
And Eric with a c. K the rare c.
K. Eric. All right, very good.
Eric,
you're getting a mug.
Eric.
Eric,
you got a comma I gave. I gave the other
guy a, uh, an exclamation point. Brandon.
Thank you very much.
All right guys,
getting rid of these last couple of
mugs right here. Dave ruby.com/donate.
We've got three minutes left. I talked
a lot today. I mean, try to imagine.
I did. I did two full on interviews. Then
I did a half hour interview. Then I did,
I started the morning at 7:00 AM with
a radio station and, um, Altoona,
Pennsylvania, I think, which actually
was totally fun. Um, let's see why. Oh,
this is a great question.
Why is the Reuben,
we're based out of California if that
state's economic and political climate is
as bad as conservatives say. Is
it exaggeration now? Um, well,
I don't think it's as bad. So first
off, the taxes here are in sane.
They're absolutely insane.
Now, I do have a business here,
so I'm able to write off a lot of stuff,
right?
So if we buy a whole bunch of bugs,
um,
we were able to write that off as
a business expense, obviously. Uh,
there's some other things that we're
able to write off that, you know,
business expenses when we buy equipment
and computers and things of that nature.
Um, so that helps a little bit on
the tax front. Um, why is it here?
I mean the main reason it's here
is that in La specifically is um,
that will a,
I moved to La,
it'll be six years in February
and when I moved to La, um,
it was sort of at the beginning of all
of this and I was just trying to get a
gig that I thought was cool and
whatever. I hadn't really, um,
sort of figured all this stuff out. What
I would say now is a, I mean first off,
so cow la, the weather is great. Like
it is 80 and sunny almost every day.
The worst day in cal is like the best
day almost everywhere else instead of San
Diego. But you're going to pay for that
because a lot of people want to live here
obviously. But, but that's
not eight, although I do enjoy
the weather for sure. The,
the real thing that keeps me
here right now is that, um,
there really is a nice thing
growing in Los Angeles,
a nice sort of center,
right? Classical, liberal,
Libertarian, conservative thing.
Rowing right here in la. I mean, look,
Ben Shapiro's here, Peter Teal just
moved down here. A Dennis Prager is here.
Um, but then there's other people that
aren't, don't necessarily fit into that.
Sam Harris is here.
I mean there's,
there's a lot of people in the
Los Angeles area, you know,
because the thing is that as politics,
as politics collide more with media,
right?
And his politics becomes more invested
in what's going on with the digital world
and youtube and all that.
Well now and La is the home of
entertainment and now politics is kind of
becoming entertainment.
Now.
That may be terrible for the
longterm health of the country,
but it's something that's happening
right now. So I think this, the,
the whole gestalt of that, I would say
is the reason that I'm here just stalled.
Good word, by the way. I'm all
right guys. We got one minute left.
How many more mugs am I
going to get rid of? Uh,
we will be doing another one of these
on January 15th when I will be, uh,
shutting down Patrion on live right here.
Uh, it's Dave Ruby. Com slash donate.
And uh,
here's what we'll do just in case you
were about to sign on right now because it
is four o'clock and I got to go, I think
the Tucker guys waiting for me outside.
Uh, anyone that donates in the
next 10 minutes till four 10.
We're going to shut the stream in a sec,
but if you don't eat in the next 10
minutes, uh, we'll, and you get the mug.
I'm going to put your name
on the Mug itself anyway,
we'll do another one of these next week.
We got Jeffrey Miller on tomorrow. Um,
we've got another bunch of cool shows
coming up over the rest of the month.
Then I hit Australia for most
of February with Jordan. Uh,
then I'm back here in March and we're,
we're already,
we're like overbooked already,
but we'll leave some room in case
some interesting things pop up.
Then I may take the Ruben
report on the road for April.
I got to look at that deal and see
where we're at on that. Then Jordan,
I may hit the road again or it sounds
like we are a for May and June back to
Europe and uh, yeah, let's
just keep going. Right.
Why not when he got better
to do so. Uh, thank you guys.
Thank you everybody that just donated.
You guys are the lifeblood of this thing.
You're keeping it going. Uh,
we're, we're going to be okay.
Like if we don't get any more donations,
we are going to be okay.
But the more we get, we can keep growing
and expanding and all that stuff. But,
but truly,
when I,
when I said we were leaving Patrion I
did not know what was going to happen.
Like I didn't know if we said,
okay, well people go to our website.
Like I didn't know if we were gonna
wake up and it was going to be like 15
people went there and we got a
couple hundred bucks. I'm like,
I've got to lay off. People are like,
figure out something else to do. Um,
but you guys have shown up. You really
have. It's, it's, it's incredible.
It's humbling. It's awesome. You
make me want to be a better man.
I am looking forward to seeing some of
you guys tomorrow night at the Ontario
Improv in so cal with Bret Weinstein.
January 30th at the Irvine Improv.
January 29th. I'm at cal state.
Uh, ah, I'm blank. And where am I?
Cal State somewhere? Um, yeah, I mean,
I think I'm at cal state. Uh, the, uh,
the College Republicans are inviting me.
I would've been glad to talk to
the College Democrats, but they,
they never invite me anywhere. Um, and uh,
all right, that's it. Catch me on Tucker.
I think I'll be on at eight 45 eastern,
which is about five or 15 minutes before
this Trump guy has given a talk about
the wall. So, all right, I'll see
you guys around. Thanks a lot.