All right people,
we are live on the youtube.
I've got the lobster and I've got the
hair.
It sounds like some sort of seventies
because that,
could that be a rock band or is that
like a,
it could be some kind of violent flick
or a mafia movie or violent band.
Violent rock man.
Yeah.
Alright.
I've wanted to get you guys together.
You two have never been seen on camera
before.
I think that's true as far as you know,
I,
I did appear in front of Jordan,
but uh,
we never intersected onstage at the
masonic.
When you decided I should have opened a.
When you paid your mean harmonica,
Harmonica,
Solo.
Out of all the Zany moments that we've
had in the last two months,
would you say that bringing Eric
Weinstein,
mathematician out onstage at the masonic
to play the harmonica and have 3000
people give him a standing ovation?
Would that be at the top?
That was good.
It worked really well too because he
turned out he actually could play the
harmonica,
which is a good thing if you're going to
try it in front of 3000 people.
It was a first for me.
I've done.
I didn't play it in front of a smaller
crowd before that,
so that was a bit of a bio.
It was pretty sweet.
All right,
so good night.
Yeah.
All right.
I want to cover 100 percent new stuff
for the next two hours.
There's a bunch of stuff obviously that
we've been hitting on on tour and some
things that we've been sort of catching
up on as this has all been going on,
so I thought the place to start I think
would be something that I've been
starting a lot of the shows with when I
go out there and I do a little intro and
to get everybody going and warm it up
for Jordan.
The idea that we're starting to win and
when I've been saying when there's a
feeling in the crowd of like,
Whoa,
maybe all of this madness that we've all
been talking about for all these years.
Maybe enough people have woken up now
that there is something shifting,
so I've brought that up a bunch and
you've sort of picked up on it on a
couple of the shows and talked about why
winning isn't necessarily the way we
should view this or what winning
actually.
So I thought that would be a good place
to kick us off here.
It's more what winning actually is,
you know,
because one of the things that has to be
contended with in the current situation
is that,
especially in the United States,
but also the rest of the Western
world,
there's a political divide.
Americans have been voting 50 percent
Republican,
Fifty Percent Democrat for,
for lecture,
pretty much split right down the middle
and there there can't be any final
victory by one side over the other
because everyone has to live together.
So the victory is how can we continue to
live together peacefully and
productively and,
and,
and we have to figure out the pathway
forward to that.
But then I think there's another kind of
victory that it's deeper than that
that's on the horizon,
which is that I think the narrative that
underlies our culture as a whole has to
shift.
And I started to think about this when I
was working for a UN committee about
five years ago.
I worked on a committee on
sustainability for the secretary general
and um,
I had a chance with the people that I
was working for and with in Canada to
rewrite the underlying narrative because
it was very pessimistic.
It was real cold war narrative north
against south and capitalists against
Socialists and doom and gloom on the
horizon.
And it seemed to me to be outdated
really by about 40 years.
And I started to read a lot of the
economic development and ecology
literature.
And mostly what I found was that things
are getting better globally so fast and
on so many different dimensions that
it's almost inconceivable.
And yet no one seems to know that.
And in the aftermath of that,
there's been about six books published
in the last five years that like
pinker's book and lightened it right
over here somewhere.
Yeah,
right.
But,
but uh,
but by no means that's by no means the
only book detailing now a revolution in
living standard progress and,
and ecological progress for that matter
around the world.
So I think there's two victories to be
held here to be had here.
One is to pull us everyone out of the
pessimistic apocalyptic Cold War
narrative that enveloped us for four or
five decades and to notice that the
future could actually be bright if we
were careful.
And the second is to make sure that the
political dialogue in the West doesn't
polarize to the degree that we start
doing things that are fatally stupid.
All right,
so let's talk about the second part
first
because I think that's where we've
really been focusing on the political
part.
So it's interesting to note there's a 50
slash 50 divides.
I don't think that's a reason.
I guess I have a strongly different take
and maybe it's the same.
We'll have to figure that out.
To me,
the 50 slash 50 mark is going to more or
less hold as long as these two parties
can calculate a what's the maximum they
can,
uh,
w with the minimum they have to give up
to win an election.
And so the,
the key issue is what is the 50 slash 50
composition look like?
And unfortunately what it keeps looking
like is the two parties becoming more
and more a nightmarish in my mind and
less trustworthy.
So we,
the 50 slash 50 continues to hold.
But what it represents as a tension,
the tension increases is getting much
worse.
So the key issue is that those of us who
are sort of center,
I mean I don't love the left right
spectrum,
but let's just use it as shorthand that
the center left and the center right
have to see each other as our natural
allies and the center left has to Clean
House and get rid of the night he left
and the center right has to get rid of
the far right.
And that's the optimistic scenario.
I think winning is incredibly important.
Okay.
Well,
that's an interesting way of
conceptualizing it and let me go a
little bit further.
Sure.
I think that we have to stop being
apologetic about winning and what
winning means.
Winning means that the advanced guard of
the a radical center,
uh,
has to make this a safe and habitable
space again.
And so in order to do that,
um,
and the reason I,
you know,
try to focus mostly most of my negative
energy on the left is,
is that it's my responsibility to clean
house on the radical bad progressive
movement that is almost certainly going
to fuel the far right.
It's not efficient for me to go after
the far right because,
I mean,
of course I'm going to be anti Nazi
skinhead,
right?
But what we've,
we've talked about that a lot too
because when we do the events,
you know,
you will all these hit pieces that come
out and we'll talk a little bit about
that.
Well,
when they say that your audience is all
these angry white men,
you,
all of this nonsense,
which every night it is proven to be
false,
um,
it's like,
yeah,
you address that every night talking
about the bad identity politics of the
right,
but it's not something that well
bullied.
The thing that's strange and then that
ties into what you're saying as well,
is that it isn't obvious to me who the
dangerous right are,
you know,
it's obvious to me who the dangerous
Lakhdar because they occupied the
universities but not just the
universities.
This is an,
I mean,
this is so mispunch,
if you will,
that we have to really break the frame
and,
and reweave it.
So,
um,
the journalists keep saying,
oh,
you guys are focusing on a tiny problem
afflicting a few universities that
mostly nobody's ever heard of.
That's definitely not true.
Well,
the first thing is,
is that it deflects the problem from
the,
the number one problem isn't the
universities.
It's journalism.
And so the idea is that the journalists
are saying,
you guys are complaining about,
uh,
the small story in the university.
It's like,
no,
you're getting it wrong.
We're complaining about the number one
story,
which is the sensemaking a apparatus
having gone haywire.
And if you think about these journalists
that we're now dealing with as like the
hermit crabs that have crawled into the
shells that we used to know,
right?
So whether it's CNN or NPR or national
review or whatever these structures are,
it's a different group of hermit crab
shells are the same.
And the great danger is that if you
recognize the font at the top of the La
Times,
The New York Times,
you think you're getting the same
product,
but the product has become radically
different.
Uh,
and there was a problem
back then.
I'm not saying that,
that,
that there wasn't.
And you know,
of course,
the,
the issue is that when we criticize
journalists now they think we're
criticizing journalism far from it.
We are praying for journalists and the
idea is,
is that we are fighting this thing where
they've got their fingers so clearly on
the scale that everything is being
tipped and what you're getting is a more
distorted reality.
There's some point at which,
and we have to talk about what happened
with,
I don't know how to pronounce it best.
IATROGENIC medicine,
the idea that doctors are creating a,
created a huge amount of the harm done
found in hospitals.
Well,
maybe stairs are the fourth leading
cause of death,
right?
So now we have to talk not about yet
regenix which is the,
you know,
the,
that which originates from the healers,
but journal genics,
which is what is the harm done to the
truth by journalists.
And that is,
so I have a,
uh,
a technological slapped on that to some
degree because one of the things that I
think is happening because I've watched
large organizations degenerate because
I've worked as a consultant for a lot of
years now.
It's really interesting to see how fast
a large organization that you think is
semipermanent can disintegrate.
It can happen.
Well,
certainly within the span of a couple of
years and sometimes a lot faster than
not.
Yes.
Well,
and I think one of the things that seems
to be happening to me is that as
television dies under the weight of
youtube primarily,
but let's say online video and perhaps
also podcasts,
is that the remaining journalists,
the hermit crabs who occupied the old
shells,
which is a good way of thinking about
it,
gets increasingly desperate for
attention.
And so there are pushed by economic
pressure in some sense and situational
pressure to exaggerate the danger.
It's like.
And it's a clickbait phenomena
essentially.
And it seems to me to be akin to what's
happened with,
with reports on the crime rate.
So,
you know,
over the last 25 years,
the five major indices of violent crime
have declined by 50 percent,
which is absolutely in,
in the United States.
Staggering decrease.
But the rate of reporting of violent
crime has gone up substantially.
And so people think that things are more
dangerous now than they were,
even though they're safer now than they
have been since the early sixties.
And they were safe for them than they'd
ever been in history.
So I think one of the things in it,
and it's interesting to think about the
technological forces driving this
because youtube and podcast do pose a
fatal threat,
I would say certainly to to to
television and so it makes sense to me
that as the journalists become less
professional and less in demand and
their messages Ha has,
has,
is,
is chasing a diminishing audience that
they're going to get noisier and noisier
about what's going on and the trick for
everyone else who's being immersed in
that is to stay sane and sensible while
the death throes play themselves out.
So wouldn't you naturally think though
that more of them would start seeing
this?
I mean what we
now see,
so clearly I meant more of them would be
jumping ship or is that old shells so
tainted or corroded?
That getting out of that thing is almost
impossible.
It has to do with systems of selective
pressure.
So Jordan raises an excellent point that
the dying throws of an institution tend
to be its most violent because it's go
for broke mode and not worrying about
tomorrow.
It's worrying about maybe serve up
buying another month or two or who knows
what,
but there's another issue of course,
which is that the formats are set.
Uh,
so your news comes to you in a form that
is more or less the same every day and
so you know how to consume it.
So everybody listens to NPR,
has a pre,
grooved a template in their brain.
I'm going to get the top stories at the
top of the hour and then they're going
to be this many pieces and there'll be
like a feel good story.
So you know exactly what you're going to
get.
Like here,
we don't know where we're going to.
Maybe Jordan and I are going to come to
blows open.
You've got to change the drink.
But the other thing that,
uh,
is,
is it in the system of selective
pressures,
as the business model fails,
you have a fascinating phenomena which
people who are willing to accept,
um,
strange,
uh,
blends of payment.
So lower financial payment and security
job security,
but higher psychic payment stemming from
the idea that they are crusading,
uh,
are going to start to dominate.
So you're seeing many more people who
are willing to substitute activism and
the sense that they are protecting us.
And a great story about the resistance,
let's say.
Yeah,
so that,
that actually becomes more and more
necessary as the stability and the
viability of the system degenerate,
right?
If you could offer,
um,
you know,
$200,000
salaries to a good reporters,
uh,
in short order so that they could start
families and buy homes and have an
easier life.
Like one of the things that you need to
do is you need to pay people more if
you're unhappy with them.
And this,
I think I learned about that,
about professors to actually sociology
professors had,
their salary's tripled.
They'd be a lot less radically.
I learned this from the New Orleans
police department where at some point
they had a corruption where people were
ordering a mob style,
hits over police radio.
And I think what happened was that the
new police chief came in and he said the
first thing he did was raise salaries
and the idea being that you have to have
skin in the game thanks to the scene to
levees that phrases a proliferative
thanks the same wherever you are,
um,
and you need to give people something to
defend.
And so it's very important to pay the
people that we are,
um,
decrying all the time.
Say everybody who's listening should go
online and donate to quill.
X patron page is doing great.
What I'm saying that we should,
we should try to figure out how to get
vox more money as well and we should try
to figure out how to get slate and salon
and all of these things so that you can
afford to pay people in ways in which
they don't have to take a large portion
of their payment as psychic
gratification from having Feld Imaginary
Dragon.
But just to be clear there,
when you're saying that,
you're not saying that the current
people who have screwed this whole thing
up deserve more money.
You're going to find,
you can find,
I have a very strange position on this,
which is in,
in,
you know,
my,
my friend Peter Teal,
and I talk about this all the time.
Uh,
his model is that,
you know,
at some level when the economy isn't
working,
people engage in this kind of
nonsensical,
a fratricide,
uh,
of a,
of a type.
And my point is slightly different,
which is this,
this bad nature is always there,
but it's like a compromised immune
system when the,
when the economy starts to fail,
you start to become aware of all of the
pathogens in the world because it can't
fight them off.
And so it's,
it's very much the issue that if you're
the guy with compromised immune system,
you're the only one aware of all the
pathogens in the world.
Um,
and so at the moment our collective
economic community system is failing,
uh,
and I actually am much more pessimistic
than you are Jordan.
I see lots of reasons to be happy about
the decrease in violence.
But you know,
one of the problems with the accounting
in these theories is that the sword of
Damocles that hangs over our heads is,
has gotten quite large and the number of
threads holding it up or seem very few
in number and so you have to do the
potential energy accounting as well as
the realized violence and also
understanding that the nature of an
income inequality and um,
differential access to financial markets
and technology is creating a lot of very
justifiable concern that the post World
War II stability it is constantly in
jeopardy and we don't,
I personally think we should think about
once every five years above ground
nuclear tests to remind ourselves of
what it is that we've pushed underground
and we haven't seen for years because we
are engaged in some kind of magical
thinking that the world is fairly stable
and that can turn on a dime.
So what kind of out do you think we
could for this crew of journalists that
were talking about that we want to be
doing more journalism.
We don't want them to be attacked or any
of those things.
Of course.
What is the out?
So the I get it.
You can give.
You could fund them in a way that gives
them a little more breathing room,
but one of the things that I'm seeing
when we're on tour is p,
everyone that comes up to me after says,
wow,
you just gave us a little room to think.
Yeah,
so is there a way we,
instead of beating these journalists,
instead of getting the wind where you
crush them so that they are losers,
what's the way that we can give them
maybe a little.
Well,
I mean it,
it's,
it's sort of standard behavioral
practice.
In some senses.
This is something that was established
by skinner a long while back even though
he used threaten punishment as ways of
altering the behavior of his
experimental animals.
He also used reward
but rewards a lot harder to use because
what you have to do is you have to watch
very carefully and then when you see an
increment in the behavior that you want
to want to promote,
you have to reward it,
but it requires a tremendous amount of
tension and subtle attention.
And so one of the things that we can
certainly do,
and that I've been trying to do to some
degree with my twitter account is to,
is to distribute good news,
good credible news and good journalism
when I see it,
which is partly why I started to get
engaged,
say with Colette,
because I think they're doing a credible
job,
but one possibility is to distribute
those pieces that seem to be
increasingly reasonable and another is
to also leaped to the defense of people
when they're taken out as individuals
and because one of the things that's
happening now is that when an individual
stands up and says something especially
that annoys the radical left,
is that they tend to get mobbed and
taken out and that's a bad thing.
It would be good if we could figure out
ways of defending people against that.
I mean,
Brett has been defended to some degree
by the emergence of this group of people
that,
that Eric has been describing as the
intellectual dark web.
And so there is some strength in numbers
there that might be usefully applied.
Can you just quickly talk about that?
Just on the personal level,
because I think one of the most moving
things that I've heard on this show is
when,
uh,
I had you on and I think,
I think it was with bread and you said
that standing with him was really one of
the most validating things that you've
ever done in your life and it's such an
example of what you've been talking
about on the tour that if you want to
fix the world than fix yourself a little
bit and then the more that you do that,
you might start effecting things around
you.
And I think that that's by,
by helping your brother in this case you
were sorta helping the world.
Well,
um,
yeah,
that's nice.
But the returns to me,
um,
were high and has nothing to do with
follower counts on twitter or anything
like that.
I don't think that,
you know,
we should talk about positive models of
masculinity and I'm standing shoulder to
shoulder with somebody in a fight is an
important part of what it means to be
complete in a masculine sense.
And I think that we are all incentivized
by shows like survivor or the last
contest or whatever,
all this stuff.
And they do the promos with the
contestants on these shows.
I'm not here to make friends.
I'm here to win.
Okay,
well what is that?
That's corporate America teaching us how
to stab everyone else in the back on
your way to the top,
which actually doesn't work very well by
the way.
Didn't work at all right or not for that
long.
If you can't follow,
you can't lead,
can't make friends,
can't make friends.
You're alone and vulnerable,
right?
You,
I mean maybe stolen had gotten to the is
the best example of a really malignant
person who managed to kill everybody,
including I think his wife.
But it's very rare that anybody,
you know,
does that really what,
what these things are.
Because you have to remember that
fragging is a possibility that the
lowest person in your organization can
take you down if they're not happy.
Right?
Right,
right.
And so I think that what people need to
understand is that there is this lost
art of standing with somebody that you
don't.
One hundred percent agree with who says
things that are like,
you know,
there are definitely things you do on
stage that I'm not comfortable with,
but if somebody comes to attack you a
fundamentally,
um,
I know that all of those points I can
bring up to you,
you know,
face to face.
I assume it's true in reverse.
And so this idea of standing with
people,
you know,
Dave,
you've been going down to libertarian
path that I'm uncomfortable with often,
but somebody says,
you know,
we hash it out publicly and privately,
publicly and privately and so,
and there's stuff I'll do privately with
you that I won't do publicly because I
think that it is important to learn how
to stand in units because otherwise you
just get picked off.
And this is,
you know,
there's a topic that I want to bring up
a little bit later,
which is what do I think the Idw,
since you've discussed it gets wrong.
And one thing I think we get wrong is
that the tribalism that we keep seeing
is so toxic that we decided that we are
anti tribal.
It's not the right model.
You want to be adaptively tribal and
adaptively individualistic,
right?
These things matter.
Groups matter.
Groups have specialized knowledge very
often,
you know,
I,
my group has certain stuff.
Your group has a different.
We engage in trade.
Um,
it is important to understand that
tribalism can be adaptive and so it's
very troubling to me that the dumbest
voices on the other side are causing us
to overreact too simplistically.
So standing with my brother.
Yeah,
there's a reason that people say he's
like a brother to me because it means
that you will put yourself at great
risk.
And I,
you know,
I've taken a lot of slings and arrows
for,
for Brett,
and there's a pleasure in it.
I'm not going to say that it didn't lead
to sleepless nights and that I don't
worry about friends that I've lost,
but it's also,
you know,
in some sense,
good to know and people respond
positively because it's in our,
it's in our makeup to to say,
well,
that guy didn't run from a fight.
So do we basically have to just model it
out for people in our behavior.
So for example,
when the New York Times piece came out
on you about three weeks ago,
the enforced monogamy piece,
now that the author of it,
I,
I'm not even going to mention her name,
but if you want to,
you can go ahead and she sat in the
green room with us,
I think on the first night in Toronto.
She was all smiles and friendly.
You even said to me how much you like
her and you introduced me to her and we
were,
you know,
we were chatting.
Um,
she seemed perfectly pleasant and
lovely.
And then of course this piece comes out,
it implies that you're for forced
monogamy,
which is which money.
Just explain that real.
Just do a,
do a one
minute on what you were taught.
The implication was,
and,
and to the degree that this has been,
let's say exaggerated in the aftermath
of the piece,
the implication was that I was promoting
the idea that,
you know,
perfectly innocent women would be lined
up by the state and distributed en mass
to undeserving males.
They wouldn't be violent.
We've only done that at one show,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
exactly,
exactly.
It's,
and it didn't,
it didn't go.
So yeah,
so,
and,
and that,
that was quite curious because that part
of the conversation I had with the
journalist lasted probably two minutes
out of what was essentially a two day
interview and it was obviously something
that triggered her imagination,
um,
in,
in the sense that she saw that she could
use it for,
for,
I don't know,
for political purposes or something like
that in the piece,
but it was so palpably absurd because
the,
and I would say amateurish in some sense
as well because the position that she
accused me of holding a,
a,
I didn't hold so that that's the first
problem.
B,
no one holds.
Like if you're going to try to pillory
someone in a manner that's at least
vaguely believable,
you should accuse them of holding a view
that at least some person has held at
some point and no one has ever held that
view.
And then the other thing that was quite
off putting let's say is that she's not
stupid.
She knew perfectly well what I meant by
enforced monogamy by the term.
It's an anthropological term,
it's been used for a hundred years and
the idea that polygamous societies,
which would be the contrast say to
monogamous society is the idea that
there are more violent,
is no one disputes that.
It's,
it's like a,
it's an anthropological,
sociological and psychological truism.
And it's also one that's been.
It's not like the left has been
promoting polygamy,
you know,
so,
so it was,
it was,
well the,
the,
the article uh,
surprised me to say the least,
but you made an interesting move
after that which ties this all together
because you did a little checking on the
phrase in the Archives of the New York
Times.
And the whole point to me was if I could
take Jordan out of the equation and I
could make it into the New York Times
wrestling with itself.
Uh,
I was pretty sure that the New York
Times would have some record of having
used the phrase enforced monogamy at
some point.
And so I went to the search engine and I
put in quote enforcement Origami close
quote.
And sure enough,
there were two relatively recent
references within the last 20,
25 years,
both of them positive.
One,
I believe coming out of evolutionary
theory in drosophila where it's a less
common term and evolutionary theory,
but it has leaked into the evolutionary
literature and the other one coming from
Afghanistan where you have polygamous
marriage and that leaves too many
violent young men with nothing to do.
And that can be useful if you're
conquesting other lands,
say,
well,
you have no wife here,
but there's a,
there's territory over there.
And this is exactly,
you know,
the New York Times was celebrating the
idea that in a culture that was at that
stage in its evolution,
uh,
enforcement origami was something that
went hand in hand with women's rights
because of course,
having the classic art,
you having fewer violent men with no
romantic prospects is in general good
for the safety of women.
And so the whole thing,
which is actually my point,
but the point was,
can I take Jordan out of it and say the
New York Times is wrestling with itself
and not unfairly.
And this is the great danger is that
that finger is on the scale.
Now,
the other thing is that that particular
journalist first met,
uh,
was talking with Brett.
I'm well before talking with you and
then Brett set this journalist to me.
And by the way,
I don't think that we should not talk
about the name of the journalist and the
journalist is certainly using your name
and the idea.
So it's Nellie Bowles.
And I found her engaging and charming,
very quick,
intelligent.
The thing that I didn't appreciate and
they got fairly far into my discussion
with her and I was off the record,
is she began with the gambit.
Well,
of course I'm going to be running your
tweet on James Damore,
which,
um,
you know,
went viral and was widely
misinterpreted.
And again,
in a deliberate fashion,
which my tweet was responding to
somebody saying,
you know,
if human resources that somebody else
from Google tweeted,
if human resources won't do something
about this,
then you know,
they're going to have trouble on their
hands.
And I was like,
okay,
you're telling people to run to human
resources because James Demore,
uh,
is looking at big five psychometrics for
personality and asking the question,
how do we increase the accessibility of
Google to female coders and whether you
agree with his technique or not.
Uh,
I think that that was clearly his point.
So the idea is I'm going to bring up
this tweet that has been widely
mischaracterized of yours,
Eric,
and you know what,
what became clear was she had the idea
that you wanted to find the men's rights
activist community and you know,
she said something about,
well,
your Mra.
And I didn't even know what that meant.
So I said,
NRA,
National Rifle Association.
And she's like,
you know,
men's rights activists.
I said what?
And so we had this.
Well that was just you being
disingenuous because of course,
you know it,
men's rights activists are right.
But the point would be,
you know,
it's like you,
you believe in human rights.
Yes.
Well,
you know,
men are human so you believe in men's
rights and you believe that one should
be active,
you know.
So you know,
at some level it's a reserved term for
people who are very often kind of
veering a spectrum of people who are
talking about bad aspects of family law
versus people who are downright
misogynist.
And I was just aghast,
which is like,
why are you trying to shoehorn me into
this preexisting thing?
That's the question.
The motivation for the,
for the shoe horning and well this is.
So this is the big issue coming,
you know,
it's hard to track all the threads.
Let me,
let me just get back to what we don't
understand is that they've invested in
all of this cognitive Lego,
right?
So they've,
you know,
equity or toxic masculinity or white
privilege,
whatever these things are.
And so everything in high dimensional
space gets shoved into this completely
inappropriate kind of cognitive lego.
Which furthermore,
the format of these things,
like I recently got asked to do a bit on
a,
on a show on television,
on an established network.
And they said,
you know,
we're really blowing it out.
We've,
we've,
we've got the message that this new form
of a long form interview,
uh,
is the wave of the future.
It's like,
well,
how much am I going to get?
We might go from five to eight minutes,
right?
The idea is I want to say hello in five
minutes.
This is the point,
right?
It's like I have access to three hours
when I want it.
Right?
You're like,
well,
that's insane,
right?
It's like they can't move that much.
And so that's partly why the formats
dying.
And it's also,
I think one of the reasons that we think
we're stupid or than we are.
I like listening to a lot of our,
including our audience is that,
you know,
because tv,
one of the things I have noticed about
television in general is that it's
predicated on the presumption that the
audience is stupid,
but if you have to force everything
through a channel whose maximum
dimension is six minutes,
then everyone's going to look was.
The stupid thing is if you think about
what happened where television went from
being the dumb medium to the incredibly
smart medium when you went from TV
dramas have a half an hour,
maybe an hour in length to many,
many shows over a season and developing
characters at a level that a film can't
touch literature approaches.
Right?
Right,
right.
So the idea is that in the sopranos or
mad men or game of thrones,
people are following incredibly
difficult enrich plots and you have to
go back to this old adage which nobody
ever lost a dime a underestimating the
intelligence of the American people.
Well,
that's only true if you don't understand
opportunity cost because people have
been losing dimes,
but millions by not understanding that
anyone who can follow game of thrones,
right?
How is it that this thing that we're
about to do,
I have no idea why.
You know,
we're just having a conversation.
There's going to be over 100,000
views of this thing.
I think very quickly.
Yeah.
I got one video on my channel of any
substance,
one video.
It's got nearly 60,000
views.
People are hungry for this thing that
they're being starved for.
What they don't understand in the
regular media is is that their format is
killing them and I know this is
something we really.
We really have to pay attention to it
because a tremendous amount of what's
going on is the consequence.
You know,
you said that a complex reality is being
shoveled into a,
a,
a tiny dimensional space and so there's
some ideological reasons for that,
but I think some of that is being fed by
the channels of the media because it's a
lot easier to take a complex situation
like that and shovel it into a
preexisting April interpretive space
because everyone already understands it.
So if you've only got a few minutes,
then there's a bunch of things that you
don't have to explain because you're
just telling the same old story.
Because what,
what,
what we also don't grasp
is that we don't file flight plans like
you're having me on the show.
You don't know what,
what I'm going to say.
You don't know what my positions are on
immigration.
You don't know what my physicians are an
abortion.
We've never gotten to that,
I don't think,
and I was actually thinking that about
both of you.
I don't think we've ever discussed it.
We can't get it,
but what the way the,
the,
this commentary at works and I've been
waking up to the idea that the slayer
even exists because they didn't think
about it too much,
is that mostly these people have
consistent takes that is they are
counted upon to take complicated reality
and you know,
give us the Tom Friedman point,
give us the,
give us the Paul Krugman point,
you know,
give us the Ezra Klein view and you're
thinking,
well,
why is there a sort of regular,
consistent view on these things?
Like,
I've watched Jordan,
I've watched you change your mind in
real time as somebody makes a good
argument and it's a little bit painful
because somebody was listening to you
and then they say,
well,
how do I have faith in your argument?
And that might answer is how do you
faith in any of this stuff?
All of this stuff can reverse it.
Won't you have more faith?
If somebody can reverse themselves?
And I'm thinking about this thing about
the the cake baking a cake for a gay.
Yes,
yes.
Well look what happened when we'll get
back to nellie bowles because I want to
return to that.
But you know,
one of the things that was really
interesting to watch in Vancouver,
I just had two discussions with Sam
Harris and the.
The discussion was set up from a
promotional perspective by a promoter
who was doing his job as a kind of a
combat situation,
right?
There was going to be a victory.
It would be sam or me in,
in the final analysis versus it actually
versus.
Right.
And so,
but what happened was that Sam and I
actually had a discussion where we were
trying to lay out our points to
understand each other's points.
And we set this up.
It was one of Brett's ideas actually
because your brother a moderated.
When the second discussion opened,
what he had us do was summarize each
other's arguments.
So I put forth Sam's arguments in the
strongest possible terms.
Steel man,
he did the same and that worked.
That worked just fine by the way.
But what was so interesting was the
audience would have settled for a debate
that culminated in the victory of one of
us over the other.
But instead what happened was they got
engaged in a discussion that we had both
designed to push both of our
capabilities of thinking farther along
and so,
and we weren't sure if that would work
because we weren't sure if we could
talk,
but it turned out that we could partly
thanks to breads help and then the
original format was we were going to
talk for an hour for the first one and
then we're going to open it up to q and
a.
But the discussion got very intense and
I would have,
I likened it to approximate level of a
pretty good phd defense,
you know,
if,
if you're,
if you have a good student who's,
who's defending and you know,
they know the literature,
you can really go after them because it
gives them a chance to show their
mastery.
Right.
So it can be a real positive thing for
them.
And so it was like a dual phd defense,
D U,
a l and D u e l at the same time,
but the audience was right there with us
and then at the end of the hour,
Brett asked them should we switch to the
q and a or should we continue the
discussion because we're in the middle
of something.
And overwhelmingly the sentiment was
continue the discussion and so we did
model the process of,
I wouldn't say respectful dialogue
because first of all that's a cliche and
second of all,
that wasn't what this was.
What we were doing was actually engaging
in the process of trying to make both of
us smarter than we were.
And and people are are in for that.
They're there,
they're onboard for that and they would.
They would prefer that to the cheap
victory by all appearances.
So what do you think that says then if
that the audience that was there and
from what I can see with our audiences,
that they care more about an unlocking
some truths than they do about the
victory.
When we live in a time where everyone
wants to dunk on everybody constantly,
I keep seeing the phrase pop up,
we'll get you a dunk.
Dinah,
you haven't.
That's nobody wants it,
but they keep shuttling,
loves he wants it.
I mean,
well,
it's better than being bored and it's
better than stacy's and it's better than
capitulation,
but it's not as good as what could be if
you got what was optimal.
When I see this with my own videos,
people keep chopping them up and say,
you know,
Peterson demolishes,
obviously that's click bait,
but that was also one of the things that
made me think about the degeneracy
degeneration of journalism per se,
and to Bait clickbait mean that's
emerging spontaneously on youtube as a
method for attracting attention and
these people,
as they get more desperate,
as their,
as their modality dies,
then it's not surprising that they,
that they turn to their
oversimplifications for the reasons you
outlined,
but also to attract attention real
quick.
Is it possible that it worked for
awhile,
that that sort of exposure and clickbait
nonsense made sense?
Sort of at the beginning of the
Internet,
because we were all so stuck in the,
uh,
in the old structures that we needed
something to really wake us up,
but now we're sort of past that.
You don't think so that we don't think
we're past it enough that it doesn't
work anymore.
If you want to avoid having me as a
guest in the future,
here's one of the standard moves that I
may stop talking about what's good and
bad and started putting the phrase
adaptive and maladaptive in front of
different modalities.
We like adaptive dumb dunking.
I've got this problem with this guy,
Noah Smith.
I don't know what his problem is.
He,
he's an economist.
He's engaging.
He's a relatively
charming.
He has got a position on immigration
where he just loves immigration.
There's nothing.
You can't have too much immigration.
Immigration is just the best thing in
the world.
Maybe it has some problems in some
sector,
but in general it's a free lunch and
I've done work on this to try to show.
No.
It's a much more complicated situation
and behind the scenes it's being abused
as has nothing to do with immigrants.
It's Americans transferring wealth into
their own pockets from other Americans
using immigrants.
We can get into this later.
I've tried,
I've had lunch with the guy I've shown
in my papers,
my research.
He absolutely does not want a
discussion.
What does he want?
Well,
he wants to have an idea that
immigration is a pure good.
And that know the National Academy of
Sciences has found that if we get this
benefit from it and it has to do with
one rights which don't show up in,
in a,
in a maximum,
in an economics framework.
It has to do with something involving
the securitization of rights so that
people don't have their rights taken as
if by eminent domain.
Um,
he knows all this stuff and he just
chooses to continue down this path.
And that Sam has seen this with Reza,
Reza,
Aslan,
um,
and with Glenn Greenwald,
who in some ways I always thought of as
pretty positive.
And then I,
you know,
he gets,
he gets a bug in his head and you get
these incredibly negative people who
don't want to come into a discussion and
it's important to reserve the dunking on
modality for when people are really not
acting as good actors.
You know,
that's kind of what I did with.
I decided to take a lawsuit out against
Wilfrid laurier two weeks ago and that
was,
um,
you know,
I've been trying to reserve my twitter
defense that say or attack because it's
not always easy to distinguish between
those.
Like I,
I,
I've learned to leave people alone when
they make untoward comments,
unless they are journalists of some
repute or professors of some repute,
in which case I think I have a moral
obligation not to remain silent.
And so it's not so easy to figure out
when you should defend yourself and when
you should shut up.
Well first before is the wrong time to
do and prefer that we don't defend
ourselves because it's,
as you always have this problem with
special pleading,
are you defending yourself because you
believe in the ideas?
Are you defending yourself?
Because it's a possible threat to your
own reputation.
Right?
So that's one of the reasons I came to
your assistance on the enforcement
origami thing because I didn't want you
having to make that point.
And if at some point in the future I get
into trouble and you think that I have
married my position,
perhaps you'll return the favor.
We can figure out the game theory later.
But that's,
that's what culture actually does.
But doesn't that also just feed the
beast in a certain way?
So if you defend a professor goes after
you,
who has,
you know,
no,
no notoriety,
but just wants to get in on the game.
Well now you've defended yourself.
Now next thing you know,
voxer,
buzzfeed is writing about the professor.
Nobody knows.
And Jordan Peterson.
Well that's a danger for sure.
Look,
I am also,
I am not a huge fan of the dunk on
mentality as a opening gambit.
I am slow to anger in these situations.
I tend to give people three benefits of
the doubt,
which is what you should do.
Yeah.
And so,
you know,
for example,
I had as recline and his wife over for
Shabbat dinner with Gad said,
um,
you know,
after the Sam Harris thing,
and I wanted to understand as position
and Ezra had,
in fact,
vox had done a piece where I talked
about the need to blend hyper capitalism
with hyper socialism in the future
because I think,
and throw up,
I think about this thing of anthropic
capitalism.
The capitalism that worked in the 19th
and 20th centuries may have been an
accident for where the parameters were
set on in our market so that it could
function as well as it did.
And you know,
Ezra,
um,
I don't want to get into all the
personal details of the interaction,
but it was fascinating talking to Ezra
and his wife as to how they see the
world and getting a behind the scenes
look at what generates vox.
So I think it's very important to try to
be charitable in understanding other
people and understanding their
motivations.
But there is a point when you hit
something three,
four or five times the person's
evidenced comprehension.
And then they go into this mode,
like you talked about this with Kathy
Newman where you had one kind of
interaction with her before and then
suddenly somebody three,
two,
one go.
And it's like,
so what you're really saying,
where did that personality come out of
that has to do in part with the masks
that we all put on.
I think that one of the things is,
I know you guys both personally,
um,
this mirrors it how we talk in a
different context.
But when you know,
when,
when vox is the weeds discussed the
intellectual dark web,
I thought it was incredibly confused.
Very interestingly,
after the Barry Weiss article,
almost no one from the standard media
called me up to clarify,
sort of learn more because barry was the
owner of this thing and so it was
assumed that barry had named it that
this was barry's beat.
And so barry was the goto person as if
we were all owned by the particular
member of the commentary.
That who decided to actually blow this
up and make it large?
We have to become more charitable.
I do think that in part,
part of the problem that we've been
having with the sort of madness in the
progressives is that first of all,
unlike the Charlottesville,
right,
the progressives are in the
establishment.
Whereas the Tiki torch holders are like
often their mother's garage and that's a
big,
big difference.
And so one of the reasons were animated
is that,
you know,
you remember that line.
It's coming from inside the house.
Yeah.
Definitely.
On the other hand,
I do see a lot of points that these
people have that they're just terribly
missing stantiating the problem of the
progressives in my,
in my estimation,
I might have.
My family has been progressive since the
twenties,
is that they're terrible at what they
do.
They're just not good progressive.
It's like really malignant form.
Let me give you an example.
English is odd in that it is inflicted
for gender only in the third person
singular.
Now Turkish for example,
it's not inflected for gender.
There's one pronoun.
Oh,
for Kishi it.
So you don't have this problem in
Turkish.
Um,
when you were referring to a character
in the story who is not present,
um,
we had this problem for a in English
form inflicted influxion for marital
status,
which was true for females and not
males.
Mr Was Mr.
but miss and Mrs gave you more
information.
So there was a one time backwards,
incompatible change that got made with
ms and it,
you know,
it's still rankles because it doesn't
sound great,
but I think it was a good idea and to
make,
to give women the equality that they
deserved and shouldn't have to ask for.
Okay.
If you wanted to actually do the pronoun
thing for English,
would you start with trans or would you
start with intersects now?
If you started with intersects,
everyone is intellectually sympathetic
with Intersex.
There are people whose gender or sex is
ambiguous,
right?
Because of the way in which development
sort of takes female and turns it into
mail if the SROI protein is present.
So this,
everyone who understands this,
just to be clear,
not everyone who hears about this,
but everyone who has in general,
no matter how conservative somebody is,
if I tell them there's a person born
with ambiguous genitalia,
um,
or you know,
they've got an Sroi protein,
a on an x chromosome or they have a
malfunctioning one on a why,
so that they appear to be the opposite
phenotype for their genotype.
There's compassion.
The person was born in Seoul,
was born without the expected assignment
and there's no question about
development.
And should we be steering.
You should be more male.
You should be more masculine,
more feminine in order to avoid the sky
high.
I'm suicidal.
A temptations for people who feel that
they are one thing well evidencing that
they are something else in the physical.
Okay.
You would make the change based on
intersects.
You'd make a onetime backwards
incompatible change to the language with
a approach pronoun like Turkish has.
And then trans would have what it wanted
without this craziness of everybody gets
to design their own personal pronoun,
which is a disaster.
Like in a computer science course,
you would never allow people,
you,
you'd give them a choice so that the
coding can go through.
Everybody can't have their own pronouns.
Right?
And so that's how you do it.
And if you wanted it to win,
that's how you push it through.
Now what they want is something else
they want to say something like Trans
Women are no less women than women who
are born biologically female.
Well,
that's not true,
right?
I understand.
It is the case that every single
culture,
every traditional culture of which I'm
aware there is gender ambiguity in South
Sulawesi.
You have a priestly class from it.
In India,
you have the hidden cameras.
Um,
Turkeys,
national treasure,
a Zeki Muren was more feminine than
Liberace.
Uh,
I just came from Italy where the Uffizi
Gallery,
there's an entire room called the
hermaphrodite room,
a dedicated to a beautiful statue,
uh,
of,
ostensibly female,
um,
recumbent a model with a male genitalia
that there is,
you know,
not the Shah of Iran.
The ayatollah in Iran came out with a
proclamation that it was okay to have
gender reassignment surgery.
So it's not like traditional cultures
don't know about this,
it's not like we haven't made
accommodation,
it's always been an issues,
whether it's the [inaudible] and in
Thailand,
um,
which are among the best spoken in most
educated people that you meet as a
traveler.
The issue is that we somehow wanted to
make a wedge issue out of this.
I am going to force you to say things
that aren't true as an evidence of my
power as opposed to,
well,
that's why exactly why I oppose the
legislation in Canada to begin with
because part and parcel what came along
with that as part and parcel of it,
and this was no accident,
was illegal insistence that gender
differences were associated associate
socio culturally constructed.
It's like,
well they're not.
And I thought,
well,
what the hell?
Why are we enshrining that viewpoint
into law?
I mean,
that's not to say that gender doesn't.
Very gender expression doesn't vary
substantially because of sociocultural
conditions because you have to be a fool
not to see that that's the case.
But that's another situation where the
multidimensional complexity seems to
exceed the processing capacity of the
ideologues.
Is that there's more than one factory
work?
No,
no,
no.
They know what they're doing.
Like for example,
should a skirt be seen as feminine or
masculine?
Well,
we know from India where the lung is
popular for Scotland where there's a
kilt that this is a variable.
In other words,
you shouldn't hardcode skirts are for
girls.
Right?
And so the idea is that there is a huge
developmental aspect to learning.
Here are the assignments in your
culture.
Now at some point you want to steer
people into,
we have a huge interest in the breeding
family is the core of lineage in a
society and we need to care both about
gays,
about um,
people have uncertain gender,
non binary people,
etc.
But we can't lose sight of the fact that
we also have to care about the family,
the breeding family in distress,
but also have to provide people with an
easy pathway to a reasonably stable
identity.
Well,
it doesn't confuse them too.
This is the point is that they have an
argument that I think we are learning
that gender and discomfort is far more
common than we ever thought,
although far less prevalent than the
discussion seems to suggest you do have
a societal interest in steering people
to roles if it's possiBle,
but once somebody is like committedly
nonbinary switch has to flip on us and
we have to become compassionate and
recognize that we have a soul that we
have to take care of and we do have to
make some allowances.
If you,
if you know anybody who's intersex for
example,
you know,
that it's a terrifying state,
that they face violence.
I mean,
you know,
why don't you see dudes kissing.
I always claim that it's the implied
threat of violence where if it makes
people uncomfortable,
um,
you don't see people holding hands quite
so comfortably and you don't see people
being themselves.
So if we,
for example,
in the idw,
stood up for intersex and say this is
the right way to do what you're doing,
I think it would be an absolute service
to the world because that's something we
could push through.
I don't think that the key that the
conservative christians in this country
are going to have a diehard,
they're gonna feel like,
well,
if the lord made people in that way,
we have to accept all the products of
god's creation.
Where do you fall on that?
Because this is where people will say,
well,
yeah,
was against trans people and gay people.
I mean all the,
all the nonsense.
Yeah.
Well then I hear about your situation in
Canada.
It was quite clear is that the federal
government following the provincial
governments decided that it was okay to
impose requirements for the regulation
of speech.
And I didn't care what the reason for
that was.
I thought that it was a terrible
legislative move and partly not because
it wasn't only compelled speech.
I read the policy guidelines that were
the framework within which this bill was
to be interpreted.
There's pages and pages of them all on
the ontario human rights commission
website,
which was late to the federal website,
um,
where they had announced how this bill
would be interpreted and it contained
all sorts of terrible things.
Like the insistence that gender was was
a social socio cultural construct and
it's in part a socio cultural construct
and these things are this,
you cannot do that because all of a
sudden the legislation seemed to imply
that at discussion about the biological
differences between men and women might
be regarded as hate speech and I also
think we're a fair ways along that
pathway in Canada.
So I don't think that my fears about the
bill were unwarranted and I think that
what happened at wilfrid laurier
university is an absolutely perfect
example of that.
So I think that my stance on that piece
of legislation was substantively
correct.
Now the problem is is that or,
or the the treachery that was involved
in the bill because I see the bill as an
attempt by the radical left to gain
linguistic dominance over increasing
linguistic dominance over the
conversation as a whole.
Using trans people as the sacrificial
victims.
And by the way,
I got no shortage of letters from trans
people saying I not so happy being
you used as a sacrificial victim for the
left to advance its linguistic hegemony.
I got a lot more letters like that from
trans people than I did from trans
people criticizing what I did.
So.
And I also think that this would have
all died away very rapidly if all it was
about was one professor's objection to
the rights of trans people that had very
little to do with it.
But let's just take this,
take this bull by the horns right now.
Am I correct?
And I,
you and I have not discussed this.
That your point would be the law is the
wrong place to do it and the culture
would be the right place.
Absolutely.
has to be bottom up like the ms thing
was.
I understand that.
so my point is law is absolutely the
wrong.
Why not let it come from us.
I mean,
in other words,
this thing has been so crazily
interpreted by the press.
This is absolute malpractice as far as
I'm concerned by our journal.
This journal agentic malpractice.
I should,
I should speak up for some of the
journalists in Canada because the post
media group is 200 newspapers came out
and supportive my stance.
So I appreciate those who aren't doing,
but my point is,
is that the fact that we're still having
to discuss this as a tax on all kinds of
discussion,
that the more time I have to spend
saying I'm not all right,
uh,
you know,
transphobic,
I don't want the fact that I'm in an
interracial marriage because I oppose
these equity proposals that are complete
abomination.
Right?
It remember when you and I were in
tempe,
Arizona at the comedy club and I said
something like,
you know,
we shouldn't be celebrating this.
I'm in an interracial marriage and
everybody clapping,
I said,
stop it.
Unless a feW of you are admissions
officers to ivy league schools,
in which case we'll talk to you later.
But the point is a terrible thing.
Credit for that,
like you happen to fall in love with a
person of color,
is there's moral victory.
Lord,
is there a metal you know in your
future,
you don't want it.
Now what I'm trying to say something
slightly different,
which is I want in on the positive
aspects of the social transformation.
I know that my intersex people are
hurting and I know that trans people,
um,
are present in every culture without
this social justice stuff,
and we should be spearheading what the
incompetent progressive,
left can't get done.
WhaT is that?
is that what we're doing?
One of the things that I want to be
doing,
like gay marriage turned on a dime over
a very short period of time,
like smoking,
right?
Somehow that there's no smoking in bars.
It's almost incredible.
You know,
if you're old enough to think about that
we should be spearheading this thing
because they can't get the job done and
what is our point?
Not in law yet,
not in law,
but do it in culture.
You can't have everybody do his or her
own pronouns,
which is an absolute disaster.
But we could settle on,
you know,
and you could do,
hey,
and they,
you know,
pronouns or something like this.
I don't know what the right thing.
Get a linguist and a to figure out the
minimally intrusive
one time backwards,
incompatible change to the language Is,
it's going to be painful.
Uh,
I'm not looking forward to it,
but we could get it done.
So one of the things that I've been
doing in my public lectures is talking
about the appropriate and responsible
position of the left.
So you know,
it seems to me that if you're pursuing
goals that have value,
which you have to do because you have to
do things in order to stay alive,
you have to pursue goals of value.
If you do that in a social social space,
which you're compelled to do,
then you're going to produce hierarchies
because people,
different incompetence and you actually
want to produce hierarchies that are
based on competence because they're
efficient tools for getting that
particular job done.
And so it's a reasonable position for
people on the,
in the center and on the right to say
stand behind the hierarchies.
But by the same token,
hierarchies can tilt towards a
corruption and tyranny and they tend to
dispossess people because talents are
distributed on equally.
So the left,
the position of the left,
that's the appropriate position,
is to speak up for the dispossessed,
to keep the,
is flexible enough so that they don't
turn into tyranny and so then you have a
dialogue between the right and the left
that's necessary to maintain the
hierarchy,
but also to prune it and keep it
healthy.
And so one of the things that we could
conceivably contribute to is to improve
the health as you're pointing out
conceptually and otherwise of the
dialogue on the left,
it's like to give the devil his due,
so to speak.
And to say that of course there's a
place for the left.
The question is when do they go too far?
Which is what I've been trying to push
to be a moderate.
So think about this.
This is beyond communism.
If you think about one phrase that sums
up the theory of communism,
what would you,
what would you say with the most famous
for it?
Well,
probably from each according to their
ability to each according to their need.
And I'll look at the first part of that
phrase from each according to their
ability.
Right?
So the idea is that there are different
abilities acknowledged in the very core
of communism beyond that,
right?
Right.
Oh yes.
I that.
Well,
I think the most pathological,
the deepest unidimensional pathology
that characterizes the radical left is
actually an attack on competence itself.
And so when I was at the aspen ideas
festival a couple of days ago,
I made the case that,
um,
our hierarchies in the west are
determined to,
at least in part by competence right
now,
the degree to which it's pure competence
can be disputed,
but intelligence and conscientiousness
are the best predictors of longterm life
success,
even though they don't predict more than
about 25 percent of the variance.
But the buzz surrounding what I said was
that Jordan Peterson is validating the
current patriarchy by making the radical
claim that it's predicated on
competence.
It's like,
well,
why would they twist that argument?
Because they didn't want.
I said,
I said that their competence is a
partial contributor to our successful
hierarchies.
And I think the reason is,
is
that the very idea of differential
competence is unacceptable to the most
radical will hang on for his left.
Let's look at two separate systems
because I think that what people do is
they focus on one rather than the other,
and I've had to learn how to do this.
If we look at chess,
which can be made blind where you don't
know who you're playing across the
internet,
and we look at musical additions for
classical orchestras,
uh,
where you can put people behind a screen
and I think this became popular in the
eighties,
nineties,
a particular basis who is also a
psychologist may have been instrumental
in getting this change.
When you introduced the screen,
women's participation in orchestras went
up,
right?
So it was a very positive social program
because competency was apparently being
suppressed by people's perception,
by prejudice.
It was a structural problem.
Now maybe it didn't go as far as people
won't want it,
maybe didn't get to 50 slash 50.
I don't know what the stats are.
I can look in on that.
When you do it in chess,
I don't believe it has a positive
effect.
When they did it in the australian civil
service for blind cvs,
it had the opposite effect.
Women got under selected right?
So,
so you're saying even though you're
saying is that this is situationally
situations.
The point is,
is that the people who want to talk
about chess,
where the top hundred players last I
checked it was 99 to one male to female,
which is so like even with structural
bigotry,
man,
that's hard to explain.
In the other case of the classical
orchestras at what was it?
Twenty percent increased participation
of females.
That's a giant amount and they're both
true.
And so the problem is when you push
everything and you shove it into the low
dimensional space,
you have this idea of is this structural
a misrepresentation or is it something
else?
Well,
it's both and it's situationally
dependent.
My wife had to make a point to me,
which I was blind to because in physics
almost nothing matters other than like
horsepower and creativity.
You don't care whether somebody red,
green,
blue,
male,
female.
it's just like almost nobody's got
interesting ideas.
It's so hard to make any progress
whatsoever.
You just want to take the far right tail
of the distribution and you don't want
to be harassed about anything other than
that.
Math,
math,
math is potentially even more.
My wife had to say to me,
you know,
eric,
not everything looks like theoretical
physics or differential geometry.
In fact,
if you think about community policing,
it can be extremely important to have
diversity a because why do you want one
ethnic group policing another ethnic
group or all cops being male?
you want diversity in order to have good
relations so that people see themselves
reflected on the force and if there is
bigotry and prejudice,
it manifests itself.
Uh,
it's harder to manifest if people are in
fact diverse.
So that was a bit of a wake up call.
The other thing that came from the
harvard math department where it for a
period of time,
it appeared that they would let in one
woman a year into the phd program and
then she would have a terrible year and
she dropped out and then one year a
woman deferred her admission and so they
added another woman and then she had two
women in the first year and the two of
them reinforced each other's reality.
Like,
you know,
I think I just said something and
everybody ignored it or I made a point
and then somebody else went to the
chalkboard and wrote it down as if it
was his idea and this group of two women
stayed in the program and that meant the
next year that there was one woman lead
in,
okay,
now there's a group of three,
and that was a situation in which there
was an organic change in the apparent
ability of women.
Now we need to be differentiating.
we can't keep reacting to the madness of
the analysis.
Right?
Right.
We can't.
We have to be the ones who are saying,
look,
let me steal,
man.
Your point.
You're making a terrible version of this
argument.
I think I can even do better.
And you're welcome.
Right?
Because the other thing it's doing is
it's deranging our conversation.
This is why I had you talked to ben.
Ask him point blank about whether he
would use the pronouns.
And his point was,
I will in general be happy to use
somebody preferred program except if
we're discussing a trans issues,
which in which case it is to see the
argument that he doesn't want to
publicly see the argument for privately
mystic grounds open about it and this is
what we have to stop reacting to the
mat,
to,
to the crazy making substrate.
So basically you think that for the
people that are keeping their foot on
the pedal at the highest possible level,
we sort of just have to let that go.
But do you think it would be enough?
So if let's say tomorrow you started,
we finished the show today and you say,
all right,
I'm going to start being the champion
for all the.
The compassion that trans people.
I mean I know you're compassionate to
all people,
but I'm going to be publicly more
compassionate to trans people and
intersex people and all of and address
all of the issues that you just brought
up.
If there's another set of people that
are never gonna,
throw you a bone on that,
that are never going to give you a
little outreach on that.
Does it actually do anything or you
think it just allows us to get the
refugees that will kind of wake up
around it.
But I think that we're being drained of
our empathy.
I mean,
let me,
let me say I am being drained of my
empathy.
Um,
you know,
there was a,
there was a tweet that Kentucky planned
parenthood put out where it was one of
these.
Remember it was,
uh,
some,
some men have have a uterus and they
repeated it like 11 times.
Yeah,
that's the big thing.
And
if they've written,
some trans men have a uterus or if
they'd written something,
but we have to be compassionate to
people who as what,
whatever.
I would be okay.
But the idea of some men have you.
Well,
there's actually something called
persistent mullerian duct syndrome where
people who were phenotypically male at
birth appear to have a uterus because of
the mysteries of development.
And again,
the fact that males and females are one
protein away from each other and
treating each other like we're separate
tribes as opposed to,
um,
you know,
fisher like compliments is absolutely
insane.
And so I find myself making fun of these
people and I had some tweet about,
you know,
either we're talking about persistent
mullerian duct syndrome or you're just
eating crayons,
helping pooping a rainbow.
And,
you know,
I thought about this,
I thought I'm so unsympathetic with
you're trying to smuggle ideology into
my world,
into compassion to the laboratory and
you know,
this is reprehensible ideology under the
guise of it just gets back to this issue
that we have been having this expert
conversation in the literature where all
sorts of things that cause people to
clutch pros and they're feigning couches
are absolutely parts of the parts of the
literature and biology and psychology
and anthropology,
all of these places.
And now everything is discussed
everywhere.
So when you hear,
you know that there are group
differences,
um,
it's shocking if you haven't been part
of the professional civil conversation.
And I think that that's a big problem
is,
is that this is this esoteric versus
exoteric speak,
which is the sort of intellectual elite
in the universities have this private
way of talking amongst themselves in
journals and in this public way of
talking,
and this is absolutely essential in some
areas,
but it's being abused and others.
So,
for example,
the trade theorists,
um,
know that,
what they talk about,
that the importance of free trade based
on ricardian equivalence and comparative
advantage is a bullshit argument.
Um,
it's a very crude thing that's very hard
to argue with mathematically,
but it's behind the scenes.
They're having a completely different
conversation and they have the idea of
we're entitled to do this.
And the answer from my perspective is
you just replaced one concept which was
a caldor hicks,
uh,
improvement with,
with paredo improvement.
Pereno improvement makes everybody
better off.
Tyler hicks leave some people worse off
than some people better off.
And you'd have to tax the better off to
compensate for the worst at.
Well,
we're,
we're having a countrywide freakout
because the economists have developed
two separate conversations,
one for the public where they push out
things that are not necessarily good for
the median individual,
very bad for particular communities and
a separate conversation that they're
having amongst themselves and they are
serving these interests.
What we have to do,
something about this,
we can no longer.
This goes back to your gutenberg point
and the technology issue.
We cannot have this level of division
between the private and the public
conversation.
I know more about what's wrong with the
immigration,
uh,
in the high tech sector than the
national academy feels.
A national academy of sciences wants to
discuss.
They are at the center effectively of a
conspiracy in the 19 eighties and early
nineties to change the laws of the
United States in order to make it
impossible for young scientists to
bargain with phds in hand with their
employers to get the six figure salaries
that the market was going to give.
Now we can,
we can play a game where the national is
having a private conversation with me
where they've had me four or five times
over there and they're not going to have
any reflection of this in the public,
but I now have 100,000
twitter followers and I know why people
are angry about immigration,
has nothing to do with immigrants.
It has to do with transfer.
It has to do with the fact that our
ruling classes had been figuring out how
to transfer money from one group of
americans to another group of americans
and if they could use puppies,
they use puppies because you can't
object puppies.
Okay,
well the problem is is that you now have
a group of people who are able to have
these conversations to say,
let me show you the playbook.
Let me show you what's really going on
on in these technical discussions.
There are,
there are differences between groups
that are measurable.
Iq,
w,
I don't think any of us really want to
be talking about race and iq
particularly,
but when you try to say there is
absolutely no evidence to show,
well that's not going to be true and the
scientists are going to have to say,
look,
I don't,
I don't right.
Reality,
I report on what the literature says.
Let me tell you what the literature
says,
and the literature says some things that
we don't want it to say,
but that's not.
There's nothing new about that.
Lots of science is very upsetting.
Evolutionary theory is upsetting.
Psychology is upsetting and it's
upsetting literature.
We haven't figured out what we're going
to do culturally as it becomes available
to everybody and we have people who are
sort of gleefully talking about things
like race and iq and I want to tell
them,
cut it out.
That's the,
you know,
we don't really know everything but
we're getting more and more knowledge
and I'm worried about where it can go.
And we have other groups of people who
say,
you know,
there's absolutely nothing to this race
and iq thing.
I'm just thinking,
oh,
this is like as best as you're,
you're,
you're now making an attempt to stir up
the asbestos to try to get rid of it and
you're going to loosen all these fibers
rather than doing this professionally
and scientifically the right way,
so I do think that there's an issue
about the esoteric,
the exoteric and what it is that we're
going to do as experts to handle the
knowledge that we've been sort of
exposed to and that the public hasn't
and it's coming out in the worst ways
and this is part of what's fueling the
whole.
Make America great again.
Situation,
which is the public knows something is
off with their expert communities.
The expert communities are not being
honest about what the literature,
so I would say that right
there is the magic of what I've been.
It's been such a pleasure of being part
of with you for these last two months or
so that you are giving people a little
bit of all of these people know
something's not right.
The information we're getting is not
right.
The language we're speaking is not
The way we're talking about government
is not right.
Everything that eric just said right
there,
and you're giving them a little room
every day to figure it out for
themselves.
That,
that strikes me.
Two things that are happening.
One is because of the long form,
it's actually possible to have more in
depth discussions about these things.
And the other is that because my
lectures,
let's say,
and the discussions that I've been
having focus on the development of ideas
rather than on the ideas themselves,
but that gives people a bit of breathing
space.
Um,
one of the questions that I'm really
curious about is,
um,
and I'd like to know what you think
about this.
What do you think it is that's
fundamentally driving the radical
newness of the left?
Like why?
Because it,
it does seem so counterproductive.
Even two to the left,
so on stated positions,
you know,
because when I was an aspen for example,
I talked about the literature on
biological differences between men and
women in,
in psychology,
right?
It's like mostly men and the women are
similar.
Even in the dimensions where they differ
most,
there's way more overlap than there is
difference,
right?
So aggression is a good example of that.
So if you take a random man and a random
woman out of the population and you had
to bet on who was the more aggressive,
if you bet on the man you'd be right 60
percent of the time,
but that's not that much.
But then all the actions at the tails,
right?
So you don't care about how aggressive
the average person is.
You care about how aggressive the really
aggressive people are and they're all
male and so you end up putting them in
prison which accounts for the massive
differential between men and women in
prison rates and so you can have small
differences at the meeting and radical
differences at the extremes.
So.
And that's the fact that people don't
understand that is he is partly willful
blindness on the part of the
ideologically committed,
but also partly because it's somewhat
complex statistically.
But then I think about the like the
audience that I was addressing it aspen,
they weren't happy about me talking
about biological differences in
personality between men and women and I
thought,
well,
what the hell do you want?
Exactly from your leftist perspective is
like,
why is it so necessary for you to make
the presumption that there cannot be any
differences whatsoever between men and
women?
It's like,
well first of all there are so that's a
big problem for your theory,
but why all of a sudden has this become
an axiomatic position of the left that
these differences can exist when what
you want to do in principle is free up
people to make choices.
I think that or to make choices in a
market that would allow for those
choices in keeping with their intrinsic
nature.
Like why did that?
I don't understand why that shifted.
And what's interesting is you're talking
about the intellectual liberal elite.
That's the type of people you were
talking in front of,
right?
If
you were just talking in front of just a
group of lefties or a group of writers
are saying about you,
about the commentariat yeah,
right.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Alright.
So what,
what do you do with that?
Well,
let me come straight at it.
We on the left had an idea that if we
could get rid of cultural bias in iq
testing,
if we could get rid of misogyny that was
structural in the workplace,
that we would get a particular kind of
outcome.
And we did make things better in many
ways,
but it didn't go as far as we were
expecting.
And so this is what people are wrestling
with and you know,
I hesitate to call it this,
but I think it's the most powerful way
of saying it.
It's the great depression shortage of
2018.
And the problem is,
is that there still is structural
oppression.
I mean,
look at Robert Moses is design a of New
York city's a highways,
bridges and byways,
um,
famously trying to keep buses from going
to jones beach,
I guess as it jumped to jones beach.
He literally,
I mean I grew up on long island,
the bus,
the bridges going over the la at that
area are lower because they didn't want
us to bring the people from meals out
into harlem so that it doesn't affect
real estate prices somewhere else on the
east side.
So you know,
there really is structural oppression
the way there was when there were
literacy tests for voting which were
constructed so that no black person
could,
could pass because it was impossible.
Okay.
But there's less of it now and there's
not enough of it to explain some of the
differences.
And the great fear is,
is that the left program to try to
produce better representation and better
opportunities for women,
for minorities,
whatever is going to stall out if we
start to think of these things as
differences.
So.
So why is it a problem that.
Okay,
fair enough.
Why is it a problem if it stalls out
though?
Is it because there's all sorts of
radical activists who then don't have
anything to do or is there that's part
of him that.
So what you've seen with the southern
poverty law center,
which is that you have an institution
that fundamentally a accomplished much
of its mission,
but then it still had a large kitty and
idle idle hands,
it sounds like humanities departments to
me.
Right.
Okay.
And then we can get to that.
But I also want to steal man,
the other position so that you have
something to fight against or directed,
wrestle with.
If I think about I do something
different with women in the workplace
with respect to trying to figure out
what is unfair to them because there are
things that are very unfair to them and
one of the things I do is to say,
tell me about the great ideas of females
and the great contributions that are
sitting there on the table in part
because they had a female discover,
right?
So you could look at,
you know,
vira ruben's work in which never,
never got a nobel prize.
Everybody knows about it in,
in astrophysics.
But I went through one of these things
with my wife where we did this thing
with gauge theory in economics in the
harvard economics department,
and I think it was one of the most
sensational breakthroughs in a
mathematical and bedrock economic theory
and the last 25 years,
and I'll just be very clear every time
people want to figure out how to tax
americans more and cut their benefits
without paying the price of touching the
so called third rail of politics.
They realized that the cpi indexes both
tax receipts and entitlements,
so payments like social security and
medicare,
and if you can show that the cpi is
overstated than the ideas that you get
to take in more tax revenue and you get
to pay old people and sick people less.
And so it's a very popular game in
Washington to gerrymander the
gerrymander,
the measurement.
Now,
the two ways that you do that.
One is,
is that you go from a fixed basket where
you have a,
let's say basketballs and glasses and
you figure out what the price of that
basket is over time to something which
is what is the utility.
So the idea is maybe I want slightly
more glasses or basketball,
you can do it with coffee and tea.
I'm willing to trade off some amount of
coffee for some amount of tea to get my
caffeine fix if there's a problem or a
bumper crop in Brazil.
Okay.
The other thing you do is that you keep
updating these baskets and that's called
chaining.
Well,
you can't do both of those things
together because there's a,
a presumed impossibility results that
you can't have a true cost of a chain
cost of living index,
except that my wife and I solved that
problem in the mid 19 nineties at the
same time that the boskin commission was
trying to back out a,
an exact one point,
one percent overstatement because that
would save a trillion dollar.
So in other words,
you have to understand they weren't
given the task.
Go find a one point,
one percent overstatement and justify it
so that we can cut benefits and raise
taxes.
And my wife got in the middle of that
bank robbery,
uh,
as it was being attempted.
And so she got whacked.
Now I wanted to fight these sons of
bitches,
absolutely.
In particular as a professor named dale
jorgenson who spearheaded the attempt
to,
uh,
really crushed her and when,
when she was on the,
she was getting her dissertation.
This is great work and the cost of it,
Jordan is,
is that there's great work done by women
that is sitting there because
fundamentally the women don't want to
fight the way you and I would fight for
our work because it's not necessarily
fun.
It's unpleasant.
And you know,
with me,
I have a very aggressive response to
this.
It's like,
how dare you talk about my work,
do you know how much better my work is
done,
your work and let's do this now.
I got that.
That's a complicated thing too because
you know,
for,
for a piece of brilliant work to rise up
to the point where it's universally
acclaimed,
it takes a lot more than merely the
brilliant work that's like.
It's like,
it's like putting a product out into the
marketplace like a consumer product.
You might have a brilliant product,
but the fact that you have a brilliant
product is about five percent of what
you need to have a successful product
because the rest of it is sales and
marketing,
and then if so you might say there's
many ideas that we have taken stock of
that we should have taken stock of those
that we have taken stock of over this
weird combination of brilliant idea plus
brilliant and forceful marketing plus
luck.
Right,
and so,
so if,
if,
if it's the case for example,
that because women are less assertive,
they're less likely to fight those ideas
forward,
although equally likely to generate as
many brilliant ideas,
then that's going to cause a detriment
in their movement forward.
Well,
we need to contend with,
well that's what I'm trying to say,
which is that fundamentally the reason I
asked for don't tell me about the women
being suppressed.
Tell me about the Ideas of women so I
can.
I can use my aggressive as long as we
have a male dominated system.
You have men who want to fight for great
ideas.
It's good.
Well,
but then the question is,
do we have a male dominant system or do
we have a dominant dominated?
So this is,
let me,
let me tease this apart.
I have been in I think five,
almost all male field.
Um,
I've,
I've touched mathematics,
theoretical physics,
economics,
finance,
and a tech and they're not all male,
but the male dominated fields,
one of those fields I found had a
cancerous attitude towards women that
was just visible.
So I got a chance to see in finance all
of the bad behavior that people talked
about,
about the objectification,
um,
you know,
locker room talk,
which was just absolutely natural.
Not in every context,
but it was often enough in the other
fields in general.
Like in math,
I don't think I ever heard people making
nasty comments about women.
So in the same weird way,
it's not like I'm deaf to it because I
can hear it.
In one case I didn't hear it very often
and the other kids in physics,
I didn't hear many nasty comments about
women,
but it was incredible.
Particle theory for a period of time was
incredibly aggressive,
like labor economics was super
aggressive,
symplectic geometry inside of math was
super female friendly.
So there is definitely this difference
in texture between,
um,
the,
these different places in male dominated
fields and having seen relatively benign
male dominated fields at hyper toxic
male dominated fields.
I can tell you that I don't love going
into a particle theory seminar where
everybody's peacocking because it's
relatively uninteresting relative to the
work you would say to some degree that
would indicate that the,
that the system has become somewhat
corrupt in the ways that systems can be
corrupt and that what's pushing you
forward in those fields is less about
competence and more about them.
And I don't know.
Well,
I don't know either,
but you could,
you could,
you could generate
that as a hypothesis,
but I'll tell you one of the things our
psychometric work has revealed this is
quite interesting is when we've looked
at differences in men and women with
regards to outcome and then controlled
for personality.
The personality differences almost
always obliterate the gender
differences,
which means it's actually not a gender
difference,
it's a personality difference,
but let's flip that because this is.
It isn't always the general.
I understand that,
so I think that that's very important,
but now you're going to get,
because I could say then for the the
ideas of agreeable man in these fields
might be as likely to be totally,
totally agree with you.
Now here's,
here's the next part of it.
Many let's say let's.
Let's not do it as male,
female,
many agreeable people have the idea that
the problem is is that the fields are so
tilted towards disagree ability.
No,
I don't happen to believe this,
that we're losing good ideas because
agreeable people can't make progress and
in those circumstances the claim isn't.
Let's just have an open competition and
see what rises to the top.
It's let's change the structure of
things now this.
Okay,
so there's a problem wIth that.
So let let.
Let me find out what metric problem with
that.
Okay.
If you look at what predicts success in
workplaces,
generally what predicts his iq and
conscientiousness,
agreeableness is a very trivial
predictor.
Now,
one of the things you do see is that
agreeable people tend to get paid less
for the same work,
but we don't know why that is exactly.
We don't know if they don't bargain as
well.
I think that's the simplest explanation
is that they're there.
It's easier to take advantage of
agreeable people.
It's almost like the definition of
agreeable.
It's the downside of being agreeable,
but agreeableness is not a very good
predictor of workplace success.
There's actually a corrupt literature
that's associated with this because
there's a whole literature on emotional
intelligence.
Emotional intelligence puts you ahead in
the workplace.
It's like,
no,
it doesn't.
Emotional intelligence is almost in
indiscriminate from trait agreeableness
and trait.
Agreeableness actually puts you behind
in the,
especially in the managerial domain.
Now you might say,
well,
that means the managerial domain is
prejudiced against agreeable people,
but then there's some evidence that
disagreeable people make better
managers,
and the reason for that is that they
can't be pushed around because,
you know,
if you're a manager,
you might say,
well,
what you have to do is you have to deal
with the concerns of your employees and
that would be the agreeable
interpretation,
but sometimes if you're a manager you
have to take the slackers and give them
hell.
And that's,
uh,
that's somethIng that only a
disagreeable person can do this.
But there isn't much evidence on the
psychometric front that agreeableness,
um,
that,
that agreeableness is a,
is a major contributor to workplace
success in general.
So it isn't obvious to me from the
psychometric work that the idea that
hierarchies in general are contaminated
by a preference for disagreeable people.
I don't see any evidence for that.
Well,
look,
part of the problem with this whole
discussion is you have,
there are roles in which agreeability
works.
There's,
you can have a team where there's,
you need a certain balance of these
things.
It's probably works for customer
service,
for example,
to be agreeable or right carrot people.
So all of these things.
I mean,
the world didn't come up with a big five
traits a and distribute us across them.
Uh,
if they,
if they don't have advantages,
like are you color blind?
No.
father is and he can,
he can,
he can see animals in the bush as I was
going to make the point is that from my
perspective,
your contrast blonde,
right?
Right.
And the idea is that when I'm talking
about this,
that strikes color normal people as very
strange with,
well that's a strange way to look at the
world,
but the fact is is that these traits are
retained because they have different
uses stats,
right?
That is the fact that if you focus on
the right tail of the distribution of
the extreme right tail,
if you hang out with billionaires,
very often in order to get to a
billionaire status,
you have to be able to oppose large
numbers of people and say they're all
wrong and I'm right.
And then you also have to be right and
you didn't even worse.
You have to be disagree.
Absolutely right,
but you know,
if I look at some of the things that,
that my friend peter teal can do that I
find very few people can.
It's like,
can you hold a position?
Even if you know two years from now
you're going to be proven right with two
years of scorn,
the average person is going to crumble.
Yeah.
Well that would also be partly trait
neuroticism is that people have to be
able to tolerate that level of stress
and that's very,
very difficult.
This is what I'm trying to get at,
which is that people are looking at
various reward structures and they're
saying,
well,
that doesn't match my particular set of
traits and I feel that my traits are
valuable in those traits.
Probably are value,
but we're not all destined to become
beyond say or peter teal,
but what seems to be happening that.
That's exactly right.
That's exactly right,
but what seems to be happening?
I think like if you look at the
scandinavian countries,
the more egalitarian scandinavian
countries,
that's where you're getting the most
radical assortment of occupational
status by gender and so I would say for
example,
that if you tilt towards agreeableness,
which is actually a pretty good
predictor of interest in people rather
than interest in things,
the biggest difference between men and
women seems to be an interest,
right manner,
reliably more interested in things and
women more reliably interesting people.
The difference is one standard
deviation,
so it's a big difference and what seems
to be happening in the scandinavian
countries is people are sorting
themselves by their temperament,
which is what they should do because
your temperament,
as you just pointed out,
predisposes you to success in some realm
and not in others,
right?
You don't get both failure and success
and failure,
so because women are on average,
more agreeable and perhaps higher in
negative emotion,
it isn't obvious how that fits into the
equation.
there are more sensitive to the distress
of others and more likely to be
compassionate in their care.
So what happens?
You open the landscape of
competitiveness to women.
They immediately dominate the health
care field and that's exactly what's
happened now and part of the problem
with that is that healthcare as an
occupation doesn't scale well like
engineering does for example,
and so it's very difficult to generate
large fortunes in healthcare and that's
one of the things that skews the gender
distribution of wealth,
but it looks like if we left people be
to the degree that we can,
they would sort themselves into
occupations by temperament and that
might be the question of like when when
we had our first child,
we had a wrote a,
a practice where there was a rotation of
the ob gyn who deliver.
We had this one woman we were totally on
the same page with.
We loved her.
Everything about her was fantastic.
We were,
we were simpatico and my wife's labor
went on and on and on and on.
We've supposedly,
we were getting closer and closer.
Finally sheet.
This woman couldn't take it anymore and
she said,
I got to go to sleep,
and the guy that we dreaded the six foot
four guy with the bow tie who came from
a totally different era.
We called them,
the undertaker,
comes in and he says she's completely
blown,
uh,
where we are in the process.
You're barely dilated at all.
We need to deliver this child
immediately via says area.
It's like,
huh,
right.
Well,
the son of a bitch saved the situation
for my,
my wife and my daughter.
Yep.
And the idea is I didn't like them.
One absolutely mad that happens.
And that guy was a woman who diagnosed
our daughter with,
with arthritis.
Same thing.
I was really mad at her,
really mad at her.
She was very disagreeable and she was
right and let's be very clear.
PaSsion and right are not the same as
same thing.
The woman who,
the reason that we didn't have big
flipper babies for thalidomide commonly
in the United States was one woman who I
think went to university of chicago at
like 16 and she stood up and said,
I don't like the data on this drug and I
don't know,
I don't think you drug companies have
done enough to prove to me that this is
safe to prescribing to pregnant woman.
And she just put up her hand and stopped
it.
Now I don't know what I'm going to use,
son of a bitch,
son of a bitch saved how many.
And then she's a national hero and we
shouldn't be celebrating.
The issue is is that it's not down to
healthcare,
agreeable or disagreeable.
The problem is,
is that we now have so much information
about ourselves and about the
occupations and the reward structures
and there is a lot of structural
unfairness and there is a lot of
unfairness about here's your endowment
and you were given different gifts and
then there's a certain amount of luck
that we are all struggling with the idea
that we have so much information and not
enough oppression to explain this and
we're not necessarily happy with the
outcome.
We don't necessarily want to have an
honest conversation about,
well,
so then,
okay,
so there's another element to that too,
which is okay.
The question might be to what degree are
we required to tolerate a certain amount
of ineradicable suffering?
Because that's the argument you're
basically
making.
You're saying,
look,
we can,
we can equalize and we can provide
opportunity.
And we've done,
we've hit the point of diminishing
returns now,
not everywhere obviously,
and and not in every sector,
but you could make the case that we've
hit the point of diminishing returns and
stIll there is a tremenDous amount of
inequality and suffering so I can,
We don't find that acceptable at csu,
but the problem is the more you push to
remove that last bit of eradicable
suffering,
the more likely you are to produce a
worst kickback in another place.
And it's not an easy thing to contain in
the fact is that we're going to be
discussing this,
whether an nbc,
cbs or abc lIkes it and they can't do
anything about shutting this
conversation down until youtube or
twitter in a really decides to get heavy
handed and give us the boot.
And so fundamentally we don't sound like
what we're supposed to send.
Is the sound like an outright
conversation?
Does it sound hyper conservative?
No.
It's a very difficult picture.
And the key problem is,
is that the only place that's being
explored is in these super luxurious
long form interview.
I have no idea how people tune in.
Like when we went to tempe,
people were tracking these conversations
at a level that we're not tracking
conversational.
It's incredible care.
They actually care.
They know that the cognitive lego they
been handed is not capable of getting a
look surgically.
Look what's happening at harvard.
This is such an interesting example
about,
about the entire landscape.
It's like the upshot.
It looks like the upshot of the,
um,
of the policies designed to produce
something approximating equity or at
least equality of opportunity.
The gerrymandering of the admissions
process has have the number of asians at
harvard and then harvard is of course
denying that strenuously.
And they say,
well,
our selection method is too esoteric to
be captured properly by the statistics.
It's like,
oh,
that's really how you're going to do.
Right?
There's nowhere,
there's no.
The harvard math department I think had
one female mathematician,
I think it doesn't have a senior female
mathematician and I can be wrong and I'm
sure that the university is trying to
put pressure.
Hey,
what's wrong with you guys?
Get with the program.
The national science foundation is
trying to do that across the entire stem
disciplines now and they're really gonna
muck up math by,
by playIng around with this because the
data show,
it's quite interesting.
The data showed that if you look at
junior high,
there's approximately.
There's some dispute about this.
There still might be evidence that
there's a small percentage of a small
advantage demand at the highest levels
of mathematical ability,
but I'll leave that aside for now.
The more general data show that there's
plenty of gifted women and there's
plenty of gifted girls.
There's plenty of gifted boys,
but the gifted boys are gifted in math
and not verbally.
Whereas the gifted girls in math or
gifted verbally too.
And so one of the consequences is that
because math is a very specialized
opportunity,
costs are higher.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
The girls decide not to pursue.
The thing is,
is that math perfectly well tolerates
the females that it understands their
work and can't live without.
I mean,
if I think about emi,
nurturer or karen [inaudible] bag,
or do some mcdevitt,
there's a huge number of women who are
very well integrated,
uh,
you know,
in physics,
people like Lisa Randall,
I,
I don't even think about there being
women.
Mathematicians are women.
Physicists like that result,
this paper.
Right?
And the idea,
thank god for that.
Right?
But the point that I'm trying to get at
here is,
is that there are still structural
barriers and there's probably something
that isn't a structural barrier,
like for example,
the incentive structures and pay keeps
going down.
My guess is that you'll get more females
in,
which is a totally perverse effect
that's been studied that you start going
into the female and minority,
uh,
sectors when men feel that they have
higher,
uh,
opportunity cost based on their level of
aggression that they can go into
management consulting or wall street or
a sheet question is we didn't need to be
able to have the real conversation
somewhere and it needs
tonight.
We also need to have a conversation
about white.
It might be advantageous to be paid
less.
One of the reasons it's it's
advantageous to be paid less is the
demands are less on you,
so if you have other things that you
want to do with your life than taking a
job that pays less.
This happens in law all the time.
All the time.
I worked as a consultant for legal
companies for,
for law firms for 10 years with lots of
high end women and I saw the same thing
happened all the time.
It end the law.
The law firms know this right?
To the core and all the women in the law
firms know what to almost all the women
bail out of the high end positions in
law in their early thirties.
Well,
why?
it's partly because if they're making,
say they're making 350 to $500,000
a year,
they're charging a thousand dollars an
hour while the workload is absolutely
insane.
You better be buIlding 2100 hours a
year,
right?
If you're going to stay in that position
and you're on call all the time and
you're basically working 16 hour days,
but so maybe maybe what you want to do
instead is find a nine to five job that
pays half as much,
but you get to have a light more
psychotic inside of the universities.
And here's what.
Here's what nobody really wants to
discuss.
The great danger according to many of my
colleagues in
placed well placed in in high level a
science departments,
is they say the followup.
We don't know which females are going to
discover the pleasures of family after
we've invested in.
And so the idea is is that sometime in
their mid thirties,
some number of of women,
they think discover,
oh my god,
I've never been so fulfilled is when
I've had my child.
And some women say,
I can't wait to get back to the lab.
Right?
And these are two different reactions.
So by pushing the point of commitment
farther and farther towards middle age,
what you're doing is you're actually
screening out the fact that you don't
know which people you're going to invest
in and they're going to decide that they
have something more interesting to do in
their life in terms of work or that
Compelled because also has to do with
aging parents right now.
Right?
The fact is that women are more
conscientious with respect to child
rearing and with aging parents
generically than men.
And so part of the game and a function
of being agreeable,
probably a function of fitness where
yes,
the idea is that uncertain,
uncertain paternity and maternity means
that in a highly k selected species,
females are going to be ever more
focused on,
on,
on kin in this way.
Maybe that's the reason that the
differences in agreeableness evolved.
I'm not even thought about that because
while that could be,
I never thought about that,
that's likely explanation,
but the issue that fundamentally we
would defer tenure as a means of
screening out,
um,
females who are going to invest in
fertility.
That is very interesting.
If you look at feminist,
uh,
scientists in the fifties,
you have women who had four kids and
they spent a life in science and very
often you look,
you poke and prod at these things.
Well,
there was an army of servants because
there was wealth in the family in a very
often.
Right?
And so what,
what are my claim is if you really want
to do something profound for women in
technical subjects,
you should pay them more and you should
get them help in the house.
Didn't work in law.
Well,
this is the issue because to some extent
it's a question of fulfillment.
Most of them,
most of the women that I work with,
they all have nannies.
They outsourced all their domestic
duties.
Like that was covered man.
And that was part of all lemme tell you
more successful group of people than I
do because very often had the money for
if when two people can't get jobs
together and contiguous states,
you know,
it's like,
oh,
I've got a job in Oklahoma and he's got
a job in Alabama and we try to see each
other two weekends a month.
You know,
things have gone wildly off the rails,
but the key point is that employers are
playing games,
trying to figure out this change in the
Life cycle where some women are very,
very happy doing kickass work throughout
their life.
maybe they can figure out how to do it
all.
Some of them can.
Yeah.
It's pretty hard to do.
It's pretty hard to do at all.
It helps if you have money.
It does.
It does help,
but we are not owning up to what,
what are these games and what are these
differences and where should we be,
where should we be subsidized?
We're also not owning up to the fact
that that gender difference in pay isn't
a gender difference.
It's a mother difference because women
take the big hit and their salaries when
they decide to have kids that no,
it's not just that,
but that no one and nothing is ever just
one thing.
Right.
But the whole thing about equal pay for
equal work and seventy five cents on the
dollar,
right,
is that when you poke and prod at that
there is an unfairness and there is a
misrepresentation.
And the point is we're not comfortable
having open conversation about do we
want to subsidize people based on this
different than my wife has a really
interesting point.
And she said,
look,
I believe in the fish area in
equivalence between male and female is
strategies were males tend to be the
high risk,
high return,
moderate risk,
moderate return.
There was a time when wars were common
in men got called up and women didn't
have as high end prospects and
everybody's working in the fields or you
know,
washing clothes at home.
And then her point it's really
interesting is knowledge work became
wildly more fulfillinG very quickly and
the number of wars,
and this is my identity to it has gone
down.
And so suddenly it's much better to be
male in her way of thinking than it is
female in a way that was never true
before.
And so there is a novelty effect,
which is that,
um,
knowledge work is outpacing the
fulfillment of child rearing at some
level because the,
the problems that you can solve if
you're well placed to do so,
uh,
have increased in number and they're
very,
very fulfilling and there are also
disproportionately lucrative at least in
some situations and disproportionately
lucrative.
And so I,
I do think that one of the things We
have to do,
um,
you know,
look at the Vietnam war memorial and I
got like eight female names on it and
it's just,
you know,
george,
tom,
Chad,
you know,
right.
So there is this forgetting of the fact
that maleness has this huge downside,
which is the high risk part of the high
risk,
high return strategy.
Know you're point about interest in
things over people at my local pinball.
Well,
san francisco would,
you know,
I take my son there,
there's a,
there's a woman's room and they're
clearly pinball machines that are
intended to get a female audience,
but it's like 20 to one males too few
meals because it's,
it's this kind of robotic activity where
you're just putting money into a machine
and you're watching a ball and some
flashing lights.
I find it quite entertaining,
but I look at myself and I think you're
saying cigs,
man,
I'm out of my mind.
Well,
you know,
it's interesting too,
is that that high risk,
high return strategy is also not that
common among men.
It's just that the people who do the
high risk high return strategy are
disproportionately men.
And so one of the things that I've been
trying to struggle with is that like
there's a small number of people who are
hyper productive in any discipline.
That's the price's law phenomenon.
So you see,
for example,
in scientific publishing,
the median number of publications for
men and women is very similar,
immediate number,
but the people who poe,
who hyper publish are almost all made
that telimans of zach's.
That's right.
The gas box of science and then the
painful part of that is is that it's the
people it looks like it's the people who
are hyper productive that drive the
science forward,
so the median types are actually
somewhat irrelevant.
It's only the hyper productive people
that count and their disproportionate.
But even then I've heard you on this
point,
I want to take issue.
Is kurt girdle hyper productive or was
he and I would say yes he was.
Did he publish very much?
Almost nothing.
Well,
quantity isn't the one good one.
I don't think so correlated at point
three with citation count independent of
numBer of publication count is.
I know,
I know we've got.
We've got a really dangerous problem in
that.
The metrics that we've developed,
we've put way too much on and you know
that's,
that's the.
You could say that that's a universal
problem.
Be careful what you measure.
Right?
And I mean it's hard to measure
scientific impact with any degree.
This is why I'm so an unpopular in this
area,
which is I just believe in giving slush
funds to highly disagreeable people of
high achievement and say,
go figure out who you want to fund
because a lot of this stuff can't be
justified by any metric,
and by the way,
that's why I'm big on the selection end
of things.
Should you select qualified people and
leave them the hell alone?
Well,
I mean I actually working together on
this.
I mean my.
My take on this is that the best way to
get radical progress is stopped worrying
about the median individual worried
about the tiny number of people who
break new ground for everybody and then
you find that a hell of a thing for a
leftist to say,
but I mean this goes back to and back
those back to the problem I laid out at
the beginning is that if you're going to
pursue things of value in a social
environment,
you're gonna produce a hierarchy and
there's going to be hyper productivity
at the pinnacle of the hierarchy.
It's a big problem,
but if you want to produce things,
that's the problem you have to contend
with.
And so it is the case that in most
fields that are attempting to advance
rapidly that it's a very tiny proportion
of people who are doing the advancing
and how could it be otherwise?
Well,
but because oTherwise everybody would
find the advanced.
so,
you know,
I have this trick.
It was a good measure.
Well,
here's another one.
You asked the leaders in the field,
uh,
effectively who they would block,
but they will not publicly short.
So in other words,
yeah,
joe's on some crazy tangent.
A,
he's wasting the department's resources
or you know,
jane fundamentally doesn't play well on
this team and the,
I think we need to send her a strong
message.
Okay,
well why don't we say something
publicly,
but I don't know.
I don't want to say that.
Why is it you don't want to say
something.
Well,
because you're frightened that that
person has you on the losing end of
history.
So you're tryIng to block that person in
private,
but you won't short them in public.
So you use the people who fundamentally
are the regular establishment to tell
you who the most dangerous people are.
When you get those people money and you
try to decrease transparency and
accountability because giving people
freedom.
The old part of this bargain was,
it's not the best paid career in the
world,
but you do end up with freedom.
The ability to know is the and that's
gone and that's gone.
They ethics committees have killed that.
Well,
my point is,
is the accuracies if killed,
it's gotten so bad man,
but it is our job to rally for
unaccountability at a very high level.
Lack of transparencY.
You can laugh,
but let's.
Let's go through this,
right?
The fact is when you have a slush fund
and you can make decisions that you
don't have to justify based on an h
index or a citation counter,
any of these poison metrics,
you get people who are able to make use
of what we still have over places like
China.
That's What we have over a place like
China is we're a little bit richer.
not much,
maybe so we can,
but we're freer and that's mIddle
finger.
That's less middle finger.
Well,
that's disagreeableness there yet.
I know,
and I mean you were the one who knows me
over dinner over my tenure is necessary
because you could say,
well,
I'm 95,
I don't believe this,
but you could say 95 percent of people
waste tenure.
They take advantage of it and I would
say that's fine.
As long as the five percent who are
taking advantage of it have their
freedom hyper produCed and justify all
the rest of them.
Nobody has real tenure because real
tenure,
academic freedom was first of all
sacrificed by the association of
american universities,
aau in 1953 at the height of the cold
war in the face of the rosenberg.
Who's so fIrst of all,
let's be very,
very honest.
The trade group that represents the
nation's top institutions of higher
learning,
the research universities fucked up and
they killed something and I don't swear
very often.
This is very important.
They sacrificed academic freedom,
freedom on an altar when they were
facing something like we're,
we're facing with left carthy is right
when they were facing real mccarthyism,
they buckled and the einsteins of the
world stood up.
There's a beautiful testimony of a guy
who was facing senator mccarthy.
Uh,
he says,
well,
I was just talking to my friend albert
einstein.
You can see in the transcript.
He's like,
excuse me,
your friend albert einstein?
And einstein said,
look,
you have to be prepared to lose your
salary,
lose your livelihood if you're going to
be a true intellectual.
Now the fact of the matter is disagree
ability needs to make a massive warring
comeback.
Right?
And one of the things I think is just
fascinating is how many top departments
have invited bret weinstein to give a
talk on evolutionary theory after
watching him tossed out by the radical
departments?
Expect the answer to that is zero.
It's almost zero.
I don't know that it may be zero.
So is so with lindsay shepherd,
her claim for,
with wilfred laurier is that the
controversy there is controversy has
made her permanently unemployable with.
And when I read that,
I thought that's,
that's correct,
because no hiring committee will take a
risk on anybody touched who did green
fluorescent protein.
Uh,
he was supposed to get a nobel prize for
it.
He was acknowledged by the three guys
who did as the fourth guy,
they flew them to Sweden.
And what is he doing?
He immediately,
afterwards,
he was driving a shuttle bus in
huntsville,
Alabama.
One year later after the New York times
a covered doug pressure story was still
driving a shuttle bus in huntsville,
Alabama,
talking about margo tool at mit who
stood up against david baltimore and a
theresa and issue shikari,
you know,
destroyed.
Now my question is,
hey,
where are the universities?
Is it the university of chicago?
Is it down to the university of chicago?
Where are the places?
Chicago?
If you're out there,
you know,
w w we need you.
We need fundamentally strong departments
and weak administrations.
This is absolutely critical.
Is that anything on that's on?
Okay,
we need an accountability.
We need strong professors,
we need strong departments,
we need weak administrations.
We need to get people tenure radically
earlier,
like in their twenties,
late twenties,
early thirties.
We need when people have the ability to
make great new ideas,
this is not appreciated and the fact
that fundamentally nobody can hear bret
weinstein who has great interesting
theories and you want to shoot them down
by all means,
but you won't invite him to give a
seminar on his,
on his work at a time like this.
This is absolute madness and I'm so you
know,
what a privilege to be able to deal with
our tiny group of people who can
actually open their throat and say find
a much larger audience than he would
have gotten any other way.
Well,
that's exactly what I was gonna say.
Maybe marketing this all the way back
and then let's do one more thing and
then we're going to bring in shapiro,
but maybe that brings us back to where
we started about this.
The speed of technology,
the amount of people that can listen and
watch and all of that and that what
brett may find.
I just brought bread up in front of a
sold out comedy club in bellevue and he
got,
when I just mentioned his name,
he got a standing ovation.
How many of those people edit journals
of evolutionary theory so we have to get
it to them.
I get it.
It's a different set that are watching
this right now to be sad.
There's something to be said even so on.
The question front is rough,
but there's something to be said for
being able to bring your scientific
expertise to a mass audience who are
actually interested in the content of
your discourse,
so I'm not saying it's.
It's,
it's,
it's the revolution in the journals that
might be necessary,
but it's not nothing.
It's and it,
it,
it looks like there's the possibility of
bringing these things directly to a mass
audience that's appreciated.
I appreciate that,
but the thing that nobody gets about
what we're doing,
because I spend my time attacking a most
of the things I'm trying to save.
I want to save the New York times from
itself.
I want to save the university.
How old are you?
50 to do,
you don't have enough time left to do
spoken like a baby boomer and my friend,
he might know kurzweil,
you know,
what we need to do is either cure it or
kill it.
These things need to.
We can let it kill itself,
which it seems to be.
I don't have time for that.
And,
and it's not a pretty death.
No.
And the fact of the matter is,
is that it's crowding out what's next
and so fundamentally,
if it can be saved,
if they can be saved,
they need to be saved and if they can't
be saved,
if they want to keep their
finger on the scales and push everything
in this direction and the cowardice is a
palpable everywhere.
Um,
it's important that they stopped
crowding out what's next?
And I think that that's the major
decision and you know,
quite the thing to market the
marketplace might make that decision for
them.
We'll see.
Maybe it'll be fast.
Maybe it'd be fast enough.
So let's,
let's do one other thing before shapiro
is gonna.
Join us.
We're gonna.
Take a little break and have lunch and
then shapiro is going to jump in here.
So I thought this would be a good segue
too to him because we haven't done that
much political snap right here.
Is this,
is this a political movement?
Is this the beginnings of a political
movement?
No,
I,
I don't think so.
I think what it is is the,
is the,
is that conduct,
it's the conducting of proper political
discourse and maybe you could say,
well it would be a political movement to
foster the conducting of proper
political discourse.
ThAt's possible,
but it's a strange political movement
because it's a political movement that's
concentrating on process rather than,
than,
than content.
Yeah.
Um,
I think that partly what I'm doIng in my
tour is the fostering of genuine
discourse,
but I don't think that's as political.
I don't think of that as a political
movement.
I think of it as a psychological
movement or.
Yeah.
Or it,
I don't know,
our constitutional principles in the
political domain.
I would say no.
they're outside the political domain
because they're axiom,
so they're inside some other domain.
They're inside a philosophical domain or
a theological domain,
and I think a discussion that's
associated with proper political process
isn't a political discussion.
I think it's a meta political
discussion.
It would be what a better way to ask the
question and then b,
do we just need a political party or a
political group or a politician or
whatever to just pick up on this and
then incorporate it so that it's not a
movement in and of itself.
I understand what you're saying.
Well,
I've been.
I went and talked to,
um,
uh,
what's the name of that group turning
point in America?
I went and talked to everybody who was a
turning point usa.
I went and talked to their women's
meeting.
They had about 1200 women down in,
uh,
we were in dallas and one of the things
I recommended to them was that instead
of concentrating on the content of the
radiology,
because they're branding themselves in
some senses,
the conservative movement that they
devote themselves to educating
themselves as much as they possibly can
because they're going to produce a much
bigger impact by becoming better
individuals than they are by promoting
conservative doctrine.
That's what it looks like to me,
even though there's some utility in
promoting conservative doctrine on the
campuses,
at least as a counterbalance to the
overwhelming preponderance of radical
leftist thinking.
but I don't,
I don't think the fundamental movement
necessarily necessary here is political
because I think the political is
actually part of the problem.
So that's,
that's how it looks to me.
I think we're,
the advanced group said to send to take
a hill for a healthy political discourse
that follows us.
That's hopefully that,
that,
you know,
situations turning point usa.
Uh,
you know,
I was shocked that charlie kirk and
candice owens reached out to me and I
was like,
you,
you do understand who I am.
And I'm very confused by it because I
find that a lot of the rhetoric that
comes out of that absolutely unpalatable
and the private discourse is much more
sympathetic,
much more understanding.
I think that the political,
some of that's a lack of sophistication
actually on,
on the part of the people who are doing
it.
But I think we can move those guys
because just for the record,
I just want to say that when they
invited me to speaking gigs,
charlie said to me from day one,
he said,
I disagree with you on a ton of stuff,
but I want to invite you here to speak.
And I go up there and I talk about being
gay married and pro choice then faculty
and all of these things.
And they give me a standing ovation.
So yeah,
but the.
But then the problem is,
is that nobody can figure out why I'm
talking to candace owens because when
she's going in red meat conservative
mode,
I don't recognize the same person who
reached out to me.
And you know,
I don't think it is the same person.
Exactly.
I think that there's a fractionation,
they're as interested because of the
niche and the idea is that there is not
yet a niche.
This came up with Douglas Murray.
It's a super important point in general.
People are in a restrictionist mood on
immigration and they want more
protection is with respect to trade.
And the question like,
let's take within an immigration is why
is it that no politician finds it easy
to exploit,
um,
this without going completely far right
or completely open borders,
like either it's ethno nationalism or
it's all people are equal.
Why should we dIscriminate from people
in any other country?
The sensible positions are
uninhabitable.
So the question is why.
And so the claim that I'm making is you
have to really know your stuff at the
moment.
If you're going to hold a position like
we cannot be easy a phobic,
we have to be somewhat restrictionist.
We cannot close the borders.
Immigration,
I mean,
I particularly want to put your finger
on it.
You have to know your stuff to hold that
position,
but you shouldn't have to know it at
this level.
I mean,
in other words,
to work I had to do to figure out what
the hell happened with technical and
scientific immigration is a hidden study
from 1986 that nobody outside in the
outside world knew about.
Nobody can devote two years of their
life generically in order to figure
these things out.
So the problem is we have to actually
take out the ground for the middle,
get rid of the crazies on both ends and
have an idea that fundamentally,
or at least stopped the crazies from
taking out the reasonable people.
That's the issue with.
I don't we are stopping the craziest.
That's like,
well probably not because they're always
there,
but getting their hands from around the
necks of the people who are sensible
would be a useful,
at least intermediary stop.
I have learned painfully that I have
more in common with what would now be
considered center.
Right?
Than do with radical
left.
Yeah.
And so this idea of reaching across the
aisle and saying you,
you take out your trash,
I'll take out my right is a very
important move that is not happening.
And so that's.
but that's one of the things that's
weird about the candice own charlie kirk
situation is like when I went to the
aspen ideas festival,
the people who invited me there,
I wouldn't say we're there not canonical
members of the commentary.
There are people who are feeling
tremendous pressure and that's partly
why they invited me and I did get
invited,
but,
and then I discussed the things that I
was discussing,
but I wouldn't say that I felt welcome
there at all.
And so one of The things that's weird
about going to talk to these
conservative groups,
it's like I went down to dallas and I
talked to these women and I like,
I didn't give a conservative talk.
I gave this talk that I'm having right
now.
And,
but they were,
they were conservative,
but at the same time they were actually
listening to what I was saying and they
were receptive to it.
and so then when I go to the talk to the
leftist types,
it's like that,
that there are ideologically possessed,
let's say in the same manner,
but they're not open at all.
Okay.
But,
but I experienced something slightly
different.
I,
I see exactly this,
I'm more welcoming center right circles
than I am in even center left circles
because of the contamination has gotten
much farther from,
from the extreme into the center and the
left.
But there's still this other thing like,
you know,
I heard the word lib,
tarred and I'm just like,
oh,
for christ's sake,
really,
you know.
Oh,
you want to enslave everybody?
your monster.
Turn on you.
And I just think,
okay,
this is some preprogrammed set of moves.
And you know,
in your comment section,
there is much more of this stuff that
I'm used to in other people's comments.
Something about actions or not.
No,
no,
but I'm saying something about your
audience that somewhere in your
evolution,
um,
you have to watch the fact that there is
this increase in the incivility on the
right.
And,
you know,
I focus my energy on the left because
it's my responsibility.
I don't think the right is my
responsibility,
but while these people are struggling
with the same prOblem you laid out at
the beginning though,
it's like we can,
we can make the case for civility and
should but,
but you say,
well,
tHe civility only goes so far until you
defend yourself.
It's like,
yeah,
well that's a big problem.
It's like exactly how far does it go and
then how do you defend youRself and when
you're defending yourself,
what strategies to use.
Now,
one of the things I learned,
and I talked about this with dave last
night and it's something I think that we
should think about as members of this
loose group,
is that you don't defend yourself more
than is absolutely neCessary,
right?
It's a minimal necessary force.
A doctorate is the correct one and so
lived hard and that sort of thing could
probably be shelved as ineffective and
counter productive.
Right.
Although part of the reason that it's
coming up at least in part,
isn't an attempt to ineffective and
counterproductive.
It's offensive and stupid.
Well,
okay,
that's fine.
That's fine.
But,
but my point is it's actually,
it's actually technically complicated.
It's like it's not that easy to mount an
effective defense that isn't
simultaneously and attack like you have
to be very like I want to push you back
just far enough so your back,
but no farther.
It's like,
I mean that's worked out in my situation
so far because generally when I've been
a dark publicly in the press,
even in interviews,
I'd been able to use minimal necessary
force and every time that's happened
it's worked.
And so one of the things I would
recommend,
and this would be to your listeners and
viewers and props to mind as well,
perhaps two years,
is that don't push back any harder than
you have to write because it's.
It gets rapidly do it,
are balanced fashion.
A typical thing is if somebody's going
to come on gang busters,
like you have three opportunities are so
to cut it out and they refuse to it,
you know?
Yeah.
I liked the rule of three.
You've been telling them to the curb and
then I offer them a hand up.
Then the question is,
okay,
are going to bite the hand up then and
then we have a further problem because
now you're just on some sort of
unbounded,
the descent into hell and I'm not
interested in following you there,
but I think that what's really going on,
and this is the hardest point to make,
is that we need to new sort of
hermaphroditic parties that combined
elements of right and left the don't
look like the terrible situation that we
inherited from the baby boomers.
No offense sir.
Um,
where for a very long period of time
we've been under one group,
a group set of ideas that are crashing
and burning and whatever the new thing
that replaces right and the new thing
that replaces left is,
is going to have combinations of these
things.
And so for example,
maybe situation specific,
well differentiated.
Every smart person I know is pro market.
The key question is,
do you believe that the market should be
allowed to do everything?
Like you get these very purest things.
I am the,
I am an iron randy and I'm a guaranteed
free markets here.
but then you put things in front of them
and you say,
look,
should physics be allowed to sign a
licensing deal where we charge you for
everything we've created,
like the semiconductor,
you know,
or,
or the communications equipment that you
use to run your life.
because if you want to talk to me one
more time about tax dollars for science,
I'm going to point out to you that
you're breaking a compact that we had,
that you were going to support us and we
weren't going to charge charge you
because we charge you.
We're going to be the ones with the
yachts and the fourth homes and you're
not going to be able to,
to pay your physics bill.
You know,
and the point of this is when you welsh
on a contract and you start to say,
no,
it's the market.
Well guess what?
You know,
public goods are part of markets and
they're very valuable and they're hard
to get to pay for them.
And so you have to use some amount of
violence,
right?
Weber's theory is that a government is a
monopoly on violence and that's why it
exists.
When you have these very pure
ideological positions that are not
tutored by reality or deeper theory,
they are very,
very difficult to dislodge people from
now because you are taking a ton of
risk.
As a smaLl business owner,
you are going to be predisposed towards
and libertarian mindset because you're
not only making money from your hard
work.
You're making money from the fact that
you're taking on huge amounts of risk.
And when people don't identify risk
management as a source of inequality,
we've got a problem.
On the other hand,
there are a ton of people I know in New
York.
We're making money hand over fist by
extracting it through rent,
seeking by putting themselves as the
toll collector so that everybody's got
to do business,
has to pay them off in some sort of
legalized form of corruption.
And those people.
I fundamentally think we should have
clawed back their property on long
island and come up with clawback
national seashore.
Uh,
when we bailed them out in the great
recession and collapse in 2008 now,
well maybe we'll get lucky and you know,
and I'm thinking that the possibilities
that these increasingly long form,
uh,
opportunities for communication and the
rise of podcasts and the rise of audio
books and all of that is going to
produce a more educated and committed
electorate and they will be
sophisticated enough to start to sort
out these problems without recourse to
these ideological or with last recourse
to these ideological overseas still
fighting Jordan.
They're still,
they're still not coming.
I mean the number of people I know who
are privately aware of me and publicly
show no awareness of what I'm talking
about.
A actually the same thing for you.
Well,
it's a running joke.
Tilting fast was much more for you.
I mean because I think by breaking it
has to get there first and you broke
through with the book and it was,
you're doing a different thing than
anybody else in this network is doing.
But my point would be that they had to
contend with you because they had a
mystery,
which is why is there a number one
bestseller,
um,
by somebody who's,
I mean,
how do we explain any amount of this,
dave,
it's just that I come to weddings,
availed my angry young white men
followers,
but those aren't the people who are
buying funny.
And I started taking pictures with all
of the people of color and the talks are
up to about 40 percent women now and the
age at least at least the age.
The one thing I do see though is that
lots of men come alone,
but very few women come alone.
But it's about 40 percent
women now.
And I'll tell you about the group of
grandmothers that I met about a week or
two ago.
I forget what city it was,
and there was this group of grandmothers
they get together and it was,
there was about nine or 10 of them and
all in their sixties and seventies.
And they all love you and it draws in
september.
Oh.
Then you'll get all right.
You
know,
one,
one kid came up to me and one of your
talks and I said,
you know,
he started talking about how important
it was that you were there.
And I said,
well,
what is this done for your life?
This is what has it done for my life.
He says,
you know,
I was,
uh,
I was at home smoking weed,
masturbating too much,
playing video games,
and,
you know,
six months later I've got a job,
a fiance,
um,
you know,
I think he had some gal who was not
interested in because of his situation,
but liked him.
And he turned his life around.
And I thought,
this is partly what's so incredibly fun
about these events is that people just
tell that story over and over.
It's so fun because they come up to me
and they say,
look,
here's six months ago I was having all
these troubles and sometimes it's
serious.
I was suicidal.
But what was really effective,
what really affected me about this
conversation was nothing about this guy
said,
loser.
and what,
what it told me is that some of the
difficulties we've had in our markets,
particularly after post 2008,
there was this thing that worked less
and less well over time and people who
were college educated,
who were hard working,
who were creative.
We're still living at home with their
parents.
And I think it's an added kick.
It's like,
you know,
when do you hit the nitrous oxide in
order to get the car to zoom into
hyperspace?
Uh,
I think,
you know,
I.
Before I ever met you,
I had this shtick about the world uncle
shortage,
that fundamentally we needed a class of
uncles and also aunts who aren't exactly
parents to put a cigar in your mouth in
a single malt and in your hand and say,
listen kid,
this is how the world actually works.
Get the hell out there and master it.
Yeah,
don't,
don't you bucko me.
But the key issue is,
is that I think you became the one man
answer to the world uncle shortage.
And I think it's important at some point
to deepen the offering because there are
many different kinds.
like fundamentally,
I need to not focus on cleaning my room.
I have because I'm a messy room guy and
I need to get my physics out and I need
to do certain sorts of things to get my
life in order that are different.
They're not doing anything.
You could start by cleaning your room.
No,
no,
no.
I didn't.
It's not bad advice.
I know.
I know,
but it's also the case that we need
sane,
tough,
funky ants because there's a lot of bad
advice being given to women and oh well,
a lot of this radical stuff on the left
isn't going to be sorted out by matt if
it's going to be sorted out.
It's going to be sorted out by sensible
women who put it into it and I'm hoping
that will happen and just a sensible
women that I,
that I've talked to who would like to do
that are terrified,
terrified,
shredded by.
I'm so glad you sent.
Oh,
absolutely.
I hear that over and over,
and these are often women who are in
positions of substantial power.
You wouldn't think that they would be
terrified of this,
but this,
this,
this is what one of these women who will
remain nameless said to me,
she said,
I've never been afraid of men,
and I said,
well,
what are you afraid of?
And we worked through it a little bit
and she said,
I guess what I'm afraid of is weak
women.
Yes.
What an interesting observation that
fundamentally,
you know,
strong people can say that comment was a
little sour.
Yeah.
It doesn't have to be lIke,
oh yeah,
what did you say?
Because very often how many boneheaded
comments I make boneheaded comments you
make if you,
if people don't have a chance to play
with ideas and to come back from it,
if the answer to everything is your
cancel,
well then,
then there's no hope.
Well then you're not in.
You're also just not inviting people to
play with the ideas that actually they
can't play with them and never be stupid
in their initial formulations of the
ideas.
Then they don't get it on the nose.
So on that note,
I want to take my two uncles out to
lunch and then we will bring in my
cousin ben shapiro.
How does that sound?
Sounds good.
Sound good?
All right guys.
So we're going to do the second live
stream.
Uh,
this is gonna end in a second.
We're gonna.
Do the second live stream with ben at
1:00
pacific.
and be nice in the comment section
because that's what your uncle want.
Addie,
you guys.
all right,
we'll be back in a sec.