Joining me today as a sex researcher,
a neuroscientist and cohost of the wrong
speak podcast,
Dr Deborah.
So welcome to the Rubin report.
Hi,
I am glad to have you here.
Finally,
I'm so happy to be here.
All right.
We got a lot to talk about.
I thought the best way to start this
thing.
I don't like to look at my notes up
front,
but you had a line on your patrion page
that I thought summed up the whole damn
thing pretty perfectly.
Your patrion bio says creating
journalism that defends science and free
speech.
You've come to the right show.
All right.
I think so.
Yeah.
Okay.
Should we talk about sex first?
Should we just start with sex and then
can you talk about it all bleeds into
one thing.
Um,
okay.
Uh,
you started as a neuroscientist,
but you were sort of more attracted,
for lack of a better word to,
to studying sex.
Tell me about that.
Yeah,
so I mean,
I decided to go back to school and do my
phd in neuroscience and along the way I
had the chance to do a placement in
sexology.
So I'd never heard of sex research
before,
I had no idea what it was,
but it was so fascinating to me and I
thought it's crazy that we have the
technology to look at people's brains
and look at sexual arousal in the brain
and it tells us so much about what it
means to be human.
So from from there I was hooked.
I loved it.
My Phd was in using brain imaging to
look at Paraphilias,
which are atypical sexual interest and
hypersexuality and men and I love
research.
I always will.
But then I made the decision to leave
academia and work full time as a
journalist now because the climate had
changed so much.
Even between when I started my phd and
when,
when I finished.
Yeah.
And that's why the stuff that you're
talking about really is at the nexus of
everything that I'm doing here because
now you're on the journalist side,
but it's because of the hostility that
you were facing on the academic side.
So what we're.
What is it that you were unearthing are
studying that was so triggering to
people?
Well,
within sexology you can't really study
anything that isn't triggering,
I'd say across the board,
someone's going to get mad at you no
matter what,
but
no,
you're really looking at facts.
You're looking for.
You're looking to find that.
Yeah,
exactly.
And even with brandon machine,
I mean,
that's,
that's definitely,
it's a growing field.
The technology is legitimate,
but no matter what I think because
sexist still considered very taboo,
people will either project their own
ideas and beliefs and values onto it or
they just don't see the value and they
think,
why is the government funding this?
I feel really lucky being in Canada,
we do have a pretty amazing,
uh,
scene in terms of sex research.
Um,
and my colleagues do manage to get
funding.
So I think that's excellent.
But my decision to leave academia,
uh,
in the last two years I had noticed
things were starting to go a bit weird
and in terms of the climate and in terms
of mainstream media,
I was seeing piece after piece about
transgender kids and how young children
were socially transitioning.
Getting on blockers,
pubertal,
pubertal blockers,
and the media was basically saying this
is the greatest thing.
This is something that we should rejoice
about that these kids are so much better
off after,
but from a scientific perspective,
the research actually shows that the
majority of kids who are gender
dysphoric actually outgrow their
feelings.
They're more likely to grow up to be gay
in adulthood,
not transgender,
and so it makes sense for them to wait,
not for them to socially transition at a
young age.
So I wanted to write a mainstream piece
about this and there has been a very
long standing history between trans
activist and a sex researchers.
Very ugly history of activists going
after sex researchers if they don't like
what someone's study says or what they
say publicly.
So I thought about it for a long time.
I wrote the piece and I sat on it
probably for about six months and I
wasn't sure if I wanted to put it out.
I asked a bunch of my colleagues and
mentors and they all said,
you know what?
The science is solid,
but you know,
you know what's going to happen.
If you do put this out and at the time I
wanted to stay in academia and I said,
should I wait until I get tenure?
And everyone told me,
even if you have tenured nowadays,
it's not going to protect you.
You can still lose your job.
So I decided to actually I couldn't stay
quiet and I thought I'm not going to
stay in an environment where I can't
speak the truth and I can't even pursue
questions that are meaningful anymore
because I have to worry about who's
going to get mad and then I'm going to
lose my money and my funding and I'm
going to lose my job.
So that piece went out and it was called
the white transgender kids show a
transition and then I haven't looked
back since.
Yeah.
So I re-read.
I've read the piece before but I reread
it this morning,
but thank you.
Got here.
And there's a lot here.
So how much of this is just bleed is
just blatantly a misunderstanding of
science.
Like I think there's partly that you
have a misunderstanding of science and
then you just have activists who just
want you to bow to them all the time.
Are you able to sort of quantify how
much of the backlash is each?
I think to be charitable,
I try to look at the other side and give
them credit and try to think that they
have good intentions.
Maybe people.
I mean,
it's pretty consistent.
All 11 studies ever done on the topic of
distance.
So this phenomenon I talked about where
kids grow out of their feelings of
gender dysphoria,
all of them say the same thing.
So the final statistic is about 60 to 90
percent.
So this is the vast majority of kids.
You can't really question those data.
So I think what it could be as people,
I mean trans people have a history of
having to deal with medical gatekeeping
of people telling them they don't really
what they feel isn't real.
I do think gender dysphoria is a real
phenomenon and I do think we should have
empathy for people who are suffering.
Um,
so I think it could be coming from that,
of,
of that place of,
well,
we don't want people saying that this
isn't a legitimate thing or that trans
people should be forced to not feel the
way they do,
but um,
in terms of these children,
we should be thinking about the best
outcome so it doesn't make sense for
them to transition if that's not
actually going to help them in the
longterm.
I,
I to give people the benefit of the
doubt,
but I do think the activists,
they,
on some level,
I think they know that they can bully
sex researchers because of that history.
They know that there's only so much an
academic can do and they've won a couple
battles.
So I think that's part of it as well.
How shocking was it to you when you were
discussing this with colleagues,
um,
that they were kind of hinting you may
want to wait on this thing.
I mean,
did you think that you'd be in that
situation?
And I'm,
I'm wondering,
did any of them sit on some other things
because they were afraid to.
It was eyeopening.
Yeah.
Um,
but I,
I kind of knew,
um,
one one I guess instance I can talk
about is one colleague,
Michael Bailey at northwestern
university,
he wrote a book that upset transgender
activists and they went off after
ruthlessly.
I mean they really tried to destroy his
life and thankfully,
you know,
he's,
he's still considered one of the
foremost experts in sexology
internationally.
But I would say that,
you know,
I've written about him previously.
I think he's kind of been the poster
boys to why people are really terrified
to say anything that goes against the
Trans Narrative.
So I think you've already hinted at this
and I know your work otherwise,
but so you have no issue with trans
people as people.
Just to be clear,
this is purely about the science related
to transitioning and hormone blockers
and things of that nature of a certain
age where they're doing it as young as I
think you're right about 14.
Oh,
younger than that now.
Well,
yeah,
I mean if there's parental consent,
definitely.
And I have to say for a transgender
adults,
and I'd say even kids who reached
puberty and still feel that way,
I think transitioning is,
is totally up to you.
If that's the path you decide to go,
then power to you.
I don't think there's any ones,
any,
it's anyone's business to tell you what
to do at that point.
So why are there basic parameters
related to age then?
Well,
there are insurance.
So I don't work with children.
I don't do clinical work anymore.
But um,
in terms of the research literature,
usually clinicians will wait until
puberty and see how the child feels at
that time,
when the body starts changing,
when they start having crushes on their
peers and that kind of thing.
And the research does show that,
um,
when kids start to,
you know,
have crushes and start dating and that
can play a role in terms of how they
feel about their bodies and whether they
do outgrow it.
Just at that point,
your whole body is in flux.
Your mental states and physical states
in flux.
And as you said,
what,
what did you say a percentage on that?
Of How many of them turn out to just so
yeah,
so they,
so 60 to 90 percent of the children
undergoing these feelings turn out to be
gay and then I assume the ones that
don't transition,
probably most of them ended up being
okay with being gay,
I would imagine.
Roughly.
Yeah.
And I would say even like I grew up in
the gay community.
I have a lot of gay male friends and
they've said to me when I was young,
I told my parents all the time,
I hated being a boy and I want it to be
a girl and I am a girl and why can I
become a girl?
And now as a gay man,
I'm so comfortable.
I'm so happy.
And they say to me,
you know,
I'm,
I'm kind of glad I'm not growing up in
this time because I think I probably
would have transitioned.
Yeah.
Well that's why the,
the external pressure seemed so crazy to
me because you just don't know at that
at that age.
And even if you do know waiting a little
bit,
is that a,
for the science to flesh out here?
That's not going to kill you.
It's just hard talking about this
evening.
Yeah.
I mean,
the thing is,
what people also aren't talking about is
that for these kids,
in some cases the parents don't want a
gay child and this is what upsets me the
most.
So if you have a little boy who's very
feminine,
he's likely going to grow up to be a gay
man,
but if you take that same level and
allow them to transition to female,
when he grows up,
he's going to appear to be a straight
woman.
And so these parents are being lauded as
progressive when really they're
homophobic.
Oh God.
How perverse that is.
That is.
That's interesting what you just said
about a certain amount of gay men that
grow up,
you know,
they wanted to be a or it felt more like
a girl or whatever,
and then eventually grew out and we were
okay because I never felt that.
Like I played sports and I played video
games and transformers,
all the,
all the things that my friends did or I
never felt like I was a girl or more
feminine.
People always say to me,
I don't seem gay,
and I'm always like,
I don't know what that,
you know,
it ain't like I'm married to a guy
that's pretty gay,
but I never had that.
But that,
that sort of just interesting about the
psychology of gay people in general.
There are gay people that grow up
feeling very feminine or gay men that
grow up,
not feeling that way and I'm sure
there's women that grow up feeling very
butch or whatever.
And there's women that grew up that are,
you know,
lipstick,
lesbians and the whole thing.
Have you done any research on it,
on any of that?
Uh,
in terms of my research,
no.
But in terms of what studies have shown
it as about hormone levels in utero.
So testosterone,
if you are exposed to higher levels of
testosterone in Utero,
you're more likely to be male,
typical and masculine when you're born.
So whether you're male or female.
So most boys are exposed to high levels
of testosterone.
So at that explains when they're born,
why they are interested in Male,
typical toys and activities.
Um,
so for gay men they were likely exposed
to lower levels of testosterone,
which is why they're more feminine.
And the same with,
with girls,
if they're exposed to higher levels of
testosterone than more likely to be
masculine and lesbian.
Right.
Even though there's obvious outliers.
Oh yeah.
This is on average.
On average.
Yeah.
Is,
is there a danger in talking about that
because I would imagine that the certain
amount of people in the gay community
that would want you to never go down
that road because then you could end up
in a place where,
oh,
we would be able to prevent people from
being a ultimately if we can really
figure out the science behind all this.
Definitely.
And I mean,
as a straight woman,
I have to say I even,
I even right now feel like maybe I
shouldn't be saying these things because
I'm not gay.
I can't speak for the community.
But as a former sex researcher,
I am very much a proponent of A.
I'd rather you speak as a researcher
that a gay person or a straight person
or anything else.
I mean this is,
this is the problem though,
you're,
you're know what I mean,
like you weren't,
you were an expert in this and it's like
even for you who's so brave on all of
these issues,
it gets weird to talk about it.
And even for me I just,
it's like a little weird to talk
like a trader.
No,
I am what I am and that's all that I am.
That's it.
But like I know that just even talking
about this just gets people crazy and I
know what our,
what our twitter feeds are going to look
right after this,
get ready.
So I mean it's crazy because even my
colleagues who have the best intentions
are doing this research because they
just want understand why are people the
way they are.
It's not.
There are no nefarious intentions there
but people are so quick to jump on.
I mean there was earlier this year there
was a study about using ai to be able to
detect whether someone is gay by looking
at their face.
And so again,
studies have shown that on average you
can see differences between straight and
gay people.
Both men and women in terms of facial
features and so everyone's freaking out
about this study and I'm thinking,
why aren't we saying this is amazing
that we're able to know this?
And I mean,
I think I've really good Gaydar I've
always thought I have and now I think
great,
like there's actually some quantitative
data to suggest that I'm not just making
things up.
Right?
And they're also,
they always say,
well gay guys have Gaydar something else
that maybe you can see or whatever it
is.
Or they'll.
I don't know the people say it anymore,
but people used to say gay face.
Like there's just something about the
facial features sometimes of gay men.
Maybe they were a little softer or
whatever it is.
I don't even know what it is,
but like people were talking about that
in the gay community.
Then it comes out through some sort of
science lens and it's like,
Ooh,
we better watch out for that.
And the thing is then researchers see
that and say,
well I don't want to go through that.
So then they don't want to touch that
topic.
So now there's,
they're eventually going to be only like
two different things you could probably
study unless you know that what your
findings,
what you're going to find is going to be
politically acceptable,
in which case you shouldn't be doing the
research because that means you're not
actually doing science.
Yeah.
What do you think it is about you that
makes you brave enough to do this sort
of thing?
Because I bet a couple of other people
we're going to talk about James Debord a
little bit because you've also written
about him and why the whole thing about
diversity and all that,
but I've had a bunch of outliers in
these communities on the show and I'm
always curious what it is about the
specific people that make them sort of
put it out there and go,
I'm going to do it.
Whether you like it or not.
It's probably my personality.
Yeah.
I mean I just generally don't really
care what people think about me and I'm
pretty stubborn and I.
I'm very.
I feel very strongly about sex research
being taken seriously and my decision to
go on it and gone into that field that
you deal with a lot of stigma as I
mentioned earlier.
You deal with it on both sides,
you know,
and when you make the decision to go
into the field,
suddenly when people know what you do,
they will judge you on a personal level.
So I think that was part of it.
You know,
I grew up very thick skin from saying
I'm going to do what I find interesting
and people can assume whatever they want
about me and that I think that just
translated into now what I do as a,
as a science journalist,
but the,
I would say too,
and I'm sure you probably went through a
similar experience once you speak out,
it becomes much easier and I find I
can't,
I can't stay quiet now.
And I find the people that are gonna,
you know,
turn their backs on you let them because
you don't need them in your life.
Yeah.
Once you start,
you can't stop.
Actually,
it's built into you.
You just can't stop.
So one of the things I think is really
interesting is how,
you know,
there's such a movement always to say
that gay people are born this way.
Right.
Lady Gaga even wrote it down on the
bathroom floor in this way and yet at
the same time,
if I know for a fact,
like I have a friend who for many years
was my lesbian friend,
my one good lesbian friend and she was
dating girls all the time and all that.
Then about three years ago we were
sitting there and she told me that she
met a guy and now she's been with this
guy for about three or four years and
they're getting married and she's
identified as basically as bisexual now,
but she's only.
She's exclusively been with a guy for
about four years.
But what I find interesting about it is
that her lesbian friends have basically
all turned on her and this is supposed
to be the.
These are supposed to be the people of
tolerance and we should accept your
sexuality and all that.
But when it goes the other way,
suddenly it becomes this other thing.
Have you have.
You seen that before?
Do you have.
I can imagine that I'm.
I'm guessing they probably think that
she sold out.
She's a sellout or something.
Yeah,
you're taking the easy road or something
like that.
Like every insane cliche and I know her
to be completely authentic and real.
How does,
how has she dealt with it?
I'm curious.
It's been.
Well,
it's woken her up in a zillion other
ways,
so for a lot of the other things that we
talk about about free speech and
politics and freedom and all that,
she's started to wake up to all of that.
She was a huge lefty progressive and now
she's basically a libertarian because
she saw that authoritarian thing.
Why do you guys want to control me?
The second I think differently.
You guys want to control me,
so now she's like the
good stuff.
All of my friends so to speak.
That's the thing.
I think all of us are eventually going
to have a moment like that where you
realize what you thought was the truth
is not the truth and there's so many
other things.
It's like falling down that rabbit hole
and real and you start to question
everything then,
and it's really liberating.
But uh,
you know,
in terms of sexuality,
that's.
I mean that's very common.
Women,
female sexuality is much more fluid than
men.
Some men tend to be very category
specific.
If you're into women,
you really like women.
You're not two guys.
If you're into guys,
do you guys not to women than women tend
to be a little bit more flexible.
It's like you find,
you know,
there are supposedly straight married
men that on the dl or sleeping with
other guys,
but I'm pretty sure there aren't many
gay men that are in relationships are
married that are sneaking out and
sleeping with women.
No.
Have you ever seen one of those who?
Your research.
Okay.
There's a,
you know,
I think the first case I think is
probably closet gays and then the second
case I have to think about that
gay man.
Well,
I guess you might be sleeping.
Yeah,
I mean I did it like I slept with women
as sort of like a,
an overcompensation or I was trying.
It's not even overcompensation.
I was really trying,
I just thought I should try.
I and tried.
I tried and you know,
eventually I tried no more.
Yeah.
I think also for gay men when you come
out,
it's such a big thing and I think to
make that decision to come out is really
committed to this as much as you know,
we don't like identity labels.
It is an identity label.
So I would see it as being less common
for someone who's gay to be sleeping
with women on the side because he would
have likely just stayed in that camp.
That would be my guess.
Yeah.
So.
Okay.
So you mentioned that you,
you study a lot of this related to the
brain,
how a lot of this is sort of built into
us and you studied this across sort of
fetishize the right word.
A paraphilia is,
yeah,
fetishes,
a specific pair of failure,
but um,
across the board basically.
So wait,
what's the definition of Paraphilia,
uh,
unusual sexual interests and how's that
different than fetish?
Well,
if fetishes,
a specific object or body part that you
have a preference for.
Got It.
So,
uh,
so let's talk about a couple of those
located.
There are a lot of them,
so I always,
I tell people this and no one ever
believes me,
but I'm actually very,
very traditional vanilla,
not kinky.
Love it.
You're going to ask you all that at the
end about yourself.
Good.
Okay.
Yeah,
but I mean,
I'm fine.
It's super fascinating and I guess it's
my way of living vicariously,
you know,
so in terms of different paraphilia is,
I mean there's a foyer ism is known as
peeping toms and exhibitionism,
so people like to expose themselves a
sadism and masochism which are different
from bdsm.
Bdsm is consensual masochism,
sadism.
So masochism being,
wanting,
wanting to be humiliated.
Sadism is one,
just your partner,
be humiliated.
Bdsm is very much about consent,
so it's not true masochism or sadism
because a partners will negotiate
beforehand and not do anything outside
of particular boundaries and that kind
of thing.
Uh,
what else is there?
Fraud or ISM.
So it's when people like to rub up
against unsuspecting people,
there are tons I could go on forever.
Yeah.
And so how are these all connected to
the same parts of the brain?
Is it the same mechanism that's working
in the fetish itself is just manifested
in
different targets?
Yeah.
So with my research,
when I was still a researcher,
I found that for men who are Kinky,
when they look at kinky pornography,
the same brain network activates as when
non kinky people are looking at regular
or vanilla pornography.
So it's adjust that paraphilias maybe
akin to a sexual orientation.
So it's not to say that's the same as
being gay,
but it's the same idea conceptually that
it's someone's preference.
It can't be changed.
Um,
and it's with them from,
from very early on.
Yeah.
How does the Internet play into all
this?
Because I know you've written about a
porn and things like that where now all
of this stuff is so accessible where
obviously even 15,
20 years ago it was a lot harder to get.
Yeah.
I think people are probably able to test
out different things and go searching
for things out of curiosity.
But if you really like something,
I don't think it's because you happened
to find it on the Internet and with porn
addiction in particular,
there's no research to suggest that it's
a real thing that excessive porn viewing
is akin to an addiction.
Usually if you talk to someone with
problems with porn across the board,
it's,
there's always some other reason why
either they're anxious,
they like to procrastinate.
Well,
they don't like to procrastinate,
but they use it as a way of
procrastinating and avoiding other
things.
It's not that they're actually addicted
to pornography.
Right?
So when you hear though that people will
say,
well,
you're getting that dopamine.
Isn't that partly what being addicted
you?
Wouldn't you become addicted to that?
What?
My understanding of the term addiction
slightly incorrectly.
That's true.
Um,
but dopamine is released during the
number of different things.
If you eat a nice piece of food that you
like dopamine's released,
um,
if you see a nice picture,
dope,
mean reward,
but it's responsible for a lot of
different things.
So I think that's one case of.
I mean,
I do have some issue with science
journalists watering things down and
liking to take one finding or one study
in kind of a,
you know,
representing it or misrepresenting it.
So it's not really an accurate take on
it,
but I understand why people think that
because dopamine has been seen as the
addiction neurotransmitter and then you
see so much about porn,
porn,
addiction,
sex addiction.
I'd say probably a year ago it was
everywhere.
Everyone was talking about porn and sex
addiction even though they're,
again,
there's no legitimate research to
suggest that those things are real.
Hmm.
So when you've studied all of these
things,
what are,
what are you finding out about the brain
as a neuroscientist and can anything be
done for any of these things?
If somebody was partaking in these
things and either didn't want to or at
least wanting to understand it or
whatever else.
The biggest thing I would say is find a
partner who accepts you for who you are.
Whatever you're into.
Especially for men,
it's not going to change.
And so the difference between someone
who has
so meaning women's kinks or whatever
will change with time where a man would
be less inclined to.
Yeah.
The same with,
you know,
in the same way with the sexual
orientation,
women tend to be more flexible with
their sexual preferences.
So if are Kinky,
they might be really kinky with one
partner or if they have a partner who's
very kinky,
they might be into whatever he's into if
it's a straight couple.
But then if she's with someone who's
less Kinky,
it might not be as much of a problem.
Whereas if it's a man who's really into
something,
if his partner is not into it,
he's always going to be into it.
He's just going to have to hide it.
Yeah.
Have you heard of this phrase,
lesbian bed,
death.
I'm all,
I'm all over the place.
I'm just going into the fall and seeing
come up with.
Have you heard this phrase before?
It's means that there's no sex after a
certain amount of time.
Yeah.
That lesbians,
it sort of burns very hot for that early
period and then the u haul shows up as a
joke and then just like the,
the desire for sex just disappeared.
There's just lots of cuddling.
I haven't heard of that.
Well,
men on average do tend to have a higher
sex drive,
so I could see if you're in a
relationship where it's two women,
how uh,
this,
you know,
their sex drive might be a bit lower.
Not sure what else?
Like what,
what are you really thinking about right
now in general?
What are the topics that are really on
your mind related to all this?
My concern number one is probably seeing
how gender is being warped to facilitate
particular political agendas.
Um,
as you mentioned the James Damore and
seeing how that whole thing unfolded
last summer.
Okay.
So let's talk about that.
Could you wrote a piece on it?
I remember the piece coming out.
Yeah.
Um,
so I remember when that news first
broke,
uh,
that this sexist memo was going around
and I read it and I thought,
okay,
this is not sexist.
And then I saw the statement from Google
that he was perpetuating gender
stereotypes and I thought,
oh no.
And so I wrote that column for the Globe
and Mail to speak to the science and
say,
you know what the science said James
cited was absolutely 100 percent
legitimate and there shouldn't be
anything wrong with saying that.
And if you actually read his memo,
you'll see that he's not a misogynist.
And we actually saw the podcasts that I
cohost with Jonathan Kay called wrong
speak.
We actually interviewed him for our
first episode and if you listened to him
speak,
you'll,
you can see,
I mean,
he's very much for equality between the
sexes.
He says that if men and women don't talk
to each other,
that's going to harm both of us.
Um,
but it was much easier for them to paint
him as a misogynist and as an outright
failure because I guess,
you know,
there's nothing else going on the news.
Did you feel that the article,
or at least when James was able to get
out there and say what he thought,
whether he did it here or,
or on Rogan or a series of other
podcasts,
did you feel that that was able to break
through to some of the people that
needed to break through to like,
I know it gets to the masses,
right?
It gets to the people who appreciate
maybe what happens in here or on Rogan
or things like that,
but for any of the people that really
need to hear it,
the ones that are at Google or the ones
that are setting the diversity agenda at
schools and all that,
is there any sign that any of this,
a pushback against it has taken root?
No,
I think it's gotten worse,
if anything,
honestly,
which is terrible.
Um,
I think they are so set in that mindset
that you really can't.
You can't say anything.
I think reasonable people if you talk to
them.
I was surprised actually at that time
because a lot of people that I knew that
were really intelligent,
really rational had bought into this
narrative that he was a sexist person
who said that women are biologically
inferior and are not capable of
engineering or working in tech,
and I said,
well,
why don't you think that?
Did you read the memo?
And most people had not,
but then because the left wing media was
so adamant about this message,
people just assume,
well,
they're not going to lie.
Why would they lie and you know,
we are in this industry,
so of course we know,
but I think most people just take it
face value.
They're.
They have their jobs and so they see a
headline or they see an interview.
They just think,
well,
I like a mainstream interview.
They think,
well,
they wouldn't be saying these things if
there wasn't some truth to them,
but no,
they.
They're blatantly lying.
Has all of this and being part of this
and being very public about your
opinions.
Has this changed your politics at all?
I find that it consistently has changed
people's politics.
Usually it shifts people to more of what
I would say as a classical liberal
position,
but what a libertarian,
just more of a less government position
because you want.
Because that's where I think at the
moment,
the most freedom lays.
Yeah,
I would agree with that.
And especially the idea of the
government.
I used to.
I used to be definitely more left,
much,
much more left.
Um,
I was still calling myself a liberal,
but definitely now that I see because I
used to think was good for the
government to come in and help people
and to kind of set the tone.
But now now I'm seeing things that are
not hate speech or being considered hate
speech and genuine facts.
We're not allowed to say them anymore.
So I'm much more skeptical now of
government intervention of policies
dictating what people can and cannot do
or say.
So I would say I have moved more to the
right,
but I would still call myself a liberal.
I mean,
the fact that I write about sex research
for a living is pretty low.
Yeah.
You're my kind of liberal.
So you're,
you're good to go.
In here,
so one of the things that I think is
fascinating about all of what we're
talking about here is that it's not just
about gender and sex and sexuality,
but this is also leaking into all sorts
of other things,
talking about ethnicity and color of
skin and all of that.
Uh,
you've written a bit about this.
I have,
yeah.
I wrote about how a university
applications,
and particularly Harvard has been
discriminating against Asians for
decades and how to the point where
Asians,
when they apply to university,
will want to hide their ethnicity in
hopes of that.
That's going to give them a fair chance
of actually getting into.
So the school.
So.
All right,
so somebody that's watching this right
now that doesn't know about this,
they're gonna go,
wait a minute,
why would harvard discriminate against
Asian people?
Because apparently there are too many
Asians there.
If it's based solely on sat scores and
meritocracy,
um,
there's a very high proportion of Asian
students.
And so in the name of quote unquote
diversity and inclusion,
um,
Asian students get penalized.
So this to me is the most blatant
example of why this diversity stuff is
complete nonsense because people on face
value,
it seems nice.
We want to help people,
we want to help groups that maybe have
struggled more for whatever reason and
there's probably many good ways to do
that.
Maybe investing in more education or
whatever else.
I'm happy to hear your thoughts on that,
but what they take as a good thought
then they don't think all the way
through,
which means okay,
now we're going to have to punish people
who have worked very hard and done
everything right.
And by and large,
the Asian community,
whether it's Chinese or Japanese or
Korean or whatever else,
have
worked really hard and put a focus on
education and family.
And then what is the result of that?
It's now harder if not almost impossible
at some level to get into Harvard.
And the craziest thing,
I don't understand why people think is
acceptable.
And even when I wrote that column,
I had a number of Asians reach out to me
and say,
you know,
don't,
don't be used as a token for the far
right.
And I'm totally okay with this,
this is fair.
And I'm thinking,
you know,
what are you on the times?
Do an op Ed,
I think by an Asian woman coming
mistaken.
Yeah.
Saying that this is okay.
And I just,
I mean,
what do you do it that you are fighting
for true equality that is simply not
what they're fighting for.
I think it's indoctrination at some
level.
I think especially for the kids who are
applying to these schools and who are
okay with having to score much higher on
the sat in order to get a fair chance.
I think they've just been told,
you know,
this is how it has to be,
um,
but this idea that it should be equality
and equality of outcome as opposed to
opportunity is,
is silly and it doesn't actually deal
with actual differences in terms of
opportunity,
in terms of the differences that we see
and the reasons why there are these
differences.
They're not actually being addressed.
Please tell me that you got some nice
support from members of the Asian
community that it wasn't just sort of
brainwashed lefties that were.
I didn't know.
I didn't,
I got across the board of,
of,
you know,
many races,
so I was grateful for that because I
wasn't sure how people were going to
respond to that piece,
but I felt very strongly that I had to
say something as Harvard issued a
response to any of this or do we even
know where they're at with all this?
No,
as far as I know that the lawsuit is
still ongoing.
It's just,
it really is just crazy.
So are you with me on this?
I sense that there's some massive
minority groups that are breaking right
now.
I think the Asian community,
because of the,
I hate saying community,
but you know,
you have to use some words to describe
how this.
But I think the black community is
breaking.
This is what a lot of what candidates.
Oh,
is talking about.
I sent to this happening in the gay
community.
I sent to this happening in the Jewish
community on very similarly because of
the Asian community,
because of hard work and an education
and all that.
And so did you decide yet we have to put
you at the bottom of the oppression
Olympics.
Um,
so there's an interesting like,
strange alliance now,
now building up or are you seeing that?
I could say yeah,
I see it coming.
I see.
Well,
we were talking about the bit about this
earlier,
about how the left is going to eat its
own until there is only one person left.
So it's only a matter of time really.
We're all going to find each other and
say,
yeah,
we've had enough of this.
I mean,
gay men,
you guys don't count.
It doesn't count to begin anymore.
So,
um,
but I never wanted extra credit.
I wanted equality,
equality,
equal credit,
not extra credit.
In a weird way.
I'm actually okay being thrown out in
that regard of this pyramid because I
don't want to play that game.
But I think actually finally some gay,
especially
gay white men because now they're,
they're fully thought of as the enemy.
I mean,
I've even seen things on college
campuses where lgbt organizations are
saying,
well,
you can't be a gay white man and be the
president of the organization because
you're,
you're one of the bad guys.
I mean that.
That's really dangerous thinking.
Well,
I saw what you had to deal with too at
that professor who said that the lgbt
community doesn't want you at the.
Was it the University of University of
New Hampshire?
Yeah.
Do you know that?
So I didn't know at the time,
so I think much of my audience will know
what you're referring to.
But I spoke at University of New
Hampshire and there were all these
heckler's there and there was a trans
woman who I did not know was a
professor.
I didn't know that until literally two
months later who was screaming at me how
much I hate trans people and all this.
And I kept saying,
I want you to have equality under the
law and I want you to be treated with
decency and respect and I hope you find
someone that loves you and all of the
things I would want for anyone else.
I just don't want the government using a
dictating what pronouns I can use to,
to refer to you and you know,
basically she was calling me all right
and all that it did.
And of course it turns out she's a
gender studies professor.
Yeah.
It should never be a surprise anymore,
but there's gonna be no discipline at
the school or anything like that.
I mean I could probably make more of a
hey,
have it and see what happens,
but it's like,
yeah,
you know,
you handled it amazingly well and I mean
it's only a matter of time.
Like I see with feminism,
they're turning on white women now too.
So it's insane.
Is that the only logical outcome of
these disciplines because they are not
held to the scientific standard of
everything else that we discussed here
in the first app that you,
that you are held to as a scientist?
Yeah,
I think because everything is,
there's so much based in subjective
feeling and validating people's
experiences.
You apparently can't question someone's
experienced.
So if someone's offended or they don't
like you,
what can you say?
So I,
I could see that and it's,
it's very much rewarding people for
being emotionally driven instead of,
I think the best way to have a debate as
to remove emotion and just try to look
at the facts as objectively as you can
no matter what the issue is.
So,
um,
it's that,
it's,
that they don't really have any sort of
method to how they do their,
even their research is,
I mean,
it's kind of a joke,
but rob kind of hearing that even the
methods now are part of the patriarchy
and all of those things that you're
using facts,
they don't want facts to actually count
because they believe in this postmodern
drivel that,
that facts have been arrived to by
mechanisms that they don't believe in.
That's a,
that's a tough thing to trick somebody
out of.
Yeah.
But you know,
I think on some level,
I think some of these scholars know that
what they're doing is very lucrative.
And so they're just basically trying to
shut people down in any way they can.
They can't really justified,
but you know,
they just keep screaming about it and
academics who have better things to do,
like actually do real research and
they've got their courses and their
students and a million other things and
their 80 hour work weeks,
they don't have time to deal with this.
So this is why there's a lopsided
discourse in terms of what you see
coming out of the universities and there
are some institutions that,
you know,
they won't allow academics to engage
with the media without permission for.
So that,
that's part of it too.
It's just,
it's really an unfair battle right now
that's being fought.
Yeah.
How do you think we get to a place where
specifically related to sexuality and
topics related to gender and sex,
where we will be able to talk about it
in a,
in a better way.
So for example,
the me too movement where everybody I
every,
I think basically thinking person
understands that there were some really
bad people here that did some really bad
stuff.
Obviously Harvey Weinstein and Bill
Cosby and some people that really that
drug people in that you know,
years of history of doing all this and
then there's all sorts of other people
who seem like they're just getting swept
up in it or basically accused all that.
Now you can be for the idea of the me
too movement without being,
for taking down.
All of these other people are also,
and I guess what the real issue is
litigating everyone's history where we
could all look back and go,
I did this.
Someone did that to me,
this,
that,
the other thing.
College kids now have an assigned things
before they hook up.
I mean really where we're creating this
situation where our interpersonal
relations are going to have almost
nothing to do with the stuff that's hard
wired into us.
The stuff that you study
[inaudible],
I think me too probably started as
something honorable and I do agree that
women and men have been dealing with
harassment for far too long and that it
doesn't get taken seriously sometimes,
but it's to the point now where
relations are so strained,
especially between men and women.
I,
I sense men are terrified and that's not
going to be helpful across the board for
anybody.
Um,
I think especially when you look at
shades of gray,
well,
I mean there's so much I could say on
this.
I'm trying to think what's the best
place to start would be,
um,
with consent.
Say I think one message that's been
missing is women I've written about
this.
Women need to advocate for themselves
and that's not to say if you were
experienced harassment or if you were
assaulted that you are at fault.
I'm not advocating victim blaming,
but I think what's missing from this
narrative,
women are portrayed as though they're
helpless and if something happens to
them,
they're helpless and that,
uh,
they're basically,
they have no say in terms of how men
behave towards them.
And you,
I've written about sexism in the
sciences and how women are basically
being scared off,
I think of going into the field.
Um,
as someone with a phd in a science
field.
Yeah.
You deal with sexism and it's
unpleasant.
But I still got my degree and now I'm
speaking out about it.
So if you want to achieve something,
you can,
uh,
sexism is not so terrible in the world
that women can't achieve what they want.
So going back to consent,
you know,
I think women need young women
especially,
you needed to be told,
you know,
you have a say in this if you don't like
something or if you don't want to do
something,
say so,
don't,
don't feel like it's on the man to um,
I know,
read your mind and I feel like I'm going
to get in so much trouble for saying
this,
but I think that empowers women instead
of telling them,
you know,
just really hope that this doesn't
happen to you.
And if it does,
then get on twitter and use the Hashtag
and talk about how men are terrible and
men are trash.
Men are not terrible.
They're lovely men in the world.
I love men.
You know,
there are some bad men,
but you can't generalize to all men.
Yeah.
But we love the generalizations.
It's easier.
I mean,
you even see this,
the amount of articles where I see,
you know,
we have to take down white.
It's always white men that we have to
take down or,
or now it's women's turn to rule the
world or all of these things and it's
like,
well,
a woman could be president or a woman
could be,
you know,
anything that a man could be,
but it shouldn't be because she's a
woman.
It should be because she's capable,
but,
but we've seen this sort of hysterical
reaction to it and I think that that now
is just another one of these places
where we're on this crazy pendulum just
bouncing back and forth.
Yeah.
I'm hoping it's going to come back to
the middle.
Um,
and hopefully not too much damage will
be done before that happens and that the
relations between men and women or I
couldn't be so terribly strange.
Um,
I do think we're reaching that point
though because there are only so many
men left to have it been accused of a me
too moments.
So,
you know,
it's only a matter of time.
You know,
it's interesting.
I have a running joke with some of my
friends that I know a lot of great
straight girls in La that are single lot
of straight great girls.
I don't know,
a lot of straight guys that I think are
great.
Like I know I know some straight guys
that are kinda whatever,
but I don't know like a lot of straight
guys that kind of have their shit
together that are.
So I have all these girls that are like,
okay,
you set me up with a guy and I'm like
not guys I know,
which does show that there's sort of a
crisis I think in masculinity or
something.
And,
and obviously Jordan Peterson is
addressing this at some level,
although now I've spent so much time
with him.
I think he's addressing it in a certain
way.
You almost equally for men and women,
although people only focus on the male
part.
But do you know,
is anyone doing research on sort of what
is happening to young men in particular
right now?
Hm,
that's a good question.
I know that uh,
levels of testosterone are lower on
average more recently.
So I don't know if that has something to
do with it.
Do we know what the reasoning for that
is?
Could be.
Maybe there's more estrogens that are,
that we're putting into our bodies.
I'm trying to think of what I can give
you [inaudible].
That's an interesting.
So how old are your friends?
I'm curious.
Um,
this sort of set of friends that I'm
talking about.
These girls usually are in,
they're sorta like early thirties.
Yeah.
Kind of thing.
And they're,
and they're single,
which,
you know,
most often cases,
a lot of them,
their friends are married already and
like they're,
they're on the hunt and they've got good
jobs and they look good and they take
care of themselves and all of those
things.
And I just don't see the equivalent
here.
I don't know,
maybe there's an odd subset of.
Because la is like a little bit of an
odd place.
Maybe there's more gay people here.
I don't,
I don't know.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I mean,
I could say the average age for people
getting married as 28,
so I don't want to,
I don't want to generalize and say that
across the board you sciences,
it's incredible and to be fair,
yeah,
but I mean it could be that for guys who
are a certain age,
if there's a reason,
but at the same thing for women of a
certain age,
and not to say that your friends of
course,
but um,
you know,
if you're focused on your career,
maybe you're not used to giving your
time to someone else.
That could be part of it.
Yeah.
Do you think that the feminist movement,
which I know is sort of,
we sort of ancillary been talking about
it this whole time that they really did
give up something very special by
putting so much focus on work and
success in that way.
I mean,
you know,
I think back to my childhood now,
which I think in retrospect was so
amazing.
My mom was home for most of it.
She,
she worked before.
I'm the oldest of three.
She worked before I was there and then
she didn't work all the years that she
was raising us and then went back to
work after,
um,
and that having someone at home that was
cooking and taking care of us and making
sure we got to school and all of those
things,
like,
that's like the greatest thing that
anyone could do.
It happens to more often be the woman,
but that's a,
that's a pretty great thing.
That's often been sacrifice.
Now we're thought of it.
It's marked in a way.
Yeah.
I mean,
I've always been a atypical in terms of
I've,
I've always been felt more masculine.
I've always been very focused on my
career.
Um,
but I definitely think that feminism and
for some people it or some proponents of
feminism,
they will denigrate female typical
roles,
um,
and motherhood and wanting to be a,
you know,
at home with your family.
And I think I've,
you know,
I've heard from women who say,
know,
I've been told that the path to
happiness is for me to focus on my
career and to neglect my personal life.
And then they reach a point where they
realize,
no,
I do want those things and I don't think
there should be anything wrong with
that.
And the same thing,
you know,
I've written about how there's such an
emphasis for,
for girls to be like boys now I saw you
tweet about babies,
babies.
And underlying that is a sexism that it
says that girls need to be like boys in
order to be equal or worthy of respect.
And no one's talking about that where
people are just saying,
yeah,
for sure.
Let's just,
you know,
tell girls that they have to be the same
as boys and women have to be the same as
men.
Yeah.
So the article you're referring to,
there was this piece,
I think it was in Newsweek that these
parents are raising their twins as
Fabian t,
h e y babies,
babies,
uh,
and they're going to let them pick their
gender and it's like you're going to
create more psychological problems then
you were trying to hide them from most
likely,
I think.
Yeah.
And it goes back to biology again,
and hormonal exposure in utero.
You,
I think it's great.
Yeah.
It might've been NBC news I think.
Okay.
Yeah.
Newsweek.
Okay.
Yeah.
But yeah,
I think there are a couple outlets that
were so excited about this and the
whole,
that was why I wrote about it.
Not because of the thing,
you know,
these parents can do whatever they want
and that's what I followed up with
immediately after an appearance can do
whatever they want and then when the
children are of age,
they can either decide my parents were
crazy or not write this on the parents.
Right.
And all that.
But it was.
But that wasn't the issue for me.
It was that the way these headlines are
always written,
it's like that this was like this is the
new thing and the implicit piece of that
is you better do this to be a good
parent,
to get tolerant parent to be a
progressive parents and that open minded
person.
And that to me is the danger here.
Not The little isolated case necessarily
have these people that are doing
something.
That's an outlier thing.
And the thing is,
I've heard stories now where people are
terrified of giving their daughters
dolls and which is what's really funny
is you have some of these really
progressive parents who raise their
girls.
They only have gender neutral toys or
they give them boys toys and then the
girl obviously goes to school and sees
girl typical toys and wants to play with
them.
And the parents were horrified and they
think,
oh,
this is the patriarchy coming in return
of the is biology and we shouldn't be
afraid of that.
And we shouldn't.
We shouldn't shame girls for wanting to
be female.
Typical.
Yeah.
But this is why when people say,
I think to a bunch of us that are in
this space,
this,
oh,
you guys are overstating what this thing
is.
It's just a bunch of angry activist or
whatever.
It's like we've seen it,
in fact,
academia,
which you addressed already.
We've seen it,
in fact,
the home and how you're supposed to
raise your kids.
Even just thinking about this now,
it's like,
I think I read something on this and
that and if not there's definite proof
of it that Disney made a decision along
the way.
Now that they have star wars and marvel
that star wars was going to be more
marketed to girls and marvel was going
to be the boy's thing.
Now I'm a big star wars guy and I would
see these commercials and it was all
girls,
you know,
girls in the ships and grows with the
light lightsabers live.
I have no problem with that.
Obviously a rave,
a leading character.
The last one is a girl.
It's all good.
The girls can do that,
but.
But pushing marketing on them seems odd
to me.
And,
and although I'm sure there are many
girl girls out there that want to be a
jetta I,
there's obviously more boys.
So the way that we even market and I
suspect they're marketing in a way
that's hurting their bottom line in the
name of tolerance in the name of what I
don't know.
Yeah.
So I mean,
how did the boys feel about that?
Right,
right.
So you're going to get this odd thing,
then we'll eventually,
if there enough marketing boys are going
to want to play with the girl thing and
then feel weird about it.
God,
that's messed up.
How much time did you have?
Too much time on their hands.
Yeah.
Just say like kids do what they want and
acknowledged that as long as you give
them free choices,
you probably won't have too much say at
the end of the day,
but at least you know,
they,
they'll be happy.
Yeah.
Uh,
is there anything else that you're
researching at the moment or that's been
on your mind that,
uh,
that we haven't covered?
Uh,
the only thing I would say is,
so with [inaudible],
we are going to be launching our second.
We just launched our first season last
month.
Um,
so spoke with James Damore,
Lindsay Shepherd.
We also did an episode on rapid onset
gender dysphoria.
So it's this phenomenon of adolescent
girls who were suddenly saying they're
transgender even though they've had no
previous signs of gender dysphoria and
actually their problems have nothing to
do with gender.
So what are the problems?
That's just societal stuff or pressure
or wanting attention or all of the
above.
Usually autism as well,
so they either will be diagnosed by a
mental professional,
but the person will say,
I can't say that I have to,
you know,
affirm your child's gender.
Um,
because they can otherwise get a lot of
trouble and lose their jobs if they
don't,
um,
you repeat that again so that they will
lose their jobs if they don't have to
affirm their.
They have two clinicians nowadays have
to affirm these kids.
If a child says they're transgender and
you have to,
they'll lose their jobs otherwise.
So,
so technically a therapist or a
clinician could feel that this is some
other issue going on,
but they have to actually affirm what
the child says.
Yeah,
the parents and in all the documents
because they will lose their jobs.
They're terrified.
And so in Toronto,
what happened?
What,
what the Preston case was,
uh,
my colleague,
Kenneth Zucker,
I had a clinic where he saw gender
dysphoric children and people said that
he was practicing conversion therapy.
He was not.
So conversion therapy I do not stand
for.
It's trying to turn gay children's
straight,
but sexual orientation is not the same
thing as gender,
so gender and young children is flexible
and it becomes more stable with age.
So when he,
when patients would come to him and say,
you know,
I want to be the opposite sex,
he would say,
okay,
what's the underlying resentment?
When you say gender is flexible,
you don't mean the amount of genders.
You mean the feeling that you have
related to gender?
I just want to be clean.
I know there are two genders.
Let's be clear on that.
Okay.
Um,
so if you have an example,
even using,
if you have a little boy who says he's a
girl,
he will likely be a gay man and he will
likely grow to be comfortable in his
male gender identity.
So for 99 percent of us are biological
sex is our gender,
man,
this,
this thing.
It's,
it's a real monster.
Yeah.
There's a lot of misinformation out
there.
So what I was saying with my colleague
has clinic got shut down.
He wasn't doing anything unethical,
but because of that,
it's set this chill across the field.
Now,
clinicians do not do not want to have
the same thing happened to them because
activists will go after them.
There's no one really practicing or
anyone sort of thought of as legitimate.
That's practicing conversion therapy
anymore.
Is there?
I hope not.
I have nothing against it,
like the that it just never worked.
Like it was just something that I guess
it's sort of twisted.
Idealogue was practicing not using real
evidence or science and it just fizzled
out basically.
I do think there are some practitioners
who are still doing it.
Not,
I wouldn't call them legitimate,
which it makes me very uncomfortable
when I see that,
but yeah,
definitely sexual orientation is
biological.
It's genetic and it can't be changed,
so conversion therapy is completely
useless.
Yeah.
Well I'm glad we got it.
At least I think.
I think most people won't be angry at
you on that.
Well,
I guess maybe some people on the right
might be angry on that one,
maybe,
but you know,
I'm all about presenting the data and
speaking to facts and the science and
standing up for sex research,
whether it infuriates people on the left
or the right.
Yeah.
Science facts reason pretty much.
Pretty much all but all sort of packaged
within,
within the free speech thing.
Yeah.
Can I call you a member of the
intellectual dark web?
Please do.
I don't know that I have that power,
but I'm going to go back to the
clubhouse later and I'm going to get me
a membership.
Yeah,
yeah.
You know,
we have to vote on it.
It's a weird thing and we can be a white
man some days.
Oh,
right.
That was the thing.
It was like the,
you know,
whatever.
All these idiots that are writing all
these nonsensical piece is about as tall
white man and it's like
there are a bunch of us that are not
white,
but I mean they call them.
I've been called a white supremacist.
I've been called a Nazi,
so you know,
that's the level that we're at right now
and they have nothing else.
So I think it's a good sign
in a weird way.
It absolutely is a good time.
Well,
it's been a pleasure.
I'm so glad that we finally got to do
this.
So much fun.
Yeah,
we will.
We will do.
I sent these issues going away,
so we're going to have to do this again,
right?
Very good.
Uh,
for more on Deborah,
you can follow her on twitter.
It's at Debra Hill.