I truly don't know if I could've come up
with a more perfect guest for the first
episode of the show.
Sam Harris is a neuroscientist,
author and founder of project reason and
according to some people,
he's also a genocidal maniac,
bent on nuking,
much of the Middle East.
Sam,
welcome to the show.
Thank you.
Pleasure to be here.
Which,
which half of that would you say
describes you better?
We'll talk about both halves,
I imagine.
Yeah.
I'll take the first though.
Well I'm,
I'm really thrilled that you're here and
that,
you know,
you came in for my first show.
You said you were going to come in and
October when your book comes out,
but I twisted your arm sufficiently and,
and here you are.
Yeah.
Well congratulations on the show too.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
Alright,
so let's start.
Um,
I want to start basically were sort of,
I really found out about you and where I
think this whole discussion that we've,
every,
everyone's been having for the last
eight months or so started and you were
on real time with Bill Maher and you
were on to talk about your book.
Bill was talking about liberalism and
Islam and Ben Affleck was on,
and I know everyone's seen this clip
already,
but let's take a look when
you want to talk about the treatment of
women and homosexuals and free thinkers
and,
and public intellectuals in the Muslim
world.
Uh,
I would argue that the liberals have
failed us and the crucial point
confusion,
like,
yeah,
thank God you're here.
The crucial point of confusion
and is that,
that we have been sold this meme of
Islamophobia where every criticism of
the doctrine of Islam gets conflated
with bigotry toward Muslims as people.
Right?
That is,
it's
intellectually ridiculous.
So even if it gets cold,
hold on.
Who the person who understands the
officially codified doctrine of Islam.
You say,
well,
this is actually well educated on this
topic.
I'm asking you if I criticize the,
you're saying that Islamophobia is not a
real thing,
that if you're critical of something,
it's not a real thing when we do it.
Right?
Well,
no,
it really is.
I'm not denying that that certain people
are bigoted against Muslims as people
and that's a problem big have you.
But the gross,
it's racist and it's not.
It's,
but it's so nice.
So it's like saying nine years shifted,
you know what we are saying,
you guys are saying if you want to be
liberals believe in liberal principles
of freedom of speech.
Like you know,
we are endowed by our forefathers of the
low,
like all men are created.
No Fan.
We have to be able to criticize bad
ideas.
So first off,
I think it's gross.
It's racist.
Should be your twitter bio.
Have you considered putting it there?
People have been just throwing that at
me on twitter ever since.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
it's a bit of a meme.
Yeah.
So what I want to start with is,
because I think there's obviously a ton
of.
We can talk about the fallout of this
and we'll get to that,
but I want to talk about actually the
specifics of what happened there.
Did you expect.
Because usually when they bring on the
guests that sits on bill's side of the
table,
usually it's for a one on one with bill
and sort of a casual conversation.
The panel doesn't really jump in.
Did you expect that whole thing to
explode the way that it did?
No.
No,
not at all.
I was selling a book on meditation at
that moment I was talking and the first
year,
that's about 60 seconds into the
exchange.
Yeah.
And so initially
it starts with,
you know,
how can an atheist be spiritual and
there was a.
we're talking along those lines and I
said something slightly derogatory about
the new age and Ben jumped into that
space and,
and you know,
it was at my throat about Islam hadn't
even come up so he clearly was poised to
do that and yeah,
it's considered a protected interview.
Everyone on the panel knows they're not
supposed to jump in.
What do you think was going on with Ben?
Well,
apart from him possibly being on
steroids for his,
uh,
his Batman role,
um,
I dunno,
I just think he clearly had he,
I think he had no idea who I was really,
but someone had given him a paragraph
bio of me and had,
had more or less told him that,
you know,
I'm a,
a bigot who's intolerant of Muslims and,
you know,
he really should,
take a whack at me on that topic.
Yeah.
And honestly,
I was,
I think I was a little slow to
appreciate how hostile he was because I
wasn't just looking at him.
I was actually looking at Nick Kristoff,
who I have actually collided with on
this topic and who my remarks were more
pitched to,
I think more appropriately pitched
because nick really deals with,
with,
uh,
especially women's rights issues in the
developing world to a unique degree.
So I had a bit of a bone to pick with
nick and um,
and there were other.
Michael Steele was on the panel and so
my attention was split and so I wasn't
just kind of out of the corner of my
consciousness was I was understanding
that there was a level of hostility here
that I didn't really expect or know how
to interpret and so talking about
knowing how to interpret it,
like it's a little different if,
if Nick Kristoff or some author or a
philosopher had immediately jumped out
at you like that,
I think perhaps it would have dealt with
it in one way,
but when a big.
I mean this is an a list Hollywood star,
this is Batman jumps at you that way.
Did that throw you off in a way that you
look,
you were cool and collected there,
but just having to deal with someone at
that level,
it's a different ballgame,
you know?
Yeah.
Well it's hard to interrupt a,
a,
a movie star who doesn't want to be
interrupted.
So at a certain point,
you know,
if bill's not going to cut them off,
I can't cut them off.
So trying to get a word in edgewise is a
challenge there.
But I mean,
the irony is the sentence,
he was reacting to the sentence where I
say everyone conflates criticism of
Islam instead of ideas with bigotry
against Muslims as people.
Uh,
he no sooner no sooner were those words
uttered.
Then he demonstrated my thesis with
every subsequent statement and it was
just impossible to,
to get that mirror bent,
you know,
close enough toward his face so that he
could recognize what,
what he was doing.
So he literally,
for the remainder of the 12 minutes,
I mean,
he continually go and repeatedly proved
your theory.
Then I continued for an hour in the
green room afterwards and it was,
it was,
it was by no means resolved.
Yeah.
And clearly hasn't resolved since.
All right.
So
I don't want to focus too much on that
specifically,
but I just want to talk about when
someone throws,
you know,
he throws this,
it's gross,
it's racist.
Suddenly I noticed that the next day the
onus was on you and Bill Maher.
And a little more to bill I think to
prove that you weren't racist.
I have never been a big fan of bills for
a long time.
I've never heard anyone call him racist
ever before,
but suddenly the next day on all the
websites,
it was Ben Affleck Call Sam Harris and
bill and my racist is Ben,
is Bill Maher Racist?
Is Sam Harris Racist?
How does that feel in that moment of the
discussion when someone throws that
gauntlet down because you're,
you're,
you're used to debate and people with
ideas,
not just words.
Well,
it's very dispiriting because it's
almost guaranteed to convince half the
audience happy and this is something.
This is the first thing I said to Ben
afterwards in the green room,
I said,
you realize just calling us racist,
convinced half the people listening and
watching that were racist and leaders
are using that word is enough for
people.
So people just assume where there's
smoke,
there's fire.
They can't figure out what anyone is
actually saying that their attention
span is so truncated that using words
like that,
uh,
again,
just convinces fully half the audience.
And the most depressing thing in the
aftermath of this was to see the
outpouring of the celebration of
disproportionally and the Muslim
community on social media from people
who thought that he had just mopped the
floor with us,
that he had exposed our racism for all
to see and he had argued brilliantly and
he's just this white knight for the
Muslim world.
And it was so embarrassing because he,
of course he did none of that.
He was,
he wasn't making any sense.
He wasn't listening to what we were
actually saying.
And he was simply,
um,
uh,
you know,
calling us names,
know very loaded names and,
and it,
it works for people who want to perceive
the conversation along those lines.
Was there was this meme or this idea of
you as a racist,
was that even out there?
Because now I see it in a dialogue all
the time.
But,
but I had never heard of it.
And to be 100 percent honest with you,
I had sort of ancillary knew your work.
I'm not even sure if I was following you
on twitter at the time.
So I know a lot of people when they're
done with this,
they're going to have just as Sam Harris
fanboy and blah blah,
blah,
blah.
But I really,
I didn't.
I was watching that and I thought,
well,
here's someone making some sense.
And Now ben Affleck's just using the
worst kind of language with him.
But was that idea about you out there
before?
Well,
not.
yeah,
I think Glenn Greenwald and a few other
people had put it out there.
So it was,
I mean,
it's,
it's a trope of,
um,
political politically correct liberal
apology around criticism of Islam.
So this notion of Islamophobia,
the idea that,
that to single out Islam for any special
attention as a set of doctrines or as a
political in today's world is tantamount
to synonymous with or covertly motivated
by racist bigotry toward Arabs are Brown
skinned people.
Um,
and you know,
there are many people like Glenn
Greenwald who quite irresponsibly,
you know,
make that point again and again.
Um,
and so,
yeah,
so,
so ben's a started.
That was not the first time criticism of
Islam has been conflated with racism,
but it's,
it's,
I mean it's such a crazy claim because
it,
I mean this has been pointed out again
and again,
and bill's done this,
but Islam is not a race.
It's a set of ideas.
You can't convert away from a race.
You can't convert to erase Rachel
Dolezal.
You can get this right.
You.
Yes you can.
You can.
A few at one person can do that.
Everything I say about Islam applies to
white,
converts to the faith every bit as much
as it does to,
to Arabs or,
or anyone born into it.
Sure.
In fact,
even more so because that means you've
had,
if you're 30 years old and had not had
this drummed into you on mother's knee
and with a full adult,
you know,
clear viewing of,
of your life and all the opportunities
available to you,
you decide to convert to the most
doctrinaire and repressive form of
Islam.
Well then then I have the most to say
about you.
You know,
someone like Adam.
Good.
Don,
who's the.
I think he's now dead,
but I'm the guy from Orange County who
joined al Qaeda,
you know,
this is,
these are so and everything I say about
Islam as a religion.
That is true.
I've said some disparaging things about
it as a set of ideas and I've compared
it unfavorably to Buddhism and Hinduism,
which you know,
their,
their adherence are,
are for the most part not white like me.
So the idea that racism has the notions
of race has anything to do with this is
just completely crazy.
I took the top five things that I think
people attack you on my opinion,
misquote you on and I thought maybe we
could take five minutes for each one,
five or six minutes for each one and
that way each time someone says,
well,
Sam Harris wants to nuke the Middle
East,
or Sam Harris wants to racially profile
Muslims or whatever it is.
You or I or anyone that's clear-minded
can just send a link and say,
here it is in five minutes.
You don't have to read a book.
You don't have to watch a three hour
interview here.
I think the number one thing that people
say about you is that when you say
Islam,
you mean all Muslims.
Right?
Right.
So take it away.
Yeah.
So the,
the claim is that I generalize about
Muslims and this is incredibly ironic
because half the time on,
in that film clip,
uh,
was spent where I was talking about
statistics and poll results and
percentages and a certain percentage is
jihadist and then there's a wider circle
of,
of Islamists and then there's a wider,
wider circle of conservatives.
And so I never generalize about the
Muslim world and in so far as we have
good data on the numbers of people who
subscribed various beliefs that I'm
always looking at those data.
And so I'm at everything I say about the
problem of,
of Islam and Islamism,
um,
takes as its area of concern.
First and foremost,
the people living in the Muslim world
who are living under the shadow of,
of,
if not the boot of theocracy.
So you know,
women and gays and free thinkers and
public intellectuals and atheists.
People who email me saying they're
afraid their,
their mother and father will kill them.
If they knew they were an atheist,
for instance,
um,
and there's nobody who I,
who I celebrate more than Muslim
apostates and muzzle and true reformist
Muslims like my coauthor on this new
book,
Magenta was who have taken just heroic
risks to say critical things about the
faith in a context where it's much more
dangerous to do so then the context and
where were you and I live and I mean,
so,
you know,
if I were a Muslim in Pakistan saying
half of what I'm saying on this show,
I would have a life expectancy of about
five hours and that is a,
that is a political and human rights
reality that every liberal who's using
this term Islamophobia is disregarding
at,
not at their peril,
at the peril of all the people who are
not being helped by,
um,
by Westerners who could help,
you know,
and non Muslims who could help and what
non Muslims can do is help in whatever
way possible to make criticism of
theocracy in the Muslim world.
Safe to do so.
Yeah.
No,
I don't generalize.
And I think,
um,
of course there are millions and
millions of Muslims who do not take the
barbaric passages in the Quran and the
Hadith seriously and who are not wanting
to kill apostates and don't and don't
want to throw gays from rooftops.
And those are not the people I'm talking
about.
I mean,
or if I'm ever talking about them in my
criticism of religion,
I'm talking about them in the same
spirit that I talk about,
you know,
reformed Jews or,
or non-doctrinaire Christians who are,
who are not a real threat to anybody who
but who,
or but who may be bending public policy
around in ways we don't like.
The problem with many of those Muslims
is they don't want their religion
criticized at all and they don't want
any link between its core tenants.
Could tenants around Jihad and paradise
and martyrdom.
A spelled out,
uh,
with,
you know,
in terms of it's,
it's the way it's generating the kinds
of violence and intolerance where we're
seeing in the world today.
So in so far,
if you're going to defend your religion
by saying Islam is a religion of peace
and the Islamic state has nothing to do
with Islam,
you're being intellectually dishonest.
And that kind of denial of obvious
realities now is I think,
you know,
irresponsible and dangerous.
Yeah.
Just to close the door to notions of
racism and bigotry against Muslims as
people.
And I think,
I think the apostates,
the intellectuals,
the women,
um,
the gaze of the Muslim world are the
most,
the most important people in the world
right now.
If we,
if we could give green cards to every
real secularist in the Muslim world,
I think they should just get to the
front of the line.
I mean,
these are,
these are the people who need to be
empowered.
And so that's um,
I mean,
the irony is that they,
if they could leave the Muslim world,
the Muslim world needs them,
right?
So maybe we,
the best thing to do would be to empower
them in the Muslim world.
But method,
you know,
life for these people is,
um,
in countries like Pakistan and Bankman,
we have Bangladeshi blogger is being
murdered in public by machete wielding
maniacs and nothing happens,
right?
Um,
it's,
um,
yeah,
I mean,
I,
so my,
everything I say about Islam is a
confession of solidarity with these
people.
And so how you get racism out of that or
bigotry against Muslims as people,
you know,
that's you.
You're a better geometer than I.
This is,
this is a big one and I've seen this one
really take a life of its own that you
want to do a nuclear first strike on the
Muslim world,
right?
Is that true,
Sam?
No,
no.
Alas,
it's not true.
Okay.
Um,
I guess it,
it was made,
made true apparently,
or at least to the satisfaction of many
people by Chris Hedges who went around
in every stop on his book tour Know
Radio,
television,
print telling people that this was in
fact my position.
Um,
and many people like Glenn Greenwald and
Reza Aslan,
and you know,
you're a old colleague,
Janky,
eager,
have,
have reiterated this claim.
There are a couple of passages in the my
first book,
the end of faith where I talk about how
a certainty about paradise and about
martyrdom is the best way to get there,
just destroys the logic of nuclear
deterrence,
of mutually assured destruction that we
had kept us more or less poised on the
brink of a mutual annihilation with the
Soviet Union for so many years.
Uh,
and I just pointed out what I think is
an obvious fact and still isn't obvious.
Facts should be an obvious fact and a
very troubling one that if you have a
regime that has the,
the,
that is the psychological equivalent of
the 19 hijackers,
but people who woke up in the morning
wanting to fly a plane into a building
that is a regime who you can't,
they're not rational actors,
you can't,
or if they're rational,
it's rational within a context of
believing that they're going to paradise
this way.
Right?
So what's the rational part of that?
Yeah,
but it's rare.
If you believe that it's rational to
blow up the world,
you know,
it's rational to hit the wall 400 miles
an hour.
So,
um,
this is not,
so I pointed out the obvious fact that
we have to avoid the circumstance at all
costs and there's no one who should be
more cognizant of this problem then
so-called moderate Muslims or so or
secular Muslims or non jihadist,
uh,
Muslims and um,
we have to collectively find some path
to a alternative future in which you
don't have a true jihadist regime armed
with a long range.
Nuclear Weapons and all of those long
range is,
is crucial.
And so you have Pakistan,
Pakistan already has nuclear weapons.
Do I think we should execute a nuclear
first strike on packs?
Pakistan?
No,
in Pakistan is not first of all age
hottest regime and though,
you know,
they're one cool away from being taken
over by one,
but they're also,
they don't have the warheads that can
deliver these nukes to the capitals of
Europe or to the US.
Um,
it's a very different circumstance.
And um,
so yes,
no,
there's nothing that I say in that book,
the suggests that we should be nuking
Iran,
you know,
and it's just,
this is all I was talking about is how
the kind of game theoretic logic of
nuclear deterrence that we lived however
precariously under,
with the Soviet Union falls apart.
Once you admit to yourself that it's
possible that truly suicidal religious
maniacs can get their hands on these
weapons.
And so all I was calling for his,
his,
um,
our awareness that is a,
that really is a game changer and we
have to avoid that at all cost.
Right?
And you know,
you said this was just a few passages in
your book.
It was literally about a page,
right?
It's like a paragraph or two.
Yeah.
Right.
So when people have blown this up into,
into some something that somehow this is
like this massive idea that you had
actually a good friend of mine who I
agree with that a lot of things and
disagree on some other things.
Uh,
he,
what he says to me in relation to this
is that you are laying the philosophical
groundwork for a nuclear first strike.
People respond to this passage as though
I invented nuclear weapons or that I
think there are a good thing.
I'm just talking about the reality of
our world.
We have a,
we have a nuclear policy,
right?
We have a first strike policy.
We have a.
So someone somewhere in a war room has,
has beaten out every choice point in
terms of what are the circumstances
where we would use nuclear weapons
first,
what are the circumstances where we
would do,
where we would,
um,
uh,
where we would imagine that they're
going to be used against us first and
then have to preempt that.
And uh,
this has all been thought out in a Cold
War context.
We haven't had to worry about anyone
else doing this to us.
And when you're talking about other
regimes like China or North Korea,
there are,
um,
there's a plausible assumption that
they're not suicidal then that everyone
isn't eager to die.
Right?
And now we are talking about a set of
ideas,
you know,
jihadist eschatology to this,
this idea that,
that martyrdom is a real metaphysical
principle and it's not only okay to die
in the right circumstances is the best
possible thing that can happen to you.
Um,
and that there really is,
there's no such thing as innocent
collateral damage because all the good
people are going to go to paradise with
you and they're just going to thank you
for it,
right?
So there's nothing can go wrong and this
world is just fit to be destroyed.
That is the ideology that you see in a
happily a,
a small minority of Muslims at this
moment.
But it is not an accident that these
people feel this way because it's,
it's a very plausible,
literal reading of the texts during real
time.
You said that Islam is the mother lode
of that ideas.
Now I've seen since I've seen you
tweeted someone you tweeted a couple of
weeks ago at somebody that Judaism is a
motherload of bad ideas.
Well,
I should've said the motherlode.
I mean,
that was,
that was the one moment in that exchange
with,
with athletic wear.
Um,
it seems to me,
I misspoke.
I mean it was just insane.
V as opposed to a what,
because I obviously I've written,
I've written more about Christianity
then Islam,
right?
So I criticize religion in general.
I think faith based religion is the
mother lode of bad ideas.
My faith,
faith based thinking,
this idea that somehow you're wanting
something to be true is a good surrogate
for evidence that it is true,
right?
And,
and a way in which you can embrace self
deception and deception of others as a
legitimate principal.
Um,
that I think as a mother lode of bad
ideas and religion has kind of a corner
on that market at the moment.
But,
uh,
Islam is an especially dangerous a
variant of it within our current
political rally or I should say Islamism
as opposed to Islamic general.
So when you,
when you say that you're talking about
because of the Geo politics,
because of the maturation of the
religion itself,
right?
We know that Judaism is far older,
Christianity's older,
they've gone through different
reformations.
So partly this just has to do with
timing,
right?
Yeah.
It's not old,
but unfortunately it's not only time,
but timing is enough to differentiate
them because obviously Christianity 500
years ago was Christians were burning
people alive,
but the on street corners,
by the way,
you've written a ton about that.
Oh yeah.
This isn't just saying.
You're saying to me right now.
No,
I've written more about that.
I wrote a whole book just on
Christianity.
I have done that with Islam except this,
um,
this newest book that I wrote with the
Majid Nawaz.
So,
you know,
there are,
there are historical differences between
Islam and Christianity and other
religions.
And there,
there are unfortunately theological
differences that make Islam a harder
doctrine to modify.
But it's just as,
as a sheer matter of history,
Islam has not had a reformation,
a,
an enlightenment.
I mean,
they had,
hasn't had the,
hasn't been modulating buy maternity in
the same way.
And um,
you're talking about for the most part,
people who have been intellectually
isolated to a degree that,
that should be unheard of,
but it's still quite common in the 21st
century and unhappily they are,
they're isolated from the ideas and ways
of thinking that the give a science and
give us a commitment to human rights and
give us a commitment to pluralism and
democracy,
but they're not isolated from the
destructive enabling technology that
we've produced.
So you have people who are legitimate
engineers,
right.
And legitimate,
you know,
computer scientists even who are
jihadists.
Right?
Who wants,
who will use the tools of maternity
against any kind of set of modern values
that,
that we would be wise to defend.
Yeah.
All right.
So I think what you said is it is not
the mother load,
but it is a motherload within the
context of timing,
geopolitics and,
and a whole bunch of others.
Yeah.
No,
I certainly should've said a motherload
about it.
It's the next one.
You want to racially profile Muslims,
right?
That was a painful.
Yeah.
Now,
yeah,
I've,
uh,
I read your piece on it.
If that's the case,
you actually want to,
you're either Muslim where you want to
actually go screw yourself.
I am of the race that should be
profiled.
Yeah.
So can you explain that a little bit
more?
So we've all had this experience of
going through
clarity and seeing people who at a
glance you can rule out as a non
jihadist.
I mean we,
we,
all I've argued for in,
in,
in the few things I've said about
profiling is that we should be honest
about where,
what we're looking for.
We're looking for gi suicidal jihadists.
Now there are other,
you know,
there are other suicidal people who may
bring down planes,
but as,
as a general matter,
we're looking for people who are the
functional equivalent of the 19
hijackers,
right?
So we're not looking for an 80 year old
women from Okinawa.
We're not looking for a little girls
from Norway.
If Jerry Seinfeld is going to the
airport,
if he gets the same search that,
that someone who looks like Osama bin
Ladin does,
that's a crazy misuse of resources.
Now there are little wrinkles here that
we can correct for.
It's possible to put a bomb and someone
else's bags.
All banks should be searched.
I mean the.
Yes,
you can think this through,
but there are people who you absolutely
know at a glance are not terrorists.
Right.
And any moment spent scrutinizing them
in this security theater we've all
witnessed at TSA is a moment not
actually intelligently looking for a
more plausible threat.
So I met my.
My view is we have $10 worth of
attention.
If you spend a dollar over here,
you've got nine to spend elsewhere.
Right.
So it's just a zero sum game.
And so my,
my sense is,
because again,
we,
we need well trained smart people at Tsa
to do that.
So that's a whole other.
Yeah.
So it's not,
it's not like we're well poised to do
this,
but when you look at what the Israelis
do,
when you look at you,
if you ever get on l and you look at how
they run security,
yes,
they look at everybody,
but there's,
there's,
there's absolutely no pretense of being
fair in this process and there shouldn't
be.
Right?
It's just like a.
and when I go through security,
you know,
50 percent of the people to me look
like,
and I'm not,
I'm not saying that I'm an expert here,
but I'm,
you know,
I pay attention to this sort of stuff a
lot.
Um,
I would be willing to bet my life that
certain people are just in this blog
post.
I showed a picture of one.
I'm a one old woman who you just know
it's,
there's absolutely no way she's joined.
Okay.
So you look at her and you say,
okay,
the scrutiny on her is a waste of time
and it's a dangerous waste of time.
And in the interest of appearing fair
and we are actually ramping up our risk,
um,
and being appearing right because it's
just appearing.
It's not actually.
Yeah.
But you and I fit it,
fit the profile,
you know,
young to middle aged men who could be,
we could be jihadists right there.
There are jihadists who ally.
Like,
as I said,
you know,
Adam Gadahn or um,
uh,
and in these other western recruits to
al Qaeda or isis who functionally look
like us.
They're not,
they don't look like Arabs,
they're not,
you know,
they're not holding Pakistani passports.
Um,
so yeah,
no,
I'm not letting myself off the hook
here.
It's not like I,
you know,
I want me and the other white guys to
just sail through.
It's just,
it's just there.
There are still people who are obviously
not jihadists and until these people
start blowing themselves up on planes I
am,
I think we're,
we'd be wise to just admit we know what
we're looking for,
we have,
we have some sense of what we're looking
for.
And just to be crystal clear in that
post,
you literally said,
I'm just reiterating what you just said,
but that you should be picked out and
you actually should be picked up.
And as I describe it as anti profiling,
it's not that I want certain people
profiled.
I just want us to admit that certain
people require less scrutiny.
And you know,
Jerry Seinfeld is one,
you know,
when you see a famous celebrity,
go through security,
treat it as though he just may have
become a jihadist,
you know,
and you know,
when,
when no one was watching,
it just,
it's crazy making it is security
theater.
Yeah.
And there,
there,
there are many people who though not
famous,
are every bit as unlikely to be members
of al Qaeda as a prominent people who we
know,
you know,
Betty White,
betty,
Betty White is,
is,
uh,
I would not be happy about that.
That would be a surprise.
Yeah,
I will have one if they weren't.
Betty white gets a profile.
All right.
So the final one of these sort of five
pillars of Sam Harris being the big one
is your anneal con.
Uh,
so I think we should define neo-con
first.
You want to,
you want to handle that or do you want
me to.
Well,
I think it means many things to many
people,
but it's,
it's the,
uh,
the attitude toward foreign policy that
I think most was,
was canonized by people like Richard
Perle and Paul Wolfowitz in the run up
to,
um,
uh,
the first,
or our,
our invasion of Iraq after nine slash
11.
This idea that we can go in in a very
muscular way and just create nations
along democratic lines and that our
foreign policy should be very aggressive
and,
um,
we'll fight them over there so we don't
have to fight them here.
And
um,
I think we've all,
I mean I was,
you know,
I was never for the Iraq war.
I was never a vocally against it either.
I just was at every moment through that
process,
I was just painfully aware that I had no
idea what to think about it.
Apart from it looked very risky and it
looked like a frank distraction from the
war in Afghanistan,
which did seem to me to be necessary and
seemed like something we were probably
gonna botch.
One thing you can say against
neoconservatism,
which is that it is idealistic to a
degree that now seems not at all
sustainable.
I mean we,
W we,
we should have learned a lesson at this
point,
which is we don't do this very well.
We don't nation build very well.
We have a political environment where we
just can't stay committed to these
things.
Even if we were,
we're doing it well,
you know,
we,
we view everything through a four year,
you know,
Presidential Lens and an election cycle.
And so,
and these are,
these are multi-decade commitments if
we're going to do this as well.
So,
um,
but Iraq looks like a disaster and it
looked like a disaster for most of the
time apart from,
you know,
15 minutes thereafter,
the surge.
Um,
and I certainly don't consider myself an
neo-con.
I just,
I,
I just think we have to be honest about
in ethical terms,
what is really going on in the world
when you,
if you're going to say that we never
should have gone into Iraq,
which I think is a reasonable thing to
say.
And it was a reasonable thing to say
then you just,
you only decent to admit how depressing
a claim this really is.
Ms Dot.
We're saying that,
that Iraq is a place that requires a
psychopathic thug to run it in a given
the level of religious sectarianism,
given the fact that when you remove a
butcher like Saddam Hussein,
everyone starts killing their neighbor,
right?
Which is,
which is in fact what happened.
And,
and which is in fact they political and
religious reality.
We underestimated when we walked in
there thinking that they were just going
to put flowers in the barrels of our
guns and welcome us as liberators.
Uh,
so it's a,
um,
it's a very depressing thing to admit
about the state of,
of a place like Iraq.
But I,
and I think we should all mean I view
Iraq as initially we went when Saddam
was there as a,
as a kind of hostage crisis when you
have a totally illegitimate regime run
by barbarians,
uh,
keeping tens of millions of people
hostage.
And,
and so the people who criticize the war
based on saying that it was a sovereign
government.
And we should never have gone in there.
It's not just a failure to engage with
the moral reality,
which is this was a terrible place to
live and if we could have done something
to help these people,
we should have.
And there are many countries that fit
that description.
I mean North Korea is one of them.
If there would be some way to,
to depose that regime and liberate the
North Koreans,
we should do it now.
We know that it would just be a bloody
mess if we tried and we're learning that
more and more in,
in these other societies.
But um,
and so,
so neoconservatism,
I don't know what its current state is
now,
but I can't imagine anyone is,
you know,
even Wolfowitz or parole is a,
I can't imagine any of them are,
are as saying what about the possibility
of building a nation anywhere from
scratch.
Right.
That's actually a great point.
Like,
are these guys still believing that
idea?
Do they think if we went back into a
rack right now,
would it,
would it be any better?
I somehow doubt it.
No,
no I.
and it's.
But the idea that that we created isis
by going into a rack,
that's also just delusional,
I mean the,
the,
the set of ideas that get gives us isis,
that is the set of ideas and the level
of sectarianism that gave us the civil
war that,
that,
you know,
we,
we could barely contain a that drove us
out of Iraq and that set of ideas in one
or another degree has been animating a
subset of the Muslim world for a very
long time.
Right.
So this is where I think some of your
critics would say,
well,
you're blaming things more on religion
than the geopolitics because had we
never gone to Iraq,
Saddam would still be there and that
isis would be controlled.
But basically you're saying this,
this thing sorta would have bubbled up
one way or another.
Is that so?
But no,
but if isis,
those religious sectarian commitments
were controlled by a dictator a that's.
Yeah.
That's.
That seems to me an intrinsically
unstable situation.
At some point they're going to,
they're going to bubble up.
But I'm.
Let's just admit how depressing that
remedy is.
And we're talking about someone who's
got a torture chamber,
is running full time and he's got sons
who show up at people's weddings and
rape the bride.
And I mean,
it's just,
it's like this is just a playground for
sociopath's,
if that's what it takes to modulate the,
the Sunni Shia Internet saying,
uh,
animosity,
you know,
that's,
it's a,
um,
okay.
That,
that does not exonerate religion,
right?
And it does not exonerate at that level
of commitment to a device of theology.
Uh,
and so it's,
um,
and they're,
you know,
I think it's a,
uh,
yeah,
I,
I think it is totally appropriate to be
humble about how hard it is to help
people in these circumstances.
But if you look at a place like Rwanda,
right where Clinton's one regret was
that we didn't do more to help,
uh,
or to,
to prevent that genocide.
Um,
and if you look at,
at a total failure to intervene and the
resulting massacre of nearly a million
people,
and you say,
okay,
that was,
that was something we,
we should not play that hand precisely
that way again.
Right?
We should do something differently.
We should have intervened.
Well then what do you think we should do
to the,
you know,
the,
what's happening to these cds and in,
under the Islamic state,
you know,
we got people being crucified by the
side of the road.
We've got thousands of sex slaves.
We've got gay is being thrown from
rooftops.
We.
So do we intervene or not?
I think it's,
um,
it's not obvious,
uh,
that there's anything we can do in each
one of these circumstances to help
people.
But the idea that you are a moral
monster to even think that we should
intervene is deeply suspect.
Yeah.
All right.
So one of my intentions with this show
is that I really want to talk about
ideas and not people and I think that's
what we've done so far for the half hour
or so,
but I do think sometimes you have to
address certain people within the
context of these conversations.
So I have to talk about one of your
favorite people to start.
Reza Aslan,
who in my view has repeatedly
mischaracterize and misrepresented your
abuse.
He's done this in a very forum.
I've seen him,
you know,
say to my former boss jaggery that you
and bill,
you know,
that this is about all Muslims than the
day later I'll see them on Huffington
Post live saying that bill is his
friend.
I mean,
just a myriad of things that don't sort
of add up.
It also,
it sounds like maybe he half made up his
bio.
Again,
I don't want to make this about people,
but sometimes I do think this has to be
addressed.
So you want to just take that and put it
somewhere because I also sense that
you're sort of tired.
We're talking about right.
Didn't you say on twitter that you just
weren't going to do it anymore and then.
And then he feels like the mafia,
like you get sucked back in,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
so yeah,
I took,
I declared a unilateral ceasefire at one
point on my podcast saying that I would
never mentioned these people again
unless absolutely necessary.
Um,
but yeah,
like I kind of painted myself into a
corner there because they don't stop.
So you know,
people like Glenn Greenwald and Reza are
the,
have the larger platforms.
But there are many people who fit this
description where they,
they seem to imagine that it's fair and
intellectually legitimate to
misrepresent the views of their
opponents as a way of sliming them
because they know it's effective.
It's like,
if you can just get something to stick,
that's good because the person you're
arguing against is,
um,
so I'm unethical in his or her
commitments that it's,
this is the end justifies the means.
Right?
So,
and,
and I'm noticing more and more of this.
This is obviously not a problem just
with razor or Glenn,
but this is a,
a larger problem in our,
um,
conversation with one another and it's,
it's,
um,
but it,
it seems to be a pathology that's
expressing itself on the left
politically in a way that I'm not seeing
it quite so much on the right.
Right.
I get attacked by people on the right,
but they actually,
for the most part,
do me the courtesy of understanding what
my views are.
And they attended a Bible thumper,
like,
uh,
um,
I don't know Rick Warren or anyone else
like that.
I have debated,
you know,
he,
he will,
he understands what my position is and
then he,
he disagrees with it based on his own
commitments and then we can have an
honest debate,
um,
and it,
and it can be totally pleasant.
It can be barbed onstage,
but it can be totally pleasant in the
green room because we,
you know,
we,
we both know what,
what game we're playing and uh,
but with these guys,
it's not at all pleasant in the green
room.
In fact,
it's interesting.
I mean,
it's impossible to,
to engage at this point.
It's just so poisonous and mean.
The crucial piece is,
and this is something I honestly can
say,
I'm innocent of Amanda,
if I've ever done this,
I've never done it intentionally.
And at the moment I've noticed I've done
it,
I've apologized for it.
The crucial sin here intellectually and
ethically is misrepresenting the other
person's views as a,
as a strategy for defaming them or,
or marginalizing them.
Right?
And this has been done repeatedly.
So in the example of Resident Glen let
they've retweeted memes saying that you
want to nuke the whole middle of all
this stuff that we've been talking
about.
So what I'm particularly interested in
here is that I see this on the left too.
I'm on the left so I care more about the
left and to me the right went over the
deep end already,
but I want to bring the left back into
some sorta saying middle ground.
So what do you think is actually going
on here?
I had a Dr Gadd sat on a couple of weeks
ago and he said that basically this is
just the age old thing where you go for
the intellectuals first.
So someone like Reza I think probably
can't really.
I know you have debated in but can't
really defeat you,
so to speak in a debate so that he has
to go to this.
Because as you said at the beginning of
all of this,
40 percent of this stuff just sticks,
right?
You say racist when our 40 percent
automatically believe you're racist.
Yeah.
Well,
in,
to,
to bend over backwards to be charitable
to these guys,
I can say that,
um,
we're all guilty of kind of a bandwidth
problem and an impatience with views
that were not sympathetic with.
And frankly we all are.
It's possible for any one of us,
no matter how scrupulous we attempt to
be,
to not take enough time to understand
the position we're criticizing.
Right?
And so you,
because you feel like if it's somebody
like,
I don't know,
Glenn Beck or rush limbaugh or,
or,
um,
Ann Coulter or somebody on the right
with whom I'm basically unsympathetic.
I basically,
I feel like I have the gist of what
their opinions are or likely to be.
And then they say something,
my,
I have a shorter fuse with them.
Maybe I have less of a reason to really
look into what their position actually
is.
And that is,
that's a time bandwidth problem,
but it's understandable.
But it creates huge pr problems in our
conversation with,
you know,
left and right and on any given topic.
Um,
but the crucial problem is,
uh,
which I,
I,
I am now to a moral certainty.
Sure.
I've encountered in these guys is they
know they're misrepresenting you and
it's a strategy and I think it comes out
of I'm just a feeling that it's a,
it's a very cynical,
a relationship to the truth.
It's a very cynical relationship to,
to the significance of ideas.
Have you started this segment talking
about the distinction between ideas and
people.
Now these are people who really don't
think ideas matter very much.
I mean certainly I don't think religious
ideas matter very much and the
differences between religious ideas and
so you know,
Razah is always talking about how,
you know,
religions are just,
so networks of symbols and metaphors and
there's this,
this kind of postmodernist nonsense that
comes out of his mouth when he was
talking about the truth claims of
religion.
And the punchline is nobody ever really
does anything based on religion.
It's always some other reason,
right?
It's psychology is politics is
economics.
I'm right.
I've heard him say that you actually
believe in this stuff the most because
that's why you quoted and he obviously
knows that,
but he says things.
You know what he'll say,
and every time I come up he'll say,
you know,
I get my view about religion from Fox
News right now.
Is there any chance he believes that
there is no chance?
I think if you've proven anything easy,
you look in the bibliography of,
of my first book,
right?
There's like a thousand references
there,
right?
There's absolutely no chance he believes
that there's absolutely no chance he
thinks I've called for a nuclear first
strike on the Muslim world,
and yet he retweets a tweet that calls
me a genocidal fascist.
Maniac,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
he's uh,
and Glenn Greenwald was in this category
and Jenkins as well,
and,
um,
Chris hedges all of them.
And um,
the problem with this is that it works.
It actually because,
because then for the rest of my life,
I'm going to be seeing people who are
absolutely sure on every comment thread
I'm ever going to see there.
I will see people who are absolutely
sure.
I've called for a genocidal nuclear
holocaust,
right?
Um,
and uh,
and many other things.
And so it's a,
um,
it's very,
it's very depressing,
but it works.
And there really is no way to respond
adequately to it.
And so I've,
I've had on my blog for years now a,
a,
um,
post entitled response to controversy
where I deal with each one of these
things as they come up.
And then a year later I'll,
I'll revisit it and fine tune it.
And,
uh,
I think it's the number,
if you search response to controversy on
Google,
I think it's the number one result.
I mean,
so it's,
it's,
it's a,
it's kind of depressing to associated
with that phrase,
but it's the um,
but it still is not an addict.
It's like a 10,000
word letter to the editor essentially.
But it,
it,
it's not an adequate way of addressing
this and it's not adequate because a lot
of people just don't care what the truth
is.
They just liked the fact that your
ready,
you can destroy your opponents
reputation by calling him a racist.
Right?
So that's where I have to bring up the
other person here that we've sort of
danced around.
Um,
and that's the personal part to me.
So jank obviously Janky.
Greg is the founder of the young Turks,
the CEO of the network.
I worked for him for two years.
I still play basketball with him every
Sunday.
Um,
you sat with him for three hours,
for three hours unaided on his channel.
They put about five commercials in it.
It has over a million views.
I'm sure they made a lot of money on it.
You calmly explained to him at the
beginning that basically he was
repeatedly slandering you.
I don't know the,
use the word slander,
but that he was repeatedly
misrepresenting your views and that you
were there to clean up the mess and then
you sat there for three hours,
clearly laid out what you think about
these things.
I was still working there at the time
and then after that he only doubled down
on the.
It's about,
you not only doubled down,
but I see this all the time now on
twitter.
People will take little video clips,
ten second video clips of him saying one
thing to you,
and then what he said when you're not
around,
even after and things that he said to
Reza,
knowing that that's not what you said
and all of this stuff.
Um,
so the personal part to me,
I just have to say it because people
have been asking me forever.
So it obviously had a good amount to do
with why I left.
So I just want to put that out there,
sort of a more for my audience.
But in terms of the three hours sit
down.
I mean,
that's a long time to sit with somebody.
We're not,
we're not going to go three hours.
You did three hours with one glass of
water.
Did you ever,
in your wildest imagination think that
it was going to get worse after that?
Because in my opinion,
at least it did.
Yeah.
No,
I,
it's,
um,
I could see he was following me entirely
so I could see that he was just,
there was a kind of a fundamental
disinclination to have his opinion about
me changed by anything.
I was going to say,
right,
so when you encounter that in someone,
you see that it's not,
it's not functioning by the usual rules
of conversation.
I mean,
this is,
this is the thing that's so poisonous.
It's the.
And again,
uh,
unfortunately I encountered this more on
the left than,
than elsewhere.
There's a,
every one on the left,
at the moment seems to be a mind reader
right there.
What they're trying to detecting you
evidence of a view which you claim you
don't hold,
but the moment they can,
they can string together anything you've
said that seems to align up with
something they want to find in you.
They will hold you accountable to that
misunderstanding.
And no matter how much you try to take
their foot out of your mouth,
they,
they did.
The mirror effort itself is going to be
counted against you if you're just
someone who's in denial or you don't
really understand how racist you are,
or,
um,
and it's a,
uh,
I mean,
so for instance,
so the classic example on twitter,
I,
I often see that,
um,
whenever I say something critical about
Islam,
I will get back,
you know,
why don't you ever criticize
Christianity or Judaism,
which obviously I do my book,
but now I recently said something very
disparaging about Orthodox Judaism and I
saw on twitter people claiming that I
was just covering for my racism with
respect to the Islam.
So that made sense.
Um,
and this is just a token way of,
of just misdirection,
right?
I don't really feel this about Orthodox
Judaism.
There is no way to dig out from this.
I mean,
really think how perverse that.
And they're all mind readers,
they're all psychics who,
who are plumbing the depths of your con,
detecting things in you that you don't
even know about yourself.
Do you wish your mind,
was that da?
Well,
I mean it's,
I,
yeah,
I wish it was amazing to me is,
I mean this is such a confused moral
position because they're claiming.
I'm saying all these horrendous things,
right?
I say we should racially profile.
I say we should nuclear the,
the,
the Muslim world.
I'm no great.
Now say they're going to select the edit
that I say it right.
I say we should torture people,
right?
These are my claims.
And then when I say no,
this is not actually what I,
what I said.
Um,
they,
I mean,
I say I,
I say incredibly controversial things if
you actually honestly engaged with what
I'm saying.
These are very,
I take controversial positions.
I'm never hiding what I actually
believe,
right?
It's just like I'm walking right up to
the line.
Like I'm going to say though,
it's though it is politically
impossible.
I want to talk about the ethics of
torture publicly.
Now.
I mean this is a thankless job if there
ever was one.
Right,
and yet they're claiming to detect in me
commitments that I'm disavowing and
there's just no way you can disavow them
once,
once they,
they,
uh,
insist there.
Yeah.
Right.
So you want to have the battle of ideas,
which is exactly what liberalism should
be for and they don't seem to want to do
that.
So I just want to wrap this up with one
final question.
This,
this portion of it.
Um,
so just putting it flat out there.
I have tweeted at Jank publicly and
respectfully several times since I've
left the network to engage him on this
and I sort of laid out some things and
showed out,
showed some evidence of,
of this or that and he just ignored me.
So I just think I just have to say that
and you know,
everyone can think what they want,
but my final question on this is what do
you think we should do about these
people?
Do you think that your engagement at
this point,
were you,
when you've seen someone lie repeatedly
misrepresent your views,
all of those things when you've seen
this happen repeatedly?
Repeatedly.
And then I started seeing it bleed into
other things.
Do you keep engaging or at some point do
you just put your hands up and I'm
guessing you struggle with this yourself
because you were sort of ready to put
your hands up and then you got sucked
back then.
But where,
where do you stand on that now?
And I wish I had an algorithm for,
for how to deal with this because
there's no,
uh,
it's very haphazard on my side.
It's just,
you know,
sometimes I'll,
I'll just see a tweet that I just can't
let go,
you know,
and then I'll go for weeks or months or
in some cases,
even years,
not dealing with this directly.
But I think in so far,
if someone has a big platform you have
to deal with,
it's somewhat some of the time because
he,
because I see the consequences of their
successfully misleading people.
And so either the people who I will
never mentioned it never deal with
because they're kind of smaller fish in
this,
in this murky pond.
But someone like Reza Aslan,
you know,
he's,
he is a kind of a public figure now and
he,
he's a darling of a certain segment of
the media and so what he says actually
matters because it is,
you know,
he's promulgating genuine falsehoods
about the,
the connection between religious ideas
and I'm a very dangerous behavior and
he's does it it with a apparently clear
conscience and I think he knows enough
to know that he's actually line.
So he's a,
he's a,
I view him as a truly bad actor.
Um,
and yeah,
I,
but it's incredibly boring to keep
poking fun at funded him or to keep
pushing back against what I said
and then ultimately you're just getting
them clicks and in some cases actual
money too.
So it sort of,
I guess there is no answer yet,
but
maybe I'll just do it,
you know,
I do it when I can't do otherwise,
but then I move on to other things.
Um,
I want to get back into some of the
religious stuff.
Um,
so I think partly what a lot of your
detractors would say is that you have
this focus on Islam that you don't,
that you've already illustrated and
you've written a book about Christianity
that whole half first half of
interfaith.
You talking about the Crusades or all
this kind of stuff.
As you said just a moment ago,
you said all kinds of things about the
orthodox Jews.
So I think we get a sense that it's not
just that,
but they're not all the same.
I think that a lot of these,
a lot of the progressives,
a lot of these people on the left,
they want,
they believe in this idea that
everything is equal.
There's just this sort of base equality
except the fact is by definition these
things are different.
If I was to right now draw the Jewish
god of Yahweh or Moses or something and
then draw Jesus in a weird sex act and
then draw Mohammed and I'm talking stick
figures.
I'm not a good artist.
Only one of those would cause a threat
to my life.
So those things are not equal.
Right?
I know they like that proposition.
But it's,
it's a faulty proposition,
right?
Yeah.
Oh No.
Probably brought out in the,
the most elegant way by that onion
cartoon.
I don't know if you saw that the title
was no one was murdered over this
cartoon and it's,
you know,
it's just,
uh,
the Buddha stickiness,
you know,
blowing Jesus.
I mean,
it's so like everyone,
but Muhammad is in there and um,
but the point is made perfectly.
It's just like,
you,
you can do that and yet you cannot draw
a stick figure of Mohammed without
having your life deranged thereafter by,
you know,
conversations with the FBI about how to
keep your,
your you and your family safe.
Right?
That's the reality of the world.
We're living in the West right now.
Forget about what's happened,
what it's like to live in Pakistan or
Bangladesh or any of these countries
where you are literally going to be cut
down by your neighbors on the mere rumor
that you have mistreated a Koran or that
you don't believe that it's the perfect
word of the creator,
of the universe.
Um,
so,
uh,
yeah,
so this,
I mean,
the crucial piece is that beliefs
matter,
specific beliefs matter,
the differences between beliefs matter,
the doctrines,
a religious doctrines are not all the
same and therefore the behavioral and
political and moral commitments born of
those doctrines are not all the same.
How has media really failed this year?
The,
the mainstream media?
Because I did a video a couple of months
ago,
you know,
there was this exhibition,
I think it was somewhere in the middle
of the country where they had the pope
made out of condoms.
Now I can see that being offensive to
some Christians,
right?
You could turn on family guy on any
given night or South Park and see Jesus
doing all sorts of crazy things.
I posted a clip of Jesus bathing naked
in front of Stewie,
a baby,
a male baby,
and they're playing porn music in the
background.
No,
there's no threat of anything.
So is this where sort of the media has
sort of helped the narrative because
they have no problem publishing the
picture of the pope in condoms,
but at the same time the New York Times
didn't,
for example,
post the Charlie Hebdo cartoons and is
this also where secular people,
we've sort of maybe we've
underestimated,
not been kind
enough to the mainstream Christians
because they get crap all the time as
I'm illustrating right here.
Nobody's being shot for things.
Yeah.
Well I think we just have to acknowledge
publicly and loudly and incessantly that
free speech has to win.
So if anyone who in the wake of the
Charlie Hebdo massacre wondered,
well,
wait a minute,
where are those cartoons at all racist,
because that,
that was going to make me feel
differently about it.
That opening that door is just a kind of
moral blindness that we should have
immediately a later itself against me.
That was just.
And people like Glenn Greenwald,
that's,
that's the door they open.
It's like,
oh,
these were.
These were not kosher cartoons.
These were racist.
Of course they weren't.
In fact,
if you understood anything about French
politics,
yeah,
and these were,
these were,
these people were on the right side of
all these liberal questions in France,
if you,
if you understood and by the culture
focusing on Islam more than any more.
We're about Christianity,
plenty of stuff.
But even the cartoons that's on their
face seemed racist and they were kind of
a racial caricature.
They,
in fact,
if you understood the context weren't
racist,
right?
Um,
but nevermind that the,
the sense that it,
it,
it's the sense that there's a tension
between freedom of religion and freedom
of speech is a total moral and political
illusion is that there's absolutely
nothing you and I could say in this
conversation that infringes upon
somebody else's freedom of religion.
We can disparage religion all we want.
That doesn't affect someone else's
political rights to practice it.
They can raise their kids however they
want.
We simply need to admit that religion
should be subjected to the same kind of
criticism and scrutiny and satire,
uh,
as any other set of ideas.
As you point out,
we do this for something like mormonism
so that you can have a play like the
book of Mormon and no one gets killed.
Sure.
It's unthinkable to have an analogous
play about Islam and we have just
acquiesced to that difference we have.
Just so you know,
it's just,
yeah,
it's too dangerous.
And the problem is not that it's too
dangerous.
The problem is that anyone like me would
want to do it.
Right.
Anyone liked someone like Trey Parker,
Matt Stone,
the,
those assholes,
they shouldn't,
shouldn't go after Islam.
Right?
That's where the moral sense that the
sensibilities of liberals seem to be
right now.
Whereas we should be acknowledging how
excruciating it is that there is this
difference even in our own societies
between Islam and something like
mormonism.
Whereas at one point,
um,
in one of my blog posts,
I pointed out that the Mormon response
to the book of Mormon was,
was adorable.
They took out ads for mormonism in
playbill,
right?
That's exactly as it should be.
Right?
And I,
and I say just incredibly withering
things about mormonism,
but that no one is no more,
man.
It's going to kill me for it and that,
and that is a difference that we know
the people,
people like Glenn Greenwald and Reza
Aslan are maintaining the status quo
actively,
energetically,
and we have the moderates and you talk
about this and end of faith that
actually the supposed moderates in this
case,
right?
And they're in their liberal apologists
and their secular liberal politics who
are not even religious.
Glenn Glenn is a gauge you,
I'm pretty sure it wouldn't go that well
for him.
It was already walking down the street
to Saudi Arabia.
I think so.
I think a Gad your previous guest,
uh,
once tweeted in response to something,
Glenn Greenwald tweeted about me know,
defending Islam.
He said,
um,
I think this was good.
It he'll correct me if I'm wrong,
but he said,
do me a favor,
Glen,
get a shirt made saying I'm gay and I
don't believe in God.
And,
and travel around the Middle East and,
and report back on your adventures.
There's one place he could do that.
And,
uh,
we'll get to that place in a second
because we're going to go,
we're going to go controversial if you
don't think we've gotten there so far.
I thought what we could do here for a
second is because I know that people are
gonna.
Say you guys are focused on Islam,
you're focusing on Islam.
Can you just give me a bunch of bad shit
about Christianity and Judaism?
I mean,
just rip it apart.
Just Gimme I know you can do it because
I read the books,
but just as telling me some really
terrible stuff.
Well,
at the level of the text,
at the level of what's just in the Old
Testament,
that is the worst book.
It is worse than the Koran.
It's,
it's,
it is the,
the most barbaric and theocratic a
recipe for human unhappiness talking
about Old Testament Judaism and clear to
some degree Christianity.
But yes.
Um,
and uh,
if you,
if you as a Jew wanted to live out of
leviticus and Deuteronomy,
uh,
you are,
you know,
just,
write of Mullah Omar in terms of your
theocratic commitments right now.
It just so happens there are reasons why
even ultra orthodox Jews aren't
committed to the letter of the law.
They're,
but they're not good reasons.
They're just,
they're just kind of accidental
historical reasons.
I was,
this is actually a,
a,
um,
a encounter I brief briefly relate in my
new book with the Majid Nawaz.
Um,
while we're talking,
I was talking to him about how I'm
always worried when I see sort of
carefully worded seemingly moderate
claims from religious people because you
sensed that there's,
there they're doing some kind of
theological correction in their brains
where it's covering for other
commitments that they're not,
not being so forthcoming about it.
And I wants discovered this with a
Orthodox Jew at a wedding.
He was a friend of the groom and,
and,
um,
we were introduced and then the groom
walked away and I said,
so I just kind of launched into my spiel
and I said,
listen,
just tell me what about all the barbers
things and leviticus and Deuteronomy and
how do you reconcile those things?
And he said,
well,
you know,
it was very interesting that all of that
was just in the context of the time.
It doesn't apply now.
There is no sand hedren,
you know,
there's no body of elders who,
who would make all of that,
uh,
effective.
And I said,
and I could see,
I could hear what he was doing there.
And I said,
okay,
well,
yeah,
but when the Messiah comes back,
as you think he will and you reconvene
the Sanhedrin in the temple is rebuilt,
then what you know,
then are you stoning people to death for
adultery in witchcraft and
homosexuality?
And,
and he said,
well,
you know,
that's fair.
It's a very hard question.
And He,
and then he said,
you know,
you don't,
I don't think you can appreciate how,
what a sacrilege those behaviors would
be in the presence of the Messiah and a
properly concentrated,
consecrated,
Sanhedrin.
Um,
and I said,
yeah,
you're right.
I can't,
you know,
so like,
aware,
what part of your body should I vomit on
now?
I mean,
it's like,
it's like the.
So the,
that was the know,
if you just push long enough you can
find the theocrat in those people.
Um,
but as a matter of fact,
there they have theological reasons why
they don't have to be stoning people to
death for homosexuality and adultery.
Right now we're working on the sabbath,
right.
Though those rules are,
are mandated in,
in the Old Testament.
But there are,
yes,
there are possible circumstances where a
religion like Christianity or Judaism is
more dangerous than Islam.
It's just we don't happen to be as,
as a global matter,
we don't happen to be in those
circumstances.
But if you take something like stem
cell,
again,
this just comes down to the specific
consequences of specific beliefs.
So Islam is totally off the hook with
embryonic stem cell research.
They don't,
they don't think that the soul enters
the Zygote at the moment of conception.
They think it enters that.
I think it's day eight or day 1:20,
depending on what you believe,
which had either you believe.
So,
you know,
when I go on and on about religious,
the religious impediment to lifesaving
medical research and on,
in embryonic stem cell research,
I'm never thinking about Islam right as
it's just as long as it's compatible
with Islam right now.
Isis could be doing embryonic stem cell
research if they wanted to.
Um,
so you just have to,
you have to be honest about who is
culpa,
what,
what ideas and what and what advocates
if those ideas are culpable for specific
problems.
Yeah.
So I'm pretty sure you're saying we just
proved your an anti Semite yes.
Oh,
I,
I got that.
I got,
I've been blamed a,
there's a passage in the end of faith
that if you read it on charitably seems
to blame the Holocaust on the Jews.
Right.
You know,
uh,
I brought that as I do.
I'm a,
no,
but I,
you know,
it's an honest fact that you have,
you have a 2000 year history of
antisemitism,
which to some degree Jews have
collaborated in by being an incredibly
insular culture,
religious culture that dogmatically
define themselves in opposition to the
rest of the world.
You know,
the non Jewish culture,
it's two sides of a coin,
doesn't,
it doesn't excuse the Holocaust,
doesn't blame Jews for the Holocaust
obviously,
but um,
well then I saw the conception of Jews
as Jews,
as a race is shared by Jews,
right?
It's not,
it hasn't been foisted on them by the
outside world and that's why it's a
problem.
Why?
You know,
why you have to get out of this game of,
of defining ourselves tribally based on
imaginary in a fictitious ideas.
Um,
and we have to realize that the way
forward is recognizing our common
humanity.
It were a single species on a single
planet trying to build a single viable
global civilization.
And there are a thousand different ways
we can screw this up and not so many
ways where we can,
we can build paradise on earth,
which should be our common project.
Yeah.
Unfortunately,
I think our definition of paradise and
some of the people that we're talking
about me,
yes,
well that may not be exactly the same
thing.
Well that's,
that's the problem you have.
I mean,
hence the power,
the,
the crucial matter of criticizing bad
ideas.
The thing is,
most people think there's a lot of bad
people running around in the world.
I,
there aren't a lot of bad people.
There are,
there are a lot of bad ideas and bad
ideas are worse than bad people because
bad ideas are contagious.
Bad ideas get good people to do horrible
things.
No,
you wrote what I think,
or I think it was on your podcast
actually,
but I read the transcript,
what I think is the most tepid defense
of Israel that has ever been said ever.
But because of it,
people think you're a Zionist.
You're secretly,
as you said earlier,
every,
you know,
you're manipulating things and blah,
blah,
blah.
Even though you've talked about dragging
settlers by their beards out of the West
Bank and all of this stuff.
I'm sorry,
can we only have about 10 minutes?
Um,
so in about five minutes,
can you just sort of sum up that what
you were talking about?
And I didn't even really view it as a
defense in a weird way.
Um,
but it was,
I didn't even,
I didn't agree with all of it by any
stretch.
I defend Israel.
It's the one tiny little democracy in
that part of the road,
which you sort of alluded to.
Um,
so can you just sort of sum that up and
then,
and then also why then even the most
tepid defense means you're automatically
on design.
Design is Nazi,
whatever.
I mean,
it was the worst titled Blog Post
podcast ever because people read it as
my,
the title was,
why don't I criticize Israel?
Yeah.
Question mark a and immediately I
reminded my readers and listeners that I
do criticize Israel,
right?
But it was read as,
you know,
this is,
I am committed to not criticizing Israel
because of x,
Y,
and z.
So I do criticize Israel.
Um,
I say in that piece that I don't think
it should exist as a Jewish state.
And I think I've been,
if I think the idea of estate organized
around a religion is just intrinsically
of noxious and divisive and
unsustainable,
uh,
with the one caveat that the only thing
that justifies the existence of Israel
as a Jewish state is the fact that the
rest of the world has rather reliably
his willingness to murder the Jews
outright.
For being Jewish.
So I mean there's,
there's no other people who are,
um,
coming out of this legacy of having been
hunted and hounded for generations until
antiquity,
uh,
by,
the rest of the world.
So it's understandable that many,
many Jews think we need a Jewish state.
Um,
and I don't deny that.
It's also,
it's not a state that's,
you know,
there's,
there's an ethnicity that is.
Judaism is not,
it's not just a religion,
so it's not,
it's not a Jewish state and quite the
same way that the Saudi Arabia is a
Islamic state.
I'm not religious in any way,
but yeah,
I like bagels and I watch curb your
enthusiasm so I get.
So I'm you guys,
I'm on precisely that sort of Jew.
Um,
and I like Israel.
I been to Israel and it's,
it's a,
um,
uh,
I've loved my time there.
Uh,
but if all the Jews woke up tomorrow and
said,
you know,
this isn't worth it.
Let's just assimilate.
Let's just,
let's just blend into the rest of the
world.
This is just,
this godforsaken piece of land is let's
give it to the Muslims.
Um,
in my view,
that wouldn't necessarily be a bad thing
if the Jews were the first religious
congregation on earth to admit that
religion as a variable,
a,
as a device,
divisive variable was just defunct and
we're just going to be human beings.
That would be a,
as a closing chapter to Judaism,
I think that would be the,
I'd be honored to be among those Jews.
And the Poles are sort of showing that,
right?
I mean most Jews are secular or
religious in any.
No,
I mean that's the,
that's the other thing about Judaism now
is that it's very hard to find Jews who
believe anything superstitious in the
service of their Judaism.
I've debate conservative rabbis who
don't even believe in God.
Apparently they believe or the God they
believe in is just like,
you know,
quantum mechanics or just pure energy or
ms dot.
It's not a god who can hear prayers,
I believe in the force with.
Yes,
that's.
I've met,
I've met that rabbi.
Yeah.
So it's a,
a uh,
but,
so my bias toward Israel,
whenever you're talking about the
conflict between Israel and her
neighbors,
my biased towards Israel is really a
bias against suicide bombing and the use
of human shields and an explicitly
genocidal aspiration which Hamas has in
its charter and many,
many of Israel's antagonists.
Ha,
have just in the way they talk about the
fate of the Jews.
I mean,
it is prophesized that,
you know,
the,
the end times will come when the very
earth cries out against the Jews were
the,
were the trees and the rocks say there's
a Jew behind me,
come kill him.
I mean,
that is,
that is the center of the fairway
Islamic Prophecy,
right?
Um,
and it's in the charter of Hamas,
right?
So how can,
how can Israel expect to deal with these
people?
Right?
So I think you illustrated in that piece
that if the
weapons were reversed,
if the Israelis had the weapons that
Hamas has and Hamas or the weapons he's
really had,
well this thing would be over tomorrow
because there would be a genocide
tomorrow,
which to me sort of sums up the white
yes conversation that's so silly.
That is the,
the,
the moral disparity that all of Israel's
critics have to admit to be
intellectually honest here and just says
Israel is showing what they would do if
they could kill all their enemies
tomorrow because they could kill all
their enemies tomorrow.
They could go into Gaza and kill
everyone.
Now they're not doing it.
You might cynically think,
well,
they're just not doing that because the
rest of the world would be so horrified
and treat them like even more like a
pariah state.
Um,
so they're not being restrained by any
commitment to human rights or anything
else notable.
They're just as pure self serving a
calculation,
but still they're not committing
genocide.
And yet you have have people on the left
claiming that what they did in Gaza was
a genocide right
there.
Their population goes up every year.
I mean,
I tweet that people all the time when
they're.
You're saying someone tweeted at you
saying about,
well,
why don't you call it genocide?
And he wrote,
well,
yeah.
So you know it's,
it's they're,
they're in a horrible and increasingly
untenable situation,
but they're dealing with people.
Some set,
some significant subset of whom support
the targeting of innocence through
suicidal terrorism in defense of
religion.
Not In,
not in this is this has flown the perch
of mere politics and mirror claims upon
a know scarce resources.
We're talking about religious
attachments to holy site,
if,
if the dome of the Rock,
if the,
if the Alex,
a mosque was destroyed as some crazy
Christians and crazy Jews want to figure
out how to accomplish.
I mean there are,
there are people who want to bomb that
building,
right to usher in the second coming of
Christ.
Or if that building were destroyed,
you would see just an all out a attempt
at genocide from the,
from the Muslim world.
Um,
again,
based entirely on the religious
symbolism of,
of just a pile of rocks.
That's the situation we're in.
I really,
I put a lot of thought to it.
How do I want to end this?
And,
uh,
I read your other Book Waking Up,
which is a guide to spirituality without
religion.
And as I've sat across from you for an
hour and a half now,
you seem to be extremely at peace.
I said to you,
you know,
in your interview with Jake,
there was a lot of ranting and raving on
his side and papers flying everywhere
and you sat there pretty much like
you're sitting here right now and you
commonly approach all these things I
think in a very admirable way.
Um,
so I,
I've read the book,
but what are some of the tactics that
you use to,
to tap into that spirituality side to
get all this?
Because we've talked about a lot of
noise and once we post these,
I know what twitter is gonna look like.
And I know what the comments are going
to look like,
how do you find some peace within all
this,
and then within everything else that is
going on in your personal life and
everything else,
how do you sort of get to that space?
All right.
Practice Meditation,
which is just paying close attention to
your experience in the present moment.
So if you do pay close attention to your
experience,
you'll notice that you have this
condition of consciousness which is
subjectively speaking,
whatever we'll learn about it at the
level of the brain at a certain point,
subjectively speaking,
it's intrinsically mysterious.
You don't know what this is or how this
is arising subjectively.
I mean you can't,
you know,
in fact you don't even know you have a
brain subjectively.
Um,
so you have this space of light and
shadow and color and energy and in that
space,
thoughts and emotions keep arising and
changing and passing away.
And the difference between being at
peace and being starkly miserable,
there's always a difference between a
being kind of free of identification
with thought and being totally captured
by your thought.
The next thought just comes up and you
don't,
you didn't notice it as a thought and
it's just all of a sudden,
it seems to become you,
you know,
so if I'm,
if I have a thought that arises and you
know,
that fucking raise Isilon,
right?
If that trims down consciousness too,
you know,
that's the entirety of my being in that
moment,
right?
So the toxicity of our lives is really
mediated by thought and the moment you
recognize it really your mind as the
level of experience and the level of
your functioning in the world,
your mind is all you have,
you know,
and,
and it's every relationship you have,
every experience you have is going to be
as good or bad as your mind is in that
context.
Um,
and we all have these experiences where
we just kind of slammed into the present
moment in a very satisfying way based
on,
you know,
some heightened experience,
whether you know your bungee jumping or
uh,
you know,
we're having sex.
So we've taken a drug or the some peak
experience,
that seat that overrides all of our kind
of habitual mediocrity.
Um,
and,
and gets us to recognize that life can
be beautiful and profound,
but you can actually take charge of that
process and just train your mind to find
that profundity in each moment.
And meditation is just that technique
and that the book waking up is my effort
to describe that process and that
possibility very much in the context of
science and without any religious Mumbo
jumbo.
I sense you'd rather spend more time
talking about that than some of these
other stuff too.
Yeah,
I mean the irony is so that,
that,
that Ben Affleck collision completely
hijack my book tour.
I was on a book tour talking about
meditation and spirituality and I'm
restricted from that instant thereafter.
They would,
it was just,
it was just all,
you know,
racism,
Islam all the time.
Um,
but yeah,
no,
I do.
I mean I just feel like I,
I view,
I really do most of my career,
certainly most of my,
everything I've said about religion as a
massive opportunity cost.
I mean,
I shouldn't have to say any of these
things.
None of us should have to say or hear or
contemplate any of these things.
I mean,
we just were talking about the,
the,
the legacy of these ancient books that
people think we're not written by human
beings,
but we're dictated by the creator of the
universe.
And,
and hence they want to throw gays off of
rooftops and,
and force women to live in bags or
prevent gay marriage in our context or
preventive embryonic stem cell research
or whatever it is.
And so we're,
we're fighting these ancient battles
which we should have outgrown centuries
ago.
And,
um,
I,
I do,
I see it as a personal opportunity costs
because yeah,
there are more interesting things to
talk about,
but I just see civilizationally we have,
we have this one opportunity to make
this life beautiful,
you know,
and we have a short life.
You know,
I have a friend who just died.
I just,
I just learned today,
right?
He was my age,
you know,
and um,
uh,
you know,
his life was whatever he made of it,
you know.
And then he had been,
he had a final hour and,
and we were all in that same
circumstance personally,
and we're in that circumstance as a
species.
And when you look at how we,
you know,
I mean,
there,
there are real challenges that make
that,
that make it make that a hard project.
I mean,
there's disease and there's no
scientific things we don't understand
that really would help us to understand
and we have environmental problems and
we can't,
we don't understand economy as well
enough to really figure out how to
prevent bad.
I'm recessions and depressions,
but we have these other,
this other area of our lives where we.
So obviously creating needless human
misery.
Uh,
and when you look at something like,
you know,
isis or,
or,
um,
uh,
the extreme forms of religion takes.
It's just,
it's just like we're just like lighting
fire to the wealth of the world for no
good reason.
And,
and um,
yeah,
so it's a no,
I appreciate the opportunity to talk for
a few minutes about something else,
but it's just a fact that I do view us
in the midst of a kind of political and
moral emergency.
And so I do find myself talking about
bad ideas more than I talk about good
ones.
Yeah.
Well I,
I feel the same way and I don't know how
many opportunities people get in life to
talk to somebody that they truly admire.
And that's what I got here today.
So I beyond that,
the first,
it's a pleasure.
And uh,
and I hope that at the end of this that
may be something good happened and if
not,
uh,
maybe we'll do it again or it was,
it was fun.
It was fun to do so.
Yeah.
Maybe next time we'll just do,
do you have a room that you do the
meditation and you have like don't,
don't at the moment they can go there,
but I could,
I could find a flights out appropriate
spot.
All right,
well,
uh,
of course you guys,
you're probably following Sam already.
It's at Sam Harris,
a org on twitter.
It,
Sam Harris Dot Org.
Uh,
you got another place we want to send
them a note on.
My website is a good hub.
Yeah,
Sam Harris Dot Org.
The website is the hub,
uh,
and his new book is coming out next
month.
So check that out.
And Sam,
I thank you once again and I thank you
guys for watching our first episode and
we're going to do it again next week.
Thanks guys.