All right,
welcome back.
So the next four lectures are also
oriented towards discussion of primarily
clinical theories of psychology and
psychopathology.
We're going to talk about lines of
thinking that in some ways run parallel
to those analysts because the thinkers
we're going to discuss now with a few
small exceptions,
well all of them,
all of the thinkers we're going to
discuss in the next four lectures were
either influenced heavily by Freud,
human adler or were themselves thinkers
who influenced Freud and young.
So there's an intellectual continuity
stretching over with with people who are
deeply educated and who are very
thoughtful.
There's intellectual continuity ideas
stretching over exceptional spans of
time and so it's exactly the sort of
thing that you would.
That sort of relationship is exactly
what you'd imagined.
Roger has had a variety of influences,
so let's say Freud and Jung and Adler,
but he was also very much influenced by
it.
Phenomenological ideas and the
phenomenologists were and are phenomenal
of brand philosophy and which I'll
explain more deeply and the other
primary domain of influence on Rogers
was Christianity likely and then
Christianity also via probably northern
European culture as far as I can tell.
The reason I'm,
I'm talking specifically about
Christianity in relationship to rogers
is because as a young man,
he was a fundamentalist Christian and he
was a seminarian.
So we had.
He was quite oriented towards mainline
Protestant Christianity,
but when he was in university,
he had a crisis of belief,
I suppose,
when he was even going to go to China as
a missionary at one point,
um,
but he had a crisis of belief in
university because he'd also been
scientifically trained.
His father was a farmer who used rather
advanced farming techniques and so
rogers was trained to think
scientifically from a very young age and
he experienced the conflict between his
religious belief and his scientific
presuppositions quite intensely.
And in that battle is formal Christian
belief was the loser.
However,
his thinking is very much influenced by
fundamentalist Protestant
presuppositions and
the effect of those all described as we
walked through Roger's thinking.
Now,
it's important to understand the
philosophical underpinnings of a global
personality or psychology theory because
every theory is set within a set of
assumptions,
things that you have to assume to be
true in order to proceed with the
theory.
I like the axioms in,
in,
uh,
in classical geometry.
You can't prove the axioms.
You have to accept them.
Once you accept the axioms,
then you can move forward and use the
whole system.
I think the reason that systems have to
have axioms which are elements of belief
is because every system is incomplete,
right?
It doesn't cover the entire world.
And so in some sense,
you need a place to dispense with your
ignorance.
And the way you do that is by making
assumptions.
We're going to act as if the following
is true and then you can proceed with a
partial theory and you'll have some
success with it,
but it's useful to understand the
presuppositions because they'd orientate
new properly towards the theory.
Now Rogers is a phenomenologist and
phenomenology is a brand of philosophy
which I believe started with Edmund
Husserl,
but was probably made most influential
by his student,
Martin Heidegger.
Now heidegger
was,
there was a philosopher,
I suppose somewhat like Nicha and that
he was very much his thinking around,
very much counter to what you might
describe as general academic philosophy.
For example,
heidegger believe that ever since the
time of Plato,
which is when people think philosophy
began,
more or less western philosophy,
had taken up an erroneous direction.
It had become too concerned with the
nature of structures of thought and not
concerned enough about the nature of
being and so you can determine those two
things being as how things are and
thought of course is how you represent
things,
and one of heidegger's missions was to
reestablish being as the central reality
of philosophy.
Now,
that begs the question,
which is what is being well to
conceptualize reality as being is not to
conceptualize it the same way that you
conceptualize it
in terms of modern Western thought.
Because one of the presuppositions at
the basis of modern Western thought is
that the most intelligent way to divide
up the world is in terms of and
objective experience or subjective and
subjective experience and object of
world.
So the fundamental scientific
presupposition you might say is that
there is an objective world.
It's the real thing.
You come to that by performing certain
procedures,
documenting them,
describing now of those procedures,
and then allowing other people to do the
same thing,
operating under the presupposition that
if they experience the same outcome from
the procedures,
then what they're experiencing is real.
That's basically the scientific method,
right?
Method results,
your detailed the method,
which is how you act on the world.
You get the results,
you compare them maybe across multiple
observations that you do,
and then other people do multiple
observations.
You come up with that with a consensus,
but it's a method bound consensus and
then of course you abstract out general
principles from that works very
powerfully,
right?
Make no mistake about it.
The objective,
the idea that there is an objective
external world and that that's the best
way to conceptualize reality is an
unbelievably powerful tool.
Now,
whether or not it's an accurate
description of reality,
that's a much more difficult question
and it's partly a matter of definition
actually,
you know,
it's the case that there are different
forms of geometry.
You might know this,
you can start from the presupposition
that reality has a three dimensional
structure and then you're basically
within the realm of Euclidean geometry,
but you can also start with the
presupposition that reality has afforded
emotional structure and that kind of
geometry was invented in the late 18
hundreds and it turned out to be the
perfect geometry to describe the
universe that Einstein conceptualized
when he came up with his great theories
in,
in the second decade of the 20th
century.
So it's interesting because you could
start from different assumptions,
build tools on the basis of those
assumptions,
and sometimes you find out that those
tools work very well.
Indeed.
Now it's not that easy to think of flaws
in the subjective experience.
Objective,
world conceptualization,
and that's partly for,
as for us as modern people,
it forms the basis of so much of what we
think that we just think about it as
axiomatic.
It's just true.
It doesn't bear any question,
but I'm going to offer you a couple of
examples of why it might bear some
questioning and you can,
you can think about,
you can think about it.
The first problem is that that the
classical scientific view of the world
has a very difficult time accounting for
certain things.
So for example,
these are called quality,
uh,
often by people who are interested in
consciousness.
So knowing the wave length of light
doesn't seem to tell you much about the
subjective experience of color.
You know,
we,
we experienced,
for example,
in a non continuous fashion,
right?
Because we see discreet colors like
you'd see in a rainbolt.
I mean they shade into each other to
some degree,
but it's not like they go from light
red,
dark red in the continuum,
there's clear demarcations of color.
While that's because of the way your
brain is wired,
you know it,
it seems like over the course of
evolution,
what we've learned is that parsing up
that wavelength fragment in terms of
categories which would be the different
colors that we see has substantial
practical utility.
Now what are the things you might ask
is,
well,
do those colors exist?
Well,
objectively,
they don't seem to exist as colors,
partly because of the wavelengths that
we see are actually continuous.
So when one color shades into another,
there's no radical transformation and
wave lake length.
It's a continuum,
but we see it categorically.
Okay,
so is that real or not?
Or The colors we see real or not?
Well,
that's a good question.
Um,
you can't get a collective experience of
pain,
like you can get a collective experience
of the blackboard,
but pain seems to be something that's
limited to subjective perception,
but it's very difficult.
No one acts as if pain isn't real.
I mean,
I would say that of all the things that
you might consider real,
we act as if pain is the most real
thing.
You certainly can't argue yourself out
of it,
for example.
It seems like a fundamental element of
experience.
Okay,
so that's two places.
We also have no account in the
subjective objective.
What breakup?
Bifurcation of the world.
We have no explanation whatsoever for
consciousness.
That seems like a big problem,
right,
because you could make a case that
there's no being without consciousness.
Like is there something if there's no
one there to receive it,
by the way,
that is not the same question as if a
tree falls in the forest and there was
no one there to hear.
It doesn't make it sound.
It's not the same question.
It sounds superficially the same,
but this is a much more complex question
because we don't know.
For example,
if we don't know the relationship
between time and consciousness,
like we have a certain perception of
time.
We have a certain temporal realm within
which we exist.
Our refresh rate for our vision,
for example,
is about 60 hertz,
which is why you can see computer
screens flicker.
If they have a reflex rate that's slower
than that,
so 60 hertz to us looks continuous,
but you know there's a lot of
microseconds in a second and for a
computer,
especially a fast process it computer
that can do maybe a trillion operations
per second.
If it was watching,
so to speak,
a movie,
it would just see a picture still
picture that was there forever and then
another still picture that was there
forever and like it wouldn't have the
impression of continuous movement.
So there's this weird subjective element
to time.
It's very difficult to understand.
And then here's more,
here's a more complex criticism of the
subject object idea.
I thought about this for a long time.
So the best example I know of it is I
read this book a while back written by a
kgb officer and it was published after
the fall of the,
you know,
the wall and the Soviet Empire.
And this KGB officer claimed that he had
worked in a biological warfare unit in
the Soviet Union.
And the purpose of the biological
warfare unit was to turn infectious
diseases into aerosols so that they can
be sprayed on enemy populations,
and so they were working on two things,
developing a very,
very silent infection.
And so if your infection is one that's
very severe but also very transmissible
because those things are separate and
then also one that could survive being
aerosolized because it turns out that
that's quite difficult,
which we should all be very thankful
about.
And one of the projects they were
working on was a,
an attempt to cross Ebola was smallpox.
Now Ebola is,
you all know about Ebola,
I presume it's a.
it's very,
very fatal,
although they've learned ways to treat
it now and maybe have a vaccine,
but at that time it was very,
very fatal and a smallpox is incredibly
contagious and so they were hoping they
could develop something that it was
very,
very contagious and very,
very deadly that you could spray on
civilian populations.
Now you know here,
here's where it gets tricky.
It gets tricky here because how you
answered this question inevitably,
inevitably depends on how you define
truth.
And truth is actually something you have
to define before you can have a
conversation about it,
which is a kind of a strange thing
anyways.
You can make a case that determining how
to cross Ebola with smallpox and
aerosolized.
It is a perfectly valid scientific
question
and because science is value free,
it's very difficult to make an argument
that that's any worse experiment than
any other kind of experiment or any
other kind of investigation.
And you could also imagine even that if
you didn't go to the aerosolization
stage,
that positive things might come out of
it.
Maybe you'd end up with a more detailed
understanding of DNA or something as a
consequence of the investigation that
would have positive consequences.
But it still seems that the idea of
doing scientific research across
crossing Ebola,
smallpox,
it,
it seems to be something wrong about
that.
And it's maybe that sense of wrongness
as well that can't be captured with
inside inside scientific models.
And so one of the things that you
claimed in and Rogers and the is that in
some sense is that the scientific
reality has to be encapsulated within a
unethical reality rather than the other
way around.
Now Rogers would say,
you know that feeling you have when you
hear about someone crossing Ebola with
smallpox,
that feeling you have in your body.
That's a real thing.
That feeling and that that's part of
being
now
for the phenomenologists being is
actually complicated to define and it's
hard to understand,
but what the phenomenologists do,
we start with a different set of
assumptions.
They don't assume that the best way to
approach reality is to break it up into
this objective and the object it presume
instead that the way that you should
approach reality is by assuming that all
of your experiences real all of it.
Now,
that doesn't mean there aren't different
categories of experience,
you know,
because you could still say a dream and
the experience you have walked dreaming
of walking down the street and walking
down the street are still different
things.
And the phenomenologists would say,
yes,
you can keep your categorical
distinctions in tact,
but you have to say that they're both
real.
Now
this is an assumption and I told you
why.
The assumptions generating part of the
reason the assumption is generated.
The alternative assumption is because
there are problems that emerged with the
set of assumptions that make up the
scientific worldview.
Now,
it's not that surprising that the
scientific worldview can't encompass the
subjective because the scientific world
view was actually established by by
Bacon and descartes safe and by well,
by other thinkers of that time,
it was set up to exclude the subjective
from the conceptualization of objective
reality.
So you can't really criticize science
because he does that,
but you can say the fact that the
subjective is excluded is a fault or at
least an incompleteness and that
incompleteness sometimes has
extraordinary extraordinarily serious
consequences that you can't just dismiss
because you might say,
well,
have the Russians being the Soviets
being successful in crossing Ebola with
smallpox and aerosolizing it.
Then we might all be dead and then he
might think that any theory that leads
everyone to be dead might reasonably be
criticized for its assumption to
universal truth.
Now you can debate that,
but and,
and rightly so,
but all I'm pointing out,
is there a reasons to go at this from
another approach?
Now,
it was Roger's basic assumption that you
were more likely to be properly oriented
in life if you adopted a phenomenal,
logical approach to your experience and
to break up reality in that manner.
So let me give you an example.
When I,
when my daughter was about three,
she have nightmare and she came running
into
her parent's bedroom and she told me her
dream and she was all upset by it.
She might've even been younger than
three.
At that point had she had dreamed that
there was a clear stream and that it was
quite beautiful and that there was
garbage littering the bottom of it.
Now,
by that time,
you know,
she,
kids are quite sophisticated in their
ability to categorize.
You know,
by that time she'd already learned the
difference between a kid things and
adult things.
And you think that's a bloody complex
form of discrimination,
you know,
because like what objective features do
adult things share in common that
differentiates them from things you,
you can't actually come up with a set of
objective criteria that allows that
distinction to be made.
But kids by the time they're three years
got a pretty clear grasp of that so they
can come up with very sophisticated
classifications.
I'm about the same time and one of my
friends had a two year old who went
outside their house one day and looked
down the street and there were a couple
of garbage cans knocked over and the kid
said,
oh,
and you know,
that's also extremely sophisticated
because you think,
you know,
the whole street is a very complex
visual set of visual stimuli.
And to be able to glance at that and
then to know that something is out of
place and then to make an otter and
solid to draw people's attention to it
is a ridiculously sophisticated
cognitive out.
And my daughter was doing the same thing
within the context of her dream.
So she was upset about this.
Now it's quite interesting because you
think,
well why would someone who was three the
upset about the fact that a stream
beautiful,
clear stream was with had garbage in it,
you know,
it's,
it's a really,
it's like innate environmentalism or
something like that and a concern for
the environment and that could easily be
the case,
you know what I mean?
If we found our environment up
continually during our evolutionary
history,
that was likely to have very negative
consequences.
Even birds cleaned their own nest and so
the fees and you know,
they keep their hives,
cleaning all of that.
So it could be a very primordial
instinct.
Anyway,
she came in with this dream and she was
quite upset and then you think,
well there's a couple of things you
could do about that.
You could say it's just a dream.
Don't worry about it,
go back to sleep,
but you know,
that's a philosophical statement,
right?
And it's,
it's,
it's a misleading one.
Or You could argue that it was
misleading because what does,
it's just a dream mean?
Well,
it means that it's certainly not
something to take,
like you would take serious.
Take something that occurred during the
day,
seriously,
it's a mirror like a fantasy,
but with the definition of fantasy being
some fundamentally useless
act of what to play,
I suppose that you can ignore with no
consequences and not only that,
but you should ignore it and you know
that's.
That's not necessarily true because then
you're making the case or you might be
making the case that you don't have to
pay attention to products of your
imagination.
That seems like a pretty dopey thing to
tell a child given a,
that anything creative that you ever
produced is going to come out of your
imagination and be the way that you set
goals and plans for your future is by
imagining them dreaming about them.
Right?
Everyone knows what it means to pursue a
dream and you know you might say,
well,
if you're depressed,
it means all your dreams have
disappeared.
It's like so maybe you shouldn't be
telling your child that it's just a
dream and so you can go.
You can ignore it and go back to sleep.
You know,
you don't know exactly what you're doing
when you,
when you do that,
you're certainly not paying attention to
the child's experience because it's.
She did have that image and it did make
her upset and those are facts and as far
as people like Rogers would be
concerned,
those are facts about reality.
Are there elements of reality and they
should be dealt with as such.
So I told her to close her eyes and to
bring the dream image APP,
inner imagination,
which she could do very well.
And then to imagine that she had some
rubber boots on and that she could go
into the street and pick out the garbage
and put it in the garbage bag and that
there was a garbage can nearby and she
could put it in the garbage can.
And so we went through that and that
calmed her down and then she went back
to bed.
And then you might say,
well,
what?
What am I doing doing that?
Because you might say,
well,
that's just a fantasy.
Just like the dream and because they're
just fantasies.
Neither of them have anything to do with
reality.
But you know that again,
that's not very sophisticated way of
thinking because the dream presented my
daughter with a problem,
or you could even say a class of
problems and the class of problems.
It includes all of those things that
people do too and I and other animals,
of course,
all the ways that the environment can be
defiled well,
that actually is an existential problem,
and then you might say,
well,
what should you do about it now?
So that might be,
well,
maybe you should do something about it
in so far as you can do something about
it because then you're conceptualizing
yourself as an active agent and not just
a passive victim or a passive recipient
of the problem.
You could actually do something about it
and that's a way different messages.
Then it's just a dream.
You can ignore it and go back to sleep.
You know what you've maybe you shouldn't
actually tell your child to be ignoring
reality and go back to sleep.
Maybe you should be telling them to wake
up and see reality as clearly as they
possibly can and not ignore any of it,
including their fantasies.
In their dreams,
and that doesn't mean that they're
fantasies have the same reality as the
reality that you experience with
everyone else,
but the fact that it's not the same
reality that you experience with
everyone else doesn't mean it's not
reality.
Now Rogers would claim,
for example,
that to ignore a private experience
warps you fundamentally.
So
here's the basic outlines of his view of
the world,
so there's first of all,
you exist within a phenomenal logical
field.
Now phenomenon.
Phenomenon comes from the Greek word
famous thigh and famous thigh means to
shine forth and so phenomena are those
things that shine forth for you.
Now the way to understand that is to
imagine that you're reading a book and
maybe a passage of it really strikes you
as meaningful.
Well then you might say,
well,
why?
There's lots of passages in the book.
If someone else was reading the book,
it's not obvious that the same passage
would strike them,
and then you might say,
well,
is that a consequence of the structure
of you as as a,
as a,
as an interpreter of the book?
Or is it a consequence of the contents
of the book and the answer to that is
you actually can't tell because the book
is neither the thing that's printed,
nor the reader.
The book is the interaction between the
reader and the book,
and that interaction is actually unique
for each person.
Even though there might be some
commonalities across people because
otherwise you would need to be able to
talk about a book.
Well,
regardless when you're interacting with
something,
some things announced themselves on your
field of consciousness and other things
don't,
and so the phenomenologists would say,
well,
something shine forth for you.
Well,
other things don't.
It's a little bit like one of us ideas
about the development of the self.
Don't believe that if you follow the
things that announced themselves to you
as meaningful,
that they would take you to through a
descent to begin with where you would
encounter things you were afraid of or
terrified of and disgusted by and wanted
to avoid.
And then the consequence of that would
be that you do incorporate a lot of new
material into your personality and the
consequences of that would be you'd be
reborn roughly speaking as a stronger
person,
and then if you just kept doing that all
the time for the rest of your life in
small and large ways,
that you'd become more and more and more
fully differentiated and developed,
and he wouldn't have said that the the
ultimate potential target of that kind
of development was what he described as
the self.
The self is a multifaceted
conceptualization,
so that's not all there is to it,
but the self from the union perspective
is who you could be if you could be who
you most deeply are.
If you didn't shy away from anything,
if you,
if you accurately encountered and then
integrated even in a pod and sense your
experience.
Now that's.
That's exactly the same idea that Rogers
had.
He believed that
there's a phenomenal field and it's full
of experience.
All of your experience manifests itself
as the phenomenal field is quite
interesting because if it means also
that other people are part of your
phenomenal field,
part of your experience,
and then that all within that field,
there's a circumscribed area that he
described as the self that's it's
different than the union itself,
so it somewhat terminological confusing.
Roger yourself is more like Freud's ego,
but Rogers would define myself as those
aspects of the phenomenological field
that you,
that you call.
I felt like I've had clients who tended
to talk in the third person about their
emotions or they would say the body.
They wouldn't say I maybe they're
describing cutting themselves.
They'd say,
well,
the body needed to be cut,
and
what Rogers would say about that was
that
person existed in the phenomenological
field and part of that phenomenal
logical field was demarcated by the
self,
like the self hadn't expanded to
incorporate as much of that
phenomenological field as it should
have.
The other concept he had was the con.
Another concept he had was the concept
of the organism.
Now you can think of the self as what
you identified with it and then you can
think of the organism as all those
things that are unique to you that you
might identify with the art.
Now it's tricky because imagine that you
get angry during a fight with someone
argument and they say,
you're angry and you say,
no,
I'm not lost.
Like what exactly are you doing there?
The other person we're gonna.
Assume the other person is right for the
sake of this argument.
They can clearly see that you're angry,
but you're not
allowing
the organismic manifestation of
motivational state or emotion to be
incorporated with those things that you
identify with.
Rogers would call that into groans and
he believed that incongruent was roughly
equivalent to psychopathology,
so that part of your goal was to
was for the organism to respond
appropriately to the broader
phenomenological field.
Now we can talk about what appropriately
means,
but we won't do that yet,
and then what the self was supposed to
do is accurately symbolically represent
organismic responses to the broader
phenomenological field.
So now you can see that there are
similarities between that concept and
say Freud's idea of the ego and they
know because the Ed was this sort of
external thing that was the home of
motivational and emotional forces that
couldn't be easily integrated into the
ego and for partly because the Super Ego
said,
for example,
that they were wrong and so there is
this,
these sets of phenomena you know,
that all of the different clinicians are
talking about,
but all of them are talking about it
starting from different initial
presuppositions and it's like a group of
people in the room shining a flashlight
on a very complex object.
You know,
they're all standing in a slightly
different position.
The complex object is the same thing,
but you can only see parts of it and so
you need multiple different ways of
looking at things so that you can come
up with a cohesive and coherent account
of something that's actually beyond your
understanding.
Because of course not only can you not
accurately,
symbolically represented the
phenomenological world,
the entire domain of your being,
you can't accurately represent even the
organismic.
The aspect of that field that's related
to the organismic you,
there's this part of you on top that you
identify with,
I roughly speaking,
and it's trying to model a model of
something very complex and of course
that's extraordinarily difficult.
Now why is it doing that?
That's the central mystery of
consciousness.
You know,
there's this problem that consciousness
researchers always refer to it.
It's an annoyingly termed,
I think it's called the Zombie problem,
and the Zombie problem is why is
consciousness necessary?
Like why is it necessary for something
complex like a human being to actually
have awareness and self awareness?
Why couldn't it just wander through the
world reacting in predetermined
deterministic fashion?
Zombie like no awareness robot,
like let's say what's consciousness for
Rogers doesn't really discuss that and
so we won't at the moment.
Although I think there are some
reasonable ideas.
Consciousness,
for example,
I was using generalized between certain
phenomena anyways,
regardless,
there's the self,
the organism in the broader
phenomenological field.
Let's say you go into a
pub bar
and you're,
you've been there many times and so you
know the people in there,
you know where to sit.
You know what's going to happen.
You may have friends there,
you might say that your organism
exists
at least in part as a very accurate
model of that broader,
phenomenal,
logical world,
and then inside that you're aware of
your knowledge of them,
the bar,
and so
if your organism is properly adapted to
the broader phenomenological field,
when you go into the bar or other
familiar place,
things that you expect and want happened
instead of things that you neither
expect nor one,
and you could say,
well perhaps that's a reasonable
definition of adaptation.
Now this isn't biological revolutionary
identification,
right?
This is personal adaptations.
There are similar in some ways,
but importantly different mean you can
be adapted to an environment without
that in any way having any effect
whatsoever on your evolutionary
adaptiveness.
So
now if you're,
maybe you're not very well organism
actually adapted to the environment.
You have a model of it and because of
that,
when you go somewhere familiar,
people don't like you as much as you
think they do and you're not nearly as
much of a master of that situation as
you think you are and one of the
consequences of that,
so that would mean that your self
representation is too rigid and
simplistic and full of defenses to
notice the discrepancy between your
organism and the broader environment
that's pathological and the way that's
going to be marked is first by anxiety.
You know,
maybe you tell a joke.
There's some people sitting around you,
you tell a joke and you see people kind
of,
you know,
making that face maybe rolling their
eyes.
It's like,
well that's not exactly.
You might think,
well,
they're joking.
You know,
they're just,
they're just teasing me.
Well maybe they're not.
Maybe they're damn sick of your stupid
stories and you've told them 50 times
and you're not very funny and they'd
rather you work in the bar at all and it
may be that you'll actually notice that,
but you don't necessarily notice it in a
symbolically fully symbolically
developed.
Now,
what that would mean is maybe you start
feeling anxiety and Roger's identify as
different levels of feeling.
It might start with this subception and
to succeed something which is a word
that I guess comes from general
semantics,
is to have the event affect the way that
you're interacting with the world in
ways that you don't necessarily notice,
so it sort of equivalent to the idea of
subliminal when you're talking about
advertising messages.
Flashed out unit suddenly changes the
way that you're interacting with the
world,
but you don't notice that.
That and that happens to people all the
time.
I mean it's actually a part of our
normal cognitive structure and when you
walk into this room,
the room tells you all sorts of things
about how to behave and you don't notice
that the room is telling you those
things because you know what it's
telling you so well that you just act it
out.
You don't need to go through all the
complex processes of actually perceiving
and thinking about it,
and so Roger's oranges that you can
detect things organismic Lee.
That will affect the nature of your
experience without necessarily either
even perceiving that or definitely not
symbolically representing it.
Now maybe the social discomfort that's
inherent in the situation rises up to
the level of perception that's not
symbolization yet.
Then you might think,
well,
what does it feel like to be anxious?
Well,
that,
and I'm not asking what are the
objective markers of being anxious
because we actually don't know those.
We know we can kind of infer them.
Sometimes people's heart rate goes up,
but sometimes it decelerates and then
there are facial expressions that are
associated with anxiety,
but you have to use those to infer.
If you get anxious,
I don't feel your anxiety,
I have to infer it,
but if you get anxious,
you feel your anxiety and so then the
question might be,
well,
what does it mean to feel anxious?
Wealth?
That's a hard question and the reason
it's a hard question is because you
never have to answer it because if you
tell someone I felt anxious,
then they refer to their own feelings of
anxiety and then they know what you mean
and you never have to come up with an
explanation of what it feels like.
The feeling this,
the idea that the feeling is an element
of experience is something that we just
take for granted.
You know,
I got angry today.
Everybody nods or maybe I tell a little
story and say,
well,
you know,
I got on the bus and I was missing like
two cents and I asked the bus driver if
he would let me get on the bus and he
didn't and not really annoyed me because
I take that bus everyday and the driver
knows me and I got angry and everybody
not.
And the reason they nod is a partly
because they can imagine that that's how
they would have reacted in that
situation.
But even more importantly,
they accept the reality of angry as a
response and they know what it feels
like.
So explaining it.
That's a much more difficult thing,
so the point is is that you can have
experiences that you know of.
First of all,
you can have experiences that you don't
know of that would be the subsea
experiences.
Then you can have experiences that you
perceive but that you haven't
symbolically represented and those might
be emotional or motivational
experiences,
and then you can have experiences that
you have symbolically represented in a
way that captures their just accurately
in a way that's reflective of your
adaptation or lack thereof to the
broader phenomena.
Logical world and Rogers would say that
latter state is preferable.
You know how to act or you know that you
didn't act properly and you know how to
fix it,
which is almost as good and you
represent that accurately.
Now you might imagine that you could
concentrate on the mismatch between
organismic responses and the
environment.
That's what behavior therapists really
do.
They say,
well,
how are you acting and what are the
consequences,
but that isn't really where Roger's
goes.
Rogers is more psychoanalytic than the
behavior therapists and what he seems to
be primarily concerned about is whether
or not your self representation is an
accurate representation of of how your
organism is responding.
In some sense,
for Rogers,
the organism takes the place of God.
It's more or less omniscient,
so your organism is going to tell you
the truth in every situation and it's up
to you whether or not you're going to
pay attention to that and make sense of
it or whether you're going to engage in
any of the different kinds of
shenanigans that you might engage in to
stop yourself from going through the
complex process of symbolization.
Because you might say,
well,
you're back in the bar and you might
say,
well,
you notice the anxiety and then you
know,
different ways of symbolizing it.
Come to mind.
These people are all people are all just
jerks.
And then another thing comes to mind is,
well,
maybe nobody likes me.
And then maybe another idea that's
associated with symbolization comes to
mind,
which is,
well,
maybe there's elements of my social
behavior that I should adjust.
And I presume that if Roger's was having
a conversation with one of his clients,
he would assume that that was the most,
that was the most fruitful potential
step towards accurate symbolization.
Now Roger's felt that anxiety emerged
when the self concept was not accurately
symbolically representing the organisms
experiences,
and so that would be in some sense if
you're a house divided within yourself,
then you're your pathological from a
Rogerian perspective.
And you can think about that in some
sense as a move away from necessary.
Simplicity
mean
if your self concept is set up property,
it doesn't contain contradictory and
misleading bits of information.
Everything works seamlessly together.
And so what that would mean is that you
think about something,
you act it out and it works,
and then that's an indication that the
organization between say these different
three different levels of being is the
right word,
is icer morphing each represents the
other with sufficient accuracy.
And so that means that you're congruent
and if you're congruent,
then the world is treating you not only
in the manner that you want to be
treated,
but also in the manner that's most
likely.
Two
further your actions in the world as an
organism,
and so that's partly why Rogers believed
that the organism had wisdom because
it's natural proclivity was to operate
in the world effectively and to expand
its competence at the same time and what
self actualized person because that's
one of Roger's phrases is someone who
self concept accurately represents their
organismic
being.
Now Rogers was primarily a clinician as
well,
and his theories were derived from his
clinical experience and his theories
informed his clinical practice and
Roger's invented or developed what he
believed to be a new kind of therapy and
he called that client centered therapy.
Now you've probably heard about student
centered education in Rogers.
I ideas have had a tremendous amount of
influence,
certainly not at least in educational
psychology.
Also in conflict reduction of various
sorts.
You start with Rogers initial
assumptions,
which is first of all,
you should regard your experience as
real.
Second,
that your organism will give you
accurate information about the totality
of experience and third,
that your self concept should accurately
encompass your actual experience.
There are implications of that theory
for therapy and one of the implications
is that you can figure out what you
should do if you want to because your
organism will tell you or at least hint
at you about which directions are
correct and which directions are,
and if you follow those,
then you're going to naturally gravitate
towards a state of being where you're
more and more accurately represented by
yourself,
but also that your representation and
your organism are going to act more
effectively in the world.
They're not bumping up against each
other all the time and you know they're
not even conflict anymore,
and so that's the goal of the self
actualized person at therapy in part is
the art of furthering that process of
self actualization.
Now,
Rogers Rogers
was opposed to diagnosis because he felt
that it didn't sufficiently represent
the vital minutia of the client's
individual experience and I think
that's.
I think that his claim was extremely
important.
No,
because medicine psychiatry tends to
classify everything and you might say,
well,
are the psychiatric diagnostic
classifications real?
And then the answer that is,
it depends on what you mean by real
anyway.
Think well that's an annoying answer,
but it is.
It is still the answer.
So I could say if I was being cynical,
although I don't really think it's a
cynical response,
if I was willing to sound cynical,
that the only reason that psychiatrist
diagnosed their clients is so that
insurance companies can pay the bills
and I actually believe that that's more
true than the claim,
that the psychiatric diagnostic
categories accurately actually capture
the essence of the person's problems.
In my clinical experience,
classification has had almost zero
utility and the reason for that is
because it's too low resolution.
It doesn't capture the individual
property because the thing about a
client clinical client is that it's
precisely their individuality.
That's the fundamental issue.
It's like they have to make their way
through the world in their body and
their in their time and their position
in culture with their advantages and
disadvantages.
And that requires a unique solution
that's unique in many ways.
And one that's also personally
and rogers also wasn't a particularly
great fan of the psychoanalysts tendency
to look for the causes of present
behavior in past events so he didn't.
He didn't regard fishing in the past as
a useful,
necessarily useful expedition or as
unnecessary expedition.
Although if issues of the past came up
in therapy,
he was perfectly willing to to to deal
with them.
He didn't accept except the Freudian
theory that the fundamental cause of
psychopathology was saying traumatic
past experience.
Right
now,
this gives Rogerian therapy a particular
flavor.
You could also call it non directive
therapy.
Now if you're a behavior therapist,
you might actively strategize with your
client about what they're going to do in
the next week and then once they've
established their goals,
you might offer some hints about what
strategies they could use to monitor
themselves and to attain those goals and
maybe you'll even have to keep track of
it.
Roger's generally speaking,
wouldn't do something that directive and
in fact he strove not to unduly
influenced the client's decisions about
important future events.
And in that way,
he was quite similar to Freud because
Freud would sit behind,
would sit,
so the client would be laying on a couch
and fred would sit so that the client is
patient,
actually couldn't see him and then he
would listen to the person free
associate,
which in some sense means that they
would ramble on and he was attempting by
doing that to facilitate the self
realization of their,
of their own memories.
If things happened to you in your past
and they still cause you emotion,
let's say they're more than 18 months
old for the sake of argument,
Freud,
but assume that if you kind of wandered
around that memory somewhat haphazardly
and in an in an association will weigh
the way conversations naturally unfold,
that you would bring things to light and
that would allow a certain kinds of
emotional expression in that.
And in fact in itself would be curative.
But for I didn't want to with your fear
with that process or guided to any great
degree.
And so rogers was like that he,
he wanted you to make your own
decisions.
So he believed that the therapeutic
endeavor required could not,
could not occur unless certain
conditions were met and the conditions
were
willingness to tell the truth.
So when,
when a client comes to see me,
one of the first things I tell them is,
you can tell me anything you want,
although you're perfectly within your
rights to maintain your privacy,
you can tell me anything you want,
but tell me the truth as much as clearly
as you can.
Because if you don't,
there isn't.
I don't know what's going on with you
and there's not a possibility on any
possibility at all that I can,
that this process will be useful if
we're talking about things that don't
exist.
So one precondition is the person is
willing to come and see you.
So that means they want to transform.
The second precondition is that they're
going to communicate with you and
communication means they're going to do
their best to tell the truth.
But the therapist takes the same
vow in a sense.
And so one of the things that I tell my
clients is that I will never let them do
anything that makes me resent them.
So if I'm asked to step out of my way
for some reason to take an additional
session or maybe to meet them somewhere
and I do it,
they can be assured that there won't be
a price that will be extracted from them
later for interfering with the smooth
flow of my day.
So,
and the other thing that I do,
and I've learned this from Rogers and
from the other people I've read,
is that I'll listen to people talk and
then sometimes something will occur to
me and I don't think about it as I
thought something because I'm actually
somewhat a follower of nickname.
She's dictum,
which is that the fact that you think is
no approved,
that the fact that you experienced
thoughts is no proof that you thought it
just appeared.
While you don't think that you think
that your dreams right,
you have your dreams.
There you are in band.
They're the dreams.
Are you having them?
Well,
it doesn't seem like it.
It seems like you're experiencing this
in some sense the same way you
experienced the external world
voluntarily creating them.
Well,
why do you think anything different
about your thoughts?
And that's a very useful thing to
realize by the way because otherwise you
think your your thoughts and then if you
have negative thoughts,
well then you assume that they're true
and they're not true just because you
think that they are just thoughts and
maybe they're true and maybe they're
useful and maybe they're not.
So stepping back from them a little bit
is incredibly.
It's like Buddhist detachment in a
sense.
It's an incredibly useful thing to do.
I mean that's another thing that's
really characteristic of modern people
because especially if they're smart,
they think they think first of all and
second they think that the things they
think are true and neither of those
things are necessarily true and
abandoning your belief in them.
It makes you much less rigid and much
more able to expand your preconceptions
or even radically change them when the
circumstances demand them.
So the person has to be wanting to
change in principal in a positive
direction.
They have to be willing to tell the
truth.
Then the next element of Rogerian
psychotherapy is something that he
called unconditional positive regard and
unconditional positive regard,
and the Rogerian tradition is something
like radical acceptance.
It's actually a hallmark of modern child
rearing techniques.
You should wholeheartedly accept all
aspects of the person's being.
Now Rogers believed that are positive,
that partly because he also believed in
what was it called,
conditions of worth.
Here's the condition of worth.
I don't like you when you act like that,
so you imagine you might tell a child
that I don't like you when you act like
that and maybe you tell them that about
a bunch of things that they do,
but maybe those are integral parts of
the child's being and by making your
lack of acceptance,
no,
you make it impossible for the child to
incorporate.
Those aspects of his organism.
Organism will experience into a self
concept.
You can see echoes of the Super Ego
Eagle idea there and so rogers would
say,
well,
if someone comes into psychotherapy and
experiences unconditional positive
regard,
that means that they'll be able to
reveal those elements up their
organismic experience that have been
rejected and say by the social world and
themselves experienced them and then
potentially incorporate them within the
self concept and that that's going to be
a good thing because rogers is a great
believer in the natural inevitability of
positive transformation.
If if you set that up as your your goal,
he also believes that that should be
your goal and that it's actually your
natural goal.
If,
for example,
you haven't been subjected to arbitrary
conditions of worth,
now I'm going to read you something that
Rodger's road,
which is quite interesting and I think I
found it extremely effective.
Oh yes.
That's another thing I should mention.
There is one other important assumption
in the idea of self actualization.
The other thing that Roger tried to
ensure that his clients develop was
autonomy and independence.
Now for Rogers,
there was very little difference between
the move towards autonomy and in any and
personal independence and the process of
self actualization.
Now,
given that we're looking back at Roger's
work,
50 years later,
you might ask yourself is if autonomy
and independence is a necessary
precondition for psychological health
because you could make the case that
productive interdependence and more
communal orientation is equally healthy,
but that's not a Rogerian
presupposition,
so
his ideal is the fully functioning
individual.
So here's his hypothesis with regards to
psychotherapy,
assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communications,
we may say that the greater the
communicated congruence of experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual,
the more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities,
mutually accurate understanding of the
communication's improved,
psychological adjustment and functioning
in both parties and mutual satisfaction
in the relationship.
Okay,
so let's unpack that.
Assuming a minimal mutual willingness to
be in contact and to receive
communication well,
the first thing you might say is that
it's pretty much thought the hallmark of
a relationship,
right?
Because if you're not in contact,
well clearly you don't have a
relationship and if you are in contact
but you're not communicating,
you probably don't have a relationship.
Alright,
so
and you know,
that also begs the question of exactly
what a relationship is for and that's
something that's very much worth
considering because people don't really
usually know what a relationship is for.
They certainly know that as a general
rule they're going to pursue them,
but they don't really have any idea in
some sense what the optimal state is or
what the desired final state should be.
Now,
of course the desired final state 50
years ago was marriage,
but I don't.
It's certainly the case now that most
people who are couples aren't married.
Now you might ask yourself,
well,
what's the utility of a relationship and
what's the utility of a long term
relationship?
Well,
the Rogerian answer to that would be the
more based on trust the relationship is
the more likely that you're going to be
in contact and to receive communications
and then as a consequence of that,
you're going to become better and better
at representing your organismal
experience within your self concept,
and that's going to facilitate your
movement towards self awareness and self
actualization.
It's a two.
Brains are better than one idea.
So we say,
well,
we established a relationship.
Okay,
and the goal of our relationship is to
make things better,
and we we make a presupposition that the
way you make things better is by telling
the truth as you see it.
So remember,
this is a phenomenological theory,
and so the truth that Rogers is talking
about isn't objective truth.
And I suspect that at least in part
because establishing objective truth
within the confines of a relationship is
I think it's technically impossible and
we talked about that before because each
interaction between the members of a
couple or people in any relationship is
contaminated in a sense by all of the
other interactions they've ever had.
Plus everything they bring to bear on
the situation and there's just no
untangling that objectively know.
What did you mean when you said that
that well,
God,
you know,
you can argue about that for
to the point of divorce and for 10 years
afterwards,
you know,
without ever coming to a satisfactory
conclusion.
All right?
The greatest greater the communicated
congruence of experience,
awareness and behavior on the part of
one individual.
The more the ensuing relationship will
involve a tendency towards reciprocal
communication with the same qualities.
Okay,
so here's the idea.
You go see a psychotherapist,
a registered psychotherapist,
at least in principle.
This is someone who's mastered or is it
tempting to master these basic modes of
being?
So what they're going to do is they'll
tell you,
I'm going to tell you the truth as I see
it.
And so the way I see that happening in
psychotherapy is that when someone comes
to see me,
I listened to them and that means that
I'm not distracted by anything else.
I'm not thinking about anything else.
I'm not thinking about what I'm going to
say next.
I'm not thinking about the things I have
to do today.
I'm not thinking about the last time I
saw this person.
I'm not allowing my attention to wander
away from the person and then I'm
watching them and listening to them at
the same time and those are the same
things because to really listen to
someone,
you also have to watch them because then
you succeed perhaps or perceive of the
nonverbal elements of communication that
go along with,
well,
partly with voice tone,
but apparently with direction and partly
with very subtle transformations of
facial gesture.
So sometimes,
for example,
I see on my clients that they'll all of
a sudden turn into a child.
It's very interesting.
It's like there'll be recounting some
experience.
It's like fixation from a Freudian
perspective.
They'll be in,
there'll be describing some experience
from the from the distant past and for a
second there expression will approximate
who they were when they were six years
old.
It's really,
it's really something remarkable to see
and you can see these things if you
really pay attention and then as they
talk,
I'm watching what's happening inside me
as I listened to their words and all
sorts of things will happen.
Sometimes I'll get an image or sometimes
I'll get a memory of something we talked
about before or sometimes I'll notice
that what they're saying right now is
different than something they said five
minutes ago and so then I'll say,
wait a sec.
No,
I'm trying to understand what you're
telling me and I noticed that you just
said this and it seems to imply this,
but then,
you know,
a couple of minutes ago when we were
talking about that,
then you said this and I don't see how
those two things are the same and I'm
not doing that because I want them to
rectify the paradox.
I'm doing that because I want to
understand what they are saying and if
someone says to you and then they say
be.
You don't know what they're saying.
And so the question is for
clarification.
There's no other direction than that.
And then maybe you know,
I'll have a little image,
like the sort of a fragment of a dream
and I'll say,
wait a second,
what,
what you just said when you said what
you just said,
this is what I experienced and then
maybe we'll talk for awhile about what
that might mean and,
and I'll,
I can say to them what.
So for example,
sometimes sometimes people will come to
my office and they do all sorts of
strange things.
Like I had one client who had
psychosomatic epilepsy and one of the
first times I saw her,
she had a seizure in my office and uh,
I was watching her and it didn't really
matter to me that she was having a
seizure.
And I thought that's pretty weird
because normally when someone's having a
seizure,
it's like you get affected
by it,
right?
I mean there's,
there's sensations that emerge in your
midsection and there's thoughts of
emergency and,
and you know,
because your body in some sense is
mimicking their body,
which is what your body does all the
time when you're talking to people.
And that produces a sense of urgency.
And I just sort of watched her have the
seizure and I thought,
oh,
it's not real,
it's not real seizures,
but she was very good at it and you
know,
as far as she was concerned,
she couldn't tell if the seizures were
real or not and sometimes if you have
cycle genic epilepsy,
you've had an epileptic seizure at one
point that was genuine.
Well,
it's exceptionally complicated and it's
not easy to develop a psychogenic
epilepsy,
but she had developed it and part of the
reason was
that she thought that she was toying
with the idea that existence as a
psychiatric patient would require less
effort and responsibility and so she got
tangled up at one point with one of the
mental hospitals and they diagnosed her
with paranoid schizophrenia,
which is not something I would recommend
it,
especially if you don't actually have
it.
Because once you've got the diagnosis,
well are you really going to know that
you.
What's going to happen?
Hey,
you do something like that.
You have a psychogenic epileptic seizure
in a variety of other symptoms there.
The consequence of a very complex
complex in union terms,
there is a secondary motivation and
Freud in terms you go through with the
whole routine anyway,
end up in a psych hospital and you see
for experts and they tell you a paranoid
schizophrenia.
Do you really think you're going to not
believe that or at least 10 percent of
you is going to believe it.
You're going to wonder after that and if
another 20 people tell you that and
you're put on medication,
which you could easily be that a year
later while you might still not have
paranoid schizophrenia,
but you are not going to be doing very
well.
So
That's a good example of what happens
when your self concept and you're
organismic valuing systems aren't
working carefully in tandem anyways.
So someone might be telling me a story
that's,
you know,
like a story about something terrible
that happened to them and like I'll just
be sitting there like a brick wall.
It's like you're not effecting me.
And sometimes I'll tell people that.
It's like,
I don't know why,
but you know,
that's a pretty terrible story,
but I'm having no emotional response to
it at all.
Do you have any reason?
You have any idea why that might be
while then maybe look,
you know,
often people are very happy when you
tell them that and that's fine.
They can be unhappy with that.
That's perfectly okay,
but the thing is now they know that
there's at least one person that they've
communicated with who's actually telling
them the truth,
who is actually not affected by their
story because look,
if someone sits down beside you and they
tell you a terrible story,
the probability that you're going to
tell them that that had no effect on you
is basically zero because really rude
not to be negatively affected by someone
who's telling you a very sad story,
but if you're negatively effected by it,
I just not true.
You're not doing them any good at all.
You're doing is providing them with
evidence to maintain what could easily
become a delusion if they worked on it
long enough.
By contrast,
sometimes people will come into my
office and they'll tell me something
that just seems trivial and it made me
tear up so which means I can actually
feel emotions.
It would make me tear up,
but it's just something they just
barely.
They barely alluded to.
You know,
I got a client a while back told me that
we had had a session family session
where I had suggested to some of the
members of this person's family that
things might go better for them and
their child who was one of my clients,
if for the next two weeks what they
practice doing was watching each other's
behavior during the day and finding one
thing that they could make a positive
comment about.
Now,
and this isn't a game like if you play
it as a game,
then it isn't going to work.
If you're going to do this properly,
what you do is you watch and then you
notice when the person does something
that actually makes you feel positively
towards them and then you tell them you
did this.
It has to be specific.
It can't be at the end of the day.
Well,
you were pretty good today.
It's like,
no,
that's not gonna work,
man.
You have to notice something.
They actually did.
It's usually something trivial.
Like,
um,
I really appreciate the fact that you
took your dirty dinner plate off the
table and rinsed it off and put it in
the dishwasher.
It's like,
you think that's so damn trivial.
It's hardly worth commenting on.
It's like,
no,
no.
It's not at all.
That's exactly the sort of specific
thing that you comment on.
If it did in fact make you happy,
you know,
when you can think about that in
behavioral terms,
you could say,
well if you,
if,
if you want someone to do something that
you like,
you should tell them when they do things
that you like,
so that they know what you like.
But of course that means that you're
putting yourself on the line too,
right?
Because if the person knows what you
like,
then they can withhold it from you.
And so you're not going to do that
unless you trust them.
You're really not.
So you know,
you might be in a relationship,
you might be in a marriage where never
once during the whole bloody marriage do
you ever tell the other person what
actually makes you happy?
It's like,
that's stupid by the way.
So like if you want to have a really
miserable time of it,
that's an excellent way to start.
You could also add to that the
presumption that if they really loved
you,
they know what you liked,
which is also what your partners no
smarter than you generally speaking and
you don't have a clue what it's going to
make them happy.
So I don't know why you'd expect them
to,
especially if they're male,
why you'd expect them to return the
favor.
So then you teach them,
you know,
like probably take four years.
It's like I like when you do this and
then of course they won't.
So you might have to mention it again in
a month.
You might think,
well it's going to take 18 months to
train this person.
At least.
I mean they're smart,
they're smarter than a dog,
but not much smarter.
So you have to be,
you have to use repetition and you have
to be judicious about it and if you do
that,
another person is also doing that to you
and you both know that you're doing that
and you're both trying to make things
better than you're going to communicate
about it.
And then with any luck things will get
better.
But that means you actually have to want
things to get better.
And that's part of the problem of
course,
because not everybody wants things to
get better and there's a part of
everyone that would be just as happy if
they didn't get better.
So anyways,
Roger's idea is that if you communicate
properly with the person that you're in
the relationship with,
that you can model proper being in some
sense and that at least you could
attempt tomorrow and then as you
attempted,
you'll get better and better at it and
as you get better at it,
the other person will get better at it.
And that works too.
So I had a client who was very anxious
person.
So when the person first came to see me,
they couldn't even talk on the phone and
now they're doing,
they're acting publicly,
they're acting in public.
And that's been the consequence of about
seven years of,
I would say Rogerian conversations were
almost all that I did was listen now the
UNCW,
I don't quite get the unconditional
positive regard thing,
although I know why Roger is set it and
his idea that arbitrary conditions of
worth can make someone pathological or
true,
but
I think a more nuanced sense of
unconditional positive regard is what
happens when you watch the person and
they tell you something and as they're
telling it to you,
you can see a little part of them sort
of come alive and that often happens
when their face loses a fair bit of its
rigidity and you can see more of what
they were like when they were a child
sort of peeping through.
So their face sort of opens up.
You can they a hot.
That was really good for that person.
Whatever they been telling me that
they'd be doing that was right on the
right track.
And then you can say,
look,
I noticed that when you talk about this,
you know your,
your face redox,
you didn't look as anxious,
you were smiling,
you know,
and it was a genuine smile.
And for like a second or two there you
look like you were doing well and you
were happy.
It's like,
let's do a bunch more of that because
you know,
if you see in someone that they're
capable of experiencing that,
then you could help them experience that
more.
And that's the purpose of a longterm
relationship
is that
you have your weaknesses and
inadequacies and you can't think them,
think yourself out of them by yourself,
partly because they colored the way that
you think.
And so you need somebody else to bang
yourself up against,
to contend with so that all the knots in
your soul can get ironed out and
hypothetical.
You're doing the same thing for the
other person.
And then both of you are on an upward
spiral.
And then in some sense that's the core
theory of Rogerian psychotherapy.
It's like genuine,
honest communication can heal people and
genuinely dishonest communication can
make them pathological.
And in some sense,
I think Roger's got closer to the truth.
If you invert Rogers presupposition,
that's as close to the truth as any
psychotherapists has gone to see,
makes people pathological.
And that's true.
A lot of,
and you'll notice this as well.
A lot of what you're doing in
psychotherapy and in any genuine
relationship is a moral endeavor.
You're trying to make things better.
And if the other person is deceiving
themselves or lying or failing to become
aware of things that they should become
aware of,
they're going to get bent and twisted
out of shape and then they're not going
to be congruent,
congruent with their body or with the
broader world.
And then they're going to suffer.
And then that will cascade.
Then all sorts of things will start to
happen.
And you know,
that's the path to perdition and an
involuntary trip to the underworld.
When we meet again,
I think I'll show you a little clip of
Rogerian psychotherapy because a woman
in the 19 fifties agreed to be filmed,
which had a dramatic effect on her life
by the way.
But,
um,
it,
it presented,
provides a nice real world illustration
of what Rogers is doing when he's trying
to listen.