I talked a little bit last time about
what we were going to cover,
but I didn't get quite through it,
so I'm going to finish that.
For those of you who weren't here last
time,
you can watch the lecture because it's
online.
So,
um,
we,
we stopped at the depth psychologist.
Really those are the psychoanalysts.
Psychoanalysts are people who are
concerned with,
well,
for a psychoanalyst,
roughly speaking,
you're a collection of loosely
integrated spirits.
That's one way of thinking about it or
subpersonalities you're not a unity and
no subpersonalities have their basis in
while and all sorts of things.
They might have their basis in past,
especially traumatic experience or in
patterns of socialization that
characterized your family,
but they might also have their basis in
fundamental biological motivational
systems.
So for example,
a psychoanalyst would conceptualize it,
anger or,
or perhaps sexual attraction as a
subpersonality.
And the reason for that is that,
well,
you know what it's like when you get
angry,
you get angry at someone you love.
And you know,
first of all,
you know at some level you're wishing
harm.
Now that might only be that you want to
win the argument and you want them to be
nicely crushed while you do it,
but so,
so there's a desire that comes along
with the anger,
but,
but there's a lot of other things that
happened to.
So for example,
if someone's annoying you,
even if you love them,
the probability that at that moment
you're going to be able to easily access
all the memories you have about how
annoying they are and have difficult
time accessing the memories about how
wonderful they mean to you is quite
high.
You know,
and you know that because sometimes you
get angry with someone,
you have an argument with them and you
sort of clue in later you snap out of
you're more or less possessed state and
you think,
yeah,
well,
you know,
I really wasn't taking the context into
mind and I was kind of harsh.
So.
Well,
so and so.
Then you think,
well who's in control?
And that's the question the
psychoanalysts are really interested in.
And their answer is it's not generally
you.
And so it's very terrifying reading in
some sense because you know,
people like to think of themselves as
masters of their own house so to speak,
and it's just,
it's only vaguely true.
And you know,
people,
you know that too because you make
maybe New Year's Eve,
what do you call those resolutions,
how you're going to be a better person.
I think one of the most common ones is
mad and you're going to hit the gym
three times a week.
It's like,
no,
you're not actually.
And so very few people do.
And that's partly because,
well it's hard and so you don't want to
do hard things.
And the reason for that is because
they're hard.
So it doesn't take much explanation,
but it's also because you can't just
tell yourself what to do.
And that's annoying too because life
would be a lot easier if you could just
say,
okay,
well you don't sit down study for two
hours,
don't watch cats on youtube or whatever
it is that you're watching.
And No,
no,
that isn't what happens.
You sit there and you study for a while
and then you know,
you're thinking about cats and next
thing you know you're watching haunted
mansions in London or some damn thing,
you know,
so,
and it's a scary idea in some sense
because if you think,
well,
if you're not reading master of your own
house,
you know,
if you don't have yourself under full
voluntary control and you certainly
don't,
then what does.
And you know,
Freud is interesting in that regard
because he really talked about the
motive power of fundamental motivational
systems.
Mostly for Freud it was aggression in
sexuality,
you know,
and those are,
those are big motivators.
Let's make no mistake about it.
And so he thought of you as,
as the conscious part of your
personality may be as the.
It's like the captain of a ship with a
very unruly crew.
It's a nice metaphor because of course
the ships on the ocean and the ocean can
be very stormy.
And so you can only sort of plot your
course and you have to work with what's
thrown at you.
And then the unruly crew is,
well,
it's all your drives.
That drives is a wrong way of thinking
about it.
That I liked the psychoanalytic notion
of subpersonality because the
subpersonality has a viewpoint.
There's things it wants and it plants.
So it's,
it's,
uh,
it's an,
it's a living entity.
It's not some dead cognitive system.
No.
So Freud was interested in some sense
more about,
I would say,
the biological underpinnings of the
subpersonalities,
you know,
because he was,
he was,
he was quite biologically oriented in
and he realized that sexuality and
aggression,
we're very fundamental subpersonalities.
And then there's young and young is much
more terrifying than Freud,
which is really saying a lot because
Freud's quite terrifying,
but you,
he,
he's just terrifying the unbelief.
And you know,
for you,
the sub personalities that make you up
are thousands and thousands of years
old.
They're cultural constructions that are
thousands and thousands of years old and
they have you in their grip.
So for union,
for example,
one of the things he said,
and I don't remember where it was,
I love this phrase,
it's so true.
And you can think about this for like
five years and,
and you can still think about it after
that.
One of the things you said was that
people don't have ideas,
ideas have people.
And that's really something to think
about because you know,
just think about your own situation,
so no doubt you have political views and
you think I have political views.
It's like,
well no you don't because you share them
with a lot of other people,
so they're certainly not yours.
And not only that,
they've had a very lengthy historical
development far before you ever showed
up,
you know,
so they're rooted rooted,
right at the depths of your culture.
But then of course they've been
elaborated by one philosopher or another
extensively over the last two or 300
years.
And there's this whole system of thought
and Poof,
it inhabits your brain and then you
think,
well,
I've got political views.
It's like,
no,
the political views have you.
And that's a very salutary thought
because it's one of the ways to stop
yourself from being possessed because
people get possessed all the time by
ideas.
Right?
That's what happened in Nazi Germany.
That's what happened in the Soviet
Union.
It happens everywhere all the time and
you might think,
well possessed is a little strong,
but.
But no,
it's not actually.
It's a very nice.
It's a metaphor obviously,
but it's the right kind of metaphor
because a body of ideas like political
ideas,
there are living thing,
you know they're not.
They're not some dead dusty words on a
bookshelf somewhere.
They're an integral part of a dynamic
society and and the motive force,
those ideas have motivates you.
You're in their grip and so you can tell
when you're talking to someone who's
completely possessed by it,
by an idea system or in India logical
system because they'll just bore you to
death unless you happen to believe
exactly the same thing.
So they'll spout out a few of their
fundamental belief axioms and then you
can identify which system they're part
of and then they just speak in cliches
from that point onward and you can
predict everything you're going to say
if you know the axioms of the system.
So it's very.
It's very non authentic speech and that
would be a way that say someone like
Rogers or or,
or Abraham maslow who were humanists of
the 19 sixties might talk about it
because the person isn't speaking from
the depths of their own experience or
from even their embodied knowledge,
you know,
they're just mouthpieces for abstract
ideas and so it's very frightening to
realize the extent to which you can be
the mouthpiece for abstract ideas,
you know,
and it's actually one of the dangers of
becoming educated,
especially in the mass system like the
university system because a lot of what
happens to you when you come to
university is that you're fed a set of
pre digested ideas.
I suppose that's one way of thinking
about it.
You know,
and it's very easy for you to think,
well that those are now your ideas.
They're not.
There are not lots of ideas you have to
earn and if it's a great idea,
then you really have to earn it.
Because why should you be able to come
along and like pluck up a great idea.
That's not how things work.
You have to earn things that are
valuable.
So anyways,
the depth psychologist man,
they're so good at that.
It's lovely to read them.
And the problem too is with a lot of the
people we're going to talk about,
it's very difficult to summarize their
work,
you know,
because often the devil's in the
details.
So you know,
you might look at someone like piaget is
a good example,
the constructivist that we talked about
briefly,
man,
the guy wrote dozens of books.
You can't just summarize those suckers.
It's not one coherent theory that you
can boil down to 10 axioms and then you
can read it while you're flying from
Toronto to Montreal and Poof,
Europe yet.
And psychologists like it doesn't work
like that.
The people who make who formulated these
theories were extremely intelligent and,
and,
and they're often great writers and so a
lot of the knowledge is actually in the
writing itself and nodding what you can
extract out from the just,
you know,
and most of the theorists,
Freud Young,
it's harder,
but freud,
rogers,
people like that.
You can extract out the gist of their
theories and then you can,
uh,
what would you say?
You can,
you can stereotype it or you can correct
your it and then you can point out how
your caricatures observed and then you
can feel like you're even smarter than
Freud,
you know,
you're not.
So it's not a good idea.
And so these people should also be
approached with respect because man,
they have so much to tell you.
It's so useful.
Okay.
So we talked about the depth
psychologist.
We talked about the constructivists.
We didn't talk about the humanists,
the existentialists or phenomenologists
a mouthful of words,
you know.
So let's put a little bit of foundation
under those.
So if you're a humanist,
to be a humanist means really to be a
creature of the enlightenment.
And a human is thought in some sense,
at least this is what the humanists
thing.
They think of it as post religious,
you know,
and they,
they think of a humanistic thought as
putting the value of the human being at
the center of the cosmos in some sense,
valuing the person as they are.
And then also valuing the person that
they could be and,
and promoting the pathways of
development that would allow people to
become what they could be as creatures
that are valuable in their own right.
So a humanist,
for example,
would be very skeptical of claims.
So let's say standard Christian claims,
and I use that example because the realm
of ideas that these thinkers emerged out
of was almost always Judeo Christian and
so you know,
their,
the roots of their thinking are in those
systems and you can't understand their
thinking without understanding that.
And so part of humanism was a rebellion
against the idea that life on earth,
so to speak,
was of limited value because everything
of any importance was going to happen in
the afterlife after you die.
So it's like,
no,
it's here and now it's right now that
matters.
And you know,
life in the present is what's important
and you don't need some kind of
afterlife or some kind of belief in a
transcendent reality in order to find
value right here and now.
So,
you know,
fine,
there's a lot of good things about that
idea.
And the whole idea that you can improve
yourself in some sense is a humanistic
idea and most of you have been,
how many of you believe that you can
improve yourself?
So is there anybody who doesn't believe
that it's,
that's willing to admit it.
So usually people only don't believe
that if they're very depressed or
hopeless,
but it's not self evident,
you know,
I mean,
and in,
in many cultures you could think of
medieval culture,
for example,
in Europe where you know,
you were sort of stuck in your position.
There is no real idea of self
improvement.
You could try not to sin,
but you aren't going to get like
radically better in some way.
You are just who you were.
And that was that.
But not,
that's not the case for the,
the existentialists were kind of a
different kettle of fish.
So you know,
when Freud talks about psychopathology,
because a lot of personality is about
pathology,
right?
How personal this can go wrong.
Freud kind of thinks of the normal
person roughly speaking as healthy in
their normality,
but perhaps transformed into a
pathological version of themselves by
some sort of past trauma and that might
often be an abusive childhood,
you know,
or or maybe a sexually abusive childhood
because you know Freud talked a lot
about that.
It happens fairly frequently,
so for Freud,
all things considered.
If you weren't healthy,
there was a reason for it.
You know,
something terrible that happened to you
and you needed to come to terms with
that terrible thing.
However you might do that and put
yourself back together and then you
could wander along.
Being a healthy person,
but the existentialists,
that's not how they think at all.
They think the standard human being is
pathological and the reason they think
that is because they think that self
conscious existence,
so life,
the life of a creature that knows it's
bounded in time and space,
right?
Knows it's vulnerable to disease and
illness and death and the loss of things
that they love and the disintegration of
all things in some sense is that's
enough of a problem to give you
problems.
Without having to have been abused by
it,
and so the existentialists view life
itself as a problem of sufficient
magnitude that it can destabilize you
mentally merely by being aware of it.
And so they also believe that often what
people do as a consequence of that is
flee from their own awareness,
you know,
so how do you deal with the fact that
life is suffering but you don't think
about it?
Well,
for an existentialist that's not a very
good answer.
And I would also say generally speaking,
for clinical psychologists,
that's also not a very good answer
because the literature suggests pretty
damn strongly that the harder you run
from something you're afraid of,
the larger it becomes and the faster it
chases you.
So avoidance of avoidance is generally a
very bad strategy.
Now it's not always the case because
sometimes if you can't do anything about
something really you can't.
Well there's not a lot of sense spending
a lot of time planning and struggling
against it.
You know,
sometimes people are in generally
genuinely hopeless situations,
but,
but often did not.
So I really liked the existentialist
man.
I think they're.
Well,
I have all the people that we're going
to talk about,
their thinking is extraordinarily
valuable.
It helps situate you in your own life.
It helps clarify the nature of your
relationship to other people in the
world.
It helps you lay out what your future
could be if you were the creatures that
you could be really wonderful
phenomenologists.
They're tricky bunch.
I'm the fundamental phenomenologists was
Martin Heidegger,
who was also somewhat also somewhat
tangled up with the Nazis.
Um,
you know,
which was clearly not a good thing.
And you know,
people debate about whether or not you
can separate out his philosophy from
what tangled them up with the Nazis and
I think you can,
you know.
So anyways,
heidegger,
heidegger learned to take a fresh look
at the nature of reality.
And so heidegger,
his idea was that we,
we made a fundamental philosophical era
way back when,
when we were Greek,
ancient Greek,
roughly speaking,
and that we started concentrating on the
wrong elements of.
He didn't read.
He doesn't really call it reality being.
So a phenomenologist as someone who's
concerned with being and you,
you might think,
well,
what's the difference between being in
reality?
And the answer to that is it.
It depends on how you define being and
it depends on how you define reality.
So heidegger's observation was that for,
for for modern people,
roughly speaking,
reality is sort of a d animated
material,
objective substrata.
It's,
it's dead in its essence,
roughly speaking,
and the things that are most real are
precisely those things you can think
about that it's all objective reality
for all intents and purposes,
but when what heidegger tried to point
out is there's a choice in some sense
because of your knowledge is finite
because you're fundamentally ignorant
about all things.
You have to decide that certain things
are true and then act from that point
and you know,
heidegger's point was there's a lot of
things that you can decide about at the
very fundamental level of,
of axiom and so one of the things you
can decide for example,
is whether or not the objective world is
what's more real or whether or not your
lived experience is what's more real now
you might think,
well what's the distinction there?
And I would say the distinction is
probably something like watching someone
in pain on a video and being in pain
yourself.
You know,
so pain is a good example of,
of an element of being.
Because it's obviously it's obviously
you experience it within your own.
It's hard to talk about this because he
uses different terminology.
Pain is an element of your being and
it's,
it's not something,
it's the pain itself is not something
that you can even conceptualize in
objective terms.
Like you can measure it,
you know,
maybe your heart rate goes up when
you're in pain or something like that or
your facial expressions change,
you know,
so you can index it.
But the indexes are not the phenomena
that's hence phenomenology,
right?
And so the phenomenologists have built
up an entire system of thinking,
predicated on the initial axiom that the
best way to approach life is to assume
that being is the fundamental reality
rather than the objective as the
fundamental level.
And then you might think,
well why do people are with that sort of
thing?
And part of it is one of the.
This is an existentialist plate.
One of the consequences of developing
the objective theory of existence was
obviously all of the amazing technology
we have around us and you know,
great thank going for that.
Otherwise we'd be sitting outside
freezing.
But one of the consequences of that is
once people established objective
reality and then defined it as
ultimately real terrible questions of
the meaning of life or ropes,
you know,
like if the world,
the universe is made out of nothing but
dead matter,
it's eternally existing.
We're nothing but a candle flashing the
wind.
The idea creeps into your mind that
perhaps all of the damn suffering isn't
worth it or,
or could put it another way.
You know,
does your life really have any,
any real meaning or is that just an
illusion?
Well,
heidegger would say the reason that you
have that problem is because you're
approaching the entire problem wrong.
Clearly things have meaning.
They just don't.
If you make the hypothesis,
that's what's our objective is
ultimately real and everything else is
merely a secondary consequence of that.
So anyways,
it's complicated.
It takes a while to get your head around
it.
I'm the humanists and the
existentialists and to some degree the
phenomenologists,
they all came out of,
there was,
there was a variety of sources for their
thoughts and I would say one of them is
the clash between religion and science
or between,
between value and objective truth.
They're trying to,
to rectify the division.
And Piaget himself was trying to do some
of that as well.
So it was young I guess.
Um,
and the other thing is a lot of the
existentialist and humanist work was
post World War Two.
And so,
you know,
after World War Two happened with its
immense catastrophes,
of course people who were thinking about
human nature,
we're very interested in why such a
thing could happen and existentialism at
least as a psychological school arose in
part as a reaction to the horrors of
World War Two.
It's a very serious,
it's very serious branch of psychology
and it was mostly characterized thinking
in the 19 fifties before the hippies
came along and made everything sweetness
and light.
So which is more where Roger's and a
maslow fit.
So we're going to talk about them a fair
bit that the three different categories.
So it's kind of a strange approach in
some sense that this class takes.
Because I talked to you about some
psychologists in that in that period,
but the other people I talked to you
mostly about aren't set.
They're not technically psychologists.
Depends on what you mean by
psychologist.
After all,
I talk a lot about Nietzsche and
Dostoevsky and then also a lot about our
Russian literary figure.
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn who wrote a book
called the Gulag archipelago,
which was one of the.
There was a few cataclysmic events that
brought the totalitarian system of the
Soviet Union to a halt and you can argue
about what they were,
but one of them for sure,
what social needs and published
publication of the Gulag Archipelago,
which is a 2,700
word book,
2,700
page book.
Can I get that right?
That describes what it was like to be
there and how many people died and it's
a.
it's a searing book you want to know
about prize and he deserved it.
I mean,
Solzhenitsyn,
a remarkable person.
He's like the Dostoevsky of the 20th
century and that's really saying
something and Dostoevsky is another
person I use a lot in that section and
both Dostoevsky and niche and regard
themselves as psychologists
fundamentally.
And you know,
it's funny because when you think about
scientists,
you know,
usually think about people who are
conducting experiments,
right?
But then one of the things,
and you'll notice this,
if you think about it,
a lot of you have taken a fair number of
science courses are of one form or
another.
And you know,
a lot of what you're taught when you're
taught how to do science is how to
generate,
you know,
how to lay out an experiment property,
how to get the methodology right,
how to do the analysis properly,
maybe how to structure the,
the revealing of your findings and
proper scientific format,
you know,
and how to test a hypothesis.
But one of the things that you never
really told about is,
well,
how the hell do you generate the
hypotheses to begin with because you
know,
really that's at least half the problem
and it's probably a lot more than half
the problem.
And so part of being a scientist is the
ability to be a hypothesis generator,
not just the hypothesis test or maybe
you need to be both to be a true
scientist,
but,
but maybe not.
Maybe you can just generate
extraordinary hypothesis.
And it's certainly the case that people
like Dostoevsky Nietzsche were
unbelievably good hypotheses.
Generators.
And so,
you know,
they're thinking in many ways underlies
the entire development of thought.
This sort of thought that you guys are
going to encounter in university
anyways.
They're thinking underlies the entire
development of the edifice of,
I would say both scientific and
nonscientific thought across the entire
entire 20th century,
and so it's quite entertaining to go
down there and wander around the roots
of these sorts of things because you
find out how things are linked together
and why they're linked together,
how they develop and what that means and
also what it means for you to have those
ideas and why you have them and what
role they play in your life.
So.
Okay,
so after that,
that's pretty much in some sense you
might think that's where the clinical
and philosophical part of the course
ends.
Now I'm a clinical psychologist and most
of the people who are great personality
theorists were clinical psychologists
and that explains to some degree wind.
The first part of the course is
philosophical because the thing about
clinical psychologists and psychiatrists
and medical doctors for that matter is
that they're not exactly scientists.
They're more like engineers.
So what an engineer to do.
They might engineer,
might use scientific knowledge and you
know,
good for them.
They should,
but really what they want to do is make
something changed.
They want to build something.
They want to transform something.
They want to act on the world in a,
in a beneficial,
generally in a beneficial way.
While the same thing as the case with
the health domains.
So like someone comes to you with a
psychological problem.
What you want to do is you want to make
it better and better is not a scientific
category.
So to the degree that you're a practice,
like you can say,
well,
it's scientific because worst means
abnormal.
It's like that's not right.
You can make that case,
but it's shallow because there's lots of
times when you don't consider normal
healthy,
you know,
you can send her exceptional,
healthy,
right,
or,
or maybe you consider exceptional,
desirable and desirable.
It might even be better than healthy,
right?
So you can't get out of the value domain
when you're trying to interact with
people and sort out their lives because
partly what you're,
what you're always asking is what's
wrong?
What's the matter?
Why are you dissatisfied?
Why are you suffering?
Why are you productive?
Why do you fight with everyone you know,
why can't you sleep at night?
Why do you wake up screaming,
you know,
why can't you pursue anything that's two
year old benefit?
Why do you hurt everyone that you know,
you know,
those are moral questions.
And then the next problem is,
okay,
well what are we gonna do about it?
What do you want?
How would you like your life to look if
it could look the way you wanted it to?
And then how are we going to get from
where you are to that?
And those are all their engineering
questions in a sense,
but above all their ethical questions
because they deal with how to act.
So you know,
I don't want to just slide over that big
because that's generally what happens
because physicians and clinical
psychologists and psychiatrists,
even though their physicians,
they like to think that what they're
doing is science and that's not right.
It's informed by science,
but that's not the same thing.
It's particularly true with doctors
because they're not even trained to be
scientists.
So.
Alright,
so that's that.
So then the next part of the course,
the last half,
it's pretty,
it concentrates on two elements of
personality theory,
more modern elements I would say,
although not more valuable necessarily
because of that I'm partly very
neurobiological because we made a lot of
strides in the last 5,000
years,
let's say,
in understanding the,
the,
the structure and the function of the
brain.
Like the things we don't know about the
brain,
man,
it's,
there are lots of things we don't
understand about the brain.
We have no idea,
for example,
what its relationship is to
consciousness except that more or less
it seems necessary,
you know,
so all,
even even that you can dispute to some
degree because they're great case
histories of people who were born with
hydrocephalus.
And so that means that your skull
basically fills with water.
And the most famous case of that was a
French guy who,
uh,
went for an Mri for God only knows what
reason.
It had nothing to do with with what was
eventually discovered,
but he only had five percent of his
cortical tissue is whole brain has all
head was full of cerebral spinal fluid
and the brain was just a little skin
around the side that was like a balloon
and as far as they could tell,
there was nothing wrong with them.
It's like,
well,
isn't that interesting?
What the hell is all the riff that brain
for you know?
And then you get the other issue.
Like,
I don't know if you've ever heard of a.
can't remember her name.
I think it's peppered.
She had a famous parent,
an African gray.
You can look it up talking African gray
parrot and that damn parent,
man,
that thing could talk like a four year
old kid.
Way better than any chimpanzee full
sentences.
It seemed to know what it was doing.
It's like it's apparent,
right?
It's brain is this big.
So how is that even possible?
So,
okay.
So there's lots of things we don't know
about the brain really.
And it's unbelievably complicated.
So.
But we have learned a lot of things that
are interesting.
We kind of understand the existence and
the location of the fundamental reward
and pain and anxiety circuits.
That's a big deal.
Those are,
those are like discovering major
continents,
you know,
we understand to some degree how people
learn and under what conditions they
learn and we understand,
I would say to some degree what the
fundamental motivations and emotions are
now.
Those are not scientific categories,
motivations and emotions,
their linguistic categories.
So what we're stuck with so,
but we,
we know a fair bit about their
underlying neurobiological basis and I
want to take you through that in some
detail because for a bunch of reasons,
partly because it provides a nice
scientific underpinning to a lot of the
hypotheses and presuppositions of the
cycle analysis.
You know,
so for example,
Freud hypothesized the existence of the
end.
Now there is no way I didn't your brain,
but it doesn't really matter because the
ID,
the idea of the ID is a functional
category.
It's like a tool.
But there are lots of end like
structures in your brain,
you know,
and one of them in particular is the
hypothalamus and that thing like human
beings like to think that they're really
impressive.
Critical cap is the thing that's,
you know,
in charge of things.
But your hypothalamus,
which is this little tiny thing that
sits at the top of your spinal cord man,
that's what's running you and let you
know as long as you're not hungry or not
angry or not chasing after sexual
excitement and not gambling and not
addicted.
So as long as you're completely well fed
and warm and comfortable,
then you can think and you're more or
less in control.
But as soon as any of those things go as
straight it's subcortical all the way
you know.
And you can see this,
for example,
in conditions like Anorexia,
you know,
because the Anorexia,
you can think of Anorexia as a war
between the cortex and the hypothalamus.
And I'll tell you then the only time the
cortex winds is when the anorexic dies.
Because other than that,
it's the hypothalamus that wins all the
time.
Which is why anorexics cannot stop
themselves from bingeing,
you know,
so they'll,
they'll cut their body weight down to
say 75 percent of what it should be and
that's hard.
Like you really,
it's not easy to starve yourself like
that,
but they'll still binge like mad,
you know,
we need a whole gallon of ice cream and
two bags of bread and they can't stop
themselves.
And that's because your hypothalamus
flint would rather you didn't starve to
death.
And if you're not paying attention,
if you're not on top of the game or
maybe if you've been hurt recently and
so your resources or your,
your,
what would you say?
You're the negative emotion that's been
interfering with your cognitive
capacity.
The hypothalamus will come up and grab
you and say,
man,
you're hungry and it's off to the fridge
with you.
You know,
so two in the morning,
you're going to be eating everything in
there in a kind of a daze.
And you'll snap out of that and think,
wow,
what the hell was that?
It was like,
well that's the end folks.
And it's no trivial thing and it's a
good thing too because if it didn't tell
you what to do all the time,
like think about how foolish you are.
If you had to breathe voluntarily,
how,
how many days do you think you'd go
through?
And it's like you wake up one day and an
hour later you'd forget to breathe and
then you'd be dead.
So like your,
your,
your brain doesn't let you do anything
important.
It takes care of all that in the
background,
you know,
because you're just not that smart.
I mean you don't know how to digest
things.
For example,
you actually don't know how you walk
even though you can do it.
So there are very fundamental subsystem.
Some of them that aren't even conscious,
weirdly enough,
even though they're neurological,
they're doing all the heavy lifting and
like your cortex is as long they're all
along for the ride in some sense.
And that sort of things.
It's in control.
But yeah,
no,
not really.
Okay.
So we're going to talk a fair bit about
fundamental brain structures and the
function of those structures.
Because I like functional neuroanatomy.
I like,
I don't want to know just what the brain
is made out of,
but I want to know what all the parts
are doing,
and so there's difficult papers in
there.
Swanson,
that's a hard paper and the grit paper
by gray,
those are papers that were written by I
think genius level neuropsychologists
and you know,
they put their whole life's work into a
paper and so you know,
you shouldn't pick it up.
You're going to think,
wow,
this is hard.
It's like,
yeah,
some genius spent 30 years writing it.
It's going to be hard,
but they're so informative.
They're worth the struggle if,
if that's the sort of thing you want to
struggle with.
So that's the biological end.
And then there's the psychometric ended
site,
psychometrics,
very unpopular field of psychology even
amongst psychologists.
And the reason for that is that
psychometric nutrition's I guess have
actually discovered things and people
hate what they've discovered.
So and no wonder.
So for example,
it was people who do psychometrics,
engineers actually who in,
who entered psychology,
who discovered intelligence,
technical psychometric intelligence,
Iq.
And people will tell you there's lots of
kinds of intelligence.
It's like,
no,
there aren't.
That's wrong,
and it's wrong in this way.
The statistics that psychologists use
were invented by the people who
discovered Iq,
and that means every single thing that a
psychologist has ever claimed that's
been verified in some way using some
statistical process has been verified,
verified the same way that I knew was
verified.
And so you don't get to say,
well,
the ICU stuffs in valid without saying
all of psychology and a lot of other
fields is invalid too because it's the
same methods of proof.
And it's even worse than that because
like the relationship between Iq and
life success is way stronger than the
relationship between almost any other
psychological phenomena and almost
anything else.
So for example,
for you guys even know,
you know,
you're,
you're all far above average in
intelligence because otherwise you
wouldn't be here like at least 80,
fifth percentile.
And that's something to think about
because a lot of that is determined by
biological factors.
You know.
So a huge chunk of the reason that
you're here is because you know,
you won the genetic lottery,
so like hooray for you and no one's
screwed it up too badly as you were
growing up,
you know,
but even among you guys,
that correlation between your
intelligence and your and your grade
point average is quite high even though
it's a truncated sample,
right?
Because you're all pretty bright and
even though there's a lot of error in
the grade measurement system because it
doesn't only index intelligence,
it's still very powerful.
And so the one,
the peep,
if you,
if you controlled for conscientious ness
and other elements of personality,
which you can do statistically in 20
years,
that the 10 percent of the people in
this room who have the highest Iq is,
will have the highest income virtually.
Certainly,
you know,
unless some terrible thing happens to
them,
you can overcome it to some degree if
you're really hardworking because then
that's conscientiousness,
you know,
and that.
But that's also a trait which seems to
have quite a heavy biological loading so
well.
So that's the sort of thing that people
hate about psychometricians because they
come up with these facts and there are
facts that are really dismal and I can
give you an example.
So,
so you guys all have an Iq of over 150,
roughly speaking.
100 makes you about as smart as the
typical high school reading 115.
That's kind of the low end for,
for managing the rigors of a,
a fairly high end university.
You know,
1:15,
you're still going to have a lot of
trouble,
you're going to have to work like mad.
So,
but okay,
so 150.
Now that's one standard deviation above
the mean.
One standard deviation below the mean is
an Iq of 85.
Now there's just as many people out
there in the world who have an Iq of 85
as there are people who are able to go
to college.
Okay?
So then you think,
what can you do if you have an Iq of 85
and.
Well,
here's one answer.
So the US army has been doing
psychometric testing for 100 and some
years.
Um,
for a whole bunch of reasons,
but they've done a lot in the basic
science,
you know,
and uh,
one thing about the u s army is they
like to have recruits and you can
understand why because do you really
want to go off somewhere and get shot?
And the answer to that is generally no.
So it's not like there were people
lining up to get into the army even in
peace time.
It's hard to get people.
And also the Americans have used the US
army as a,
you know,
imagine you have a,
an underclass of people who aren't doing
very well,
which is the case in every society and
you want to boost some of them up,
you know,
into something resembling the middle
class.
You can do that fairly effectively by
inducting the young men in particular
into the army because they get some
training,
you know,
they get some discipline and maybe they
can kind clamber up into the middle
class.
And so there's a lot of policy reasons.
A why the American army or enforces want
people and be,
you know,
just to be in the army.
But also for social reasons,
positive social reasons,
so they're not likely not to let you in
the the consequences of 100 years of Iq
testing was the PR was the establishment
of a law in the United States.
You cannot induct anyone into the army,
cannot accept them into the army.
If they have an Iq of less than 82,
that's 10 percent of the population.
So you think about that.
That means one person in 10 cannot do
anything that is a positive value in an
organization.
It's rather complex,
but not more complex than other
organizations.
That's desperate for people.
Nothing they can offer has positive
value.
It's worse to have them in the army than
not to have them there at all.
Really.
Now you know that that's a terrible way
of putting it,
but it's not.
It's a horrible.
It's a horrible statistic because it
also means,
you know,
if you think about the army as roughly
equivalent to the world in some sense,
in terms of its complexity,
it means that there's 10 percent of the
population who just cannot really exist.
Well in a complex cognitive society.
So you might say,
well,
you know,
something should be done about that.
It's like good luck.
People had been trying to do something
about that for a very long time.
There's been billions,
if not trillions of dollars poured into
attempts to do cognitive remediation in
the United States.
Not to mention that we actually have an
education system and the cool is
actually make people smarter.
So we're going to talk a lot about
psychometrics.
And the thing about the psychometricians
is they're basically brute force
statisticians in some ways they're
atheoretical,
you know,
and they use computer power roughly
speaking and advanced statistical
techniques to look at large data sets
and extract out patterns.
And you know,
I was,
I hated the big five when I first came
on it.
I thought,
Oh God,
this is boring.
It's like there's no theory behind it.
It's not prescriptive,
it's not interested in any literary
manner.
Like it doesn't have a good story.
Um,
it came out of,
it's so dry,
but you know,
it works.
And,
and that's,
that's how it is.
So we're going to spend a lot of time on
psychometrics and you know,
my lab two has done a fair bit of work
over the last 10 years elaborating out
the big five models.
So one of the things we'll talk about is
the big 10 model and what it does
roughly speaking,
is break each of the five into two,
we call them aspects and they're pretty
interesting like they predict political
belief for example,
quite nicely.
So conservatives tend to be more
orderly,
which is part of conscientiousness and
less creative,
less open and liberals tend to be more
open and less conscientious,
which a cynic would say.
That's why they're so into income
redistribution because they actually
don't work.
So you know,
the conservatives work like mad and the
liberals say,
hey,
how about some of that money,
you know,
the system is unfair.
And the Conservatives say,
well no,
we worked hard and we're not giving you
any.
Well,
you know,
they both have flaws in their theories.
But liberals by the way,
make very good entrepreneurs like.
No,
let me rephrase that.
Most entrepreneurs are liberal in their
political outlook and that's because
they're high in openness.
So the way it really seems to work is
that liberal minded people start
businesses and conservatives run the.
So they're necessary for one another.
Yeah.
Well,
because the liberals being open,
they're often the next idea,
you know,
and they don't want to attend to the
damn details.
They get bored by that.
They're not particularly orderly,
you know,
but once you've established a process
and it works,
you need someone to watch to make sure
the process keeps working well,
that's not very interesting if you're a
creative person.
So.
Okay,
so that's basically that.
That's the course.
So now what are we doing time here?
So I think what I'll do now is I'm going
to tell you a story and you're going to
think it has absolutely nothing to do
with what we've been talking about,
but it.
But that's okay.
That's okay.
So I picked this weird picture.
It's the picture of Jonah Biblical
character,
so 2,500
year old story.
So that's a pretty old story.
And generally if a story is 2,500
years old,
it's a lot older than that,
you know,
it's just happened to be written down
2,500
years ago.
But no,
that long ago it wasn't like there were
novels and books and that you could find
50 different stories,
you know,
at your fingertips.
There were a few stories and everyone
knew them and God only knows how long
they been around,
but it was a very,
very,
very long time.
So this was written down 2,500
years ago.
But we don't really have any idea how
old it is.
And in some sense it's,
it's almost infinitely old at least on
any human scale.
Now you see this picture and what you
see is this thing that,
what would you call it?
Well,
it's a medieval idea of a whale is what
it is.
You know,
when you might think,
well that isn't really what a whale
looks like and that's kind of right.
But a medieval Wale wasn't the whale
that we have.
Like whale in medieval times meant
large,
terrifying underwater thing,
you know?
And so maybe that was maybe a giant
squid was a whale and the whale was a
whale in the shark was a whale,
you know,
the categories not to save.
So that kind of accounts for the.
That in pure ignorance is what accounts
for the kind of strange mythologized
representation.
But it's still a representation of
something.
It's just a little generalized.
Now what he's doing is vomiting Jonah up
onto dry land.
So.
And you think that's pretty damn weird.
How many of you have Seen Pinocchio?
That's a lot.
Hey,
how many of you haven't really.
You Haven't Seen Pinocchio?
What kind of parents did you have?
Anything?
Okay,
Well Are you Remembering Pinocchio?
Pinocchio.
Father stuck in,
away away.
And then Pinocchio asked to go down
there and rescue them.
And one of the things you didn't notice
when you were watching Pinocchio is just
how daft that is.
There you are sitting there,
you're watching a puppet go down into
the ocean to rescue his father from a
whale.
And you think that makes sense.
It's like,
well,
so that's interesting.
Right?
That's interesting.
Why does that make sense?
Because it doesn't make any sense,
but,
but see,
that's a,
that's a good example of the grip of an
archetypal idea because in archetipal
ideas a very deep and old idea that
makes sense to you even though if
someone points out to you that you
believe it,
which more or less do while you're
watching the movie you think,
Oh yeah,
it's really weird that I believe that's
like kill and that isn't a puppet going
down into the ocean to rescue his father
from a whale either.
Just so you know it.
It's a drawing of a puppet going down
into the ocean to rescue is far from a
whale.
So it's like divorced from reality,
my life in all sorts of ways.
But what's so interesting is you go into
the theater and watch something like
that there.
If someone taps you on the shoulder and
say,
Hey,
do you know what you're doing?
You say,
why don't you shut up and let me watch
the movie.
Right?
You don't notice.
Oh yes.
I'm very peculiar.
Very peculiar thing sitting here
watching this and not noticing how
strange I am,
you know,
and so,
well,
that's partly why I'm going to tell you
this story because.
Because it's true even though it isn't,
you know,
and that's,
that's a funny thing.
I had a very,
very strange professor at the University
of Alberta.
He died a few years ago.
He got on a bus,
I think it was in Winnipeg and he never
got off the bus and no one ever saw him
again.
So he had,
he'd been a prison psychologist.
He worked in the maximum security prison
in University of Alberta.
So who maybe he met one of his old
clients,
you know,
it's possible,
but it's very strange.
Very strange ending.
Anyways,
one time we were talking about fiction,
you know,
and he said,
uh,
he said fiction is a lie that can tell
you the truth.
That's a very interesting way of
thinking about it,
you know,
because you read fiction and you know
it's true,
but it's not obviously because it's not
really about a thing that actually
happened,
but it's more than that some ways
because if it's good fixture it's about
a whole bunch of things that happened
sort of like that.
Right?
It's a distillation.
It's like someone tells you a long story
and then you know,
you,
you talked to your partner and they
asked you what was that all about and
then you tell them in two sentences what
it was about.
You boil it down to the just,
right.
Well a really good story is the gist of
something and some of the really old
stories,
the really weird ones like Jonah and the
whale for example,
which as I said is,
is told to some degree in the story of
Pinocchio there,
the gist of a lot of things and people
have been boiling those damn stories
down for,
for a very,
very,
very long period of time.
Thousands of people over thousands of
years and they come up with these weird
stories that people remember and then
people think,
well,
they're real.
It's like,
yeah,
they are,
but they're not real.
The way of scientific story is real.
It's a different kind of real.
So here's,
here's the story of Jonah.
So it's an old Jewish story.
There's probably a very intimidating in
the Korean,
but I don't know that variance.
So,
and maybe there isn't.
Anyways,
Joe Lives in 500 BC and uh,
God has a chat with them one day and he
says,
look,
Jonah there,
there's this city,
Nineveh,
and the people there,
you know,
they're really not on the straight and
narrow and things are going to go to
hell in a handbasket very rapidly if
someone doesn't do something about that.
So I think that you should go to Nineveh
and you should tell the king and all the
people that are there that are really
there,
they're just not doing the right thing.
And Jonah being a perfectly intelligent
person says,
you want me to go to a city and you want
to go meet me to tell the king like this
authoritarian die who has absolute power
of everything,
that there's something wrong with what
he's doing,
that all of the citizens are corrupt.
That's what you want me to do.
And Jonah says,
there's no way I'm doing that because as
I said,
he's a smart guy.
So he runs off and he goes to this town
and and as he's reading off,
he rents a boat more or less than it's
big boat.
And there's fishermen and they're gonna
like him somewhere.
God can't find them,
which is not going to be an easy thing.
And so god of course cannot be fooled by
such relatively poorer strategic choices
because he's omniscient and all that.
So he's out on the water Jonah and
there's the fisherman there.
And then some God calls up this big
storm and up.
The fishermen are shorting out about
this and because they're going to swamp
the boat and then they're all going to
die and they're not that happy about
that.
So what they decided to do is throw
everything overboard so that the boat is
lightened,
but that doesn't help much because the
storm gets worse.
And so then all of them start praying.
They all have different gods.
So you know,
it's like a little God competition.
One fishermen talks to one God,
another fisherman talks to another God
and nothing's happening.
So Joe and it happens to be asleep in
the hold of the ship.
Now he's already told them that he's
been running from his God and so they
think,
ha,
we'd better go wake up Jonah because
maybe he's the guy that's causing all
the trouble.
So they'd go down there and they wake
them up and they asked him about his God
and he says,
well,
my God made the heavens and the earth
and their gods,
they weren't doing anything that
magnificence.
So they're pretty freaked out about
this.
And so they tell Jonas like,
what the hell are you running away from
this guy for it?
It's not a good idea.
And Jonah says,
yeah,
I'm sure it's my fault that this storm
has come up.
So why don't you just throw me over and
they say,
well,
we can't really do that because you
know,
you shouldn't run away like that,
but you're not a murderer or anything,
we can't just toss you over.
And so they decided to try to row to
shore,
but God's not having any of that.
So he raises up a big storm and it's
getting worse and worse.
And finally the fishermen say,
Oh,
you know,
over you go in,
join is into that because he knows he's
a bad guy and so away all swallows them.
Now you think,
hmm,
that's probably not exactly right
because first if a whale swallowed you,
then you'd be dead.
And it was probably a shark anyways.
It's not like you're going to be driving
down there.
It's not a big cavern.
Like,
you know the Pinocchio Whale,
it's,
it's solid and there's no oxygen.
So your dad.
But that isn't what happens.
Jonah's in the whale.
And he's Kinda freaked out by this
because now he's in a whale and there's
a storm in God's angry at him.
So the first thing he does is pray and
tell God what an idiot he isn't,
that he'd like to be forgiven,
and so the whale zips up to shore and
vomit some onto the beach,
which is the very,
very undignified mode of arriving
anywhere.
So,
so that's,
that's the Jonah Story.
And then of course Jonah picks himself
up and he thinks,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
that wasn't so good.
It was a little rough.
I think maybe I'm going off to Nineveh
to tell the ninevites or whoever they
were that they're just not living
properly because that's a lot better
than making God angry,
you know,
because what with the storms and the
fishermen and the whales and all that.
So then he goes off to Nineveh and he
tells them what's going on in it seems
to more or less work.
So.
So that's a very interesting story and
you think,
well,
how did people believe that?
Me?
And one question might be,
well,
do you believe that story?
And then you think,
well no,
but then you think,
well maybe that's more complex question
than you might think because it turns
out that I believe the Pinocchio Story.
And you say,
well no,
I didn't really believe it.
And then I would say,
well it kind of depends on what you mean
by bleed,
doesn't it?
Because you watched it and while you
were watching it,
man,
you were into it,
you understood it,
you didn't want it to be disrupted,
you followed it.
So it's like,
did you believe it?
No.
You were like a four year old skeptic
sitting there thinking,
well,
you know,
pop it whale.
No,
it doesn't add up.
You're not.
You're acting out your belief in it by
being engaged in it.
And if someone taps you on the shoulder
and wakes you up 30 years later,
20 years later you say,
oh no,
I don't believe that.
It's like,
you know,
it's kind of remarkable what you'll
believe.
You know,
how many of you are star wars?
Like Aficionados?
No,
you won't admit it,
will you?
But there's lots of you in here.
I know.
You know.
And so that's all mythology,
all mythology,
you know,
that of course the person who,
uh,
what was his name,
the guy who came up with star wars idea,
Lucas Lucas was a student of Joseph
Campbell.
Joseph Campbell was a psychologist slash
mythologist.
And The star wars stories are updated
mythology,
just like Harry Potter and all the other
things that capture people's
imagination.
So you bloody well do believe this.
And there's a reason for it to now.
What time is it now?
We'll stop there.
I'll tell you the reason.
The next time we meet.