So
there's a couple of things I want to
tell you about today.
Many things I want to tell you about.
I want to tell you,
I'm
give you a Schema that's going to enable
you to understand.
I think it'll enable you to understand
stories like the one I told you last
time,
you remember Jonah and the whale.
I want to provide you with this Schema
so that you can understand stories like
that,
but many,
many more stories like that and partly
what I'm telling you about today in some
sense our archetypes and there's a and
an archetype is isn't.
It's an idea that was made most popular
over the last hundred years by Carl
Young,
but it's a much older idea than that.
It's really a platonic ideas and in some
ways,
and it means it means something like
fundamental pattern.
And so an architect can manifest itself
in different ways.
It could be a pattern of emotional
response.
So that could be something that you're
feeling.
It could be the way that that emotional
response displays itself on your body,
on your face.
It could be the way that that emotion
just fields and displays itself on your
face and then plays itself out as a
drama in your local environment,
so like an angry argument is an
archetypal phenomenon and the reason
this architectural is because,
well,
you have one them,
you have them,
everyone has them,
and so you can't really think about them
as individual.
You have to think about them as
universal and you can't think about them
as something that you create in a sense,
although in a sense you do,
but also as something that happens to
you now.
When you read about young and
archetypes,
it's quite confusing because you can
never be sure whether he's talking about
an instinct and emotion,
a motivational system or a
subpersonality or the subpersonality
within which those things manifest
itself or even the social drama that's
being played out in time and space in
the social world.
But our real archetype,
I would say is all of those things.
At the same time.
Now we use archetipal means of
expression to represent how we act and
that's not the same thing as resent
representing what the world is made out
of.
It's a very different thing and so you
could say in some sense,
we tell stories and understand stories
so that we can figure out how people act
and how they should act,
and then we conduct science so that we
can figure out what the world's like
from a material objective perspective
and the two things coexist.
Uneasily,
I think the more primary form of
knowledge is actually how to act with
the scientific model nested inside it
because the most important question that
you have to solve as a living organism
isn't what the world is made out of.
It's how you should act in the world
safe from a Darwinian perspective even
so that you can live long enough to
reproduce.
That's basically from a strict
biological perspective.
In some sense.
That's what you have to do in order to
be successful.
It's kind of obvious,
first of all,
because you're not very successful if
you just go and die,
and then of course deaths from a genetic
perspective and failing to leave
offspring are much the same thing,
so now one of the questions might be how
is it that we conceive of the world as a
place to act in,
and that's partly,
I'm going to outline a hypothesis for
you and then explain the significance of
that hypothesis and the hypothesis
involves the description of what you
might consider constituent elements and
also transformation processes.
Okay,
so as far as I can tell,
the constituent elements of the stories
that we tell about how people acted
should act our characters.
Now that makes sense,
right?
Because you really can't have a drama or
a story with characters.
Now the thing is the characters have to
be understandable and so for them to be
understandable,
they sort of have to be like you or they
have to be like someone that you know,
but they have to be human.
But then again,
it's not exactly that they're human
because even when you're telling a story
about what happened to you today,
it's interesting to think about what you
do.
So someone might say,
well,
how was your day?
And you say,
fine.
I mean maybe that's the lowest level,
lowest resolution,
highest abstract story.
My Day was fine.
It's pretty boring story.
It's better than terrible I suppose,
but it's not interesting and it's not
detailed.
But first and gets the notion that
things went according to what according
to plan or more specifically the things
unfolded the way you wanted them to just
not exactly the same as according to
plan because a plan is kind of a cold
cognitive thing,
you know,
or or,
or expected expectation.
The cognitive scientists sort of used
whether,
well while what you,
how you wanted them to implies that you
have desires and emotions and
motivations and that they inform the way
that you're acting in the world because
you don't just act in the world.
You Act in the world so that you tried
to turn it into something better than it
is right now.
Assuming you have any sense,
you know,
because some people act on the world to
make it worse than it is now,
but we're going to forget about those
people for now.
So when you say fine to someone,
you basically say,
roughly speaking,
I got what I wanted today without undue
hassle.
Okay.
So that's a really condensed version of
the events of the day and it's not a
very good story,
although it might suffice for casual
conversation.
Person might say,
no,
what did you do today?
And then maybe you'll say,
oh,
I woke up this morning and I went to
university and uh,
you know,
the subway took a lot longer than it
usually does.
And so,
you know,
I used that time to do some studying and
then I got to school and I particularly
don't lecture,
but lunch was really good and I met some
friends.
And so that's kind of a story,
right?
And you,
the person that you're talking to might
listen to you.
It's not a particularly compelling
story,
but it's probably better than fine.
And you might say,
well,
why did you select those elements to
talk about?
You know,
you didn't talk about how many times you
blink your eyes,
the first minute that you woke up and
you didn't describe the motor movements
that you used to put your left leg on
the floor and you didn't describe.
You know what bowl you used for
breakfast,
and the reason you didn't do that is
because a,
you don't remember for whatever reason,
and B,
you don't care and neither does your
listener,
but that's the peculiar things that your
listener is going to care about some
things and not care about other things.
And if you're a good storyteller,
you kind of automatically know which of
those things that you should talk about
so that you're interesting.
Which of the things you should ignore so
that you're not boring your listener to
death.
And you also understand that.
They will also understand that.
And but you don't know how you do that.
All you know is that you're trying to
tell an interesting story and in some
sense what you're doing is you're trying
to reduce a sequence of actions and
conceptions of exceptional complexity to
the just right,
which is like the essential or the moral
in some sense and you're trying to
convey that and the other person is
listening partly because they want to
indicate that they care for you and
would like to know.
They want to stay caught up with your
ongoing narrative so that they
understand you and maybe also because
they might think that they'll gardener
some bit of information factual or
behavioral that might aid them in some
way.
You know,
so and we're doing that to each other
all the time and we automatically do
this.
We automatically know how to tell
stories.
And so what I'm saying is that even the
person that you describe when you
describe yourself to someone else isn't
exactly you.
It's some representation of you as a
sort of generic human being that's going
about doing certain kinds of interesting
things in the world.
Or here's a way of thinking about it.
Roughly is that you make yourself the
hero of your own story and so you kind
of know that because when you go to a
movie and movies are usually romances,
say or hero stories will,
romances or adventures or both roughly
speaking.
Um,
you know,
sometimes they turn out well and that's
a comedy and sometimes they don't turn
out so well and that's a tragedy.
But when you go there,
what you basically see is a story about
another person who sort of like you,
who's the hero and what you do is you
track them through a sequence of
adventures.
And usually what you track them through
isn't things were good and then they
stayed good and then at the end they
were still the same as they were at the
beginning.
And good,
you know,
because why do you want to watch that?
And you might say,
well you should because isn't that
pleasant?
The person's happy and then they stay
happy and then they end happy and
everyone's happy.
It's why.
Why isn't that interesting?
But it isn't.
And really what want to see is you
either see,
you want to see someone get into trouble
and fail in a spectacularly interesting
way,
or you want to see someone get into
trouble and then overcome it in a
spectacularly interesting way.
And so there's this idea in the,
in the story that the person has to
undergo some kind of transformation in
the midst of their travails and efforts
in order for it to be interesting.
So they have to start in one place.
They have to end up somewhere that's not
so good in a very,
very complicated way.
And then maybe by transforming their
character,
by transforming the surroundings are but
coming to some sort of realization,
or maybe just by dimwitted luck,
they managed to solve the set of
problems that emerge triumphant at the
other end.
Right?
So that's the meaning of Jonah and the
whale,
or you remember what happens to Jonah is
that he's got this destiny he supposed
to be pursuing.
Any decides that it's too much trouble.
Well,
not unsurprisingly,
because if you remember what he was told
to do was go to tell a whole city that
they were misbehaving,
assuming rightly as he did,
that that would not make him pretty
particularly popular and maybe he'd get
killed and even if he did it,
it would be extraordinarily difficult.
He thought,
there's no damn way I'm doing that.
So he denied his destiny and as a
consequence he fell into the abyss and
was swallowed up,
and then because he repented and decided
to carry on with what he was to carry on
with his responsibilities,
the creature of the abyss spitting back
up and he got to go along his merry way.
Now you might say,
well,
nothing like that has ever happened to
you,
but that's wrong.
Things like that happen to you all the
time and you know it.
So here,
here,
here's a couple of examples and you'll
be able to draw all sorts of examples
from your own life.
That's the story of betrayal.
For example,
maybe in one of your relatively
uninformed
flurries,
you ended up establishing a relationship
with someone who was really not good for
you.
And that might mean while they just,
it was just a bad personality match or
it might mean they really weren't good
for you because you know,
you could get pretty unlucky and you can
get tangled up with someone who's very
deceitful and very malevolent and who
could care less about your maybe who
even wants to hurt you.
And then you can establish a trusting
relationship with them.
Or at least you trust them.
And then one day you know,
you find out that they are not who they
said they weren't.
Or even more importantly,
they are not who you thought they were.
And so then maybe you're in a committed
relationship and they'd be trained you
with someone else.
And so then you think,
well,
there you are at home and you're,
you know,
you're perfectly happy about being at
home and then your partner comes home
and for one reason or another,
you find out that they're having an
affair or that they'd be trained you or
that they'd lied to you.
And some other spectacularly important
way.
And maybe it's a lover and maybe it's a
family member.
Maybe it's assembling and maybe it's a
friend,
whatever,
it doesn't matter,
and so here's the way of thinking about
it.
The minute before they come home,
you're in one place and you remember
places just to place,
right?
A place is a place in time because we
live in space time.
We live in time and place and what that
means is you can be in the same place in
one minute and a completely different
place in the next minute even if you
haven't even moved and so places a very,
very complicated idea,
so you're sitting at home and you're
watching oprah and you're perfectly
content to do that and then the person
comes home and the bottom of your world
falls out and then all of a sudden
you're not where you thought you were
in.
It's a really weird place that you are
now because it's not where you were.
That's for sure,
but you also don't know where it is
because you don't know who that person
is.
That's in that room with you.
You don't know what your past with them
was or what it meant or anything else
about it.
Because it was predicated on absolute
misperceptions,
so none of your memories about those
events are valid even though you have
them as memories and then you have a
worst problem,
which is if you're betrayed badly
enough,
not only are you not going to understand
your immediate past with that person,
oh,
and by the way,
your future is also gone.
So that's a big problem as is your
presence has become radically more
complex,
but it's worse than that because if
you're really betrayed,
you're also going to think,
who am I that I could be that stupid?
And then you're going to think what is a
human being that they can be that
corrupt and so not only has the have the
fundamentals being kicked out of the
substructure of your perceptions,
but your notion of what it means to be
you and what it needs to be human
might've been seriously disrupted.
And you know the thing about that is
that's a non trivial event.
People call that traumatic it didn't
like and it's like a physical wound and
in fact it has.
Certainly if the trauma is great enough,
it can produce a psychophysiological
wound because that sort of trauma,
a deep betrayal is a good example,
will damage your brain and maybe you'll
recover from it and maybe you won't.
And one of the ways that that's been
represented forever in mythological
stories is by being swallowed up by a
subterranean beast.
It's something that comes up from the
depths and pulls you down and then
you're in it.
Now why is that?
Well,
that's an extraordinarily complicated
question,
but here,
here's the answer.
As nearly as I can tell,
we evolved a very complicated
neuro-psychological system to signal
alarm.
So that's anxiety,
threat,
threat sensitive,
right?
And that makes us freeze,
for example.
And when you look at how an animal uses
that system,
let's say a mammal,
just to keep it simple because we're all
mammals and so we can kind of understand
mammals.
So if a rabbit sees a wolf,
for example,
it's going to freeze so that the wolf
camp c and if I,
if a rat smells like cat,
even if it has never smelled a cat and
it's whole life,
it's going to also freeze.
And interestingly with rats,
if you put rats in a natural
environment,
which means they get to help little rat
dominance hierarchies,
a little rap families and they're not
like little white rats alone in a cage.
They're happy family rats and they've
got their burrows and they live in their
little societies that maybe there is a
part of their territory where they can
go get food and they're used to that.
So they'll scurry out there in the day
kind of hiding because they don't like
light.
Or maybe they'll scurry out at night
because rats are night things and
they'll get their food and they'll eat
it or bring it back or whatever they,
whatever they do,
share it with their family or at least
bring it back.
Well,
let's say that you put a cat out there
or maybe you even just put a cap there
and take it away.
So that the place smells like cat.
Well,
if one of those rats goes out there and
sees that cat,
first of all it's going to freeze and it
is not a happy thing because imagine
you're a rat and a thing that's four
times as big as a lion suddenly appears
on your front yard.
It's like,
that's rough,
man.
You're going to phrase it,
then you're going to go hide downstairs
and what are you going to do?
Well,
if you're a rat,
you're going to screen for 24 hours,
which is nonstop with your little beak
poking out of your borough so everyone
can hear you scream.
And that's the same given the length of
life as you're screaming nonstop for two
weeks.
So like that,
racks nervous.
It's not happy about the whole cap
thing.
And then maybe maybe if no more cat odor
happens by and no hypervigilant rat see
any more cats than after it screens for
two weeks.
It starts to calm down a little bit and
maybe then it starts to remember that
it's hungry and that you know,
there's things to attend to.
And so then maybe it very,
very carefully goes back out where it
was foraging for food,
sort of crunched over and hypervigilant
to not moving very much in case that
damn cats around.
And then maybe slowly it regains control
over its territory.
It runs back and forth trying to ensure
that none of that place that used to be
safe has gone troublesome cats
associated with it anymore.
And so in some sense,
the bottom fell out of that rats life.
Now the thing is the rat has predator
detection systems that are associated
with extreme anxiety and escape.
They're automatically activated whenever
there's a Predator in sight.
And we have those systems too.
But human beings are.
You might say,
well,
okay,
rats have predators,
enemies.
Humans have predators and enemies.
Okay?
So then we might say,
well,
what's a human predator slash enemy?
Well,
it depends on how long a period of time
over which you wish to calculate what
constitutes human.
Because we know,
for example,
that $60 million years ago,
your primary Predator when you were
wandering around in trees and we're only
about this big with stakes and so snake
is a Predator and an enemy and you know,
you guys can easily learn how to be
afraid of snakes and maybe you're
innately afraid of them to begin with.
No one.
The science on that is not exactly
clear,
although it certainly indicates that you
could easily learn snake fear and uh,
probably indicates that really it's a
neat.
It's an eight inch chimpanzees.
So why not us,
you know,
it's not that long since we split off
the evolutionary pathway from the common
chip human ancestor.
So enemies,
snakes.
What else?
How about crocodiles?
Those things pulled a lot of your
ancestors.
Well,
not your ancestors because they got
pulled under water.
But when we were wondering around on the
African Veldt and we went down to the
river to have some water,
you can be sure that a fair number of us
got pulled underneath by crocodiles.
And so crocodiles and you know,
those are creepy things.
Crocodiles.
Hey,
it'd be.
They figure it nightmares and they
figure in horror movies and you can
imagine yourself in Florida now,
there with alligators and thinking,
you know,
it'd be just as well if they didn't come
too close to your boat with their little
beady eyes and they're great big teeth
that,
you know,
they're unpleasant things.
And then there's lions,
hyenas,
okay.
Another one of those things.
You might take a lion in a Hyena or
different things,
but they're not.
I would say they're large tooth
mammalian carnivores.
It's like a medic category.
And so they sort of fit in that Predator
enemy category and your nervous system
is prepared to respond to predatory eyes
and teeth and no wonder because
predatory eyes track you down at teeth
eat you and they bite you.
And so it's a good thing that you're
aware of those and that you can detect
them rapidly.
Um,
what else is a human enemy?
How about another human?
How would that be?
You think more people have died from
other humans are from predators?
Well,
I suspect that since we've actually been
human,
if that's maybe 150,000
years,
because that's about when it appears
that we were more or less genetically
identical to what we are now.
My guess is that humans have got it all
over predators.
I mean lots of us,
God eat and let's not be too shy about
discussing that,
but now at least man,
it's other people.
Okay,
well what about yourself?
How about you as your own enemy?
While?
Well,
then you make it psychological.
Maybe it's not other people may,
but it's the evil in their hearts or
maybe it's the evil in your hearts.
So you see,
so this is a way of thinking about it,
is that we have a circuit to deal with
threats,
but the threats exist all the way from
the primordial biological,
like actual predators,
snakes,
all the way up to the incredibly
abstract.
Like my great enemy is the evil
intentions that other people harbored
towards me or that maybe I have in my
own heart.
Okay?
So that's that entire complex of
predatory slash threat slash evil
because it's become psychologize to that
point.
That's one of the things that can be a
character in a movie,
and it is right.
It's the antagonist,
it's the adversary that's the,
that's the architectural element.
It's the thing that opposes you in every
way and you can locate that in all sorts
of different places,
right?
You could have a story about how someone
is grappling with their own evil
impulses up.
What's the name of that serial killer
thing?
I'm Dexter Dexter's.
Got that problem.
People are pretty fascinated by that
show,
right?
A serial killer who can do good,
like sort of like a human being in some
sense.
You know,
so that's.
There's golf,
this psychological barrier between good
and evil in his heart or maybe the,
maybe the,
the enemy is externalized.
So maybe it's Batman and the joker and
the joker is a pretty.
The is really a figure of,
of chaotic evil.
Fundamentally,
you know,
in the Best Batman movie,
which was the one with a,
with the joker.
And it wasn't Jack Nicholson who played
the ledger ledger.
Yeah,
yeah.
Heath Ledger,
you know,
that was rough on old heath and no
wonder,
you know,
because he embodied this archetypal
character and that joker was so much of
an adversary that he didn't even want to
win,
right?
You can understand adversaries that want
to,
when its adversaries that want to make
everyone lose,
that are really hard to understand,
and that's part of what made that movie,
you know,
relatively striking and memorable.
And he really embodied that character
well.
And so one,
here's two sets of characters that make
up stories,
hero and address Siri,
okay?
So,
and you can,
you can understand that at multiple
levels simultaneously.
Um,
here's another set of characters.
Now,
here's why I think these characters are
fundamental elements of our cognitive
structure caught cognitive substructure.
First of all,
I think that really what we want to know
is not what is,
but we want to know how to act,
how to conduct ourselves in the world.
We're moving creatures,
right?
We don't just sit there on a rock and
filter seawater through our guilt.
We have to go out there and contend with
the world.
And so we need to know how to do that,
we need to know how to do it and how not
to do it.
So we can look for good examples and we
can look for bad examples.
We don't want just any old good example.
We want a good example that's boiled
right down to excellent example and we
want a bad example that's boiled right
down to excellent bad example.
And so a good example would be a
character who is an amalgam of all the
good things about good people and an
evil character would be an announcement
of all evil things about bad people and
the more pure in some sense,
in essence,
both of those characters are the more
architects of the story.
And so an archetypal story is good
versus evil and you might think you
don't believe in good versus evil,
but it doesn't really matter what you
believe because when you go to movies,
you watch that and you watch it as if
you believe it.
And I would say this is an existential
claim by the way,
is that it doesn't matter what you say
you believe,
because what do you know about what
matters is how you act out what you
believe,
and if you really want to find out what
you believe,
you don't ask yourself what you believe.
You Watch yourself act and you did those
from that what you believe.
And so if you don't believe,
for example,
in a good versus evil architectural
struggle and what are you doing?
Watching wars,
for example.
Okay,
because obviously that's an archetypal
story,
just like Harry Potter is an archetypal
story.
And both of those are archetypal stories
about good versus evil.
Okay?
Next set of categories.
So imagine that we've been living in
familial groups for who knows how long,
let's say 3 million years.
Just for the sake of argument.
We were living in tribal groups way,
way longer than that.
You know,
if,
if you think about a tribal group at
something that might extend back farther
than chimpanzees were living in
dominance hierarchies for way longer
than tribal groups,
but the family group,
you got to think we'd be living in
family groups for about as long as we've
been extraordinarily dependent as
infants and as long as we've had really
large brains.
And so again,
that's why you can't draw,
you know,
pipeline.
But because we'd been getting bigger and
bigger brains for quite a long time,
but it's,
it's in the millions of years let's say.
And so,
and the other thing that you might think
about is that you know,
your cognitive apparatus,
your perceptual apparatus to your
emotional apparatus has originated
within an environment.
Obviously now we tend to think of the
environment as the natural environment.
And then we tend to think of the natural
environment is like a forest.
But the natural environment for primates
say is only forest to some degree.
I mean,
first of all,
we didn't just dwell in forests because
we were also veldt dwelling creatures,
but also we didn't really dwell among
trees.
We dwelled among other primates like us,
and so our primary environment is
actually other people and then you might
say,
okay,
what are the fundamental categories of
the other people?
Well,
how about mother?
That's a big one because the probability
that you had a mother,
it's like it's up there at about 100
percent.
You know,
and if there wasn't even if you're new,
you lost your biological mother at
birth.
If someone didn't fulfill the archetypal
role as mother,
then you don't live and that doesn't
just mean providing you with food and
water and shelter.
Because if you provide a child under one
with food and water and shelter and
that's it,
they die.
You have to pick them up,
you have to touch them.
You have to rock them back and forth.
You have to communicate with them.
If you don't give them physical
attention,
their nervous systems shut down and they
die.
And so that's part of the reason why in
well in eastern European orphanages,
orphanages before the wall fell down,
the death rate,
especially in places like Romania in the
orphanage,
is it's an awful story,
was unbelievably high.
And if the kids didn't die,
they were just so crippled
psychologically that they never
recovered and that was because people
didn't touch them and didn't interact
with them.
And so you need a creature playing out
the architectural role of mother to
entice you into life.
Otherwise you just perish.
So mother,
that's a category man.
And then well,
fathers to category two and it's the
same thing applies there.
And even if you don't have a father,
there's a male power structure around
you,
a dominance hierarchy,
roughly speaking,
that acts in the paternal role.
And there's no getting away from that
unless you don't live in a society.
And then if you don't live in a society,
then you just die because you can't live
by yourself.
So father and mother are primary
categories.
And then there's the primary category of
the individual because wherever you are,
there you are.
And that's been the case for every human
being that's ever existed.
So the fundamental categories are
individual,
mother and father.
And there's another fundamental category
which we alluded to,
which is horrible thing that lives at
the bottom of a pit that will devour
you.
And that has a psychological reality,
objective,
reality,
and that's,
as I said,
that's equivalent to the story of Jonah
being gobbled up by the whale.
That happens.
That sort of story is very common.
Pinocchio is a story like that,
right?
Pinocchio has an existential problem.
He doesn't know how to be a real boy.
It turns out that in order to become a
real boy,
we might regard that as a fully
developed individual.
He has to go down to the bottom of the
ocean,
into a whale,
and rescue his father.
Well,
you,
it doesn't take a lot of imagination to
see the kinship between that story and
the story of Jonah.
It's the same story.
Jonah had to reestablish his
relationship with God the father in
order to successfully make a passage
from aimless and disobedient character
to someone who was alive on shore and
pursuing a particular path.
It's the same motif.
It's a very,
very,
very common motif.
And the reason for that is that that's
how people transform.
You know,
they hit an obstacle of some sort that
just blows them into pieces and they go
down into the depths,
into the abyss and they lived down there
for awhile and it's not pleasant and
maybe they learn something while they're
down there if they're lucky and they get
back up and that's the story of human
development.
You never learn something without having
something small die and sometimes you
learn something and something big dies
and then you know,
you put yourself back together and you
pick up the pieces and you emerge
unscathed,
hopefully in perhaps transformed and you
carry on.
And so the human developmental story
isn't an upward march in a linear
manner.
You know,
up on even slope.
It's perhaps upwards and onwards,
but it's like this,
it's punctuated by catastrophes.
And of course you guys know that because
obviously,
I mean how many times,
how many people in this room have been
seriously unhappy at one point in their
life for more than two weeks.
Okay.
Is there anyone who hasn't had that
experience breathing?
Yes.
Have you not had that experience?
Oh yeah.
Oh,
sorry.
I thought you raised your hand.
Has Anybody had that experience?
Okay.
So maybe not you.
Well,
that's good.
Congratulations.
That's really amazing.
So it's coming.
So yeah.
Yeah.
So,
so the thing is,
you know here,
here's one way of looking at it.
That's reality.
Reality is that you're,
your environment is punctuated by
desense your pathways punctuated by
descent and when you're ascending,
that's one place.
And when you're descending and at the
bottom,
that's another place.
And I can tell you that and this will
help you with your interpretation of
stories,
is that the times when you descend is
equivalent to a voyage to the
underworld.
That's what a voyage to the underworld
means and mythology.
The bottom has fallen out and down you
go and you know,
this sort of thing because look,
if I say we're all skating on thin ice,
like is there anybody here who doesn't
know what that means?
Okay.
So what does it mean?
What does it mean to break?
The ice can fall out in anytime and then
what happens down?
You Go,
right?
And it's cold down there.
Yeah.
Maybe you don't get back up.
And it's the sort of story that sort of
sends a chill down your spine and it
should because that's life.
And so one of the things that I really
like about advanced personality theory
is that it takes that into account and
says,
yeah,
that's life.
Okay,
now that we've established that,
what do we do?
And so then it becomes something like
this.
It's not so much how do you stop
yourself from descending and ascending
because good luck with that,
but since you're going to have to do
that,
how do you do it?
And so part of the reason that I called
this course personality and its
transformations is because one,
one thing that you can learn about
yourself as who you are,
and that's really useful,
but the other thing that you can learn
about yourself is how it is that you can
conduct yourself across time.
And that means you're going to have to
conduct yourself so that you can weather
storms.
And some of those might be you make a
mistake in the ice breaks,
you know?
And some of it is,
yeah,
the ice breaks and it's no mistake at
all,
it's just how it is,
you know,
so when you're one of your parents
developed Alzheimer's disease for
example,
but you could say that's your mistake
because you're not smart enough to do
anything about it and you know,
be a better clue in because otherwise
the disease is going to continue.
But on the other hand,
really thinking about it as a personal
fault seems inappropriate.
It's just a catastrophe that's
associated with being alive.
And that's what life is,
you know?
And so one of the things you see,
for example,
in all of the major trends of religious
thinking all around the world and talk
about religious thinking because those
are the deepest kinds of stories.
That's really what makes them,
by the way,
it's always the same message.
Life is suffering.
And the reason for that is because we
skate on thin ice.
Okay?
And you can say,
well,
we should pick up the damn ice and fair
enough,
you know?
Right.
Definitely.
But you should also prepare yourself to
swim so that when you fall in,
you don't die.
So now the job story has a hint or two
in it,
you know,
so the first thing that happens is job
is in some sense called the action now
because that's an old story because it's
a primarily Judaeo Christian and
religious story.
The call to action takes the force of a
divine command.
Right now you might think,
well,
there's such a thing exist and it's a
silly question in some ways because
whether or not something exists depends
on what you mean by exist,
you know,
and that can vary with your
philosophical presuppositions,
but it also,
it also varies on why you're asking the
question and where you're looking for
the answer.
So for example,
here's an example.
Do you believe that there are things
that you shouldn't do?
Like is there anyone here who doesn't
believe that?
Or more importantly,
is there anyone here who doesn't act
like they believe it?
So you wake up in the morning and you
think,
yeah,
there's a bunch of things I should do,
or are there some things I should do
next week?
Are there some things I should do with
my life?
Yes,
that's a common thought.
Is anyone not think that way?
Okay,
so you know,
if you're not thinking that way,
you end up pretty depressed because then
you think,
well,
there's nothing I should do with my life
and that's not such a happy thought
because life is hard and then if there's
nothing to do with this wall,
all you're they're stuck with is a bunch
of suffering and that doesn't seem like
a very good idea.
Okay,
so then you might say,
well,
what exactly does should mean?
Well,
it means that you have a moral
obligation of some sort.
You might say,
well,
you decided that yourself and the answer
that it's like no wrong.
You haven't decided that you yourself,
are you kidding?
You'd be at a complete psychopath if you
decided that by yourself,
right?
I mean,
if you're even the Vegas civilized,
then you decide what it is that you
should do or what you should do
manifests itself within you as a context
of a dialogue that you're continually
having with yourself,
but also with everyone around you and
not only only with everyone around you,
but with the entire history of mankind
because we're all historical creatures
and you know what you think you should
do is been shaped by what your parents
think of that was shaped by what their
parents thought that was shaped by what
their parents thought and so on.
Back into the depths of history as far
back as you can possibly imagine,
both historically and biologically.
So in some sense there is a call to
action within people.
Now,
you know,
in any sort of quest story like the
Hobbit,
let's say,
or the Lord of the rings for that
matter.
You know,
the story always starts with a call to
action,
right?
For some reason or another,
the little hobbit character,
which by the way is,
you know,
the hobbits live in this little
protected place and they're not very big
and they're not very smart and they
don't know about the wide world beyond
the board of the great forces of good
and evil are at combat and one hobbit
who's a little bit more adventurous than
the rest gets called act gets called
upon to act and in harbord stories,
it's usually the wizard who manages it,
right?
So it's a magical figure of some sort.
He's extraordinarily wise and
extraordinarily old who might as well be
gone for all intents and purposes,
who says,
you know,
it's time for you to go and become a
thief.
Will.
That's what happens in the Hobbit,
right?
Because very weird thing because
obviously that's Frodo,
right?
Photos,
the hobbit in the Hobbit,
and Bilbo is the hobbit and the Lord of
the rings.
If I remembered the other way around.
Bilbo is the poverty in the hobbit.
Fine,
Bilbo.
Okay,
so bill will gets called to action and
he's gonna go,
he's gonna.
Go find a dragon.
The dragon is the same thing,
that swallow job,
it's the same story and the Jew and the
dragon has a treasure,
which is a weird thing.
It's like what's up with dragons,
right?
What do they hoard?
Virgins.
That's the St George Story.
It's a very,
very old story or goal and that's weird
behavior for a predatory lizard,
but anyways,
you accept that without any problem with
course,
a dragon lives underground in a big
mountain that was excavated by doors and
sits on a treasure.
It's like we go to.
We don't have any problem with that
idea.
Well,
why fate?
I mean really,
you really believe that?
And the answer is well,
well enough to read the damn book and to
make the.
I mean,
how many people went and watched the
Lord of the Rings?
How many people?
And think about it worldwide.
How much money did a Harry Potter
generate?
You know,
I bet to Harry Potter generated more
money than the remaining steel mills in
Britain.
If you calculated it across the amount
of time since those stories emerged,
right?
So of course there's a lizard in a
predatory lizard and Harry Potter too.
It's the thing that skitters around
underneath hogwarts and turns you to
stone with the glance of it.
I.
Oh,
and does that Lizard Hoard vergence?
Well,
what's the name of the woman that.
The girl that he kidnaps Jenny.
Right.
Okay.
What's the word?
Jenny?
From Virginia.
Right.
Good.
And she's Harry's first month interest
and he rescues her from the damn snake
and he gets parallels.
Won't paralyze,
wouldn't while he's doing it.
What rescue is?
Harry Phoenix,
right?
A Phoenix.
Okay.
So the Bass Bites Harry and so he's
going to die.
The Phoenix comes along.
Who owns the Phoenix?
Dumbledore.
Yeah.
What does the Phoenix do?
Cries and cries into Harry's wounds.
Yes.
What happens then?
What happens to Harry?
He comes back to life.
Death and resurrection story.
So the thing that's willing to die and
resurrect is the thing that gets the
virgin from the snake.
It's like,
does that make sense?
Well,
you think it makes sense even though you
don't really know why it makes sense.
And then what happens to the what?
Ams to the Phoenix after it does that
Burns itself up in a puff of flame and
is reborn,
so it's the story told twice the thing
that dies in Israel.
Reborn is the thing that conquers the
serpentine and and rescues the feminine
roughly speaking.
So it's not gold in that situation,
but it doesn't matter.
It's the same story.
It's always the same story.
So,
and when you don't hear that story,
like when your culture isn't providing
you with rich stories of that sort that
are derived directly from your
tradition.
Somebody like an unemployed welfare
mother in Britain has it pop up full
fledged into her brilliant imagination
and lays out seven books and makes
herself more money than the queen.
Right?
Right.
And that,
you know,
it's a cinderella story.
It's a bloody amazing story.
And then there's all those books and all
those kids learn to read because of the
books.
And then there's all those movies and
everybody goes and sees them and no one
notices that they don't know what the
hell they're doing while they're doing
it.
And it follows the same old story.
Alright,
so you've got your individual that's
you,
the hero,
then you got the adversary to that.
That's your enemy.
Wherever that enemy might happen to me,
that's the forces that oppose oppose
you,
but mostly psychological forces of one
form or another.
Then you've got the father.
Well,
there's two kinds of fathers.
What guy?
Good for others and bad fathers.
So here's an example.
I'm the lion king.
So the lion king as a father,
right?
A asa and asa has a brother who's his
brother scar and what's up with scar?
Not a pleasant guy.
Partly maybe because he's scarred
sometimes.
Ha.
Well really a,
he's kind of skinny.
He said he came from the shallow end of
the gene pool.
Obviously something's happened to him
because he has this scar.
He's arrogant and brilliant,
which is very common set of attributes
for negative father figures and he's out
to doing the cane.
Right?
So what does he represent?
Well,
you could say,
here's a way of thinking about it
sociologically.
One of the things you hear very
frequently,
I'm sure many of you have heard this ad
Nauseum,
is that there's such a thing as the
patriarchy,
right?
The patriarchy,
while.
Okay.
The Petro Patriarchy is a mythological
construct and I mean that,
I mean that technically speaking,
you have a paternal figure that
basically represents it can represent
the father directly or it can represent
the structure of male power.
It's not just male power,
but whatever for for the time being,
we'll,
we'll stick with that.
It has a positive aspect which is why
you get to sit here and you're not being
snowed on and freezing to death.
So that's the positive element and it
has a negative element and the negative
element is the arbitrary tyranny that's
associated with any social organization.
Right.
So,
okay.
What do you think of the u of t like
your first year?
Did you enjoy it?
How many people didn't enjoy it?
Okay.
How many people did enjoy it?
All right,
so mark,
by the looks of things,
some of you and some of you are neutral.
You either enjoyed it or,
or didn't enjoy it or you don't have the
mental energy to crank your arm,
so.
Okay.
So mostly you didn't enjoy it.
What the hell are you doing here?
They're like,
what?
Why bother?
So someone who didn't enjoy it as
answered me that maybe you really didn't
enjoy it,
but here you are.
Why are you still here?
That's the sunk cost answer.
It's like you,
you waited for a bus for half an hour.
It hasn't shown up.
The right thing to do is wait for
another half an hour.
Right.
Well,
to put it in the morning,
I approached it from a different angle.
So basically I change when I was
starting.
How would that work?
Worked out well,
was it the second time?
I did try it.
It worked out well.
Good.
So was that an unpleasant process?
Were you confused?
Did you come out the other end?
Um,
yeah,
right on.
You more mature.
Uh,
yeah.
You know more than you did five years
ago.
I hope so.
Was it worth it?
Good.
Good for you.
Well Look,
look,
you make a calculation and what's wrong
with the University of Toronto?
Well there's 60,000
students for a starter.
Like what the Hell do you matter?
You know,
really your numbered and it feels like
that a lot of the time.
So it's a very impersonal institution
and you're sort of tossed into it so
you're basically facing a giant of some
magnitude who's kind of blind and who
sort of archaic,
which is always what culture is,
right?
Culture is always blind because it's a
product of yesterday and it's.
And it's archaic,
it's not up to date,
so you're going to have a problem with
it and you have that problem when you
come to the university.
So you stick with it though because it's
got two faces.
One face is sank or swam there guys.
And the other face is man,
if you're careful and you and establish
a relationship with this kind of
institution,
you can learn so much that you won't
even be the same person when you come
out.
Maybe you'll be able to think that'd be
good.
You know,
if you learn to think,
then you don't run into sharp things
when you wander through life because
you're smart enough to see where they
are and avoid them,
you know,
and maybe you can think your way to a
target or maybe you could even think
about a target that's worthwhile and you
can figure out how to attain it and
maybe you learn to write and then you
can articulate your ideas and you can
express them with some power and you
could make,
you know,
you can be a positive force in the world
and you can be successful in all sorts
of ways.
And if you have to put up with being
tyrannized by a half dad monster,
with,
with Alzheimer's disease,
that's blind.
Well that's life and it could be a lot
worse because at least you're contending
with something that has a positive
element.
You know,
in lots of societies if you're up
against the,
the blind giant of society,
the best that you can hope for is that
it isn't running around trying to stomp
on you all the time.
And I would say that's more the standard
human experience.
So yeah,
there's a patriarchy and yet it's
negative.
Obviously it's always been like that,
but by the same token,
you know there's a good guy embedded in
that too,
and that's the thing you want to have a
relationship with and that's the same
old story.
It's always been like that.
There's always a wise king and tyrant
and they're always fighting and
sometimes the wise king,
king winds,
sometimes the tyrant winds and then when
the tire,
when it's up to the hero to defeat the
tyrant and reestablish the rightful
king,
and that's actually what you're trying
to do when you're in university because
the rightful king in some senses,
a corpse that's embedded inside the
university and your job is to revivify
it.
You know,
you're the living element of the
university and all the knowledge is
dead.
It's just lying around and some of it's
out of date.
You know,
you come in here and you,
you revise it so that society can
continue and so that you can benefit
from the relationship.
Well,
that's the positive and negative.
Great father,
the king and the tyrant.
And then another,
another level is the feminine.
The Feminine is not women.
Women partake of the feminine and the
masculine,
just like men partake of the feminine
and the masculine,
but the maternal element,
the feminine elements is nature.
Positive nature.
Well,
that's the thing that the
environmentalists love,
right?
That's flowers and French landscapes and
you know,
pleasant days,
picnic in the park and and beautiful
sunshine and fresh air and clean water.
But then there's another side.
Another side is,
do you know what the Guinea worm is?
Does anybody know what a Guinea word is?
Well,
I'm going to tell you,
although you're not going to be happy
about it,
so a Guinea worm is this horrible
parasite that burrows under the skin,
mostly of children,
mostly in Africa,
and it's about two feet long,
so it makes these coils around their
legs and then it'll poke its little head
out and then you can pull it out,
but it tends to break and if that
happens,
then it gets infected.
It May,
maybe you die and so you can wrap it
around a pencil very slowly and pull it
out.
That's nature.
Now there's a doctor who's a Canadian
doctor who wasn't really very happy
about those Damn Guinea worms and he's
just about eradicated them and like
hooray for him,
but you know,
when we're talking about the
environment,
especially when we're thinking about it
and mythological categories and we're
talking about nature,
it's like,
yeah,
it's nature and all its beneficial
glory,
but it's also all the things that would
just assume,
eat you in the most awful possible way
and you need to know that too,
because if you think of nature has only
been official in its positive archetypal
element that that's mother nature in all
her glory,
then you tend to denigrate the utility
of the positive element of culture.
You know it's culture that protects you
from the horrible elements of nature.
You wouldn't even be able to think
about.
Nature is beautiful if you weren't
already so protected from it.
You know you're more protected from it
than any human beings ever have been
anywhere in the entire history of life.
And so in this unbelievably protected
environment,
you can think,
oh well we should go easy on nature
because isn't it so beautiful?
It's like,
yeah,
well,
yes and no.
And it's not all beauty.
It's certainly not because nature will
eventually kill you.
So it even if it doesn't go well,
it's going to kill you.
It will also make you sick.
It will also make everyone that you know
sick and it will kill all of them too.
So it's not so such a bad thing to have
a little bit of empathy for human beings
given that we have to contend with that.
And you know,
if we're destroying everything,
which we're not,
it's also returning the favor.
So.
Alright,
so there's the sub stripe at the bottom
of things.
There's this terrible monster,
but it hoards gold.
And so encountering it,
defeating it,
challenging it,
facing it can be unbelievably
productive.
And that's a symbol of the absolute
unknown.
That's where you go when things fall
apart,
you don't know where you are.
So where are you?
You're aware,
you don't know what things are.
And that's a place.
And what's interesting about it is that
there are rules to act in that place and
that's what's so helpful because you
know,
if you're in a place that you don't know
what to do and that's that you're done.
But if there's a pattern to what you can
do in a circumstance like that,
then in July and on your feet and you're
ready to contend and maybe the trip down
into the underworld is something you can
undertake on your own accord.
And you can come back with the treasurer
and steadying instead of ending up as
dragon food or worse.
And then when you're conceptualizing
your relationship to other people,
well,
well let's say this society,
first of all,
it's like,
yeah,
obviously you face a tyrant.
Of course you do.
But that is all you face.
And you need to be grateful for what
you've been given by your culture.
And you actually have to understand what
that culture is because it's you.
And if you don't rescue that part of you
and that part of the culture that
everything gets dad and stale and
tyrannical and everything goes
immediately to help.
And that's not a good thing.
And then with regards to nature,
well you obviously have to appreciate
the positive element of nature and you
have to enter into a relationship with
it,
but you don't bloody well want to forget
that like things are out to get you and
you know you have to be intelligent and,
and ready and awake so that you can
prevail against them and you have to be
grateful for what you've been offered by
other people and by the tremendous
efforts of all of culture across all of
the time,
that's put you in a position where
you're so unbelievably privileged and
have so many opportunities at your,
at your disposal.
Well.
So that's kind of the archetypal story
of human beings.
We always face nature and it's always on
our side.
We always face our culture.
It's always on our site and we always
have ourselves and those things that are
arrayed against us internally,
externally.
And that's the.
You could say that's the existential
world.
It's the world of drama and the things
that are really compelling to you as
means of communicating.
Use those categories to provide you with
information because what you're trying
to figure out is if that's the landscape
that makes up your being.
So that's a phenomenological idea.
How is it that you weave your way
through it?
While that's what we're going to figure
out?
Well,
we go through this class.
Okay,
so that's the mythological background.
So there's the character,
illogical elements that I just
described.
And then there's the punctuated movement
forward.
Now you know,
the problem with that is that when
things fall apart,
it's not like you just fall apart
psychologically.
It's not just a psychological condition.
You know,
if someone's be trade you deeply,
that might be because you're naive and
unready and maybe that's a psychological
element.
Maybe you're just young and you know you
don't know battery and you couldn't,
but there's also the real fact of the
problem that you have in fact been
betrayed and now you don't know what to
do.
So there's reality in it as well as just
what psychological.
And so
one of the things that you might.
One of the ways that you might construe
personality theories that have to deal
with a description of the way people are
and a description of how they might move
towards mental health is that there are
maps that tell you how to their maps of
that landscape that tell you how to
Orient Yourself so that you can succeed
and even better,
and this is a Piagetian idea.
It's not only so that you can succeed,
it's so that you can succeed in a way
that your family succeed so that they
can succeed in a way that society
succeeds so that everything works better
at the same time.
And that's really success,
you know,
and that's like you're winning a game
that everyone wants to play well,
what a deal.
You get to move forward and everyone
else gets to enjoy it.
Well,
that's a good definition of success.
It's an architectural definition of
success actually,
because if you succeed properly,
then your success benefits everyone else
so hard to imagine that there could be
anything particularly wrong with that.
Alright,
so
that's the mythological element.
Now I want to tell you a little bit
about the shamonic element.
Now
the reason I want to talk to you about
shamanism is because shamanism is a
very,
very old phenomena and Sharmin isn't.
Looks like a phenomenon that involves
the dramatization of transformation
processes,
so so one transformation process might
be the initiation of young men.
Now it's more typical for young men to
be initiated.
Then young women and no one really knows
why that is,
except men seem to be able to go more
spectacularly wrong than women so well,
so if you look at what we'll talk about
that later,
but there's also competing theories that
say you don't have to initiate women
because nature does that all by itself
and I think that that's not a
particularly bad way of looking at it.
So women are going to be confronted with
the brute force of nature,
but men can either do that or not do it,
and so there's in some sense an element
of choice.
And so the initiation rituals take away
the element of choice.
And so on a typical initiation ritual,
what happens is that young men usually
at the onset of puberty or taken away
from their familial dependents,
which really means their mothers and
then they're put into some situation and
terrified three quarters to death.
Now more or less,
they do that voluntarily.
So perhaps here's an example,
maybe you're 13.
So remember,
think about your 30.
Think about that.
Okay?
And so you're still afraid of the dark
when you're 13,
even though they'll tell people that you
aren't,
but you are.
And so like if you were dropped naked in
the middle of a forest when you're 13
and it's midnight,
you're going to be plenty frozen with
terror and a good thing too,
because you know it's dangerous out
there.
Okay?
So then you think,
well maybe it's just a park,
but you're still out there and it's dark
and you're afraid.
You might say,
well,
what are you afraid of?
And one of the things you might come up
with as well,
you're afraid of what you're imagining.
And then you might say,
well,
does that mean that you're afraid of
your imagination or are you afraid of
the things your imagination represents?
Well,
you kind of have to think if there's no
actual objective danger there,
then what you're afraid of is your
imagination.
Now,
did you guys ever see the Blair witch
project?
How many of you have seen that?
How many of you haven't now?
So it's a pretty lousy example.
Anyways,
it's a horror movie now there's kind of
two kinds of horror movies.
There's the splatter type horror movie
and I think actually those expose you to
discuss and then there's the fear kind
of horror movie and that doesn't need to
have any Gore at all.
It just makes you afraid.
And the Blair witch project is very good
example of that because all that
happens,
nothing happens,
but you think something terrible is
going to happen every second and the
sense that something terrible is going
to happen keeps climbing through the
whole movie.
And so what they do is put you in a
state of radical uncertainty and never
let you off.
Okay,
well so basically they're playing with
your imagination and that can work very
effectively,
like it's often horror movies,
often more effective if they don't show
you what's making those horrible noises
off screen,
you know,
because no matter what show you,
the probability that he can be as
personally horrible as what are their
monsters you're dredging up out of your
imagination is very low.
So,
and you know,
it's reasonable to be afraid of the dark
because throughout our biological
history,
lots of unfortunate people were devoured
by things in the dark or hurt very badly
by them,
etc.
Etc.
And wE're also daytime creatures,
right?
So we don't like the dark very much.
So what do you do to someone if you're
going to initiate them is maybe you take
them when they're 13 and you put them in
a really dark cave and caves.
There Are so dark man,
like if you're in a cave,
you just can't believe how dark it is.
It's,
it's,
you can't see anything in a cave.
So you don't know how big the space
you're in is and you don't know how
small it is and you don't know whether
or not it's going to collapse or when
it's going to stay up and you don't know
how far you are underground,
especially if the people who took you
there didn't,
you know,
walk you around in circles and didn't
let you know where you were going and
then maybe they leave and maybe they
leave for three days.
And so you're sitting down there
thinking,
well,
what are you thinking?
Exactly?
Well,
you're thinking the most horrible
thoughts you could possibly imagine,
right?
I'm never going to get out of here.
They're never going to find me again.
some horrible snake thing that lives in
the darkness is going to come and eat it
slowly because fast would be merciful
and I'm.
And then I'm also going to go completely
out of my mind so that even if something
doesn't eat me,
I'm going to come over here and it will
be worse than being dead anyways.
And so partly what you're doing in that
circumstances,
you're facing that demons of your own
imagination.
And if you can stand that,
then you grow up and that's what an
initiation ceremony tests.
Now a lot of what you'll find if you
look at clinical theories of psychology,
the same motif applies if you want to
get better,
you have to find out what you're
avoiding and what you're afraid of and
maybe what you're disgusted by evil and
you have to expose yourself to that
voluntarily and you have to let that
change you.
And so it's not a pleasant prospect.
I mean,
it's not dancing through a field of
daisies,
right?
With muzak play and it'S not follow your
bliss.
You know,
it's not the natural unfolding of a
positive process.
It's not that at all.
It's the voluntary confrontation with
the things that make up life's horrors.
But what's interesting about it is that
there's,
there's an idea there that lurks under
the surface architecturally,
and that is there's a lot more to you
than meets the eye,
but it won't be released unless it has
to.
And so you don't have to even figure out
what it is until you put yourself in
peril.
Now,
part of that you might think like
imagine that you're.
You're an introvert.
You're socially awkward.
You're highly neurotic,
so you feel a lot of anxiety and
depression.
You don't like going to partieS and
that's because the horrible tyrant lives
at parties and always glaring at you and
judging you and telling you how useless
and insufficient you are.
And so you go there and you don't even
look at people because you know that if
you did look at them,
you just see the face of the judgmental
tyrant,
which by the way,
you wouldn't if you actually looked at
them,
but you won't because you avoid and so
you're going to go there and you're
going to put yourself in this terrible
situation.
And if you're lucky and you're a bit of
weight,
then you're going to incorporate all
sorts of information from the external
world that will help you develop your
social skills and make you more
sophisticated.
And even if that doesn't happen,
you're going to learn that.
You can tolerate your own fear.
And you might say,
well,
what's better to not be afraid or to
know that you can handle being afraid
and obviously to not be afraid,
but give that up because that ain't
happening so that the next best thing
and the realistic thing is to know that
you're the master of your own fear.
And so a lot of what we're going to talk
about in relationship to classical
theories of personality is exactly that.
It's not that the world isn't terrible,
is that the world is terrible,
but you're a lot stronger than you think
and the way you.
Okay?
And so part of that is the strength that
you gather is partly the information
that you gather when you go somewhere
that you're not good at.
You know,
so you're establishing new skills like
you haven't university.
But there's another part that's
interesting that's related to the little
video that I showed you at the
beginning.
Dna turns out to be a very complex
structure.
And so if I put you in situation a,
then dna codes,
certain kinds of proteins that help make
up the way that your mind is in the way
it works.
But if I take you and put you in another
situation,
completely different genes turn on,
and so what that means is that you have
a biological repository of potential use
lying dormant at the highest resolution
level of your molecular structure.
And then if you push yourself and all
sorts of different directions and you
find different things to pursue and test
yourself against,
then you're going to turn on parts of
yourself that aren't currently on and
god only knows what you'd be like if you
turned yourself completely on.
Maybe I could use a better metaphor.
I'll tell you a little bit more about
the shavano routines because they're
more,
you know,
if there is a initiation archetype which
are kind of just described to you,
which is you can do this to yourself.
I'll Tell you,
oh yeah,
and this is a good way to live.
It beats the alternative.
anyone?
So which is like the definition of a
good way to live so mad and you're
trying to pursue something so you've got
a goal.
That's a good thing.
You got to have a goal and you don't
want to hold onto that too tightly
because he might be wrong.
You've got to be willing to let that go
and have a different goal,
but you need to go and then you know
while you're pursuing the goal,
you're gonna.
Find out that there's some obstacles in
your path obviously,
and maybe some of those obstacles are of
a frightening time,
or maybe they're even have a disgusting
type.
You might say,
I don't want to turn into that kind of
person,
so those of you who are sort of
socialist utopia,
left wingers might think that way about
business people.
It's like,
I would,
I would recommend that you get over it
as rapidly as possible.
So anyways,
you might think there's no way I'm going
to act that way.
So you sort of put it off limits saying,
or maybe you're afraid to do what you
need to do next.
Well,
here's the rule.
Don't avoid doing things because they
make you feel negative emotion.
If you have to do those things in order
to pursue your goals,
in fact,
you should do exactly the opposite.
So let's say you're pursuing a goal and
you find that you're afraid about
something and so you're avoiding it.
The first thing you should think is a
hot look.
I'm afraid of something and I'm avoiding
it.
Dragon treasure.
Exactly there.
And that's exactly right.
It's precisely right.
If you're.
If you're afraid of the thing,
then what that means is that you're not
developed enough to handle it and you
need to be.
So you should think about that as a
discovery,
like a positive discovery.
You found out where you have a weakness
and you're now able to address it.
So you know if you're an introvert and
you think it's friday night,
I could go to this party,
but you know I really don't want to.
Then you think,
oh,
that means I should go.
And that's exactly right because
because you already know how to do the
things that you know how to do and it's
the things that you don't know how to do
that bother you and oppress you.
And of course those things are going to
be difficult to learn about,
but you need to learn about them because
you need to get yourself all switched
on.
How's that switched on?
Because then you'll be able to tolerate
the fact that life is fundamentally
suffering and so you don't know.
The world doesn't get safer us.
You developed,
in fact quite the contrary.
You just get more competent and that's
better anyways because it's conceivable
that you don't want safety anyways.
You probably want adventure.
You probably want to be compelled.
You probably want to be engaged.
You know,
if you want security,
you might as well be dead well because
nothing's happening then and that
there's no danger to be alive is to be
contending with the world and you want
to be the best you can possibly be.
And that's partly what we're going to
learn about as we go through the entire
course.
But certainly the elements that have to
do with clinical psychology because all
of them circulate around this
fundamental fee.
They have to.
Because it's the fundamental story of
mankind and we want to know what that
fundamental story is because we're all
human and you need to know the story and
then you know,
you can decide how you're going to act
it out,
but at least you need to know the damn
story first.
So we'll see you.