Well,
after all that,
so welcome to psychology to 30.
Nice to see you all here.
So what I'm going to do today,
oh,
I'm going to start is I'm going to give
you an overview of the content of the
course and then I'll give you an
overview of the class requirements right
at the end of.
I think we might as well jump right into
the content to begin with.
So there's a website,
I don't really like blackboard,
so I have my own website.
You can go to Jordan with Peter,
Jordan,
b Peterson,
dark palm and underneath there there's a
menu that lists all the courses and the
full syllabus is listed there.
So all the information that you're going
to need about the course can be found
there,
including most of the readings,
although there is also a textbook which
I presumed a majority of you have
already purchased.
So it also lists the other things that
you need to know,
like what days the tests are going to be
and what the assignments are.
And I'll go over that anyways at the end
of the clocks.
So,
but to begin with,
I'm going to tell you what the course is
about so you can decide whether you're
in the right class or not.
So
personality is a somewhat peculiar field
of study in psychology because it spans
a number of sub disciplines that aren't
particularly well suited to one another,
so for example,
it spans clinical psychology and
experimental psychology and it also
spans and approach that is associated
fundamentally with single individuals
with an approach that analyzes
individual characteristics in large
groups,
which is generally what you have to do
in experimental psychology.
It's also a relatively strange admixture
of philosophy and I would say
engineering and medicine as well as
science and you might think of medicine
as a science,
but it's not and the reason that it's
not as because it's concerned with the
promotion of health and health is not a
scientific category.
It's a category that can't help but be
value-laden because you have to decide
what constitutes health,
health and what constitutes illness or
what constitutes wellness and what
constitutes pathology and there's no way
you can do that without bringing value
judgments into the equation.
It's particularly true in psychology
because when you're thinking about what
a healthy might be,
you generally don't merely think in
terms of the absence of pathology.
You think in terms of the presence of
positive traits,
right,
and someone who's fully healthy mentally
and physically.
While the psychologists,
especially the humanistic psychologists
from the sixties might consider someone
who's truly psychologically healthy,
self actualized,
which would mean in some sense that
they've been able to develop the
entirety of their positive potential,
whatever that is.
So because of these peculiarities,
personality psychology,
the course of course in personality
psychology has to be pretty wide
ranging.
And so this course is in fact wide
It,
it,
it brings in elements of cultural
history,
um,
elements of moral philosophy and then
elements that I would consider almost
completely biological.
And it does that in order to provide you
with a multidimensional view of what it
means to be a human being.
I have some other principles that I
abide by while I'm teaching this course
as well.
And one of those is that I don't really
want to tell you about anything that I
don't think you will find useful and
useful,
like there's a difference between a fact
and a useful fact,
right?
There's lots of facts.
You can go on Google and you can drown
yourself in facts.
I'm sure you do that every day,
but a useful fact to me is one that
transforms the way that you look at the
world or the way that you act in the
world in some manner that you find
beneficial.
And so another way of,
of describing useful from that
perspective is relevant.
And so one of the principles I abide by
is that I don't really want to teach you
anything that isn't relevant and my
criteria for relevant is first isn't
going to make a difference to you
personally.
So are the things that you learn
immediately meaningful to how you
interact with the world.
And then the second is,
is there some evidence that the facts
that you're going to be,
that you're going to be presented with
actually have some social utility or
some political utility or some economic
utility.
So that the fact that you know them
makes a difference to the way that you
act in a way that also affects the
people around you.
And so
it's for those multiple reasons that I
brought together the material that I
have brought together now that means
that there's some factors that you have
to take into account
before you take this course.
And there's another personality course
being given at exactly the same time,
like,
well,
I don't this semester anyways.
And so it may be that that one's more
suitable for you to network.
I don't know,
but I can tell you what this one is
going to be like.
And so if that isn't what you want or if
that's not what you're interested in,
then you probably shouldn't take this
course.
So the first issue is that there's a lot
of,
there isn't as much reading as there
used to be in this course by the way.
Um,
but there's still a lot of reading and a
lot of its original source material,
both from the personality theorists
themselves and then also original source
material from empirical papers.
So I would say that not only is there a
lot of reading,
but the readings actually quite
difficult.
Um,
I think it's useful given the way I
already defined utility to you.
And so I believe that reading what I
present to you is going to be good for
you,
but if you don't have time to do a lot
of reading,
then you're going to find this course
frustrating.
So there's also because of the emphasis
on clinical theoreticians,
which is a major part of personality
theory,
especially the more classical
personality theory,
which by the way is generally the
elements of personality theory that most
students are most interested in.
Um,
there's a lot of what I would consider
philosophical material and the reason
it's philosophical is because it's
concerned with how a person should live.
And that's a much different question
than what a person is.
So it's how a person should live or
perhaps how a person might transform
themselves or act in order to transform
themselves so that their personality is,
well,
for lack of a better word,
better now you can substitute healthier
for better.
But in a context like the one we're
discussing,
the difference is trivial really.
So then the last thing that I would
caution you against is that I don't
lecture from the reading material so
often.
I'm not exactly sure even what I'm going
to tell you when I come to class.
I know the material,
but I don't want to stick to a
prescribed beltline.
I want to talk to you about the things
that I think are important and so with
luck that'll make the lectures worth
attending and worth listening to.
But if you're more inclined from a
temperamental perspective,
do you want it a course where things are
laid out in a very orderly fashion and
they progress in a linear fashion and
it's predictable and the lectures
reflect the reading material,
then this is not a good course for you.
And so I would presume that would be the
case if you're orderly.
And by the way,
that's one of the subdivisions of the
big five personality trait model.
An orderly people tend to be
conscientious,
but they like things cut and dried and
laid out in linear fashion.
Um,
I'm not that orderly.
I'm higher in openness and openness is a
creative dimension and open people tend
to use relatively loose,
loose associations when they speak and
to cover a wide amount of territory.
And so some people would like that.
If you like reading literature for
example,
you probably liked this course.
If you don't,
then you probably won't.
So
anyways,
that's pretty much enough for the
warnings.
So,
uh,
now I'll tell you what we're going to
talk about.
One of the things that makes human
beings unique
is the fact that we're self conscious.
Now,
you'll see ecologists are people who
study animal behavior,
do relatively elementary tests of self
consciousness on animals.
So one of the most famous demonstrations
of such self consciousness is the mirror
test.
And so in the mirror test,
what you essentially do is you take an
animal,
maybe a chimp or maybe a three year old
child,
and you put a lipstick mark on their
forehead or on their nose,
and then you show them a reflection of
themselves in the mirror.
And if they wipe off,
or Jeff,
you're towards the lipstick mark,
then you can make the presumption that
they understand that it's them that's
being reflected in the mirror,
or at least they understand that well
enough so that they can use the mirror
as a guide to action with their with
their hand or or whatever it is that
they happen to be pointing with,
and the reflection now,
dolphin seemed to be able to manage
that.
There some members of the core of the
family.
So those are basically crows and ravens.
Those things are really smart and they
seem to possess rudimentary
selfconsciousness said dolphins
citations in general.
So whales,
although I don't know if all whales are
self conscious because it's,
for example,
difficult to get a mirror and big enough
to show a blue whale
human beings.
That's about it.
No,
I don't think that's a very good
definition of self consciousness really.
Because the mere fact that you can
recognize yourself and it's also not
fair to some animals like dogs,
right?
Because dog would need a smell of mirror
really because.
And most animals are very,
very smell predicated.
Most of the brain is structured with the
olfactory system as its core,
unlike us really because our brains are
structured with the visual system at the
core and that makes us rather peculiar,
but it's a little unfair to animals like
dogs and rats that relied primarily on
olfaction to orient themselves in the
world.
But the thing is I don't think that's
really a very good definition of self
consciousness.
It's very rudimentary.
You might say,
well,
that's the first sort of step to being
self conscious because if you're fully
self conscious,
I think you need two more things.
You need the capacity to imitate,
which is a much more important capacity
than people generally realize.
In fact,
I would say it's a equivalent
importance.
It's of equivalent importance to
language.
In fact,
I'm not even sure that you could use
language if you can't imitate.
First of all,
obviously all the words you used are
also the words that other people use.
Otherwise,
you're not going to be very
comprehensible,
so even the mere fact that you do speak
means that you're relying on invitation
to get your point across.
So you need an invitation and the reason
you need invitation is because once you
can imitate,
you can use your body as a
representational structure to represent
the world and other people you can even
use your body as a representational
structure to represent yourself,
which you might do,
for example,
if you're telling a joke at a dinner
party and then you know,
act out of self parody and everyone
likes so.
And then with regards to language,
well language obviously enables you to
build sophisticated models of the world
that are well articulated to exchange
those with other people and to think,
okay,
so in order to be self conscious you
have to be able to recognize that you
exist in this physical envelope,
at least here and now.
You need to be able to imitate because
that's partly how you come to understand
yourself and other creatures like you,
which is a very important part of being
self conscious.
Right?
I mean everything I learned about any of
you is also going to help me understand
the sort of creature that I am,
whether that's for good or for evil.
And then with language,
well not only can we articulate our
representations about each other in the
world,
but we can also store those articulated
representations over very,
very,
very long spans of time and we do that
partly in ritual which is the acting out
of a representation.
And we do that partly with regards to
stories which are in some sense and
articulated representation of an acting
out,
right?
Because you can think of a story as a
drama.
So drama is behavior representing
behavior.
And then the story is an articulated
representation of a drama.
Now we have very old rituals and we have
very,
very old stories and so part of what we
do in this course as we go back to as
close to the beginning as we can
possibly manage to start to understand
how people have understood themselves
and represented themselves across the
span of human history.
And we're doing that because we want to
be able to put our current knowledge in
some kind of historical context.
And part of the reason for that is,
well,
one of the things that characterizes the
human personality is that it's a
historical phenomenon.
You know,
I'm sure you've heard in many classes
that much of what makes up your
personality is a cultural construct.
Well,
whether or not much of it is or not
isn't really the issue.
Certainly some of it is an important
part.
You're a cultural creature and that
means that you have emerged within a
tradition that's been shaped and in any
number of ways by an extraordinarily
lengthy historical past or historical
and biological.
And so what that means in part is that
if you don't understand your history,
and that's your history as it matters,
not necessarily some collection of
facts,
then you don't understand yourself.
So,
you know,
human beings in their self conscious
form,
we don't really know how old we are,
more or less biologically or genetically
identical creatures to us existed at
least 150,000
years ago.
But we seem to have discovered fire and
were able to master it maybe 2 million
years ago,
you know.
And that required a fair bit of
intelligence.
Um,
and there are,
there are artifacts that indicate a fair
high level of,
of cultural capacity that are at least
50,000
years old.
So we can't really say when,
when we got fully self conscious and
perhaps we might also say that we're not
even fully self conscious yet because
you know,
really what the hell do you know about
yourself?
You know,
you're really,
really,
really complicated.
And at best you have a partial model of
who you are and that thing fails all the
time,
which as you can tell,
because you're always doing things that
surprise you and often not in a
particularly positive way.
So there's no end of mystery.
Anyways.
The upshot of all this is that we're
going to establish the context first.
That's a historical context and I want
to do that two ways.
The first thing I want to do is to talk
to you about mythological
representations of personality,
and that's more important than you might
think.
In fact,
it's probably more important than you do
think.
I'm by myth.
What I mean is the representations of
human beings in extremely long lasting
and persistent stories.
And so some of those are the stories
that are found in various religious
traditions,
but there's oral traditions that
surround those religious traditions just
assuming that the religious traditions
are written down and there's fairy tales
and that sort of thing and standard
narratives that people use to guide
themselves as they move through the
world,
and most of the clinical theories that
we're going to discuss,
so Freud's theory and theory and the
theory of the existentialists and the
phenomenologists in the humanists and so
forth,
are variance of those mythological
stories.
Now,
part of the reason for that is that
neat.
You said once that a philosopher was
seldom anything other than the
unconscious advocate of their cultural
worldview.
So what he meant by that was you already
come to the scene with a set of
presuppositions.
Now,
some of those are embedded in your
behavior.
So for example,
when you walk,
when you attend a funeral,
you know how to behave.
He generally,
you're quiet and solemn.
You might not be able to explicate the
rules that a person should follow at a
funeral,
but you can do it now.
You could perhaps articulate them press,
but it's not like you're following those
rules.
You go to a funeral,
you just know what to do.
If someone pressed you,
you could turn it into a list of rules,
but it's really more encoded in your
actual behavior.
You just automatically know what to do.
You can tell when you ever.
You interact with someone who's really
socially fluent,
you can tell that they're not
consciously processing the way that
they're acting.
Otherwise they're self conscious and
awkward.
They're just very fluid.
It's automatized behavior and it's coded
right into them.
So if you're a great philosopher,
then according to Nietzsche,
at least what you do is you take a look
and how you act and what you think,
and then you say,
well,
this is what it's like.
It's not so much that you're inventing
new ideas.
It's that you're articulating the nature
of structures that are already there.
So you can imagine,
for example,
imagine that you're particularly
interested in wolves and so you studied
some wolves and one of the things you
see is that the wolves have a dominance
hierarchy.
So there's,
there's a leader and then there is
struggle in the pack to see who's going
to be the dominant leader.
Now there's a couple of problems with
that,
which is that,
you know,
if we'll fail and we'll be fight and
they're pretty evenly matched and they
tear each other to shreds,
then we'll see is going to come in and
pound both of them.
And that's not a particularly useful
strategy for welfare for Wolf B plus.
Then the pack loses the power of Wolf
and wolf be.
And so that's hard to useful at all.
So what's happened is that wolves have
evolved dominance and submission
strategies so that they can figure out
who is going to leave and who is going
to follow without having to engage in
the kind of physical combat that's going
to result in damage.
And so usually what happens is that the
two wolves face off,
you've probably seen cats do this when
they encounter each other,
you know,
other on the street,
the first thing they do is sort of
turned sideways and they puff themselves
up,
right?
And they dance back and forth.
It's quite comical.
But what the caps trying to do is look
back and exposed to try and make the
other cat nervous enough to leave.
And so what was do is roughly the same
thing they puff out so they look big and
they make all sorts of ferocious noises
and they threaten each other.
And usually what happens is one wolf
will lose his nerve,
flopped down,
roll over,
show his throat,
and that basically means something like
I'm useless and,
and you know,
and pathetic and you can tear out my
throat if you want because of that.
And the other wolf.
Thanks.
Yeah,
you are pretty useful and pathetic,
but you know,
we're going to need you tomorrow to hunt
down a deer so you know,
you can get up and protect your
miserable self and that'll be okay.
Now,
if you were watching that,
you might say we'll just follow rules,
but of course they don't.
That's just how wolves,
Zach,
when you describe what the wells are
doing,
then you turn it into a rule.
But it wasn't a rule to begin with.
It was just a pattern of behavior.
Now,
human beings are like that were chalked
full of patterns of behavior and
they're,
they're the consequences of our biology,
which is something we'll talk about in
depth in the last half of the course,
and there are consequence of our culture
and they're built into our bodies.
Like every,
every time you interact with another
person,
they're telling you how to behave,
right?
Don't be too obtuse.
Try to be a little bit witty,
have something interesting to say.
Don't be too annoying if you're going to
say something funny,
make sure it's funny.
Take turns while you talk.
Play nicely,
take your turn.
Don't eat all the bread,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
You know,
and so if you don't abide by those
rules,
then people lift their eyebrow at you or
they don't smile at your jokes are they
don't look at you or they roll their
eyes when you come in,
which is really not a good sign by the
way,
and you get punished severely for it.
And then if you do act like they would
like you to act,
you know,
then people smile at you and they're,
they invite you to their place for
dinner and you know,
maybe you have an intimate relationship
and some people that like you.
And so we're exchanging information
about how we should manifest ourselves
in our bodies with every possible
interaction.
And what that means is that shapes the
way that we act.
Now the problem is or partly is that you
don't really understand the consequences
of that.
Like you,
you can act it out more or less
depending on your social skill and the
degree to which you've been exposed to
other people.
But that doesn't mean you're a conscious
that you have that.
You can consciously articulate all the
rules that underlie that.
And if you think that maybe you can,
well fine.
You know,
imagine a well behaved four year old,
you know,
by four,
you've got a lot of the social rules
down because by four you can play with
others if you're ever going to be able
to.
You can already do it by the time you,
for.
If you can't,
by the time you were four,
you are in serious trouble because other
kids won't play with you and then they
won't teach you how to act,
and then you stay immature and isolated
and you know often your little corner
dejected and bitter for the rest of your
life.
Now you might think that's a little
rough,
but it's not.
That's what the.
That's what the data indicate.
So.
So anyways,
what this means in part is,
well,
we've been shaping how all of us behave
as long as we've been social.
Now you might say,
well,
how long have we been social?
Well,
crustaceans are social.
So lobsters for example,
organize themselves into dominance
hierarchies and they modify each other's
behavior.
And that's $400 million years.
So we've been social and living in
groups since our ancestors departed on
the evolutionary timescale from the
ancestors of lobsters.
So that's very,
very,
very long time.
There weren't any trees around back
there.
So social life is older than trees,
so you can be sure that you're adapted
to it in a major way.
So it's built into your biology.
But then there's the historical element
of it too,
and it's quite.
We're quite flexible from a cultural
perspective.
So there's an example skier named Robert
Sapolsky,
who I really like.
He's a great scientist.
He went off to Africa to study baboons.
Baboons are not pleasant generally
speaking there.
They fight a lot.
They're bullies.
They bite.
They can really bite at that boom,
like a predatory cat will think twice
about taking on and by mood.
They've got major teeth and their.
Their temperament is not particularly
positive.
Supposedly went and studied a group of
baboons and they were engaged in typical
baboons,
gang behavior,
harassing each other all the time and
bullying each other and they're all
stressed out because he knew that
because he measured their levels of
stress and their testosterone and so
forth and so it was pretty miserable
baboons existence.
But then what happened was that
the baboons went to feed somewhere that
I don't remember and they,
a lot of them contracted tuberculosis
and it turned out that almost all the
hyper aggressive males got tuberculosis
and died and all that was left was the
Beta males roughly speaking.
And then the whole book by building
culture transformed so that it became
much more agreeable and much more
cooperative.
And then when aggressive baboons would
move into that territory,
you know,
singly or their own,
then they'd get all placid and calm too.
So it's interesting gay because
obviously baboons aren't social to the
degree that we are,
but it does indicate that even at the
advanced primate level,
you know,
their brains are pretty big but not as
big as ours.
But cultural transmission of behavior
expectation can be quite powerful and it
can transform quite rapidly.
So anyways,
we've been shaping each other's behavior
for a very,
very,
very long time.
And a lot of that is encoded deeply in
biology and in culture.
Now,
biologically,
when we'll talk about this a lot,
when we get to the biological section,
one of the ways that you can know how
social you are is by noting how hurt and
ashamed you get.
If you make a serious social error.
You know.
So if you're at a party and you make a
fool of yourself,
you know,
depending on your level of neuroticism,
which is also a big five trait,
that index is how sensitive you are to
negative emotion.
You might obsess about what an idiot you
are for the next three or four months or
maybe even for the next five years.
You know,
people do not like social exclusion.
You know when you have a little counter
that's more or less built into the back
of your brain that roughly,
first of all estimates how successful
you are.
There's an estimation that actually
seems to occur right at birth where when
part of your neuroticism levels are set,
and then that can be modified to some
degree by learning,
you know,
and if you're a talk baboons,
well you're going to experience less
negative emotion and more satisfaction
than you are if you're a bottom baboons.
And it's exactly the same with people.
So,
you know,
we like to be climbing up dominance
hierarchies.
We'd like to be near the top of
dominance hierarchies.
And if the little counter out the back
of your brain notices that you know
you're doing a good job of climbing
towards the top of irrelevant dominance
hierarchy,
then it's going to produce more
serotonin and you're not going to be as
in as much pain,
you're not going to be as depressed,
you're not going to be as anxious,
you're not going to be stressed and so
forth.
So,
so there's a biological basis for our
social being and it's extraordinarily
important to us how we fit into social
groups.
Okay.
So we've also been trying to figure out
what the hell we are,
who we are for thousands and thousands
of years.
Partly as a consequence of invitation,
you know,
because I can act you out and it'll sort
of help me understand what you're like.
And partly as a consequence of
articulated communication loader that
storytelling now people have been
telling stories for.
We have no idea how long.
I mean if you go and visit peoples that
have no written language and who'd been
isolated from the rest of human society
for say,
tens of thousands of years and such
people still exist.
You find that they tell stories,
they danced,
they act each other out,
you know,
so we know certainly that the propensity
to tell stories and to engage in ritual
behavior is far older than our ability
to write.
I suspect you could push it back at
least 50,000
years.
Although I suspect it's a lot older than
that.
And so what's happened is that across
those sorts of timescales,
we've started to tell stories about one
another that represent how we act.
And then you might think,
well,
some of those stories are interesting
and memorable and some of them aren't.
And then we tend to remember the
interesting and memorable ones and pass
them on.
And so you can also imagine human beings
aggregating together in groups of
thousands and thousands of people over
thousands and thousands of years telling
their stories to one another and
hammering those stories into some sort
of mutually acceptable and
comprehensible for.
And so for example,
one example of that is that if you look
at the creation stories,
the creation story that say occurs in
Genesis in the Old Testament,
it's a member of a class of creation
stories that characterized Middle
Eastern mythology and it seems to have
arisen out of the organization,
have separate Middle Eastern tribes
thousands and thousands of years ago,
each with their own traditions into a
relatively homogenous story that
characterized a large group of people,
central beliefs.
So we have information about how we act
from the representations that we've made
of those actions that we passed forward.
And Lot of those take the form of miss
religious stories.
And so part of what we're going to do is
we're going to begin the course with two
foundation establishing themes.
One has to do with the structure of
mythological representations and the
second has to do with a set of rituals
and processes and beliefs that have been
identified more or less worldwide that
have to do with shamonic transformation.
Now,
the title of this course is personality
and its transformations.
And the reason it's titled that way is
because you aren't just who you are.
You're also something that changes all
the time.
You're more like a river than like a
rock.
You're constantly transforming.
The physicist.
Erwin Schrodinger thought that people
were dissipative structures.
It's a very interesting idea.
So a dissipative structure is a
structure that maintains its structural
integrity.
Well,
it's elements transformed completely.
So you know,
when you let the water out of the sake,
you get a whirlpool and the whirlpool is
a fairly stable entity.
But the water that the whirlpool is made
of,
it's constantly changing.
That's a dissipative structures.
Well that's what you're like.
You maintain your form across time,
but your elements are constantly
transforming and people are very,
very transformative creatures.
You know,
we can,
unlike animals,
because animals are sort of what they
are.
And that's it.
I mean they have some capacity learned,
but not very much.
Your typical beaver is acting more like
more or less today.
Like you know,
his great,
great,
great grandfather was acting 5,000
years ago.
There's no real accretion of culture.
Whereas with human beings,
we transformed like mad.
I mean we do that culturally,
things aren't much.
There's so many things,
for example,
that are different now than there were
20 years ago that it's almost impossible
to manage it and then so we transform on
a cultural scale quite rapidly,
but we also do that individually.
I mean,
you guys have all just made the
transition to university.
Just roughly speaking,
you know,
I'm sure that your like you were in some
ways when you were in high school,
but well,
hopefully you're better than you were in
high school.
A whole bunch of ways as well.
You should be more mature,
but your personality may have
transformed substantially.
You know,
and with any luck you're not done with
your sequences of transformations.
You know that's going to be something
that characterizes you for the rest of
your life in so far as you're a dynamic
person,
your eyes are open,
you pay attention,
you and you can learn.
And so one of the things you might say
is that the most stable thing there is
about human personality is its capacity
to transform.
And that's really something that's worth
knowing,
you know,
because one of the things I can tell you
about the great myths of mankind,
there's lots of them and they have
different themes.
One of the most powerful themes is the
way you get yourself out of trouble is
to transform your personality.
Now you think you kind of do that every
time you learn something,
right?
Because you learn something in your
little different than you were before,
hopefully different in a significant way
and hopefully different in a way that
helps you solve some problems that you
couldn't solve before.
So you could say one of the late motifs
of being human is,
well,
if I were to encounter an obstacle,
I can just transform and I can figure
out some way of getting around it.
And that's something that makes us quite
remarkable.
No one.
One of the things that I could suggest
to you and I,
I think this is one of the largest ideas
that exist especially communicable in
this short time,
is that it's much better to identify
with your capacity to transform than it
is to identify with who you are.
Now.
And that can get you out of an awful lot
of trouble.
I mean,
one of the things that characterizes
video logs,
for example,
or people who are trapped in fixed
belief systems is that they worship who
they are now and that'd be all fine if
everything was going 100 percent for
them,
but it's seldom the case.
And so unless your life is perfect and
that seems highly improbable,
maybe if you were someone else,
it would be better.
And you know,
that's all you've got in some sense
because changing the world in some way
that's going to make you feel better
about it.
Well,
you know,
you might be able to do that in some
small way,
but the probability that you could or
should try to do that on large scale is.
It's pretty low.
So.
So in the mythological representation
section,
I'm going to talk to you about the
fundamental elements of narrative.
And the reason that I think that that's
necessary is because there's,
there's sort of two things that you have
to consider when you're talking about
people.
And one is objectively,
what is a person like?
They'll say what you might think about
what a rat is like or maybe even what a
rock is like.
So that's a,
that's a scientific question in some
sense,
but then there's another question which
is,
or maybe two questions.
How do people act and how should they
act?
And maybe the first one is a scientific
question,
but the second one certainly isn't.
And the way that we explore how people
do act and how they should act has a lot
more to do with narrative then it has to
do with science and you know,
you know this,
all you have to do is think about it.
You know,
when you think about where do you get
most of your information about what
people are like when you're not actually
just interacting with some people.
And the answer to that is quite
straightforward.
You read novels,
he read literature,
you go see movies,
you watch a game of thrones,
you've been John,
game of thrones,
you know,
you go watch star wars.
You know,
maybe you line up for three days if
you're completely insane to go see star
wars.
You know,
and you might ask,
well,
what in the world are you doing?
Well,
people are hungry for information about
how people do act and how they should
act and we're absolutely compelled by
narratives and there's a reason for
that.
Well,
and you kind of know what a narrative is
and one isn't right.
Go to a movie and you think are the
character development is pretty good.
But um,
you know,
as a story it was terrible.
And then maybe you talk with your
friends about why it a terrible story.
But the funny thing is you kind of know,
right?
It's like some things are stories and
some things aren't.
And laying out what actually makes
something,
a story that's very difficult,
but you still know it and you can come
to some consensus even,
you know,
if you look on I am deb or rotten
tomatoes,
you know,
people form large group consensus about
what constitutes an acceptable narrative
pretty damn quickly and there seems to
be at least a certain amount of
agreement,
you know,
barring individual differences.
So the mythological and the demonic
discussions that were going to undertake
have a couple of purposes.
One is to provide you with the
foundations of a language that you can
use to understand narrative,
and that's going to prove very,
very useful because most of the clinical
theories that we're going to talk about
are really narrative based and once you
understand their mythological
substructure,
so to speak,
it gives you a framework within which
you can slot the theories,
you know,
because one of the things that's
complicated about personality theory is
that there are a lot of personality
theories and you might think,
well,
how the hell can that be?
Because if it's a theory,
theoretically there can only be one.
There's only one theory of relativity
route.
Roughly speaking,
it's a little fuzzy around the edges,
but people agree on the core elements.
Well with personality theory,
there's,
there is many,
many different personality theories and
so then you might think,
well,
how are you supposed to make any sense
out of that?
Well,
there's two ways.
One is to put all of them into a more
fundamental underlying structure and
that's something that I'm really going
to strive to have you guys do while
you're taking this course and the other
is to actually adopt a slightly
different set of presuppositions about
personality theories and so you could
say,
well,
there's only one theory of relativity,
but then you might say,
well yeah,
there's only one theory of relativity,
but then consider a tool box,
so maybe some of you are relatively
handy and you have a tool box.
What's in the toolbox hammers or a
hammer saws,
wrenches,
pliers,
vice grips,
etc.
You know when you might say,
well,
their tools,
why do you need all those tools?
And the answer is,
well,
you can hammer a nail in with a ranch,
but it'd be a lot better if you could
use a hammer and you can probably bang a
bolt off with a hammer,
but it would be a lot better if you had
a ranch and so then you might think,
well,
if you're trying to do something
complicated and sophisticated,
why not have a bunch of tools?
Now?
We don't generally think of scientific
theories as tools,
although that is what they are above all
else,
their tools and then when we're dealing
with something as complicated as a human
being,
while you know we may need more than one
tool to get to the bottom of it and it's
also the case,
you know that to say understand that
human being.
Well,
that's a complicated thing.
It's guess You might say,
well,
I understand.
To what end you don't mean comprehensive
universal on esc and understanding.
Obviously you mean I want to know x
about someone because I have some desire
in relationship to my interactions with
and so there's all sorts of tools that
can facilitate that.
So what I would say is that no freud's a
microscope and young as a telescope,
that's one way of thinking about it.
I mean,
there's no particular reason I
associated either of those with those
two tools,
but the point is is that if you paid
careful attention to personality
theories,
they can expand your capacity to
represent yourself in ways that's
extremely useful because you should
understand who you are and why and what
implications that has for you because
you're a transformable creature,
but you also have a fairly stable
underlying sub structure,
right?
Otherwise you just melt like an octopus,
so you're this weird dynamic combination
of relatively permanent structure and
then embedded capacity to transform.
you have a nature and so understanding
your nature is extraordinarily youth
worthwhile and so hopefully what we're
going to do during this course is give
you a whole bunch of tools to understand
yourself and other people with tools
that will really be useful.
Things you can use day to day to
understand yourselves and your families
and so on and to improve your future
with any luck.
And then also cover
the elements of you that are stable.
Most of which I would say have been
discovered,
at least in the more objective sense by
biological psychologists.
So mostly animal researches peculiarly
enough.
Okay,
so mythological representations.
We're going to take a trip back through
time.
We're going to look at our kick and
ancient stories of mankind told by
members of our species to each other,
and I'm going to concentrate on stories
that have lasted.
We don't know how long we have stories
that in the written form or 4,000
years old,
but all the evidence suggests that those
stories are based on traditions that go
back far,
far beyond that,
at least 50,000
years and maybe way before that.
So we'll take a look at those and now
it'll give us a foundation that we can
use to build on.
And then we're going to look at shamonic
rituals and descriptions to get some
sense of the archetype of
transformation,
which sort of means,
well,
what is it that you have to undergo when
you're changing and what are you likely
to experience when that happens?
Now I cAn give you a bit of a preview.
It's not always the case.
Maybe it's seldom the case that if you
learned something important that it's,
you know,
this happens to people all the time,
so maybe I don't know.
Maybe you had a recent relationship that
went seriously sour and you know,
maybe it was because you were going out
with a jerk or maybe it's because you're
just not very sophisticated and no doubt
you're trying to figure out which of
those happens to be true.
Well you're,
you know,
considering the relationship,
but generally what happens to people
when they're moving towards something
and the bottom falls out because
something occurs that they didn't
understand and couldn't predict.
Maybe in their own behavior.
Maybe you had an affair while you were
in your relationship and you didn't
expect that.
while what happens is that your current
model of yourself and perhaps even if
the world is demonstrated as
insufficient,
not rattles,
you are badly and then you're rattled up
for some good length of time.
Not very motivated,
somewhat depressed,
fairly anxious.
You sort of fell apart.
You don't know which way is up and then
maybe if you're lucky you think about it
and talk about it and put yourself back
together and when you come out the other
side,
you're a little smarter and a little
more together than you were to begin
with.
Now,
if you're unlucky,
you just stay in the little pit for
people can stay in the little pit for a
very,
very long time and that's not so good
and so you know the process of
transformation is actually quite
dangerous because it doesn't necessarily
have to be completed in a successful
manner,
but it does have a pattern.
The pattern usually is you think you
know what you're doing and then
something happens to demonstrate that
you actually don't know what you're
doing and that puts you in a spin and
then through careful analysis and
support and discussion and other
processes that we don't really
understand very well.
You come to incorporate the anomalous
knowledge,
knocked you on your back.
You reconstruct your personality and
your representations of the world and
then you move ahead hopefully more than
you were before.
But it's an interesting thing to know,
you know,
one of the things nature said again was
that you could,
you could tell the character of a human
being by how much truth there willing to
tolerate.
Now that's an interesting phrase because
you generally think of people because
they're optimistic.
They generally think of truth as
something positive.
Obviously it's better to know the truth.
It's like no if you pulled the wool over
your eyes as a general rule,
learning the truth is not a pleasant
experience.
That doesn't necessarily mean that it's
not something you should do,
but the idea that the path to
enlightenment is blissful.
A,
that's not a very smart idea.
In fact,
it's quite the opposite.
So the shamanic rituals basically
manifest that's in an architectural way.
So one of the things you see happening
with the typicals,
the sharman,
by the way,
shamanism is a worldwide phenomenon.
It seems to be associated with a
primordial or archaic psychology of
transformation.
It's often drug aided and generally what
happens is that a shamonic
transformation is accompanied by a
descent into something approximating
psychological death and then a
rebuilding and a rebirth that puts the
person out on the other side.
It's like an initiation ritual and
that's another way of thinking about it
or you might think about it as the
depression that possessed you during
your first semester of university,
which either
knock you out of the university
altogether because that happens to a lot
of people are which you recovered from
and finally became a university student.
Although perhaps that wasn't a
particularly pleasant transition.
You know,
we've done some testing with u of t
students and it's interesting to note
that about a third of you meet criteria
for clinical depression your first year
here.
Now,
what that indicates to me is that the
criteria for clinical depression,
our little on the sensitive side,
but,
but regardless,
because if a third of people meet the
criteria,
thank yeah,
well that's a little sensitive,
but by the same token,
you know,
it's not an easy adjustment and the old
you has to die and generally that's not
very pleasant,
so and it's a good way to think about
the impediments to learning because you
hardly ever learned something without
having part of you dies first and that's
part of the reason that people are
rather resistant to learning anything
new.
That's important.
Okay,
well,
so you've got that.
Now after that we're going to talk about
piaget and piaget isn't necessarily
known as a personality psychologist,
but that's okay.
Psj published a developmental
psychologist,
maybe the greatest developmental
psychologists.
he published a very large number of
books,
many of which haven't even been
translated yet,
some of which haven't even been
published yet.
So piaget thought a lot of things about
a lot of things and he's generally known
for his stage theory of development,
but he really wasn't all that into that
stage theory.
It just seemed to be the part of this
theory that I would say rather dimwitted
western intellectuals could grasp onto
most easily and so that's generally what
you hear about,
but piaget was a very,
very sophisticated thinker and one of
the things he was interested in was,
well,
he was interested in how the child,
in some sense boots itself up.
That's a reasonable way of thinking
about it because you know when you turn
on a computer,
what happens is a certain number of
primitive functions,
primitive fundamental functions come
online first and then those functions
enable more complex functions to emerge
and then those functions may enable more
complex functions to emerge and soon
there your computer is waiting for you
and human beings are kind of like that.
So when we're first born were very
primitive.
When we're first born were very
immature.
That's a better way of thinking about
it.
We're not precisely primitive.
We still have very large brains and
there are more connections in those
brains.
Birth and there were any that there will
be for the rest of your life,
which is quite interesting.
You actually dye into your personality
because what happens isn't so much that
you make new connections instead a whole
bunch of the ones you already have that
you don't use disappeared,
so that's pretty peculiar anyways.
When you first born,
there's not a lot to you in terms of
capacity to engage with the world.
Your mouth is pretty wired up.
Your lips and your tongue,
which is a good thing because you have
to breastfeed and that's actually not
very simple.
You have to have a clue to do that and
it's the first complex social
interaction you're likely to engage in.
So you.
You're born with a fair bit of a
priority.
Sophisticated wiring already in place,
but the rest of you,
man,
it's not there much at all.
You can't control your arms.
You know,
if you watch a baby in a crib,
a young baby and it's not swaddled up,
you know,
their arms sort of float around in space
and so to their legs and now and then
they might get themselves and generally
that seems to come as quite a shock to
the baby.
It's not.
It's peripheral nervous system.
The peripheral elements of its central
nervous system are not well developed at
birth,
and so it's almost as if the baby has to
discover its limbs.
It sort of expands from the middle
outwards,
it has to discover its limbs and then
start to figure out what to do with
them,
and so what piaget attempted to do was
to lay out the processes by which a
child unfolded into the world.
Now,
some there's a biological basis to that
because you come into the world at birth
with a set of reflexes at hand,
and those reflexes are enough to get you
started.
And so piaget,
here's one way of trying to understand
piaget.
I like it quite a bit.
It's a bit of an over simplification,
but it'll do.
There's lots of different ways of
thinking about what the world is made
up.
Now you know if you're a classically,
if you're a classical scientists,
you tend to think that the world is made
out of matter.
Matter is made out of atoms,
and then atoms are made out of god only
knows what atoms are made out of,
right?
Because by the time you get uNder adams,
you just have no idea what's going on
down there,
but you know,
we generally don't think about that too
much and we sort of assume newtonian
reality and that everything is made out
of hard little particles like dust and
that's the scientific one.
But there's other ways of looking at the
world that are not only equally valid
but equally necessary and equally
powerful.
And one of them is that you could look
at the world as a matrix of information
you know,
and so inflammation generally has
significance and meaning or at least in
so far as the information is
conceptualized by human beings.
And so for example,
if you're two years old and you're
crawling around on the floor and the dog
has a bone and you grab it and the dog
nips you,
that's informative.
And so what piaget claims is that
children come into the world with an
information seeking structure and that
as they interact with the world,
phenomena emerge that they can model
with their bodies.
So for example,
if I'm going to drink this,
then I'd have to model it with my hand
before I can do so and so it turns out,
for example,
that wouldn't.
If this thing sitting here,
especially if I'm thirsty and I look at
it,
my eyes tell them my hands to get ready
to grab it.
And so when you say you understand
something,
what you mean is that at least part of
what you mean is that when you perceive
it,
it maps itself onto your body.
And so this happens at pretty low levels
of your nervous system.
So for example,
there are people who are blind.
They say they're blind,
they can't see anything.
But if you move your hands up like this
and you ask them to guess which hand
you're lifting,
they can do it with almost 100 percent
accuracy.
And you think,
well,
how the hell can that possibly be?
They Were blind.
Well,
the reason that happens is because your
eyes are detecting patterns in the
world.
Some of those patterns you perceive as
conscious reality,
but other patterns you just mapped right
onto your spine or or onto your
emotional system doesn't.
You don't need the perception of the
object in order to have that activated
because you know you probably fade.
There's the world,
you see it,
you think about it,
you evaluate it,
and then you act.
It's like that isn't how it works.
It's very seldomly how it works.
Partly because it's just too damn slow.
You know?
If you had to think about everything,
you'd be running over pedestrians
nonstop,
right?
You have to be able to react very,
very quickly and part of the way you do
that is by having your sensory systems
map right onto your motor output
systems.
So,
so piaget,
well,
for piaget,
part of the way that the personality
emerges out of the doldrums of infancy
is that the child encounters the world
and incorporates the information that
they gather as a consequence of bumping
up against it and then they build
themselves in some sense from their
bodies and the ability,
the abilities that they're practicing
with their bodies,
like the gripping mechanism.
And the pointing mechanism and the
scratching mechanism and all those
things that they can build,
they build those up to the point where
they can start to use abstractions and
so the baby sort of spirals out of
nowhere using it's exploratory capacity,
absorbing information from the world and
creates its personality that way.
So lovely marlin.
We'll cover that in some detail.
The depths psychologists,
I concentrate primarily on young and
freud and you know,
if you take a personality course,
generally you'll,
you'll be introduced to freud first and
then you'll be introduced to yoga and
maybe I'd learned some of the neil
friday ends more or less as
afterthoughts to freud,
but I don't really think that's
appropriate.
First of all,
I think you can make a strong case that
you was that the utility of [inaudible]
theory is particularly evident when
you're talking about radical
similarities between people.
So young was very biologically oriented
in some ways.
he was way ahead of biological
psychiatrists and psychologists because
when young was beginning to formulate
his theories in the west,
in,
in north America anyways,
in the United States,
most of the people who were studying
human beings were behaviorists and
behaviors basically presumed that you
are a blank slate at birth and that you
learned how to do everything that you
know how to do.
Well,
that's not true at all.
Um,
first of all,
you can't learn everything that you know
how to do because you have to know
something to start the whole process
off.
And second,
you know,
you don't have to learn really to
understand what a dog's grown means.
You know,
it's kind of wired into you and you
already don't have to learn to be afraid
of the dark man.
You've got that down by the time you
were about three,
you know.
so there's lots of things that are built
right into people and what exactly that
means,
we're not sure about.
I mean it does.
Look,
for example,
like snake phobia is,
is innate.
And even if the actual phobia isn't an
eight,
and it probably is,
you can learn to be phobic of snakes in
no time flat.
whereas like trying to become phobic of
pistols is very,
very difficult.
Now,
young was very interested in the,
I think what the best way to think about
it is the substrata of human cognition.
You know,
because human beings are a particular
type of thing.
It's not like our,
our souls are disconnected from our
bodies and that our knowledge is somehow
appropriate or universal in some way
that would make sense if we didn't have
bodies.
We're not down at all.
We're in our bodies.
Our brains are adapted to our bodies.
Our minds are adapted to our bodies and
so as our knowledge.
And that means that our cognitive
abilities are theories of the world,
have biological substructures,
and those are preset positions in some
sense for our knowledge that we don't
have to learn.
So for example,
you don't really have to learn that
being punched hers.
You just discover that you don't really
have to learn what a smile means.
You don't really have to learn what
anger means.
You'll experience it so it's right in
you.
It's you like little kids,
little babies.
When they're crying,
they're often angry.
So for example,
by nine months of age,
a baby can more or less identified its
mother.
So someone walks into the baby's room
and takes a look at the baby and it's
not the baby's mother and the baby
starts crying and you think,
oh baby.
It's like,
fair enough.
That baby is not sad.
That baby is angry and you can tell if
you look at the baby because it's
turning all red.
And that's what people do when they cry,
when they're angry.
And so it's a good thing to know when
you're arguing with someone and they get
upset,
maybe they start to cry.
You think,
whoa,
the poor person,
but then if you look,
you'll see that they're all red and that
means they'd like to strangle you,
but they're,
you know,
they're social niceties is hopefully
preventing them.
So that can certainly change your
attitude towards whether or not you
should be feeling sorry for them when
you hurt their feelings.
So,
so there's all sorts of things that are
universal about human beings and what
yoga was very,
very interested in what those universals
are and how they played out in patterns
of behavior.
So you can imagine,
you can imagine that you have an
instinct say like anger and thinking
about that way.
He's like a cross section that person's
angry,
you know,
and you can imagine a facial
configuration that would go along with
that,
but in a more sophisticated way if you
want it to represent anger,
maybe you've represented like a drama,
like a story you know began.
that's actually what you want to know.
If someone gets angry,
what happened?
Well,
imagine that you took a thousand stories
about angry people and you blow them all
into one story so that everything that
was common about all the stories about
anger were encapsulated in a single
story.
Well that would be the archetypal story
of anger and everyone would recognize it
because it's like anger represented like
a movie in some sense in its purest
form.
Well,
that's an archetype and that's the sort
of thing that was extraordinarily
interested in understanding a document.
And it's a tremendous amount of fun.
So one of the things we'll do is I'm
going to show you some movies,
probably the lion king,
at least parts of it,
and I'm going to show you how the
archetypal structure manifests itself
and that's really worth knowing.
It's kind of a pain because then from
now on you go to movies and you think,
oh well no,
that's that archetipal structured and
that's what that symbol means and you'll
really be annoying to your friends.
But it's very entertaining and it's very
illuminating.
And partly because what's really cool
about these archetypal story structures
is that not only they do,
they tell you who you are,
but they tell you in some sense who you
should be.
Now that's cool because one of the
things that modern people have a real
problem with is trying to understand
whether or not life has any meaning.
You know,
we look at the world from a scientific
perspective and we say,
well,
it appears that all of this is,
you know,
without meaning,
it doesn't mean anything in any cosmic
sense.
It's,
it's a pretty dopey conclusion as far as
I'm concerned because the originators of
the scientific method excluded
subjective meaning from the doctrine at
the outset.
So you know,
if you look at the world scientifically
and you saying,
well,
it's without subjective meaning.
It's like,
well,
yeah,
obviously because science was set up so
that all the subjective meaning would be
stripped away from the phenomena.
So you knoW,
it's not something to be really shocked
about afterwards.
And it also doesn't mean that there's no
such thing as subjective.
Meaning it just means that it's very
difficult to get a grip on it from a
purely scientific perspective.
And one of the lovely things about
architectural stories is they tell you
in a way that's universally believable
who you are and,
and that's very cool and you know,
because you think you can learn this in
university too,
and it just tears me up.
You know,
you learn implicitly or explicitly and
almost all of the fields of study that
you're going to undertake,
especially on the humanities and that
moral morality is relative and that
there's no ultimate meaning,
which is a really rotten thing to be
teaching people of your age.
You don't because you're too damn young
to be nIhilistic.
You know you can meet our listing when
you're 85,
you're,
you're all done by then,
but to be nihilistic now that's a bloody
catastrophe.
You know,
when it's completely pointless because
the notion of the notion that things are
meaningless in some ultimate sense.
It's a,
it's an extraordinarily primitive
philosophical theory and it does not
serve people well.
It makes them sick.
And so one of the things that you might
consider that is that if you're stupid
theory makes you sick,
maybe there's something wrong with it.
It might be a criteria for the utility
or perhaps even the truth of the theory,
you know,
depends how you think about these
things.
You know,
you might say,
well,
If a truth makes you sick,
that doesn't mean it's any less than the
truth.
Well,
maybe,
maybe it really does mean that it's
much,
much less of a truth.
It depends to some degree on what you
mean by truth.
So anyways,
[inaudible] very,
very,
very useful for that.
He's at terrifying thinker really.
Like I read when I was about 23 or 24,
I spent two years in.
I read preTty much everything.
You wrote about 23 volumes and it just
blew me into bits.
I had no idea what the hell was going on
in my dreams changed.
And really it was really,
really rough.
I was reading nietzsche at the same time
and he's just about as bad,
like nature setting philosophize with a
hammer,
you know,
and that's great unless he's taking a
hammer to your skull and that's not
nearly so pleasant.
So you know,
young,
he's,
he's a completely different sort of
creature and I think that's part of the
reason you never really learned about
them in the university.
You know,
if you don't understand,
to me it looks weird and if you do
understand them a little bit,
he's terrifying and you're bloody well
going to stop.
You'll think,
oh no,
that's okay.
I don't really need to know that.
So freud,
freud tonight,
nice whipping boy for psychologists,
which I also think is pretty pathetic
because it's in great,
ungrateful to begin with.
You know,
freud was really the person who
formalize the idea of done unconscious,
you know,
now everyone takes that for granted that
there's the cognitive unconscious.
That's what the psychologist discovered
in what the 19 eighties.
There's a cognitive unconscious.
It's like,
yeah,
good work guys.
They'd figured that out back in 1910,
you know,
but you don't see the credit being given
to freud for making that sort of
discovery.
If you look at experimental psychology,
which I think,
like I said,
I think that's really ungrateful for
it's a strange guy and you know,
you can take issue with especially the
details of his theory,
you know,
like the eatable complex for example,
or penis envy,
those sorts of things.
It's like,
nO,
in some ways they seem laughably
anachronistic,
but you know,
sometimes someone can be wrong in the
details and right in the overall
conception because theories are
multilayered things,
right?
So sometimes I read a student essay,
you know,
and the sentences are just awful.
This person like our god only knows
where they learned to write probably in
a high school somewhere and you know
It's incomprehensible.
But if you read the whole thing and you
think,
man,
there's an idea in here,
you know,
the person is smarter than their ability
to write and so then you can write,
you can say,
look,
you can't write worth a damn,
but you know,
you're pretty smart and you've got some
ideas here that if you could articulate,
might be a really high quality so you
can be wrong in the details and right in
the overall picture.
And freud was like that all the time.
And freud was also unbeatable in
relationship to familial pathology.
So from [inaudible] perspective,
the fundamental task of the emerging
human being was to extricate themselves
from their family.
Now you might think,
well why is that such a problem?
Well,
here's a couple of reasons.
First,
your parents take care of you.
So it was like maybe you don't want to
dispense with that too early,
especially if they really,
really take care of you and that's the
whole situation from the freudian
perspective,
it's like the atypical situation arises
when you have a parent or two parents
who do so much for you that you're no
longer able to do anything for yourself
and that is not a good situation.
It's extraordinarily pathological and
there is nobody like freud who lays out
the detaIls of that pathology and we're
gonna watch a movie from it's called,
which is very disturbing movie,
which I suppose is a trigger warning for
those of you who think you need trigger
warnings.
Um,
it's a very,
very distressing documentary,
but it will show you freddy and
psychopathology that like,
you've never seen it unless you happen
to live in a thoroughly eat whole
family.
All right,
so look,
I didn't get through the whole outline.
I'll tell you very briefly what you're
going to be required to do and then
we'll continue this in the next lecture.
So just three exams,
two midterms and a final.
There are multiple choice.
Okay.
I'll post some of the questions before
the exam so that you know what you're
getting into.
I don't think they're particularly
difficult.
Some of you will beg to differ.
Um,
there's pressure on us this year to
curve the grade,
so beware.
I may have to do that.
Okay.
Just in,
you need to know that,
um,
you have to write an essay,
750 words.
that's not a very long essay,
but that makes it actually more
difficult.
The signup for the topics for the essay
or on the website or you can just go
there and sign up.
There's 20 different topics and there's
15 slots for each topic.
So I would recommend that you do that
quite quickly.
You have to do a personality self
analysis,
seven point five percent of your grade.
The link to that is online too.
You can get started on that whenever you
want.
Um,
your ta.
One of them,
that's christine brophy.
She's over there in the corner of
patiently waiting for me to introduce
her.
she has office hours.
they're posted online.
You can sign up for her office hours
online.
You can also sign up for my office hours
online,
so.
Well,
that's halfway through what the course
is going to be about.
So we'll see you on thursday.