Now,
where you're at now is a very interesting
situation because John is in exile.
No one knows what's going to happen
in terms of how long it's going to be
suspended. DC is now fighting Steve Bay
Meo chicks for the heavyweight title.
And who knows what's happening there.
I mean that,
does that bother you because it seems
like it Kinda like puts the two oh five
title in limbo. It does. It does. Oh,
I didn't see that coming at all. This is
typified at all. You know, it's a, it's a,
it's a great fight for, for them
and for the financing for the sport.
But you know, for us standing,
standing in line, we just, you know,
we just sitting there on our, on our,
we just sitting there and waiting for,
for an opportunity and it's not going
to come. It's not going to be there. So,
you know, and, and, and uh, you know,
that that's also a thing that had
been motivated me a lot because
often if I were glove,
I got engine and,
and all that and I was really looking
forward to come back and, and, and make,
make it really strong,
uh, performing, you know,
very strong next performance.
I just really wanted to,
I had my eyes on that goal
and, and uh, and then they met,
I actually counted almost, you
know, fighting DC, but then,
then it was all gone by him going
up the step. And so, so it's,
it's a crisis situation. The
whole division is, is you
just crazy right now? Yeah,
it really is because that fight is not
even going to take place until July.
So here we are in April, May, June, July,
we have three months till
that fight takes place.
So that fight and then
obviously it least three months,
most likely more before the title
could be challenged again. So that's,
we don't even know if it's
coming, if it comes back. Right.
He might notice what happens in that
fight unless once he gets used to eating
again, like, you know, it's to be
tough on you see wins. I see, I see.
I see it in pictures. You know, I'm
going to meet him a couple of days.
It looks a little bit, you
know, heavy right now. Well,
he was a on TV the other day eating
potato chips and you're in a cab.
No, I loved that. Yeah. He loves food,
that's for sure. I mean, and uh, I,
you know, you look back at his performance
in strike force as a heavyweight.
It was phenomenal. Good, good,
phenomenal. If you didn't lose,
I didn't lose that heavyweight and he's
good tossed around gorillas like Josh
Barnett lift him up. Like nothing
crazy. This fight against TTIP.
It's, uh, you know, if it will be another,
I guess another heavyweight, I'd probably
60 people. It's going to win this fight.
But do you see, it's like you said,
he's, he's a really good heavyweight, so,
and those, what happens? Well, his
wrestling is just so next level. Yeah.
It's such a, it's an interesting position
because Steve Basie, very good wrestler,
but of course DC's worldclass hey,
it's world class and he,
he doesn't take one step back.
May just comes out been,
and he's just in your face.
And it's tough to count out Steve Bay too,
because Steve Bay's though pound for
pound consensus. Best heavy weight ever.
I mean, the guy is defend the title more
than anybody. You look at his resume,
it's impeccable.
You Max out a junior dos Santos nax
out Overeem of beats Francis in Ghana,
who was everybody's scared of.
I mean, he's a bad ass. Yeah.
So you know, but the seats, he such a
competitive guy, you know, he, he does,
he doesn't want, he doesn't take a
step back and he just goes for it.
Even if even in a tough situation,
he's just,
he just eats it and comes
back and do what to do always.
And therefore for being a fat guy
that gets books, he's screaming at
you right now. Hey man, settle down.
But that guy is, he's doing
fire rounds like nothing. Yeah.
So the creek nation in is on top. Yeah.
He just eats the wrong food. Yeah.
That's awesome. Yeah. I mean, I
mean, maybe some of it's genetic.
I just think it has eaten the wrong
food. I mean, this evidence. Sure.
Chips. Yeah. I mean, there was evidence.
It's not like I'm just
talking out of my ass.
I've seen him eat the wrong
food at me too. Yeah. But yeah,
nothing but respect for that guy. He's an
awesome human being to you see is just,
he's a fantastic guy. Have you ever
thought about fighting heavyweight?
It crossed my mind from time to time,
but I feel I'm, I'm, I'm not done with,
and I'm not done in light heavyweight yet.
I have still things to do.