So I think it'd be fair to point out,
you know, like youtube criticism too,
because in talking about censorship,
I think a lot of people
immediately assumed I'd come
on here and start waving my
arms and they're screaming,
they're biased against conservatives,
which I think 27 I kind of did. But
Youtube is, is, is, is a bit different.
Youtube does,
it has demonetized LGBT content and
Youtube has said that these topics are not
suitable for all advertisers
because it deals with sexuality.
They have target many left wing channels,
there are a lot of non mainstream
left wing, you know, outlets.
And when you say target,
which means D monetize demonetize
the war sometimes outright ban.
And I think then for d monetizing, I think
they've made a state what was the, uh,
the policy there. It's essentially
things that are political correct.
If they made that statement, I have
to run another thing I was gonna say,
I was going to interject that
they've also been, are not banned,
but do monetize people are extensively
people that smoke weed on their channel.
Yeah, totally. Actually certain video game
channels that have for unknown reasons,
just stopped having
monetization on their channel.
And that is the problem of ultimately
them having this incredible power where
they, they really, there's no,
there's not real open competition
in terms of like another,
like a parallel competitor.
I don't think there will be real but,
but here's the thing, I, I think you
took out a bunch of really bad things.
I'm going to give a a very important
shout out to Monkey Jones who was wrongly
terminated from youtube for highly
dubious reasons. He is a dark, dark,
dark comic.
He had hundreds of thousands of followers.
He made jokes about things like
school shootings, very dark stuff,
but it was clearly mocking some of these
people. He was mocking Elliot Roger,
he was making jokes about it and in fact,
some of his videos were approved
manually for monetization,
but for some reason youtube just
wiped them out one day gone.
So I set up a new channel and said, okay,
you know, we're not gonna do that anyway.
It doesn't matter. They got rid of
him, he's effectively off of Youtube.
And he was like, he's a well known,
funny guy. He wasn't breaking the rules,
he wasn't, but they still
deleted, deleted this channel.
So I bring him up because I
think it's worrisome that yes,
without an alternative, you're career is
wiped out in a second with no recourse.
And no reason why. And the response they
give you is, it's our platform. Yeah.
And you'll hear people say, oh,
but there are private business.
They can do what they want.
Sure. But they're a monopoly.
We've got to have restrictions on that.