At gap between the
understanding that you have,
the understanding that
the average person has,
and this could be a real problem
and trying to expand this platform.
Well, we have to, to inform
you. I gotta tell you though,
when I say this to people,
they're like, that makes perfect.
So that does make perfect sense.
That's scary about it. When I'm not,
I'm not disagreeing with you in any way,
shape, or form. I'm, I'm just thinking,
man, for young kids or young kids and,
you know, you're a parent. I'm a parent.
But what, so our education system, um,
has a lot to be desired. And one of
the things I'm saying is like, uh,
is it's making all these kids think that
college is the end all be all and it is
not. And so that's one issue is that, uh,
we need to try and prepare kids for
different kinds of paths instead of saying
college, College, college,
because they're going to college,
they're getting loaded up
with record levels of debt.
College has gone two and a
half times more expensive,
even though it has not gone two
and a half times better. Uh,
and the reason why it's gotten so
expensive is because they've just gotten
really bloated administratively. And what
would you do about that? Like you know,
Bernie Sanders wants to
have some sort of a um,
free college free university. Yeah.
The, he wants to do it across the board,
have education to be 100%
free something. I mean, look,
I love that on paper.
I,
one of the things that I hate is talking
to my friends about college debt.
You know, friends that are in
their thirties and forties.
Is this following them
around? Yeah, it just,
it just stays with them like a wet
blanket that you can never get out of.
I used to call my school loans,
my mistress,
cause I was writing a check
to like another family and
another town. I was like,
I hope they're enjoying themselves.
So it's like I was I think
like $900 above to buy loans.
And what's crazy is that if something
devastating happens to you and any other
form you can file for bankruptcy,
but you never escape your student
loans no matter what happens to you.
That was just some lobbying on the part
of the, the financial companies. Man,
there's lots of other crap out of it
and it's dirty. That's really dirty.
When you think about how many people that
run corporations that have racked up,
I mean, just think about what happened
with the savings and loan crisis.
Just completely man. And
those guys skated. Woo. Yeah.
The vast majority have.
They're carrying around zero,
zero burden from that vast majority.
No one went to jail,
set up a few people and it really anybody,
no real criminals.
Like Bernie Madoff went to jail.
You know, a few people went to jail,
but that's about it.
You know,
you'd have to be a real fucking thief to
go to jail. And these people that just,
they did this and got away with it and,
and profited and redistributed all this
money into their own personal accounts
and,
and stop the whole economy sideways.
But heaven forbid you would take out a
bunch of school loans and then things go
south. Like you can't
get out of it. I mean,
I know a guy who's in his fifties who's
an ophthalmologist who's a deeply in
debt still. So easy. Yeah it is crazy.
And if you look at it just economically,
it's a massive burden on
people starting businesses,
starting families,
buying homes with their parents.
It's possible to fix for sure.
So the first thing you do is you go to
the people that are currently in a debt
and say, look, we're going to give you a
path out and there are ways to do it. Uh,
you know,
you can have a payment plan.
One of the things I'm proposing is like
a 10 by 10 where if you commit 10% of
your wages for 10 years
and you're debt free,
and that means like if you're not making
a lot of money then you can save a
whole lot. And the schools at this point
have long since forgotten about this,
these loans,
cause they got paid off already.
This is just these financial
companies that are holding the loans.
So it's important for people to
understand because people think, well,
if you don't pay them in, the
colleges are going to go away. No, no.
So if you're the government, you
can be like, Hey, loan loan company.
Guess what good news went to like,
take this off.
It's a stimulus because like you said,
we've done a lot of things that
we're supposed to be a stimulus,
like give $4 trillion in the bank and
be like, that'll stimulate the economy.
Nothing's going to stimulate the economy
better than getting student loans off
the backs of freaking young people
because they'll actually do what they're
supposed to do, which is I actually
spend money, the economy, take chances,
take chances, and start businesses.
And the rest of it, I mean,
one of the reasons why our business
formation rates are at multi decade lows,
that we are up to one point
$5 trillion in school debt.
It's like 38 k ahead. That was like
a hundred billion in like 1999.
So we've like gone up 15 x, uh,
since then and it's crippling us.
It's like insane. Anyone who thinks
that that's not burdening the economy.
I mean he's got so, so president Yang
will be like, hey guys, it's a stimulus,
but this time is a stimulus that people
were going to forgive some of the
student loan debt because half that stuff
was generated. They're morally anyway.
A lot of it was just schools you know,
lying about just to
get people in the door.
The second thing you do is you go
to the schools and say, hey guys,
why are you two and a half times
more expensive than you used to be?
That's kind of weird cause
like as far as I can tell,
there's been no massive quality change
and the reason is that they've hired a
lot of administrators. It has not gone to
faculty. It has knock on the facilities.
It has gone to just administrative
access and bloat and then say, okay,
you can do whatever you want,
but if you want access to federal loans,
which they all rely upon for their
life's blood, like without it, they die.
If you want your students
have access to federal loans,
you have to bring your administrator to
student ratio in line with what it was
like in the 1990s and then the
schools would scream bloody murder.
They'd be like, I can't do that.
That's impossible. And you'd be like,
well I have a feeling you're going
to figure it out that they went,
they would start bringing it down and
you would realize it doesn't impact the
student experience at all.
Like I and I understand it cause I've
run a large nonprofit organization that
had started and you're very natural
tendency is just to hire excellent people.
And then before you know it, you're like,
have excellent people like you know,
vice deans of everything.
But then over time that ends up building
a very large cost structure, uh,
that gets passed along to the public.
So you'd bring the costs down.
Now you'd said before,
Bernie is like free college for everyone.
The problem with that solution is
it pretended that college solves the
employment problems of young people.
And anyone who's coming out of
college knows that that's not real.
The underemployment rate for recent
college graduates today is 44% so you had
like a 50 50 shot. If you come out
of college, you're doing a job.
It doesn't really require a degree and
94% of new jobs created right now our gig
temporary or contract or jobs that don't
have real paths forward or health care
benefits of the rest of it.
Yeah. I was reading something about, um,
people actually it might've been in that,
uh,
book that it was just telling you about
Yuval Noah Harari. Yeah. 21st century.
Yeah. It was, I would say that guy's
name wrong. It's a tricky name.
You evolve. Noah Herati yeah.
21 lessons for 21st century.
I think he was talking about how many
people plan on not being in the same job
in 10 years because that job won't
exist anymore versus what it used to be.
It used to be that people would think
that they were going to get a job and they
would stay with a job. Yeah, I know.
And now they're planning that
they're going to have to move,
that they're not going to be able to keep
the same job and has automation kicks
in.
This is obviously going to bottleneck.
It's going to get even it's
going to give him worse. Yeah,
completely. So the ideal is that you end
up training young people to be really,
really adaptable and have low cost
structures and just be able to, you know,
become entrepreneurs.
And I spent seven years trying to
train young people to do just that.
But one of the things I've discovered is
that we're overemphasizing college and
what were under emphasizing his technical
vocational and apprenticeship work.
Because a lot of that work believer now,
it's actually really hard to automate.
Like uh,
you know,
we're not going to automate
an air conditioning repair
person or plumber anytime
soon.
And for sure craftsman,
people who build things and is good for
your mental health and a bunch of other
things.
So right now,
only 6% of American high school students
are in technical or vocational training
in Germany. That's 59%. Give
you a sense of what the,
the gap can be to what we're doing is
we're overprescribing college were saying
college, College, college for everyone.
It's not really working that well.
And then we're still treating people who
are working in trades and everything as
somehow uh,
you know,
like not in great careers when a lot
of those careers are actually really
awesome and they pay great and that
people enjoy them. They're persistent.
So right now we're going to automate away.
It's a lot easier to automate away a lot
of repetitive cognitive work than it is
a non repetitive manual work
because like actual robot digits,
you know,
it's like if you can imagine what it
would take to have a robot plumber like
come into your house. I mean that
stuff's really, really tricky.
There's a lot of fine motor work.
They have to like unscrew pipes and
like stuff that stuff's not going to get
automated for a long time.
You know what is going to get automated?
A lot of like entry level cognitive
tasks because a lot of journalism tasks,
a lot of bookkeeping,
a lot of stuff that college graduates
think they're going to get a job in and
then those jobs are going to disappear.
I was a corporate attorney for those
five unhappy months and my friends are
working on uh, AI. They can automate
away a lot of basic legal work,
you know, so these colleges, these
college grads are like, Oh snap,
don't know what to do man.
I'll go to law school.
Didn't like load up with another
hundred 20 k in debt and then like the,
the legal jobs,
they're not going to be there for him.
It's often the problem of the parents
giving them pressure to go into college as
well because they didn't want the kid
to become a loser. And if the kid,
you know like where I grew up in Boston,
if you went into the trades,
if you abandoned like the
idea of higher learning,
going to college and just went right
into like learning to be a carpenter or
something like that, people look at
you like, ah, you sold yourself short.
But there's so many people that I
know that went to school that just got
university degrees and then they got
out and they were fucked. I mean it's,
it's so common.
It's so common that they thought that
there was going to be this path and this
path to sit and exist. Once they
got out or it was, it was far,
far more difficult than it was then.
They were led to believe.
Yeah.
If you look at it,
about 32% of Americans graduated from
college right now and that level has been
more or less constant for a
long time. It's not like, Hey,
I've got another 20% I
could get into college.
Like right now the college
completion rate in six years,
about 59% so like four out of 10 people
who start college are not graduating in
six years and a lot of them are
just not going to finish ever.
So like other the people that
have other pads available,
then we have to build those pads up and
this is one reason why I'm so into the
freedom dividend instead of something
like free college cause why would you
subsidize something that only the top
third of the population is going to use?
You know, an end. It's a highly
inefficient costly system anyway.
Like counting money into that.
You're much better off putting a thousand
bucks a month into every 18 year olds
hands. Didn't they go to college?
Great colleges partially paid for it.
They go to trade school,
great trade schools partially paid for.
They start their own business.
They do something creative like
they want to do something to help.
That's great too.
Like you can actually start building
more varied paths and make it so that
people don't feel like I need to get
into this institution or else my life's
going to be over.