No. Well, yeah, it's not the experience
for everyone and it's not really,
I don't think it's what
everyone wants either.
Sometimes people just like to go
on there and talk shit. I mean,
as someone that's trapped
in a cubicle right now,
it's true and they just want to go on
there and get in arguments about gun
control or you know, whether or not
Nancy Pelosi's the devil, I mean this is,
this is what you know, it,
it serves a purpose for them.
The thing that gets strange
though is who's to decide,
you know,
there's this is this concept,
there's a discussion I should say where,
uh,
some people believe that things like
Twitter or Facebook or any forum where
you're having a public discussion should
be considered almost like a public
utility. Like anyone has
access to the electric power.
Even if you're, you know,
even if you're a racist,
you still can get electricity and some
people think that you should have that
same ability with something like Twitter
or the same ability with something like
Instagram.
Obviously this is,
we're in uncharted territory and you are,
you are in uncharted territory. It just,
no one has been there before.
So who makes the distinctions
when you see someone that,
that it's saying something that you might
think is offensive to some folks but
not offensive to the
person who's saying it.
Maybe the person who's saying it feels
like they need to express themselves.
And this is important to say and how
do you decide whether or not this is a
valid discussion or if this is
air quotes, hate speech, which is,
you know,
there's some things that are hate speech
and there's sometimes people use the
term hate speech and it's just a cheap
way to shut down a conversation. Yeah.
We, so the simple answer is
we look at conduct. We don't,
we don't look at the speech itself.
We look at conduct,
we look at how the tool is being used.
And you're, you're right in that.
Like I think when people see Twitter,
they see and they expect
it to be a public square.
They can go into that public square.
They can say whatever they want to,
can get on a pedestal.
Um,
and people might gather around
them and listen what they have.
So some of them might find
it offensive and they leave.
The difference is there's,
there's also this concept of this
megaphone in the megaphone can be highly
targeted now with Twitter as well.
Right? So it's not, it's not the,
it's not the speech, it's how
it's amplified. So what do you do?
It's like say let's, let's say
there's someone in the media, uh,
let's say it's a prominent feminist and
then you have a bunch of people or let's
say just one person and their Twitter
feed is overwhelmingly attacking this
prominent feminist, just constantly
attacking or calling her a liar,
calling her this calling that when
do you decide this is harassment?
When decide this is hate speech,
when like how do you,
I mean this is a look at the conduct,
an absolute,
this is a fictional account write
fictional person we're talking about.
But in this for instance,
what,
what would dictate something that was
egregious enough for you to eliminate them
from your platform? Well, that's
a, that's a, that's a heavy action.
So that's the last resort. Um,
but we look at the conduct,
we look at oftentimes as you said,
like the,
the probability of someone
who is harassing one person.
It's highly probable that there
also harassing 10 more people.
So we can look at that behavior.
We can look at how many times this
person is being blocked or muted or a
reported. And based on all
those, um, all that data,
we can actually take some action.
But we also have to,
we have to correlate it with the other
side of that because people go on and
they coordinate blocks as well and
they coordinate harassment and they,
and they coordinate, I'm sorry, not
harassment, but reporting, um, uh,
reporting a particular account
to get it shut down into, uh,
to take the voice off the service.
So these are the considerations
we have to make, but it's, it's,
it all starts with conduct and oftentimes
they'll see coordinated conduct,
whether it be that one person opening
multiple counts or coordinating with
multiple accounts that they don't
own to, you know, go after someone.
And there's a bunch of vectors that
people use retweet for that, uh,
the quote tweet for that a
lot as well. Like, you know,
they'll quote tweet a tweet that
someone finds and they'll say,
look at this idiot Twitter,
do your thing.
And then just this mob starts
and goes and tries to, uh,
effectively shut that person down.
Um,
so there's a bunch of tools we can use.
The permanent suspension
is the last resort.
One of the things that we can do
is we can down rank the replies.
So any of these, any of these behaviors
and conduct that looks link linked,
we can actually, uh, push
farther down in the reply chain.
So it's all still there. But you might
have to push a button to actually see it.
You might have to see, show more
replies to actually see, uh,
this harassing account or what
might look like harassing language.
And this is manually done.
This is, this is all,
this is all automated. It's automated.
Yeah. Yeah. But how would you,
a lot of the ranking in the,
and looking at amplification and looking
at the network is, is automated, right?
Like,
in terms of down ranking,
is there a discussion as to
whether or not this person's reply,
she'd be down ranked? Like how do
you, how do you figure that out? It's,
it's a machine learning and deep learning
model and they just say it's Ai and
they, and they learn, you
know, and we, we look at, um,
we look at how these things are doing
and where they make mistakes and then we
improve it. It's just constantly
improving, constantly learning.
And does that feel like censorship to you?
Like automated censorship is, I mean, who,
who's to decide other than people,
whether or not something is valid? Well,
we're not, we're not looking at the,
at the speech. In this particular case,
we're looking at the conduct,
the conduct,
the conduct of like someone in fast
philocity attacking someone else. Okay.
Right. So those are the things
that our technology allows.
It changes the velocity
changes. Uh, how, um,
you know,
to broadcast semesters that someone
didn't really ask for and didn't want to
hear. We don't touch,
if I follow Joe Rogan,
you'll see every single tweet.
We don't touch it. Right, right.
But that's an audience that you earn.
But in your replies page,
we have a little bit more
room because this is a,
this is a conversation that starts up in,
some people just want to disrupt it.
And all we're saying is we're going
to look at moving the disruption down.
Not that it's hidden, but it's
still there. But you know,
you just see it a little bit farther down.