Her low freak bitches for people
that don't know what's going on.
Let's lay out all of,
uh,
all the events that have transpired.
Essentially,
you were being asked to step
away from your college for a day.
Is that what it was? Is it one day?
Well, this goes back farther than that.
Lay out the whole thing. Okay. So we
couldn't possibly lay out the whole thing,
but let's just for people that have
no idea what's going on right there
listening right now and they're like,
who's this Bret Weinstein guy?
So the core of it surrounds a tradition
that we have at evergreen called day of
absence. And this tradition stretches back
long before I was ever at the college.
I've been there 15 years.
This tradition of stretches back into I
think the early seventies. And it's a,
it's built around a play
written by Douglas Turner Ward,
a black playwright and the play,
um,
portrays events in a fictional town
where the black population decides not to
show up one day, um, in
order to emphasize their,
their roles in the town that the
white population is unaware of. Um,
and as you would imagine, all hell
breaks list. So anyway, that's a,
it's an excellent play. And, uh,
some early faculty at our college decided
that we should have a day that mirror
and disadvantage and that,
uh,
originally black faculty and students and
then later people of color would leave
campus for a day to emphasize the
role that they play in our community.
And then they would later the,
um, the tradition was amended in,
had a day of presence attitude at
where people would come back to campus.
And this has been going on.
Uh,
as I said since the 70s and
the whole time I've been there.
And then this year it was announced
by the organizing committee that the,
uh, the situation would be reversed
and they asked white students,
staff and faculty not to
come to campus. And, uh,
that did not at all sit well with me.
Um,
as I said in my letter to the,
uh,
the person who had announced this Rashida,
who I should say a staff and I,
she has ended up at the
center of this controversy,
I think wrongly just because my letter
and response is addressed to her.
And then it was made
public by our school paper.
So her name has been dragged front and
center. But in any case, my letter,
I said that there was all the difference
in the world between a population
deciding to absent themselves from a
shared space in order to highlight their
role and a population deciding to absent
another population from a shared space,
which I find unacceptable as as a person,
as somebody devoted to,
uh, the gains of the civil
rights movement. Uh, I just,
I and I should also probably say as a Jew
and when people start telling me where
I can and cannot be, um,
it, it rings alarm bells.
Um, so that, that's the gist of the story.
And the letter caused
quite a stir amongst,
uh, students, staff and faculty who
responded. Many of them quite angrily,
privately.
Of course people were much more divided
on the matter and there were plenty of
people who agreed with my letter,
but publicly speaking,
there was condemnation of the
letter. But the uh, the event itself,
they have absence was mostly uneventful.
I,
I did go to campus as I said
I would in my letter and um,
I actually, uh, it's neither here
nor there. It was accidental.
But while I was on campus,
I ran into a student
that I know very well,
actually a student that my wife and I
were abroad in Ecuador with last year we
were teaching abroad and uh,
we had 30 students with us.
And so one of the students who
had traveled with us to Ecuador,
happen to be on campus to, this is a
student of color. I'm going to stop this.
Too much banging around in
here is very distracting.
Sorry.
That's all right.
That was going to go on and I was going
to drive me crazy. Right? Keep going.
So I ran into this student that I,
I know well and care about quite a bit
and we had a very nice conversation.
Mostly not about day of absence.
As a matter of fact,
I can't even remember if we
did talk about day of absence,
but there was something poignant to me
about the fact that while I was being
condemned for, uh, re refusing
to accept this new formulation,
that I was able to meet with a student
who is important to me and thee neither
of our racial backgrounds is fun,
is primary in our relationship.
We know each other as people.
And that's really how I would like to
see all of us interacting on campus.
We all have our backgrounds,
they matter to us, but it can't,
it cannot become the primary
interface between us.
Let, let, let me stop you here
and let me try to understand, um,
what the reaction was because you rightly
said that you think there's a huge
problem with asking people to not show
up simply based on their color of their
skin. Exactly. And what was the
argument against that? Like when,
when you said that,
and I read your letter and your
letter didn't sound racist at all.
It sounded very well thought out.
It's a, it made a very good point,
but the response,
the inflammatory response to your
letter was so disturbing and shocking.
Was there anyone who had reasonable
debate with you about this?
Was there anyone who said,
well,
we should take into consideration
why they're asking us to do this.
We should sit down with them. We
should talk through this. Was there,
was there anything reasonable or was it
just dig your heels in the sand and then
let the insults and the white
privilege and all these accusations can
fly? Well, um, like I said,
there's a huge difference that you can't
see unless you're at the center of one
of these things.
Between the public discussion and
the private discussion privately,
I had very interesting discussions
with many people that was not absent,
but if you were to look in on the
discussion at the public level,
it looked as if there was
consensus United against me.
Now when you say public and private,
are the same people making contradictory
statements in public that are,
that are commiserating with you in
private or is it just different people?
A few of them do that.
The act that actually is the thing I
find most surprising is that sometimes
people will privately say one thing to
you and then publicly do another. Uh,
mostly it's different people.
And I should say the people who have
talked to me privately and expressed
concerns are actually
quite a diverse group.
So it's not as if white folks are
disturbed by this and people of color are
United. It's not at all like
that. But the part of the,
the hidden story here is that
in order to invent advance,
certain policy proposals,
it has to appear that the community is
United behind them and that anybody who
stands against them is standing
against them for illegitimate reasons.
So that means that the number of people
who are willing to express any sort of
nuance about what's taking place has to
be small and they have to be dismissible.
So what they did is
they called me a racist,
which is ironic, um, because
I'm an antiracist, I really,
I've,
I've gone out of my way to,
first of all study the question of
why racism occurs. And, uh, I've,
I believe been pretty
courageous in fighting against
it where I've run into it.
So to challenge me with
that particular epithet, uh,
was a mistake on their part.
It was a strategic mistake.
And I kept trying to tell them all this
was still internally being discussed in
the college.
I kept trying to tell them that they
should really check the concept that I'm a
racist.
They should ask because if they did,
they would discover that
they were actually way off
the mark and then they would
have an interesting puzzle on their hands.
Then they would have to explain to
themselves why they had found themselves
hurling.
This most poisonous a term at somebody
who not only isn't a racist but is pretty
nearly the opposite.
Yeah.
Well it's, it's a standard maneuver
when someone wants to silence someone.
When someone wants to put someone in a
category that's instantly recognizable,
one of the best ones is racist.
Oh, absolutely. And, and
what I found is that, um,
people simply could not figure out what
they would do if that a term was applied
to them. They were able to preview in
their minds what that would be like.
And so many people could see that
there was no escape for them. Right.
So
it's like being called a rapist almost.
It's like even if you are exonerated,
there's still that cloud
hanging hanging above you.
Yes. But this also actually points
to something pretty important.
And for anybody who travels this ground
themselves, they're going discover this,
that many of the terms that are
being used have been redefined,
but they haven't been fully redefined.
So one of the things that I've seen in
several places is that a term like racist
has been redefined so that the bar
for being a racist is so low that you
couldn't possibly help but trip over it.
But then once you've tripped over it
and you have accepted that you are a
racist, then the stigma goes
back to the original definition.
So it is the dodging and weaving between
the two definitions that actually does
the heavy lifting.
Well,
there's also a really disturbing idea
that's being bounced around lately,
that it's impossible to be racist if
you're anything other than white. Right.
Which is ridiculous.
It's preposterous.
Anybody who looks up the actual definition
of racism will discover that that's
preposterous. Um, but yes,
that does pass in certain
places as logical and just
it's parroted and this very
bizarre way it's supposed
to be on challenged. And
this is a very recent thing.
I mean this is not something that existed
two decades ago. Right. I agree. And uh,
the pace at which it's moving in the
last few years is very surprising.
It is surprising,
but it kind of makes sense because you
get into these root groups of people,
they have this confirmation bias,
they lump up together and
they all reinforce their
ideas and this echo chamber
and they all do it inside the colleges.
And then when it gets out
to the rest of the world,
as we're seeing with your
case at Evergreen, it, the
rest of the world is like,
what is going on over here?
Like what is happening in school?
And people who are sending their children
off to school are very concerned with
the indoctrination of these ideas and the,
the Eh,
adopting these very rigid mindsets that
the rest of the world just simply could
pick apart pretty quickly.
Well,
this is the most shocking thing
because I'm, you know, I'm,
I haven't been censured,
I haven't been suspended them still
on the email distribution list.
So I'm watching the traffic inside of
my college and I'm able to compare it to
the huge flood of stuff that I'm seeing
from the outside world as they get wind
of what's going on at Evergreen.
And the difference is a million
miles inside of evergreen.
Actually, we are descending further
into madness. The, the faculty, um,
are,
uh,
blaming the fact that the campus had to
be suddenly closed due to a threat from
the outside yesterday,
uh,
on me for having talked about this
in the outside world specifically for
hilarious. I can't see you.
I can't use that term yet.
Hopefully some day. I hope
it's soon. And you know,
I must say one thing that I don't know,
we haven't even talked about where this,
uh, where I got thrust
into the spotlight here,
which your listeners are going to have
to know in order to understand why I'm
even sitting here. But, um, but the, uh,
the intensity and the out of touch nature
of the discussion inside the college
simply reinforces the,
uh,
the impression that something
is desperately off that,
that what we really have is
a filter bubble that is so,
so strong that even when the world sends
very clear evidence that you've missed
something somewhere and it's time
to rethink what you've been doing.
They're not waking up. And I, I
love this college, this college.
We maybe we'll get to talk about it,
but the structuring of this college
is so unusual and what one can do as a
professor at Evergreen, uh, if
you're really dedicated to teaching,
it is the place to be because you
have unparalleled pedagogical freedom,
more freedom than you'd have as
a tenured professor at Harvard.
And you also have room
to teach individually to
students because our students
take one program at a time,
they're full time in one program,
and the professors teach one
program at a time full time,
and they can go on for a full year.
So imagine you've got 25 students and
you have him for a year full time.
You really know every student in your
class individually, not just by name,
but you know how they think, you
know, their backgrounds, you know, um,
their blind spots.
And that allows for a kind of teaching
that can't be done anywhere else.
So I am quite distressed at the fact that
evergreen is now endangered by what's
going on.
Um,
and I really would like to see it wake
up and rescue itself because it is worth
rescuing.
[inaudible].