Oh, Jamie, you pulled up why
Alex was band two, which is,
you know,
it's not very clear that like when,
when you think about the fact that
they were saying that he had never done
anything on their platform
that was bankable.
And then what was the one
final thing like, and it,
Jack didn't know what he was,
he got it. He confronted
Oliver, Darcy of CNN, uh,
in DC and for several minutes was
yelling at him while they filmed.
And apparently that's my understanding
was the justification for banning him.
That he was harassing a journalist
or something that effect,
which is in my opinion, absurd.
And was he doing it on Twitter?
Um, I guess they post it to terminus,
Clive on periscope. There we go.
Put her bone platform.
So if you do something on periscope
they could get you banned from Twitter.
Well that's the same thing, right?
Cause they're connected. They, yeah.
I don't know at what point last,
I think it was last year,
there was like an announcement,
I saw it on twitch,
but I think it also happened on Youtube.
They like collectively said,
if you do something on our platform,
I'm sorry,
if you do something on another platform
and we see that you could lose your
status on our platform too, or a
funeral. That means public also.
And we see that with with patriot,
but I don't want to deviate into patriot.
We can, we can get to that later.
But so, so I, in my opinion,
so it's make it makes a good point.
How does Alex Jones get banned
for giving that guy a hard time?
But Kathy Griffin doesn't get banned
for literally calling for these children
leading a harassment campaign against
kid names of someone with millions of
followers led a harassment campaign.
I'm going to use their language, right?
If you're calling on your
followers to do something,
you are engaging in a campaign.
But Alex Jones confronting the journalists
who advocated for his banning is
obtainable offense.
Here's the important thing about Jones.
Oliver Darcy said on CNN,
it wasn't that Jones broke the rules
that got in band because you know what,
what Darcy said is he's been breaking
the rules in the past. They never cared.
It was only because of media pressure.
They took action against him. Okay,
well we know many other
people break the rules.
We know fall up the accounts
have doxed law enforcement.
We know Kathy Griffin let of harassment
campaign. There's no media pressure.
That's one of the big problems.
Twitter knows conservatives aren't
going to be able to level any kind of
campaign against their platform.
There's not scared of it. But you know,
I often wonder why is it that as,
as,
as prominent and powerful as conservative
groups can be why they often lose
these cultural battles. And I'm not
going to say this is the primary reason,
but I will point out, do, does,
does Twitter believe that?
Um, you know, I often use
Sargon of a cotton example,
the liberalist anti SDW character.
Do they believe he'll lead a group of
liberal liberalists and individualists to
Twitter headquarters with Crowbars
and Mal toff cocktails? Of course not.
So what did he get banned
for? Um, my under, he, uh,
cause I know what is
happening with Patrion,
but what happens is his original Twitter
thing was that he posted an image of
interracial gay porn at
white nationalists. So,
but I, I, I don't, I think
that was the first time and
then he got banned for that.
He, he, well, he, then he came back
to the platform and then got, um,
I don't know what
happened the second time.
I think it was banned evasion
or something. The porn rules.
Because sometimes I'll be scrolling
through my feed and you'll just see porn.
I understanding it. It's not allowed.
I porns just not allowed. I mean,
what about porn star? It is, I've
heard it. I've heard it is a lot.
And I've heard it isn't, it's
definitely there. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's like porn stars have porn.
If you go to a porn stars page,
you'll see porn on it. A lot of it.
Yeah. Like real penetration porn.
They don't care.
Or maybe there's,
there's the truce between
marked by someone that's
saying this is inappropriate.
And if enough people that follow a porn
star, I don't think it's inappropriate.
It doesn't then get flagged in the
system. Well, wait, this is good news.
I think we may have found the, uh, the
Switzerland of the culture war porn. Yeah.
No one wants to ban porn. The left and
the right, they're like, Whoa, hold on.
Hold on. It's okay. We can
ban them for their ideas.
We just leave the porn alone, you know?
But, but the point I was making is,
you see Antifa at Berkeley. Yeah. $100,000
with a damaged lung Molotov cocktails,
threatening people in, uh, in Portland.
Do you have a Bernie voter carrying an
American flag? These, uh, antifascists,
the Antifa tried stealing the flight
from him, clubbed over the head,
gave him a concoction,
put them in the hospital.
So when I see the ramifications of
iron from the left or the right,
what does, what do
conservatives do? I mean,
the GOP couldn't even find a yearbook
in the Virginia Governor Race.
I don't think they're considered to
be that big of a cultural threat.
They react to things. They get upset
about things that are unfair against them,
but they don't go through the streets
with clubs and bricks and smash windows
like Antifa and other, you know,
far leftist to do. So if they do,
they're considered racist.
It's always like some sort
of a racist mob that was the,
that's like the label they
get put on them, right? Yeah.