Uh, it's, it's huge because until then,
I was winging it. You know, it, the,
the way quitting part of the sport is
cloaks and daggers and you're trying to,
you're, you're overhearing conversations
and you're googling. So, you know, I was,
it was pretty much guesswork
on, on, on, on my end. You know,
I got him to one 45,
um,
nearly 20 times on my own.
But when we brought George into,
and I wasn't even just
about making weight,
what I noticed with him was
that every session was, um,
productive.
There was no sessions where it was,
he didn't have to pop in the
shots or soreness or you know,
that that would just be a
normal part. Whereas when we
brought in George, um, that,
that was a lot,
each session was a lot more effective.
So it wasn't just about making the way
it was making the training camp, um,
where he was improving
the whole way through it.
He got down to one 45 a couple of times
and he looked like, like a monster.
You look like a Zombie. It
was terrifying. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean that had to play a big part in
your decision to no longer have to fight
it that way. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean we'd already gone up to one 55
is his final flight before going to the
UFC was was at one 55 and I was kind
of like, oh thank God, you know,
this is just to see what in the better,
because when he joined he was a
sort of a scrawny 16, 17 year old,
but then you start becoming a man.
So getting down there,
it was getting scarier and scarier.
And in his last fight outside UFC,
I taught you look fantastic.
It was a handy way coat. Um,
and he just looked at,
so it looked like a tank.
Now the offer came in a couple of weeks
later, Sean emailed me and said, hey,
we're offering you at one 45 fight in a,
in April.
And of course I tell Connor and
he's screaming and running around.
We didn't care what weight class. If he
had to say, well in 25, we would have,
we would have done it.
John Specifically,
you want as as a one 45 and
that we've sort of went,
we went back to back to that lighter
weight class and it was almost accidental
and then as soon as we got the
opportunity, you went back up again. Yeah.
He looked very thick at the weigh ins.
He looks heavier, he looks bigger. Yeah.
And it, you know that that's a part of
a, you know, the lifecycle of an athlete.
If you're with the same guy for over
a decade, you're going to see changes.
You know, he's Turkey
now, he's not 18 anymore.
It's these different things going on in
his life. So you have, you know, it's,
that's the benefit I think of working
with someone for a long period of time
rather than, you know, kind
of Jim helping that you,
you'll know what they can and can't do.
And he does a lot of
unconventional training. Right.
In terms of like physical conditioning,
like I know he, is he still doing that,
that the, all that stuff with Ido Portal?
Yeah. Anytime. Ito's in, in, in Europe.
Ped tends to drop in Ireland.
We have a great relationship with them
and he'll play around with that. A,
you know,
the reality is,
is most of our time is going to be spent
on the fundamentals of MMA and grating
with ido is he's, he,
especially in training camp,
he will come in near the end where you're
just tired of doing single leg defense
is you're tired of doing pad work and
he comes in, he does these fun games.
So we're still working out. We're still,
he's firing his brain in different ways.
He's where he's working on coordination
and balance for me is the, you know,
the head trainer. It's like, it's
a nice break and you know, a, um,
I'm sure it was John John Wayne
power heard say to, you know,
when you have a fight coming up, you know
him anymore that you're going to ruin,
you know, how many kicks you're
going to trow every night. Again,
you want to come in and want to do
so long back and jumping in the air.
Spinning Albert's itself at breaks the
monotony and am amazed is fantastic.
You know, cause it's all the
martial arts together. It's,
you're almost never going to get forward
because you can always do something
different, but it's still, there's
still a repetitiveness to it,
but it's nice to break with
something unusual. Now,
how much does training change when
you're dealing with a specialist,
like a guide, like could be who
is just, uh, uh, grappling phenom?
How much do you shift the emphasis
of the training to take down defense,
working on grappling and
do you work mostly takedown
defense or do you just work
overall wrestling so that takedown
defense becomes a part of that as well?
Um, all of that. All that. But yeah,
definitely I would maybe talk about later.
Like I,
there's one thing I could change is
that I think I was too defensive in,
in my mindset for this
training camp. But, uh,
Habib has very specific types of
take downs depending on where he is,
whether it's shooting on the low
single, on the, in the middle.
And then on the fence. I, I, you know,
long before Carnaby street, the fire them,
I loved watching him. Um, that's
kind of my areas. The fence.
I just love right from the Randy
couture days, how to use the fence and,
and a beef does it to a, you know, a new
level, um, you know, when to take downs.
The hidden Conor [inaudible], he hadn't
actually done it until the eloquent,
the fight. So it was nice that we kind
of got to see that at the high crotch.
I was, I, I see a bit of DC in that,
the high crotch and then trip on the
far leg and I think he blocked the ones,
but he did catch him with it. Um, so, you
know, it was a very specific take downs.
Um, definitely for this training camp
was the most specific that we went.
And then I remember about a
week out or whenever it was,
he did an interview and he said, well,
if he doesn't make it a fight, Tony,
I don't care who it is.
And I was going down it.
I hadn't even looked at
Tony's fights in so long.
So me and the other coaches
like start like, okay, what
does he do again? Oh yeah,
he has that style because we
work so specific for this one.
Um, Tony could possibly be a fight
in the future. When you, when you,
when you think about the future now, after
the could be fight, how, what do you,
what are you thinking?
Are you thinking about just rest,
let the dust settle and then look at
the landscape? Like what, how did,
how did you approach it?
I might, but he doesn't,
what is he screaming and shouting
for the rematch within minutes?
It's hard to push for that rematch
though, after that fight. Right? Sure. No,
I understand the logic of that. You
know, Tony's kind of errands and stuff,
but I also understand
this is a business and
it will be a huge fight. You know, the
rematch would be a huge fight. Does it,
don't you think that it would be difficult
to sell because of how dominant could
be, wasn't that fight? I'm sure. Uh,
I do think the Roundtree showed
promise. Um, I, I, like I said,
I would like to have change
things up a little bit,
specifically a more offensive mindset.
I thought defensively we did quite well.
Um, but offensively we weren't
really where we usually are. And,
and you know, right when the fight was
over, I was thinking, you know what,
I was kind of going into this like
not to lose, but not to win, you know,
and his shots warden is Christmas.
They normally are.
He had opportunities to hit him,
especially in the third round.
And he just seemed to be the range
at the time. Something was off.
And then I had to do with the fact that
he hadn't fought at my main two years.
Absolutely. You know, I'd say
right. Yeah, of course. Of course.
And we tried to mimic as
close as we could in the gym.
And I brought in guys that he didn't
know and I would say, this is fight day.
And He, you know, he would do what George,
exactly what it's gonna do on fight day
and we'd have a referee and so t to get
the fight feel, but it's still in
the gym, which rides, you know,
is he at a position now where every
fight has to be a gigantic super fight.
And is that, is that a problem in that,
you know what, I thought after the fight,
after it was all over, I was like,
you know what a good fight would be.
It would be him versus Pettis.
Like that would be a really good fight
and it would be a really interesting
fight in terms stylistic matchup and
it would be a great fight I think for
Connor to sort of just get a wild three
round or I guess it would probably be a
main event. It would be five rounds,
but oh well it would be a wild fight.
They would probably favor him. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean the boxing have, you know,
when Tyson fury was kind of coming
back, the government, you know,
not the toughest guy in the world.
It doesn't happen.
It never doesn't happen to them.
And me
specifically to USC and there's
an issue with that I think. Yeah.
You know, he was, you know, I
did. And as it is, early stages,
we was fighting all the time.
And as is natural,
as you get older and as you achieve more,
it is going to start becoming, you know,
once or twice a year. That's just a
natural progression. As an athlete,
I don't care who you are,
but the wild fights that he
could have at 155 pounds,
whether it's James Vick or just engag
or pedis or there's good fights for him.
Yes. That aren't necessarily could be,
they aren't necessarily Tony Ferguson,
but they're a good fight
to get that timing back,
get everything locked in,
you know,
100% but you have to factor in his
personality and he's only fighting now for
fights that are really interesting to him.
He's not that interest in anybody.
Not that I've heard Mayweather paper.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. Well money, money,
money, money. Right. So, you know.
Yeah. What more can he, you know,
even with his spending,
well kind wouldn't be the eye on the
future and on the eye, on the rematch,
you know,
like getting everything dialed in so that
when he does have a rematch with Kirby,
he is Samurai sword sharp. Yes sir. Yeah.
As opposed to having two years off,
one one boxing fight in between them
and then such a grappling heavy contest.
Yeah, I don't disagree. That
would be a trainer. You know,
for me as a trainer
that would be the ideal.
But it be hard to motivate him for that.
I think it would be hard to motivate
them and it's, it's not the, you know,
it's not really the UFC model.
It's obvious it was going to be though.
You know what I mean?
It was going to be those two.
Anybody could tell the UFC what
time it is. It's Conor, Khabib time.
I mean if anybody is the guy that
can say, hey, this is what I want.
I want a fucking tune up fight. I want a,
I want a tough guy. He absolutely could.
Yeah. And he absolutely wouldn't.
You know who is like when, when,
when he lost the Diaz as
one place and a backstage,
he was screaming and shouting
at all the top brass.
So they get getting the rematch at
one 70 as quick as possible. I'm on,
I'm in the background going, please
don't, did you not see that fight?
He's a terrifying the individual
that's good at one 55, five.
Yeah. Okay. Maybe you meet him again,
but he was not letting that go.
And then four months later
he fought the exact same guy.
That's where he is right now with Khabib.
That's all I,
that's all I'm hearing from you. Well
listen, you could sell it for sure.
Especially with the fucking
chaos after the fight. You know,
just keep Dillon dance at home.
He's grounded.
Yeah. So with what would
you do differently? Um,
like I said from it,
from a strategy point of view and my
number one thing would be to be more to
think more offensively that we definitely
had opportunities to learn shots on
when Connor land shot, you know, you know,
watch the Eddie fight back again. It's,
it doesn't take them a whole lot of shots.
He rarely misses, you know, even if,
if you look at strikes that it didn't
land, those strikes were for a reason.
They were to see what way he holds his
hand. See what we mean? It was like,
you know,
you used to love watching Anderson civil
back in the day and I thought they were,
you know, they have a similar
kind of approach, but this one,
we just didn't seem to be landing in my,
only,
when I look back at the training camp,
we did spend most of her time
with a defensive mindset,
and I think that's a mistake.