You're full
all day,
ladies and gentlemen coming
at you live from paradise.
I'm in Hawaii right now
and uh, I was gonna,
I was gonna watch the Bisping fight,
the Bisbing Kelvin guest
him fight live and uh,
do like sort of a breakdown
of it while it was happening.
But the shit was going on at like two
o'clock in the morning out here and
it wasn't happening. I have been
eating like a pig and drinking.
I've been doing vacation type shit.
I'm a strong believer in that.
You need to do vacation time.
Like vacation time is important. You
can't just be working all the time.
Occasionally you have to just fuck off.
And so that's what I've been doing.
I just been fucking off. So I,
I was tired and I decided I
am not going to stay up late.
And so I watched it in the morning.
I watched it this morning and I've got a
couple of thoughts on it. First of all,
um, Brennan Chub said this on his
Instagram and I could not agree more.
I don't think you should be allowed to
fight three weeks after you have a brutal
fight like Michael Bisping
did with GSP. He got rocked,
he got choked unconscious,
and then three weeks later he's fighting
a really dangerous young and up and
coming Kelvin gasoline
and Kelvin is a beast.
He's gotten nasty boxing and that
is what he showed in that fight.
He hit him with a,
a beautiful straight right jab and a
right hand behind it and Oh my goodness,
it was just the kid is just on fire. He's,
he's just on another level right now.
I'm, I'm super, super impressed
with Calvin. Kelvin has got
lightning fast hands and he's,
he's an interesting guy because
he's what I would call a tweener.
And what that means is that I
don't, I mean I think Kelvin
[inaudible]
in the best, best of times, like if
Kelvin has the best camp and the,
the best performance,
it's entirely possible that he
could beat anybody at 185 pounds.
But should he be at 185
pounds? Boy, I don't know,
because Chris Weidman is that 185 pounds.
And when Chris Weidman
got Calvin to the ground,
it really did look like you're talking
about two completely different weight
classes. And Chris Weidman
was able to choke Kelvin out.
And obviously Weidman is a former champion
and there's absolutely no shame in
losing to Chris Weidman,
but it's just the way, um,
it looked when you were
watching the fight,
to me it looked like two
different weight classes and, um,
there's a lot of people that think that
really Calvin should be fighting at 170
pounds if he got the proper diet.
And he doing that for a while.
Uh, it w at one point in time he was, uh,
I know Dolce was working
with him for awhile and, uh,
he had his diet in line and
he looked fantastic and then,
you know, just things happen and he
didn't want to pay the Dolce money.
And, uh,
I dunno who he's working with right
now as a nutritionist, but I just, uh,
I think he's a phenomenal fighter.
I just don't know if 185 pounds is,
is the right way class for them.
It could be. I mean,
it could be that maybe what he really
needs to do is just lose some body fat,
put on some muscle and maybe 185
pounds will be his weight class.
It's just that constant debate of whether
or not you should weaken your body and
drop down to the minimum weight you can
or whether or not you should fight at a
natural way and have a healthy
body. It's a real good argument.
And I'm pausing right now because
I'm pulling something up. Uh,
there's a girl that just died
in Australia. Uh, she died,
um, very recently. Uh,
she was preparing for a
Moitai fight and it's just,
it's just part of what this
sport is about. Unfortunately.
It really bothers the fucking shit out
of me. I think it's the scariest thing.
Uh, I think, um, yeah. Here
it is. Teenager dies training.
Here it is. Um, the, the girl's name,
she was 18 years old and her name was
Jessica Lindsey and she died while she was
cutting weight. She was an amateur
kickboxer in Australia. Um,
I cut weight a bunch of times when I was
doing TaeKwonDo tournaments. And, uh,
it is brutal. It's, it's terrible.
I'm, I was bad at it too.
I didn't do it correctly.
I just worked out real hard the night
before and wore rubber suits and the whole
deal and dehydrated myself. And I
did rehydrate myself well either.
So I felt like shit the next
day when I was fighting.
And a lot of wrestlers back in the
day used to do the same thing. Um,
my weight cut though was nowhere near as
extreme as some of the MMA fighters do.
Some MMA fighters. I mean, they're
getting on death's door and, um,
I just,
I just think it's one of
the most disturbing and, uh,
most unfortunate aspects of MMA. Uh,
Kevin Lee said before his last fight
with Tony Ferguson that, you know,
he felt like he was,
he was dying when he was cutting weight
and he made the weight Habib number go
mid off, who's the, if not the best,
one of the very best
lightweights in the world. Um,
undefeated had his body
shut down last time.
He tried to make the and couldn't
make the Tony Ferguson fight.
They pulled them out and took
him to the hospital. I mean I'm,
I'm beating a dead horse here cause
it's something that everybody knows.
Everybody's aware that it's a
terrible, terrible aspect of our sport.
And in my mind it's contrary to what
martial arts are supposed to be about.
So in that sense,
I encourage Calvin to stay at 185 pounds
because obviously the guy's knocked
out. Vito Belfort at one 85 it
just knocked out a former champion,
Michael Bisping at 185 pounds.
I mean he could knock out anybody at one
85 but a guy like Chris Weidman who is
very smart about cutting
weight, he cuts a lot of weight,
but he does it the right way.
Rehydrates the right way and
he's just a fucking beast.
He's just so much bigger.
And when he got Kelvin to the ground and
submitted him with a head and arm choke
boy, it just really seems like that's
the wrong way class for Calvin.
And then you see Calvin next fight,
fight Bisbing and just fucking
lights him up in the first round.
Now would he have been able to
do that if he fought the Bisping?
That was training for
George Saint Pierre. I mean,
if Bisping did not have the George st
Pierre fight and just went right into the
Calvin gasoline fight with
the same result of happen,
it could very well have the way
Calvin hits, he's fast as fuck.
His hands are beautiful. He throws
really crisp straight punches.
And in this sport there's not a
whole lot of guys who have crisper,
sharper hands at 185 pounds than Calvin.
I mean he just has beautiful head movement
and boxing and when he moves in for
the kill with those hands, Whoa. I
mean you saw the Vito Belfort fight.
I mean he just fucked be tore up.
But those straight punches and he throws
them efficiently and they have snap to
them. And just, and on top of that,
he's a very good wrestler. I mean,
a lot of people forget how good his
wrestling skills are on top of all that.
He's just a real threat at 185 pounds.
Fascinating thing because it's
just such a wide open division.
He just called out, um, Robert Whittaker,
who's the interim champion
of course, and uh,
call that Whitaker and wants
Whitaker to, uh, to fight him next.
But of course Robert Whittaker is,
uh, waiting for the big pay day.
I would too if I was him to fight
George Saint Pierre. So it's a,
it's a wide open division now
that st Pierre choked out.
Michael Bisbing and then
gelt Calvin just lights up.
Bisping and of course you've got to
think that Weidman is still in the mix.
I mean, even though Waiban lost to
Yoel Romero and then lost to gig,
Arden was saucy. He's
still in the mix. Uh,
he was winning that Yoel
Romero fight in my opinion,
until he got caught with
that wicked flying knee.
But that's the danger
of fighting Gol Meryl,
you all Ramiro could do that
to anybody in the world.
He's just such a fucking
freak athlete. Uh, so really,
really wide open division to
get back to that fight. Uh,
I agree entirely with a,
to get back to the Bisbing
and Calvin gasoline fight.
I agree 100% with what
Brendan Schaub said,
that you really have to protect
a fighter from themselves.
You really can't be letting a guy fight
three weeks after an absolutely brutal
fight like that. It just does not make
sense. It just does not make sense. Um,
I don't think it's smart.
I mean I understand that
UFC needed someone to fill
in and short notice because
Anderson Silva tested positive
for performance enhancing
drugs and they did not
want to lose the, uh, Shanghai main event.
So it turns into an even bigger fight
when you've got the former middleweight
champion right off of his loss three
weeks later fighting again. But
it's just not smart. I know
Bisbing wanted to do it.
I know Bisping would probably do
it again if you asked him to do it.
If you ask Bisping to fight in a couple
of weeks and probably probably do it
again. And, and um,
someone was talking about him fighting
in England, I believe in March, which
boy, I mean that's less crazy,
but still crazy, right? Cause uh,
we're basically in into December. So
you've got December, January, February,
three months off really, and then March.
But of course during that time he's going
to be sparring and you know, you know,
Bisbing he's a fucking animal.
He's not going to train easy.
He's not going to take
much time off. And, uh,
there's a lot of debate as to how much
time a fighter should be forced to take
off after they get knocked out.
And here's the thing about that.
You're, you're seeing guys
when they're fighting, fighting
and you're seeing them getting knocked
out and you're seeing them fighting,
you know, X amount of months
later. So you saw Bisping,
he didn't get knocked out
by George Saint Pierre,
but he certainly got rocked with
that left hook. And then, uh,
he got choked out when he
was on the ground out. Now,
for people who don't know a lot about MMA,
getting choked out is not nearly as
bad as getting knocked out. It's,
there's almost nothing to it.
The way to look at it is if you look at
a garden hose and you know how you can
bend the garden hose, crimp it down,
and it stops the water from coming out,
that's exactly what happens to your
fucking brain when you get choked out.
When you get choked out, it's basically
cutting off the blood. Your brain,
you wake up and you're fine.
You don't have memory issues,
you don't have balance
issues for the most part,
especially if you've only been
out for a couple of seconds. Um,
it happens all of the
time in training. Uh,
I've seen many, many guys
get choked unconscious.
I've choked people unconscious.
They come back and they're fine.
It's not that big of a deal, but you've
got to realize before he got choked,
he got hit with a big fucking left-hand
and hurt. And it was a great fight.
Before that, uh, both guys were,
were giving and tanking fighters
need time off after fights.
So you're seeing that, right?
You're seeing the actual competition
between George Saint Pierre,
Michael Bisping. Well,
where are you not seeing is how many
times he got hit during training?
Did he get rock Devore did he
get clipped and dropped? Uh,
did he get dropped in hurt and take a
couple of days off and then get back to
training again? Only he
knows only his camp knows.
And most of the times they're not talking.
But you hear about it all the time.
And matter of fact, I was
talking to Forrest Griffin wants,
and Forrest was telling me that
before he fought Anderson Silva,
he was knocked unconscious twice
in training. That's fucking crazy.
I mean, here he is
about to fight the greatest pound
for pound fighter of all time.
Next to, I mean there's, there's, there's
three guys in that debate, right? My,
my number one guy right now is
mighty mouse. I think just, he,
he represents the highest skill level.
But does he represent the
highest competition level
in terms of like the guys
he's faced? I don't think so.
I think number one competition
level is Jon Jones.
Jon Jones has choked out
Liotta Machida rampage Jackson.
He's beat Rashad Evans. He
beat Alexander Gustafson,
he beat Glover to Shera.
He beat Vitor Belfort.
He beat Daniel Cormier twice. I mean fuck,
he's beaten everybody. I think
you look at competition wise,
John Jones is a very strong argument
for the greatest of all time,
but Anderson Silva's fucking
right there. Two men,
Anderson Silva in his prime.
I think when you look at the way he
knocked out Vito Belfort with that front
kick to the face, when you
look at the way he fought,
Forrest Griffin in that fight
we were just talking about,
andK owed him like a magician the way he
fought Stephan Bonner and literally put
his back up against the cage. And again,
Stephan Bonner and Forrest Griffin,
they're just, no disrespect.
They're not at the same level as the
Liotta Machida or glow over to Shera or
some of the guys that Jon
Jones has phased. But it's
the way Anderson beat them.
I mean, Anderson was just in his
prime. He was off fucking master,
like a real master. Uh,
so Forrest Griffin fighting Anderson
Silva after being Kao twice in training
camp is just insane.
But these are the things that fighters
do when they have to do them. You know,
you're talking about a giant pay day,
you're talking about a big fight.
You give the guy a chance
like, do you want to fight?
Do you think you could fight?
Yeah, I, yeah, I could do it.
I could do it and they'd go out there
and they're compromise and they get
clipped and you see it immediately.
Sometimes. Sometimes you see guys,
they get clipped and you don't know why.
I mean they get hit with something and
look at any deal anytime when a person is
throwing a punch or kick at you and
it connects, it can put you out,
but there's no doubt at
all, no doubt about it,
that the resiliency of a fighter
after they'd been code is compromised.
There's just no doubt about it.
When you see a guy who has been code
and then you see them get hit weeks,
months later, they cannot
take a shot at the same way.
Their brain is still recovering.
Their body is still recovering
from the concussion.
And you have to figure out a way to
balance being a risk taker and seizing an
opportunity,
which is a huge opportunity versus
concentrating on having a long and healthy
career. Now that said,
for Michael Bisping,
he's kind of at the end
of his career. I mean,
he said essentially that he wants
a fight one more time in England,
which would be beautiful for him.
And I hope they give him a, you know,
a good match up. So it'll be
a good fight for the fans.
And I hope they give Michael
some time off. You know,
give the man some time to really relax
and then go through a real nice three,
four month training camp,
getting excellent shape and give his
best effort for one more. Go at it.
I would like to see that,
but it might be the hardest shit in the
world to talk a fighter into retiring.