But this is the thought process behind
it and there's no pushback because the
public speaks and then I pushed back in
the attack me and they attack you bring
it on,
bring it on because ignorance bounces
off me like personal hygiene from Michael
Moore. It just has no impact
whatsoever. I think he washes.
You don't think I have a shame like
a more, you know what a what a swine.
He is as a subhuman Mongrel. If I borrow,
when I met him, he was in his car.
He's a prick.
He's a liar.
What do you think he's like scam
artists like gun control. Well,
how about the fact that
he put together that move,
that so called documentary that Hollywood
actually give him an award and he
copied and pasted out of
sequence the attack on the grid.
Charlton Heston claiming he was somehow
responsible for the little child killing
herself with you're paroled felon father's
gun and they put it out of sequence
and attributed Charlton Heston defending
such irresponsible gun ownership.
Michael Moore is a line,
cruel,
stoned punk cause he's don't
constantly all day all the time.
I think he uses depositories.
I don't know him.
I do and I, he's a punk. Have you
ever had a conversation? Yeah. Yeah.
I was on his TV show and I was responsible
for ending his TV show cause he tried
to fuck with me.
And I don't know if you'd noticed Joe,
but I'm unfuckable you fuck with me.
I'll eat your family tree and shit.
Saw dust into your face.
Ask Pierce Morgan.
That seems like I saw your compensation.
Not even close.
I was arm wrestling a torso.
Well the Pierce Morgan,
the problem is he didn't understand the
facts. When you talk about gun violence,
he didn't understand that. How much of a
guy he knew them he avoided. Absolutely.
Plus he explain what we're talking about
because when you say the numbers of gun
violence,
the a giant percentage of 'em are suicide.
A giant percentage of them are cops
killing bad guys and citizens defending
their family.
So all of those are out of the,
and then accidental gun deaths,
mass summarize it for you.
So Pierce Morgan fancies himself a conky
rather witty limeys you got the accent
and everything. It's funny that actually
an accent, it's an impediment. But, uh,
he came out and of course he's going
to take on the motor city madman.
I mean this guy is going to be easy.
Pickins he actually wrote Wango tango
be all intellectually this thing you're
doing.
That's the Limey Eve God manufactured
confidence based on nothing except an ego
that has no foundation in fact. So
Pierce Morgan, the CNN exec. So,
but it's put Pierce Morgan
on the Motor City Madman.
This will be in a gun store to at the
first time you didn't see the first one at
the CNN officers. That's the best. Both
of them. Yeah, that's the best one.
And so they think I'm a dirt bag and
then a goof ball because I not only wrote
Wang Dang sweet poon Tang, I meant
it. Um, but when they take me on,
they don't realize I never went to college
because I was too busy learning shit.
And if you take me on,
on any subject that I am even slightly of,
I will fuck you up because
I've studied this stuff.
I live this stuff.
I've been with guns since I could walk.
I have had universal unlimited
access to firepower my whole life,
both in a recreational,
a disciplined,
a law enforcement,
military training,
and just a family plinking competition.
So when every considerable,
uh,
imaginable gun use,
I've been 68 years of it.
Um,
so they sick Pierce Morgan Ami to teach
me a lesson about how irresponsible gun
owners are and that if we could just band
guns, that all the violence would end.
And of course, uh, if you haven't seen
it, you got to Google it because it was,
what's his take? Well,
I almost fixed him, um,
because I,
I so overwhelmed them with evidence that
they finally research and realize that
every word out of my mouth
was absolutely indisputable.
What was most compelling
that you were saying to him?
I'll summarize it as this way like I did
to pierce the anti gunners have their
dream.
It exists.
It existed in Paris where all those
people were shot with collision kickoffs,
collision concert band. They have their
dream Pierce Morgans dream exists.
It's called a gun free zone.
Virginia Tech, Columbine,
Sandy Hook,
Aurora Parklin.
Every instance where the most innocent
lives have been slaughtered have been in
Nancy Pelosi, Maxine waters, Eric Holder,
Hillary Clinton,
Barack Obama's dream.
Their dream is a gun free zone,
but we're three people are forced,
forced into unarmed helplessness where
the most innocent lives are lost and that
dream has produced more carnage and
destroyed lives than anything in the world
compared to the NRA convention where
you have the highest incidence of gun
ownership or opening day of deer season
in Michigan where you have 100% gun
ownership and access
where nobody gets hurt.
So if you know that your dream is a
gun free zone and that's where the most
innocent lives are lost,
what kind of demonic dirt
bag would actually want more?
Well,
let me stop gun Fritz and I stopped his
position or anybody's position on the
other side.
You would say the real gun free zone
would be no one having access to the gun
that killed those people in the gun
free zone. It's not a gun free zone.
And the real,
and the real answer to drownings in
America would be to ban water fuels.
You work on banning water,
I'll work on banning guns and we'll touch
base every few weeks and see how you
can not ban. You cannot
eliminate guns. Finland,
you can not eliminate guns.
Uh,
Alberta Canada where the guy who came
into the University of shot everybody up.
It's so what you do instead of
thinking you could ban water,
learn to swim and watch
your children by the pool.
Call me weird.
But the way to handle violence is
to carry a gun practice with it.
And when someone brings lethal force
against you, shoot the mother fucker.
But people are very uncomfortable with
the idea of an incredibly armed society.
Comfortable babies.
Sorry,
you're uncomfortable and go
ahead and bend over and die.
But you know what I'm saying?
Fuck, I know what you're saying.
But wouldn't it be better if there
weren't any concern that the,
the idea is to somehow
or another takeaway,
the concern of people being shot randomly
by some psycho that you've got to
figure out if you get all the guns away,
how do you get all the guns?
We don't know. I don't know. But this is
what I'm saying is that you don't know,
so let's just start. If they're
not try, if it's not that,
then everybody's got guns to shoot.
Nobody.
Everybody will not have guns and
some people have guns. People here.
I studied San Bernardino. I started
to roar. I started at Virginia Tech.
I studied Columbine. I studied
sandy hook. I studied them all.
Do you know Joe and everybody better
write this down because I'm the only guy
that will tell you this. I've studied
the cadence, the bullet manufacturers,
the rate of fire,
the movement of the Perp and
the movement of the victims
in every instance,
including in Connecticut,
including Aurora, including
San Bernardino, right here,
there were American citizens who would
have had a gun on their person if they
were allowed to and they could have been
a meaningful force to at least reduce,
if not terminate the violent,
murderous threat.
But by law we have been so dumbed
down and so forced against our natural
survival instinct to have a tool on our
belt that in every instance where the
most innocent lives were slaughtered,
those people that would have intervened
with a firearm, not many of them,
but there was a janitor, there was a
couple of guys in the office they add,
can see a weapons permit,
but they weren't allowed to have
Monette building in Virginia Tech.
There were guys that had guns,
concealed weapons permits,
but they weren't allowed to have
them there in Aurora, Colorado.
Are you kidding me?
All kinds of people would have had
guns and they could have returned fire,
but they were forced into
unarmed helplessness. Here,
here's the gun debate in its
con irrefutable conclusion.
If you are forced into
unarmed helplessness,
you are unarmed and helpless.
What a horrible,
irresponsible,
suicidal condition that Ian,
I'm just a guitar player. Joe.
I've never been unarmed since
I graduated from high school.
I've always had a Hanky in a pocket full
of guitar picks and a pocket knife and
a belt knife and uh, built tool and
a pistol. And some extra bullets.
I just have them everywhere I go.
I've never been on armed. I find it.
How do you travel around? I
improvise, adapt, and overcome.
I luckily I helped pass
house resolution to 18,
which means all sworn law enforcement
officer allowed to carry a gun nationwide.
I've been sheriff deputy
since 1984 in my credentials.
Allow me to carry a gun everywhere I go
and I carry a gun everywhere he goes.
In fact, even in England, uh,
American law enforcement are allowed to
carry guns and I carry gun over there.
It's just a tool. If somebody comes
at me, carry a gun in England. Yeah,
eat some dirt bag comes at me with
a spiking the, I've just shoot him.
But why not? What's plan B? No, I,
I agreed that I've just had to be hard
to have it and not to need it than to
need it and not to happen.
Go.
The thing that we would all like
to have is no school shootings,
no mass shootings. Noah roar a no.
Columbine. No. So how do you stop that?
Do you think you stopped that with more
guns when you think you stopped that
with mental health education, figuring
out how to get people off of pills,
figuring out how to keep people from
living despondent lives where they want to
just tear it all down and shoot everybody
in her hurt a bunch of people. Well,
here we are. That's the route,
right? Sure. Here we are,
2018 so we can't go back in history in
find the goofball from Virginia Tech and
what motivated him?
We can't go back there because we have
failed as a society to take care of
people or respond with any sense of
responsibility or effectiveness to the
glaring dangerous sides.
Most outrageously in Parkland where
the guy called the cops 42 times,
called the FBI three times that guys
are going to shoot up the school. Okay,
we'll make a note of that. No, the guy's
going to shoot up the school. Okay.
We'll make a note of that. The guy is
bringing a gun to school to shoot people.
Here's his manifesto. Uh, we've made a
note of that, but are you kidding me?
So now if we go for them to do something
and when someone does something, no,
it's not. No, no, it's not. I don't
think it's a failure of law enforcement.
I had, what's the matter? It's just a
shooting two hours ago. Oh Jesus Christ.
Another one,
five people are dead and multiple people
are wearing apolis Melik Maryland at a
Oh Maryland where no one's
allowed to have a gun, by the way,
Marilyn to a newsroom and shot a
bunch of reporters. How much Jesus,
how much you wanna bet
it was a gun free zone.
Annapolis newsroom shooting leaves.
Five people dead suspect in custody.
A newsroom. Yeah. Well, what's my point?
So I made a news room and I'm ready to
rock. I'd rather be sitting where you are,
but I get figure you've got me covered.
My point is, is that the cat is,
is already out of the bag,
right? It's not too late.
Columbine guys,
glaring signals,
red alarms going off over
at Virginia Tech Guy,
red alarms going off for
years and Columbine thing is
a difficult one because it
really hadn't happened before
that no one expected it.
But to parents walked through
the garage for three years.
We're the bomb making materials
were I'm the table. Yeah.
They weren't the best parents
guys were like zombies.
These guys were like
doper freaks from buns.
I just Zulu land maniacs. Well, he's just,
he's just different. No,
he's not. He's freaky.
We need to sit down with this
guy and get him some help.
The Aurora guy told his psychiatrist,
my goal is to shoot as many people
as possible in the psychiatrist.
Didn't say anything
really or it's on record.
He said it in numerous visits with his
psychiatrist that he had threatened his
golden life was to kill as many people
as possible and he's now got his new ar
15 to do it with and the
psychiatrist didn't say anything.
I've studied this stuff. We need to
not only see something, say something,
we're missing the part.
The final part do something when this
kind of abberant threatening violent red
alarm behaviors going off.
Inter veen sit down with this kid at the
first instance when your kid comes home
all glassy eyed and goofy
and incommunicable and in
showing weird signs like the
Sandy Hook Guy did all his life and
the Aurora guy did all his life and the
Parkland guys Zombie, you know, staring
like uh, wouldn't blink in a sandstorm.
Somebody got, I know I
would, I mean in my life,
whether it's musicians or family members
are going, are you going to write?
What is it going on? You look like
you're going to shit yourself, man.
Are you okay?
What do you do with that conversation
with somebody like the psychiatrist did to
the Aurora shooter does mean, how
do you fix these people? I mean,
what you're saying is if you have no
gun free zones and people are allowed to
have guns, at least they'll have
an ability to defend themselves.
I agree with you.
I agree with you on that,
but how do you stop it from
happening in the first place?
The anti gun people say the way to
stop it is to have no guns available to
civilians that can do things
virtually impossible. A virtual pasta.
So what we're dealing with
is just pragmatically,
when you look at 300 million people
and probably 400 million gun,
where you haven't counted mine
yet. I mean, how many guns? Yeah.
For every guy like you that has
hundreds of guns, you know, I am almost,
everybody I know has hundreds
of guns and he just like a man,
I got hundreds of arrows. I have
four, I have dozens of guitars.