About this. What do you think about Pettis
fight and Wonderboy guy? Good for you.
Pedes I love, I get great fight. Isn't it
Kinda crazy though? He's, it goes from 45,
can't make it any more. All the way up
to 70, 25% about it. Fucking did this.
How much of a beast? Pegasus fights
Tony Ferguson. Amazing fight, right?
Tony wins that. He gets hurt then fucking,
he was like, you know, fuck it. Uh,
broke his hand.
Pedes broke his hand in that fight.
So it was a tough fight from either way,
but then he jumps up and he's
fighting Wonderboy. Yeah.
Both use me dog in both fights.
He's an underdog and both
fights. Yeah. Yeah. That,
that, that Ferguson fight
was fun. Yeah. It show,
it shows you what a survivor Ferguson
as he gets clipped and you know,
he got hurt in that fight
and he just grabbed,
how about Max Holloway and Tony
Ferguson Talking Shit to each other?
Uh, that's the on the, on the dark
web. That's the room. I liked that,
but I don't like that. Why don't
you like it, Ferguson versus Khabib?
I want to see that fight, but to beads
out for, he won't fight in Vegas.
He has a suspension,
so he's out for a little bit.
Tony's ready to go that
he won't do the the,
he won't do that thing that Vegas
is asking them to do commercial.
They're asking me to do a commercial.
It was like, you have prostitution,
you have gambling. Fuck you. What's the
best? So why does that seem right to,
what's the problem with Connor? Tony?
What's going on with that? How can that,
it's going to be Connor and cowboy,
Connor and cowboys.
A done deal as far as I know to
as far as I know. As far as that,
we signed the contract. Doesn't
Connor? Tony make more sense though,
know what kind of cowboy is great and
Connor, Tony's great. They're both great.
They're both great sites. If, if I'm,
if I'm Dana, I'm sitting on this.
Eddie, you laugh. I want to be careful
with Tony because you love him.
You're friends are going
to question why not?
Because he works for like two years.
Here it is Eddie, Tony, Connor,
Connor. Be a slight under
Doug. I think in that fight.
Tony's a monster for anybody.
So I think Tony Max it and cop
cars caught and he's get a win.
I'm not saying Congress can be
a huge favorite over cowboy,
but he's more favorable in that fight
they need. Is it going? He's a window for,
he comes back and he needs,
he needs a more favorable fight.
And I'm not saying that's a great Matt
Cowboy's a motherfucker and you know,
fire cowboys on fire right now.
He's just so lucid in the zone right now.
And Cowboy. Yeah. Kelby, it's a
great fight style stylistically.
That's a better fight for
cowboy and Connor. Yeah.
Tony's Tony is a great wrestling back
then and he's a motherfucker cardio for
days and he's crazy. I liked that fight
a lot. I really liked that fight a lot.
Max Holloway. Tony's a motherfucking
fight. I love that fight.