And I could link it by the way to
marketing. So, uh, the dove that Eh,
and so on.
If I have wrinkly skin,
I'd like to believe that there is no such
thing as an universal beauty standards.
And in that sense dove has been incredibly
successful because by peddling false
hope, they've actually been able to tap
into women's insecurities and incense.
That's good marketing.
Right?
Did you see the cover of Cosmopolitan
magazine that was widely criticized
because they had a morbidly
obese woman on who was, uh,
you a bikini plus size model? Yeah, yeah.
And they were challenging beauty norms.
Like this is a person that's eating
themselves to death. You fucking assholes.
And so your lack of discipline and your
desire to shame people who exercise and
is what you're doing right,
to make them feel bad because you feel
bad that you can't put the fucking cook
cookies and cupcakes down as a lead you
to try to push this ridiculous standard.
And me and one of the things,
my point of view was,
could you imagine if the cover of men's
health had an enormous fat guy with his
gut hanging over his belt and people
were saying the new standards of
attractiveness for men have been changed
by Mike who just drinks beer and eat
cake. You'd be like, get the fuck
Outta here. That's never going to fly.
It's not going to fly with men,
but it does fly with women
and by the way they go ahead.
The Fat Acceptance Movement
doesn't just argue that you know,
not being 500 pounds is unattractive
because of the patriarchy.
They actually argue that the medical
evidence suggesting that there is a link
between obesity and downstream
bad effects is all bullshit.
They not done,
not just that they there.
They also point to one incredibly flawed
study that has been widely disproven
that says that there's some sort of
vigor or vitality involved in being
overweight because they get sick less.
There's no,
no truth to that whatsoever.
They only,
they only analyze people who were healthy
at the time. Like it's, it's there's,
you can go and Google the study and find
out the, this criticism of that study,
but it's a hundred percent horseshit
folks being fat's not good for you.
It's really bad for you when you're
as big as that woman on the cover of
Cosmopolitan magazine.
She's literally morbidly obese.
She's fucking dying.
She's addicted to food in a horrible way.
And to promote that and pretend that
somehow or another, this is okay,
and we're gonna, we're going to show
new standards of beauty. You Go,
you giant gelatinous bag
of meat and tissue. No,
that's a dying person who's addicted to
food. She doesn't want to look like that.