Now,
how do you guys start out?
Do you start out like is there a
like a open mic night or something?
If a guy wants to become a rapper,
how do you get going?
Like I'm from the underground rap
scene in that I like these cults rap.
I like battle rap,
that type stuff coming up.
So I was more out of the open mic scene.
Um,
I got to hang around the older guys
and the cool guys and the drug dealers
because I can rap about street stuff.
Right? Whereas you take like a, ah,
he was always interested,
love music and stuff.
But tip was a trap rapper
from the start. You know, he,
he was entertaining for
the streets so he didn't,
he didn't need to go to fucking open mic.
He just needed to be opened up on the
mic and then allowed the greater public,
the hearing, I'm said, excuse me,
I talk about him and I'm in big boy
because there are two of my best friends.
So I know I got poetic license to talk
about those guys where I don't really,
you know, tread lightly with
other rappers. You never
know. Feelings get hurt,
but so there's no need for him to do open
mics as much as just find someone who
believed in him. And
that was um, KP La Reid,
Dj toomp and gave him platform to create
the genre. Now known as trap music. Me,
I came up more of how to, to battle
rap scene and out of thing, you know,
go show your wares. Kind of like a
comic. You get up in front of everybody,
do your shit, see what works, go
home, readjust, come back next week.
So when you do like a battle rap thing,
we sign up.
How would that work those days?
You just threw you in the pit.
I mean it was the first time. Yeah.
You show up. Um, I got my name,
my name, my nickname Scott. Right.
My nickname was skunk or my
family called me Michael. Um,
my friends were the unruly scholars and
those guys were like just east coast
rap.
One was from Connecticut and one's from
South Carolina was family is from New
York.
They could wrap their ass off.
They were like Rakim and big
daddy came in and sang group.
They defeated a lot of
guys may better records.
And then one day there was this thing
called green lights where people will play
their music and then they'd be battled
each other. My homeys income and man,
you could just everybody who
you thought was the homies,
homies was just shitting on them.
And I'm like, what the fuck?
Like this is my homies and
my manager, Rod, GG Mcgee,
who I had just seen like
a couple of weeks ago,
he was the person that kind of pulled
me out of knocking around in a trap,
trying to be a petty drug
dealer into a studio.
And he was the first person
to say, Yo, this kid could
really wrap. Like, you know,
fuck that shit. I know he steals
cars and you know what I mean?
And he rides around, do a hood
rat shit with his ratchet friends,
but he can really wrap,
let's get them in.
So he was the guy that started
bringing me in. So it offended me.
They were talking about
my friend like that.
So I just start fucking off with their
heads paddle wrapping them and a man,
they double Dee called me, killed her
that night. He said his kids are killer.
Mike's a killer. And that's how
I got the name killer Mike. Ah,
what a great story.
So the battle rap scene,
you would just get tossed into a
pit and how much time would you get?
This is in the nineties this
isn't like formal battle rap now.
Like battle rap has
evolved like boxing now.
Like what I'm talking about is
essentially cockfighting. So,
but like when you would battle up
there would be no, no time limit.
You time you just went,
you just went until you won the crowd
or the other guy shut the fuck up and
walked away with his head down. What was
a long battle? Rap Man died that night.
Those guys were still,
I literally took out four and five and
six and those guys were still trying to
come at me before d who was
fucking built like you when? When?
When we were children.
You know what it was like as I
was dede knock you the fuck out.
Just told everybody shut the fuck up
this kid one. So, and it was decided.
All right, these spoken, you know
what I'm saying? Dj Double d gave me,
my mom gave me my rabbinate.
It gets heated man.
I've watched a bunch of them online with
dudes getting each other's face man.
My um, my um, my, my Dj,
Dj tracks star keeps me up with the battle
scene and I couldn't do it like as an
older man, I'm just
saying to myself like, Yo,
I just the how to fought somebody like
straight the fuck up like by day day man,
it's, the disrespect is
amazing but amazing. It's a
martial art of sorts. You know,
it's a mental martial art.
The ability to stay self disciplined
enough not to wile out the ability to give
it and take it. You know what I'm
saying is, I mean it's an art.
If you've ever seen roast battle,
no roast battles with,
they're doing standup comics, but
the same principle. They go, well,
they prepare for it like sometimes like
weeks out and they tell them who they're
going to be battling against and they
write a bunch of jokes about each other
and just shit all over each other.
Ruthless joke writing.
It's on comedy central and Rickles worthy
shit, ruthless shit. This ruthless.
That's what comedy should be.