There's a supermassive black hole,
the center of every galaxy. Yeah.
But there's also other black holes that
aren't necessarily in the center of
galaxies.
So these little ones,
a little [inaudible] a few times the
mass of the sun and they're from collapse
styles. So they are stars
at the end of their life,
very bigger than us and
more massive than the sun.
But they run out of their fuel and they
start to collapse because gravity squash
she's done.
And if they're sufficiently massive,
then there's nothing that
can stop the collapse.
And so they collapse as far
as we know to a point, right.
Essentially an infinitely dense point.
We don't really know what happens.
We don't know what happened
right in the middle,
but they collapsed to such an extent that
there's a region around it where from
which light can't escape. And that's
uh, so nothing can escape and that,
that's a black hole. And what
happens to them? Do they travel?
They moving through space? Yeah.
There, there, there, there still stars.
So they, they still there, um, they,
they surrounded this region where you
fall in, it's called the event horizon.
And if you go across that horizon,
then you are going to the center.
There's one way of thinking about it,
which is quite cool,
which is that at the time and space sort
of flip is one way to think about it.
So in the same way that we are
going into the future now, so,
so we're going to tomorrow,
there's nothing we can do about it.
We are going to tomorrow. Um, in the
same way, if you fall in the cross,
the event horizon of a black hole,
you are going to the middle,
the singularity is called. So
that's, that's your future. Every,
every line of your future points
to the center of the black hole.
So it's kind of the ultimate of
no escape for the ultimate prison.
You're going to get squashed to
an infinitely dense. So point,
not every star becomes a black hole
at the end of its life. Now. Cause if,
if I'm syncing light the sun and we
have a small star, it's quite small.
Yeah. And when it collapses,
there's, uh, there's a, uh,
I saw the pressure of force,
if you like,
which is caused by the fact that electrons
don't like to be very close to each
other. So it's called the
Paleo exclusion principle.
But essentially what happens is that
says they get squashed closer and close
together. They move faster and faster to
get out of each other's way, if you like.
And that makes a force
which holds them up.
And so that creates what's
called a white dwarf star. So,
so you can have a blob of Matzoh,
they're about the size of the earth,
but they're about the mass of the sun. And
uh, so that's, that's for smaller stars.
They end up as these white dwarf things,
which are very dense
objects as another version,
which is called a neutron star, which
is the same thing, but for neutrons.
And they move faster and
faster. So the, if it's,
if it's massive enough that he
overwhelms the electron thing,
then the electrons so fought,
crush into and turn into neutrons
and the whole thing starts again.
And so a neutron star can be,
you know,
elite one and a half times the
mass of the sudden, let's say.
But it can be about what,
10 miles across. So,
so that's an incredibly dense
ball of matter held up by this.
The neutrons moving around.
It's got a fancy name,
it's called Neutron degeneracy pressure.
But that's what it is.
But if you go even bigger than even that,
can't hold it up. And as far as we know,
then there's no known force
that we know of that can hold,
hold the thing up if was too massive.
And so that's when it just almost
winks out of existence, if you like,
it collapses and collapses and collapses
and that's when you get a black hole.
We try it.
Put that into perspective. The, the sun
is a million times bigger than the earth.
Yeah.
And there's this neutron star is,
would you say one and a half times
the mass of the SAS 10 miles wide.
Yeah. Yeah. So, and the loads of that
around that, they're cold wholesales.
So we, we, we see those
all over the place. That,
the first one that was discovered was
called LGM GM one because their spin very
fast.
And then the,
it was called LGM one cause it's a very
regular pulse and they thought it was a
little green men, so they called it kind
of jokingly little green men one. And um,
so yeah, we, we've seen that
there's one called the crab pulsar,
which is in the crab Nebula,
which we saw the CIF for Nova Explosion.
So that's when one of the stars
explode at the end of its life and then
collapses to form a neutron star.
And we saw that in 10
54 Aidy Wa wasn't it?
There's some speculation that our Gao or
our source system at one point was had,
it was a binary star system and that
one of those stars had become a dwarf.
I don't know. Um, some,
someone had said something about that
in relationship to the dense object they
believe is outside of the Kuyper belt.
Yeah. I mean there's some evidence,
the bits of evidence that there's
something out there. Yeah. Yeah.
It could because of the
periodic extinctions and
things on earth that you get
periodic bombardments from out
in the Kuyper belt. So yeah,
I think one of the theories is
the attic extinctions. Well, yes,
I figured out like they,
you know, they've been,
there had been mass extinctions on
earth when a lot of the life died.
And, um, we don't know what
caused all those, but, um,
sometimes their impacts from space,
that seems clear. And so, yeah,
there are theories that there's something
orbiting out there which can disrupt
all these objects out in the kite.
The belt that sends loads of comets and
asteroids inwards to the inner solar
system.
And that can cause havoc.
And so there's some people
look at those theories.