The joe rogan experience.
What does the Scientology network,
what curious. I just started everything.
Get the fuck out of here. Yeah,
and there are, there are advertising
it on paramount hold serious.
Desperate is paramount. Well they
might be paid. They got whose money?
So yeah. Do you ever drive by Scientology
building? I drove by last night. Oh,
I got the test and I want it in there.
I got the test.
I went to one of those things that
you did. I held the cans. Yeah,
I was a film and a TV show for CBS and
we were outside in San Diego and a while
we had some downtime.
They had this thing set up like a stress
test and you go and you hold onto these
cans. They asked you questions I think I
want to say Brian did stand up in there.
So we go up there and do,
I either did standup or like a Ted talk
or some shit in Scientology building.
Really? And he did something weird
to talk. Well, he was taking,
he was taking acting lessons with a guy
who was a rabid scientologist and then I
went to see Brian's acting
teachers sing songs from musicals,
not even a musical,
just the songs from the musical like,
oh, it was amazing. It was great.
Me and Brian were high as
Jesus on the space shuttle.
I mean we were gone. We were hugging
each other. Why it was going on.
We couldn't believe how
ridiculous it was. Like, oh,
he either did like a motivational talk
or stand up there though. Well, he was,
you know,
which is a thing about acting classes.
A lot of my ex girlfriend,
one of her acting classes when I first
moved to La and I started dating,
this chick was an actress.
Her acting class was assigned tology
based act in class and apparently it's
really common. There's a lot,
or at least it was at the time.
They get kind of up with
everything coming out with that.
Leah Ramy or whatever her
name is. Leah Remini. Yeah,
it should be the gigs up now there's,
there's the Internet podcasts when
I'm full of Shit. It is, you know,
some people are just dying to get took.
They're just dying.
So it was like, Yo, bro, you can be
the next fucking expendable seven.
You just got to jump into the Scientology.
I'd probably check it out.
What happens with girls with girls?
Apparently they come to them,
then they'll arrange like boyfriend
situations and weddings here.
That's what happened with Tommy Cruz.
Right. Allegedly Katie Holmes, allegedly.
She said, fuck that noise. Now she's
with Jamie Foxx. I worked for ea
to do, do, do, do, do, do shit.
Fucks linic down and
know shit. Fucking, yeah.
Tom Cruise's uh,
laying low right now.
He apparently did some crazy ass stunt
for mission impossible where they had a
film at like a hundred times. Did
you see it now? I heard Jamie hit it.
You didn't see it.
He jumped from a bit from building to
building that he does all his own stunts.
He's, he is a bad ass. He's
crazy. He does all stats it,
even when he's flying out
of the helicopter, he's the,
he doesn't let anyone else do it.
Okay.