The Joe Rogan experience you anticipating
seeing like a lot of freaky things
come out of China? Yes. Whoa. You said
that very quick. Yeah, no, it's true.
I suppose I spend, I spend a
lot of time in China. I in this,
it's a different meeting,
but the thing with China,
China had this great ancient civilization,
but they destroyed their own civilization
in the great leap forward and the
Cultural Revolution. They,
they burned their books,
they smashed their own at historic
relics and so it's really,
it's a society in many ways it's starting
from scratch and so all of these norms
that people get inherit
through their traditions.
China in many ways doesn't
have and so and so it's,
it's a very different,
and China is growing Monday
are increasingly powerful
in China is going to be a
major Foyt at forest defining
the world of the 21st century.
That's why America has
to get its act together.
That's a hard concept for us to grasp.
When we think about the fact that they
had the Great Wall and they have so much
ancient art and architecture, we just
assume they're a really old culture.
They are, but they wiped it out. That's
crazy. That's why if you want to see,
if you want to see great Chinese art,
you have to go to Taiwan.
Because when the Chinese nationalists
left in 1949 when they lost,
as they were losing the civil war,
they took the treasures and they put
them in the National Museum of Taiwan in
the the cultural revolution,
the great leap forward. China,
the red guards were just
smashing all of their own stuff,
their own ancient history. Now, now the
Chinese Communist Party is saying, oh no,
we're going back and we have this
great 5,000 year old culture.
And some ways it's true,
but in some ways it's like an adolescent
culture without these kinds of
restrictions that other societies have.
That's such a unique perspective
that I haven't heard before.
It makes so much sense in terms of like
how frantic they are restructuring their
world. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and they feel that they got screwed
over because there is this, this vague,
the sense of Chinese greatness.
When you hear the word middle kingdom,
it's like China as the center of
the world and everybody else's,
some kind of of tributary.
And so their monumentally pissed off
that these colonial powers came and
overpowered them and they had to
make all of these concessions.
They had to give land away and and
hell bent on Regainey gaining that are
playing the long game.
They are playing a long game and we have
to be and we are not and we have to be
mindful of it.
That's also something you can do if you
have complete control of your population.
You don't have to worry about people's
opinions or you can just go in the
direction that you feel is
going to benefit the Chinese
power, the power that be,
wait,
this is a country run by engineers.
We per country run largely by lawyers
and, and, and reality TV people I guess.
Um,
but in China it's run by engineers.
So there are all these problems and
the answer is always engineering.
So if you have a population problem,
it's the answers,
the one child policy environmental
problem. You have Three Gorges Dam there.
You don't have water
in the north of China.
You build this massive biggest water
project in the world from south to north.
You want to win the Olympics,
you engineer your population,
you take kids away from their families
and put them in their Olympic sports
school.
So I write about this in Genesis Code.
If you're China and you kind of have
this Plato's republic model of the world
and we're going to kind of identify
the genetic or maybe manipulate these
genetic superstars to be our greatest
scientists and mathematicians and business
leaders and political leaders,
like there is a model that you can
imagine for for how to do it. Wow.
It makes you really
nervous. It should, yes.
That's why like I just feel
like with this country,
we don't have time to have
all of these distractions.
We're focusing on junk. Like what
it just like all of this, you,
I'm on CNN all the time when I'm,
when I'm home in New York and
I always say like you guys,
and I'm talking about kind of geopolitical
issues, China and North Korea.
And when I would say it's like you guys
recognize this is porn like CNN and MSGB.
That's like one kind of porn and Fox
and, and whoever else, info wars.
That's another kind of porn.
But it's all porn and we're just kind of,
we're drawing people's
attention to these few stories.
But there's these big stories that we
have to focus on and certainly the rise of
China is such an essential story for the
21st century because China is competing
in all of these technologies.
And China, it's like go, go, go.
I mean people in China who were
involved in the tech world,
when they go and visit silicon
valley uniformly, they say,
we cannot believe these
people are so lazy.
Like why are they not
working 24 hours a day?
Why are they not issuing product
new products every, uh, every week?
And so this is,
I mean they are racing somewhere and
it's going to have huge implications for
the world. And so if we believe in our
values is that I believe we should,
we have to fight for him.
And the place that we have to fight for
him first is here and we can't, you know,
it's just like every day that we're
just focusing on this, this drama,
this reality TV drama of our government
is another day where we're not focusing
on the big things.
How are we going to get our act together?
How are we going to lead the
world and technology? I mean,
if another example is this is immigration,
like we have this whole fight
of how do we keep people out?
What I'd like to do is to go to to
the State Department's all right,
every embassy in the world, you
have a new job, you have to,
we're going to give you whatever,
a number 500 slots per year.
You have to in your country find
the 500 most brilliant, talented,
creative, entrepreneurial people and
say, we're giving you a green card.
We're going to give you
a little starter money.
We want you to move to the United States
and just start a life and have kids.
And if we we,
we should be creaming the crop,
skimming the cream over the rest of the
world. I think we could take over, we,
we could revitalize this country,
but we're having this fight of how do we
keep a small number of refugees out and
it's just we're not focusing on the right
things. That's a, that's again another
very, very interesting
perspective. We are,
we learned about Huawei in
this country really. Not just,
well I learned about it because they put
out some pretty innovative phones and
some interesting technology but we learned
it because the State Department was
telling people to stop using their phones.
Yep.
Do you think that that is trying
to stifle the competition?
Like to try it like cause cause
the market share that they have,
if they do really have the number two
selling cell phones in the world now
that's not from America. America is
largely out of that conversation. Right.
And if they were in America,
they would probably dominate in America
as well because they're cheaper. Yeah.
And they're really good. Yeah. I mean
[inaudible] they're phones are insane.
They're, the cameras in their
phones are off the charts.
They put some video of the,
the zoom capability of their newest
phone and people were calling bullshit.
There's like, there's no way that's not
impossible, but it turned out it was true.
It really can. It really can zoom like
an a super expensive telephoto Lens.
Yeah. Yeah. So Huawei,
it's a complicated stew.
I for sure.
The founder of Walway is a former
Chinese military officer for sure. Sure.
In the early stages of their company,
they stole straight out stole lots of
source code from companies like Cisco.
Um, for sure we should
be really worried if, um,
Walway is the sole supplier of the
infrastructure that supports 5g all around
the world because that Chinese government
would have access to everything.
And so that leads us to the question is,
one,
is there a problem with
Walway itself? Um, and,
but then two is let's just say,
and I inciting the answer to that
first question is probably yes. Um,
but then the question too is let's
just say Huawei is a legit company and
they're not totally intimately
connected to the Chinese government.
Can we trust their relationship
with the Chinese government?
And the Chinese government has a rule
that every one of these companies has the
big Chinese national companies,
national champion companies,
they have a communist party
sell inside of that company.
And so these,
like,
I think that we can't think of big
Chinese companies just like we think of
companies here. We have to think
of them as quasi state actors.
And that's why this, this fight that's
happening right now is, is so important.
And that's why like when China is out
investing in different parts of the world,
including Africa,
their companies are kind of acting
like arms of the government.
I mean they're making all kinds of
investments that don't really make sense.
If you just see,
well this is a company doing something.
If you say that this is a company with
backing by the state that's fulfilling a
function that supports the state. It's,
it's just, it's a very different model.
So I, I am actually quite concerned
about, uh, about hallway and,
and I'm not a fan of everything
that this administration is doing,
but I think on,
on China,
it's that we need to stand up and I
think pushing back on Huawei is the right
thing to do. I'm uncomfortable
about this for two reasons. One,
I'm uncomfortable about that,
about the Chinese government being
inexorably connected to this global super
power in technology,
but I'm also uncomfortable that it sets
a precedent for other nations to follow.
Yeah. Because they're like, look,
as the only way to compete because what
you were talking about the investments
that Walway or that the Chinese government
makes in these other, these countries.
And that don't seem to make sense if
you're just dealing with a company, right.
But if you're dealing with someone who's
trying to take over the world, yeah.
It makes a lot of sense.
And so when we have our companies that
you're out in some place in Africa and
you're competing with a Chinese
company and to do something,
build a port or whatever,
and you're competing because you are an
American company and so you have your
CAC, I this is the poor, what's the
income stream going to be about it?
And you have a certain amount that you
can bid because otherwise it becomes a
bad investment. But if the Chinese
company is that their calculus is not,
is this a good or bad investment?
It's what is the state interest in
controlling or caused by controlling this
asset.
And so that's why we can't project
ourselves onto the Chinese.
We can't say they're just like us.
Just different.
We have different models and
our models are competing.
Do you think that we should avoid while
we products like consumer? Should I, well,
I think the government should
very tightly regulate, um,
products like Huawei products
because some of their network, uh,
look routers or, exactly.
They've shown that they,
they're using them to extract information.
And so we've,
we have a long history of European,
Japanese,
South Korean companies that
have invested very well.
They've out competed us and we've,
we've allowed,
we allowed the Japanese companies to
outcompete our auto manufacturers.
And that was, that was fine in
the sense it are in the 1970s,
our cars had become shit
because we had this monopoly.
And so I'm all for open competition.
I'm all for free trade.
It has to be fair.
But I think that what China is doing,
China recognized as a state that they
could use the tools of capitalism to
achieve state ends. And I think we
need to be very cautious about that.
That's interesting that you'd compare
it to the automotive market because the
consequences are so much different.
Right.
So much different cause but
we do have a model to go on.
We could see what happened.
We did, we made shitty cars.
The Japanese took over and
then we made better cars.
Like I have a rental car here. I'm
in Los Angeles. And I went to the,
to the, um, the rental
car place said at lax,
and they had all of the different
cars and there was like a,
a Nissan and Toyota, and there was a
Cadillac. And for the fact that, you know,
I said, I'm going to go with the
caddy. So it's a great car inside.
They're amazing. Incredible. The American
cars are very good now. They're great.
And then so like, I'm all for competition,
but I just feel like what Chinese,
some Chinese companies are, it's not
competition. It's, they have become,
not all of them, but quasi state actors
and gift. That's what they're doing.
I think we need to respond to
them in that way. Interesting.
[inaudible].