The Joe Rogan experience.
Some people are failing into
people being really into that. Yes.
He just wants to be admired.
I,
I've known some women like that
who are into dating trolls, trolls,
because they've never had a woman like
that. And they're like, don't fuck.
And they're just,
my sister had a friend like that to her
friend was only in guys that she knew
she could do better. Oh, that's
fantastic. She wanted that.
She wanted them to worshiper. Well,
there's that. There's a state,
apparently there's a psychology where a
lot of men will overfeed their wives and
get them super fat so that they
don't step out on him. Oh Geez.
There's a lot of those subconscious
behaviors that go on. God,
why are people so God damn crazy? I don't
know. Trauma, you know that Carl Young,
is it the Carl Young, uh, fucking, uh,
a line that says that, which we
don't work out in our subconscious.
We will act out as fate in our lives.
How about that?
Cause you will relive patterns.
You'll relive trauma.
You will relive these patterns. Yeah.
And you'll do it on your own terms.
And you'll wonder why you keep far.
Why do you keep dating the same person?
Why do you keep falling
into the same problem?
Why after two years is this go
bad? What? What is that? Well,
there's a way to actually creatively f
at least sit with that and observe it and
be aware of it. That's what
therapy does. Yeah. Goodness.
You make the unconscious conscious.
It will direct your life and you will
call it fate. What a great quote. Wow.
Until you make the unconscious
conscious. Yeah. I mean,
there's a lot of fucking
strings pulling on.
You will direct your life
and you will call it fate.
Knowing your own darkness is the best
method for dealing with the darkness of
other people. Yeah. Ooh, well that's
what Nietzsche, that's why I like niches,
niches, niches. Idea was like, look man,
you can have these false models of life,
which is a lot of times life is a
bitch, right? And you're not going to,
you're not going to be able to
compete or you don't want it.
So what you'll do is you'll go, it's
okay. Meek will inherit the earth.
That's all right, I'll, I'll, hey, you
have money. But is he happy? Is He happy?
You know, there's a lot. We make
all of us do this. We make excuses,
not live our best life. And he was
like, Nah, live dangerously. And, uh,
try to be the best you can be. Just work
your ass off. And if you have to die,
if you have to take risks and die,
leave a good luck in corpse.
Is the idea of turn your
life into a fucking circus.