Oh, superhero movies are kind of
fundamentally ridiculous and silly.
I love comics. I grew up on
him and stuff, but they never,
they never take physics into account
or it's always like you get hit with a
gamma ray, you get powers,
right. It's like, why would
it choose to give you powers?
It would just melt you. Like, that's
not how forces in the universe work.
They don't, you know, generally
speaking, mystically, you know, no,
never gets enhanced in real life
by like nuclear radiation. No,
I don't think that's ever,
ever happened at the boat.
The best theory would
probably be like Godzilla.
Like some monster was born of it
that came out of the ocean. Well,
there was a time where vice
went to Chernobyl and uh,
this was back when vice was really vice,
when Shane Smith was going all these
journeys and shit. That was what was nuts.
Yeah. Before vices, sort of vice. I
mean, vice still does some great stuff,
but vices just as huge
multimedia corporation now. Yeah.
And back then, uh, Shane
went to Chernobyl and, uh,
they were hunting like these
radioactive wolves. Oh my God.
Radioactive Wolves and Chernobyl and
like, you know, there are mutating,
there's fish in the water that are
enormous and they're fucking weird. Yeah.
And you can never eat them.
They're like the fuel efficient or the
plant in a sentence like with three eyes.
Right, exactly. Yeah. But it's real.
Like they really do have these animals
that live in this highly radiated area
and they've managed to survive.
I just guy mean that the,
the level of the levels that we,
that we have taken to get an energy
and affected our environment. We,
you ever dropped San Diego,
you know that ride me drive down and you
look to the right hand side. Oh look.
Nuclear power plant. Right. I could
throw a rock and hit it from the highway.
Like what in the fuck is that doing
there? Yeah. So close to the water.
Well, I think it needs to be close
to the water for cooling. Oh yeah.
That's how they cool the reactor core.
Okay. I think notice how I say that,
like I know what I'm talking about.
That makes sense. Yeah. There's a,
there's a nuclear physicist right now.
Nope. Well, that was the Fukushima thing,
you know, that's, that's what's
happening over there. Yeah.
They still don't have that thing
under wraps. Well and that,
that volunteer army of, of Japanese
people older than 70 that were like,
I don't have long. I'll go work
there. I'll go clean it up.
They're all going back in time.
They're all 39 you go there.
It's like a Stephen King movie.
Amazing. I knew twilight's years old.
They don't want to tell anybody
the commission. I didn't know that.
What got done one on the way to San Diego.
Yeah.
Probably broke how everybody
around it's dead. Yeah.
Cause everyone was throwing
rocks. So Joe Washes. Yeah. Yeah.
But maybe they woke up and like
1980 and they go, hey guys,
maybe this isn't a good place for
a fucking nuclear power plants.
Steam generators failed in 2013 Jesus,
the steam generators.
There it goes. There it is the fuck
out of here with that. It's sober.
Meanwhile that's still there. Like the
core is still there. They can't move it.
It's currently in preparation
to be decommissioned. Jeez.
A however long that takes. Even
Jay's even that means, man,
go fishing around that fucking thing.
Good luck.
You'll catch a big fish though that
no weird. They'll have human hands.
I'll talk to you. Don't, what?
Would they talk with thoughts?
Yeah, right. They just stare at you
and I enter your mind. Fukushima,
they were doing something where they dug
this giant swimming pool and all around
this giant swimming pool they dug,
they put like ice cores.
They put like some sort of cooling element
so they could freeze all the nuclear
waste to an insanely cold
temperature. Wow. It didn't work.
This is like a strategy that they were
developing, but apparently it fell apart.
I don't know what the fuck
to do. It's just you just
don't, you can't do anything.
I mean, I like, they gotta do something.
We've got to keep trying to shoot
it in a space. I don't know.
The aliens are going to get mad at us.