When it comes to meat.
Um,
do you guys prefer a grass
fed beef or do you like, uh,
corn fed?
Because I had this discussion with Tony
and he was telling me that he actually
liked corn fed beef. He's
like, it's a fattier. There's,
there's two schools of thought and then
there's two schools of what is quality
beef,
right?
So one school will say,
yeah,
quality beef is organic animal
pasture raised eating grass.
The flavor is different.
It's not as tender,
but it is high quality beef.
Okay. Then the other of course is,
you know, a cow, USDA
prime cracked corn fed,
incredible marbling,
ridiculous fat content,
restricted motion.
Uh,
I'd say a lesser quality beef.
Okay. Then then the other,
but they all start eating wise.
All pastored at first eating wise,
you know,
grandma pat pound for pound,
the corn fed steak will be more delicious.
Okay.
For some people. And then for
some people the other one will be,
and my,
my mind,
the grass fed organic pasture beef with
it's different flavor for me as a higher
quality animal. I, I prefer that taste
correct. I feel it's a Richard taste.
It's a denser, darker meat. Iron
taste. Yeah. I just like it better.
And I do like a corn fed steak.
I do like and the general public,
the steak eating public that come to
restaurants and counter more corn fed beef
that and they,
their first judge of character to the
quality of that meat is tendering.
It's tenderness. It's marble.
It's not tender. It's not tender.
That's the reoccurring thing
that we fight with every day job.
While they're juicy and tender to
see to a 16 ounce fog walk tender.
I know. I mean, what are they looking for?
Can teeth work but we
get to take sends back.
It'll be because yeah, it's
tough. Yeah. Oh. Dot. Exactly.
It's not advice.
You usually go to this steak house and
it's two more tender because you're
bringing your serving of grassroots.
Sorry, I grass fed or grass fed steak. Uh,
that's not as marbled as it's
not organic. Well, it's an,
it's an oral that healthy, but you can
also have set up great valley. It's like,
it's like the natural wine versus
conventional wine fight. Right.
That we're having, you know? Yeah. But
it's also, we're calling it binary now.
It's like it's only corn
or it's only grass. No,
I think the solution is maybe a little
bit of a corn, a little bit of barley,
but mostly grass fed, you know, a brief
finish and like quality grains, why not?
And then there's a whole other point,
like, I'd like to raise giant feedlots.
I like to sell beef,
uh,
in my restaurant that comes from
very close to my restaurant.
You know, when we opened Joe beef at
the beginning, when that first book,
the first book was written, uh,
beef was a problem back then.
You know, local beef was kind
of difficult. And you know,
we were buying beef from
larger wholesalers and we,
if we didn't know how to read
the barcodes on the boxes,
they would say it was Canadian beef.
But it might not beef,
it might be north northern USA beef.
But we didn't know because only a
professional could read the Barcode.
But they were saying it was Canadian.
But one day I had a professional come
into the restaurant and he said, no,
actually this beef is,
yeah, from a company with
investiture is in Canada, but this
is from Western Australia. And I say,
I don't want to serve anything in my
restaurant from Western Australia.
That's super far. Like I'd like, you know,
this is like remove beef from the
menu or seek alternatives. Uh,
but it's a business that's complex
because there's pastures and feed lots
slaughterhouse and packers. Right.
And, and it's not like a, you,
we have lambs,
got a baby lamb that come from the
parents lamb and then they farm,
they raised the lamb and they bring
it to the slaughter house themselves.
And then we get a lamb. Beef is like
you can get, it's like tracing bourbons,
you know, it's like trading and
brokerage and stuff and we're not,
it's the most sketchy
item on a restaurant menu.
Like I know that I bought land from
you and I know I bought rabbit from,
you know,
Beatrice and I know I got go cheese from
this family and all of the products in
my restaurant.
I know exactly the farm and the farmer
beef is always dicey because beef always
goes to the packer. Beef always goes to
the distributor but fought, you know,
to,
and the general public only really
eats two cuts of beef in restaurants,
you know, three cuts, the tenderloin that
the, what do you call it, an English,
then I'll put a coat, you know,
the loans. The loans, right.
That's what people leave the
hamburgers beefs or not that, you know,
there's two big humps and there's two
big shoulders and there's a lot of brays.
So, you know, it's a,
it's difficult. This is,
we see that a documentary on steak. Yeah.
We're in it. We were in, it's right. Yeah.
You were in it.
What did you think of that and then
their conclusions and what was the
conclusion?
Well,
just basically we're saying to Peter
Luger steak house in Brooklyn is a greater
stake in the world. Da Prime
Corn Fed for taste. Maybe.
It's good. It's good restaurant.
Good. Good story. Good
history. Great restaurant.
I ate there just a few months ago. It was
very good. Yeah. Very good. Yeah. But, um,
but again, it's a subjective thing, right?
The flavor in terms of like what you
actually look for and they as they were
talking about like your customers saying
they're accustomed to a certain type of
meat. Like they were saying that their
customers are accustomed to this.
They're not interested in grasp at
anything. But I understand that, you know,
they've been doing that for a long time
and you're hitting that beef that way
and I don't think they should change
ever. Not based on anything. Right. Well,
it's a great place. We get
consistency. I mean, you go there,
you get this fantastic steak.
It's, I mean it's so old world.
He too and you get in there
that, I mean, how long has,
Peter Luger has been around
for cod forever. Forever. Yeah.
It's 120 years or something.
Something insane like that.
And they get the moisturizers like that.
In my trial,
I was very old steak restaurant.
Moisture's is a famous restaurant
in Montreal and they, you know,
they do have their beef program and they
should not change because there's new
conversations happening. He
knows what he's doing. Lenny
lighter and he should do,
you know,
keep on doing that.