Started as a test.
Jane Fonda workouts though.
Jane Fonda back in the day with the
doggy thing. What was that like?
1970s seven to me.
Damn. Oh, that was crazy.
That was so fucking big.
It was the first time women were marketed
to for exercise. Think so. I think so.
I think before that women may be competed
in athletic events like gymnastics and
shit like that when they were young,
but then when they probably got
families or moved on to jobs,
they probably stopped. What is this
one? Just go aerobic championship.
Oh my God.
Look at this as a choreographed dance.
This is so strange. Wow, that's right.
Do you remember aerobics really quick?
I'm going to take an aerobics class.
Yeah, you remember that? I'll be kind of,
that was people would just dance around
and you would do stuff. Feel the pump,
pop the pop and two and three and go.
They turn.
Everybody gave for about five years, but
it, all these guys, look at these guys.
These guys are straight as fuck and they
don't even know they're doing gay stuff.
You know? It's like, it's like when,
before everybody knew that Rob
Halford from Judas priest is gay.
He used to make everybody dress up like
him because everybody like the kids that
were straight kids,
so we're huge fans of Judas priest.
They would wear the cap and the j wearing
gay aesthetic like gay biker looking
right. Tough guys. Everybody got into
it because they loved him because Judas,
it is so bad ass and he's such a fucking
awesome front man that like he had
straight guys dressing up like a gay bike.
That's fucking hilarious.
And then he comes out and they're all,
they're like, what? This so confused.
But he did it in a
concert. Does 100,000. No,
I'm just saying what if he did and they
looked down and there were y'all wearing
is what I like in my men.
I had him on a show I did once.
It was a like this um,
thing for VH one called the list.
Oh yeah, I did that. You did it
too? Yeah. Here he is. Look at that.
I mean look at the outfit Bro. Seriously.
Wow. The leather paper boy hat on.
Yeah,
well it's more like a soldier's hat and
he's got leather vest on with no shirt
underneath. Leather gloves. It's
spikes all SNM shit. Tight, tight,
tight leather pants.
It's hilarious.
Freddie Mercury. Yeah man. Um,
what was my point? What we're, we're,
we're talking about something right before
we were talking about that. Oh, the,
the, the rubiks. The aerobics
guys. Like, come on man.
They had dudes were in singles. Look
at this. Look at this outfit. This,
that's like a singlet from
wrestling but with long pants. Yeah.
This is bananas that they got man dressed
like this. Good. What they're wearing.
You see their nipples like
their nipples are popped out.
They're all super gate out leg.
There's three quarter length Reebok
high tops. Exactly. What the velcro.
You had to get the velcro. That's the
newest technology especially. Yeah.
So look, every girl is
dressed like, you know,
I guess they look more like why
they have tutors for an outfits.
The girls have some of
them expose the mid drift,
like the dirty girls that they are.
Then the other ones that
we're a a one piece. Oh,
Alan Thicke was hosting this mother
fucker. Oh Shit. Course he was, oh shit.
Look at him. Look at that hair.
It's wonderful. Look at his jacket.
Solve Miami vice doubt.
Yeah. He's got shoulder pads.
You got up,
got to get rid of shoulder pads back
then you could have shoulder pads. Yeah,
I remember having shelter pads
and my first jacket. It's nice.
It makes you look better.
It isn't like a stuffed bra for a girl. It
is. Yeah. It's the same thing. Yeah. Yeah.
But how weird that people,
so do you remember people
actually dressing like that
and in a class situation,
did they go to classes,
dress like that grade school?
We had uniforms and stuff,
so no,
I never took an aerobics class.
But see if you can find video
footage of an aerobics class,
if all the guys that dress like
that, those dudes got punked. Yeah.
Somebody talked to him into
dressing like a dancer. Yeah. Yeah.