Which are crucial to our wellbeing.
And one of them is the capacity to openly
debate ideas and to expose ourselves
to ideas across the gamut. And I'm not
just talking about political ideas,
I'm talking about scientific ideas.
Yes.
So how are we going to win the
battle against anti-vaxxers?
Like how are we going to persuade people
who believe that vaccines kill people
for which there is no scientific
evidence that they're wrong.
We could imprison them like
that's force. Uh, we could vote,
which is sort of what we're
doing. We're saying, okay,
well you're a minority group who believes
these things so we're not going to
allow you to control policy.
Or we could try to win the battle of
ideas and persuade them. Ultimately,
that's the only path that's in my view
that gets us to where we want to be. Yeah.
And
just an honest assessment
of the actual data.
Like what we really know and understanding
how the scientists come to these
conclusions.
But the problem is these echo chambers
where people get involved with online
that magnify,
uh,
all of these beliefs and
you get radicalized. I mean,
I've seen people get involved
in these Facebook groups.
He's anti vaccs face Facebook
groups or you know, all,
all sorts of different things.
I mean that's how these
flat earth people get going.
They start listening only to people
that are involved in this circle.
They don't have a, a greater
understanding of the science involved in,
did you just see,
I just saw online their sec accrues to
the flat or cruise for a flat earth.
I don't know if you saw it to
ice wall. Yeah, the ice wall.
That's a new wrinkle.
Cause the old flat earthers used to think
that the water was shown falling off
the disc of the earth. You know, like the
edge of the earth. They was just a disk.
Now the new theory that
there's an ice wall, actually,
it's kind of not falsifiable.
That is to say you,
you could get on a cruise and sail to the
edge of the earth and you would find a
wall of ice there. So you
Antarctica. So you'd think,
Huh, it's flat. In other words,
they,
they have redefined their theory too,
to make it so that you can't disprove
it. Right. You don't get to an edge.
There's no edge. There's an ice
wall is what they're saying. No.
And Are you aware of Hashtag
spaces fake? No, I'm not.
I have to say,
but not expose myself to that space.
There's a bunch of people that I
believe that space is fake.
It's not real,
but there's no real space and
that there's like lights up there.
Oh.
And that this is some sort of a,
a plan by Satan to a, it's a
lot of, it's very biblical.
It's really interesting. A lot of the
flat earth stop is very biblical. That's,
it has to do with the firmament.
And they use descriptions and
depictions from the Bible. Oh yeah.
It's super bizarre.
And what's really bizarre is when you
listened to the youtube videos or these
discussions that are done by people
that use words that are real,
they string them together correctly.
They have like full sentences.
They appear to be articulate. It's very,
if you're a dummy, if you listen to those,
you go like, wow, this guy's
making a lot of sense. He's not,
but it sounds like he's making a lot of
sense because he's using all these words
that are correctly users. There's
oms. He saying it articulately,
there's like everything seems like like,
oh my goodness, this man is exposing.
He's exposing the reality, but it's
not. It's just fucking nonsense. Yes.
And if you don't know any better,
and that's all you listened to,
that's where your head will go.
The same with the Anti Vaccine Movement.
If you only listen to these anti-vaxxers,
they're making so much sense of like,
oh my God, it's giving everybody,
uh, all sorts of ailments.
Or you're on the spectrum. They have a
theory of how it does that, which is not,
it's uses, as you say, scientific words,
but it's actually not scientifically
correct. Right? It does this,
which then does that, which then does
that, they lay out a kind of causal chain,
which is false.
And then there's a problem of nuance
in perspective because there's so many
people that get vaccinated.
There's hundreds of millions
of people in this country,
billions of people worldwide.
And then there are instances,
rare occurrences where people have
real issues with vaccinations.
Well, there are some where they
have real issues. So for example,
there's some vaccines which are known to
cause certain neurological conditions,
rarely one out of a million
or 100,000 vaccinations.
More commonly is a situation in which
you have vaccination is so common.
Everyone is getting vaccinated.
And often that occurs near
to an occurrence of some
other rare condition. Yes.
And people associate the two, they think,
oh, because of the vaccine, this happened.
No. It's a coincidence. Either a war. Yes.
There's both in the, and there's also,
you know, if it's one out of a million
and you have 300 million, exactly.
You have 3 million, you know, I mean,
1 million people with an
issue is a big deal. Yeah.
With 300 million people. Yes. You,
you easily could have
300 really big cases,
you know,
300 cases where if something died from
vaccines and then you bring those in
front of people and say, Oh my God.
And then there's this one and this one,
this one, and there's 298 more.
And you're like, Holy Shit.
All these people are dying
from vaccines says, you know,
it doesn't feel good if it's your child.
But when we look at the greater
perspective of humanity,
and you say, well listen,
you don't want to bring back smallpox.
You don't want your child to get measles.
Babies can get measles when they
can't even be vaccinated for it.
This is one of the reasons why
we need to vaccinate children,
is to make sure they don't get measles
is a serious fucking problem and a
serious problem that scientists have
labored for untold decades to try to try
off of our civilization. That we can
actually stop these diseases. Yes.
And save children's lives.
I had a woman yesterday who is an
expert and she's a medical historian,
an expert in Victorian era
surgery. Uh, Lindsey Fitzharris,
and she wrote this great book called
the butchering art. And in it,
there's all these images
should shoot one of them.
She brought up of what smallpox
actually looks like when people get it.
It's horrible. Yes. I just
covers people's bodies. Yes.
For radicating this like
in and you die from it.
It's actually gone. Yes. We
don't get it anywhere credible.