Like this is, okay, this is
the tonight show your Carson,
but we figured out a way,
Carson. Now, do you know that?
Right? That's the difference.
That's the shift. That's why Netflix
can't even compete. Netflix has done,
they're not done done. What
are you talking about? You
see Charlie Wilson's war,
no movie about Tom Hanks movie about
America getting an evolved with the Afghan
conflict and Afghanistan board doesn't
really matter, but the idea is this.
They're fighting the Russians,
the Afghanis, right? So the
Americans go, okay, boom,
give them a $5,000 rocket launcher and
they're going to shoot down a $5 million
helicopter and eventually Russia
just won't be able to compete, right?
Netflix pays $100 million to Aaron
Sorkin or whoever to make a TV show,
right? Right. That distracts
you for two hours, right?
Youtube pays zero million dollars to Joe
Rogan and Jamie to make a podcast that
distracts you for two hours every day.
Netflix cannot compete, but it's a
different animal. You got to realize,
first of all,
they have way more people than just me.
They also are putting together something
that requires a lot of money to create.
Sure. You enjoy films or if you
enjoy a show like Ozar, sure.
Stranger things long for narrative.
It takes a lot of money to make
those things are special effects.
There's camera people and
makeup people in here.
There's a lot of lock on our writers and
directors and producers and actors and
he'd say giant fucking tense filled
with people. People aren't watching it.
You know what they're watching?
People are watching them.
They're watching friends. No,
no, no, no. Not 10 free. Dude.
There's a reason they
paid us terrible bro.
It doesn't matter if it's terrible as
Jamie two most viewed shows on Netflix
right now. Netflix doesn't own, okay.
Netflix isn't even trying to make money
anymore. They're getting bought out.
It's Facebook. Uh, Amazon. Do they want
it? That's the goal of the strategy. Now,
the 10 billion in debt,
there's no way they can make money.
There's 10 billion billion Billy and,
but they make hundreds of
millions dollars a month.
Like how many people do they have
on board? How many subscribers?
So they have that are
paying $9 as far as I know,
they don't share that information. They're
killing it in terms of subscribers,
but they're 10 billion in debt. They
just talk on another 2 billion. Right.
When I say Netflix has done, I'm speaking
when anytime I make declarations,
I'm speaking in the future. Right. I'm
like, we prepare now for the future. Well,
how will they hear it goes?
Netflix will keep friends through
next year and $100 million payment,
$100 million, right? For one year
of friends. And then the office too.
That is though, that's like
nostalgia style jet, right.
So all viewing right now is nostalgia
even? Well, not all viewing, no.
If you look at TV, right? What did great
this, this, this past years in TV, right?
The OJ trial and FX. What
does that, I remember I was,
when the Oj thing came out,
did that do that, killed it, won all the
awards, everything. Uh, the Versace story,
which is another thing like what? That
out of the loop. I'm just 39 million,
339 million subscribers paying
$10 a month. Is that what it is?
How much does the cross like that?
Maybe even more.
Maybe 11 how much does it cost? Uh, at,
they just bumped it up to 12 I think.
12 bucks a month. Sure. That ladies and
gentlemen is a fuck load of income. Sure.
So they got a lot coming in,
but they're spending a lot
too because they're trying to,
they're trying to overtake all the others
and then they got Jeff Bezos, you know,
captain moneybags up there,
a scrooge McDuck. Right.
He's trying to do the same
thing. Facebook should, which,
where I saw you right on sneaky
Pete. Yeah. I was like, yeah, true.
But that's the basis can lose money on
this shit because he's making tons of
money on paper towels.
I wonder how much he is losing because
he's got a lot of fucking series at,
ain't nobody watching them
that put it out there,
but he's doing something that's even more
weird because there's no one watching
those shows.
Yeah.
There's a ton of fucking shows on
Amazon that fucking no one's watching.
Yeah, I would like to see their numbers
because I bet they have some shows.
They might, they might have
spent $1 million to make
and have like four viewers.
It's fucking, no one watched these
shows. They were just going after awards.
They're thing was,
we're going to make the artsy shit,
oh it's going to give us a grammy or
something like that and then we'll like
qualify our platform.
It's a smart approach.
Like youtube approach was the
exact opposite, right. We're like,
we're just going to create this stuff
that we think people want to watch. Well,
Youtube doesn't create much. They did a
little and they took down the paywall.
Like my thing I, my guests with
youtube is there waiting for Netflix.
You know that scene in the movie where
like that's somebody's caught in like an
enclosed space and water starts coming
in and the water gets right up to like
his lips. You know, he's like,
he's trying to breathe a little bit more
and I think youtube just is going to be
the one to pour the last drop of water.
I think it's such a different thing.
I think you're talking about two totally
different things because Netflix has
never aimed to be a user created content
streaming site. Right? Right. They're not,
but at the end of the day
it's just distraction I think.
I think that's what we've got to start
looking at content as, right. It's, it's,
it's just raw distraction and Netflix
occupies a space for distraction did
smaller than youtube, so I can watch
a two hour thing on youtube at home,
on my TV.
I can watch a two minute thing on the
bus as I'm going to work on youtube,
you know, I can watch
a 15 minute, you know,
peace like Vlog or something like that.
I can watch all the whole spectrum.
Netflix, I'm really just watching
at home or like a foam on a trip,
you know what I mean? It's really, I'm not
watching a two minute thing on Netflix,
you know what I mean? It's, it is
the shit for now. Don't get me wrong.
It absolutely the shit for
now. Right, but if I was being,
if I'm putting my money on it,
I would say if I'm Facebook I buy it and
then imagine having your Facebook feed.
You just watched a show and then you
get to share it immediately on your
Facebook.
If I was Facebook I'd be super careful
about buying anything because I think the
government's been thinking about breaking
them up for a while and Elizabeth
Warren is already talking about that.
That's one of the parts of their,
her platform and running for
president is breaking up apple,
breaking up Facebook,
breaking up.
Twitter just wants to break up all
these things. She are monopolies.
What's your feeling on that?
Get the fuck Outta here with that first.
She is goofy. He's Goofy
as fuck. What's up?
Disney takeover of 21st century
Fox takes place I think next week.
The 20th to Bega. They are going to
put out their own stream. Everything.
They've just,
they bought like everything except for
Fox News and Fox sports took over all of
their production movie facilities,
like 5,000 people might be
losing their job because
it's coming off a Netflix.
Marvel shows all that shit is
going to come over to them.
So now they're going to
have a nice [inaudible].
That's why they've been canceling
all these marvel shows on the flower.
I keep investing in something,
right. You're going to take off,
like I'm going to build up a brand
and then remove it, right. You own it.
They've got so they got all the
kids movies. You're a bear at that,
you know what I mean? Dude, I go to
Disneyland twice a year at least.
Which you're gonna not have
the streaming Disney program,
will they all apples also starting their
streaming service soon tomorrow or some
show and knows when, but there's
tons of rumors are coming out today.
You know what it's like, you know the
perestroika, like what happened in Russia,
like where the overnight, you know, it
fell and they sold off the state assets,
like a few people and everybody
came. Billionaires. Right.
That's what's happening right now in
entertainment. Dude, don't realize it,
but like,
it's fucking done.
Like the days of the days of like
fame being about distance are done.
Distance, distance. Like I'm Johnny Depp.
I'm going to go to way to my little home
somewhere in the Alps and you will see
me twice a year. You're not, I'm weird
on Marlon Brando. I'm, I'm out here.
I'm weird. I'm different. You know, it's
like now it's proximity as reasonable.
No value in being weird anymore. Well,
Marlon Brando, Tyler Perry has an island.