The joe rogan experience
like that's been solved.
You know, I, I'm into the geopolitical
and domestic policy shit, right?
That's where I, I was drawn more about
what's really going on, you know,
behind the news, all that sort
of stuff. This is bullshit.
And I was lucky to train a lot of law
enforcement and then military high level
military and get connected to Intel
guys who go, pat, we need to talk.
Like now you're completely off. Let me
explain things to you. Right. It was like,
as far as like, what will you
completely off about? Well,
I can tell you what I was right about when
I called up my buddy and I go, hey, uh,
four years ago, whatever it was,
four and a half years ago, I go,
we're funding Isis, aren't
we? He goes, well, yeah. Yeah.
Those the go between guy.
What do you think?
I'll news row Isis friggin Al Shabaab.
W what are you fucking think
fun dices to take out Syria?
It was obvious,
right?
The mujahideen in Afghanistan was
the frigging take out the Russians,
but the way I looked at it was
when that was going on funding,
the mujahideen was to
bankrupt Russia. Right? Right.
We wanted them to go bankrupt
and it worked. Reagan was,
was a genius in that park. The diabolical
part, of course, is rushing in America,
both fighting over the resources of
Afghanistan, but Isis was just theirs.
That's some weird shit.
When you have a 50,000 man army just
appear out of nowhere with professional
cameramen and editors and producers and
directors making the high level films
that they were putting out
where it's every three seconds,
they're cutting different
angles professionally put
together films of people
being burned. I go, this is this.
This is too weird. This is too weird.
You know when people stop talking about,
do you remember when they blame
Bengazi on some bullshit video,
some video that someone made?
Right.
What's it like the tears of Muslims or
something like that or I forget that.
Nobody even knew it existed.
Nobody knew it existed and everybody knew
it was bullshit and they were pushing
that as a narrative. Like this is
what was the motivation behind.
And everybody was like, what have you
had Perato on your show? No. Who's this?
Uh, Toronto's last name. Former
seal. What's his name? Toronto Peel.
Rol Name. T a. His last name's Perato,
but I think he's a former seal.
There were several seals obviously
that ran to try and help, uh,
the ambassador and some of the other guys,
Toronto lived through it,
but you know, he, when he talks about it,
they're moving massive amounts of
weapons through Libya, into Syria,
into other places in the Middle East,
right there.
It's just a fact that it's happening.
And that whole thing going down I think
was a way for them to just cover it all
up or remove and erase any people that
knew about it. You know what I'm saying?
That's the way it spells out to me,
pretty obvious because it's documented,
it's all documented that weapons were
being moved. And if you look at, um,
arsenal weapons manufacturing in Bulgaria.
So de Leon had guts and shy by who I had
on my podcast, the conspiracy. Right.
She was the Bulgarian reporter that got
fired for it. Now you had a podcast?
He has called the conspiracy farm. Oh,
okay. Yeah. Oh, I'm going to Google it.
We don't, we don't start the
conspiracies. We just add the water,
but I've got to click the name.
Yeah. My cohost Jeffrey Wilson.
He's a really bright guy. Cool. Cool name.
Yeah. So we have fun with tee shirts.
Can I wear it?
Conspiracy theory that was going to bring
you on and why he couldn't ship me one.
So I will, I will. Okay. Yes. So it's
a bar. It's a barn with a CT Fletcher.
It's a barn with a satellite and the
satellite dish down next to the bar. Oh,
that's hilarious. That's it. Are you doing
it out of Iowa? Oh yeah. Perfect. Yeah,
it's pretty, yeah, that's right. But,
um, arsenal weapons manufacturing,
she exposed,
the Isis fighters took here.
I took her to their weapons caches and
there was massive amounts of artillery
rounds, depleted uranium
stuff, a small arms stuff,
and it was all arsenal weapons,
Bulgarian weapons. Right?
And she got fired for exposing it. Now
at the same time, silk way airlines,
who is a Azerbaijani airline,
they're manifests,
got exposed by Bulgaria and anonymous
with manifest of all the white phosphorous
weapons, the depleted uranium, our
artillery rounds, all these shipments,
massive shipments going into Turkey,
going into Libya, going into the Ukraine,
right? We're a bunch of
shit was going down there.
And every one of those places who showed
up, the broker, the deals, John Mccain,
Whoa, John Mccain, right?
And look, we can't prove it,
but there's people telling
me that potentially there's
an offshore company that
owns a big percentage of arsenal
weapons manufacturing in bull. Right?
So that's the kind of stuff I'm going in.
I'm into who's who's causing it?
Why are they causing it? The truth.
I'm just a truth seeker. Right, right.
Would you seem like that kind of guy?
For sure.
Do don't you think that that stuff is
exposed at a level that's never been
possible before because of
the Internet? Yeah. Yeah.
And that these people are probably
used to operating in a certain way that
they've been doing for decades and now
they're having to adjust. Yeah. Well, and,
and people like you just doing
these podcasts and talking about it,
which opens the minds of other people
and has them thinking about it. We,
you know, w w who are the people
screaming the most of the, I wasn't, uh,
I wasn't even a Trump supporter.
Right. I'm a rand Paul Guy.
You got to fucking Rand Paul Shirt
on right there. Ron Paul Guy.
You've got to teach him, take down defense
off of a lawn. A lawn mower. Right.
So you got blindsided in his
defense, right? Yeah. But yeah,
I was that about this neighborhood tack.
Those neighbors alluded tech. Right.
Good Times.
You know,
but it's a risky thing to do live right
next to a guy and attack them like
you're a fucking burning the bridge.
I don't know what kind of sentence
that guy got though. I don't,
I haven't kept up on that,
but that was given sentence.
Yet during the presidential run,
I was given speeches for Rand Paul,
a couple of them to introduce him.
So I give a speech,
then bring him out and I got to know him
a little bit better in Iowa. Yeah. Yeah.
Amazing Dude. We had great conversations.
Big Fan of his dad. Yeah. Yeah. So, uh,
but the people that are yelling the most
now about Trump and all the other stuff,
you wonder what they're guilty
of, right. The deep state is just,
it is a way of doing business right there.
Smash and grab.
There's pay to play,
smash and grab his,
me as somebody who is very powerful in
government, going after an industry,
crushing, it ruined that stock.
And then my buddies by the company,
right when the stock collapses and then
bringing it back up like the Gi bill for
a University of Memphis,
we go after it.
No longer will there be any
GI bill money put toward that.
The stock goes from 100 down to $3
Obama's buddy goes in and buys it.
Then they go, wow, we're going to
allow GI money to go back into it. Now.
Stock goes back up. Right. That's the
kind of shit that's going on. It's,
it's some bad stuff and we just do
our best to follow it. Educate people.
And we have a lot of people to say you're,
you're not,
you're wearing a tin foil hat. Well,
you just talking about Jamie, about, uh,
something that you'd seen
about politicians being
exempt from insider trading
rules.
Someone on Twitter. I couldn't, I'll find
the name later, but, uh, if this guy,
he told me about this guy, his name's
Peter Schweizer. He's a Stanford
per secret empire. So that's the
book. That's the book you want to,
he wrote Clinton cash also.
Yeah. There was another book
that he hit me up about. Yeah.
But this is the one they had.
Have you had him on your show? You have
no, that's a guy that I've been here.
I would love to have them on
how the American political
class a hides corruption
and enriches family and friends. Yeah.
Without a doubt. There's that Shit's real.
Yeah. Without a doubt. That
shit's going on. I mean, look,
we were just talking about this recently,
about how half of what it is to be
president and is to get yourself into a
position where after you're out,
you can make these crazy speeches for
these bankers. Like why is that? Like,
I mean it's, it's almost
like a man. I tell you,
there was a time when a good friend of
mine who was an agent for me at the time
got me involved because of all
the years in MMA and martial arts,
I've met people from all over the world
who had eventually moved in the piece up
positions of power in government or
cities or this or that. And so they said,
we want you to help us get our foot
in the door to sell waste to energy
projects. So it was basically a
facility that bonds anything garbage.
I mean, you can burn tires in
the thing at low oxygen levels.
So the emissions are very low, but
that generates electricity, right?
And in Europe it was everybody
from the city province,
uh, that country and the European Union.
Everybody wanted a piece of the projects.
Right? That's just the way
they do business in Europe
and South America and other
places like that.
They have to have a different model
for it here for the corruption. Right.
They just do things differently
here and that's just the way it is.
They've made adjustments and either way
they're going to find their way around
it. Yeah. The idea that there's no
corruption is ridiculous, right?
No one thinks that.
So it's how much corruption is there
and how how many people were out there
exposing it and their neck
out there to expose it.
That's a big part of the problem
because if you really know about it,
that means you're probably
entrenched in the system too.
And the cognitive dissonance of the,
the citizenry of knowing that Hillary
Clinton and a few other people sold,
you know, the document just came
out. It was 15 million kilograms,
15 mil million kilograms of
depleted uranium. Yellow cake,
right.
Sold to the Russians.
At what point in any part of
a discussion on any planet,
is it okay to sell your enemy 15
million kilograms of frigging uranium?
What was the justification behind it?
Dev,
they agreed that this is a fact
and this is, it's a fatty greed.
I mean there's this, is there any dispute
that this is a fact? No, there is no,
there's no they, but they sit
there and use the excuse. Well,
there was eight other people that
had to sign off on this. Right?
What does that mean? Right.
But suddenly that company,
suddenly that company invests $145
million in the, in the Clinton Foundation.
Yeah. That's a big problem. That
Clinton Foundation is fucking insane.
And all these people that were blind
supporters of Hillary that didn't look at
that like, how do you not, how do you not
find a giant problem with that? Right.
And that book by Schweitzer talks about
it, he goes in detail about that stuff.
Yeah. I'm sure. How's his sobriety?
I'm surprised that that's what
that was just going to say.
He's not going after the Russians do it.
Clinton cash was bad enough.
This one's even worse.
I'm surprised he's not dead.
I wonder how many people are actually
reading it. You know, it, I just,
I feel like they think that there's always
going to be a certain amount of that
stuff out there and they just
tolerate it and they just,
as long as it's not really fucking
up their business cause it's not,
the politicians are still allowing it.
Law enforcement still allowing it
and no one's really going after them.
It makes you wonder like if Hillary had
actually gotten into the White House and
she faces the same scrutiny that Trump is
facing right now over the Russian pros,
we know none of this would be uncovered
had she won. Right, right, right.
Know that right.
Yeah.
All of this stuff would have been swept
under the rug most likely and all this
stuff with McCabe and uh,
uh,
struck and page and call me and all
these people of going out of their way to
try and derail Trump to get these FYSA
court frigging spawn surveillance,
frigging warrants to spy on a president
elect and then a sitting president.
Are you kidding me?
At what point is our people not,
not charged with treason
for that? Right. When
they were recent, they were doing this
spine before he ever won the presidency.
Don't you think that if he was doing
something wrong with the Russians,
they would have frigging
made it mainstream news
and and bustled him for it?
Yeah,
there's for sure some dummies in his staff
that made some inappropriate meetings
and had some, I mean they definitely
had some intentions. Well,
but they had something on him.
The way I look at it as this,
I mean if you win the presidency, I'm
going to send whoever is underneath me.
If I'm the president,
we have to have meetings with diplomats
from other countries to make the
transition. That's, that's
part of the, that's part of
the deal, right? It really is.
That goes on.
That's just the way it is.
But that's not what they're talking about.
They're talking about
before the presidency.
They're talking about having meetings
with Russians long before, right,
where they had planned this whole
thing out. Look, they got enough.
They're all dirty. They got
nothing. They got nothing.
I mean like if they had something new,
it would be out there.
It's that projection and diversion
and everything else, because you know,
the Podesta is,
we're doing lobbying for the biggest
friggin Russian bank in the world, right?
Right.
In Washington DC that it never comes up.