The Joe Rogan experience. You
like cars too? Yeah. I love cars.
I know you love cars. I love cars.
You got a corvette? Tutoring.
Yeah. 65 I know, man.
It's fucking bad ass too.
But you didn't know that. I'm a car
in that too. I do know your car.
Not We talked about it. We did.
Yeah, we get, Oh, do you have,
what do you have?
Oh,
I have a four Corvettes for,
I know you were a corvette
man. Damn. I have a 65,
a 72 or 74 and [inaudible] 71 I got,
I see threes. Threes. Yeah.
That's wow. Damn you are good on
that day. You speak about, yeah,
that's yours too. Oh, that one's nice.
Black with the side pipes
as for 27 try carb. Right.
That's a beautiful one that sent me to
that. So that's all generation three,
right? Yeah. My, my, my, uh, my
neighbors hate me. That fucker is loud.
I bags. The gap year is amazing.
Those, those are gorgeous cars, man.
And compared to what you can, but you
know, I like it, man. I loved them.
I love Corvettes. I like the new
ones too. I like all of them. Yeah.
Well you got something else besides
a corvette too? I heard about,
but I haven't seen, I seen the
corvette, but what else? Um,
I have a 69 Nova that they're
building right now. I did something,
I think I did. Yeah. And you,
everything's like super new. It's, yeah.
Yeah.
I don't like old shit.
Fucked up suspensions. We
can't go around corners. Yeah.
I'm not interested in dying.
Not like that. Oh yeah.
I like what they call [inaudible].
[inaudible] that's yours. Oh No, no. Well,
yeah.
Um,
the yellow one I got from a guy who's
a plastic surgeon and that was like his
bottom of the line car,
but he did everything to it.
It's got the suspension and everything
and that's a big difference. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I could try that
thing anywhere. But the, uh,
the black one for 27 try carb.
It's old school,
old school all the way and breaks.
No, no, it's got this spray. Yeah.
That's where you gotta draw
the line. Yeah. Yeah. Got
It. I gotta be able to stop.
Gotta be able to stop it. That
fucker is. And actually I like,
I like shit like that. I, I
wouldn't mind the restaurant,
but I liked the, I like,
Oh shit man. I just,
I like old houses and I'm like,
oh, cars. I collect old bikes.
Yeah. Just old shit. I just,
shit man. I do too. Yeah.
I think this character to old things.
Yep.
It's like either you like it or you don't
like some people just like everything
new and modern and shiny.
Like when I started making money,
I started buying older cars.
I like older shit does have a
different feel to them. Totally.
Totally. Totally. I have a, uh,
yeah. Yes. Is to trade his truck,
man. What did I get this? I got that. Uh,
probably six months ago.
[inaudible]
see I liked it motherfucker. Man.
I look at all the Patina on that.
It's a crew cab or for 61 crew cab.
Find those creek and it came from
the factory. A crew cab. Man,
that truck looks like me.
Bashed in windows.
Shit's cars. I love it. I love you.
Tried that around that motherfucker.
You know what? I'm waiting there.
I am going to get the body work done on
that motherfucking because it's got some
holes in it. Oh, it's pretty
beat up. Yeah, it's pretty.
I got to get the body though.
There's something to that.
When you look at those old cars,
you realize that they don't make
anything like this anymore. No Man,
they didn't fit the style. Uh,
they really put a lot into style.
Carson 50s and 60s.
Man do now,
but it just doesn't seem the same
look good. Like a new core Vat,
like a 2019 corvette. It's a beautiful
car. But you look at that old truck,
it does not have what that truck has.
It's like you put it,
it'll put a smile on your
face. Just driving it, man.
One of my biggest joys is it sitting
behind the wheel at one of those old cars.
Man.
It just makes me,
I feel like a young mother fucking when
I'm sitting here like a kid. Yeah, yeah.
Oh, like a ride. Like you drive it around
the ride. It is, yeah. It's so much.
You pull up to a stoplight, some
mother fucking in the, the chronic,
some guys give me a thumbs up and I
be cheesing from ear to ear when that
happens. And you don't even have to drive
those fast. No. Yeah. Even that corvette,
you don't have to. Every once in a while
it's fun, you know, break them loose.
It's a little funny to break them with,
but yeah, you don't have to drive.
Well for a power lifted though,
it's almost like mandatory for you to
have some sort of a muscle car. Yeah,
I guess so. It's like, it
goes with the territory,
doesn't like a big block
engine. There's, you know,
somebody got a video of you
driving by. Yeah. That's hilarious.