So I think this is it.
There's a bigger discussion.
I think both of you could probably shed
some important light on too outside of
Twitter.
This weaponization of content
from platforms is being
used to get people banned
from their banking accounts. You
know, they're getting there. Uh,
we can talk about Patrion for
instance, and again, I'm not, this is,
this may just be something you
could chime in on. Patrion band,
a man named Carl Benjamin and
also known as Sargon of a cod.
He's also banned from Twitter.
And it was because you know why he
got banned from Twitter. Um, I can see
that's an interesting one.
Uh, I do have some, some
of the details here. Um,
do you want me to read them? Okay. Um,
it looks like it's going to be growth.
It's not stuff that I love saying.
Um,
but I will say it should make,
he doesn't like cursing either. Um,
let's see. I curse more than he does,
so I guess I should say it a first strike.
Um, fuck white people kill all men die.
CISCOM none of the above qualify
as hate speech. Was that,
uh, I don't have the dates, I'm
sorry. But he's, he's a white guy.
I mean obviously he's joking around there.
Fuck white people.
It also sounds like he's trying to make
a point about your roles and how you
enforce them. Not actually also exactly
why you got kicked off patriarch. He was,
it was exactly.
Well,
I know he also posted a
photo of interracial gay porn
at some white nationalists
to make them angry. Yes.
Yeah. He's funny. He's funny.
I'm dying.
I can understand how a posting that photo
is that an egregious violation of the
rules, whether, whether or not he
was trying to insult some people.
That's a very good point.
And I wanted to bring that up.
Is Porn a violation of the rules?
Uh,
porn generally? No. Good.
Really good for you.
Why would he bends in
my feed all the time?
I follow a couple of naughty girls
and occasionally they post pictures of
themselves engaging in intercourse. I'm
like, yikes. So then what, what else,
what are the other strikes for
Saigon or car? Let's see. Um,
there was the use of a Jewish
slur. Um, how do you use it?
A to a person.
You trader remainer white
genocide supporting Islamic file.
Did you slur lover
that should keep you going
Hashtag Hitler was right.
But these are general opinions. These are
targeted. They're targeted at somebody.
That sounds like he's being sick.
Like he's making a joke.
You're going to say understanding context.
It sounds like the other one,
like in context what he's
saying, particularly the
fact that he's a white guy,
that doesn't sound like
a racial slur at all.
I mean he's saying fuck white people
and he is white and context. Again,
these are tied together. I always knew
that person was not to be trusted.
That fucking Jewish slur.
Oh you saying there's a bunch of very
specific person trying to be very precise.
A specific Jewish person. I don't know
the race of this person. I'm sorry.
And this is not okay, but this
is it. This is not parody.
This is not joking around. We didn't
view it that way. I'm just telling,
I'm not trying to like re litigate all
this. I'm just telling you what they were.
I knew he had done things that were
like egregious violations of the rules
because you know, plain and simple,
I didn't bring him up to, you know,
go through and try and figure out a feat,
but that it does sound like at least the
first one was meant to be a critique of,
yeah. So there are a bunch of others.
If you want to hear him more than that,
keep it rolling. Again, targeted,
this is how I know one day that I'll
be throwing you from a helicopter.
You're the same kind of malignant cancer.
Don't forget it. Um, so there's this,
it's not one thing or two things or three
things. This is like a bunch of them.
He could imagine thinking,
going to throw someone from a
helicopter helicopter. But admittedly,
and I so, so he, he, he,
he's on youtube by the name of Sargon
of Akkad is a big account and I've
criticized him for being overly mean in
the past and I think it's exemplified by
angry, but, but he, he
is a very different now.
And I guess the reason I brought them up
was not very different now. How so? Well,
a lot of the content, he
makes as much calmer. He's,
he's less likely to
insult someone directly.
He makes probably recognizing that
he's on his last straw. Oh, definitely.
Essentially kicked off of Twitter.
He's on Youtube.
He's probably got a mind his
p's and q's. Oh, but so, um,
the reason I brought him up again,
but we'll move on was that activists
found a livestream from eight months ago.
I totally forgot why I was bringing it
up because we've moved so far away from
where we were. But, um, they,
they pulled a clip from an hour and a
half or whatever into a two hour live
stream on a small channel.
They only had 2000 views sent to
Patrion and then Patriot said, yep,
that's a violation and banned him out.
Right. Without warning. Which again,
I understand it's different from what you
guys do. You do suspensions first. But,
uh, I guess the reason I was bringing
up was to talk about a few things. Um,
why blocking isn't enough,
why muting isn't enough.
And if you think that it's
driving people off the platform,
people post my tweets on Reddit, I
blocked them, they use a dummy account,
load up my tweet, post it to reddit and
then spam me on reddit. So you know,
blocking and even leaving Twitter would
never do anything short of me shutting
up. There's nothing you can do
to protect me or anyone else.
Look, I mean, these are exactly the
conversations we're having are one,
the reason why I don't think blocking
and reading or enough is one,
I don't think we've made mute powerful
enough. It's spread all over the service.
Uh, you, you can use it and then you
got to go find where you actually meet.
These people are under their profile
page and that's just, uh, it's not a,
it's a disaster. It just doesn't work
in the same way that it should work.
In the same way that follow works,
which is just the inverse event,
I noticed that now I get
a notification that says,
you can't see this tweet
because you meet it.
This person right before I would just
see a weird reply and be like, oh,
it's one of those. Exactly. So
there's also all this infrastructure
that we have to fix in order to like pass
those through in terms of what action
you took or what action someone else
talked to be transparent about what's
happening on the network. The second, um,
the second thing that block is
really interesting. I think it's,
uh,
my view is it's wholly an unsatisfying
because what you're doing is your
blocking someone. They get notification
that you've blocked them, uh,
which may embolden them even
more, which causes, you know,
others around and ramifications from,
from the network.
But also that person can log out of
Twitter and then look at your tweets.
Uh,
just on the public web because we're,
we're public so it doesn't feel
as as rigorous and as durable.
Something like making mute much stronger.
I guess the challenge is no
matter what rule you put in place,
people are going to
harass you if you're a,
if you're engaging in public discourse,
you know,
if I go out in the street
and yell out my opinion,
somebody could get in my face if I get
off Twitter cause I'm sick. I mean look,
you know, I'm sure you get a way more
than I do, especially as you know,
the high profile probably getting it
right now. Yeah, totally. Oh me too. God,
I can only imagine, but so, so
the only thing I can do is, look,
we're not on Twitter right now.
We're on Joe Rogan's podcast and they're
still going to target you on Twitter.
They're still going to, I guarantee
we're all of a reddit. The the,
the leftest probably railing on me, the
rights wailing on you guys. So it's, it's,
it seems like even if you try everything
in your power to make Twitter healthier
and better,
it's not going to change anything
that I'm not sure about that because one
of the things that I do think is that
just,
I'm not in favor of a lot of this heavy
handed banning and a lot of the things
that have been going on particular
like a case like the Megan Murphy case.
But what I think that
we are doing is we're,
we're exploring the idea of civil
discourse where we're trying to figure out
what's acceptable and what's
not acceptable and you're
communicating about this
on a very large scale and it's putting
that out there and then people are
discussing it whether they agree or
disagree with a vehemently defend you or,
or hate you.
They're discussing this and this is,
I think this is how these things change
and they change over long periods of
time.
Think about words that were commonplace
just a few years ago that you literally
can't say anymore.
Right. You know, I mean,
there's so many of them that
were extremely commonplace
or not even thought to
be offensive 10 years ago,
that now you can get banned off
well, soaps for, but that's,
that's a good point to argue against
banning people and to cease enforcing hate
speech rules. I agree with that
as well. I think it's both things.