Yeah. I got into all the gas
monkey garage, Jay's garage, uh,
getting that gas monkey guy on the
show. Oh, Richard Rawlings. Yeah.
I just got an email yesterday. Fuck
yeah, I love that guy's a fucking right.
I love that guy.
Ask him about my favorite episode,
my favorite fucking episode of that.
Cause he always like,
I watched that show so much.
I knew the number he was going to come at,
they'd be like, okay, what
do you want for this gun?
And he always get them to say it first
and they'd be like, yeah, I mean I was,
I was thinking like a five
grand and then he'd be, oh wow,
he's five now, man. I can't,
I mean, I mean I could do,
I could do like 2,700,
right.
And then the fucking guy would then go
down to four grand and he would come up
like, like 300 bucks and he'd end up
getting the car for like three grand.
Like whatever the fuck you want it.
Right?
So one time he went out and he
busted this guy down on like a f, uh,
an old trans am or a
Firebird is some shit.
I forget what the guy sells
it to them for like fucking,
he wanted like 18 grand or something.
He sold it to him for like 11.
So he fucking gets the car over there.
He's talking about he's going to do about
with it and all of a sudden the guy's
brother calls up and says,
Hey,
that guy didn't have the fucking right
to sell that car. That's also mine.
You got to, you know, I'm
going to come down and got,
I got to buy it back from you. So the
guy comes down and he's, you know,
asking what he wants for it in
Richard's just like, I mean,
I was thinking like 20 and
the guy goes, he goes, dude,
you bought it from my brother.
I know what you paid for it.
He actually got embarrassed.
He's like, Oh man, that's sorry.
It's the only time I ever saw him
get like embarrassed. He wasn't,
he just went into like his, his
thing and like, I swear to God,
like watching that show,
like you get better at like
negotiating and like, uh,
and like occasionally he does
like the sketches to where he,
he'll do like a character imitating like
an old school used car salesman and you
just how good he does it. Cause you
know, it's like he's a performer,
an actor or anything. How good he
does. It's like this guy is like,
this is just in his blood. He's just
been a car guy. He's been flipping cars.
I'm trying to, I'm seeing the
show in a minute, but like,
he used to talk about how he, uh, uh,
you know, by the time he was like 19,
he was on like his 30th car or something.
Like, he was just like, I liked that car.
I'm gonna buy this car. I like
that one. And he was just,
every month would just
flip them. Um, those cars,
there's something about
those shows that it, those,
an auction shows or anytime
like a pawn shop shows,
there's something about wanting to
know how the deal plays out. Yeah.
That is so compelling for people.
There's something like, and I'm a moron,
I'll just sit there staring like,
how much are they going to get?
How much are you gonna get for that?
Yeah. Who that civil war coins,
what are those worth and how much
say down and just like, yeah,
I mean that Guy Richard.
Richard's probably the best I've seen.
He's the most entertaining cause
he's like a fun guy to watch.
It's a performance. He's like, aw
man, I man, I was thinking, Oh man,
I don't know. Yeah. And then he goes up
there and he pulls out this giant Wad.
It's like, dude, you
had, you had the money,
the other guy has to
sit there and watch it.
Then he kind of makes fun
of him afterwards. Yeah. You
know, we can kind of make,
you know, in a funny, like a
funny way or whatever. But um, um,
it's a funny thing to that
how appealing that is to men.
Like I bet if you looked at the number
of women who watch those car shows versus
the number of,
like Neil motor trend has a channel now.
They have their own channel
and I guarantee you that
is 97% dudes and 3% women
complaining. 3% women going,
what the fuck are you watching?
Like if you looked at the actual numbers,
like what is it about cars
like girls can drive cars,
girls drive cars all the time. Girls
liked cars. They don't like cars.
The way guys like cars, it's just
most of them generally speaking. Yeah,
I'll say like Danica Patrick and a
few psychos. Yeah, I met her one time.
Yeah I saw a picture with you.
She took me around.
The Indianapolis Motor speedway is coming
down that straightaway and seeing like,
you know where they have the leaderboard
and everything was iconic and I've been
to that race a couple of times
so it was crazy. And as we going,
she ended up, she only went like
half the speed of what the car,
how fast they would be going or something.
And we got up to maybe like one 40 but
we were like going around turns and like
my face is doing this.
But what I loved about her was
she had like test pilot vibe.
Yeah. Like she came up and it was
just vice like handshake and shit.
Beast. Yeah. It was
pretty, uh, you guys are,
yeah. She was just totally
like a difference in her
sunglasses. In my sunglasses.
I definitely, I have
passengers, sunglasses. You
know what he's talking about?
They look the same. No, no, no. Those
are like right off the fucking shelf.
What's wrong with your sunglasses
or his or hers? Like you'll see it.
I don't tell him the details.
Come on, man. That's like
we, you know, I, I probably,
you know, your crescent kick
probably looks to save his fucking,
some guy in a strip mall to me. I mean, I,
he said crescent as one of the
rarest kicks anybody ever pulls off.
It's leftover from the 80s, whatever.
Um, but that's kind of legit.
Cressend kicks kind of legit.