Gear. It doesn't give you that
part, you know? Yeah. What was the,
um, so you had gone through
a series of ketamine therapy.
Yeah, I did. Uh, I did the tms. The uh,
cause I was looking to at the last time
was here was this alliance, Dermal Mag,
transcranial magnetic stimulation
and which worked that men,
the problem was, and I think, I don't
know if I talked about on here or not,
I h someone gave me some HGH. Did they
tell you that human growth hormone? Yeah,
basically.
So I did tms,
which transcranial magnetic stimulation,
45 sessions. It worked great.
Like it literally stopped taking,
it takes like 35 minutes and they just
put like electrodes on you are so I think
I have video. Um, they
put, uh, they put, um,
they, yeah, they put video on, uh,
looking,
Chris rock t sends me every single uh,
uh,
rape thing.
Oh my God. Everything that
comes out, every sink,
every page six f literally he
sent me 25 of these. I don't know.
It's just like a thing now because
then we go like, I just like literally,
it's just like a tick.
So for the morning there's
so many guys not real Batali.
And by the way, the more salacious they
can make these stories, the better.
They were talking about some room that
Mario would take people up to and the
third floor was the rape room.
I'm like,
what in the fuck off me
laugh is the SEO habit.
Yeah. The uh, you know what
makes me laugh is the, um,
the pictures of Louis got
progressively worse and worse.
Oh, the ones that get fined
like the New York Times,
I was waiting for them to just put up
a picture of Lee Harvey Oswald fucking
hits. You don't have to find
the shittiest, the guilty
is looking picture of this.
So much video of him beating
off air, beating on, you know,
play that video like this.
This is the last time
was here or this is unlined? Yes.
From last time you were here. Yeah.
Wow. Look at that, man.
Give me some volume. If I am
talking about, I went to this,
whoa dude,
that sound is like an Mri.
So it's an APP. That's what
it is. Yes, that's right.
We talked about last week right
here. Um, the uh, but uh, case.
So then the problem was after that I did
HGH for someone gave me some HGH and I
was like, yeah, I'll fucking take you.
I don't want to give a shit. Yeah,
I'll take HGH.
I'm always looking for an advantage.
And I started having panic attacks
from Hga. Yes. Which is a, we,
it's a narrow side effect, but it's one
of the side effects of HGH. Basically.
It like supercharged my whole system.
I started having panic attacks on stage.
I had a panic attack the night before.
I take three mikes.
Why couldn't go onstage?
Spade was supposed to bring me on and
I told Adam, I was like, I can't go on.
I literally couldn't breathe.
Wow.
The night before you
fell? Thankfully, yes.
I thankfully didn't get one that
night. Like, oh my God, dude, trust me,
trust me. And then I, and
then I had anxiety for months.
Literally like, just like when people say
I have anxiety, I had never had anxiety.
I was like, I'm not an anxious person
and wouldn't even know what that's like.
It's fucking miserable.
It's,
to me it was worse than depression
because you're agitated and like,
you just feel like static. It just was
like a static over your body. It was like,
you're, you just have
like this, like cortisol,
snow in your, and it
sucked. So I went back on a,
on a Zoloft, um, to, and then it ended the
anxiety now. But you were trying
to get yourself off of it.
Yeah. So now I'm going
to go, I'm, I'm back.
I just stopped taking Zoloft for like
two weeks ago. How did you can't,
I feel actually really good because,
oh, here's what I didn't say.
I also micro dosed do,
uh, while I was on Zoloft,
I microdose shrooms, uh, like three times,
which is actually like pretty fun.
It's Super Fun,
but it's like not daunting. It's not,
you're not like, it's not trippy,
right? You're not like, oh
yeah, you just feel good. Uh,
I did that three times a did
LSD once and I, I'm thinking of,
so now I'm going off and,
and interesting happened when I microdose
I got significantly less angry just as
like an operating principle. Like I
was just like, oh, I'm less angry.
Like I just didn't feel as
like snappy and shitty. Um,
like for a long,
for like an like an over big period.
I've got a buddy of mine who's a world
champion kickboxer remind her doses and
he fights on it fights high on mushrooms.
Do they test for it or are they,
it's just, nope, that's fine. I fucking
people up while he's on mushrooms.
That's great. And I mean better
than he's ever looked in his past.
He said he could see things
coming before they happen. Yup.
He said he'd literally feels like he's
got some sort of psychic ability when
he's sparring. Like he sees what guys
are doing and if you watch him fight,
he just looks way sharper than
he's ever looked before at home.
Boys doing mushrooms.
Yeah. Then that's the, so I've been,
I stopped taking it all
off because you can't, uh,
you can't be on it. And
do I have a game? Uh,
you can, uh, you risk serotonin syndrome,
which is like it too much serotonin in
your body or Nah. Yeah. Yeah. And so
were the first guy that tell me about
five HTP before we even started selling it
and all that before we
started having a mood,
you were telling me about five HTP
and that you were at Sandy Anto
told me about no shit. Yeah. Cause I,
he saw me some ecstasy and he was like,
yeah,
and also take the next day and I was
like Mongo and then I like research and I
was like, oh, I should just take.
So I still take that five inch.
I think it's good for
weight loss. Really. Um,
it like when I take five
HDP, I'm just not hungry. Um,
it like that was the other sort of
weird side effect of the micro dosing.
My appetite went down like
significantly across the board.
Wonder how much of the appetite is
not really how much food you need.
But rather you need something
to do. Yeah. Or it's just like,
at this time of day I do this.
Um,
but I ended up like losing 10 pounds.
That's interesting to me.
Like one 50 from,
I've lost 12 pounds from like
one 59 to one 47. Wow. Yeah.
But it's not like a, not starving
myself or anything. Right.
So you didn't feel uncomfortable? No,
not at all. He was like, yeah. Yeah.
Do you monitor your diet? Are you,
do, are you eating healthy? Yeah.
Like I got my blood tested probably
three months ago and everything was good.
Do you, are you eating sugar and
bread and things like I've eaten,
I've stopped. Uh, I've eaten.
I used to be a big dessert
person and I kind of just like,
I think the mushrooms might've
maybe just kind of like, Eh, you,
I think that you don't, um,
and don't sugar, you know,
the thing with sugar is you don't need
it for three days if you don't want it.
Right. Like you just, your
body doesn't like, you got
to fucking get us some sugar.
You're just like, Eh, I'm
good. Once you cut free. Yeah,
and especially if you're really conscious
about what you're eating in terms of
like probiotics and things that
sort of help the landscape,
the biome landscape and make sure
you've got healthy things in there.
I think that's so significant in the
more researchers that I talked to and the
more people that are nutrition experts
to start talking about your gut biome and
how important it is to
take the proper probiotics.
I think it affects your personality.
I think it affects your immune system.
I think it affects virtually the path of
your life that you take depending upon
what foods you eat. It has a different
effect on how you live your life.
Well that's,
meditation does the same thing cause
you're like you get a feeling for
meditation and then you're like,
do I want to spoil this with like garbage
thinking or behavior like running?
Just try to bring a bit of that
in know in my every day. Yeah.
I mean that's the tank for me.
Yeah.
The tank is literally forgot about tanks
until you and I'm like I live like a
block from float lab. You got
to go like I, I went, I went.
I think you must.
How long have you been doing this?
2002 was the first time I got one.
When did you start doing the podcast?
I think you told me about it.
You told me about it.
I went to float lab.
Had the thought in the, in the
tank. You got to love something.
Literally that was the thought.
I had an and then I got a dog.
Literally like he's always like,
I fucking like that,
that I like that shit.
Like and I just forget that it exists.
The tanks? Yeah, I think they're
giant. I think it's like one of them.
It's one of those things that requires
you to block off a chunk of your time,
so if you're a busy person it's hard to,
it's hard to pull it off,
but I think it's like one of the
most important things you could do.
How often are you doing?
Well,
I haven't done in a long time because
I took the one out of my basement and I
had it installed here.
It took me a few,
few times off and we just
got to put in two days ago.
So I haven't even been in it. So I haven't
been a tank at all and three months.
Oh Wow. Two months, two
months, something like that.
How often do you think you'll do it now?
A couple of days a week.
A couple of days a week is good. If I can
give myself two days a week, I'm happy.
Do you ever go in and just think
about your daughters? Yeah,
sure. Yeah. Yeah. So it's
not, I don't like have a plan.
Sometimes I have a plan,
like maybe I'll have a bit and I'm trying
to work out and I just like this bed.
It's just clunky.
There's a part of it that's clunky.
I'll smoke some pot and climbing that
tank and think about it. There's a
in the, in the, the, there's like a pre
fucking syllabus for the Ibogaine and
it's like you need to come with questions.
Ooh for Ibogaine. Well for
sweet lady Ibogaine. Whoa.
And it's like I have to write.
And then a friend of mine was like,
can you ask a question for me? It's
like, no, I don't think that's legal.
Okay. So where Lucy needs,
it's about what's going on with her feet,
but I'm like looking forward to asking,
asking big questions.
Although I gotta say the last year has
been very revealing for me in terms of
like what,
what's important.