Out of Iraq and Afghanistan. It's a waste
of time. It's so stupid. Why are we the,
we need to rebuild our own country.
And you know,
those are tweets where I read that
and I go, I totally agree with that.
Donald Trump 100% but then the other
half the time when he was on the campaign
trail, he spoke about how, you know,
we need to bomb isis to smithereens
and we need to wipe them out.
And those things are
kind of contradictory.
Either you bring your troops home and you,
you know,
didn't you think he would be able
to fix everything really quickly?
Wasn't that one that one of his premises?
Typical Trump, you know, bloviating like,
I'm going to be tremendous.
I'm going to be amazing.
It's gonna be the best job you've ever
seen over. It's not a bad impression,
but you got to change the tone
because I'm not doing the full hand.
You doing good movement. The movements
I have is the movement. Joseph Rogan.
Can I call you Joseph?
What did you think personally when you
saw Kanye with that insane and ask you
about that too. Bipolar ramp. Yeah.
I feel kind of bad for him. I do.
And I'm not,
and I want to be clear,
I'm really not saying that as a partisan
thing because even if Bernie Sanders
was president and Kanye West was in
the office saying the exact same stuff,
I'd still be like, Whoa, what is going
on here? Yeah. Yeah. Did you burn?
It helps them do it too.
Because remember when he left those
black lives matter chick type to remember
that. I remember that cost
him, but he just stepped aside.
That really did cost him. You think
so? Yes. Yeah. People do. You can't do,
you can't just take the microphone
away from someone you know.
So here's an interesting question.
Do you think this helped Donald Trump
at all with black voters having Kanye do
that, but how much a good number.
Really? You think so too? Yeah, I do.
I don't know. I don't know
because I feel like there's a,
Kanye West has been disinvited from a lot
of cookouts now as a result of what he
did with Trump. Jamie's on black Twitter.
Jamie says, not at all. From what I read,
it did not in black Twitter.
So this response has been very negative.
So it was con Kanye is
really almost in a sense,
blowing his own reputation on this. I
guess that to said, I don't think so. No.
I think everyone who's a fan of Kanye
west who's seen him blow up on Jimmy
Kimmel and blow up on all these different
people that have criticized him, he's,
he's obviously got mental health issues.
When he went on that rant, I think it was
in San Jose, is that a concert? He said,
I didn't vote, but if I did vote, he
was, I would have voted on Trump. Yup.
And everybody went and then he wound up
going into a mental hospital after that.
Oh Wow. Checked into a mental
hospital and then canceled his tour.
I remember that.
I do remember that.
That was because he couldn't handle
the criticism. It's part of it.
And also part of it, he's legitimately
mentally ill. I mean, look,
he didn't marry that lady and be a part
of that family because he's thinking
straight. He's got some problems. There's
something wrong with them. Yeah. You know,
he's a genius in terms
of music. He's, he's,
he's fantastic at creating
beats and songs and hooks.
He knows what the fuck he's doing there,
but he,
he's got a problem and
you hear it when he rants,
when he's ranting and when he's
talking about Ford making dope cars,
we don't use the word dope cause we only
use words like magnificent and positive
words like he's,
he's making,
he's listening to himself and jerking
off to the noises that are coming out of
his own mouth.
I love,
I loved when he said to the reporter
when the report or pushed back on them a
little bit, he's like, you
just asked me a question. No,
you can't do that because this is like
taste and a fine wine. It's complex. Yeah,
exactly. I thought that was really funny.
My read on him is sensical. He's he,
I think part of what he's doing
is that he's a contrarian.
And when you are in a place like Hollywood
and you're there all the time and
you're always surrounded by
people who are anti Trump,
I think there's something about just this
knee jerk reactionary feeling of like,
like, no, I'm not with you guys.
I'm different and I'm special as a
result of being different. So I'm a,
I'm a contrarian and I'm
going to disagree with you.
And then I also think there's narcissism
in the sense that he looks at Trump and
he really sees himself in Trump and that
everybody laughed at Trump when he said,
I'm going to run for president.
I'm going to win.
And if you remember a few years ago,
Kanye West said,
I'm going to run for president.
And everybody was laughing at him.
Wasn't even a few years ago. It
was recently. Yeah. He and uh,
what the fuck's on guys
named Piers Morgan, right?
Right into it on, on Twitter.
Who said you're talking to your future
president? That's what Kanye says.
Oh my God. Maybe it was
Harvey Levin. He said it too.
You're talking to a future president
actually dislike piers Morgan more than I
dislike Kanye West.
Kanye on that one.
I think Connie's ill. Oh really?
Do. And I know he's been medicated.
I mean remember when he was all
Chubby and he's on his medication,
he got fat and apparently he got off
his medication and there are a lot of
people,
by the way,
who would hear the point you made and B
would be really angry at the fact that
you think that he's mentally ill even
though I think that's a problem I've seen.
I've seen it all my Twitter, I've
seen it on my Twitter. People saying,
oh it's just a cheap partisan hacky point.
Oh it's not because he's
admittedly mentally ill.
I mean he's been in say that and the
thing he said, I was diagnosed bipolar.
Institutionalized.
Yeah.
He spent time in a mental
hospital for being mentally ill.
And when you listen to him brand,
this is just my opinion.
That is not the ravings of someone who's
carefully considering the implications
of each word they're saying and thinking
about how to express themselves in a
way that's going to portray
some sort of a clear,
cohesive message. This is
not, he's not what he's doing.
What he's doing is jerking off.
He's just jerking off with his mouth.
I'm not kidding. It's just,
it's just like, let me get
it out. This is a fine wine.
You know, we gotta, we gotta
make the dope. It's caused,
why can't fly by the
dump was cause you know,
did you hear what he
said in that same thing?
The reason why we got to help Larry
Hoover is because in a different universe
there are alternate universes.
I am him.
I don't think that's correct.
So song lyrics to a song.
Was it saying he says that when
he's off his Lexapro? Yeah. Oh No,
you ain't see nothing crazier than
this Nigga. When he off his Lexapro.
Remember that time in Mexico?
Remember the law that last time,
the episode asking me, why the hell out
texting code four times just to say,
don't text me Ho told you four times.
Don't text me how and we
Finna lose all self control.
But you ain't Finna raise
in your voice at me.
Especially when we end the
Giuseppe still modern day Socrates.
Larry is, man, it's lit, but I love that,
that nothing crazier.
Then when he's off his Lexapro,
oh my God, yeah. I do kind of feel bad
even though this is such a, you know,
like a side show type thing because I
mean the state of the country so weird
that beach simply because of his
celebrity and the fact that the mainstream
media doesn't know how to
keep their eye on the ball.
You never know who can become president.
It could be somebody like Kanye.