I appreciate, I don't give a fuck style
more than any other style of comedy.
For me, my favorite shit was like,
first of all, Joey Diaz, but then the,
when you go back to the greats,
like Kinison and Hicks and this guys
didn't give a fuck. They went out,
they went off and it was the most
fun to watch as a person who was a,
an audience member for me was the most fun
to watch. And I think, you know, that's,
that's the shit that
I got. And it's, yeah,
we grew up on that and then society
changes. And I'm like, no dude, I've been,
I've been working on this for so long.
Please let me,
I have to change my entire like foundation
of what I think is funny now because
it's almost like,
and that's why I think guys like Legion
of skanks and then the specialist's name,
it Legion of skanks me in big J.
Okay.
So big would constantly
cheat on his wife and uh,
it was like a regular car and she
knew it and everyone knows it.
And one time we were there and then we
were hanging out and we were about to
leave. They were in an argument and she's
like, fuck you, why don't you go, hey,
how was your legion of
skanks and me and pick j?
We were both playing guitar hero at the
time. There was like a big game in town.
We both looked at each other.
We were like guitar hero name and
that's what we named our band initially.
And Guitar Hero, um, was legion of
skanks and then we're not that creative.
So we wrote a script. How long ago was
this? Probably 10 years ago. 10 years ago.
10 years ago. The name. And then that was
the guitar hero band. Maybe if I'm more,
probably more, yeah, actually way more.
Cause it was right with me
in big Jay became friends.
Um, and then we wrote, yeah,
Legion of skanks is a great name.
It's probably one of the all time
greatest names of anything, right.
You stop and think about like bands
or television, legion of skanks.
That is eight. Great. Thank you.
Thank you Jeff. Great Name. Yeah,
well I've got to give it a big Jay because
he recognized it immediately and then
every project we ever did since then has
been named Legion of skanks until the
podcast worked. It's good move. Yeah.
And it uh, yeah, it's, you know,
people know what they're getting.
They get it, dude. They get it.
And to be honest with you, people,
people want that type of humor.
That's the other thing is
like, it's the new alternative,
um, is like dirty, edgier,
ballsy shit. Well, it's when we
were talking about earlier, look,
if you like punk rock,
you should be able to listen to punk rock.
But if you like the kind of comedy
that some people like aggressive,
like outlandish comedy you like,
if that's what you like,
then you should be able to
enjoy it or not. It's up to you.
It's like you don't have to like it.
You don't have to listen.
You don't have to watch.
It's not that it makes you immune from
criticism if people don't like it.
But you know, it's, everybody's
got different tastes it,
and to be honest with you,
if I wanted to sit here and deconstruct
everything that could trigger me in life,
I'm just not a bitch.
I don't,
I don't sit here and I'm
triggered every moment by the,
the amount of shit that I've seen in my
fucking life. Everything triggers me,
everything triggers me.
And every movie that I watched it,
if there's some fucked
up scene, I can go, oh,
that reminds me of some fucked up shit.
Um,
but you have to appreciate those things.
Don't you sort of want sort of
everything to be represented.