The Joe Rogan experience.
Well there are a lot of people that
are growing marijuana that are using
pesticides and chemicals that are,
that are dangerous. And there was one,
what was the company that
got caught recently? Jimmy?
They tested their stuff cause she
put I believe, yeah. So that again,
cause she punched it with the microphone
and fucked up it cushy punch. Um,
we had a guy named John Norris on the
podcast and he wrote a book called hidden
war and he started off his career
as a game warden. You know,
I'm investigating people
that caught too much fish,
things along those lines and he thought,
Hey, what a great job this would be.
I'm going to get in, get a
job in the great outdoors.
I love the outdoors and you know,
I'll get to do some good
for the wildlife. Well,
turns out along the way they started
stumbling upon these public land Mexican
cartel grow operations where they
would grow these marijuana plants,
just giant plots of them. And they would
use these extremely toxic pesticides.
And also they would use
poison to keep animals out.
And they had vats of this shit laying
around and some of the marijuana was
actually infested with this shit.
Yeah. Yeah. My friend, uh,
Amanda Chicago Lewis is
this great journalists,
folks focused on marijuana and yeah,
she put the fear of God in me about
those pesticides and carcinogens. And um,
the other thing is just
like these, you know,
these different oils
that people are smoking.
Some of them are marketed
as like all natural,
but they find synthetic cannabinoids
in them. And basically, you know,
synthetic cannabinoids like K two and
spice are what they're known as sometimes.
And those are the people
call it synthetic marijuana.
But the big difference is that, um,
THC is known as like a partial agonist.
So it will like these receptors, they
will, it will activate them to an extent.
You're chill, it's relaxed.
But the cannabinoids,
they also interact with the
cannabinoid receptors same as THC,
but they're full agonists.
And so they make you basically like go
crazy and your heart starts beating fast.
You start, um, people overdose and
die on these, these cannabinoids.
And um, they, these are
all made in China too.
I went into a lab in China where they
made these and they made fentanyl analogs.
They let you in? Yeah, I mean
it was, it was a whole thing.
I like wrote them on the internet. I
made a fake email address and I said, um,
I'm a drug dealer, I'd
like to visit your lab.
May I do that when I come to China?
And they said, yeah, yeah, that's like,
do you have a fake drug dealer
name? Um, I called myself,
what did I call myself? Uh, I tried,
I had this like Skype avatar
picture where I looked like a bro,
like a 23 year old dude with like
big hair, like kind of a stoner look.
And uh, they just, um, they
said, yeah, come by. And so,
so I went to Shanghai and uh,
I met this guy at the train station and
he owned his own lab and he asked me if
I was a journalist actually like
pretty straight away. He was like,
are you a journalist though?
And I was like, nah, like no,
crazy question. Do I look like
journalists now? And so he didn't,
he didn't know whether to trust
me. So we went to his apartment.
It was like the top floor of this fancy
high rise. He's a total family man.
He had like lived there with his wife
and kid brings a stranger to his home.
Yep, yep. Meets a guy who
says this is a drug dealer,
picks him up at the train station, says
Hey come to where my kids sleep. Yeah,
exactly. Wow. And so then he showed
me, cause he had there the website,
a lot of these companies in China,
they make legitimate chemicals
and recreational chemicals
and they specialize in
drugs that are legal in
China but banned in the West.
So band in the U S so all
is illegal in China. Well,
in the U S we have this thing called the
federal analog act. And so that bands,
all these drugs even
before they're invented.
So anything that's similar to marijuana
structurally or in fact anything that's
similar to opioids is just automatically
banned, automatically scheduled.
But in China they have to do
it one by one, by one by one.
And so fentanyl itself was scheduled in
China was banned in China decades ago.
But these chemists spent
like this when I met,
specialize in this window when something
is banned in the U S but it's still
legal in China, but it's become
popularized on the internet.
So there's all these websites,
these web forums where these like
drug nerds basically are like,
you can't get fentanyl but you can get
this thing that's kind of like fentanyl
and that's hilarious. Drug nerds.
Yeah, yeah. That's what they are.
And like psycho naughts, I'm sure
you've heard of Psychonauts, right?
They specialize in these new,
uh, usually psychedelics.
They tend to prefer that have never
been tested on human subjects.
But this guy was entirely
specialized in, um,
fentanyl analogs and
synthetic cannabinoids. And
so he took out, you know,
he had his like fake list on his
website of all the legitimate, you know,
like Cialis and you know,
legitimate pharmaceuticals,
things like that. But
as a, at his apartment,
he showed me the real list and
that had all these, you know,
it was a cannabinoids, fentanyl.
It was like fake Vallian,
like different types of Xanax.
And he showed me the prices and I was
like, all right, I'm looks good. Can I,
can I go see your lab? And so
finally he decided, he trusted me.
He called up his driver
on the phone and um,
the driver showed up and he was kind of
this big like muscular dude who didn't
speak any English. And I was a
little worried. I was like, Oh,
this is the dude who's going to break
my kneecaps if when he finds out I'm a
journalist, you know,
but I just got in the car and we drove
like 30 minutes to the outskirts of
Shanghai and we got to the lab and it
just looked like a regular office park,
like a suburban office park.
There was a fountain in front of the
building. There was like, you know,
you use the key card to
get in the parking lot.
And then it looked like kind
of a new construction building.
It smelled like cement. We
went inside, um, we went up to,
to the labs, all the windows were open.
It was the middle of the winter and it
was kind of a strong chemical smell. Um,
but it looked kind of just like
breaking bad, like, you know,
like industrial sized
glass where, um, you know,
beakers Bunsen burners, all that
stuff from high school chemistry.
And, um, he would point, he points
up like basically I had my recorder,
you know, on my phone and I had it,
um, in my jacket pocket just on record.
And so he told me I couldn't take pictures
and so to take notes I would just say
stuff aloud. I'd be
like, Oh, that's um, uh,
oranges, a light orange mixture that's
being mixed up by a mechanical arm.
And you say it's benzo fentanyl.
A very interesting. And so, but,
but the language barrier
was such that he, you know,
didn't think I was being too
much of a weirdo that, uh,
I clearly was, but so,
but the cannabinoids would w were
crazy. There was like a table like this,
like almost exactly this size that was
piled up with the cannabinoids that were
there for drying and it was uh,
they were mounds like this high just
sitting right out in the open Zillow like
pot? No, because it's
not a plant, you know,
it's just basically it's a chemical
that's sprayed onto plant matter,
like dried Sage and stuff like that.
So they try to make it
look like pot and you know,
you can smoke that stuff out of a
pipe or even rolled into a joint.
But if you look closely though,
it's very clearly not pot. Wow.
And so they're drying this stuff.
That's what I think that, you know,
they also had like, um,
drying machines they looked like a mad
at or didn't like it when I use this
term. But you know,
when you go into subway and there's
the bread baking machines right there,
it looked exactly like that. Why did
he not like that term? I don't know.
I think he thought subway would
Sue us or something, but, um,
that they had those and then they had
like big buckets of one pound bags of
these, these cannabinoids and these
fentanyl analogs just ready for shipping.
He said they were sending them to
Russia, to Belgium, to the Netherlands.
And then I think a lot of
times it's repackaged there.
And so I don't know if you knew that
the cannabinoids used to be sold legally
and head shops like 10
years ago. Yeah, yeah.
And they would always be
in these colorful packets.
They almost looked like
a pop rocks package.
They say like spice spice
and laugh out loud and stuff.
And so I think in Europe
that's where they do that.
They put it in this colorful
packaging. They, um,
and then they ship it to
the U S and um, but yeah,
he was saying that like,
he kept like really close track of
the law and all these countries,
especially China, like they're
scheduling this next week.
So we're going to take all
this and throw it away.
And I thought at first he was
like probably just putting me out.
But I think they actually do that.
Like these guys are businessmen first.
They want to make money and
going to follow the law.
It just doesn't, you
know, it's not conducive.
This is where bath salts came
from. Right? Exactly. Yeah.
Bath salts tend to be Kathy unknowns.
So synthetic Catherine was there,
have you ever heard of the cat
plant? K? H? T? T? Yeah. So the,
the hijackers pirates in Somalia,
they, they take that. Yeah,
it's really popular in the middle
East. It's like, it's a stimulant.
It gets you really w um, have you
tried it? No, I never have. Yeah.
But I, uh, grew up in Minnesota though,
and there's a big Somali
population and so a lot of,
there was a big controversy in Minnesota,
whether or not to ban cat leaves from
being sold in regular stores. Is it legal?
I think it is. Um, I think it's not
legal in the U S now if I'm not,
but I don't know for sure.
Interesting. But so H a T. S yeah,
exactly. And so the synthetic cathinones
are the synthetic version of that,
like made in the lab, but
they're there, you know,
there's tons of different kinds.
You don't know how strong it is.
And the bath salts, um,
they of course it has nothing to do
with like salts for your bath. You know,
this was a misnomer and they also
wrote called them like incense,
sometimes plant food.
And on the back of all of them it would
say not intended for human consumption.
So that was like the way they got around.
They thought they could get around the
federal analogue act because part of the
law says that something is automatically
illegal if it's intended for human
consumption. So these guys were like
not intended for human consumption.
Just put it in your bath. Yeah. You bet.
It smells like fucking toxic chemicals.
Yeah. Do you remember when the homeless
guy ate someone's face? I remember that.
And they said he was on beta. Yeah.
But that was actually disproven.
There was none found in his system.
Cannibal Causeway. Cannibal. I think that,
yeah. And he was just crazy. Right. I
think he may have like smoked some weed,
but yeah, I don't think he had
any thing else in his system.
It was just high on life. Yeah. Oh man.
Florida original Florida man. Yeah, it is.
It's funny that one state is so
synonymous with fuckery. Yeah.
And they also had this thing called
Flocka. Have you ever heard of that? Yes,
I have, but I don't remember
what it is. It's more Catherine.
And like if you look it up on YouTube,
there's all these people
going crazy that killed like,
I think maybe a hundred people
in Florida during a time. And um,
the problem is, you know,
like the prohibition on drugs causes
people to do really stupid things,
right? So you have this
cath known like Flocka.
And as bad as that was,
once they banned flock, uh,
the chemist started manipulating
the chemical structure.
So they change one little thing. They
add like a chlorine group for example.
So like a, a chlorine
like molecule, you know,
it has nothing to do with the drug,
but they just added on there
to make it so it becomes legal.
But then it becomes more difficult for
your body to like digest it so it becomes
worse for you and the high becomes worse.
And then they ban that and then they
make something new that's even worse for
you. And it's just like down the
line and, um, and these Chinese. So,
so that's what all these new drugs have
in common. My, my book is about, uh,
they're called NPS novel
psychoactive substances.
So fentanyl is the most
famous and the most dangerous,
but these include basically like
synthetic new versions of every drug.
So there's, you know, marijuana, the new,
the NPS version is the
synthetic cannabinoids. Heroin,
NPS, Virgin is fentanyl.
There's LSD. So you take LSD,
it's like a wonder drug, right?
No one has ever died of an LSD
overdose. You know, people may have, um,
thought they were a bird or
whatever and jumped off a roof,
but no one has ever overdosed
on the drug itself. But,
but once they started banning, once they
started really cracking down on LSD,
these Chinese chemists
started manufacturing this
new type of psychedelic that
was sold as acid. And so if
you went on the dark web,
this was like in the, like
10 years ago or so, 10, five,
10 years ago, you would
search for acid and it,
you would think you were buying LSD,
but you're buying this new psychedelic
that could kill you and did kill you.
These drugs are called N bombs. It's
like the worst name of all time. Um,
these, these N bomb drugs.
And they started killing people in
like the suburbs in Dallas fell.
Um, and, and yeah, you
really were a music editor.
Yeah. So, so these kids all, um,
thought they just wanted, they,
they did their research. These
were like smart kids who said, Oh,
Alice D has never killed anyone.
Let's get that, this new thing.
And it killed them. And so it wasn't
really LSD, it was just, it totally,
no note. Nothing in common at all. Yeah.
[inaudible].