Hello Freak bitches. And we were just
talking about Chris Cornell. We uh,
found out last night at the comedy store
that he died and then this morning and
found out that he hung
himself. Just fuck. It's,
it's hard to even comprehend.
How do you comprehend that I'm,
I'm living in a parallel universe.
Doesn't make any sense.
Like how could someone like,
you know, it's easy on the
outside looking in. I like,
I like that. But you're like,
that guy was one of the best ever.
Like how does a guy like that
even want to kill himself?
How does the lead singer of sound garden,
to me,
it just really kind of reveals of
the complexities of human life.
Yeah,
exactly what you're saying.
To have a guy that is at
the pinnacle of his skill,
the Pinnacle of fame,
the pinnacle of money,
and for him to say, you know what, not
going to do it anymore. Yeah. I don't,
I don't know what was going
on in his head obviously.
Who knows if he was on medication, if he
had some sort of an issue, health issue,
who knows? I mean, I would
never speculate, but it
just, I don't understand.
I mean, again, I don't know his life,
but I couldn't even comprehend it.
I can't even imagine it. Well, it's,
that's one of the really hard things
when you start talking about suicide for
people that for someone like me and
I haven't had suicidal thoughts,
right.
So when you,
when you go from that to somebody that
not only has the thoughts but then goes
ahead and executes it, it's
very hard to comprehend. Yeah.
I've met people that have done it before
of I've added a few friends that have
done it. I just have never understood it.
I don't get it, but I don't know them.
You know what I mean? Everybody's got
their own unique mindset and it's just,
you, you know what's really crazy, man,
as I read this statistic the
other day about suicide, um,
that people in poor neighborhoods are
far less likely to kill themselves.
People that are in the
struggle. Yeah. Well,
I actually believe that because
they're fighting for something. Yeah.
And someone that's already got everything
and then they end up with no drive
with no goal and nothing left to achieve.
And so then all of a sudden they're just
staring at the mirror without anywhere
else to go. You know, and May,
I'm not talking about Chris
Cornell in particular,
but for some people I know one of the
things that happens is that when they
become very successful and
they're still not happy,
then they get hopeless.
They just feel like, well,
I have everything and yet I'm
fucking miserable. You know,
I have a nice big house, I drive this
fancy car and I still am miserable.
Like there's no hope like
this life is meaningless.
I don't even know what to say to that.
I don't know what to say to be honest
with you. And you hear, you hear that,
you just don't even know what to what to
say to that. You know, one thing that,
why I don't understand it,
I liked struggle. I like it.
I think it's important. No,
there's no doubt about that.
There's no doubt about having something
that you're striving for some goal.
And like you just said,
all those goals had been achieved and now
you're sitting there at the top of the
mountain and you now you don't feel happy.
What do you do?
Just pick up a fucking Hobbie man.
Find something you suck at and get better
at it. I mean, that seems so simplistic,
but, um, uh, you know, I just,
you and I are, we share this, uh,
this is very important,
uh, part of our lives,
which is a intense exercise
indeed. And I think that, you know,
I go to your Instagram almost every day
to look at your watch. It's hilarious.
If you go to Jockos Instagram,
it's a fucking Timex watch advertisement.
It's all that iron man watch at four 30
in the morning, the occasional three 30.
This is motherfuckers up at three 30.
And you know,
and you working out like that's
his fucking Harry gorilla arm and
a Timex ironman triathlon watch.
But that's what's up, man. That's what's
up. I mean, just fucking doing it,
getting out there and struggling. And then
once you do do that, here's the thing,
like, you know, like a friend of mine
said that he's just like a w I was a,
I was saying something about you
could come on the podcast and he goes,
can that do take another
picture of his fucking watch?
I hope he takes a picture of his
watch every day until he dies. I go,
it's important. It's
important. It's, it's,
it's sort of in a lot of ways
it's symbolic of what we're
talking about. Like, no,
it's not fun to look at your watch every
day, but you fucking doing it every day.
Like that's what's important. Yeah.
And I actually, early on I had someone,
you know, say something along
the lines of on social media,
on Instagram or on Twitter, you know, oh,
you just going to post another picture
you're watching. I was like, unfollow me.
Like, just don't follow me. It's no big
deal. I'm not making you do it. And,
and now it is kind of turned
into something where I'm,
I'm doing it every day regardless of
anything else in the world. Fuck them.
I like looking at you.
I want to know when I get up at seven and
I think I'm getting up early human for
hours. You already gone to work now.
I like it. I think it's uh, it's,
but it is a lot of ways. It is, it's
symbolic of what we're talking about.
It's a struggle. Yeah. And you know,
you know who doesn't complain about it.
And I always make this point too,
there's like a,
a single mom somewhere in the valley
here that's working three jobs that's
getting up at three 30 in the morning so
she can go work as a waitress somewhere
before she's got her other day job that
she's got to go through so she can feed
her kids. I get up almost as a luxury
at this point. I mean, you know, I'm,
I'm a retired guy from the,
from the military,
so I can kind of get up whenever I want.
I get up early as a luxury sort of,
but you also get up because that's who
you are. Yeah. And I get up because it is,
it is a way to maintain
discipline in life for sure.
Get that stone out and sharpen
that blade every morning.
It's the grind that sharpens the ax.
Indeed does no other way.
There's no other way,
and I don't want to say that this would've
saved Chris Cornell or anybody else
that did it.
I'm not saying that,
but I mean for some people out
there that aren't feeling good man,
if you just fucking struggled more, you
get over that struggle, you feel better.
It sounds so simplistic,
but I swear by it,
I felt shitty myself and then
force myself to work out.
And then after I get out of there
I'm like, Whoa, what a percent, fuck,
it's 100% guarantee. And you know,
actually I had, I had, you know,
I had Tim Ferris come on my podcast
and when he came on he was like, Hey,
I don't know if I'm the right kind of
guests for your podcast because you know,
my podcast is like about war and
death and killing and all that stuff.
And so, you know, Tim's are about
being better and stuff like that.
So it's easy to raise your voice.
But that's what was right.
Tim's Tim's podcast is about improving
yourself and mine was about war and
genocide and horrible things.
And he said to me, you know, hey,
I don't know if if I come
on the podcast but you know,
maybe I'm not the right type of
guest or whatever and I, and I,
and I wrote back to him and
I said, hey man, you know,
you've been through some dark stuff in
your life because he wrote a blog post
years ago about him being suicidal and
him contemplating and planning commit
suicide. This is Tim Ferriss.
Did he really? Yeah, he
went through a full motions,
you know, typical Tim Ferris
methodology. What did he do?
He went to the library and got out a bunch
of books on killing yourself and then
did the research and how he was
going to do it and planned it all.
And then when was this,
how long ago he was going,
he was like just done with college.
And so, I mean, what does that,
what is he 35 or something?
So maybe it's 20 he's 15 years ago,
Christ and he was under all this pressure,
you know,
he was an ivy league guy and
he was trying to finish school,
but then it wasn't working out
and it was just problematic.
And so he started saying to myself, okay,
well how am I getting out of this? Well,
there's one way to get out of it.
And luckily he didn't do it,
but when he came on, you know, that's
what we talked about and what he said,
you know, as he was making
recommendations from again,
from a guy who's been there was like,
hey, if, if you're trapped in your,
in your mind and you're starting to
feel that way, go do something physical.
Get in your body,
you get out of your mind.
The same thing you were saying
it when you're feeling bad,
when you're feeling down,
go out and swing a kettle ball around
and you will feel better. Yeah,
this is just too much.
For some people especially they're just
experienced in way too much pressure and
that pressure a lot of times it's just a,
an imbalance and perspective.
And some of it's in like a, I
was talking to this mom once, uh,
her daughter does gymnastics with my
daughter and we were talking about, um,
kids killing themselves
where she used to live.
She still live in one of the
really wealthy tech areas
outside of San Francisco.
And a bunch of kids that went to school
with her daughter that were like 15, 16,
we're jumping off bridges and chin.
Like it was a like an epidemic and they
were trying to figure out what the fuck
is going on.
And they're literally calling it Affluenza
that these affluent kids and their
families are literally worth
$1 billion. You know, I mean,
everybody's super rich and they're
having this insane pressure.
It like before high school and in high
school to be an Ivy League schools and to
get 4.0 is and all and they're fucking,
they're not having any fun and they're
not experienced in life and they don't
have any hope.
And their parents are all on fucking
pills and they're just killing themselves.
And as you said, it really is a piece of
perspective because if you think about,
think about some,
when you watched one of your
buddies go down the downward spiral,
maybe it's not the suicide,
but whether it's drug addiction,
a lot of times some female,
the girlfriend, the ex wife,
we'll just take them on the
downward spiral and theirs,
they can't get out of it.
And if they were to step back,
if they were,
if it was you and your buddy watching
one of your other friends go down this
path, they go, oh my God, I can't
believe he's doing that. That's crazy.
But when you're in that spiral,
people get caught in that and they can't,
they can't get the perspective of
what it looks like from the outside.
Okay.