And, uh, is, say what you want about
Giuliani who now is bat shit crazy. Uh,
what happened with him? I don't know.
I think there's some blew a fuse.
He's not respectable anymore.
It's like some kind of, well,
he aligned himself a Trump, so that
immediately gets you put into a category.
But he's also a little,
I think he's got some dementia going on.
Like he just doesn't seem
right, but it is. Hm.
Losses comb over that he had a comb
over for, what is that like, uh,
what's his name with the comb over and he
realized, Oh my God, I'm fucking crazy.
Samson's hair. It's like that.
He, he lost the last wisps,
those last wisps of comb-over that
he'd had during nine 11 going on. Yeah.
He was at one point, you know, after
nine 11, they call it nine, 10, 2001,
he was a piece of shit. No one
liked Giuliani. He ruined New York.
He ruined it by commercializing it,
cleaning up all the porn theaters, uh, uh,
getting rid of the tunnel bunnies and the
squeegee guys. Like he went on a tear,
just gave the police department carte
blanche to start racking head and taking
care of business.
He cleaned up New York Times Square,
turned into a Disney type atmosphere
instead of that drug addled fucking mess
that it was.
And,
and people hated him for kind of ruining
that Gritty New York that we saw in
taxi driver and shit.
And then nine 11,
he was America's mayor. That's what
they called him, America's mayor.
He's going out of Yankee Games and to
ovations and people he's standing with the
comb over. He looked so crazy
person on the right. Yeah. Yeah.
She is totally shaved his
head. I said, listen bro,
there's a lot of power in just
shaving your head, motherfucker. Yeah.
You feel good. You feel like a guy who
has like hair on the side of his head.
Unless you do a lot of drugs like
hunter s Thompson, it's hard, right?
You can't pull that off, I think. Yeah.
Uh, who does it offer? Right hand side.
That's a, that's a comb
over in the beginning. They
are above that. Above that.
Above that to the right to the
right with a suit. Oh yeah.
That's where it's first started. That's
the full clover. Oh my God, look at that.
Oh, it's working the back. What did he do?
Did he try to get plugs or something
in the front? I don't think so.
I don't know what that is.
It's just,
it was rocking that full strong
comb over that is, uh, he, uh,
he had a lot to do with the, the, the um,
getting rid of organized crime
in New York City, like the mafia,
the five families,
all that shit was still running pretty
rampant throughout the seventies and
eighties. Uh, as a kid, me and my
brother used to laugh our asses off.
We'd open the newspaper and there
was like Johnny the horse boldly.
Yachty was found dead and we be
laugh our asses off at the names,
just those, those mob
names. It's, it's hilarious.
And that scene in Goodfellas at the
beginning when they're just going through
and you know,
the nose and killer and this guy and they
all have those fucking names that are
hilarious. And a, yeah.
Giuliani was a big part of that.
I'm surprised they didn't kill him.
Like he was absolutely responsible.
He kept going after them and kept putting
them away. Uh, with the, you know,
the new Rico statutes that they had
and a locked up a lot of mobsters,
man. So, well, you know, another problem
with the mom says they started writing,
I mean other, yeah, yeah, yeah. As soon as
you start ratting on each other all year,
mystique is gone.
Your whole legend has gone.
Just the whole thing is that you guys
have Omerta you keep your fucking mouth
shut. You do your time like a man, right.
You get out and you're a hero and
that this whole thing keeps going.
This thing of ours was, but those fucking
pussies didn't want to go to jail.
Isn't that something like the old
school guys would be offered, you know,
you could walk. Yep. Or You could get
a really easy sentence, just talk,
Oh fuck your mother. And, and then, yeah,
they reached a point where it's like,
yeah, I, I'm not built for prison.
When they would put them in prison
though, it was like in Goodfellas. Right.
They would be able to cook and they
paid the guards off at a sweet set up.
The internet ruined all that
too. Yeah. Yeah. You wanna well,
it was probably all dead before
the Internet, but, but you know,
like Sammy the bull Gravano he was free.
He did his time,
did the minimal amount of time.
He killed at least 10 people.
They mean pa, he, he confessed to them,
you know, talked about the,
that he did and how he did them.
He wanted it got so bad. They
want to, God, he's so bad. I mean,
Sammy the bull Gravano was a fucking
straight up psychopath. Yeah.
That's total serial killer.
And they let him walk and then he got
arrested eventually for selling ecstasy in
Phoenix. He moved to Phoenix after
that. Yeah. Yeah. And then he, uh,
was running shit down there.
And how did he just not get whacked out?
Like was the mob was gone. They all
were gone. There's no one cared.
Hated it at all. It all crumbled at
that something. Yeah, just like a,
yeah. Poof. Went away.
The thing that like, God,
he was the first one that was like
real flashy and public about it.
They didn't like that Vincent the Chin
always used to walk around like a crazy
person in the bathroom.
It was nuts. But he would,
he would give people directions
while he was doing that,
but he felt like everything
was being bugged.
So they would do is they bug
cars along his walking route.
They could record him. Oh, that is
hilarious. What he was doing. Jesus.
There's always a way. Yeah. There's
always a way to get you. Yeah.
The mystique was gone though.
Yeah.
It wasn't really like the Russians still
have the mystique Russian mobsters.
They are brutal. Tells Gary Ones like
they are the scary ones. There's,
there's everyone's now worst smile
because regardless of what it turned into,
there was a time where the
Italian mob did have a line.
Like you didn't cross family, things
like that. Uh, but the Russians,
all my God, will they fuck
up an entire family? The dog.
Everything gets in the worst
way. Yeah. They're scary.
Scary mother fuckers. I had
a, an experience, I'm out.
It was a Broadway, I guess. Uh,
and they have those peddle cabs that go
around and they were all Russian dudes,
big kind of legs on him.
And they peddle around and I was
looking for a cab or real cab to take me
downtown. I wasn't gonna
ride 15 blocks in a tricycle,
uh, with a Uri peddling in front of me.
So, uh, this guy pass by once and said,
you need the cab. I was like, Nah,
I'm good. Thanks. Comes around again.
I'm still waiting for a cab. And
he goes, cab. And I was like,
I'm not going to have you pedal
me 15 fucking blocks. No move.
And, and you could yell at
a cab driver in New York.
They'll yell out your window and stuff.
They'd rarely, we'll get out of their car.
They know, you know, you've
got the medallion right there.
You could just call the number and say
you were being harassed by a cab driver.
So they won't do anything.
This guy gets off his fucking bike,
you'll have a fucking problem,
you have fucking problem.
And I was just like, oh shit.
It's going down black eye.
This guy means business. And of course
I'm like, no, no, all good. All good.
Thank you. I don't need a a cab.
You'll write the mother fuck.
And that was it. But you
don't fuck with Russia? No,
they're not regular white
people. No, they're not.