Is there are alternatives that
are getting very big. Yes.
And and together like what?
Like signal has tens of millions of users.
I don't know what that is.
It's never heard of it. That's like
the encrypted messaging app that,
do you know what? I don't,
it's open source. What is it?
Snowden is on there, but advisory
board or whatnot. What is signal?
It's just a messaging APP.
So a messenger like whatsapp or
like a Twitter or whatsapp. So it's,
you have to know the person and
then contact them through it. Yeah,
but we're talking,
we're,
we're considering using
the signal protocol for our
messaging system cause our
messaging system needs an upgrade.
But all of us together are going to be,
be able to create sort of like a,
a group of apps that are like sort of
a more open freedom supporting privacy
alternative and like, so we're not
gonna solve it by ourselves. And
it would be way easier if one of these
big companies would just switch gears and
start doing things the right way. I mean,
we've spent eight years building this.
If one of the big companies,
Google Facebook had just
been free and open source,
we would have spent the last seven
years building on top of them. Right?
Because you know they already did
something cool that they're sharing with
everybody.
So it's,
it's actually closed source project
stifle innovation because if you think we
had to reinvent the wheel,
we literally,
we went and built in alternative with
much of the similar functionality.
Think about how,
how much further the world would be if
everyone was building on top of more
common calls.
But you're looking at it in terms of your
own personal benefit you're looking at
in terms of mine's personal benefit.
I mean, you created this thing,
it's not just pure for altruistic
reasons, it's a business, right?
So if they had established this open
source network that was Facebook and then
you just came along and built yours, will
that, yeah, that would be great for you.
But why would that be great for them?
I mean they,
they're obviously in a business now
the problem with the businesses,
this business is the business
of distributing information.
And then we have to decide,
okay,
at what point in time do we allow these
air quotes overlords to dictate what can
and cannot be distributed? And how did
this happen? Because in the beginning,
I bet it didn't happen.
I bet in the beginning you could just
put on whatever the fuck you wanted and
then they had to deal with that and then
they had to figure out after a while,
okay, maybe we shouldn't
have this on like, hey,
if we're going to sell advertising,
we really should maximize the amount
of clicks. Okay, how do we do that?
While we put things in people's feeds,
they want to see,
we put things that people want to debate
about and argue about and political
things and all sorts of different things
that excite them and get them to be
engaged with the platform that's,
that's their business. The businesses,
I mean it's no different in a lot of ways
than Amazon or then any other business
that wants to grow.
Like how do,
how do they grow while they grow by
maximizing their profits and by the amount
of eyes that get to their advertising.
So they get more clicks and
more people get engaged.
That's what their businesses,
you're deciding by saying
if they were open source,
look how much further on the world with
be. They would be further along to,
I don't know if they
would agree with that.
I don't think they're there worth
fucking cajillions of dollars.
So they figured it out.
Well,
it just depends on whether or not you
think that people have a right to know
what is going on. It's, I mean
it's like food transparency.
Well yeah, we were. Yeah.
So I'll talk about that.
I like,
I will talk about that until the end of
time you were interfacing with this and
it's affecting us. I agree. Yeah. I
fully agree with what you're saying.
I'm playing devil's advocate by saying
that in their position they have a
business and their businesses to make
money and they're going to lose because of
what they're doing because it's not as
insistent up even at polar losing active
users, are they? Yeah,
but I've thought their business
went up after the hearings did it,
but it's not going to last.
I mean, look, when I say that
it's just the game's over. It's gonna
take a long time for us to build it up.
As you know, all of these
different organizations and
companies working together.
But
Linux for instance,
is the operating system that most banks,
it is the most popular operating system
in the world. It's, it's, it's, yeah,
it's open. It's in your
phone. It's in everywhere.
It got there because of that,
because everyone used it and incorporate
it into their product. Facebook,
they are all using free and open
source software in their stacks.
They're just not sharing their
product with everybody else.
So they're benefiting from it but
not giving back. And you know, I,
I almost feel like I shouldn't even
be saying that they should just pivot
because you know,
that's their only chance to survive.
So this is based on your
estimations of the future. Yeah.
It just seems like things are becoming
more open and if is that possible because
you engage with a lot of other super
nerds and you guys all have these similar
ideas. You just have to look at
what's happening with bitcoin.
I don't know what's
happening with bitcoin.
It's become a bitcoin and ethereum and
you know, lots of other blockchains are,
are, are growing really fast. Maybe
the, you know, the price is separate,
the development energy,
the number of people who are building
apps on top of bitcoin and ethereum is
growing massively. There's, there's,
it's a whole new infrastructure that's
like a common protocol that people can
build on. So that is growing
rapidly. The price is secondary.
That's not even what bitcoin and
ethereum are really about. It's,
it's a decentralized database.
So this is just where the Internet,
the Internet is meant to be decentralized.
It sort of started out that way.
And then we moved into this like web to
silo system with like just these massive
companies that are controlling everything.
But it's gonna, it's gonna keep waving.
Okay. Again, to play devil's advocate,
the vast amount of users are
not using those platforms.
The vast amount of users are using these
controlled platforms like Facebook and
Instagram and Twitter. Like if that's,
if you're, if you're talking about,
I'm just guessing, but if
you're talking about the, the,
the gross number of human beings that
are interacting with each other on social
media,
they're mostly uncontrolled networks.
You're saying that this is not gonna last,
but there's no evidence that it isn't
going to last. There's tons of evidence.
What is the evidence? Wikipedia,
what is happening in card?
I remember that desk you put in your
computer, that was your encyclopedia.
Where is that? No one uses it.
Okay. That's, that's different.
This is not a social media network.
The social media networks that people are
using are almost all controlled, right?
Yeah. No I it's not, it's going to
take a very, very long time. How long?
I would say 10 years.
And what do you think is
going to be the catalyst?
Like what's going to cause these people
to make this radical shift to open
source?
I think we have to be,
we have responsibility to be
competitive functionally. Like you know,
science does. We were saying we do, we're
getting, we're moving there fast. Like,
we just hired a ton of new developers
and it's going to take time.
We're not there yet.
Right.
But once we have functionally competitive
products that you wouldn't even know
the difference and there's
enough people there,
then it's basically the
decision of, uh, you know,
am I going to choose the one that respects
my privacy and freedom or are the one
that doesn't? And people are all
kids don't like Facebook, right?
No. Everyone is sick of it.
We're just drug addicts. Hmm.
Um, is that what it is? They're just
sucked into this thing where you,
you constantly want to check and
see who's writing what and yeah,
and there's monopolies,
arguably. Yeah. Yeah. Right.
Especially when Facebook
owns Instagram. Right. Um,
what if they bought Twitter as well?
They almost did,
I think Google almost into two steps in
and buys everything. Then you're like,
oh no, they probably could.
Right? Yeah, they easily could.
They could probably buy everything
apple could with cash. Yeah. Yeah.
Tim Cook had come in with
a big purple pimp suit on,
just slap down a briefcase patch.
I just wonder and like look all the,
all of these executives,
you know,
Jack seems like a cool person.
She's a very nice guy. It's not,
I just sent so much
inconsistency and you know,
he's talking about Bitcoin,
like it's this important new internet
money simultaneous, which is,
he knows the infrastructure is open,
but then his platforms or the opposite,
why is he selling consistent?
It's like there's,
it's just hypocritical to the maximum.
I think it's partly because
it's a giant business, you know?
And I think when you have an obligation
to your shareholders and to maximize
profits and when you're trying
to maximize profits too,
and there's this universal growth model
where every year just has to get a
little bit bigger.
Otherwise you're fucking up as a CEO.
Like you don't have to
experience that with mines.
You were one of the cofounders.
How many people are involved?
Just like 15 of us now.
And do you have like a board we sit around
when you make critical decisions such
stressful as fuck.
Yeah.
Luckily we've started off from the
point where we're saying, okay,
we're embedding principles
into how we're doing things.
So we're not in a position
where we would ever change that,
that that's for us to do.
That would just be a total waste of time,
right?
So we're making it harder for ourselves
to make money in the beginning.
We're making it harder for ourselves to
grow because we are not gonna compromise
people's privacy in
order to do those things.
And so we're just going
to build up slowly,
steadily find and just get
there when we get there.