Man, Jeff Bezos. Oh yeah. Jeff Bezos, man,
crazy is the national inquirer.
Allegedly we should say, allegedly,
I believe, allegedly, I don't wanna
get sued. Tried to extort him.
And it's about the Jamal because Shogi uh,
investigation from the Washington Post,
it's all connected to that. I read,
I read a bit about it.
Um,
I started reading more when Ronan Farrow
came out and claimed that they went to
him too.
So I'm not as versed like I haven't read,
I read through the ae they meaning
the inquiry inquiry I run and Pharaoh,
it was a store,
I think it was from the week where running
pharaoh says that they approached him
and, and you know, put pressure
on him as well. But you know,
the interesting thing is
when I read that story,
I kind of laughed because I was like,
member caulker yeah.
Remember when they public,
when they outdid Peter Teal
and then yes. You know, uh,
Hulk Hogan, like, you know,
these people were really brave to go up
against billionaires like this and try
and drag them. Yeah. I'll also point out,
it's kind of scary that you live in a
world where billionaire can destroy your
company because they're angry at you.
But it's also kind of scary that they
can use this to extort him so that he
doesn't,
he takes the Washington Post or they're
attempting to get him to take the
Washington Post and remove a legitimate
news story about an actual murder.
I don't trust the Washington Post, but you
know, that's an aside that isn't aside.
Like if,
you know,
when I look at what the
national enquirer did,
it just reminds me of what the media does.
They know what they can do
and they know how to do it.
The media is influenced its power.
You know, uh, brands, they're scared,
they're scared.
So you look at what happens with some
of these Twitter accounts that will lead
campaigns where they encourage all their
followers to send emails. It's, it's,
it's not the same as blackmail
by no means, but when, you know,
there's an attack vector, like, you know,
uh, what does that wild sardines company,
they don't want to deal with a brigade
from activists. You tweet at them,
you're fans tweet at them
and they immediately cancel
on your show and they just
value unless you do something,
unless you say something,
unless you disavow something,
you know. So granted, it's,
it's leaps and bounds worse when it, when,
when, uh, national inquirer allegedly,
you know, tries to extort Jeff Bezos.
The craziest thing about it is allegedly,
again, allegedly that the investigator,
I think his name is Becker,
was entertaining the possibility that a
government entity intercepted the texts,
the nude selfies from those.
But I did see another journalists
tweet that they're not entertaining,
that they're not pursuing it. It was
just a thought. So maybe it's not real.
What part of the thought was
that his girlfriend's brother,
who's a Trump supporter,
might have somehow or another
got screen grabs of her phone.
It was really interesting when Bezos said,
because he owns the post people per se,
uh, people presume he's their enemy,
you know,
and that's it.
That's another point I would bring up
to when it comes to like banning Alex
Jones.
Just because someone's reporting something
doesn't mean they're advocating for
it. But sometimes they are. It's like
you got to understand the nuance in that,
you know, but I, yeah,
I mean Bayzos is probably not
the person you'd want to target.
I could you imagine what would happened
if Bayzos shut up at the Washington Post
and said, guys, kill the story.
Every journalist which tweet it base,
I'll shut up and just killed our story.
Yeah. It's almost impossible. It's so,
so unrealistic. But maybe there's more
to it. I mean, yeah, the, the, the real,
the, uh, and this is the big
conspiracy theory was that, you know,
Trump always calls him Jeff
bozo. Right, right, right.
Someone from that side is involved
in this. Yeah. And you know,
cause Trump's always had this relationship
with the inquirer and big concern.
Yeah. Right, right. Yeah. So I don't,
I don't know, I guess I, you know,
this is relatively new
story and I've been here,
so I don't know as much about
it as I probably should,
which just shows you how crazy digital
media is and the digital things like
sending things through the air.
And it's just that people
can get intercepted.
That's why, you know, when
I, when I mentioned earlier
the potential for civil war,
like we don't know what it could
look like. This could be it,
it could be special interests using
information. It's the information war,
you know,
things that people have talked about.
I was thinking about this a
while ago. It's like, man, why?
Why did people shoot each other a hundred
years ago? I mean still do, but like,
you know, World War II,
why are they running it?
Because they wanted to gain control.
They wanted,
they wanted to centralize power or
they wanted to push an ideology or a
government or expand their power. You
don't need to shoot somebody to do that.
You just need to convince them you're
right or you need to get them to fight
each other. So I think
it's fair to say, yeah,
the Russians are absolutely screwing
with us, but we've learned through,
if you trust the reporting,
and it's hard to know what's real
or not that the Russian campaigns,
we're not only promoting Trump supporters,
but they were promoting black lives
matter. Why you give him to fight? Well,
they weren't just doing that.
There's a fantastic
podcasts at Sam Harris released
recently with a woman. Let me,
let me get her name so I
can see if you can find it.
Jamie called the information war.
That's the name of the podcast.
But uh,
they were,
they were doing all sorts of different
things like not just trying to Rene dear
Resta the rest. And I'm working on getting
her down here soon. Um, that they were,
they also had like a Texas culture.
They had trans rights.
They have,
they even organize Facebook campaigns
where they had a pro Texas group and a pro
Muslim group meet across the street
from each other. Yeah. I mean they're,
they're sowing seeds of descent,
like organizing it.
And I think I,
I'd be willing to entertain
the possibility that what
we call the culture war
today was seated specifically by
special interests, potentially Russia.
Nothing we can do about it.
It's done. You know, when, when,
when people adopt an ideology,
you can't easily break that.
And some people refuse to
cross that divide, you know?
Yeah. But it's just so funny how many
different ways they were attacking this.
They had a blue lives matter groups,
black lives matter groups,
and they put people at odds with each
other and one of the big ones that they
did was they,
they targeted African Americans and we're
trying to get them to vote for anyone
other than Hillary.
And this is like an engineered campaign
that Jill Stein's our vote and like we
can't vote for Hillary. Like
Hillary not support us. We
can't vote for Hillary. And so it made it
very tribal. The first thing we have to,
we have to assume is that it was effective
in that what we view in the culture
war was exacerbated by these campaigns.
We don't know.
We don't know to what extent they had an
influence over the u s but I will say,
I think it's fair to point out they play
a role and then we can see what happens.
Charlottesville. Yeah. You know,
where we can see the dramatic escalation
where you end up with some crazy guy
associated with,
you know,
white nationalism ramming a car into
a bunch of protesters. It's, you know,
people get riled up to a point as a
really great video called this video will
make you angry by,
um,
CGP grey where he talks
about how these groups,
they argue amongst each other,
not against each other.
They make each other angry by posting
images of the other. You know,
there's certain subreddits why don't
want to, you know, start a brigade,
but they'll post memes nonstop
attacking a particular politician.
They're not arguing with
the left or the right.
They're arguing to themselves
about what's wrong with the other.
And so these groups grow
and get angrier and angrier.
And then when they finally meet in the
real world, you get extreme violence.
So it's very,
it's very possible to seed
those communities and rile
people up to push these
things.