You would love it, dude. There's an
octopus who makes a seashell suit.
He literally makes us suit of armor out
of shells to block himself from a shark.
It's nuts. It's super nuts.
Yeah. Animals are huge. I mean,
they're weird and we're,
we're, we're animals.
We don't like to think we are because
we can talk and sing songs and Shit and
get her eyes done.
But we're,
we're animals and some sort of strange
way. We're the same as Trump. Yeah.
Do you see the shoe boxy suits somehow?
He's got a good ass Taylor man. Well,
is the Trump statute. Jamie and I
were talking about it yesterday,
which was it? The presidential
house of wax or some show? No one.
Please tell me it's bad. It's crazy.
It's like they're punking him.
Do you ever seen it? I look at
it. Look at it though. Good.
Make that larger so he could
see what it looks like.
Operation Trump debuts at Disney world.
But I'm telling you,
it doesn't look anything like him.
Like if I was the person who created like,
look, that's George Washington
seems normal, but look at
the Trump one. Wait. Like,
what in the fuck is that? It doesn't
look anything like him. Oh God,
look at him.
He looks like he's like 20 years older
than he doesn't even look like him.
I mean, whoever that artist is
like he's gotta be punking him is,
this is no way.
He liked did some weird shit to his jaw.
His jaw is like extended and creepy.
He made his neck skin is the same artist
that did the Chris John, Chris Johnno,
Renaldo bust. You saw that right?
He looks pretty much the same.
And see if you can go find a photo of it.
Because in high res
photos is a low res video.
It's difficult to see how shitty it is,
but it's so shitty that it looks fake.
Like, like no. This is not
really the one. Like, no,
they fucking commissioned an artist
and this is the artist's creation.
Where is this animatronic
question? I don't know, but
I'm going to remember this.
And Disney world.
Disney land in bread looking,
um, do you think they are looking
bread? Eric Trump. He looks odd.
He looks like he has no upper
that come on. Oh my God,
that's parking. Good. But either way,
good or bad.
This is clearly [inaudible] if Hillary,
no, do not tell me that. No two
they saw, okay this is the fire.
This guy who at the Obama one.
That's terrible.
They just saw I could do better than
that and I suck at Scott Wax Museum.
Look how bad that is. And it doesn't look
anything like him. Oh God, I turn it off.
It's great that they can do like
Jefferson and Lincoln and all that stuff.
Cause all they had was drawings. No,
terrible. Yeah, it was pretty bad.
I don't know how we got onto that.
Oh, humans malleable humans. Yeah.
I mean I'm hoping, you know, intimate,
just like slavery doesn't exist
anymore in the United States at least.
I'm hoping that as time goes on there's
going to be less tribalism and then as
human beings are able to freely travel
and communicate with each other that
we're going to be dealing
with less of this.
But isn't it sad that it seems
like it's almost getting worse,
even though we have all the information
available at our fingertips, we're still,
like,
we just elected someone who basically
got famous politically because he said
Obama was a secret
Muslim and Kenyan people.