The Joe Rogan experience
and a few other things.
I actually got, um, I got like
hypnotized to before. Yeah, dude,
who did too. Um, and my
friend Dominique, um, he has,
he has this, like I met
him through one of the, um,
one of the other UFC fighters.
Like Julia Marquez. I met him,
I met him through him and he's like, oh
yeah, I do like hypnotism, all this stuff.
I'm like, okay cool. I've done it
before. I did it in California and um,
so I think three weeks,
two or three weeks prior to the fight,
we had a few sessions a week where it
just like helped me to really get that
visualization clear cause we have so
many thoughts all the time. Right.
And everything,
just like thoughts are constantly coming
in and to stay focused and to really
like,
like
get the outcome that we, you know, set
our intention to. It's kind of hard.
So many distractions.
So when you go into his office and,
or wherever you do it and
you guys talk about it,
do you set a goal before
you start the session?
We do this thing called timeline therapy.
So it's like I'm just kinda sitting
there with my eyes closed and, um,
we kind of just do this.
We'll pick a subject, whether
it's like, you know, pain,
fear, you know, nervousness, something.
I'll just pick a subject of feeling
whatever's going on. And um,
it's kind of just like a visual
timeline of like, where did this start,
where did it come from,
what's the event, whatever.
And we kind of just talk about
that for awhile. And, um, I just,
yeah,
Kinda dig to this place of where the
nervousness is coming from or where the,
you know, where the fear is coming
from or whatever. I kinda just,
I find a place on my
timeline and I dig from it,
whether it's in the future or
the past, whatever. And um,
then we get things clear. And then, um,
and then after that he kind of helps
me, guides me into this, like hypnotism,
which is really just like a really,
really deep relaxation.
If I wanted to open my eyes or something
like that, I feel like I could,
but I wanted to relax. I
wanted this to help, you know,
I wanted my vision to be clear.
So I did my best to just like surrenders,
hit the process and I'd say it's not
something where I woke up and I was like,
oh yeah, my life has changed. But um,
I can definitely remember the thoughts
that I had so that I can stay more on
like in that,
in that lane of what I wanted and in my,
in my hypnotism actually visualized not
winning the fight because I didn't want
to strive too hard to win.
Like it's just something that
I've been kind of studying.
It's like the outcome is not
really like the winning or losing.
I don't want to base too much on that.
I just want to put on
like a great performance.
So I visualized after one thing hand,
like just having my hands in the air,
seeing my brother's smile, my coach,
his smile and then slapping hands
with the crowd, um, on the way out.
And then I was also like,
and I want to see my wind bonus and my
show money and these are the things that
I wanted to see.
These are the outcomes that I wanted.
Not so much just I want to win the fight,
but the things that I like,
how I wanted it to happen. Yeah.
And having that vision clear,
it helped me.
And so like everything that
I've visualized before that
it happened, I was like,
cool hands, raise, slap hands with
everybody on the crowd the way out,
sign both my checks.
And that was like,
that was the end of it for me until the
next session until I want to get clear
on something else, you
know? It was cool. Wow.
So had you done anything like that before?
Any mental coaching before they go
come toxify I did something very,
very similar. Yeah. With
um, with another guy.
I was out the first time you'd ever done
it. First Time doing hypnotism. Yeah,
definitely. And um, yeah, my
friend Matthias, he's here and uh,
he's really good too. And he
was just like, take some notes.
You kind of just have a conversation in
the beginning and everything comes from
your own conscious mind.
It's not somebody telling you something.
I just dumped out whatever my own
conscious mind was telling me.
He was just helping me to like relax and
be at peace and just listened to like
my own conscious mind.
Just unfold all of these kind of
like hidden answers that we all have,
you know?
So that's it.
Now when you get hip and ties and
you're thinking about a specific fight,
do you think about specific things
you're trying to accomplish?
Things that you think you'll do to him
that you'll have an advantage at or
strategy or like how do you will,
those were thoughts that were
happening before my hypnotism,
but then all of those thoughts were
coming from the anxiety or coming from the
nervousness. You get what
I'm saying? So it's like,
let's go back on the timeline to
why you're feeling nervous. Yeah.
Like all these things are happening.
They're going to you,
you're anticipating all these
things happening and it's
making you feel nervous.
So let's go back to the nervousness
and revisit that. Why, you know,
and then like my subconscious,
my unconscious mind, just
like spewing things out.
And then after the process of
that mixed with the hypnotism,
I'm not even thinking about, oh, I'm
going to hit this arm drag or whatever.
I just,
I'm thinking about having my conscious
clear in my mind clear and everything so
that I can get the expectation that like,
or the the visualization that I created.
Yeah.
So have you tried different versions
of that or different styles of,
of hypnosis? Mm, no.
Not that I can, I mean I've done
a lot of just like close die,
like emotional intelligence type
of like exercises, you know?
Like where I'm just like my eyes are
closed and I have someone helping me
visualize internally,
you know,
like just whether it's dreams or
emotional pain or whatever it may be.
Yeah. People just like guided
meditation almost. Yeah.
But the actual name, like hypnotism,
I've only had it done by two people.
Well it as when you're watching fighters,
if you are,
I think fighters are one
of the most complex puzzles
for psychologists because I
think it's a super rare state.
Like the rare state that someone gets to
the weather, it can be completely calm.
See everything in the heat of a dangerous
encounter with another train fighter.
And when you're watching these things
play out on TV and you often times see how
much anxiety plays a factor
or doesn't play a factor,
how much someone having the,
I don't give a fuck attitude
for real at Ken play.
It can be a benefit and it
can fuck you up sometimes too.
And to see these complex psychological
puzzles will play out and see fighters
struggle and then regroup,
have a bad fight and come back better.
All that stuff is like,
it's,
it's really like a giant microscope
on the human character and you know,
and I like a guy like you who comes back
from the Johnnie Walker fight and looks
sensational against Eric
Andrews. Man. It was like,
that was one of those things you're like,
I like what I'm seeing his guy,
he figured some shit out man. We like
that was, that was, that was incredible.
It was really fun to watch, man. This guy
really loves Moitai. It was fun to watch.
Thanks man. That was, and that's,
that's kind of the goal too going forward
is that I want to continue to like put
on stuff like that,
continue to learn Moitai and then cause
that like kind of raised the bar, right?
People are like, Oh man, this guy for
sure. Kind of put me back on the map.
So now I'm ready to just go back.
And you know,
how many guys use mental coaches now?
If you had to guess?
A good handful. Good handful.
Yeah, a good handful I think.
I think a lot of vitamin Vinny
shoreman he hypnotized me and he uh,
he has a lot of fighters.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It was a
trip. It was a very strange,
it's like, oh, this is real. It's a weird
feeling. Right. How long ago was it?
It was the old studio, so it had
to be at least a year and a half,
maybe two years ago. Okay.
Yeah, it was pretty weird.
But he's a great mental coach too though.
You knows like what's creeping around
your subconscious just waiting to pop up
and play tricks on you. You know you
shouldn't be short put in enough rounds.
Where does he live? Ah,
he's a UK guy. Okay. Yeah, I
gotta get linked up with him.
Yeah, I'm all about it. I don't
care anybody. I'm like, yeah,
like whatever you got any short minute,
let's go. Yeah, he's a good dude.
I'll connect you guys.
I think it's a,
probably one of the least trained aspects
of fighting is the mental aspect of
it. You know, you realize how good
guys are just by watching them train,
you see them spar,
you see them do all these things y'all
with Tammy's got this guy's fucking good,
this guy's got great Jujitsu Guy,
great kickboxing.
You ever hear about the people that
like they're, they're saying's right?
Like man that guy's amazing in the gym.
But when he shows up to fight,
like he just doesn't put on like I've
been that multiple times. And like yeah,
a lot of it has to do with mentally.
Yeah.
That's almost like an unaddressed
giant chunk of the puzzle.
Like a third of the puzzle. Like if it
was a pie, a third is keep it together.
You know,
like,
you know when it's ready to go
and now and it's all happening,
don't freak out and you never like
here's kind of the something that I think
about. You never know
everybody's situation, right.
So the day before the fight we have weigh
ins and then Dana comes back and like
he gives us this, our speech,
right? So everyone there,
you don't know what life position
they're in. You know? So it's like, hey,
there's a potential,
we can get a bonus.
So all those guys are affected
emotionally somehow. You know what I mean?
Some guys maybe they don't
care. Some guys, maybe they do,
but then like we walk out and then
there's a crowd, 15,000 people sold out.
Look around. We got Joe Rogan sitting
here, we got Mcmahon and say we got Dana.
Why we got everybody sitting around
and then like we're still human too.
So we're thinking like this is
kind of like a test, you know?
It's like we got all the, we got the
whole board right here in front of me,
ready to take my test. You know,
like, yeah, it really depends on like,
there's so much that goes into it.
Like mentally you gotta be prepared for
a lot of things or some guys block it
out,
but it's just like,
like anything else you had to know
about halfway into the first round,
some special shit was happening
though on this fight. Yes. Uh,
after, so after the first
round, I was very happy.
I sat down and my coaches were like,
okay, this is good, this is good.
You're doing this. And I was like,
listen, I don't want to know what's good,
what should I expect the next round.
Like I was ready to go.
I told this straight to George,
I'm like, dude, I don't care.
What do I need to do next? What
should I prepare for? And he's like,
prepare for a little bit more pressure.
He's probably going to try to shoot
for the take down on this round.
And I was like, okay, cool. So that,
I was just looking for that
and using my tools to kind of,
to just prepare for that. But, uh,
definitely midway through the
second round I was like, okay,
like I know he's still got a lot of power,
all this stuff,
but I think that that leg, I
should be able to, you know,
buy some time and take away
a little bit of damage,
like coming at me and he had to be an
agony and he never stopped coming. Yeah.
Let me like, he didn't wince at all. Like
even on the cage when I was just like,
when he was on the back and I was trying
to kick his leg, he just, his face,
his facial expression never changed.
He's fucking savage. Man is crazy.
He's a bad man. Respect that guy.
Yeah, for sure. Sure. For sure.
Even before, like even before the fight.
No. How far and after for sure. Yeah, no,
maybe even more. So man, not everybody
can do that. Not Everybody can take that,
you know, and to do it the way he did
it with 100%, it was character intact.
Never shirked never shied away from it.
Kept moving forward.
That's a dangerous person. And he's still
getting better. Oh yeah. Hello guys.
Just getting better. Oh
yeah. When you were doing,
how much do you think
the hypnosis helped you?
A really good amount man.
How much different did you
feel like in what way? Um,
I just, I felt more clear. I'm,
I feel like a lot of times I can be just
kind of like an anxious guy. I just, I,
I feel like I feel a lot of just
energy. The kind of like, I don't know,
I go into a room and I'm
just like, ah. So having,
having the focus on having my intention
set on what I wanted to happen
was
70%.
Like I'd owe 70% of like the hypnotism,
all that stuff to just help me
to keep my thoughts on track.
Something never fall back
onto every single time.
If I felt like I was getting distracted
or getting nervous or whatever,
I would remember,
you know,
the things that we went over and the
hypnotism and so every time just kind of
like that, hit that reset button
or just a delete button on,
on thoughts that I just didn't want to
have or thoughts that would make me feel
anything other than happy and ready to go.
Yeah.