Well,
what other like crazy trips do you
want to do that you haven't done yet?
Oh, there's a lot man. I mean,
the one that I've had on my bucket list
and sounds are, so there's a couple.
One is there's one really one place on
earth left where there's true cannibals
and it's pop when you're Guinea.
And um,
unlike the missionary that
went in with an agenda,
I would just love to actually see these,
these cannibalistic tribe.
So I'd love to do that.
Nobody has successfully and less tapped
in very recently and I'm unaware of
successfully done source to see of the
Congo River from guerrilla warfare,
from crazy waterfalls disease.
That's an expedition I'd like to try.
And then when it comes to wildlife,
I mean, the list is infinite.
There's so many of these animals that
I'm desperate to try and find those sound
like very dangerous trips.
Like visiting cannibals. Yeah.
I mean like, I don't know how to
say this without sounding arrogant,
but that's what sounds exciting to
me. You know, is giving that shot,
that other taking that shot
that other people aren't taking.
So have people visited these cannibals
and come out of there? Yep, Yep.
There was a, there was a
nat geo photographer who
got some incredible photos.
They're called the car away tribe and um,
he went in there,
took them a while for them to kind
of assimilate and get comfortable.
And then he got these photos
that are just mind blowing.
Now how often do they
practice cannibalism? It is a,
it's not a daily thing. It is a spiritual
thing where they actually eat the,
eat the other tribes deceased after a
war or an inter tribal conflict as a way
to like ward off bad spirits.
So it's not like a daily thing.
It's not like they're going
out hunting each other.
It's more like when these things occur
they have to eat a certain killer,
a certain body to keep
evil spirits at bay.
Do they get that version of mad
cow's disease that cannibals get?
Was it Jakub Scottsville I know what
you're talking about. I'm not sure.
I think it's probably infrequent
enough that they're not getting it.
Cause like in the, in the South
Pacific they got that all the time.
But they were eating each
other like all the time. Yeah.
Well I think you'd get it from nerves,
right. And nerve tissue or brain brain.
Yeah. That's, that's where
they're getting it from.
It's essentially mad cow
disease. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause this guy hanging out with them
there, it starts off as sounding,
he's eating something I don't think cause
eating people with is going to eat a
fucking person. That's that person
that's like a finger or something.
I don't think they'd show that. But
yeah, I look at the tribe. I mean,
they're just look amazing. Yeah. What?
It is just so incredible that there's
still people that live the way they lived
many, many, many thousands of years ago.
And they essentially just get the
resources from the land area they live and
they're, they're just rocking it old
school. And then for me, it like,
the cultural significance is huge,
but what's the biological area like?
You're right. Nobody's going in there.
How much biological studies been done?
The answer is none. And these
people have large, popular, like,
look at that lady. Oh my amazing. Wow.
Yeah. Um, do you have you,
uh, read 'em sapiens, sapiens.
Now I'm not sure.
A evolutionary book about human history.
You've all Herati I think that's the name
of his, he's amazing writing it down.
Yeah, it's a, it's a great book.
But one of the things that they talk
about in the book was these nomadic tribes
that would, yeah, that's it. Uh,
you've all Noah Herati I
fucked up his name. Um,
they would talk about these nomadic
tribes that would kill the old ladies,
like killed the people
that were burdens and like,
cause you sh shows like them
and I'll just kill them.
Just talking about like what people became
a problem. They would just kill him.
And this was normal,
but they got along together great.
Everybody was like laughing and smiling.
Everybody's really friendly.
But as soon as someone seemed to
be a problem, they'd fucking club.
I'm from behind. And just, it's
like, this is gonna sound just awful,
but doesn't that make sense?
It kind of does. It sucks,
but it Kinda does like you're a burden
on the community or on the society.
You know, there's no fucking old folks
home out there. Yeah. Like that's,
it's crazy.
Like to us in our culture that's absurd.
But as a culture removed from the
rest of the world, makes sense.
Like you're a burden, you
know, you've had a good life.
It's time to move on and there are
nomadic. That's the other thing.
It's like they have to keep moving.
So if someone stops like this one guy,
he was sick and so they left him on a
tree and he became covered with buzzard
shit cause the vultures would just
sit over him and wait for him to die.
But he eventually recovered and he caught
up with the rest of the tribe and for
the rest of the,
they call them something like
buzzard shit or something like that.
That was their nickname for him.
Yeah. Imagine being that guy.
Imagine sitting under a tree
looking up at vultures being like,
it's moments till I die and they're
going to drop down and eat me.
At least they're polite enough to wait
for you to die straight. They don't just,
the guy probably couldn't have
fought him off. That was, yeah.