Well what I'm, what I'm trying to get at
was like, okay, like when things come up,
like say if you find out that
there's people from Isis,
they're using Twitter and they are
using Twitter and posting things.
Like what is the conversation like how do,
what do we do about this?
Do we let them leave this up?
Do we we recognize this as free speech?
Do we only take it down if they're
calling for murder or hate speech?
Like what,
how do you handle that?
Well, it evolves. I mean,
because like we first saw isis when the
world saw isis and we needed to change
our policy to deal with it.
What was the,
what was the initial reaction to it?
So once you realized
that people from Isis,
we're making Twitter accounts and they
were trying to recruit people and doing
all these things, what was
the, what was the thought?
Oh, it was a question. Like what,
what are we gonna do about this?
We haven't experienced this before.
We need to, nobody has, I mean,
you're [inaudible]
pioneers. Yeah. But there,
there are people who have experienced in
different forms and different mediums.
So we reached out to our
government partners, for instance,
our law enforcement partners.
Uh,
we reached out to our peer companies to
ask if they're seeing the same things
that we're seeing. Um, we have a
punch of civil societies that we, uh,
talk to, uh, to get
their take on it as well.
And we try to balance that across,
um, you know, various spectrums,
whether it be, uh, you know, uh,
more organizations that are more focused
on preventing online harassment all the
way to the Aclu and the eff who are
protecting the first amendment online.
So we, we try to get as many
perspectives as possible,
take that and then make
some informed decisions,
but also realize that we're probably
gonna make some mistakes along the way and
all we can do to correct some of
us just be open about where we are.
And that's probably where we failed the
most in the past is we just haven't been
open about our thinking process.
Um,
what led to particular decisions,
how our terms of service evolve.
A terms of service as an area
in our industry is just a,
it's a mess. No one reads
them. You, you know,
you sign up for these services and you
quickly hit accept and we expect people
to read these rules of the road,
but they haven't read them. And have
you ever read them? I have read,
read Facebook's.
I haven't read Facebook's Facebook.
I'm not on Facebook for Facebook. Right.
I'm just kidding. What about Instagram?
Do you ever read theirs? I was, uh,
I was in the first 10 users
of Instagram. Really? Uh,
Kevin was a intern.
Kevin Systrom was an
intern at Odeo and um,
I was one of the first investors
of Instagram and love the service.
I don't think I've ever read their terms
of service. Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Even you, even me. But I read ours
and you, one of the things I noticed
right away is, you know, you read our, uh,
you read our terms of service and one of
the first things that we put at the top
of the page was copyright.
And intellectual property protections.
You go down and you scroll down,
you see everything about violent
threats and abuse and harassment and uh,
safety.
And it's not that the company
intended for that to be the order,
it just,
we just added things going on.
But even a read of that puts
forth our point of view.
Like what we're, we're actually putting
copyright infringement above the safety,
the physical safety of someone.
So we need to relook at some of these
things and how they've evolved and how
they reacted and visit above
just because it's listed second.
I mean they're essentially all in the
same one sheet there on the one sheet when
you bring it up, when you
discuss it first. Is that
really critical? They're all,
they're all part of the terms of service.
Yeah. But I think the ordering matters.
Like what,
what do we consider to be most important?
And then we have to consider
physical safety to the,
to be the one thing that we protect
the most. And so I to go threats,
physical threats,
doxxing anything that impinges
on someone's physical safety.
This is an area where I don't think a
technology and services like ours have a
focused on enough.
We haven't focused on the off platform
ramifications of what happens online.
So what do you do? Like, like
here's a good, for instance,
this situation with this,
a young kid who had the Maggot hat on
and the native American gentleman who was
in front of him banging the drum and then
people are calling for this kid's name.
They want his name, they want us
to address including Kathy Griffin.
Like how do you,
how do you handle something like that?
Well, cause that's essentially
request for doxing and that's,
that is a new vector that we haven't
seen in mass. I this, these are,
these are the cases that bring up entirely
new thing. So we have to study it.
We have to see how we reacted,
what happened with a network.
Um,
but this goes back to the incentives.
Like we are incentivizing this very
quick reaction and it's taking away from
some more,
some more of the like considered work
that we need to do to really diagnose
what's happening in the moment.
And it was,
it's such an interesting case study to
see how that evolved over just 48 hours.
And that's one of the most fascinating
new cycles or stories in the news cycle
and quite a while because it's nuanced.
There's,
there's many different levels to it.
Yeah.
And a lot of like really
knee jerk reaction.
It's totally, and, but we
helped that had to help it.
Well, it's just, that's how some of
the dynamics of the service work.
But is the nose of this
things we can dynamics
of the service or is it the way
people choose to use the service?
Like if you're a thoughtful person,
you wouldn't just like for instance,
the original image that was distributed,
uh,
came from an account that's now
banned. Right. And so it was,
it was discovered that that
account was a troll account. What,
how does that happen and what,
what was the thought process behind that?
Because the image that they posted was a
legitimate image. It really did happen.
It wasn't, it was a part of
an actual occurring event.
So why did you abandon the person
or the troll account that put it up?
I Dunno about this particular case,
but it's likely that it was found.
There's,
there's a lot of what
you see on the surface,
the Twitter and some of the actions
that we take on the surface.
But where we spend a lot of our
enforcement is actually what's happening
underneath. So in many cases we have, um,
trolls or people like the case that you
mentioned whose sole purpose is just to
harass or abuse or spread,
uh, particular information.
And oftentimes these accounts might be
connected or they start one account that
gets banned, they start another
account. But we can actually see, um,
this through a network Lens and we can
actually see some of those behaviors.
So that might have been one of
the reasons I'm not sure in,
in that particular case.
But, you know, the,
how do you know, do you know because of
Ip addresses? Do you know, because of the,
the
Alrighty of things.
Like it could be,
it could be trying to use the same phone
number, same email address, Ip addresses,
um, device ids, all these
things that we can use to,
to judge what's happening with them,
the context.
So we do have a lot of occurrences of
suspending or temporarily suspending
accounts because of activities
across accounts. Um, and, and that,
that happens a ton. But what I mean,
what I mean in the, in that we're,
we're helping this right now. It's
like some of the incentives, like just,
just imagine seeing that unfold and
when you see someone with one take,
it kind of emboldens something to follow
along and then this mob kind of rules.
So there has to be a way
for us to incentivize, uh,
a lot more, more considered and more
nuanced introspection of what's going on.
Yeah.
Give everybody mushrooms.
Probably the only way to know how are
you going to get people to be more
considerate? I mean, what,
what do you mean writing constantly
engineering social behavior, right? Yup.
Provided more context.
One more context. I could an
example. Let's, let's take
Brexit for example. Okay. So,
um, if I followed a bunch
of accounts that like,
like Boris Johnson who was constantly
giving me information about reasons to
leave, I would probably
only see that perspective.
Nigel Farrage yeah. And those, and those,
a lot of folks just will not follow
accounts that have a completely different
perspective, a different
influence. A number of people do.
Hopefully journalists do,
but most people won't do that work.
So this is the only tool we give
people follow an account. If, however,
during that time you followed the Hashtag
you followed the Hashtag vote leave
95% of the conversation and the tweets
you see are all reasons to leave.
But there's a small percentage that shows
a different perspective and that shows
a different um,
a different reasoning.
We don't make it easy for anyone
to do that and that is a loss.
Anyone to follow perspective,
follow the Hashtag follow topic,
follow, follow an interest.
And because of that, um,
we help build an echo
chamber and something that
doesn't really challenge any
perspective. And not to say that
we should force it upon people,
but we don't even make it easy for
people to do in the first place though.
The way you do that today, as you go
to this, the explore tab, you look,
you search for a Hashtag or you tap
into a Hashtag and you can see all the
conversation. But that's, that's work.
And most people just won't do the work.
They'll stay in their timeline,
they'll see what they need to see.
And I can certainly imagine,
you know why?
If I'm just following a bunch of people
who have the exact same take on this,
it just continues to embolden and
Bowman bolden and they see nothing of a
different perspective on the exact same,
the exact same situation.