The problem is when I tell them
I, the problem I had, dude,
the problem I have with
be an entertainment before
they give you questions to
ask and you have to ask them or
literally it could be your job.
So they float out like a
bunch of real dumb ones.
Did they give you any room to like, oh
yeah, you could do whatever you want,
but there'll be like, hey,
you gotta ask this question.
And it's like if somebody just got
divorced, you gotta be like, Hey man,
what happened in divorced? Oh, and it
sucks. You got to ask women that. Yeah,
that's why I stopped doing
it, man. I couldn't one time.
Uh, what's her name? Uh,
and uh, God, what's her name? Uh,
she, she was in devil's wear Prada,
not a Meryl Streep,
but, and Anne Hathaway.
So they gave me the dumbest question
as Anne Hathaway, she, Kim Kardashian,
Kanye West were on the cover of vogue.
And right before that it
was Anne Hathaway. And so
they told me, they go, hey,
why don't you ask her what
she thinks about the cover?
Because everybody was like, oh, this is
bull crap that Kim Kardashian was on it.
I asked Anne Hathaway that
question and she goes, well,
you know I don't run the magazine so it
really doesn't matter to me. I'm like,
fine. So I've finished the question.
I'm walking down the stairs and killed.
Then I hear, she goes, why the
fuck would he ask me that question?
I don't give a shit
who's on that magazine.
And I was about to turn back around cause
I kinda got mad. But now I was like,
man, she's fucking right. That was a dumb
ass question. If you could say, I'm sorry.
They made me ask you a question.
I just too late and it was too late.
I just feel so stupid
asking those questions.
Series like winding you up like a little
robot. Click, click, click, get out there.
Ask the question, don't ask. Oh,
they get so trouble. Oh yeah, yeah.
They threatened your job with it.
Well that's why those shows
are always so canned. You know,
when you have people talking to as
entertainers and everything, so canned,
it just seems so inauthentic.
Like they wanted me to ask
my first interview ever was
with Jennifer Aniston and
Marley and me. And this is right
after she broke up with Brad Pitt.
They want you to ask about
proud. They wanted me to ask
about, and I was like, no,
I can't do that to tell them no, no.
I, I, no, it was my first gay you too.
So no, I didn't. So I said, what if
I figure out a different way to ask?
So I found, so what I, they
were like, whatever you get,
we need a clip. You know?
And this was when I was at e entertainment
and this was my first big shoot ever,
Jennifer Aniston. And they were
like, you're going to go out there.
So it was Marley and me. So she just
broke up with Brad Pitt. So I go, uh,
since the movie's about a dog, I
go, what's the, uh, what's the, um,
what's the similarities
between a dog and a man?
And she labs and gives a great answer
about you. No one will be around,
but a dog is always forever. You
know, like men could treat you wrong.
So I got a great answer from it and
I didn't have to ask about prep.
And that's the thing is if you find a
smart way to ask it, you can ask it.
But they just sometimes want you to be
just so brutal. It's, it's, I can't,
because they don't have to do it and
they don't keep the relationships.
They don't care about the,
exactly. And they just don't,
they don't even care about you.
You're a little trained person that they
send out a little monkey. Hey Patterson,
little person listened to me as a
person. You have to listen. The,
the person who signs the paper.
Yeah,
it's the send you off and give
you little fucking direction. Oh,
it's the grossest,
I mean it was amazing because I got
to build relationships with people,
but like good for you for recognizing it.
Oh,
100% a hundred I knew they were doing
so once, you may not even be that,
but I recognize you've got
to get out of that. Oh, 100%
it's, I, I, my soul couldn't.
I couldn't,
I couldn't ask people about them breaking
up or something tragic happening in
their lives. Like, how are you doing now?
Is running to some of them TMZ dudes
that feel bad. I'm like, look, Bro,
I feel bad too,
but I'm not talking to you like this.
There's nothing good ever comes out of
these. Like it's no disrespect to you.
I know you're doing a job. I'd probably
do the same job if I was in your place.
If I was a kid when I was a kid of TMZ
was around it. I take that job. Yeah,
we're going to do is just try to ask them
famous too. Funny question, but it was,
it's just like, it's not the
way to discuss things. No.
I discuss things and you're coming out
of the airport or you're on your way to a
fucking restaurant somewhere and someone's
takes a camera in your face. Like,
come on. Well, I wasn't doing that. I was,
I was. We were going to junk it. No, no.
We're talking about TMC. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. But I mean, there's these,
these junkets are a
brutal assault on reality.
This, you're saying the same thing
over and over and over again.
You asked you in this sense,
everyone asks you the same question and
they'll tell. So tell us about this show.
Michael, you play, uh,
play Michael Yo real name.
This is crazy.