I get a lot of letters from
people asking me, well, you know,
I'm facing a similar situation. What
should I do? Uh, professors out?
And my answer is fight back hard.
So I've had a couple of these situations.
I had a guy on Twitter, the guy, the
guy who money referred to as a retired,
started,
started contacting my university,
trying to get me fired when he,
when it wasn't working with his
tagging my university on Twitter.
He actually contacted the HR department,
Human Resources Department at my
university. This is a random person.
What's a troll?
You got in touch with a troll and you
gave him what he wanted attention and then
he just started to run with
it. You basically gave him
an opportunity to score.
He's playing a video game. Exactly.
But now here's what happened.
The university's HR person
contacts me after hours.
I mentioned this actually recently
on the Ruben report. The, the, the,
the lady in question contacts me to say,
look,
here's a complaint that's
been filed against you. Now,
my first react instinct was,
oh,
someone in my job as a professor at
the university has complained about me,
which I couldn't think who that would be,
but I would think that that's where the,
the,
the template of their influence
over me would reside. No,
they had actually taken seriously a random
person on Twitter contacting them and
filing a complaint under the guise of
he's a student. Well, he's not my student.
Right? I mean, if a student, uh,
costs me in an alley to Mug me,
I can't fight back because Bruh, he's a
student or I'm allowed to, to deck him.
Right? So this is a guy that I'm
just having fun with. I mean,
I'm doing it with a smile.
We're going back and forth the size that
he's willing to go as far as try to get
me fine.
Now let's suppose that he had succeeded,
let's suppose that I hadn't fought back
because basically what I did with the
university,
I said,
are you literally thinking that it is
reasonable for you to be monitoring what I
do on my Twitter account? And the
example I gave her as an analogy, I said,
if if I see you coming out of the pharmacy
with your daughter and I feel that
you're speaking to her and occur manner
that I don't agree with as a parent,
can I report you to the university?
And that pretty much ended
the conversation very quickly.
But the fact that they felt sufficiently
in bolden to actually reach out to me
to address this complaint shows you
how chilling the environment is.
It is. Right, but let's
play devil's advocate. Sure.
If I was someone who was taking your
class or if I was someone who is very
sensitive or someone who has certain
ideals or morals and the professor who's
teaching the class that I take
called somebody a retard, I would,
I mean just being honest and I
love you, I would, I would say,
why is this guy doing that?
Like that's a stupid thing to do.
Like why are you engaging with
these people online and these,
these base insults like
that distasteful insults.
Fair enough.
And I engage with people like that.
I mean literally the reason I do it as
once in a while, my wife falls asleep.
I don't feel like working on my
scientific papers or my book or whatever.
I'm tired and I'm on Twitter and I heeded
your advice to try to not engage with
people. Some idiots
catches my eye. Oh Gee,
I use the word idiot idiot
for some strange reason. Okay.
It ain't call more on his own. Okay. You
just can't call them. So someone, someone,
our word catches my attention and I
decided to spar with them. You, you,
you like to get into the
octagon and do MMA sparring.
I go on Twitter and I
have fun with some idiot,
but when I just enjoy it and usually
we both laugh it off and we move on.
It's just part of my personality,
right? I'm, I'm, I'm a fun guy.
I could be deadly serious and
very academic and scientific.
And as you've correctly pointed in the
past, I could not take myself seriously.
It'd be just one of the guys.
So this is a manifestation of that now
that this person felt sufficiently in
bolden and his indignation
that he would try to fire me.
That's where you should be focusing
on sort of. I don't think that's real.
I don't think he really
felt so emboldened.
I think what it was is he recognized
that there is a climate today where a
person like yourself,
who is a professor who uses a certain
word that is deemed to be offensive by
society, that he can call you
on that word and get you caught.
You got caught up in a net of your
own doing, sir. Well, I'm, I'm,
I'm still here smiling and looking fans,
so that's okay. Do you do look 10 d,
do you regret using that
word at more than anything?
I regret that I ever get sucked
into these battles. That's,
that's it as much because again, it's
a slippery slope today. It's retarded.
Tomorrow it's more on the
next day it's schmuck. Yeah.
Well that is true in terms of like were
people don't understand calling someone
to retard, like say if you're a 30 year
old person today or 25 year old person,
let's try 25. Um, you realize
that that is forbidden.
Taboo war when you and I were
25, that word was nothing, right.
That word you would, you'd get taught
called it by your teacher. Right? I mean,
it's true. That was, and it,
and it was known to be someone who was
retarding you or growth or retarding the
class or saying things that were
retarding development of ideas and,
and logic moving forward that
you're, you're, you're a roadblock.
You're a pile of rocks in the
road. Right. You fucking retard.
Like that's how people talked about it.
Like that's how they said it,
but then it's become a new word
that's victim to this war on words.
Because you're not saying you
have down syndrome. Right.
What you're saying is you're
a dumb person, you know,
and that terminology, like,
especially the word retarded,
it is not even used
medically. Right. So it's,
it's not a word and the to say that
there's no nuance in this word cannot be
used again about a really
stupid fucking person, right.