You know, like to say that you've never
dated anybody who's over six foot five,
well, you're tall phobic. Right.
That's, that's a ridiculous statement.
That doesn't make any sense. You
know, to say that you've, uh,
you've never dated anybody that weighs
more than 300 pounds. You, you know,
you're a, you're a mass phobic.
That's ridiculous too. Yeah.
It's just all of it's stupid. It's all
stupid people telling him. But this,
what they're doing is,
it's a bunch of people that are pushing
this idea of being open entirely open to
all things trans,
that you as a heterosexual person should
not just recognize that this is a woman
because they chance for furred
from a of male to a female,
but recognize even if they haven't
transferred and recognize them in terms of
sexual selection in terms of a date.
Right.
And that's just fucking stupid
because you can decide, right?
You're not into certain things. Like I'm
not really into girls with short hair.
You could decide that it's not my thing.
I don't like girls with shaved heads.
I don't find it attractive.
Like a woman can say that too.
I don't like guys are creepy
mustaches and nobody gets mad at him.
But if a man says to certain people,
I'm not in to chicks with Dicks,
then that guy's a piece of shit.
Or what about,
there's a thing called sexual
racism where you specifically,
you know, I'm not attracted
to a particular, you know,
I don't like Asian men. I
don't like black women. Right.
You're not supposed to instantiate
those sexual preferences.
If the racial queue is the one that's
causing you to either be attracted or not
attach to someone, what do
you think of that? Um, well,
there's certainly beautiful
people of all race,
so that doesn't make a whole lot of sense
to me in terms of the person selection.
Like if you tell me you've never
seen a beautiful black woman, right?
Like you crazy.
Like you have met enough black women.
If you tell me 17 a beautiful Asian
woman, like what? What are you saying?
Like there's beautiful
people in and there's also,
you should be allowed to, to be with
whoever you want in terms of not,
but why is it, it's always sex,
right? Because like obnoxious people.
Here's the perfect example.
I don't like friends that are
loud and get drunk in public. Oh,
what are you drunk phobic?
No, I just don't enjoy that.
So like in terms of sexual selection,
that's on the dates.
I tell you why that analogy might fail.
And some of the progressive's you could
alter your level of obnoxious snus.
You could grow out of your boxes as well.
I know some people conceivably,
theoretically, I know some people
are fucked. That's just who they are.
Fair enough. Or you want
to name any names? No,
but your race is a immutable part of you.
Okay.
That's the perspective. I see that. I
mean I'm, I'm playing devil's advocate.
I'm not, I'm not agreeing
with it. Okay. Well what about
a tall versus short? Right?
You know what,
if you're a woman volleyball player and
you're six foot three and you don't want
to date a guy was five feet tall, you
know, are you, what are you, what are you,
by the way,
that is one of the biggest problems of
being a very tall woman because one of
the,
one of the,
so there's something called assorted of
mating and evolutionary theory sort of
mating is basically birds of
a feather flock together.
And that's very much the mechanism
that drives may choice much more than
opposites attract.
So one of the sorts of mating cues
that people most assault on his height.
So it's not so much that women want
guys that are only six foot or taller,
it's just that the woman wants
a guy who's taller than her.
So if you look at the, there is a study
that I've discussed in the past, uh,
that looked at something
like 720 actual couples.
And I think there was only a single
one out of the 720 where the woman was
taller than the man. Now once a woman
gets to be over a certain height,
she's six foot two,
six foot three,
her potential pool of prospective
suitors really shrinks.
And so if you have a daughter,
you really want to pray that she
doesn't get too tall because boy are her
choices going to be limited because few
women want to date the shorter guy than
them. Yeah. When you're at six
foot three, six foot four woman,
that's gotta be a tough spot.
You're basically relegated to big
athletes are big exact people. And the,
the nick,
the other place where you get this sort
of a sort of May thing is where you get
women who are super educated, uh, that
makes sense. The exact same thing happens.
The more educated a woman gets,
the worse her marriage prospects because
the more sophisticated women are,
the more they insist on a high
status male. And therefore,
as I get more educated as a woman,
there are just fewer men who
are as educated or more than me,
and therefore I'm doomed
to a life of solitude.
That totally makes sense.
Especially considering that men,
you know,
in general they get insecure around
women who are more successful and more
educated or more intelligent.
Like very rarely are men comfortable
with a woman who has to explain things to
them. Absolutely. Yeah. By the way,
I think I have another theory which
I'd like to at some point test,
maybe someone will steal it now.
So when you have a couple
that gets married very young,
they are judging one another based on
their mate value at 18 or 19 right.
So Tony is the high school quarterback
and so he's the hot guy and I'm the
cheerleader and then later he stagnates.
He doesn't go on with his career.
Whereas I go on and become a physician.
I am a cheerleader.
So at 29 there is not a huge inequity
between our two mating values on the
mating market.
Right.
So when we were both 19 the fact that
we had roughly the same may think value
made us a very attractive,
stable couple.
But Tony turned out to be a fucking
loser. Exactly. He's a lame duck. Exactly.
And so I so I have a theory that,
and I'd like to at some point tested
maybe some graduate student will write to
me saying that I'll work with this on you.
The doctor side,
I have a theory whereby I think that in
many cases where people end up divorcing
when they married young,
it's precisely because that which started
as equitable mating values at time t
zero turned out to have huge in our
trajectory on the mating market and that
puts a huge strain on the
marriage, especially when
the wife status is going up.
That the best way to ensure that the
marriage ends as for the status of the
woman to keep going up and that of
the man to either stagnate or go down,
that's going to be
doomed. That makes sense. It May.
It makes sense that also, you know,
obviously the young marriages are rough
because people grow and they don't
necessarily grow together.
We you catch people 10 years later and
they're oftentimes radically different
people.
Right.
But then there's also the
thing that women don't seem to,
for the most part, respect a man is
not doing as well as them. Right? You,
that's a, that's a giant issue.
Even if the guy's doing okay,
like say if your guys making $50,000
a year, that's a very good living.
He's out there doing well,
but you make 300 let me 300 grand a year
and this fucking losers over here with
his 50 grand,
like you're kicking ass.
You'll like some big wig at
some big corporation like that.
That seems to be a real sticking point.
And with men,
especially if they have a household where
they contribute income together, they,
they pile all the income
and the man starts spending
the woman's money on stuff.
You know,
he starts buying stuff.
You've got a new fishing rod and what
did you get that with your money or my
money. You know, it gets weird. Right?
And incidentally, uh, so speaking of say,
consumer psychology stuff that I study,
when you take a very rich woman
and you go out on a date with her,
even though she obviously can afford the
dinner and she can afford anything that
you're going to buy her, if you
exhibit cues of frugality, cheapness,
that's the perfect way to ensure
that you won't have a second date.
So it's not so much a question of
uh, you know, it's an old sexist,
the ritual whereby men were wooing women.
It really is an honest signal
of your commitment to, to
a woman. So the best way,
and I get many of these
letters where people ask me,
hey professor, what are you,
you know, you know, dating advice.
Well you do have to exhibit generosity
when you go out with that, I mean,
nuptial gift giving them,
she'll give, giving.
Is it sort of the fancy term for
courtship rituals across animal species?
So many species,
you have typically the male engaging in
some form of courtship gift giving and
depending on the quality of the gift,
will determine whether the female will
mate with your not while so much of what
we do in marketing context
is exactly that, right?
It's the exact same phenomenon repeating
itself in the human context, right? Uh,
uh, engagement rings, right?
The fact that you are supposed to spend
a quarter of your yearly salary on this
rock, is that really what it
is? Yeah, that's what I'm,
I don't know if everybody meets it,
but that's right. It is that right?
It's three months. Exactly. God, when
you say a quarter of the yearly salary,
it makes you just go,
what in the fuck is wrong with people?
But there is so much money, but
here's the, but here's the reason.
Here's the reason you ready? It's, it's
what's called is the Javian signal.
I don't know if I've ever
discussed this in this,
in this podcast is a Javian signal is
basically the idea that for a signal,
to be honest, it has to be
costly. Otherwise everybody
could imitate it. Right? So,
so think about, for example, rites of
passage in different cultures, right?
If you want to demonstrate
that you're a top warrior,
the rite of passage has to be
brutal. Otherwise, if it's only,
we all have to do five setups
than every male could do it.
And then the females can determine the
pretenders from the real guys, right?
So you have, for example, bullet ant,
do you know this one through, right?
You put your hands through, right? I mean,
that takes a lot of
courage and capacity to,
people don't know what
we're talking about.
So this is a tribe in the Amazon
whereby you take the bullet,
ant is supposedly the,
the biggest purveyor of pain
that is humanly possible
that you could experience.
My friend Steve gets done by one,
did it and what did,
he was in Bolivia, I believe. And uh,
he got stung and uh, in his heel, got
them in the heel and he said it was just,
he was delirious. What's happening?
He said it lasts for a few hours,
then it goes away.
Right?
So what they do in this tribe is they
take a bunch of these ants in the order of
a couple of hundred. One is enough
to cause you agonizing, impossible,
delirious pain. And they
said, date them through this
compound. Uh, and then they enter,
weave them in these gloves,
these a leaf gloves so that
when they're coming to,
they come out of their stupor
and you have your hands in there,
they start viciously biting you,
stinging you,
and you're supposed to withstand
that pain without screaming.
You have to take it. And so you sort of
almost go into this religious fervor,
this kind of uh, incantation.
And you have to do that ritual,
20 separate occasions,
the tech 20 different times
on different days, 2020,
before you are admitted into
the tribe of Warriors, whatever.
Well now let's think of back
to the engagement ring, right?
If all it takes for me to convince you
of my honest intentions is to buy you
flowers. And now let's go back behind
the shed and you know, have sex.
Well then a lot of cheaters are going
to convince you of doing this when they
really didn't have good intentions.
But if it takes for me to spend a quarter
of my salary to convince you that I
have on us,
so therefore,
this is a form of what's called as a
hobby and signaling because the Harvey was
a Israeli ornithologists that
studied this type of behavior,
this costly signaling behavior using
Arabian babblers, which is a type of bird.
So here's another example of
as a hobby and signal, uh,
you probably have seen this, uh,
when you have a Predator, uh,
that's looking at who to attack,
you often will have gazelles starting to
actually make themselves conspicuously
visible to the Predator. They come
close him, they start jumping from,
have you ever seen this gentleman,
and I think it's called stroking,
not strutting. And can you
think why that would be? Like,
why are they not hiding? Why are they not
making themselves? Uh, in conspicuous.
Why?
Why are they drawing attention
to themselves when they
are 50 different gazelles
that the Predator could be pointing
to? Why? Well, because what it's, what,
what that animal is saying is the fact
that I could stand here in front of you
and jump up and down and make myself this
visible suggests that it's probably a
lost cause for you to try to go
after me. I'm super fit. Right?
It's a costly signal of my fitness.
It's an honest signal,
right?
The one who is not doing this behavior
is the one that you should be paying
attention to. Ah, so this is called,
and so I use this principle of as a hobby
and signaling to explain things like
conspicuous consumption,
right?
The reason why you buy the fancy car
that the other males can't hope to
purchase,
it's precisely because they can't
afford to match your signal.
Therefore,
it's an honest signal.
The reason why I buy $100 million painting
that a monkey could have drawn shows
how wealthy I am,
that I could waste $100 million.
Ah, that makes sense. That makes
sense. It's all just meeting stuff.
It's mating and food.
You don't want to become somebody dinner.
You want to find dinner and you want
to have sex. Good night everybody.
Yeah.
Those signals are so fascinating when we
see them in our culture and people get
angry at them.
Like you see some guy pull up in a Ferrari
and you go look at this fucking loser
with as Little Duke,
right?
You're like maybe or maybe a guy with
a shit load of money wants to let the
world know cause he likes to fuck you.
Right. I've shared actually on this
show, I think the stories about my,
one of my brother's who was a big
car collector, three Ferrari's,
Aston Martin Ligand,
and I've even shared a story
which I'm happy to repeat, uh,
of we would go to
nightclubs where he's this,
this is the Olympia and this
is the five foot three guy.
And we would go to nightclubs and he
would pick the most beautiful woman and
approach her even though she's
accompanied by six foot four, you know,
tough fucking guy.
And he had that confidence.
I think because he had that
wealth catapulting him,
he certainly helps. It
certainly helps. Yeah. It's um,
it is a weird ever prevalent aspect in
the communication between men and females
is how much money does the
man have? Right. I mean,
and this is one thing that a lot of women
hate because they don't want to feel
like they could be purchased and
they can't. They can't. They can't.
Some can write a lot, Ken. It's a factor.
It's a big fee and a lot of women are
very rare, rabidly ruthlessly independent.
They don't want that ever in
their life and good for them. But,
but the reality is it's a
very effective strategy.
You pull up in that Ferrari or that
Rolls Royce or whatever the fuck you're
driving and it has a big impact
and you get to that nightclub.
And those studies have been
done endless sea and psychology.
So here's one example and you don't need
to have a signal as big as a Ferrari.
Just how you dress in terms of
the status that is exhibited to,
there's a study that was done
I think in the early nineties,
where they manipulated the
status, the, it's the sartorial,
the attire of men and women into one
of three different types, you know,
high status medium and you know, some tee
shirt or Mcdonald's uniform, whatever.
And then they asked men and women,
uh, one of six possible, you know,
would you go out on a w for coffee with
this guy? Would you go out on dinner?
Would you have sex with him?
Would you marry him?
And across all six
levels of relationships,
the status of the attire of a man had a
profound effect on the likelihood of the
woman saying, yes, hire the status.
The more likely she said yes.
That same manipulation on women had zero
effect on men and other words no man
has ever uttered the following words.
Words, my God, you've got a juicy but,
and I'd love to have sex with you, but
you're not exhibiting cues of ambition,
therefore no sex for you, Linda. Yeah,
that's a,
that's a reality.
That's a reality that people are very
uncomfortable with and I don't think women
necessarily are craving the same reaction
from men because of their ambition.
I don't think women are ever
sang through my ambition.
I'm going to get a good man. Right. You
know that just, it's just not a factor,
but they do say through my I ambition,
I'm never going to need a map. True.
That's because that's because,
look,
there's the reality is there's a lot of
shitty human beings out there and some
of them have penises and if you're a woman
and you run into too many of those or
for buy for whatever reason,
because of your environment,
because of your behavior,
because of the circles you travel
in your around too many of them,
a large dating pool of shitheads
out there. You know, you just say,
I don't want this in my life. I
want, I don't want to be like my mom.
I don't want to be like my sister.
I want to be independent.
But what you're not saying is,
I am going to get a or house and a
baller car and I'm going to get me a man.
And the only woman that I know of that
I've ever heard say that is disgusting
and the only woman that I
ever, she's like, you know,
talking about her success and our
success allows her to get men.
She's a foul beast.
Loud.
Yeah, she's not, it's not
healthy. A lot of women,
it's not so much at their interest.
I mean resources are good only to the
extent that they allow you to ascend the
social hierarchy, right. This,
this doesn't explain why some women are
attracted to the starving artists, right?
Because what, why are so
many women romanticizing
over the guy with the guitar,
but that's because they are choosing him
based on his future trajectory. Right.
I am.
I am banking on the fact that you exhibit
enough talent that I suspect that by
investing in you, by choosing you, it's
going to take me to that trajectory.
No woman has ever authored the
following words. You have no talent.
You exhibit no ambition. You're never
going to step out of the basement.
Let's have sex. Right? So, so it's not
that women are only interested in money.
They're interested in a panoply of cues,
all of which relate to the potential
of ascending the social hierarchy.