Happen. The Joe Rogan
experience. Yeah, it's,
it's tragic.
The things the words are going to do.
I was going to be in the military
when I was a kid. That was one of my,
I want to be in special forces.
And Are you looking at me now being a
transgender guy with that? But yeah,
that was where it was.
I know Trump wouldn't have let me in the
post is right now if I applied to write
the second. Um, but yeah,
so I follow everything. I,
I kind of run my life on, on the
military and that sounds a bit weird.
I run my career on a military thinks
it's quite difficult to, you know,
any career, putting it together.
Kind of weird. What's your next move?
What's you'll you like strategize and that
yell? Yeah, strategy up. That was due.
I planned 50 years ahead. Really? Oh yeah.
Well if you think about it, you came out,
I came out as transgender 34 years ago.
That's not the first good thing that an
agent wants to hear. Your transgender,
that's 85. This is such a hot thing.
This is even now, they would say, okay,
well it's got a little better than
it was for five, 10 millennia.
This a little better now. But it's still
not the hardest ticket that everyone's,
we welcome transgender guys in
here for this, that the other,
it's not the top of the list.
And I've also got boy mode and girl mode
and I do drama dramatic films in boy
mode.
And then I'm touring and Gilman and doing
standup and I campaign for politics in
go mode and I just,
how do we do that?
I just switched change, you
know, take off heels, flat shoes.
Yeah, because if you were
just talking, like if you,
you didn't have makeup on and he
didn't have the heels and the nails,
you just seem male. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, it's a, it's,
I think it's genetically and
built, you know, there's some,
I think there's quite a lot
of people maybe who were, um,
uh, the, the way that light, they live
their lives live their own personality.
They're not particularly male
or female, I feel. But I felt,
I've always felt since I was four or five,
I want to express this side of myself.
And it's built in. I
think it's genetic. Um,
and if you analyze masculine and feminine,
if you really get down to it, you see,
I, I find it impossible to come up with
anything that was particularly masculine,
particularly feminine,
except for the ability to build muscle
mass is easier for men in inverted
commerce. That's it. But you know,
great football is soccer players,
men and women in athletics, runners,
men, women, strong character,
men's wheat character. Sure. Men
and women, um, mathematicians,
whatever, whatever it is, there's
nothing that you can really say, ah,
that is earning good shot with a gun.
No. Anyone could do that. It's a,
we're all humans and so, and we get
fixated by the masculine feminine wisdom.
It's a tiger tiger attacking you and
trying to kill you. You don't go,
now is this a girl to girl, boy
tech? We don't care about it.
And they don't care either the Tigers.
So you've always felt like you gravitated
towards feminine things toward no,
gravitate towards both. I had, I
gravitated towards playing soccer.
I was in the first team for
two years when I was a kid,
was planning to do officer training corps
and then go marines or Paris and then
get into special forces RSAs which be
the equivalent of your Delta Force.
Um, and that was a distinct pleasure and
you're a lot about that. And I thought,
which war they're going to send me to
actually which one they sent me to it and
it could be the idiots that I'm at
school with or send me to the wrong war.
World War Two was very clear.
And then after that, every
other words kind of hazy.
Uh, but there's all this
feminine side girls' side.
I'm not sure how to do it. The, the
articulate, even after 34 years,
it's difficult to articulate,
but I wanted to express that. Um,
and if I look more like a woman than I,
you know, it would be much easier. But,
um, yeah. So I decided to do that in
85 when it wasn't cool. And I go, man,
I've had a lot of fights in the street.
A lot of people screaming abuse at me.
I'm taking a couple of people to
court or just report it and police.
And then we went to court
and uh, yeah, and you fight,
you fight your fights instead of
going to do a military fighting thing.
I've done, I've done, I said, this
might be wrong for me to say this,
but I say I've done special forces,
civilian division, you know,
fighting people's to skew that people
see and outperforming four languages.
I've run over 80 marathons. I'm going
into politics next year. And uh,
and yeah,
and I came and the transgender thing is,
it's in a better place
than it was back in 85.
Well,
it certainly now I think because of
probably Caitlyn Jenner and the movement
that you're,
you're seeing for,
to accept people that want to do
whatever and anything you want to do.
Yeah, it is. We're more accepting
of each other. We do see three more.
Um,
what's the word?
Begins with a t the more open,
more allowing. There's a welfare.
It was just walked out of my
head. But anyone that would, um,
but uh,
yeah,
and at the same time people are getting
around doing more killings and stuff at
the say well there's more people.
There's just sheer volume of humans
at the end. The population growth is,
and saying this took us something like
200,000 years to get to 1 million and
then it's taking this and our six 50
years to get to seven and a half billion,
which is scary.
Yeah.
When I was a kid,
I think the United States population
was less than 200 million.
Now it's 300 million
global was whatever it was.
Now it's seven plus bordering eight.
Yeah. Several often people when
I came out, I think it was 6.5,
I think that's just running away.
And one of the weird things
is if we are having less wars,
if we're getting better health to people,
then more kids are around.
And some people in, in, in I suppose lower
income backgrounds in around the world,
they will say, well we need
to have six kids. Cause that's
what, you know from, uh,
from water much money. Yeah. That's
what we do. But as economics get better,
people have less kids in that.
Hopefully that should calm down.
There should be a butting me.
I think they feel that it'd be a
leveling off of the population,
the theory that they believe that
industrialized nations and Westernized
Society, when people start
having two careers, um,
you know,
and then two career households,
people are less likely to have a bunch
of kids. Yeah. So as people do better,
they have less kids. Yeah.
Yeah. So I'm, I'm a guy. I,
I'm a glass glasses.
Two thirds full person.
That's real actually instead of a
glass is half full, half empty person.
So you're optimistic.
I'm a big,
I couldn't be here in
the hills with the nails.
I'm planning to do this
and got a film coming out.
Then I'm touring the country and
then I'm going to politics as well.
When you first started wearing women's
clothes and dresses and makeup on stage,
did people think it was a gimmick?
What did they think they did?
I decided not to go on
women's clothes just,
and I should say that family and close, I
would just wear dresses. Right. You know,
like women can wear trousers or pants on.
We used to call the high men's pants.
That pan is faggot. So,
um, but yeah, they felt,
I first started talking about it
and not wearing anything. Again.
Look kind of boy like and male like,
and then you were talking about
it like I had the first check.
This is my first ever joke. I had this
about two years before I did it. I said,
look, you don't stand up. Um,
so if you're from a minority,
it's kind of a good thing.
So if you, in standup terms,
so if you're from a low ink, come back
round, you'd say, rich people, God,
they're so easy for them to
show or what music man. Ah, man,
if you're an ethnic background,
you say white papers. Oh, I bet.
So if you're a white male,
middle class, stand up. Useless.
So thank God I'm a transvestite.
That was my first love.
And everyone thought he's making jokes
about something that he's not and they
wouldn't believe.
Me and journalists were going,
I don't know why he's doing this
because he's doing pretty well now,
but there's this idea, is this a joke?
So I thought I better wear addresses,
you know, put your makeup on. And
then they said, okay, he's doing this.
He is serious but he looks a mess
kind of baby elephant thing I was doing
okay gotta get your weight under control.
You could have better haircut than
that and you just got to fail a lot.
And there's a humiliation period.
I mean this is the weird thing about
coming out that it's kind of humiliating.
People say you look at people say
horrible things. What they say, uh,
what the fuck is that?
Somebody said to my face right there
as I was walking out of a restaurant,
so I thought that's not very nice. And
you have to be able to deflect it and go,
well you're obviously a scumbag,
so fuck you man. So I mostly men,
yes, and occasionally women,
k occasionally women. But
yeah, I mean, you know,
it's low. If people have low, lower
character, they are less a character.
She's a strong character in yourself.
You don't get live in that live.
What the hell? You know people, okay.
It doesn't look quite look together,
but you know, life's tough enough. But
if, if you want to put someone down,
you raise your own status by
doing it and they will do that.
And so I have stood in the street
and people have unloaded, you know,
swear words ineffective to me and I've
just, I rung you and the violin and viola,
they got what you'll fuck?
Oh fuck you. And among, and
there's literally, you know,
two or three of them or one of me just
screaming at each other and I just won't
back down. Now that this happened
recently, it was nine months ago,
someone outside my house in, in
London, just having a go at me.
So he knew who you are as well. They
did. They knew exactly what they knew.
Who I live with it we're going to do, your
house is on the hell. Is this awesome?
And I want to speak because of
the way you dress. Well it was,
he added that into it. There was
a, there was a altercation over,
I was just packing my car cause I was
just driving home to see my dad and
somebody said, you gotta give me
a ride in your car. I said, oh,
am I someone heckles me like that in
the street. I just come back with,
you will never have a ride in my car.
I have to give you one African.
So that happened. And then this guy
went off and yeah, this and that.
And the other one is just screaming at me.
And so I'm shouting back at him,
giving him word for word. And then I went,
I said, who is that idiot? And they said,
oh, that's this guy. He's a known, ah,
he's a nutter, you know, he's just,
he does this. I went, all right,
maybe I should mention it because
he said he's going to do my og.
I mentioned it to the police
two weeks later. Same thing.
Who's shouting at me? Oh, it's
the same decade. So I felt right.
Next time I go by now, he knows
where you live. Well, he always did.
He was right in front of the house.
That's always fun, isn't it? Yeah. Well,
and he said, we're going to do your
house when you're away, you know?
So this was the, that was
his opening gambit. Do your
house when you're away. Yeah.
I'm letting the, letting you know
there are a coward. Yeah. Well it was,
it was a very positive, he didn't run
a PR company. That's kind of terrorism,
right? They're trying to strike terror
in you when you're away. Well, yeah.
Well that is, yes. That
is the hatred thing is,
did you think about just going out
there and fucking them up? I don't,
they don't quite,
that I would have liked if I've gone
through the military thing of a Gulf,
that I would learn how to do that,
you know?
And I've never have craft my God myself
up to the thing I do need to grab my gun
was half out,
but I haven't got there.