What was it like finding
Bernard who, you know,
and I don't know if this is the stage
stage I want to fighting Bernard was,
it was um, totally different than
what I expected. What'd you expect?
I expect him to be tricky and sneaky
and just a very crafty and obviously I'm
experienced.
Um,
I did jump up two weight classes
to take that fight and um,
but at the same time,
that was not an 80% Kelly public.
And this is true and this is documented.
Um, I have it on my phone and I was
going to actually bring that out,
but that fight I sport,
you know,
three times for that maybe for the fourth
time was with an arm brace and then it
went into it and I'd never said
anything cause I'm the type person,
I don't want to have people
think that was making excuses.
I love Bernard and I think he's,
uh, one of the greatest of all time,
greatest middleweights. But that was
not that night. You know, I came down,
we had what's wrong, what was
right, I had bronchitis, I was sick,
I was running a temp.
Actually in the locker room,
we had to go through what to commission.
We almost took the inhaler for it.
Then we found out through the commission
that you cannot take that cause it's
steroid. So we had to go to the
nasal, um, or not nasal to the pill,
oral pill. Uh, we had
it in the locker room.
I don't know if you ever heard of
a Guy Thomas houser. He writes,
you mean he used to write from New York
Times? He does a lot of big box in books.
He was a nerd and houser don't,
he's not one side. What's anybody?
He's Bryce. What? He knows what he
sees and that's the truth. And um,
he was a nerd when it commission came in.
They were going through my prescription,
you know, they ever taking a temperature,
uh, giving me the exam
and that's what happened.
How it was a look Dardick fight
with what, uh, of all people,
what was wrong with your arm? You had
burst, burst, sac bursitis, societies,
bursitis in your elbow. And you know,
that came into an issue. And we sport,
you know, like I said, it was a handful.
It might've been more than three or four,
but it wasn't a lot because usually in
training camp you do three days a week
for about eight week camp for about six,
six and a half weeks.
And it was because of your elbow that
you couldn't spar. Yeah. You know,
cause he didn't want to keep hitting it.
And then I didn't like just the way I am.
I didn't like having a brace on it or not.
And um,
so that was an issue and there was a lot
of things that sometimes if you could
go back and you wish you
could do it over again,
but there was a lot of other things going
on. Why we didn't postpone to fight.
First of all is sold out. And uh, the
Youngstown people bottle or tickets,
um, we had the issue with the
Paul Williams fight, you know,
that that fell through. So I can't, I
just came off fighting Gary Lockett,
who was really not a well known name,
a household name.
So if I were to postpone that fight,
the backlash on that would have been bad,
really bad. And you know, so it
was more to ego thing I think.
And worried about what
everybody was going to think.
Taking nothing away at all from an s
where I wanted to tap into taking nothing
away from Bernard Hopkins unfortunately
against a guy like Bernard Hopkins.
I had to have that happen
to me is what socks and,
and he was a tremendous fighter.
I mean, he did things in there.
A lot of times I've seen him make a
moves that I knew what he was doing and I
just couldn't pull the trigger on it.
Um, and he was fast and he was strong.
And then there was times that he just did
some crafty things also that, you know,
got to me and, and his body work
in that fight slowed me down a lot.
But it was just one of them fights where
I could honestly say that that was not
an 80% Kelly Pollick. And that could
be honest to say if I was 100%,
I don't know if I would have won that
fight. And I'll be honest about it.
I'm not going to be the guy that's,
that comes there and says, well,
I thought it was 100% I'll or knock them
out. No, it was Bernard Hopkins, you know?
Um, when you think about your legacy and
you think about looking back at your,
your career,
those kinds of fights where you had to
take it when you were compromised, um,
how do those factor in to do those
fuck with your head? Mm, yeah.
That never a bad way, right?
But enough for you. Like if
I was 100%, yeah. You know,
I got an a buddy to the international
boxing hall of fame over the summer and it
was cool as hell and it'd be there
and you start seeing the inductees and
everything and I start, you start
breaking down your career. Like, am I,
am I able to qualify for
this? You know, and it's so,
so going to get pissed off who didn't
get in because I got in and I look at it
and I break it down a couple of ways.
I say 40 and two with 34
knockouts is a hell of a record.
You know, I held the belts
for over three years. Um,
I be a handful of guys that were
legit when I beat them. And then I,
then I look at the fight though I
fought Bernard Hopkins and I got my ass
whooped in that fight and there was
no other way of putting it, you know,
it's the truth. So how much
did that damage? You know, uh,
people remembering that nobody looks at
the fact of the two way class jump and
they call him back down and defending
against a very game. Antonio Rubio.
And then of course the Martinez fight,
which a lot of people,
and it was documented and, and on
Hbo with the commentators, you know,
the weight issue in that fight. But what
was the way it, it shouldn't know fine.
Well, how we had to get down. That was
my last fight at middle weight, you know,
trying to cut the weight. I was 29 at
the time and another great fighter.
It happened. It was tough
with the weight. Um,
I really can't use that as an excuse
though, cause I don't know. But you know,
I know I was doing good in the
ninth round. I did hit a wall.
A lot of people try to use the cut
and I think even without the cut,
the same result would have
happened though, you know,
he would have boxed my ears
off the last four rounds.
It was just one of them things that there
was nothing you could do. So when I,
when I have some up my career,
I look at those fights and I,
and I know personally that
it could have been different,
but at the same time I'm very happy and
content with the way my career went.
You know, I was 40 and two,
um, my last four or five at
one of my last four fights,
you know, before I retire. So
I went out winning, um, and,
and I was done with the
sport. I truly was. And so I,
I think right now I'm, I'm kind of content
and happy with my career. Of course.
I think anybody says could have been
better and I wish it was better.
It may be a little bit, but I'm not going
to have ever beat myself up over it.