Yeah, well everybody feels
like it's somebody else's job.
Everybody feels like work like,
yeah. And everybody feels like, well,
you just got to get out
of that neighborhood. No,
that's what I was supposed to work.
Roxanne Shawntay talked about reentry
vacation. She said, you know, she,
she doesn't want to hear people keep
complaining about gentrification when the
kids that are leaving these neighborhoods,
whether they'd sing dance, rap or not,
or just Cokie good jobs and
Colby decent human beings.
You should be reentering
your neighborhoods.
Who should be buying houses or pieces
of land near one of the most impressive
things, one of my favorite
players of John Stockton,
and I'll know if it's true or not,
but I read a story that he actually
bought a house right on the street he grew
up in. So an Aussie that he'd go
back essentially home with his kids.
So they'd had some type of
normalization to their life. We,
we should be doing that.
You know, um, Tiana,
I have bought properties together in
the same neighborhoods we grew up in,
were developing things
like restaurants and stuff.
I like to see more athletes or rappers
become the merchant in business class,
net weight and I like to see people who
grew up in neighborhoods move back to
those neighborhoods they grew up in like
like the typical iconic American dream.
You know, you can build a, you know,
another 8,000 square feet in the back
of the a frame house if you want to,
but you shouldn't be going to 50 60
minutes outside the city and they
complaining about the blight of the
city because you took yourself away,
you took the talent
and the resources away.
Do you think that everyone should feel
that way though? Or is it, I mean,
do you feel like you have to be committed
to the city that you grew up in or
couldn't you want to just get the fuck
out of there and go somewhere different?
It's nothing wrong with
getting the fuck out,
but you just think you should go back and
support it. Yeah, it's like I tell kids,
you know, in college and they say, Mike,
you know, what can we do? You know,
kids and college kids,
when you go speak at a college and say,
well what could we do? Kids want
to affect the world. Very easy.
Find a kid in high school,
tutor that kit and make sure to replace
you with this university or another.
I said, you're just please replanting
a scene. If you grow food, you know,
you don't grow the same land
you have to year after year.
Some you have to give that land a break,
retail it, you know what I'm saying?
And it was kind of like the neighborhood.
So you don't have to stay in the
same neighborhood your whole life.
You don't have to feel like I never
win anything or escaped anywhere.
But you do have to, don't sell
your mother's house, you know,
rent it to your cousin, you know,
let your younger assistant but don't,
don't sell your mother.
That piece of land was worked
for the blood to toil the soil.
It means something and it should. And,
and for working class people especially,
it keeps your neighborhood and communities
more like the ones that made you be a
good human being. You know? So
I think that there is something,
most people don't leave the town he grew
up in and moved to the other side or
they moved to the suburbs for most
people or most people marry somebody they
knew. You know what I'm saying?
My thing is make the best of it.
Don't let it keep becoming a worse.
A man named Mr John,
my wife and I own barbershops
or people don't know.
We own these things called
the shea washing room shops.
We have one at state farm arena
that when the Atlanta Hawks play,
we have our flagship
store on Edgewood Avenue.
Edgewood avenue was once an Auburn Avenue
when wants to centers of black Atlanta
in terms of commerce and retail and money,
Atlanta life insurance company with the,
are you guys Google?
Some of this stuff's is big time shit.
You know,
this isn't the old narrative of we've
never had nothing because that's not the
truth and it was a very rich
city for African Americans.
Still is on his street,
used to be owned by African Americans.
The storefronts in there, their
children after these people. Dot. Off,
sold the buildings off and sold it for
cheap. And I know this because many,
Mr John who runs the grocery store, they
are stopped me one day he said, you know,
Michael,
after we're gone and this neighborhood's
been gentrified and everything's
different,
they're going to come along and say
that white people stole this from us.
And he said, that's not true. He say,
the children or the people that were here
left and they never came back because
they didn't think what the parent's bill
was good enough. Oh man, to kill me.
Because that is snatches black
people, less Americans, period.
We have gotten to a point
where we are unappreciative,
we are entitled, and we don't think
what happened before us was good enough.
So we don't treasure it. We don't
honor it. We don't reinvest in it.
That could be a farm in Milledgeville,
that could be a house in Adamsville,
but we have to do a better
job of appreciating ourselves,
appreciating our community and income
preciate now greater community and you
have to reenter.
You have to reenter fi day.
You have to be a part of
whatever gentrification
happens to make sure that your
stake is still there and net what you
care about from a morals and civil
perspective is represented there.
My uncle, my uncle John Blackman,
who's a huge influence on me dad
and had a five car garage where,
where he did transmissions and stuff
and I begged my aunt to sell it,
please, I don't want you, I know they're
going to come. The beltline is coming.
I was, but please sell it to me. I didn't
want my uncle's building, you know,
for to go to strangers and become, you
know, an apartment complex or something.
And I walked in your building, not
seen your building. And I said, wow,
I know what I'm gonna do with it now.
I've had it for like three years
and now it's just, I just had it,
but I didn't never knew what I
wanted to do. But you would like, Yo,
you need somewhere to go every day you're
building is impressive. I'm like, Yo,
I'm just going to just make my bit, my
uncle's building, my office is right.
And I figured out a way to make
a lot of money off of it. I mean,
I've already made a lot of money,
which was me and leaving me to buy it.
But it's important to me that as his
neighborhood turns into hipster land,
cause it's definitely going to be,
she's going to be black hips,
going to be like chocolate hipster lands.
I just wanted to make sure that's there
still some chocolate working class in
there and sometimes they're going to
go buy coffee and there's going to be a
loud ass muscle car and lots of
marijuana smoke point out of it.
So they'll know that, you know,
my uncle's nephew still in town.