The Joe Rogan experience. Um, there,
there's a real thought,
and this is something that turns
Mckenna described way back in the late
nineties,
early two thousands.
He believed that you're going to be able
to recreate a lot of psychedelic states
through virtual reality so that people
that don't want to actually do a drug
will be an ideal experience. What it's
like to be on that drug and that, I mean,
that's, it's very theoretical
and hypothetical and yes,
you know, who knows whether or
not that's possible, but that,
that could be one other way that human
beings interface with technology.
So humans,
in my view,
are far more hackable than we think that,
that there are so many that we just
imagine our biology is being fixed,
but our biology is really variable.
Like I have a, a friend, um,
who is an anesthesiologist at Stanford
and she's done this experimentation of
just running just like very mild electric
currents through people's brains.
And people have these very real
experiences and whether it's arousal or
something that it's,
that you're,
you're entering people's minds through
different ways. So you talk about, uh,
that virtual reality when we are
entering a world where the pixelation of
virtual reality will be equal to life.
And so you're going to be in this
VR space and it just, it will look,
it may smell,
it could even with haptic suits,
it may feel just like life and our brains,
I don't know if you've done these things
with the, these um, uh, these, uh,
VR glasses where you go
and you can see people,
you're just like in a,
in a hall and the put on the glasses and
now you're in an elevator going to the,
the top on the outside, like a window
cleaners elevator to the top of this,
um, highrise and there's
a little rickety board.
And then there's this cat at the end
of the board and they're saying, yeah,
you have to go, go save the cat.
And you've already seen that.
You're just in a hall. You know it
in your brain. Um, there's this cat.
Everybody's looking at you and you've
seen all these other people panic.
And when I'm there I'm going to be,
so I'm just going to go grab that cat.
And you're terrified.
Like you're trying to override your
lizard brain and your lizard brain saying
like, no, don't step on this. Love
that for HTC vive. Yeah, yeah, we have,
we need to set that up Jim. And we need
a two by four we put on the ground floor.
It's incredible.
And so I think that this whole concept
of reality is like that our technology is
going to be changing our sense of reality.
And then what's real like if you feel
arousal in your brain because of an
electric currents or you feel it because
you're with your girlfriend or wife or
reading a magazine or whatever.
Is that different?
Is One real and one not real?
And I think that this,
there's real big issues here. I mean
that is the Matrix, right? Yeah.
I mean the idea that,
and if it feels better and it's
more enjoyable than real life,
what is going to stop people from doing
the Ray Kurzweil deal and downloading
yourself into this, this
dimension? Well, and not much.
Whether it's possible to do a
full download or not. Right?
I think that's an open question,
but whether people are going to be more
comfortable living in these alternative
worlds and whether we're booked,
we're going to be able to say, oh no,
that is the fake world. Like if
you're in this virtual world, right,
but your do you have friends in that
world, you're interacting in that world.
You have experiences that feel every bit
as real in that world as in our world
and people say, oh no, that's not
real. Those, those aren't your friends.
Like even now, like you know,
we all people with global lives,
you kind of have these friends,
like I have a good friend in Mongolia,
we talk all the time. Do you ever
see them in person once in a while,
like once every year or two? It's great
to see him. That's a real person though.
Real.
That's someone you actually know.
It was a control plane that
you actually do know him.
But if it was someone that you only talk
to online and they lived in Mongolia,
that's where things get weird.
It's true.
But let's just say hypothetically that
hypothetical, you have that person,
they're part of your whole
life and you're there with you.
They're with you through
your life experiences. You
call them up when you're sad.
Like is it so essential that
you've met that person physically?
Like is that the core of what it means
to be someone's friend that you is not
essential, but it means a
lot. It does. And I, and so I,
I mean because we are not like we are
these physical beings and we are these
virtual beings, but figuring out what's
the balance is going to be really tricky.
Yeah.
What is the balance like what I'm
worried about augmented reality too.
Cause I,
you know,
when you see people that you snapchat
filters and give themselves dog ears and
stuff like that,
like yeah.
Well how long before that is just
something that people choose to turn on or
turn off about life itself.
Yeah.
Like you'll be able to see the
world through different lenses.
The Sky could be a different color than
plants. Could be a different color.
May write about this in one of
my novels, Eternal Sonata, um,
where I think we're just going to
have these contact lenses and I'm,
and it'll be different kinds
of information based on
what people want. I mean,
like I'll meet with you and it'll
say, all right, this is Joe,
here's a little bit of background,
whatever,
and we'll have useful information.
Or you're walking around
a city and he'll be,
get little alerts of things that
you might do or, or history.
And so I think that that's what they
were thinking about with Google glasses,
right? Yeah, I know,
but he just was so annoying that people
wanted to kill people too weird. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. It was
just too, everybody felt like
they were getting filmed too.
They were, yeah. I mean, when you're
walking around with Google glasses on,
you assume that people
recording everything. It
was very strange. They were.
But I think that's another
thing that we're just,
all of our lives are going to be
recorded. Of course. Yeah. Now,
do you think that that's going to come
in the form of a contact lens or do you
think it's going to come in the form of
like ski goggles you're going to put on
and see the world through the
ones to look like an idiot.
And so in the beginning, in
the beginning, all these,
you talked about Michael Douglas with
these or like my favorite one is um,
is Kurt Russell in escape from New
York? What do you have there? It's like,
it's like this really cool tech.
Like he finally gets out of this Manhattan
Hell and he's got this phone and it's
like this big and it's pre cell
phone is free. It's like very,
very early days.
And so you know,
now we have these kind of glasses and
there's like a little bit of a little bit
of cachet but all I'm has a cell phone
that's that big. It'd be seen that no,
I was at the Verizon store. Yeah, I
think it was like an attachment. Earnest.
An accessory to a phone. Yeah. You can
bring it with you intervention, find,
not bring your other phone.
That's the idea behind it. Yeah,
so like you could decide,
well, I'm going out,
let me just bring my tiny phone
for essentials, all this tiny,
I mean the phones are
going to get quote unquote,
phones are just going to get so smart.
So I say they're going
to come inside of it.
So you'll have like a little contact lens,
maybe a little thing in your ear,
maybe like a little
permanent implant in your,
you'd behind your tooth or one of your
teeth to replace a tooth with a computer,
you know,
pipe it right into your nerves.
Any kind of crazy stuff you can think
of that it's probably going to happen.
And some of it, some people take, some
of them won't, right? Yeah, right. Yeah.
It seems like that's what we're going to
have to see. Like how it plays out. Yeah.
That's one of the things when you were
talking about scientists that are working
on these things, they're working
on what's right in front of them.
They're not looking at the
greater landscape itself
in terms of what the future
holds. It's not their job. And
that's why we need other people.
And I certainly see myself or
those people. You and who else,
who would you elect Trump came to you
and said, Jamie, we've got problems.
We need to figure out the future.
What should we do? So we'll certainly,
and we need to have a mix of
different kinds of people. And so I,
I'm certainly people like me who are kind
of big picture futurists. We need that.
We need scientists.
I work with some really incredible sign.
I did an event at Harvard last week with
George Church who is kind of like the
Living Charles Darwin Davidson Claire,
who you know,
has been on this program is a friend of
mine working on, on life extension. Um,
and we need people just
from all backgrounds.
And so like I would say like, we
need people, we need poor people,
we need people from developing world.
We need all kinds of people.
But in terms of the people who are kind
of articulating the big picture of the
world and what are the
challenges that we're facing,
I certainly put myself in that category.
People like Yuval Noah Harari,
who were just kinda big,
also kind of big thinkers,
people like Sid Mukherjee Am.
I just think we have to articulate the
big picture and we have to do it in a way
so that people can see themselves
in this story and then,
and then enter into the conversation.