I read the Elon Musk is sleeping
on the floor of the Tesla factory.
These,
they said he,
he's sleeping on the floor of the Tesla
factory while they're trying to get
production ready. Ooh. And the
Tesla's finally going to look at this.
Eli Musk is stressed. Oh, son of a bitch.
Elon Musk is stressed,
says he's sleeping on the Tesla factory
floor and has no time to go home and
shower. Wow. That guy's
an animal. He really is.
Has there ever been a guy who does
more shit? Benjamin Franklin? Nah,
but asshole with a kite and the key,
fuck that guy wouldn't teeth.
Now what he's done think of is he's in
the middle of making this boring company
that bores holes under
the ground and make,
get all of the high speed
train speed train. Yeah.
He's in the middle of the hyperloop.
He's in the Middle Space X.
He's in the middle of Tesla production.
They've got approved for the satellites
to go in the space for the Internet.
You hear about that? Yeah. We'll
hear about that. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
At least can it provide
worldwide Internet, right? That's
the idea. Yeah, Dude. Yeah.
It says,
how does one,
how's one guy able to do
so much that I don't know.
The crazy thing I was
saying the other day,
he's so smart that people just let them
drill under the ground in La. Like, yeah,
go ahead. Go ahead man. Nobody else.
Like who the fuck would let anybody just
drill into the ground? Who Do you who,
where do you, what office do you walk
into with that presentation? You know,
it's like people,
it's like a six month thing to build
a fence in La and he's like nice.
Go down a bunch like way
far and then make trains.
Like they would never listen to him
if he was like a regular person. No.
Or even regular genius.
Like you almost have to be like Elon Musk.
He's like are, it's like a guy and it's
a brand new tips. He's like our guy,
you know,
Elon Musk plan for high speed car tunnel,
gets initial approvals from La.
I would like to see the
documentary about the presentation.
I'd like to see what happens
when an earthquake kits
and not think fills up with
water rushing towards you and
you're on that scooter, God damn.
2.7 mile proof of concept
tunnel along to pull with the
damn zero emissions,
high speed underground alternative means
of transit for personal vehicles and or
single rider use according to urbanize
which reported on the approval man.
I mean, what, what, what motivates a guy
like that to do so many different things?
That's what's so confusing.
It's, it's not, it's um,
it really is that real curious.
He's an engineer at heart and it's that
I think it's the curiosity and, uh, of,
of the challenge and
accomplishing something that
hasn't been done before and I
want to make it possible. You'd be
like, that has to be the real drive.
It can't be the money and
the, the, the stardom of it.
I feel like he really gets off on how can
I find a solution to this thing? Yeah.
Well they're all
technologically based things.
Everything he's doing is like
Tesla, the Tesla, those home units,
the tiles, the solar tiles that
he's putting on people's roofs.
And also it all ties into like
better for humanity. Yeah. Yeah.
It's amazing. Yeah. He's
an, he's an incredibly lucky
that we got a guy like that.
I mean he's, he's essentially like our
version of a Tesla. Yeah. You know,
and Nikola Tesla, you know, like a
guy who just keeps coming up with new,
crazier shit to just,
it's amazing.
There's only one of those guys though.
That's what's crazy. Of course.
The other ones, like you
would think there'd be a bunch
of those kind of guys. No,
he's standing down. Yeah.
Yeah. What if he wasn't born?
You know what I mean?
Like when you have a guy who
has that much of an outlier,
it's just so, it's so strange
because you're forcing it to be like,
how has it kind of canopy and at
a nation of 320 million people,
that one individual be such an outlier.
Yeah.
But even I would even outside of that,
there's not even someone like
really like him somewhere else.
So it really like no billion, 7
billion people. Yeah. Yeah. Who is,
who is the one person that you think
of when it comes to technological
innovation and,
and producing the crazy new inventions.
And we used to seem to the public of jobs
like that, right? I mean, it was, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Sorta,
sorry that he didn't do it the way that
this guy doesn't know he was just within
my company is new shit.
You're going to want, yeah.