I take it. You like those kinds of pants?
Yeah, I love that. It's not his pants.
This boot cuts or give
me some predictions.
I'm a Ryan Bader Tko second
round grandpa first round.
And Jesus said he can show respect bro.
Knock him out in the first room
crying babies. Oh really? Wow.
And he's been on one tonight
though. Yeah, that'd be right.
I hate to ruin it for you.
So calm.
I think if Ryan doesn't respect
for it fade or he can get cracked.
Well here's the thing about bait or too,
as much as he loved [inaudible] I'm high,
I'm so hot.
Remember when he and his big fights like
you lost the rumble Johnson, John Jones,
like a lot of the big moments,
he is caught up sometimes Johnson shot
a bad shot and fucking he balanced his
head to the moon.
So this is the finals of their
heavyweight tournament tournament.
That would make Brian Bader be the
heavyweight champ champ champ champ champ
champ. He owns the light
heavyweight one right now. Yeah.
What's up John Jones trying and
run it back, Bro, those years ago.
Are you bringing up old shit? Is that
he says, well, you bring up old shit.
It's run it back. Is that what he
said? Nope. That's what I'm saying.
Terrible site visitors like that to lift
champ shit, right? Yeah. More. Hey Bro,
that song or started it now. Fucking
everyone wants to do it. Well,
there's a few guys, it gets a little
dark. I like that. I love it. Yeah, it,
it ties up the division so it gets
a little messy, but I'd love to see,
could be,
but 70 and Woodley's go 85 is the belt
and 45 are 35 pound belt and I was going
to go out there. Here's the thing, I
really believe this. I think if some,
this is an egregious error and there's
a fight that stopped prematurely.
I think you should almost put it
up to the vote of the Internet.
I really do take you at your goddamn mind.
Bueller vote. Yes. Popular vote.
Didn't you say most people like 70%
of the pump duration of dummies? No,
68 it's about why the fuck would
we ever want to popular vote Amy.
Okay, but let's, how
about we have and say,
how about we have an organization
of esteemed ladies and gentlemen,
an organization of maybe 200
accepted martial artists,
worldclass martial artists,
people that,
a committee of a hundred people, young
guys, what the fuck they're doing?
You're going to get the decision,
right? That's a great idea.
If you have it so much better
than the Internet. Trolls, voting,
John Hackleman fins and John,
Donna,
hers and for Rasa hobbies
and Duke Roof Rack Jackson,
Mike Winkeljohn or whichever Whitman's
and you've got a committee of the whole
eastern friends, friends,
Brian Killen and leave. You do have
something like that, Dwayne lushy fair.
If you have those, Tom Scurrah, Burt,
if you had all those people in like
a database and they all put in their
opinion, you would be 100%
probably in agreement,
especially if the experts, yeah.
All right, here we go. Fade
or looking, stoic. Nervous.
I'm kind of nervous. Or Ryan.
Well, it's scary, man. He's fighting to
fade or bro and he comes out. They get,
you know, as he's older, he definitely
doesn't give a fuck anymore.
He just wants to take your head off. He's
the second round hammer. My watch bro.
He's looking for that hammer.
Could that right hand feed or it's just
get that left hand loose and that right
hand balled the few fucking laughing pico
is ever going to lose again. So I've,
I don't know what's going to happen.
Hey man, anything could happen.
It's still one of the greatest
heavyweights of all time.
And Ryan Bader is a better fighter than
he's ever been and and really slick man.
He's smart. He's smart
and his approach. Oh.
Oh,
what's up bro?
Beautiful Shot.
I told you to holy shit is left Eddie,
but call it dude. He's got a sneaky
left. Took a turn. Done this,
this fucking tournament.
Oh, Chemo beat mitre.
Own Fuck. Did I just starch fucking
fade or two? No one starts his fate or
luck and it was a weird left.
Took like, it was almost like a,
like it started out as a jab and
then I'll turn it over at the,
at Arizona state left hook, like how
rose knocked out. You are a racks.
So yes, I want to see that. Holy Shit.
Call it the top shelf gods were grabbing.
Keeps the cookies.
Trying to tell you guys,
you guys list top shelf a damn.
Look at this. Watch this.
Watch this left hand.
It's almost like a jab he draws,
which she was going to it almost
like fake the single. Oh Yeah,
look at that again.
Being so crazy good for him.
That's a good stop. Stop.
There's two shots. Gosh,
that was almost like that Dan
Henderson Bisbing shot that extra shot.
Do you think that's add? That's
evident. Watch this again.
Is that evidence of fader just can't take
a shot or is it a perfect punch or is
it both? Hey, there has heavy fuck.
I think it's both. I think it's,
he's also forward a little bit of that.
It's a little bit of both, but damn,
it's a perfect punch.
He,
he dropped his shoulder down like you
almost like he's going to jab to the body,
right? Yeah. Yeah. It looked like
almost a shot. Jeff Damn Dude five.
I was about to get paid. So what
happens now? He's a free agent.
They've got to pay the cow. Look at the
heavyweight Kaos light heavyweight champ.
Hail. Shout out to be a left,
right? Shout out to Ryan Bader,
man. It's party. You sad to watch
fate or get cracked like that. Oh,
interesting. Well just cause I'm
up to date as my buddy. Listen,
you did call it dude, and he's texting
everybody. Twins. He's texting.
Everybody told you pitch
told you motherfuckers nice.
At a certain point you just can't take
shots. You get hit. That wasn't a,
that was a nice shop,
but it didn't appear to me.
You know that it was
the heaviest shot ever.
I hate to say I told you so to anybody,
but to young fighters,
this kind of shit is what I'm
always trying to point out.
Don't get caught up in the moment.
Don't get caught up in wars because
every one of those will, eventually,
there's gonna come a time when that
credit card bills going to come and you've
got all these charges and it just,
you don't have the money.
You can have to pay it.