Late two minutes.
I'm going to shit on Bobby Lee real quick,
even though we've only about
Bobby. I love him, but,
and it's not even shitting on him.
I admired him probably when we were on,
when we were on mad TV together.
Eric Price and I were both on there.
We've got hired the last season
and then they canceled it,
make of that what you will. But uh, uh,
when we worked with Bobby when he didn't
have his dick and balls out eating a
salad, he would watch playback and
we'll just watch himself and be like,
to the point where Keegan Michael Key,
me and Eric would just point,
pointed them and go like,
see me, I'm me. It's me.
He would literally laugh at his own shit.
And I admired that about him.
I'm just like, I could never,
it's a mental delusion.
He's got something wrong with his brain.
He, uh, he needs to put it on a special,
I've been telling him forever,
dude,
you are one of the best stand up comedians
alive and you don't have a special.
And he, he still goes to clubs and
he's like, can I just do 20 minutes?
No one is like, fuck no. What,
we're paying you to an hour. Yeah.
He asked if he could do 20 minutes
over an hour, but he's always,
he's just so down on himself.
He's like, I don't think I got it.
Can I just do like 20 can you let this
guy do 45 really says that when he goes
to a club and last were there
to see last I checked. Yeah.
Cause he's just so down on himself and
get up and just crush you. So funny.
I talked to him about it. I was like, why
aren't you doing so you, I'm going to,
I'm going to, I'm like,
you're not going to know.
You've been telling me
you're going to for years.
I've known Bobby Lee for 20 plus years.
He's never put out a comedy special.
That's insane.
Bobby Lee almost got me killed at a strip
club in San Diego are first time I met
him. I already believe it be continued.
We were in our twenties and uh,
and uh,
uh,
I met Bobby Lee down there at the La
Jolla comedy store and then we went out
after the show,
this is probably like 90 [inaudible],
late 90 [inaudible] somewhere.
And we went out afterwards,
went out to the Strip club and there was
this Mexican gentleman with a tattoo on
his face and the nineties,
which is rare. And he had long,
straight black hair. Wow. And he had a
look in his eyes like, he's killed people.
I'm a good, I'm a, I'm a good at
sniffing out danger. I'm like,
that's real danger.
And Bobby was hitting on,
his girl was trying to get a
lap dance from his girlfriend.
Got mean in Bobby's defense.
It's at a strip club.
But this girl was apparently his
girlfriend at a strip club and bar.
And the guy stood up,
you know,
and he stood up and he said something to
Bobby and Bobby comes over, he's like,
fuck that guy. And I looked at
the guy and looked at Bobby,
I'm getting out of here right
now. And he's like, either I go,
either come with me or you're going
to walk home. I'm like, fuck you.
I'm not getting killed for,
you know,
we all ran out into the car and I had a
Toyota super at the time and I got in my
car and Bobby was like, that guy
ain't gonna do shit. I'm like,
cat in the fucking car. I'm like,
dude, you don't understand danger.
You're going to get everyone killed.
It's guys like you,
Bobby Lee's one of those guys that has
no spidey sense. None. None. Zero. Ah.
You know I have very strong where
it's tingling, where I'm like, oh,
I'm about to get jumped. I needed to
abandon my pride and run down the street.
Right. A was a real one. I was like,
oh, this guy's like a gang banger.
Like this castle. He had tattooed tears.
He was legitimately scary looking. Yeah.
Even if he was bluffing, I'm wanting,
what does that, this is a video,
like what would happen? This
big guy right here, he just,
he gets pissed off and he basically
knocked everyone out here in the bar and
like nothing. Nobody can do
anything about it. Oh God.
He just starts to fire just
one guy. One guy's like, hey,
you need to stop this
guy, Alex, that guy out.
He starts beating up a guy over here who's
beating people up for no reason. Yeah.
Someone must be pissed him off. He was
dancing at the beginning of the video. Oh.
And he's like, he's not
doing anything. This fight.
He's telegraphing every punch.
I'm not even a fighter,
but he's letting him punch him. He just,
well, they're all drunk as shit too. Oh,
they're bumping into him. Oh Man. Oh,
he's a nudge you in the
morning or something like that.
He's a Dick. Yeah, that's,
but that's what could have
happened in that situation.
You have to send this to me because
that looks like my friend Vince Averil,
who's a comedian from the Midwest.
He's got that same kind of balding,
same size. He's like punching little kids.
Yeah. It's a giant punching little kids.
Yeah. One of my favorite videos
of a bar is a girl and a guy.
The guy got in this girl's
face and she grabs his,
his collar and headbutts him unconscious.
She grabs and goes wow.
Drops. It's fucking hilarious.
Like that bitch must've grown
up in a hard family this too.
Cause this guy's way bigger than her and
it was a dangerous thing to try and she
just grabs his collar and fuck. It's
slams her forehead right into his nose.
I think you can, you can get
away with that if you're a lady.
You know what I mean? Cause it's, cause
it's guy, well not that it just skews,
but like you're giving bad advice.
I'm not saying do it.
I'm saying this is it. Yeah.
Watch this. The guy like put,
they get closer to us.
Look at this. Boom, Kod.
Go to sleep, bitch. Holy Shit.
I looked at her just strolling away that
Carl's done that before and that guy's
like, Sheila, you killed again.
Yeah, whatever gets you help,
whatever. Who's going to rest may you
don't. You don't tell him he's moving.
He's like, we didn't give you a
bionic limbs to let you do this.
There's just got to play
[inaudible] when she was six.
Yeah. Your hands on your
chest. That guy had to be like,
what are you going to really,
he didn't see it coming touched.
You never let people touch?
No.
Even if it's a girl girl grabbing
like very careful. That's a red flag.
If someone does that you you feel tension?
Yes.
Feel like they're about to do something.
Yeah.
If you're a dumb dude and you think you're
invulnerable and then wake up with a
shattered nose, get headbutted
into oblivion. That was insane.
The real scary thing is falling out.
Did the,
the the thing about getting hit is that
you fall in, your head, bounces off.
That's the most dangerous thing. Yeah.
I mean I'm so tall I would probably,
I would have permanent brain damage.
Right. All the falling. Yeah.
Cause you kind of just, you're
just a sack. A sack of Jelly.
Maybe that's why Bobby so cocky because
he's not falling very far. That's it.
He's just woken up on the ground
rules like and roles. He's like,
I was talking to that guy and I must
have bumped my head on something because
I'm, I woke up in the alleyway,
but I'm fine. I'm fine. Yeah. Yeah.
Have you ever done his podcast? No. I
gotta reach out. He's a good dude. I love,
I love hanging out with, he really
does do a comedy special this year.
I really do. Cause he's so funny.
He's a no brainer for Netflix.
No brainer. Right. Diversity. How
should he go? Yeah. And he's a nut.
He has great stories. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
He told me a story once about, uh,
he's, he's at mad TV. They had
a table read and uh, he, uh,
hadn't slept in a couple of days.
He'd just gotten back from Mexico.
He had a giant Bowie knife,
like tucked into a shirt and it was fucked
up on pills and he was just sweating.
He been up for days and
he's at the table read.
And that was before he
decided to clean his act up.
I was lucky enough to come across
like, well after those days, uh,
and we, they wrote, they wrote
a script to fuck with him.
They gave him the wrong script.
We'd like extra lines with a monologue
that took up like the whole page so that
he would have to remember it. We
know no, he'd shut her, read it.
And everyone's like,
like cheap.
They tell everybody like don't worry about
that part where he thinks he's a bird.
And so Bobby's like, I'm
a burden. I'm supposed to.
And like the writer was coaching. I'm
just like, do the wackiest bird boy.
And he's like,
God,
God supposed to fly car and I'm a
birder and he looks up and we're crying,
laughing and he see someone screaming,
fuck you got any through
the script across the room.
And I remember just taking
pictures of yeah, just to,
they just did it like on his birthday
or something to mess was like the best
prank. Wasn't mad TV like
the longest running sketch
show ever outside of center.
It was. Yeah. That's crazy. Nobody
watched it. It 10 people watch that show.
It costs too much. I think what it was,
yeah, because they do a lot of like um,
song parodies and things like
that and, and uh, it, it just,
I mean I wish it would've kept going.
It was one,
of course you were working on it,
but it was one of those things where it
was like, you'd see here it was still on.
You're like, Whoa, that
show's still on. Oh yeah.
Cause I was on it with
Brian Callen in 1994.
Brian Callen and already Lange like 94,
95 95 that's crazy.
That's a long fucking time
ago yet. And then all those
years later, I'm like, what?
It's still on dude. When I got the call
to audition was still on the television.
This was 2008 that is or
shocking. Crazy. Yeah.
2009 it ended 1995 to 2009 that's insane.
We shot the last,
they cancelled it,
I want to say January of 2009 and it was,
they can't do it on my,
they told everyone my day on my day
off. Oh. So it was original network.
He was on Fox. And why does it say the
CW two they tried to bring it back.
Tried to bring it back.
Yeah,
like what Adam Ray was on it and
a couple of people, I don't know,
but what is the CW, is that
a real, oh look, there I am.
Set up like a drug dealers, money
laundering operation. The CW network.
What is that?