Well,
one of the things that was so interesting
about Australia is that in certain
ways it's a more,
you know,
it's thought of as sort of a macho
culture may be more masculine,
a little bit more conservative than here
generally, and yet the left has one,
they're on so many of the major
issues that we're fighting,
we're killing each other over now.
Universal healthcare,
mandatory 401k ninth.
It's like $18 minimum wage pensions,
four weeks of vacation a year. Like I
think they get maternity leave as well.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's just like so many of the things
that here are up for grabs they already
solved.
We have to take two things
into consideration. One, um,
that they have a small population,
small in homogenous in its enormous place.
You're dealing with a place as large
as contiguous United States of America,
but there's only 20 million people
because the Whitney, they were like,
it's crowded in that restaurant.
And it was like, you mean I don't
have to wait for an hour to get in?
They had no con they've
never seen a crowd of people.
Yeah.
They don't know what a real crowd is.
And also I think their culture is less
constrained by history because they came,
they were essentially prisoners.
I mean they,
it's like several generations
removed. Yeah. But it's not,
not only that they not indigenous. No, I
mean like the nonindigenous populations.
Prisoners, yes. Um, yeah.
Well they came from,
they were sent there because England
didn't want him and that's literally how
the country got founded for like stealing
a watch. Like they were low level. Okay,
well then they sent them to the much
better place. Oh yeah. Way Better.
It's an a gold coast. You're like, Holy
Shit. It just takes forever to get,
if you're a Manchester, it's raining every
day and like fuck this place and you,
you, you know, you stole a watch and
they shipped you off to the Gold Coast.
You'd be like, what? Which has
happened. This is hilarious.
You fish out here. It's fucking
beautiful. They're nice people.
And I wonder if there,
so nice.
I feel like they are slightly less nice
than Canadians who are way more nice
than us.
I think that's right.
I also think that they have,
they have it so good that they're a
little complacent and that makes me
concerned because
China. Okay. Right. That's
like the big story there. Yes.
Yes. I see what you're saying. Yeah.
Well you know, that is to be considered,
but I think the United States,
first of all,
we have this momentum of
innovation and of ass kicking and,
and,
and getting things done in creating
things that's so different than any other
part of the world. If we took that shit
down a notch, I think we'd be okay.
You know, I mean I think we definitely
do have to worry about China and we,
you know,
I've been really trying to closely
follow all this wowway stuff where these
executives keep getting
arrested and you know,
it's the close relationship between
some tech companies and this communist
government is very confusing.
But some people look it over.
Like if you talk to people that are
Chinese natives or who have been to China,
they almost look it as a positive.
There's less resistance. It's more,
even though the censorship is open,
it's at least you know what you're
dealing with over there as opposed to,
you know,
the NSA is spying on us.
Oh,
I don't buy it at all.
I've seen some people make that argument
and it's horrifying. Weird. It's weird.
It's horrifying.
Yeah.
Great. I agree with you. You
do have to worry about China,
but I think Australia is like, ah, it's
fucking Americans to take care of it.
That's how they think sorta,
except like their situation is
that they're enormously economic.
They're enormously dependent on China
economically and they love having that
money.
Uh,
but they seem to be a little bit like
sleep walking through history and not is
at least some people that I spoke to it.
But that's,
that's the real story
in Australia is China.
Yeah. Well I think when you're,
you're not a military might, you know,
you're not like one of the big players.
You're kind of like sitting back watching
because what are we going to do? Like,
what if Australia decides to ramp up its
defense budget by 5000% over the next
10 years and develop a crazy arsenal
of weapons and super soldiers and shoot
them all up with steroids and give them
exoskeletons and get ready to go to war,
start building bunkers, right, and
freak the rest of the world out.
I mean this and take this like North
Korea with money approach to the world.
If any man in North Korea with money.
Well,
North Korea is basically like this
scary spot that nobody wants to invade,
even though we know that
there's a military dictatorship
there. They have, yeah,
they have nuclear weapons.
They have a mad man who's in control.
They have people that escaped
with horrific stories and
we have a president who
talks about them as if they're sort
of a normal country. Yeah. Well,
in the weird thing is like he might be
able to sit down with them and actually
talked to them as his unconventional
approach might actually lead to some sort
of communication at least. Which is
better than nothing, I guess. But,
but if,
I don't mean like in North Korea,
like they take over the country
and in prison it's people,
I mean like there they become kind
of dangerous and sketchy and small.
Like North Korea is not
a military Dick Power.
Like in terms of like the way the Soviet
Union is where they could take over the
world, but they're scary but they're
untouchable and that's scary. Exactly.
If Australia became that then I think we
have a totally different attitude about
Australia. No, Australia.
Yeah, we don't, yeah,
Australia is just laid
back and they're like,
Hey Americans a take care of it and then
we're over here building fucking walls
and shooting missiles. Um, yeah. I,
I would imagine it would be really
weird to watch us from afar. You know,
if you were paying
attention to world politics,
they know everything. I mean
everyone I talked to there was like,
let's talk about gerrymandering in
Virginia. And I'm like, what? Like what,
what do you say that simply
follow what's going on here?
And the way that I found kind of amazing,
like genuinely actually
Gerrymandering, good Virginia. I was,
I would move over there. Don't you
often knew it was going on for a year.
You know the answer is sort of note.
Yeah. Comedians move over there.
They move over there and
become huge in Australia.
Shout out to my friend ards barker.