Will happen,
the Joe Rogan experience and then I get
on that elliptical machine and now I'm
doing the elliptical, you know,
for the universe like Flash Gordon,
he letting motherfuckers
know I'm saving the planet.
Ever watched the old Flash
Gordon from the 1950s nope.
That was the first one I saw was the
cheap chitty one in the eighties uh,
I was on a plane,
not really recently.
It's like I guess more
like a couple of years ago.
And they had a one of those video catalogs
so you could just watch stuff. Yeah,
I think it was an international flight.
Yeah.
And it had a old TV shows and it had
flash Gordon and I watched a bunch of
episodes of flashcards.
Wild. It was weird.
It's weird to watch.
Yeah.
It's weird to watch what people thought
like space was going to be like in
aliens. It's so strange. Yeah.
I mean I think Flash Gordon was
probably from the fifties right?
Those are comic book Lizard. Yes. Yeah.
It was originally a comic book CV get
pull up video of they need to remake that
fan photos of the green room.
And the punchline.
I was looking for that Hicks line.
Oh we've showed that before.
I wish they would remake Flash
Gordon and make it accommodate that.
Keep the soundtrack cause it's quaint.
Oh human rights. These huge queens.
Huge right now. Keep the exact same
soundtrack. Make Flash Gordon a comedy.
Jack Black. Get a, what are
you thinking of a Flash Gordon,
the movie now the movie that's,
that's totally move way, way, way.
There's the original
flash board with meaning.
The merciless may the most of them.
Cause I to Sun Bowl. I'd look at him.
How Wa how weird does he look? Look at
Flash. Like that's what they thought.
People are going to be wearing weird
neck collars in the future belt buckles.
Like it's such a strange look man.
It just a lightening bolt on your chest.
Pull up, look at the yellow bit so we
could watch a video because it's so,
it's so weird to watch cause it
looks like, what years did it say?
50 64 to 55 wow.
Ming the merciless.
So this is where he like,
it's so shitty.
Like the special effects were. So this is
not even the movie. This is the, I know,
but I mean I'm saying the claim jumpers,
Steve Holland does Flash Gordon, Irene,
chaplain Dale Harden. Look, she's
hot. She's hot in a real way. Yeah.
There was no faking it back
then. Doctors are, yeah,
same care. I've not seen this
though. So this was a whole TV show.
How many episodes do you think they made?
If I had to guess.
I bet they made 50 or something like that.
I look at that. She's Ah, that shirt.
She is hot tea. That side. Look at
that. It looks like a drill. Yeah. No,
she's holding a drill.
Women back then all have flat butts.
Unless they did gymnastics.
That's right.
Unless there's some freak of nature
accident and that is some sort of weird
deal.
Does stupid.
That's what Jack Hammer that you
know what the handheld Jackhammer.
It looks like that Tim
dam that there are gun.
That's what it looks like right
there. What does that, this thing,
this is a thing I do.
It's for massage. Oh Shit.
[inaudible]
May I? Yes. Hang on.
Probably shouldn't do it right in front
of on a microphone like I did. Yeah.
It's great. It doesn't hurt.
Yeah. It's real good for
loosening up muscles on, Bro.
That's what they had. Good to the, yeah.
Again, that's their weapon, but to me,
I'm gonna Punch you in the face real fast.
It's always weird seeing what,
what people thought the future was going
to be like once the future he hits.
Okay.