The Guy was trying to do that,
but with like some Winkeljohn
strategy coach these young,
he's only like 26 right?
He's going to be a prom dress.
Super Crystal.
I am interim belt stun,
Holby POC talking about Colby just had
to get a nose operation for sinuses,
but this the thing Colby goes and I
spoke to someone very close to Colby.
Colby goes, dude, I'm down for the
fight. I just went five rounds.
Willie's been out for how long? Give
me, I can do it in October, November.
Just let me get ready.
I just said I'm going to have sinus
surgery is fair and they went, nope.
Stripped me of the belt until you
want it until it's like, fuck yeah,
I'll take it.
See that.
That seems to be a problem for anybody
that's considering taking interim title
fight in the future.
That's what Paul Ryan Ortega Ortega
saw that and he was like, listen,
they're offering him before that when
his flight got canceled because Max
Holloway was running to
all those medical issues,
they offered him a fight
for the interim belt.
And I think it was against Jeremy
Stevens is fighting this weekend.
They offered Frank Yeager, Andrew
Stevens, and so he, Frankie Edwin's crazy.
That doesn't even make any sense.
That's what Brian said. Yeah.
And so then Jeremy and Jeremy
Stevens is fucking dangerous.
He is sleeping dangerous for anybody.
He's doing such a good fighter for
antibody. He and he is guns blazing.
He's fighting all of this weekend.
So on. I know that's a great fight.
So at 55 right? All those 40 45
so they offered him all those,
those offered him or take up or take
a fight with Jeremy because Jeremy is
already cut and wait for this fight or
you know it training for this fight,
which is only a few weeks later. And
he says, well, it's an interim title.
It doesn't mean anything. I want the real
belt fighters. Don't take it serious.
Well, here's why they shouldn't now.
Right. Well, this is the base example.
Like why would I fight for interim belt?
You just strip Kolbe.
Now this is us assuming that
we know the whole store. Right?
I don't know the whole story. I haven't
talked to Colby. I haven't talked to Dana,
but I don't,
I think the conversation,
I'm not a fan of the idea of an interim
title unless there's extenuating
circumstances.
Like someone's got a broken leg,
they have to be out for six months,
but it should be a year out a year.
You got to do something so you
wouldn't lose out a year. Correct.
So that's why it made RDA. It made sense.
And also just to play, if I'm Dana,
hey Woodley,
we need you to fight and you want
the super fights turning down fights.
What can we do? Let's force the
Sand Creek. This interim belt,
he's been out a year, which I
like. I wasn't talking about that.
I was talking about sign
Ortega. Okay, Gotcha.
Let's talk about Brian or Tayga because
Max Holloway's defended fairly recently
and he was getting ready to fight Khabib.
It's not like he's been out of law.
They offered him that Khabib fight.
He tried to cut weight for it and he
might have fucked himself that way.
Is that what it was? Yeah,
it's entirely possible.
They're still trying to
figure out what happened.
Well one of the pieces of speculation
is that his body started shutting down
because he went through
a real bad cut for the,
when he was trying to make the cubby
fight at 55 on super short notes.
That's a hard thing for him to
make. 55 is a huge, huge one.
85 what? Yes dude. Max is a big fella.
Bribe or Tayga is fucking huge to
it goes up to 85 I couldn't really,
I stood next to him. I was like,
how big are you in the is bigger,
Holly's bigger and so this is
the problem with these guys.
They need a lot of time to get
down to this weight. Right?
So how all the way trying to do that. This
is one, this is pure speculation, Holly,
we to do that is it was very hard for him.
His body broke down and then in
cutting weight for this fight,
once his body started the water load,
his body knew what was going on and
start shutting down. This is speculation,
pure Spec,
but here's my point.
You can't make me and let and let until
you know that he's going to be out for a
certain amount of time.
It seems like an interim title belt is
almost disrespectful. Like he's, he's,
the champ makes zero sense. But I think
it was a corporate decision find out,
but I feel like it was a corporate
decision where they went, okay,
we have to fight. We need to fill
this gap. We have to fight. Well,
it has to buy somebody.
Of course we get,
you're talking about something different.
Yeah, but I'm saying, I'm saying they go,
they go, we want this gotta be a
ton of fight. How about use? Okay.
How about you have this,
how about you give you the Colby retains
his interim title because there's
extenuating circumstances with him
medically. He had to get nasal surgery.
He's out until November.
Colby gets the next shot.
Whoever the fuck wins his fight.
Colby fights neck straight. See,
but you haven't talked to her boy Dana.
Maybe he's saying that maybe
every same stripped UBB. Listen,
fuck your belt,
but you will get the next shot.
Everyone's just taking your
buy it hers and they did some,
well maybe it was Uzma Uzma and wants
to fight till next and he's like,
let's do this for the real
number one contender spot.
Cause Uzman is a guy who has quietly been
beating everybody they put in front of
yes.
His last one he has and I love him.
His last fight I wasn't the most exciting.
But if you go through,
you know who my has fought, you look at
the way Colby. Did he look prior to that?
You know, you Uzman would have the
worst argument but he has the eye.
The most potential
probably like he's a not,
no one wants to fuck off
for the Damien Maia fight.
I wouldn't agree with you because both
guys beat Damien might before that was
not good. I'm saying that their
decisions right. It's not like he was,
he wasn't telling people I meant the,
before the Damien Maia fight with Colby,
Colby didn't have a lot of big names
on his resume. He had one decision.
Damien Maia. So like, what do we got here?
I beat Damien Meyer as
well in his last fight.