When you retired from the
military, was this, um,
did you envision yourself doing
something along these lines,
like teach and tactical stuff or, oh man,
I went through some rough patches, um,
as most guys do. Right?
Yeah, man, man, it was, no,
I,
I morphed into who I am only in
like the past six or seven years.
I retired,
no five,
I got hired before even retire by
a corporation to do training stuff.
And um,
I kind of fell,
I was almost falling into that
Rut of accepting mediocrity.
Plus what I didn't know is
that, uh, I had depression.
I didn't know that because he no idea,
which is common,
especially in like the SPEC ops world
guys retire because you Ben there in,
in units with guys with
the same guys for a long,
long time and you've,
there's a level of intimacy there that
can't be replicated with another human
being.
And then when you retire,
you miss that comradery,
that connection. Um,
so I had working for a
corporation, um, I was,
uh, had a really bad relationship. I was
living in the bonus room and my garage,
I'd lived there for five years because
I had a ex who was on chemistry,
you know, prescription
meds go big Pharma. Um,
and so the neuro receptors were freaking
gone. I mean, delusional and, and, uh,
it was, it was a real bad. Uh,
and then I started at Booz and,
uh,
with depression and I,
it didn't even occur to me that dude,
you got to fucking problem.
Man didn't even occur, I guess,
which is common with a lot of guys.
But I had an epiphany.
A lot of things happened at one time.
My local cops saved my life.
They said, Bro, you need to
get the fuck out of there.
Um, and a bunch of things
happened all at once.
And this was in 2013.
Um,
I didn't want to leave because I had
little kids, so I didn't want to, I was,
I was gonna stay there
and just wither away.
Um, I, and I almost
capitulated to darkness,
but I got up before I went
to sleep one night. Well,
my kid is sleeping with me and I'm
hammered. And it's like eight at night,
you know, and uh, and um, I had an
epiphany. I said, you know what, I can't,
I can't do this and I will not. I remember
saying this to myself, I will not,
I will not be defeated.
And I put my running shoes by the side
of my bed and some shorts set my alarm
clock, got up early next
morning and went for a run,
I la Forrest Gump.
And I pound the pavement for about 10 or
12 miles. And I'm not a runner, you know,
I like to run. I like to spirit.
And when I came back from the run,
worked out in my driveway
for about an hour and, uh,
my local cops came all
happening the same time. And uh,
they came and said, hey bro, get the
fuck out. The kids would be all right.
You need to do this and that. And, um,
and then I started, uh,
kind of figuring out
re, uh, reevaluating my path
in life. Oh, back up a step.
I also got laid off from this
corporation and you know,
with a guy in the military, you don't,
you don't ever think about job security.
And whenever tired,
I'm working for a corporation that was
mostly made up of a retired military guys.
So you get laid off and you're like,
what the fuck am I going to do now?
What does that even mean? Getting laid
off? I don't, what am I going to do? Um,
so all that shit happened at
the same time. It was like a,
it was like this massive spiral of
bad events and a man I was able to,
um,
I was able to rekindle my own,
my own, my own fire because I recognize,
all right bro, you still got an ember,
you still got this. All you need
to do is just nurture that amber,
turn it into a flame,
turn that into a flame and then just start
adding would add would add wood until
it becomes just a perpetual, uh, blaze.
And which led me to this thing that I
tell people now, you know, is that, uh,
you got to keep the blaze alive.
Um,
I've got that on t shirts
even because I like,
I like to kick people in the ass who are
willing to sustain their own fire once
they get that ass kicking.
If they can't,
if they can't keep their fire going,
then it's not worth,
it's not worth it for me, you know,
to, to keep kicking him in the ass. Um,
but uh,
yeah,
so ever since that point
in time and you know,
getting laid off to
depression, the booze and, uh,
I was able to read, discover
me and rebrand and, and um,
pretty much start from scratch.
I mean,
I had to start life all over again
when I was 48 years old. Wow.
You have the whole thing from scratch.
And I discovered like social media and
all this stuff because I've met a gal and,
um, I'm married to her now and
she's probably the best purse,
one of the best human beings I've ever
met, you know, all around human being.
Um, so she was able to help me with
that and said, hey, you need to do this.
You need to get this social media
platform. Or that one. And so it's,
it's, it's detonated pretty
well considering I bet on
a short amount of time.
Um, but apparently, uh, the
messages resonating. Yeah.
So
it's a genuine message.
That's why I picked up on it,
but I'd love that you figured
you shit out. I love that.
That's my favorite thing
when, when, I mean, look,
everybody's prone to mistakes and prone
to depression and people are prone to
hitting rock bottom.
Yup.
Your life can go down a series of bad
roads and you find yourself in a bad
relationship or a bad job, a bad
situation in life. And it's very,
very difficult at that moment
to have faith and confidence
that you can readjust,
reconsider, and reengage.
And that's what you did.
That's awesome. I love that.
I love those kinds of stories.
I love when people get their shit together
and I think that
that helps me help other people
for sure. You know, cause I could,
I could relate and I don't,
you know,
I don't sit down with them and pat
them on the shoulder and say, hey bro,
you know, I was there too. Or anything
like that. I don't even share with them,
but I empathize and that's
sometimes that's all it takes.
He empathize and um,
and you just give them just,
just, just that, just a little bit of
the right advice. Just a little bit,
you know,
not too much.
Well, oftentimes people just need
momentum. They need one good. Right.
You need one day.
That's what I said to that one guy.
Just come to the gym one day. Yeah. If
you want one, good day, we eat clean.
You drink lots of water and you like,
you did, you got that day, you woke up,
you put your shoes on,
you went for a run,
you worked out your driveway if
you got a good day. Yep. Yep.
That's sometimes all you need to do and
decide, this is what I do from now on.
I have good days.
Tomorrow's going to be another good day.
And then I'm going to force
myself into another good day.
And the next thing you know,
I've got some momentum, right?
You've got some momentum. You
can change everything. I've,
I've felt many times in my life I've felt
like I could slip the wrong way and I
just, I see it. I see the dark hole and I
go, fuck that and just go the other way.
Go the other way. The problem is,
and people fall into that dark hole.
They think that that defines
them, but it's, it doesn't, right?
It doesn't define you.
It's just you right now,
you could be totally different tomorrow.
You are a human being who can think
you can adjust and there's so much.
It's one of the beautiful things
about your Instagram page and many,
many other Instagram pages
is that you can take,
if you curate your feed correctly and
you don't follow a bunch of knuckleheads,
you can go to your Instagram
or to whatever social
media platform you like and
you can go and check out a
lot of cool shit. Oh Man.
You feel you feel good about it.
You get fired up and you want
to do good with your life.