The Joe Rogan experience.
No one one scared me more than
anyone that I've ever read.
I read about this thing that I'm,
Darpa was putting together a
robot called the eater robot,
e a t our robot.
It's a robot that fuels
itself on a biological matter,
so it essentially can eat bodies.
So you've got a murderous
robot that eats people.
There is fuel was kind of things
that human beings could achieve.
It's like people are sat
around Trynna yeah, come up
with them. Well, they're the,
you know,
they,
they're responsible for a lot of really
crazy innovation in terms of like
military stuff, you know, but
Boston dynamics, you know,
they're the ones that make those crazy
robots and they work with Darpa and those
are the ones that make those robots that
you can't kick over. Right. You know?
I mean,
that's what you need one of those that
eats people and you send them to the
battlefield. Kicky Anova. No,
that was the first thing we
established is you can't kick out over.
I just think that's,
that's the big fear is that future
warfare will be our robots versus their
robots.
You know,
if we're starting to bring about the
worst aspects are the worst things that a
human being can conceive of that
channel them through into reality. Yeah.
It does make you feel that
there are pockets is real.
I thought it was bad enough when
in the malaise of my younger days,
I see like a for a,
wow.
Imagine if there was a cleaning service
where the person would come around and
clean dressed scantily.
They do that. They do that.
Why have a devious shit?
You can dream up.
Someone's trying to turn a buck off it
and they've taken it to the extent of the
non kick over the robot.
Fleshy in robots. Yeah. Yeah.
What is this? James is a new one.
New video today. God, watch this.
This is so scary. This
is Boston dynamics. Yeah.
There's something very eerie
about that type of motion.
You know that the way that the movement
of a snake is deeply coded to be
unpleasant when you see it.
Let's talk about your thing that moved me.
Think that ain't good for the
truck. It's telling, wow. Oh my God,
they're pulling a truck when
he's tiny little Tutsis,
those they're that strong to get
pull a truck and a little robots.
That's a giant ass truck.
I mean,
he's also just a Husky sled might
have expensive robots and a truck.
They've spent a lot of time and endeavor
to go backwards, I guess kind of.
But to an Asia Santa close, they're
showing how strong these things are.
I don't like, I don't like their
gate, Joe. That's an unpleasant gate.
Yeah, you should be. You should be
uncomfortable with it. Yeah, that's not,
I'm not at ease with that.
It's not good.
It's not animal and there's no compassion
in it. This is, it's, it's feeling lists,
but that's what you got to worry about.
If you've ever see that episode of black
mirror or the lady gets chased down by
the drones, I have nothing that
will, they've won with a BS. No.
There's a woman who's being haunted.
She's being hunted by a robot and it's
terrifying because if it's remorseless
lack of humanity and empathy, just
like that looks just like those things.
Those are real. Charlie Brooker. He,
yeah, he intubate. That man's got good.
Imagine that. He's amazing. He's
amazing. That show. It was fantastic,
but these things,
look,
what we have to worry
about is once artificial
intelligence become sentient and
you can somehow or another attachment to
these objects that move and they run on
solar power or they have you know,
nuclear fuel cells or some crazy shit
that allows them to exist for a long
period of time.
Maybe you don't have to worry about
them contaminating environments.
If your plan of killing everybody
in the environment, aw man,
I know that there's no means of
regulation. Is there because this,
because this is the apex of
human endeavor there in Wa.
What can govern that?
What can regulate it and like you say,
there'll be a Chinese equivalent
for any of this stuff.
There's nothing that's above it guy and
is this a good idea? Should we pull back?
What did he do?
He just pulled up a thing
that said they're making
that now you can cut that one
I just showed you.
They're good.
Are a hundred different models
of it are going to be available.
Starting production this summer.
Doesn't say how much they're going. Wow.
But available for people to buy.
Well it says a hundred different
models has produced a hundred models.
That probably means it'll
produce a hundred of them.
Like a hundred different
companies are going to want them.
But I bet it's more than that. Yeah.
Depending about how much they cost.
It doesn't say how much it's gonna cost.
They're going down to that later.
But there's showed uh oh like a robot
arm come. Although it looks so creepy.
Look at that thing. Imagine we have one
of those things in the room filming.
We should get one. No, I'm taking
notes. One day we come here,
it's got red eyes and it's
like, fuck you. Fuck you.
What were the first ones to
help it be friendly chat.
Can they listen to us like
Alexa? It begins, isn't it?
There's something arachnoid and
now that it's almost like you know,
not your church and see if this tuned
into their DMT component of what we've
been talking about. It's almost as if
we've already experienced to this reality.
We've already been through the version
where those evil insectoid robots take
over. So when we see on the screen and
say, oh no, we're doing that thing,
that thing where we create those
things that bring about destruction.
And I believe it's because we've become
biased to commerce and a particular type
of progress.
But one narrative has succeeded because
we necessarily have to throw off
religion but you know,
at the dawn of the secular age,
because religion was becoming systems of
bias and systems of oppression and what
systems of a but what do I want to say?
Elevate in certain types of power.
One supporting it at least lets go
hang on a minute. This religion,
a lot of it seems like bullshit.
What we've done is we've abandoned the
sacred and I think if you abandon the
sacred meaning there is more to
life than what we can understand.
I listened to the Brian Cox
episode enough, spoke to Brian Cox,
the British physicist,
astrophysicist on my show as well.
And when he talks about like he said that,
you know,
we know that there's not some additional
component to a human being because we
can break down everything that happens
when you move an arm, you know, whatever.
And I feel like we only have limited,
we only have limited instruments.
There's certain frequencies
that we simply cannot read.
What else is going on when people are
having these transcendent psychedelic
experiences,
we're accessing elements of consciousness,
energies and frequencies that we are
not able to access while we're in this
state and everything were achieving
and everything we're building,
we're building on this platform and the
bias of this platform is towards prior
progress and materialism and I think
the result is fleshy in robots and those
evil monkey warrior.
So Jess and we might want to calm down.
I have a little talk about what it
is we're trying to design. Yeah.
I don't know if I agree with Brian on
that particular point that we think we
know everything about where
consciousness emanates.
I don't think that's necessarily true,
but I like the fact that he thinks
that way because he's such a rigid,
hard liner for science. And
Yeah, we've got works at cern.
I mean, he's a brilliant,
brilliant man.
So of course he thinks that way.
I also don't think he's ever
had a DMT experience. Yeah.