I was military for four years.
We really are.
We in commerce as it, I was the
word. I was a cop in the military.
Really.
Nobody believes I was the worst cop
ever have made one arrest in four years.
And I was because of girl
came through the gates,
he has some big titties and I
decided I needed to pull her over,
but I was the worst fucking car and I
had to get out of the military because I
used to hear this phrase all the time,
airman Rollins,
your blatant disregard for established
military policy shows a lack of military
brain and integrity. I
didn't hear that. I was like,
these muff was going to gun to
kick me out if was four years.
I was a cop station and coons on
Korea station in Bolan and you SEO,
Tom saying NSCO Nuna how you go.
They get talked to care. Herso wow.
Um,
four years military,
three years to two years in Korea,
two years at Bolling air force base.
And I got out and just randomly went
to a comedy club, became a heckler.
I was an asshole.
I just go to his comedy club every
Wednesday to fuck with the comedians were,
was it Kami connection to greenbelt?
It was like the black comedy club in DC.
This was the time of when Martin
Lawrence is on fire to def jam thing was
popping in and they had on
black comedy clubs. It would be,
it would be a pizza shop. They'll just
turn. Okay now. And it's a comedy club.
Monique had a club that she made a turn
from a restaurant to a comedy club just
because she got more business on the
weekend as a comedy club in restaurant and
it took it over and I used to go
heck with the comedians and I,
I was such a good heckler that people
used to come to the show to hear me
heckle. There'd be at the door like, Yo,
is that asshole do gon be here tonight?
And that was me and the club owner dare
me to go on stage because he wanted to
shut me up Java.
So cocky after four weeks of Hecklin I
tried to make a deal with the club on,
come on, I swear. I know,
I'm telling you. I said,
I know I've increased business by 30%
we just started working on the door.
He looked at me like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Anybody in DC to tell you this story?
And they wanted me to shut up.
They asked me to go on stage and I went
on stage and the first time I went on
I've murdered to shit and I knew that I
wasn't going to be doing anything else
with my life by doing that. I just
knew it. It was just like, fuck,
fuck all like Pat, Pat, pat. How did
it feel? It felt great to remember it.
I remember it because
she was in your mind.
I remember it because I had
talked so much shit to this point.
And the thing about it was,
but th th th the room of the energy,
the energy of the room was there because
there was a lot of people that came.
They saw me and they were like, I think
like when you gonna go with you should,
you know, they were like, you
should try. You should try.
So the first time I went on,
people were excited about it.
They didn't know what to expect and I
wrote all these jokes. I'm like, I got,
I got 30 minutes. I was like,
I was so cocky. We say have
an open mic and you know,
Mike List is like 30 people and I would
be like 10 on the list and they would
keep bumping me. And I thought they were
just trying to save me the headline.
I didn't think they were just trying
to give me the shittiest spot,
but half the club came to see
me so they will stay there.
And at first time I went on,
I had all these jokes I planned I was
going to do and when, what else date? Uh,
drew a complete blank. I don't remember
shit. And then I went, what I knew best.
I started fucking with someone in
the audience. I got a laugh. It did.
I did my material and I've,
I didn't know what the light was.
They gave me the light and
I was like, oh, I got go.
Like you're not a light means
just make that your last joke.
And I got off abruptly.
As I said,
I got to go and people started
booing. Hosts went up and
there was, I know Daniel,
he doesn't know he's new. Is this first
time he don't know what the light me,
he'll be, he was like,
he'll be back. And um,
I was there almost every Wednesday for
eight months and then I moved to new
first I moved to New York and six months.
Wow. Said I'm Outta here. Where'd you go?
First Club was on live, either
one. Brooklyn, Brooklyn.
You got them as a bad barrel. That's
why I till it stops. But Brooke,
it was interesting to me cause I didn't
go from DC to like mainstream white
colors. I was doing still
to kettle rooms and shit.
And a lot of times I couldn't get spots.
So I would go to a, I will go to the um,
poetry open mikes,
cause that she used to be so dull,
the water was shifting the
wave wave and I'd be like,
does anybody want breaks for the shit?
Right. And then I will go do Chelsea.
When I couldn't do Conoco's,
I would do that too.
I started making a name for myself
and never looked back. It was dope.
New York is a great place
to get your chops up. Great.
What year do you enter New York?
It had to be probably like 95,
probably like 95 giant already moved.
I'd gone,
I left in [inaudible] 94 to come to la.
Oh yeah. When did you get out of here?
I got here like seven years ago,
maybe eight years ago. And there was,
because my,
my sister was different because I wasn't
getting a lot of roadwork and I was
like,
well fuck,
if I'm not getting a lot of road work I
might as well try to get more film and
television stuff to move out to la
and they to move out here. I um,
started getting more personal.
Parents are.
So basically I moved to La and became
a road comic and I wasn't mad at it
because after you've done it for a while,
you just want an,
where the fuck can I can make money doing
this shit. You know what I'm saying?
If it's the road is the road, you
know what I mean? If it's Hollywood,
it's Hollywood.
But who's going to pay me some money?
And it was the road to now
like I do 40 weekends a year,
but with me having a,
a young kid now trying to focus more on
film and television and get some more
stable shit, cause I'm, I'm getting a
little, you know, it's getting burnt.