Hello Freak bitches believe
what's on salon.com. Look,
it's impossible to believe those things
in good faith because you have to lie to
make the,
you have to lie so much to yourself
and to others in order to make those
arguments that I just, it is one
long practical joke. That site,
it is just a gigantic,
it's the same time.
I'm convinced it's funded by the Koch
brothers to discredit a liberalism.
I'm convinced, absolutely
convinced. If you trace,
if you trace the sell on money
back far enough, you will discover,
you will discover the surname coke
because it is the only explanation for how
badly sal on discredits progressivism
is the only exposure just today they
published another editorial
from this fucking pedophile. Um,
you know who I wrote about and he wouldn't
even dare bring my name up because
he's too scared to get into it with
me cause he knows he lose. I probably,
you know, he published this thing
about how, you know, I'm a Peter Farb,
I don't act on it right after
I'd exposed a pedophile,
Sarah Nyberg in Gamer Gate, right.
And it went all over the world.
And it was a huge story that I broke
the, hold on, I'm going to stop coming.
I exposed this file, I expose
this pedophile, you know,
she was backed up and they double
all the social justice warriors.
Doubledown protected her. She
was, you know, on message.
Basically she had the right politics.
So they stuck a kiddy fiddler.
This is the state of the modern left
directly after that with a coincidental
timing salon publishes this thing by a
pedophile saying, oh, well my pit of hell,
but I don't act on it. Which is precisely
the defense that this person's used.
So I respond and I, you know,
and I assume, and I did a,
I did a very good piece of knowing I
urge all of your listeners to seek it out
because it really is excellent journalism.
Um, yeah, it was called something like,
this is why the left.
This is why liberals,
this is why progressive's
stick up for Peter Falls,
explains why pdf files can get
away with this stuff and why,
why progressives and liberals back
then, um, you think people back,
pedophiles who backs poor,
they're making excuses for them as
they make excuses for them as San Juan,
just today,
today they gave us space to this guy
who was a pedophile about whom there is
horrific stuff online, which hasn't
come out yet, which you know,
you should watch this space for that.
Cause I know Steven Crowder knows about
some of it instead of why, um, excuse me.
Uh, you should, you should
just go, who wrote this?
Did he get a second PA under his own name?
This is how brazen now wrote a second
piece for salon today playing the victim
saying that he came out as a pdf file and
he's been subjected to right wing hate
so that he says this is
the right [inaudible]
I'm a creator fall and I, I think so.
I'm a pedophile and I don't act on it.
And I did this like peace and everyone
like came out and said that it was really
supportive and it was really great and
they tell people to get through their own
experiences and everyone's
really sympathetic except
the right wing hate machine
meaning me, whether he didn't
dare mention me by name. Um,
who are the white right wing hate machine,
well apparent according to him. Um,
you know,
uh,
exit the right wing hate machine had
the temerity to say we think paedophilia
his role and why you sell on giving a
platform for it to this guy when there's
so much dirt on the Internet suggesting
that he is physically touched young
girls for example. Um, you
know, and I'm going to put yeah,
there is a completely different argument.
Well this is the thing, it's so long.
Gave a platform to this guy in San
Juan ought to have known about this
allegation.
If you're going to,
if you're going to make space on your
platform for a self confessed pedophile
and you will,
you will only find this on the left.
This is what I mean by the left.
Sticking up for a bit of,
I was there making excuses when
they tried to legitimize them.
They tried to give it,
they tried to habilitate this as um,
as an unfortunate sexual
orientation rather than, you know,
these people being dangerous predators
that we need to be protected from.
But I've never seen that.
But you're saying it's all I've seen is
where this guy's just discussing this.
But no,
honestly all bullshit aside,
like psychologists and sociologists and
neuroscientists have tried to figure out
what it is that causes
someone to have these desires.
But we know from the transgender debate,
the left doesn't care about that.
What it cares about is who can,
you know who,
where it can place people
in the oppression Olympics
and the victim hierarchy
and pet. If I'm telling you I'm
warning you now, that is the worry.
I'm warning you now is
that as the header files,
pedophiles are going to be the next.
Transgender has been one. Now they've won.
They've won that battle. It's over. Um,
do you think so? Yes, absolutely. Stay.
It's done and dusted.
We lost by we,
I mean people who actually wanted
to find out what the science said.
Two is simply telling people lies
born this way is a lie. And you know,
because if you're a true
story with some of them,
nobody that's holding the signs because
most of the ones holding the signs,
the militant homosexuals are the ones
that chose to be gay to get it. People
uh, do, do you have like
debates with gay people?
Well is willing to bait me
because they know they'll lose.
Well they've got woman brains.
They're not very good at logic brains.
I'm just kidding.
You accuse me trolling earlier.
So I thought I'd better get about 72 to
live up to the reputation. Certainly do.
And you're also very aware that uh,
you, you are right wing views and the,
those kind of a little bit
of a right wing Ben to you.
You talk about conservatives
dress to wear a suit and tie this,
this right from your suit tie.
Like a good way to align yourself in the
club is you have to espouse Christian
values or talking about being Christian.
Give us stuff about what the conservative
establishment thinks of me. If I did,
my career would have turned out
very differently. I've, I, you know,
I would have chosen a very different path
through my professional life. You know,
I was at the Telegraph and it,
you know,
the most respectable establishment
newspaper in England, uh,
eight years ago if I'd want it
to be, you know, a sign of the,
of the conservative Republican
establishment. I could've done that.
I did the exact opposite. I've stuck my
nose up and my middle finger up at the,
at conservatives every available
opportunity. I Bright Pour,
pour Breitbart who put up with
so much from me. You know,
they published Black Dick
Jokes every week for me.
And that is a direct assault on the kind
of stomach churn that the conservative
writers or were said to have
about gay things. Right.
I don't just tell them I'm gay, I tell
them I'm sucking Black Dick, right? I,
you might seem really good column,
very funny and entertaining
and I'm right about everything.
And that also puts them in
a very interesting place
where they can say, look,
we have a gay guy working for us.
I tend to think probably about gives us
stuff about whether people think that
homophobic or not.
They certainly wouldn't hire me.
The second is do they call everybody?
Buddy does trust me, trust me.
Right, but doesn't care about, doesn't
caffeine, you're homophobic, they're not,
but they don't care if
you do or they would.
They care about is is the facts of
what they published and the facts,
what they probably should,
but this was the time I see.
It's so strange is someone who
believes but doesn't practice.
You believe in religion,
but you don't practice any of the things
that that religious bouses especially
the sexual things, but it's the church
brought out the book. You can buy it now,
but it's like a,
well now it got republished a few years
ago by this guy named John Irvin and you,
so you can get a hold of it now,
but for the longest time used to
have to buy it as a used book. Well,
I will look it up. Yeah. This one also,
the Dead Sea Scrolls, the Christian myth,
he wrote a second one after
the Catholic Church bought out.
The first one stopped production
of it and bought all the books.
That's your people Catholics.
I tried to hide that information.
[inaudible] they last thing they want.
I went to Catholic school,
man for a whole year.
Cured me. Fix me up. Good.
It's where you get you a fine sense
of right and wrong from no wait,
let's not do that well,
right and wrong as far as what is
wrong with you now? I got lucky.
They beat me a little bit.
Lucky you didn't get that taste of no,
I said just like I said earlier,
if it went for Father Michael,
I would have given far less good head.
I mean it was a real father Michael,
so much less. You know, he's,
he's, he's going to get killed now,
but who is Father Michael?
I betcha there's a real dude I should
have made you suck his dick for real. Um,
I make me, I was going to ask about
it. I thought my English teacher too.
But how old was he at the time? Um, oh, I
didn't know he was quite young. Quite hot.
Really? Yeah. And so that's where it
all started with Father Michael. No, no.
Is that post the tranny? Yeah,
it was post. So it wasn't like,
it wasn't drag queen as a
child or anything like that.
So, uh, it was quite a,
you already had the five someone
when like this is all wrong.
I need to talk to father Michael. He's
like, suck my Dick and shut the fuck up.
And you're like religion as
Aussie. I really, I really
had no hope. Did I? I was,
I was,
I was never going to end well.
Well it seems like you
kept stumbling in a decks
on them through life.
I don't know what would have happened if
a heterosexual man I just been falling
on Dix was in the same
circumstances as you early on.
I mean obviously things would
have went very different.
So I'm not sure if I buy the nop,
you'd go down great.
And the gay club go down.
Well, I mean, you know,
we have to push the expression. You
go down. Well it ain't already match.
Yeah. So good demo means you would
a, you'd be popular, you go down to,
well it would be like the way you
would describe a meal or a drink. Oh,
like it goes down. Well we
like taking the piss. Yeah.
It took me a while to get, what the hell
do you want a cup of mind? Yeah. Which,
which again is another thing.
Gay people seem disproportionately into,
they're a peanut on each other.
That seems to be
the Lord only gay to be transgressive.
They choose to be coming up prior
in the gate. She used to be gay,
to be naughty of all know sexual place.
Pray the gale can't.
Full belief Christian values count.
Tear myself away on maybe as
you get older and you know,
drive dries up,
I would've made a good priest.
Do you think I'm making a good priest?
I think a bit.
Well you make a good priests.
If you think the guy that made you
suck his dick was a good priests.
That kind of, he was a great
priest. Honesty, like he
was good. Other than that,
I've never had a better senior tutor.
He was great singing
teacher got notes out of me.
I didn't even know I could produce while
he worked. Your plumbing shattering,
the Chandelier's kind of thing,
but was he good outside of what he did?
Like was he a good religious scholar?
Was he a good parish priest? I mean,
I just said fucking creep.
Getting his dick suck.
Then it's gonna to get lynched now. How's
it going to get lynched? Does people,
do people know who he is? I don't
think so. What's his name? Well,
I'm not saying any, well,
I won't be at the time.
You were a little kid and he
was like, what? You're just
trying, you're trying to,
was he in his twenties or thirties it's
another yet another feminist strategy
that you have adopted in
addition to your language buddy.
I told you it wasn't the pedophilia.
I was [inaudible].
I was in my teens 14 I was in my teen.
Something like something like that.
That's what you said,
your buddy.
I don't know how they rocket and was
very old England. I was in my teens.
I'm here in my country and
he's saying it right now.
Maybe seen a 15 year old girl at any
point in your life, however old you are,
you've never seen a 15 year ago
thought was off when I was 15 no
dude,
when you were 25 when you were 13 you
will have seen girls about 15 you thought,
whoa, whoa. No, you did a
dental book going to be hot,
but he didn't want a fucker.
Bullshit.
You can't tell me what I was born into.
I think if you're 14 when you were
born this way, you're born a Jew in it.
Picker. No, you're trying to
make it so I'm a fucking creeper.
Like you know I'm not, I'm not in the
14 year olds. How dare you sir. No,
he's a 14 year old fucking the guy
that you said it's a great guy.
He was in a 14 year old stick.
It's a terrible person. No,
surely I was a very mature 14 year old.
Yeah.
Well in your case he got it right.
You got the right guy to molest.
It wasn't molestation.
That's absolutely,
most of the station is
perfectly consensual.
I don't think it is when they're 14 when
I was 14 trust me, I was the predator.
I was the Predator,
the Predator chasing after the crease.
It's to try to stay close to God.
Everybody I was,
I was aggressively seeking out sexual
company of adults because I knew it would
horrify people because I
wanted sort of power over them.
It was my way of rebelling,
my way of rebelling. I was,
I was the Predator of 14 let me tell you,
do you think that's what's going on
with that guy who directed x men?
Bryan singer? Yeah. Much of 10 year old
predators going after that. Poor man. I,
I'm not sure it's the case with him.
That's a guy I,
I lived Hollywood I a while ago.
Did you meet briefly and
you got one of his parties?
I went to other people who I won't
name of a similar stature in Hollywood.
I went to their boat parties into their
house parties and things and some of the
things I have seen their baggage
belief. Yeah. Can you give us like a,
well, just, I can't,
I don't want to be indiscreet about
specific people because I think it's going
to be around the fact, yeah, dangerous.
But I can tell you the truth
without dropping anyone in it.
And some of the boys that were very young,
very young, I don't necessarily recent,
don't remember. No, no. Like, I don't
know, eight years ago. Um, I don't,
I don't remember,
um,
whether I ever met Bryan singer or
whatever or even knew who he was then.
But I knew other people of
similar stature, as I say.
And there were some very young
boys around at that time.
There was a lot of drugs
and a lot of tweaks,
a lot of twinks taking drugs and
having unsafe sex with older men.
And some of these boys were very
young, desperate for a job. You know,
when Andy Cohen, the guy, Oh,
what runs bravo had to apologize for
the use of the word twink apologize for
Twain. I thought that was one of the
most adorable things. Yes. Gay as fuck.
And he said the word twink and
he had to apologize because what?
Cause it was demeaning to somebody thought
someone was like a perfect twink and
he made like a social media comment.
Nothing. Nothing's wrong with that.
I got and you see this,
this is the thing you
see the progressive's are
starting to police homosexual
slang. You know this theory,
right? I'm, I believe that um,
pedophilia is the next
progressive rehabilitation drive.
But I also think that straight,
sorry that homosexual white guys are going
to be put back into the establishment
bucket very soon. If you look at some
of the whining editorials coming out,
I was like the daily beast,
this female female columnist
and the daily beast who will,
who will publish things about
seeing it on your Grindr profile,
this app that you use
to pick up guys nearby,
which is best just to see if torsos and
you just pick or you want to get the
fuck by. It's correct.
Jesus would've planned that.
I don't feel like the iPhone and
I don't use it for that reason,
not for that reason. I think he is that
it needs it. Um, but uh, on that, um,
on the APP, some people say whites
only. Some people say only Hispanics.
People just express their
sexual preference. Everybody
has a sexual preference.
Perfectly reasonable.
But of course, you know,
there's some progressive column is
just finally like five years later as
cottoned onto this and decided to
make a thing about it and said it's
problematic that gay people express
racial preferences in dating.
Of course it isn't. We won't. The okay
cupid data actually shows us which racism,
which genders, um, you know,
come out on top and come out of the
bottoms like Asian women do very well,
black woman right badly, um, you know,
and the sort of league tables of, of,
of hotness, uh, minimum. And
Anyway, um, so the sign to police,
the language now and the police, the
sexuality of homosexuals, I mean,
there was me thinking we were sliding
dangerously close to tolerance and
understanding.
And now progressive's are starting to
police the sexuality of homosexuals again.
Um, very interesting. There's a game of
Gotcha though. So chemos. Gotcha. So it's,
they don't really,
they're not really upset that upset it
should looking for something to complain
about. Yes. But the problem with it,
the problem that rich culture, I mean,
I've always said that outrage
culture is what it is. Right. Right.
And the problem with, without any
way to approach outrage culture,
it was just what I do is to be outrageous,
right.
Say Ridiculous and outrageous things,
um,
simply to draw attention to the
people, to get upset about it. Yeah.
I think it's a very important project and
it's what I do in a lot of my columns.
That's what I do on Twitter.
I've done a little bit today, um,
and I think it's very
important to wait a minute.
You've done a little bit of
it today. Well, I've been
outrageous. I haven't said,
and again, I believe, but I've
been outrageous. Outrageous,
outrageous, outrageous.
Um, just a little bit, I've toned myself
down for you because I know what a quick,
you intersectional lump lumping Cree.
Sure.
It's so much threatened me.
No.
Okay.