My kids always make fun
of me because I'm bald.
So my whole head is covered with sweat
and they come over my head like it's so
gross. And then how old are your kids?
The youngest ones are eight and 10.
And you have, you have, uh,
how many? Three. I have three
daughters, all daughters,
22 year old, a 10 year old and an eight
year old. Live longer with daughters.
If you, if you, if you plot, uh,
Dad's survival on the y axis and fraction
of female children on the x axis.
A survival is slightly longer for men
who have higher fraction of daughters
because boys drive you to your fucking
grave cause they're so goddamn crazy.
There's lots of theories as to
why it happens. But I think,
and that is in fact one of them,
it's framed a bit more scientifically.
Well my basic theory, my 10 year old
is a maniac. My 10 year old daughters.
And I would just imagine if she was a boy,
I'd be terrified that she knows
just lighting things on fire.
Blowing up buildings. Yes. Yeah.
Boys are a problem. That can be,
I mean, I think, yeah, I mean, I
think, um, you know, I think it's, um,
I think, um, the, the, well,
I mean we could get onto the whole
gender issue. I'm not sure we want to,
but I think, um, boys are responsible.
Let's talk about chimpanzees. It's easier.
Okay.
Male chimps do most of the violence.
About 95% of the violence and murders
are committed by male chimpanzees.
And most of the victims are males.
And, um, you know, I think it's,
there's no doubt that,
um,
biology plays a very important role in
male proclivity to violence, for example.
Sure. So let's tear trouble. Yeah. So
boys can be a problem that way. And Yeah.
And I think the many ways in which a
society are of cultural traits that we
invent,
their purpose is to shape and
guide those tendencies to violence,
to kind of mitigate them. So
we don't just need, again,
going back to the books or observe,
please do. We don't just need, uh,
we don't just use culture
for that purpose there.
There's an argument in the book that we
humans have, have domesticated ourselves.
So if you look at,
if you compare a dogs to wolves and
domesticated cats to wild cats from which
they descended,
or a Guinea pigs to the wild Guinea
pigs from which they descended or,
or horses to, uh, to the wild horses to
which they send, if you, again and again,
you compare these couplets,
these pears,
you find that the domesticated version
of these animals that are much more
placid, much more peaceful, they
also tend to have floppy ears.
They have piebald for,
so Guinea pigs and dogs and cows
all have splotchy black, white,
and Brown for why is that? The animals
from which they evolved didn't have those,
the kind of splotchiness. So, uh,
and they become much more peaceful
if you compare human beings and,
but they had a, uh, the, those
animals were domesticated by humans.
Like I deliberately allowed
the reproduction of this
member of the litter and
not that member because this
member was, was, was nicer.
And so across time we evolve a more a
domesticated version of the ancestral
species. So we get, you know, we get
my miniature Dachsund from a wolf,
like the wound,
like the kind of things that were
photographed out in your studio here.
Crazy transition.
Uh,
now if you look at humans
and you compare us to, uh,
to the [inaudible],
to our ancestors or to other
primates for all the world,
it looks like we have been domesticated,
we are more peaceful and placid.
We have sex outside,
non reproductive sex is and other things.
So these domesticated
animals, we'll have sex, uh,
even when it's not time to
reproduce. Uh, we, uh, we, um,
uh, we, our tails, we
don't have tails anymore,
but our tails gets shortened or all
these features that we have, these,
these behavioral qualities and these
physical properties that we have are,
are we get a feminization of our faces.
Our jaws become smaller.
Like if you look at,
you compare these domesticated animals
to their non domesticated ancestors,
the domestic version or less violence.
So we lose a lot of the traits
that physical and, and, uh, um,
psychological traits
associated with violence.
But there was no one that domesticated
us. So the theory is, the question is how,
how did that happen? And one of the
theories that's discussed in, in, uh,
in blueprint and that's advanced by
other scientists, this is not my work,
is that we self domesticated.
And that what happened over the centuries,
over the millennia,
over millions of years,
is that weaker individuals
into our groups.
When one individual became too autocratic
and too violent and too powerful,
they banded together and kill that guy.
And so over time we were killing the
more violent members of our species,
weeding out those people, and therefore
the gene pool changed across time.
And we self domesticated.
We are more peaceful today than we
would have been because we domesticated
ourselves.
And this is one of the arguments that's
also made to help explain the origins of
goodness,
actually in the origins of cooperation.
Because that would take a few good people
to kill the bad person that's running
everything that's evil.
Correct. That's exactly right.
Recreational sex does occur in Bonobos,
which is really weird,
isn't it? Yeah. They're so
similar to regular chimps. Yes,
but they're not the same species.
They also have homosexual sex. Uh,
they use sex to make up, you
know, so, uh, it's, yeah,
they're very licentious a species.
That's exactly right. And, and, and,
and Bonobos are felt to be a self
domesticated chimpanzee. So the similar,
so bonobos are to chimps as uh,
as let's say dogs are to wolves and,
but there was the dogs.
We domesticated the Banabos
self domesticated is the theory.
Do they know why or how? Well,
the theory is that they did it.
Like we were saying by weeding out
the more of aggressive members it was,
what we know must have happened is that
the nicer guys must've been able to have
more offspring.
So the gene pool changed over time because
of the differential success of the,
of the, of the nicer guys. Now people have
looked at this even in human societies,
they've looked,
for instance,
there's a study I talk about in the book
of different pathways to reproductive
success amongst that Sumani which is a
group in Amazonia and other societies are
similar.
So you can either be like big and strong
or you can be charismatic and have
useful knowledge. And both ways.
You have more children. Mm.
Um, so there are these competing ways, uh,
in our species of enhancing
your reproductive fitness.
Are you aware of support
[inaudible] work with baboons?
[inaudible] that's a fascinating case,
right?
Because they were studying
baboons in Africa.
They would eat from human garbage and
a bunch of them got sick and died.
And it turns out that the most violent
and ruthless of them got sick and died.
And it changed the entire culture of the
baboons tribe. I don't know that story.
That's an interesting one.
Let's start grooming each other and being
kind to each other. Oh my God. Yeah.
That's a good example. But there was
an alleged dental, it was an accident,
an accident, and that it
lasted for generations. Yes.
And when he returned to study them, he
found that they were still this different,
kind of talked about this a little
bit. Yeah, I'm doing a shitty job.
I'm sure I'm explaining
it, but I'm, I'm, no,
I think you'll have the books fascinate.
Yeah. Work. Yes. He's very impressive.
And a, I know the, I, I'm, uh,
now that you're reminding me,
I'm a little familiar with
that particular study.
I didn't know that it started with
garbage, however, that at coincidentally,
x extermination of the more violent
members of the troop. Yes. Yeah.
So they were removed from the gene pool
and it changed the entire culture to the
point where generations later they were
still using this more peaceful ways.
Full. Yeah. Yeah. More kind. Well,
it didn't just change the culture.
It may have changed the culture,
but it appears were arguing
the two of changing gene pool,
second evolutionary pressure that's
been applied. So you have, you know,
big dogs and small dogs.
You don't allow the big ones to reproduce.
You just reproduced the small ones.
You get small dogs in the end.