Removing it. They're removing all the
stores. When I was there, they were like,
they were having some sort of a
closeout sale cause they were,
they were getting shut down. I don't know
if that's since been amended or fixed,
I don't know. But socks died
and when he, when he moved in,
when he moved in, I was like, okay,
this kids fucking pissing me off.
He's not picking up his shit.
He'd not not doing his dishes.
He eats like mom did all that
for me and I'm like, okay,
I either could get pissed off and kick
him out, but then I realize I'm like,
he doesn't even know. He doesn't even
know. So I'm going to work with them.
I'm going to try to treat him like
my little brother and help him.
And he was willing to
like kind of follow along.
And then he started slowly
starting to eat better,
started eat spinach and his back
problems started to go away. And um,
what kind of background? My back would
always hurt. Always inflamed, always.
I don't know what it was. I just, I
remember getting it looked at my lower,
lower back. It was, it
was, it was nothing.
It was literally from eating shitty food.
It's just all the inflammation from
all the shitty food I was eating.
And I didn't know that at
the time. I remember my mom
took me in there, like, up,
your back's fine, but it's,
it hurts so bad. Always.
I started eating more anti inflammatories
that started making shakes with
spinach and almond milk and
blueberries and Chia seeds.
I started eating healthier and I'd
slowly notice like, oh, I feel better.
I started, so I started getting
more into eating healthier.
I remember just recently,
um,
I eat a vegan diet for six months and the
people on Instagram hate me now that I
don't eat vegan diet anymore.
Again,
go off Vegan Diet, man. That's
like when you become a Muslim.
Apostacy seriously. They
want death to you. Yeah.
Yeah. Because I've been posting pictures.
I posted a picture of, I got this, um,
grassfed beef jerky for him. Whole foods
yesterday. Got Probably 30, 40 messages.
Why aren't you vegan anymore?
Or just meet like people that they're
mad at me for not eating a Vegan diet
anymore. But I, I would say like, I hate
that Vegan diet for six months, but I did,
I incorporated eggs and do it. Cause I
just couldn't, I wasn't eating enough.
But I never, I never felt bad. I didn't
feel worse. I just didn't feel great.
Once I started eating good quality
meeting and I felt my energy levels,
I'd wake up, my energy levels were way
higher. I just felt more aggressive.
I felt more like manly. Um, so
vegans right now getting angry
in the contenders, I know you lost
me. The contender series fight.
He weighed 138 pounds. He was a
Vegan at that time. Sick lease,
dislike skinny.
There's more to that,
to them than just the weekend that I
had a concussion, a bad concussion.
Three weeks out from that fight against
Alfred and licking tender series.
I remember waking up in the middle of
night puking. Um, I couldn't train. Um,
I remember I even woke up with a
little headache going into the fight.
Do you remember? It was from, um,
yeah, I was from sparring. I hit hard,
boom. And I remembered, I'm like fuck.
But I knew it was the huge opportunity.
Um, I liked the matchup. I knew I had to
go out there and perform, but yeah, I was,
I weighed in at one 36 and I walked into
the cage at one 38 like I was, it was,
and you can even look, go by. I look,
go back and look at that video and it
looked just unhealthy, but it all works.
Yeah. I just, I so skinny. I
was like 138 pounds right there,
but I still dropped his ass.
Then two weeks later we went to,
to hang out with her buddy, a Scott
Holtzman in the UFC for a UFC Fresno.
And Dr Andy Galpin was with him for
the week and I knew sugar was with me.
He watched what the health,
and that's what turned him Vegan.
So I made sure to ask doctor
handy in front of sugar. I said,
how much would Sean benefit from
eating like elk or a grass fed meat?
Twice a week. He's like
fucking hugely, hugely.
And then Sean right
there made the decision,
I'm going to start making
some guys tell him if this,
if he's this smart and he's telling me
that some good quality meats going to
benefit me,
I would be stupid to not
take him up on that and, and,
and do that. So, and I don't
regret, I feel so good.
Eat and media and I feel way stronger.
It's hard when you see those documentary
and also you get a lot of positive
reinforcement from other vegans that
are very happy that you're Vegan. Yeah.
They love that you
joined the team and look,
people want to be healthy
and for the most part,
eating vegetables is very healthy.
The problem is there's a lot of nutrients
that you're gonna really have to
search for if you're just
eating plants and it's,
the protein is not as bioavailable.
The amino acids are not as bioavailable.
It's very hard to get vitamin
B without supplementation.
There's a lot of shit that you're just
not going to get and they like bang for
your buck in terms of what the amount of
nutrients that you get in like a small
grass fed steak versus
a big plate of Broccoli.
It's just not the same and they don't
want to admit it and a lot of these
feelings,
those,
I think those what the health guys I
had the mom when they did Cowspiracy I
think they mean well but they are
fucking true believers and they,
they are not trying to put together a
documentary that states all the facts
subjectively they're doing
a vegan propaganda film and
on it debunked a shitload
of the things.
We had an actual nutritionists
analyze what they were saying,
go over the studies and they debunked a
shitload of what they put in that film.
That film is propaganda film and it gets
a lot of people thinking this is the
way to go is going to reverse
heart disease and help
your body and but they get
so many things wrong deep into
the meat does not cause diabetes.
Like this is nonsense like that when
they do these studies with people,
especially like um,
studies that they do on people that
show that people that eat meat more than
five times a week have a higher
instances of heart disease.
All these different things,
they don't measure what else they eat.
These people that are eating meat all
the time or eating fries and shakes and
soda and you're not analyzing someone who
eats sauteed spinach and olive oil and
a piece of grass fed beef or bison or
elk or something like that. No, you're,
you're getting some assholes eating
Jack in the box. Yeah. Like, yeah,
that stuff's terrible for you.
It's fucking sugar and refined
carbohydrates and nonsense and trans fats.
Oh, it's those terrible
for you. If there's,
there's no studies that show that
eating clean like people have eaten for
thousands of years.
I mean literally if me caused cancer,
97% of the planet would have cancer.
That's the,
that's the numbers that eat
meat on a regular basis.
It's like 95 plus percent. Fuck, and
then those people like that are Vegan.
They're like, oh, I'm
going to try a Vegan Diet.
And then they're eating all these veggies,
getting these nutrients that they
didn't get before and they're like,
I feel fucking kid off that bullshit diet.
You Stop Eating Jack,
The star Jack in the box
in the middle of the night.
Sometimes I do go to us for comfort,
but it's just fast food, shitty
food, processed food, you know?
That's what the problem is. We to like
people like you're saying like ramen.
I like ramen and every now and
then, fuck, it tastes good,
but it's not good for
you. I couldn't eat. Yeah.
It's just like knowing what that what
that what it does your by knowing that you
are what you eat, it's high can't, I
can't cheat. I can't do it. If I have no,
that's not going to benefit my body. I
can't eat it. It's hard from what you eat,
like 100% and I so simple. You know, it's
such a simple, it's such a simple phrase,
but literally your body is made out of
what you eat and that mouth pleasure
[inaudible] hi damn man.
Ice Cream Sundae,
but hot fudge.
But there's so there's
all these healthy you can,
you can replace all of
that with healthy stuff.
I haven't had any Quito ice cream,
but I've heard good things and some people
said there are some Stevia sweetened
or Xylitol sweetened Kido ice cream
that doesn't fuck with your body. Nice.
That new halo top man has that coconut
sweetened coconut milk and Stevia.
That's pretty tasty. Well there's, there's
stuff that you can eat that is good.
And of course fruit, you know, eating
healthy fruit. I mean look man,
a nice delicious ripe peach
is about is fucking good.
It's any bullshit. Fucking fake
dessert you're going to get anywhere.
We don't appreciate it because we think
of it as being like a healthy choice.
So it doesn't,
you don't get that I'm being a naughty
boy reward that you get from having a
banana split or something. Fuck
God. It's just not worth it.
It functions might asleep up. It fucks
your blood sugar up. And that's the thing.
It's crazy that most people
don't know. They're like, God,
I just eat and then I'm tired and
then I just get starved again.
They just don't know about those blood
sugar. Fucking, yeah, the insulin spikes.
And I had a regular coke the other day,
like a couple weeks ago for the
first time in years. How come? Oh,
just whatever it was there.
So I haven't had a coke in forever.
Let me have a coke.
And it was, I was like,
it was like drinking syrup this sugary,
it was like felt thick when it was,
when I was chugging it down and it was,
I was like, stomach. No, no.
But I did feel like shit after,
after it was down, I was
like, Whoa, I feel terrible.
But how many people drink those
fucking things every day? Every day.
First 42 at 34 ounces or what are they
doing to us? Pop. It's hard. Yeah.
It's hard cause it's who you're
surrounded with to like, fuck dude.
If you're surrounded with everyone, like,
oh come on pussy. Just have a good time.
Enjoy your life.
If you're like pocket and then you're
like exactly like who you you like it's
such a
common thing. You are who you surround
yourself with but people don't,
I don't know.
It's like I'm so lucky that when
I was surrounded myself with Tim,
like he,
he introduced me to eating healthy.
I remember when I was 19 I
moved to the lab every day.
We have pro practice Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, Saturday,
every day I was going to the coffee shop
and reading mind gym books meant not
like all these mental books and we're
doing it the other we were reading
constantly improving each other,
wanting to get better,
wanting to help each
other improve and that's,
it was so important for me to you are
who you surround yourself with and I see
people not surrounded with themselves
with the best people they can be around.
And
to trap. Yeah, it's a terrible trap.
And sometimes those people that are not
the best people are really fun to be
around the problem. That's a
distraction. It's like what's keeping you
back from wanting to be the very like,
I want to be the best
Bantam weight in the world.
Like what's keeping you people back
from wanting to be the best of them and
still distractions. People who are fun to
be around alcohol, you know, even women,
like certain foods,
like distractions of what's keeping you
back from wanting to be the best you.
So just our brains are crazy.
Our brains are nuts.
Yeah. I mean just, well you got to think
about just what you do for a living.
I mean, just that alone, it's
crazy, right? The desire to
be a professional fighter,
to desire to fucking kick people in the
head and choke them and have them try to
do it to you and that this is what excites
you and that this is what's driving
you to go to the gym to improve constantly
at, I mean, that alone is crazy,
you know?
And then these other people that are
living their lives and drinking too much
and smoking too much and eating
shitty foods, and you know, they,
that's their path, you know? But their
path is not compatible with your path.
That's the big key. I like that. Okay.