But you, but even if you train,
you put it on your back. Let's say,
let's say if you put a lama in a backpack,
say you got like a fucking
Cafaro backpack, good luck
stuff. The alarm in there,
you had the whole Lauw zipped
it in, had it, okay, go over
that fence. He'd be like,
well, my buddy who's a guide
in Alaska, my buddy Chad,
he said that they were climbing up this
mountain. It was a fucking nightmare.
Like they like just slogging up
this steep mountain just like,
and they were like looking up and they're
like, God damn, this is a nightmare.
You know, you're making like inches. Just
like, ugh. Oh, and you got a backpack.
And it just like,
when is this going to be over?
And don't try not to think about
digging. Let's take a break, you know?
And they just hear this and they just
see this grizzly with an elk in its mouth
and it just bounds up the mountain.
It just goes Shagun Shagun right by
them with, uh, with, uh, with, uh,
and just goes up over the
mountain and over the ridge.
Just no problem in 12 seconds. And
they were like, well that's a grizzly.
That's how strong a fucking girls
face. And this is me, Jesus Christ,
I don't want to get that's I'm
so terrified of, I'm terrified.
I don't want to fuck get fucked
up by a chimpanzee or sheep bones.
He will eat my face and my balls.
So I don't want that.
And I definitely don't
want to get attacked by a
grizzly because they'll start
eating you when you're still alive.
And that's a problem.
Most of the time grizzlies eat people
though or most of the time of grizzlies
kill people.
They're not killing someone because
they want to eat them or killing someone
because you startled them and
they're with their female,
the females with their cubs.
Oh that's most of what happens when,
what are you supposed to do
when a grizzly just pray?
Well if it's a female grizzly,
you are literally better off
letting her fuck you up, right?
It just curl up in a ball. You're supposed
to put your hand behind your neck,
lay in a fetal position and don't
let her get access to your organs.
Cause she wants to chew your
Oregon's apart. Jesus. Yeah.
It's one of the reasons why it's really
important to have a strong backpack.
He was strong. Backpacks will fuck up
that backpack while you're on on your,
you know, underneath, curl
up in a fetal position.
But that's assuming you can survive that
she's probably gonna break your arms.
She's probably going to snap your legs
bite into you in ways you can't imagine
the kind of force and
power she can generate.
I mean she's trying to immobilize you.
She wants to mobilize you as a
threat to our children. But a male,
if a male is trying to kill you, it's
usually because he's starving to death.
They don't recognize people as a
food source. They rarely people.
So that mail PR,
it probably has never eaten a person.
It's one of the reasons why it's safer
to be in a place where they hunt.
Grizzlies cause in a place where they
hunt Grizzlies Grizzlies, he's a person,
he goes, fuck this, they'll smell
you and get the fuck out of there.
But like Yellowstone, they haven't
hunt grizzlies there in forever,
so people still get jacked.
They're stupid.
They get jack there every couple
of years now it gets killed.
We have a gun with me.
You should,
but you might not be able to get to it
and you also have to be able to prepare
to pull it out and shoot quickly.
You can't think that just because you
have a gun you're going to be okay. No,
cause you don't hear him coming up on you
come up. So they move so fast. They run,
they run fast as a dog and
they're huge. Is that true? Yes.
There they run fast as fuck man. And
they're huge. It's a giant animal man.
800 pounds.
Think about that.
I just stumbled across a story about,
this is happening about bear spray didn't
work and it was attacking the guide
and the the,
the client went to grab the glock out of
a pack and it didn't fire and then the
bear came after him.
So he tried to throw the gun to the other
guy and then it didn't a deck I just
ran into. I guess I'll just have to
follow this guy who died. It doesn't,
I don't, I didn't find, no, I mean
it happens all the time. Yeah.
That story is Rinella. Story, uh,
Rinella and Remy Warren and Yannis
Portallis and uh, our friends, they,
uh, they got attacked while they
were in a fog neck island in Alaska.
Jesus. Yeah. Blog now.
Yes. Like two years ago.
And Remy came on here and told the
story and it's fucking terrible. God,
what happened? Well, they
killed an elk and um,
they had hung it in a tree and they
had taken some of the meat back.
Cause you know, you have to hike out of
fog. NAC is particularly dense. It's very,
very dense. Vich Mitch, like, remember
when we were on Prince of Wales Island?
We went on that intense dense. Yeah.
Well it's like that, but even worse.
Chrisleys everywhere. Yes.
Grizzlies everywhere with
this huge problem with that.
When we were on an island, that island had
black bears. Yeah. Which weirdly enough,
they're not as dangerous, but they
are more predatory towards people.
I want to try and spike Telmate and spiked
collar and I want my guns like close
clothes, iron man suit. That's right.
I want to be able to correct shoot
rockets out of my hands. That's right.
And I want to be able to electrify it when
the, when the thing bites, yes, kill it,
and then immediately cut its
head off and put it on a steak.
So all the other grizzly bears, no, not
to fuck. That's exactly right. Okay.
There you go.
We're on like a man.