It's, um, I mean, time to change
me. You been around for a long time.
My friend, I remember the first time
I ever saw you fight. It was a bar,
a backyard, bare knuckle
fight in the Kimbo slice days.
That was the first time I heard about you.
And then I saw you fight Eve Edwards
and Bodog remember Bo dog fight? Yeah.
It was a golden age. The golden age is
manager while ago. Damn. It's crazy.
Like Bodog fight was fun organization
and Cain Velasquez fought there.
Chill son and fought there. Eddie
average. That's right. Yeah.
Pay Door fatal or had a fight over.
They're afraid or had a fight over there.
Brad Pickett as well. Yeah.
Yeah. I'm Mike Brown. Yeah. What,
what happened with them?
They went under because of the,
the whole gambling rules online changed.
Right.
From what I heard from no one I heard
was the spending budget. This is what I,
what I heard, um, Calvin there,
there was the owner of both, right.
He put up this huge budget and these are
just rumors from what I heard from the
people working, you know, but it was
like $100 million for Xyz amount.
I used to get him publicity so people
would see the fights and then go to the
casino and that a hundred minutes and
got blown out like in two to three years
is what I heard.
Oh.
And I wouldn't disagree cause they used
to pay me really good and give us super
perks. They usually give us
some super perks, you know,
take us to exotic locations to fight,
be there for two weeks,
you plus two they'd fly out,
take care of you. They really,
really took very good care of me.
So when I heard that they
blew out a hundred minutes
in three years, I was like,
yeah, it could be, you know.
Well they were fighting on the beach
with hot girls in bikinis and wandered
around dancing. But you were on the
beach like in the sun. I was like,
what the who the fucking ideas to
fight in the sun. But let me tell you,
the training sessions that went on,
there were some of the best that I've
seen in the world because they it.
So you would go and you'd bring two of
your corner men and then somebody found
that and then before you know you had
like four people over your entourage going
with you from whatever team that was.
And everybody was doing that.
And we'd have a,
a training place.
And what they had done was laid
out tarps and mats and it was huge.
So we'd have like a hundred pros,
50 pearls from all over the world,
just training, you know, and when you
to know each other and it's like, hey,
you want a roll? You know, it
gets competitive, you know.
So there was some great training
sessions that I saw and that I,
that I took a part of, you
know? Wow. Yeah. It was fun,
man. Good fucking time. Look,
the, the world needs more of
those. They meed more one fcs.
We need more bell tours. We need
more, you know, competition,
whatever the professional
fight leagues called now,
what do they call themselves now?
Is that what it is?
It's Pfl used to be world
series of fighting. That's
right. Yeah. We need more,
need more of them. Also PFLs world series.
He used to be world series downs. PFL.
Okay. Yeah, I think pretty sure. Most
of the same organization. Oh yeah.
Do you need, we need more.
You know, I need more money.
She's got that Oscar de la Hoya thing.
You know that.
That's probably never gonna happen again
after the, the Tito and chuck fight.
It does look like,
but someone of that ilk,
someone like a golden boy promotions,
they started getting involved
in MMA and putting together,
they could get some guys that aren't
signed but are super high level with a big
name.
Like maybe the contract comes up and
they decided to do something with a big
name promoter. You know,
it'd be good for everybody.