At the end of the day,
everybody wants comradery
and love and friendship.
That's why like what's the worst shit
that can happen today? You get canceled,
everybody wants to cancel people. You're
out. Get out of here. You're done.
Pits over.
There's a weird strange,
it's also like I want you to not be
able to make money but it's signed.
I want you to starve or go home, be
homeless. I don't really understand.
Is that specific?
It's not specific in terms of like they
don't want you to be able to make an
income.
They want to hurt you.
That's what it is because they're
scared of someone doing it to them.
This is the a big part of why people
pull the trigger on that stuff.
Whether I just, people are calling for
people to get canceled for like nothing,
like little tiny things.
Never again.
It's because they're scared of it
actually happening. So this is like,
you have this ultimate power to just
like get upset at someone for virtually
anything. Pick it, pick a cause,
whatever it is you can get. Also,
it's sort of intoxicating and it's fun
and most people don't have real opinions
on anything. And then you
have this, this, you know,
on on Facebook or Twitter or
whatever social media platform,
you have an immediate
gratification of like,
I just got 20 likes on a thought of
mine. Yeah, that's addictive as fuck.
It's super addictive. You know that
that right there would, you know,
I understand why people continue to
come back and nobody really cares.
As soon as you put your computer
down at your phone down,
nobody gives a fuck about any of these
issues at the supermarket or at the
bowling alley or in the library.
But that's not what's important.
What's important is the
Internet is essentially,
the whole world is a big
window and everyone has a
rock and people just look at
it, throw rocks. And if you find
a thing to throw a rock about,
whether it's throw rock about politics or,
or gender or race or social
justice or you know what,
fill in the blank. The environment,
the saving, the animals,
everyone's thrown rocks, you
know? And very few people
are actually communicating.
It's a strange time for you would think
that you would want, in an ideal world,
you would want people that have differing
ideas to come together, sit down,
have an honest conversation. Yes. And
Go, awesome dude. Go live your life.
I'll live my life. I learned
a little bit just now. Yeah.
And then you go off and you go,
yeah.
That's how you learn
from different cultures.
That's how we ultimately got to
a place. You know, I think I, I,
I think it's a great country.
I, in a weird way, I think it's,
I'm proud to be an American, you
know, I'm proud. Um, you know,
I don't think all the things that people
think they're are awful about this
country or necessarily
awful. Um, you know,
I think the opportunity to make money.
I did grow up on wealth and I grew up poor
and, you know, you know, I'm, you know,
for all intents and purposes,
I'm living my dream right now and I
get to kind of do what I want to do.
Um, and I look at that and I say yes
because I live in a place where that
Opportunity's there. Of course,
look, America is amazing.
It doesn't mean it's perfect.
No,
certainly it gives you more opportunity
than anywhere that I've ever heard of.
And it's a fun place, man. I like it
here. Yeah. Fucking country is fun.