A lot of this early work was reported
and there was no voucher specimens to
document the collection.
So a lot of it had to be dismissed,
you know, uh, they,
the Beta carbon chemistry
of banisteriopsis didn't
really get well defined
until, um, some Chinese scientists, uh,
or at least they have Chinese name worked
on them and discovered harming tetra
hydro harming and the harmer
lien as the main alkaloids.
They could reference that to
botanical voucher specimens.
So they really should get the
credit for discovering it.
And then once that was done,
then it was known and you know,
other scientists had to acknowledge that.
Why did they describe it as telepathy?
That there was supposedly some sort
of a story about some group telepathic
experience. Yeah. This was just
romantic. This was just some story,
you know, out of the literature. Um,
yeah. I mean, I mean it, it was
rumored to be able to cause telepathy,
but this wasn't Iowasca they
were only taking hormone.
It's not clear. It's not
clear. It's not clear. Yeah.
I mean they may have been taken
but they may have been taking it.
But whether they were getting telepathy,
I kind of doubt it when we know
we could get telepathy on Iowasca.
It's not so uncommon.
It happens all the time.
People have group hallucinations,
group visions.
Has anybody ever bothered to independently
legs a quest or people put them into
like a different rooms,
have them do Iowasca and then have them
describe a very similar experience are
almost identical experience to prove that
these telepathic you experiences exist
or at least to as far as I
know that hasn't been done.
See yeah cause everybody wants to talk
afterwards. I do see the dragon. Right.
I don't think that's been dug. That
seems like a worthy study. Cause if,
if I've heard from more than one person,
in fact,
my friend Kyle Kingsbury and his wife
had an Iowasca experience with a,
both had a visualization of their child
and then when they got back she was
pregnant and they want to having this
child from their visualization from,
from, from this experience. Um,
obviously they're very close and
they were together and they probably
communicated quite a bit.
And you know,
I would just think it'd be
really interesting experiment.
It would be very interesting. I mean,
and that sort of points out there is,
you know,
a realm of experience,
a realm of knowing that these things give
access to that's normally close to us.
I mean, that's kind of a
trivial statement of course. Um,
but then you get down to questions
of how verifiable is that?
How real is that? How, uh, you know, and,
and people get,
um,
I don't know if the term is hung up,
but they can get baffled
when you start talking about,
you know, the reality of say the
entities you encounter on DMT. I mean,
this is, this is, uh,
some people I know are obsessed with
trying to verify the reality of the
entities that you find on DMT.
And again,
it comes down to if you experience some,
they're real.
If anything you experienced as
real because you've experienced it.
Does it have a corresponding
existence in the external world?
Well, you know, what's external?
What's internal? You know, we, we,
we throw around these terms,
these,
these epistemological metaphysical
terms quite carelessly,
you know,
without really thinking about it.
What does it mean when you say
I'm in here and you're out there,
you know,
and then you take a psychedelic and you
realize that's an artificial boundary.
You know, we're all one.
There is no separation.
It's separate in normal consciousness
though it's separated in normal conscious.
But then what is normal conscious if
not a reflection of your neuro chemical,
brain, state. I mean,
everything you experience is an altered
state because it's filtered into this
brain processed by the brain and you know,
the brain is a biochemical
engine that, you know, as I say,
often we're made out of drug.
So it seems that our normal consciousness
is the best state to propagate
biological life and to keep our s are
whatever we've created in terms of our
community structures and relationships
and friendships and the ability to build
structures and houses and
things like that. These,
all these things are done best
when you're here and present,
whereas when you're on a psychedelic
state, I agree with you. Well,
the way I've always described it as if
you had a meeting with God and you went
and God gave you all the answers to the
world and you have, you experienced, uh,
undeniable beauty in the most extreme
form possible where you couldn't have
imagined it and then you came back.
Whether you hallucinate it or not, it's
the exact same experience. Exactly.
I can't put it on a scale.
You can't weigh it like we've stretched
the tape measure around and God is 47
inches across. Like just because,
you know what I'm saying?
Just because you can't draw and
measure it with what we term our, our,
our, you know, our metrics
for reality. Right.
And that is exactly the,
the thing.
Don't worry about whether it's real
and the way we would define real.
Is it good information or is it bad
air, is it not? That's the thing.
It doesn't matter where it comes from.
It's such a fits good information.
Then it has its own internal validity.
I'm whether it came from some part of
yourself that is normally up security,
you or a came from the plant teacher
or the aliens transmitting it through.
It doesn't really matter. But
we, we are obsessed with that.
We are specific reality because we
think we're being fooled a lot. Right?
Like the,
and this goes back to Terrance's
La Chorrera psychedelic
experience where he had
a Ufo encounter,
you know,
easily dismissing amongst us would go
while he's tripping his balls off on
mushrooms. Of course I saw you. Oh, is
there a leprechaun drive in the UFO?
Like all that's nonsense, right?
Right. Easy to dismiss. Yeah.
And in fact,
that is the nature of these phenomena.
That's what's really interesting.
Easy to dismiss that.
That was another aspect of the experiment
of the La Chorrera I left out when I
was talking about my lecture.
But there's almost always an element of
absurdity in these experiences and the
imperil normal experiences
in Ufo encounters.
It's like little green man.
Are you kidding?
But right the fuck there are little
green man and little blue man.