I'm on social media now.
Deleting social media
from your applications,
from your phones that give
you a 10% boost to happiness.
What was,
what do you think the percentages?
Yeah,
I think probably something like that.
Yeah, that's about right. Good. 10%. Yeah.
I mean,
the only thing I've kept as Twitter
because I kind of like need some means of
getting a message out,
you know? Right. Um,
well that's about it.
Okay.
So far so good. Well, what's
interesting with you, you,
you actually occasionally
engage with people on Twitter.
Okay.
Yeah. It's what percentage
of that is a good idea?
Good question.
Right?
It's hard. It's mostly, I think
it's unbalanced. More good than bad,
but there's definitely some bad.
So do you ever,
hopefully the good outweighs the bad.
Do you ever think about how odd it is,
that weird feeling that you get when
someone says something Shitty to you on
Twitter and you read it, that weird
feeling, this weird little negative jolt?
It's like a subjective negative jolt
of energy that you don't really need to
absorb, but you do anyway. Like,
well, fuck this car for chem.
I mean there's a lot of negativity
on Twitter. It is, but it's a weird,
it's in its form like the way if
you ingest it as it, if you like,
you try to be like a little scientist as
you're ingesting it, you're like, wow,
how weird is this?
And I'm even getting upset at some
strange person saying something mean to me
it's not even accurate.
Well, I mean the, the,
a vast number of negative comments,
uh,
Slovakia for the vast majority of, I just
ignore them. The vast majority. Yeah.
Every now and again you get drawn
in somewhat good. It's not good.
Make mistakes. Yes. You could make
mistakes. Some mistakes. We're all human.
We can make mistakes. Yeah, it's hard.
And people love it when you say something
and you'd take it back and you're like,
fuck you, we saved it forever.
Fucking screenshot that shit bitch.
You had that thought. You
had that thought. They were
like, well, I deleted it.
Not good enough. You had the
thought, I'm better than you.
I never had that thought you
had that thought you piece
of shit. Look, I saved it.
I put it on my blog. Yeah. I'm
not sure why people think that,
that anyone would think that to
deleting a tweet, it makes them go away.
It was like, hello. Then the
Internet for a while. Yeah.
Well it's even like anything is,
they don't refer you to be able to delete
it because the problem is if you don't
delete it and you don't believe it
anymore, it's really hard to say, hey,
that thing above. I don't really
believe that anymore. I changed the way,
the way I view things, because people go,
well, fuck you all right. That over there.
I'm going to just take that. I'm not
going to pay attention to that shit.
You wrote her a needed it.
It's on your permanent record.
It's forever, Bro. Tattoo.
Put this on your permanent record. Yeah.
It's like a tattoo. You keep it. Oh yeah.
Yeah. Well, it's, it's this thing
where there's, it's, it's uh,
there's a lack of compassion.
So lack of compassion issue.
People just like intentionally shitty
to each other all the time online and
trying to catch me. Yeah. It's,
they're more trying to catch people doing
something that's arrestable like a cop
trying to like get, you know,
arrests on his, his record.
It's like they're trying to catch you
with something more than they're logically
looking at it,
thinking it's a bad thing that you've
done or the to an idea they don't agree
with so much. They need to insult you.
I'm trying to catch you. Yeah. I mean,
it's way easier to be mean on social
media than it is to be mean in person.
Yes. Ways or, yeah. It's weird. It's,
it's not a normal way of human
interacting. It's cheating.
You're not supposed to be
able to interact so easily,
but people were not looking at yes.
You would never do that.
You'd never be so mean to somebody
looking in their eyes. And if you did,
you'd feel like shit. Most people,
yeah. Unless you're a sociopath,
you'd feel terrible.
Yes.