Yeah, it's so fucking good, man.
Why is style bender and Jon Jones,
why are they talking shit to each other?
Do you know what started it? Yeah. Um,
John did a, originally it
started, it did start with John.
He came out in the interview and goes,
you know, style Benner's looking good.
He's fighting 85 it's only a matter
of time before I think we cross paths,
which is silly. And then style bender,
I think TMZ asked him, he's like, oh,
I already beat one goat. I need another
one. You know, I'm just getting started.
But if you're a John,
why are you even engaging in this?
Why are you punching down
John? Because Sanchez, well,
it's great for John because he
wants to let everybody know, hey,
I'm the best motherfucker on the planet.
But yeah,
but he wants to let everybody
know like when he's,
when there's a car that's about someone
out. I mean, he's active now, right?
Jon Jones got momentum.
Now think about where he's at right now.
He's in his thirties right?
Long Ass fucking career as
champion as the best ever. Correct.
He's on a run right now.
That's what I think.
I think they took it away from him for
all those months when he tested positive,
that long suspension,
all that time off,
all money that he should have made all
the legacy that he could've laid down.
And I now, I think, I think he's just
fucking chasing it and the best about it.
Have you sent all about it?
However, talking to 80 183
pounders, kinda silly. Yeah,
but what if you say that in an interview?
I don't think that's that disrespect.
I don't either.
By the way.
You said it is that one day
maybe we're going to fight. Yeah.
But then style bender, you know TMZ ask
them, they know shit about finding like,
oh, this guy's big. This guy is big.
They're both black. Let's fight.
They have no idea. Yeah, no, that's
what they think. Right? So then,
then it gets picked up. But then also
I think Jon Jones is the hot, you know,
senior in high school
and style of vendors.
The new freshman who's hot and it's
like mean girls like fuck that dude.
It's also a wonder how much of this is
like, they all agree is good for business.
It's entertainment. Consonance, anytime
there's a fire blast, something out.
Well not just blast something out.
I mean is real good about that.
But like the way he's
able to turn these shit,
talking back and forth into
publicity for fights, they all,
there is real shit talking
to his psychological warfare,
but it also hypes people have to know
and like the Khabib fight all the
craziness that led to that.
Obviously that backfired.
When could we tried to fucking attack
him after it was over and it was,
it was an adjustment crowd.
Even alveolar people punched him
in the head and all that craziness.
That beams never been bigger. Yeah.
Look, could bebes never been bigger.
Connor's never been bigger and yeah, I
mean he needs to fight. You need to find,
needs a fight he needs to fight on still.
You guys know this.
I ride Connor's nuts. I write
competes nuts. Stop. And there's nuts.
But with condom, like God, hopefully
something gets lined up. Yeah.
But what I'm trying to say is like that
shit talking keeps you relevant. It was,
yeah, it's worth something.
It's worth something. The green,
both of them agree like if style bender
and Jon Jones did decide to fight one
day it, that shit's worth something
to both of them. Agree. Yeah. Agree.
Just a big gap between 85 and two oh
five though, man. John's a giant tool.
Fiverr John John could beat up any
heavyweight in the world with these could
beat up probably six of them in a night.
So to,
to fight a one 83 or is weird.
Yeah.
Well obviously he wouldn't be one 83
if style bender was going to do it,
I'm sure he'd want to put some
some weight on and imagine it just,
that's such a nightmare.
But that's what makes style Ben or
special cause those guys same as mashed,
hollered. He goes, I'll fight
anyone. Yeah, sure. That's,
that's what it's all about.
Also like, and this is not a
knock on Santos or you know,
the level of competition at two oh five
there's really nothing there you get
excited about. There's just not,
you look at the other divisions.
Santos can be a fun fight.
He's going to be a plus 700
plus 800 underdog. So, you know,
but I liked that John's active. I like
watching John. Yeah. Beat everyone's ass.
Yeah.
It's,
it's one of those things now where you've
got to find contenders for John, right?
Because there's no one's
really standing out.
Rockhold would be cool at two oh five so
heavyweights, Dominic gray is just beat.
Who did he beat? Did he fight Volk on
hosed Amir? No. Yeah, he did. He thought,
and I didn't think he beat him.
And I'm a race fan,
but I don't think you need those.
The man, I thought he lost. Yeah,
that's what I was, I was a weird
decision that, so that one is, look,
Vulcans have very good fighter.
No doubt about it.
But you saw with Daniel
Cormier did to him.
Neither one of them are ready for
Josh not ready for John's. Not even,
they're not even the
same realm. Right. So,
but we were looking at Dominic and
we're like that kids really talented,
super pro. He's got massive potential and
I still think he does. They all, yeah,
you know, so stuck. He's just going to
get better from this Johnny Walker. Right.
But that guy might have blown shoulder.
Let's say he doesn't though.
If he doesn't, he's still thinking
we're fight away from John Jones.
He might be four fights away.
Here's the thing,
he might knock for people into another
dimension on the way to John Jones.
Like guy's something special.
And that's what I'm saying. Yeah,
but you got to knock this four guys
out so we can sell this thing. He does.
I mean he's, he's put away to top
level guys, uh, pretty spectacularly.
And um,
I mean you look at the way he fights too.
He's loose and weird and then boom, jumps
on you and it's so special. Hower dude.
Fucking crazy power. But I think with
John, his team smart the gun, no,
we know heavyweights there.
We're going to clean out to a five.
Ain't nobody been this were clear,
clean out.
So we're considered the
greatest of all time.
Then when go to heavy weight and get paid,
well, you know they wanted this fight.
They thought it would be a good fight
with Tiago and I think one of the,
one of the things that a good fight,
one of the reasons why it's a good fight
is Tiago can shut anyone's lights out.
He knows he can shut anyone's lights out.
That motherfucker throws for the
beliefs and used to fight at 70 no 85
[inaudible] 85 [inaudible] 85 struggled
to make 85 like he's big. He's big,
he's big. A big dude. He's like the
fucking power that that guy has.
And I heard the Manoa fight
and he just swings, man.
He swings wild now John is not
going to fight him the way man.
And we'll finally get in touch.
You know John is going to keep on the
outside with those kicks and take him ties
to clinch him. He'll
clinch him, wrestle him,
take them down John's ground and pound
his horrific as top games off the chart.
Missions are great submissions.
Everything strikings better.
Elbows are from hell,
from the top.
Just gets on top of you the best you're
getting elbowed to oblivion and they're
coming one after the other. Fti
there after the other, but the,
in the wild exchange where he has
to be careful is that that Tiago,
dude, Tiago Santos, we'll
swing with everything Johnson,
he will throw it all in there.
John Diamond engage in that.
You're not going to see the opportunity.
I mean,
that's what makes them so special.
Those guys that go,
that's where your one places dwin watch
this. Yeah, he just canceled it out.
I don't think that he would
willingly wade into a firefight,
but like that could happen, but it
could have that tie cell fight, sir.
It could happen. See what John
is going to do. If I had a gas,
has tried to further cement his legacy,
he's going to fight the best way he can.
He's got great coaches.
They know what the fuck they're doing.
He's going to go in there.
He's going to kick that dude.
If you decided to clench with them,
he's going to have a giant
advantage in the wrestling,
but he's got to be careful on the
way in, man, that dude will swing.
We'll try to kill you.
He tr he swings in a different way.
He swings like this ain't making it to
the fifth round. There's no fifth round.
He's not even looking to get,
he's, that guy is just every shot.
He's trying to take the lights out. No,
I'm out. I'm definitely gonna Watch it.
He's a wild motherfucker, man. I
think this is an interesting fight.
Jon Jones should be the strong favorite,
should be a giant favor,
but it doesn't mean it's not going to
be interesting because this dude's style
cause he's so fucking wild.
The question's going to be how he perform.
How does he perform when you, when that
octagon door shuts and you look over,
you see it's Jon Jones and
title fight the tunnel fight.
But I think one of the reasons why John
Talking Shit to style Benner is one of
the pros is we're talking about them,
right?
Because we probably want to talk
about him. Verse Santos on this show.
If it wasn't happening, it
keeps them relevant. You know,
he is probably the biggest name
in the sport now. Outside Connor,
the guy who's the most active him and
could be proud of the biggest names and
talking shit to stop bender actually
think it helped style bender too, right?
Because now he's associated
with the greatest of all time.
He wants to be the greatest of all time,
but when you just did and
it's going to get there,
and I can't fucking wait when he goes,
all right,
I'm ready for heavyweight him verse
Francis. What are we going to do?
What are we going to do?