Hello Freak bitches. It doesn't get
any better than this for boxing.
Especially like after the Conor Mcgregor,
Floyd Mayweather fight.
This is a fight that like,
hey, this is how it's done.
Yeah, this is the real deal.
I mean obviously Floyd did it
how it's supposed to be done,
but that wasn't two fighters on the
same level. Look at this. This is crazy.
These were absolutely glorious.
It's fine.
These are both great
moments for boxing though.
The Mayweather Mcgregor on this ship
both really, really great for boxing.
Brendan Schaub, I should say this
before the decision gets announced,
said that if Golovkin didn't win
by some ungodly lopsided beat down,
that he could lose a decision
because of corruption. He goes,
cause that's how boxing roles and there's
way more money and Canelo winning.
So that's sad. Now that we know that
the cop tie sponsor, that's true.
Well apparently the audiences are like
half Mexican. He's a superstar in Mexico.
Just a super sweet talking about Canelo.
Yeah,
so let's see at Brendan Schaub predicted
this correctly because we think it has
to be Golovkin the rap,
the unofficial scorecard guy had
it for Golovkin by several rounds.
We think it was go off can clearly,
although canela fought a great fight,
have there been bad decision
if Canelo winds have there?
What was the last time there was
a decision like that? Tim Bradley,
Manny Pacquiao who won that, I
believe Bradley one, but pack,
y'all should've won and then came
back and outboxed him. It was worse.
It was worse. If I remember correctly, I
said, what was the reason? Look at that.
Boom, boom, boom. Oh
Jesus, they're shown hello.
Oh my goodness.
This is the last round that was Canelo
just tried to put it to them and go off
and he's like, come on, come on,
come on. I'm from Kazakhstan bone.
Just boom over the top.
God Damn just war here.
That had just paid back every
punch he took in the combination.
Just sharp jab to his gem.
So snappy. Okay. Change it.
Give me a guess. Eddie Bravo
for sure. Glove again, for
sure. Right. Unless there's,
unless there's corruption,
like Brian says, he's not
crazy to say that. I doubt it.
They're cutting scenes, corruption pad.
We're, we're saying this, look at this.
They got it. One 16 one 12 for Golovkin.
Harold led him in here. Harold,
they gave that last.
Lufkin ran away with it.
They gave ten nine on that last fight.
I mean that last round to fucking know
Canelo yeah. You know what I really like?
I don't know why they did that.
I like how these girls just stand there
and smile. They're doing really good job.
They're always smiling. It
seems easy, Dude. It's hard.
You've got to be frozen and fucking
clapping. It drives me crazy. I hate it.
I love it.
I love the f their focus.
They're focused on not being
even remotely normal. This bird,
the job, their focus, their
job is to stand there,
smile in Assam psychotic way. If they
were a guy, like if they were a guy,
if you were,
if they hired a guy to stand there in a
nice suit and tie and stand there like
this,
could you fucking imagine how crazy
it would be if you hired guys to stand
behind fighters with giant smiles
on their face and just not,
especially if they were in their
underwear. Just imagine that.
Imagine guys in a speedo
standing there like ripped,
like holding a [inaudible] sign with
a big giant smile on their face that
happens on Santa Monica Boulevard going,
it doesn't happen during a big fight.
Paper view. Eddie Bravo. You
silly goose one day when, hey,
let's hear the volume. Let's here
it. Is this a split decision or no
told you son. Oh boy. They fucking boxing.
Fucking stinks.
Told you son boxing shot.
Apokyn is a sage.
Brendan.
Brendan Schaub as a safe fucking stinks.
He mad cause he knows.
He knows he got fucked.
You know Canelo well he's going to feel
terrible now. He knows he got his ass.
That's a draw. There's no way.
That's how is that a draw?
Okay.
No, it's, hold on second.
He's actually going to see,
if he was happy then that would
mean that he thought he lost.
So the fact that he looks pissed,
that's smart. He's going shoot a one
to eight [inaudible] 69 I think
he's mad because he didn't win.
He threw 200 more punches.
Win. But he's definitely mad.
Did he got outbox and they made it a
draw to me. I did 50 more punches. Yeah.
The fuck is that a draw to me stinks.
It's not even close.
Our punches different. No, there
you go. That's the difference too.
Maybe I'll go higher percentage.
Oh, I can't stand it. Yeah,
but it's a higher number. Landed two one
14 and one 10 and total power punches.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, all right. Jab,
weird thing though. When you're looking
at it numbers wise, I mean it's one,
it's one way or looking at it,
but like one big shot that's a power
punch and then another power punch.
It doesn't do anything. They're both
power punches. You know what I'm saying?
Like one shot that really fucks you up
and your legs go and you get wobbly.
That's a power punch and another power
punches his shot that lands in the same
spot but doesn't do anything. They're
both powerful. And these colors mean.
What are the, what are you what I'm
saying? What is the blue ear? Maine.
I don't know. Look at the number of
punches that, uh, landed on Canelo's face.
Hundred nine on his right side and
a 95 on his left to 10 landed two.
One 27.
Yeah.
Big Difference in how many landed to
the head getting 40 level and landed way
more.
He wait a minute,
said only four shots were
landed to Canelo's body.
That doesn't make any sense.
Does that word really when it said, I
see what he says here. Let's hear this.
What happened tonight?
What happened tonight
today?
Really big MACs.
All my friends,
romance,
good move. Go right to the
Mexican fans. Fucking smart move
able to neutralize you.
Especially early in the fight
when it looked like you went
starting to build the lead.
I want to,
we probably can't play this without
getting yanked off of a youtube,
so we're going to go to the, first of
all, I didn't think that last fight was a,
I mean that last round
was a ten nine Canelo no.
How was he not fucking angry about
this? I mean, why am I angry about it?
Big Drama show tonight.
He retains his belt,
so nothing really changes for him and
he gets all that money now that your
record in the rematch is going to be
insane. The rematch will be insane.
Those dollars to 19 good job by
Brendan Man. Fucking good call.
Yeah, box. He filled it.
The fighters were amazing,
but the organization of it just
stinks. Brendan. Nailed it.
Can you hear this? Are you, are you
guys hearing this? What? No. Okay.
What am I hearing what
he thought I wouldn't,
you know,
I don't want to hear.
And here he's not saying I got really
lucky that they gave me that draw.
I don't want to hear what he's saying.
If he thinks he wants to stupid.
Still those a great fight. Amazing.
I love it. I don't, you know, I mean,
I do care, but I don't care. I do care.
The thing that I thought the gun go
off getting one, but I don't care.
It's a great fight.
I liked seeing great fights.