The joe rogan experience. Right,
and there's two on each one,
so it literally might be 200 for
fucking pumps. Well, that's crazy.
Why doesn't Chuck Norris Make Jeans? Sears
too. Awesome. He used to, he didn't use,
did I still own a pair of Brown? Let's
see these. I'm not alive any. No,
not anymore, but I used to, they
used to only claim on these.
The lace up in the front. They did? Yeah.
The laced up in the front and let
you do sidekicks. There it is. Bam.
It has a gusset.
Looks like Chris Irwin.
They had a gusset in the crotch area.
I like that. The lace up at the front,
so I might be lying.
That might be a little longer
in scene there for that.
That cowboy boot kick back in the day,
they didn't understand
about barbell jeans.
They didn't have the time
of fabric technology.
I do have a pretty good kick distance.
Have you ever seen mine?
I'm sure it's very long.
It is.
We'll make a video at the
top of a doorway. Ooh,
look at that and I'll dress shirts.
That gentleman right there
will always have my respect,
him and Bruce Lee or the reason why I
got into martial arts a hundred percent
today. Watch it. Chuck Norris
movies. When I was a kid,
one of my most proudest moments in my
life was in Chuck Norris. Dude, who I was,
I ran into him at a kickboxing event
in New Jersey like way back in the day.
And it gave me this big hug.
It was one of his events that he had.
He had a world combat. He gave me a
big hug and I was like, Holy Shit,
Chuck Norris knows who I am. Damn
right. It couldn't have been happier.
No wonder you're unbreakable. Soccer
was Beeman. And then we'll later,
uh, I took a picture of me and
Tate Tate again. Um, there was a,
a award show that they did for an old
school karate master and Chuck Norris was
there and a bunch of other, uh, old
school, American black belt karate guys,
and they're telling these awesome old
karate stores and asked me to be there and
speak a little bit. And
I would, uh, I mean, I do
anything for Chuck Norris. Like,
no bullshit.
Go corny as you want for watches.
Chuck Norris changed.
He changed my life for real.
If it wasn't for Chuck Norris Movies,
who knows?
I might not ever got into martial arts.
I've watched him like lone wolf,
McQuaid and shit. I was like, God damn,
that might be the coolest
guy that's ever lived.
Yeah.