I wish that with Trump. Sam Harris
has been on a, he was at least,
I think he's abandoned it,
but he was,
it was on a quest to get jack to try to
hold up his terms of service agreement
and, and kick Trump off of Twitter.
He's like glued, he's doing,
he's threatening nuclear war.
Like,
do you understand that this is
the craziest use of Twitter ever?
And I think Jack's
position was that it is,
it's more beneficial to
have him on and it's really,
we are getting to see his personality in
a way we've never seen any president's
personal.
Absolutely.
I mean the most ridiculous petty shit
that he does like attacking Michelle Wolf
of because of her White
House correspondence, calling
people losers, you know,
making fun of, uh, the girl
on Joe Scarborough, the
girl he married. Yeah, yeah.
Saying that she had
fucked up plastic surgery.
Bleeding makes shit up. I
mean, do you think she really,
really thinks she showed up at maralago
bleeding fucking plastic surgeries cause
he's a fucking maniac. But he
really is a meanwhile that it, it,
it's good for us to see because it
educates us to who he is as a real person.
There's a lot of who you are just gets
exposed in those tweets we little bit,
you can't know everything about a person
from their Twitter, but you can get,
you can parse out little chunks
where you get a good taste.
And for him it's very, very
revealing. Yeah, it is a weird thing.
This is what I think this will be looked
back on as a very pivotal moment in
American history and in politics where
that kind of crossroad happened because
we were, we were pretty
satisfied with, uh,
that political speech thing that,
and we need to bring up the lower middle
class to the door and they just go on
and on and drone on.
It's this weird speech that no
real human being ever speaks.
Like Hillary was hilarious.
And Wayne, Hey ted. Hey,
it's the guy was fake. It comes off as
fake and phony. Trump comes rolling in.
It's absolutely batshit insane.
Like the stuffy says,
like you were saying the other day,
he's,
he's giving a speech and he
said that when he was younger,
people said he looked like Elvis
because he was doing some kind of a
commemorative thing for
Elvis. Um, uh, down in, um,
it was it Tennessee or
somewhere and he says, uh,
he looked like Elvis and we're
laughing our asses off me and Keith,
because no one ever told him he looked
like Elvis. No one ever told him that.
And, and there's so many
things and I'm a Trump guy.
I voted for the guy because I wanted that
monkey wrench thrown into the machine.
I felt we had gotten screwed too many
decades and it was time to let Washington
know, like, look,
we'd rather elect this
nut than any of you guys.
So I think it proved a point.
Uh,
there are enough checks and
balances in place. You know,
the likes of any one president really
isn't going to do that much damage.
I think he's pulled the
cover off a lot of stuff.
I think people are trying to
compete with him on Twitter.
Politicians are trying to play his
game and it's kind of fun to watch.
As a comic entertainer, it's gold
to see what Tulsi Gavin said to him,
what? She's a congresswoman
from Hawaii. She said, uh,
being Saudi Arabia's bitch isn't
making America first like that's a
congresswoman.
Say they're all kind of taking that.
They never used to do that.
No they didn't.
And it's odd that a 70 year old guy was
the one that was like bringing Twitter
to social media into this
a forum it is on and yeah,
you would think it would be some
young guy get in there and do it,
but I would never do it
the way he's doing it. No,
that's just like a reckless maniac. It's
and, and that's because he can, the guy,
you'll never see a chain of events like
what happened to elect Donald Trump.
The rich guy is a billionaire and
billion of whatever you want to call him.
He's got a lot of money from his dad,
from his, his dad. And then, you know,
I remember him in New
York when I was a kid.
Trump was always in the news developer.
He was always banging
heads with politicians,
trying to get some kind of zoning
thing going or build some other tower
somewhere. And, uh,
so we were all familiar with them and we
knew he was like this piece of shit guy.
You know, like everyone was surprised,
like, Oh God, he grabbed by the pussy.
He's like, we saw in the Daily
News in New York Post every week.
Trump was with some other hula
and said,
so it wasn't a surprise to, to us. Uh,
but he got out there and it was the
perfect timing. Like we come off the, uh,
the heels of eight years of
a Democratic president, uh,
and it just was, people were ready
for a maniac to be in the White House.
People were,
some people were exact.
My favorite image of the election was
that lady with the sock hat on their knees
with the glasses,
screaming
like that to me,
ushered in this era of outrage and chaos.
Yeah. Yeah. It just,
that was like the primal scream that
set off the dominoes and they're all in
motion right now. It wasn't supposed to
happen. It wasn't supposed to happen.
Hillary was supposed to be president.
That's what everybody thought
it was going to go down in.
History is just one of those
wacky elections and then
business as usual. But uh,
you know, when, when Trump won,
it turned everything upside down
and rip the cover off of I think,
not only politics in Washington,
but uh, Hollywood, uh, uh,
the mainstream media,
the news media,
everything had the covers ripped off
and everyone's now got a peek inside and
realize how fucked up everything is.
You know,
you used to assume Washington,
at least the people had some
kind of control like they were,
they were adults doing the job that needed
to be, and then you realize, oh my God,
everyone's just a piece of shit.
Do you remember,
here's a story that
disappeared from years ago.
Do you remember the Washington
Madam that suicide herself? Oh yeah.
Book filled with politicians
that we're getting there.
We're banging all these prostitutes and
she was going to release everything and
she was doing press conferences
and then she committed suicide,
committed suicide. But it's like welp
case closed, you know, no big deal. Oh,
well lost her books. Yeah.
Yeah. Never would. Whatever.
And then it disappeared. Yeah.
It disappeared. Thinks
like that happen. Oh, flag.
Do politicians kill people?
Oh yeah. Uh, there's,
there's secret backroom deals
that happen and it's crazy.
House of cards is way closer to reality
than people would like to believe. Yeah.
Yeah. Way Closer. We, uh,
over the course of the decades upon
decades, uh, every year that goes by,
we seem to get a little more knowledge
and a little less confident in the
government. I mean, I watched some
shit from the fifties you know,
there's plenty of things on youtube
and even even industrial films,
just this thing of how a family,
how to raise your family [inaudible] they
had to be a good wife, all that stuff.
And it was all this weird
propaganda of what America was.
And then as years go by, you
realize, oh, it was all bullshit.
Like politicians were always getting
rich and no one seems to know how we're,
why and these deals that are made
aren't always in our best interest.
They're not civil servants there
to represent and help you. And,
and as the years go by,
we see more and more of this.
And the past two years with Trump has
just been a man quite a crash course.
It really has. Yeah. It's crazy. Um,
I'm fascinated to see where it goes. Um,
I'm fascinated to see if he seems,
you know,
I mean they always called Gotti,
the Teflon Don,
but it seems like Trump is the
Teflon Donald. Yeah. He seems,
it seems like all these
things keep happening and,
and even because like I
remember Justin Martin Dale,
a comedian friend of mine
is hilarious. He goes, uh,
he was talking about stormy Daniels.
He was like, she's our Monica Lewinsky.
She's going to take them down. Oh my
God, the fuck that's not happening. No,
you don't get it. He doesn't care
that they know he fucked her. Yeah.
He doesn't care to understand.
It's not you have to care for it to work.
Right. And that's just it.
People don't really care. It's a,
well some people don't care.
I,
I follow like Rosario Donald's account
on Twitter and Rob Reiner is another one
and for two years, over two years, uh,
they have just been like counting
down and the day that it's like,
oh impeachments right around the corner.
Oh he's out.
Oh they're going to put him in prison.
I hope you and your son get a
cell to each other. And it's like,
how long are you going to do this?
Eight years.
Is it going to be eight years
of you going well any day now.
How about Keith Miller is going to,
yeah.
Do you remember when he was doing that
wacky show in a basement somewhere?
Gq like a mental patient like legitimately
wick a mental patient resistance
screaming and he was like,
he was doing like,
it was almost like burlesque or something.
I know what I'm saying.
Like you know how it was like the,
the radio version of burlesque ask is
like when you see a girl doing burlesque,
it's like an a throwback to an
old timey way of doing things.
Like the guy of the handlebar mustache
with a bowler capital introducer.
She's body, she is bought day shares,
please welcome Madam Blah Blah Blah.
And she comes out to music that nobody
listens to any more and she's dancing
around. It's very we and they're there.
They're always kind of big girls.
They're not skinny and like little
strippers, there are girls who eat.
So it's like it's a throwback to
a different time of of rowdiness.
And when he was in front of that screen,
like doing this thing with his suit
on and his tie and everything was like
really well written and rice
precise points and I don't
understand like what the
red blue and the background was either.
It's just,
it was so it seemed like something that
someone had set up like not as good as
your compound. The basement live
from the compound. It wasn't,
it wasn't as good as that. It's like
that's the background. This is for Gq.
Gq was like, okay, we have $30
$80 I think a, I think a,
Charlie's got a camera,
he could bring it in $30
good. Okay. We have a table,
the Ikea table that's $12 $18 left.
We got some construction paper for
the background. What the fuck is this?
I got some big ass blue
and blue and red pate.
Yeah, posters. What? What is that?
And then he would just
pontificate there and,
and he Glen and his last thing was like,
because the end is eminent, there's no,
no reason for me to go on right up
is finished. Yeah. What is this?
My work here is done play. Some of
this. Trump is finished 17 year.
One year ago. This week.
Exactly. One year ago. Wow.
Remember 11 2017 it was when he quit.
Get a pardon from Trump or that
molar as I have also reported here,
has succeeded in finding
a way around trumps.
Pardon power and either of these near
certainties spelled Trump's doom.
So that's the most obvious of the seven
ways for Trump to go. Now we're really,
we'll get him on Russia.
It will be ugly and it will
tear this country nearly apart,
but it will be necessary.
The second way is as I've also
repeatedly suggested here,
that Muller doesn't really need to
prove anything about Trump and Russian
sabotage of the electric.
There seems to be so much obstruction
of justice or the of James Comey
to the lies about Trump jr's
meetings with the Russians,
that it's hard to pick out a key player
in the Trump inner circle who could not
be guilty of it.
It's so funny. [inaudible] year ago and
it's like, it's still going. Still going.
Still going and it's fake news.
Yeah, end it now. Fake News.
It's a hoax,
but it is interesting like Mueller to me,
it's fascinating because he seems
like a ruthless motherfucker.
Takes his time. He's like a guy says,
hey, look at me. I'm going to kill you.
It's not going to be today. Okay,
that's all you need to know.
It's not going to be today,
but I'm going to fucking kill you.
And like every day he's
plotting on killing you.
You see him drive by your house
and wait, and you're like, when is,
when is the hammer fall? And you
look out your window of your office.
He's out drinking coffee. Oh, he
has seen some shit. Oh, I mean,
this guy, he's, yeah, I mean, he's
a cold blooded intelligence agent.
Yeah.
Those guys have seen everything.
He knows the inner workings of the machine
and he knows how you bring a guy like
that down and how you fuck it
up and he's doing everything.
That leads me to believe that he's not
fucking it up. This is a slow play.
And if there is,
if there is anything to the Russian thing,
I, you would think something would
have leaked out by now. Well, it has.
I mean it was a,
there was a video the other day of Donald
that they just played on CNN of Donald
talking about how many times he's actually
been the rush Donald Jr and you know,
he had said that he hadn't been,
and then there's another video of
him from years ago saying, yeah,
I've been there many times. Dan, five,
six, seven, eight talking about business.
The problem with,
uh,
the people that are going after Trump
that they don't seem to understand.
The Guy Right up until he became
president of the United States was just a
private citizen businessman.
So he had a lot of dealings around the
world with his real estate and buildings
and,
and a golf course is all this shit
happened when he was just a citizen doing
business. Now, whether it
was ethical or not, um,
that that could definitely be brought
into question, whether it's legal or not.
Uh, I'm sure that's what they're
looking into also. But he wasn't,
he wasn't beholden to the
people as a public servant.
There wasn't a conflict of interest
because he was a lifelong politician and
using the power of his
office to make deals. So,
and that also goes hand in hand
with him just fucking around. Like,
like if he went from a,
a selectman in his hometown and then
years and years go by and then you're the
president and you built that career up
any at any point in there they could call
you out on being a horrible human
being because he fucked girls.
Or your this or your dad
of shady business dealings,
but were up until two years ago,
he was just Donald fucking Trump.
So it's hard to call them out on even
dealing with Russia because there's plenty
of businessmen and deal
with Russia and China.
I think the question is whether or
not he colluded with Russia to get
information about Hillary and also to,
to,
to put out all that propaganda against
Hillary and also saying that they're
going to make a deal to do
the Trump tower in Moscow.
This was all while he was running for
president, not being honest about it.
I think that's, that's where
it gets again. I don't know,
almost there's anything illegal there. I
don't know if there's anything, uh, that,
that he did that is illegal because
I believe when you're campaigning,
say whatever the fuck you want to anybody,
I don't think you're really running,
I mean you're, you're, you're running,
but you're not really running anything.
And it really running the country.
If he lost the presidency,
he would still have to have some ducks
in a row to continue his business. So,
you know,
and his son took over that part of,
of what he was doing so he could campaign.
So whether Donny Jr went over to
Russia or not, I don't really see.
You might think it's unethical and you
might go, well, did he say, if we win,
we'll do this and help you out.
So who knows about that part of it,
but I don't see in and of itself him
going over there being that big a problem.