The Joe Rogan experience. So you, you
guys are dealing with Brexit, right?
Yeah. We've got a how's that changed
the climate of England? Well, it's made,
it's made a very toxic, very, I'm like,
come on, like what's happening over here?
You know, it's all gone polarized. Um,
like with the build the wall stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. And it's one side of the,
other than this, no one in
the middle in a way, if,
if you look at succession and a,
um,
American civil war that was
bound to happen at some time.
If you go back to the
constitution, um, 17,
seven and 87 that was, was
happening, happened. I think
once you, European Union,
no one's ever tried from
countries that have hundreds
of years of, of, uh, history,
choose to try and lend to live together,
work together some shape or form.
This tricky thing we're trying to do.
It's the hottest thing politically that's
ever been done in the history of the
world.
Um,
and I th cause I'm saying the American
muddle with native American lands and
rolling over manifest
destiny is a different model.
It's a different way of things happen.
It's a different time as well. Yeah.
Different time. And native Americans
didn't have this idea of, oh,
we mark this off in when
we've registered this land.
So the idea that people are
learning to work together is, um,
it's tricky. At some point someone
was going to say, I think we,
we'd like to change this
or we'd like to move out.
So this fight was bound to
happen. And, uh, so it's,
it's very toxic.
It's,
I'm, I'm not getting too in right at
the center of it cause you could just,
you know, probably like
you have a New York, um,
news broadcasts,
you can listen to people talking hours
and hours and hours or what do you think
about, what do you think about,
and it doesn't seem to get anyway,
so I worked out when my worldview is
this view that everyone's got to have a
fair chance in life. I know the
automation is happening right now.
So there's going to be a whole load of,
uh,
people who won't be able to get jobs
because of the unskilled labor force that
job's going to get automated.
That's going to get tricky.
So the universal wage is probably going
to have to come in the idea of universal
basic income, universal basic income,
which everyone's gonna have to get,
and it's not going to be a negative
thing. It's gotta be something. Okay,
then you can go off and you can retrain
or you can live your life. And uh,
and then there's artificial intelligence
parity by 2050 next 30 years.
And that's what is that mean? We can't
even work out what that means. Right. Um,
I think it's going to get harder before
it gets easier. And so I'm going to just,
I always play the long game. I always
do the long game. So, you know,
I came out and it back in
85 and I just thought we'll,
hopefully it'll get better over time.
And now this world up in 2019 and it's
definitely better than that was where he
can go backwards, phones back. But I just,
I ain't going to try and shoot for that.
And the,
the,
everyone has a fair chance
in life and as to Brexit,
where that goes when they, you
know, positive, negative, you know,
I'm against it so I was
just going to find it.
I don't need to think about whether I'm
against it. I just know that I want,
the younger people are coming online to
vote now they're old enough to vote and
they,
78% of them want to be part of Europe.
And the older people who are passing away,
probably 70 80% of them
wanting to be out of Europe.
And it's a fear thing like immigration,
fear of well is the thing you've gotta
we have to be brave and curious rather
than fearful and suspicious. And these
are the two ways I think people can go.
If we're brave enough, we can be
curious and say, hi, how are you?
Where are you from and what do you do?
Can we learn for you?
Can you learn from us? I think that
is the way for humanity to go forward.
Or You could be fearful and suspicious,
what? Hang on, they'll back off outside.
Don't, I don't want to talk to you.
I don't want to know about you.
And that's the fearful and suspicious way.
And um,
I think we have to be brave and curious,
otherwise we're not going to make it.
So for us in America,
what you're essentially dealing with a
bunch of different countries that speak a
bunch of different languages,
whereas we're dealing with a bunch of
different states that speak the same
language, but it's kind of
doesn't make any difference. Yeah.
It's interesting because I thought
if everyone could get the hang,
because English has become a
Lingua Franca for the world,
hasn't made much difference.
And as America shows,
you can be completely at loggerheads,
whether you're saying
the same words or not.
I think if you're not saying the same
words, it's easier for people to say,
who are these people? We hate them because
they can't understand a single word.
They're saying that's easier.
But yeah,
it's an easier way to be
xenophobic slash racist on it.
And I've always said the xenophobia is
just a racist, where the xylophone check,
which I got to somewhere to
political situation. Um, but
[inaudible].