Without, we say are the best, I'm
gonna fail to sell them the best.
And so I get defeated, you know, and um,
right now I'm in a candidate for,
you know, fight of the year and also,
you know, uh, fight,
uh, fights of the year.
I didn't have the cane,
I came back with Louisa,
a tease that was an epic one
and it came back with theory,
another app we fight and then
we're going to hit the two again.
That's the thing about you that makes
it interesting is that you're not just a
guy who knocks guys out,
but you're a guy who can take it,
your guy who can take it and you're
a guy who figures out a way to win.
There's a lot of guys that when it's
going bad, they don't come back.
When it's going good, they went
forever. But when it's gone bad,
it's hard for them to come back.
You figure your way through bad
situations and you make adjustments
even when something is
going wrong with my body.
I didn't have seven operations
on my arm, you know, it'd be
like surgery breaking, you know, just
breaking my arm turned my boss up, um,
break breaking my hand. You know,
many times in my, in my fights,
I broken my hands and still
fought, you know, tore my boss.
He'll come in with third degree burns,
you know, all that stuff. Like I'm a,
I'm a true warrior, you know,
I always think I'm like,
if I do something, like if I break my hand
or when I told my boss up in the ring,
my whole mentality is training,
change it to what?
That motherfucker had a fall off. That's
why I'm glad I got to keep fighting.
I got to keep going.
I'm a warrior, you know,
and you can never tell you no because
I still throw it with bad intention.
You know, I'm still, you
know, lending and hitting it.
Just like with the Chris Areola fight.
When I broke my hand and tore my bicep,
my camp,
my team knew I broke my hand,
but I didn't mention I tore
my bicep cause I'm like,
well I tell them I don't want no one
to panic. I'm not worried about it.
I'm going to keep throwing it.
I got to keep me in.
Chris was so surprised that I did all
these things that we're still able to
throw it. It's just a mentality when it
comes to comeback, like my mentality,
just overall logist I feel I'm the best
and if you're going to come and beat me,
you got to come and beat me.
He's just not going to be easy.
That's why most of the guys,
when they fight me,
they bring their a game every
last one of them, you know,
because they know it's going to be tough
and they also know I have the power to
get them out of there. You
know, and a lot of guys,
you know that they're afraid of that
because I mean over and over again,
like I said, my power last from
the first through the 12th round,
you can never be too comfortable with
me because of that, you know? And,
and that's big for me to have. You know,
I've always sat back and like saying,
you know,
I've said the same question
myself. Like, damn well you,
you got all this power light and you know,
me being the person with it,
I felt many times where I felt dangerous.
I felt like,
I felt like at times it can be too much
power because I get scared of myself at
times because I know I got the potential
to potential to hurt someone seriously.
You know,
just Dylan when it,
just looking back and seeing some of
the guys I've knocked out and seeing the
reactions and you know,
the unim broke guys arms out and
broke the ice soccer is to, you know,
put them in seizures,
you know,
almost killed speaker in New
York. You know, he laid there for,
for a while. You know, I didn't
even see him breathing, you know,
and so forth and so on.
You know,
it's been amazing to have so much power,
but still trying to understand it.