The Republican's and hate
for Trump in particular,
ramps up and that they're really worried
that there'll be some sort of a violent
outbreak between the right and the left
and that this could actually really
happen. Man, it's not impossible.
It's not impossible that at least battles
could break out because people are
fucking polarized, Matt. Yeah. Yeah.
But I think what's interesting to
me is that more and more people,
it seems like,
at least from my perspective on the right,
are now coming out against Trump.
It seems more common, more common,
especially with this government shutdown
people like what the fuck? You know,
there's so many videos of people going,
what are you talking about?
What this wall like? We need money.
Like people, it's government people.
A lot of them are living check to check.
Yeah. You're shutting down their pit.
This is the only way you
can negotiate this wall.
Does the only way you can fund this
wall. This is crazy. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean it's, I don't know. I mean,
people always say the government sucks.
Fucking shut it down and then it shuts
down. Everybody gets mad. You know? It's,
it's makes an argument that the
government should be doing less things.
This is the real argument.
The argument is some of those
things that the government does.
Why does the government have to do
it? Why can't it be privatized? Why,
why can't it become a business?
It would probably run better if some
of those things we're not run by the
government like airport security or like
road maintenance or like a lot of other
things like don't have the government
do it, have private contractors do it.
Cause I'm really strong standards and,
and strong competition and uh,
John Stossel actually has
a video about it right now.
Um, it's on his Twitter
page. It's a long video.
But explaining how one of the things
people are realizing from this government
shutdown is that the government does a
lot of things that they don't have to do.
It would be probably better for
everybody if some of these things were
streamlined. Some of these things
were done by the private sector.
I don't think that's a bad idea.
I think there's a lot of things that
could be done better if there was
competition as soon as the government
controls certain businesses. I mean,
maybe they do it really well and maybe
they don't. You know, I think the,
I think there's certain things that
were, socialism works really well. Like,
here's one fire department.
Fucking you gotta pay
for the Fire Department.
Everybody wants to fund the
fire department. Don't you
cut the fire budget, man,
what if my granny house
and we once fire man,
we gotta pay for the Fire Department. Pay
For that shit. Pay for the police. Yup.
Pay. And everybody says
pay you shouldn't be rich.
People only get cops and poor people
don't get comps. That's crazy.
Everyone would say that's
crazy. Yeah. Right.
Well why is that not the case with
education to them? Well, right.
Don't you want people to learn things?
Like when,
when did education becomes such a
big business? Why is that a business?
It should be our goal as patriots,
right? To make less losers,
more happy, successful people. More
aware people, more educated people,
you know.
But instead it's like subsidized by
the government and that makes it even
weirder. And then you have student
loans you can't escape. Yeah.
A lot of that is pretty bizarre. It's
bizarre is fuck, it should be free.
But there's also like
there's another like a lot,
some people don't want to do anything.
They does true want to be
alive and they just, they just,
they don't want to contribute and really
have any sort of life and they have no
desire for that.
And there's generation and generation
and generation of them dead is true.
But what if you ever,
do you ever look at universal
basic income? It's a weird idea.
I flatly rejected it when I first heard
it. We have it. No, we don't have it.
They've tried it out
in a couple of places,
but I don't think it's really worked
out that well. But the idea behind it,
I'm having a guy who comes on soon,
his name is Andrew Yang,
is a proponent of universal basic income.
And the idea is you give people
x amount of dollars per month,
whether it's $1,000 per month and
everybody gets it no matter what.
And by doing that,
you take care of all of
the burden of survival.
Like we take care of everyone in the
civilization. Everyone gets food,
everyone gets shelter.
So that eliminates a lot of crime and
a lot of strife just right away, right?
Questions more laid back.
Where's all that money come from?
There's $1,000 a month.
308 million. Is that what it was? Plus,
you know, that was 2010 it's
probably more now let's slate.
Let's say three 20 that is a lot of money.
320 million thousand.
So that's 320 billion.
Gee, isn't that what it is?
I have no clue. And the 320 billion
a month when that would be the,
if you gave a thousand people $1 million,
isn't that what it would be?
A thousand million is a billion,
right? Just to it in the calculator,
Bro. Don't do it in your head. A thousand
a million. Yeah. So that's right.
So it must be so that that's so
much money. So three. So the,
the wall, like him talking about building
a wall, isn't he asking for 5 billion?
Five Dale. Okay. It's not that
much, I don't think. Well,
that's to build a wall once.
This is every month,
you would need all those billions.
That's all a lot of fucking Chadha.
And so that means everybody would
have their basic needs met. Yes.
Everybody get 1000 bucks
where that money comes from.
This is what I need to
talk to this guy about.
Obviously I'm not a mathematician
or any sort of an economist,
so I don't have any idea what they've,
how they feel like they can do that.