I like this is two banks. Should we
take couple rips right now? Okay,
that is fucking awesome. This is a here,
here, here's your own little joint.
We're like,
we're in like this wave of like being
evolved and not being involved at the same
time,
like technologically spectacularly evolve
to the point where we can bend matter
and create nuclear weapons and fly robots
to Mars and take pictures and send it
back to us.
Like the shit that we could do is
off the charts when it comes to like
technology and our ability to manipulate
the world around us and create giant
buildings and structures and
airplanes and bridges and shit.
But the monkey interaction
thing is still not very good,
so we still have war.
We still have places where we send
people over with metal tanks and guns and
shoot people and protect people from the
other people that are shooting people
and get involved in all these fucking
crazy things are physical interactions as
organisms are just still
in this barbaric stage.
We're still in this one tribe going after
another tribe stage from 20,000 years
ago, 30,000 years ago. It's
like the same programming,
but now this programming can fly jets
filled with missiles and shoot them out of
the sky. Sneak up on you underwater
in a metal tube, a submarine.
It shoots fucking nuclear with
missiles and shit underwater.
I mean we're in the weirdest flux.
We're in this weird sort of unbalanced
period in the evolution of the human
organism because we can do so much and
then put Donald's in charge man about
fucking everything.
We're mad about men who decide they're
women who want to use the girls' room.
We're mad about everything.
We're about about religion.
We're mad about rights and gender and
everything. Everything. We're mad,
everyone's mad. Fuck Roseanne
Barr, everyone's bad.
Everyone is so mad and while all this
is all this weird personal interaction,
shit is happening that's
distracting the fuck out of us.
The more it ramps up the the better.
Ai gets our foot artificial intelligence
because it gets just keep working on it
and keep getting better and better.
We're going to be in like a full on rock
fight. When AI goes live, it's like,
it's like we're, we're falling into
this whole, like if this was a trap,
if I was artificial intelligence
and I knew how to be like,
well as what we'll do is just go back
in time and set people up and make them
make us.
We'll just plant this idea in their heads
and just like an aquatic worm makes a
caterpillar or one of those grasshoppers
rather jump into a pool and drowned
itself so that it could
swim out of its brain.
You ever see one of those things happen
just like that. Ai is doing that with us.
They give us Shiny Samsung Galaxy note
nine look at how big the whole pottery is
and now it takes photos of
your face and knows your face.
They can tell you face to face id and
fingerprints and before you know it,
listen, we found the best way to
get a signal to talk. People there,
you just stick it in your ass.
It's a little palate.
We're going to put our little robot Dick
in our ass, a little pepper that pellet.
If you could just hold in your ass.
It's smooth.
Do you barely know what's in there? But
it connects with your, your ass is open.
It's not like the rest of your skin
and y'all got to keep it in your mouth.
Right. Well to ask is the way to
go cause it's like open, you know,
it's not like you don't have to go
through the dermis and so that just just
connects with you and you can
fucking see augmented reality.
But the little tiny robot dick, it's
about that big. You barely feel it.
It's like a BB. Uh, that's what's
going to happen dude. Fucking prior.
I do. These things are growing
or not the anti aging shit too.
Who knows how crazy that's going to get.
I think with the weirdest
thing is not the anti aging.
I think that we're going to run
into biological limitations.
I think the weirdest shit is gene editing.
Fuck yeah.
It's took a turn for the stoner
gene editing scares the shit out of me.
Was that unexplained on the explain
that new Netflix, Netflix show,
gene editing and how did that shit's
going to go wild wild country.
I only watched the first episode,
but I was like, Holy Shit,
I see where this is going
to follow show baby.
Fuck everyone man.
As far as tech and I'm like,
it takes a turn,
but I'm sure he still had good intentions.
I think trying to build the community,
I'm just passionate about
us. Again, this is the thing,
it's the fucking human interaction part
is the part that we can't get right.
It's real weird.
If you look at all the different kinds
of interactions that we managed to
successfully navigate and me,
people have obviously have problems in
business and there's lawsuits in business
and there's people that get fired and
there's all sorts of problems with people
doing business, but overall they
get a lot of things done right.
Like business keeps improving.
Things keep getting better.
We barely improve with
how we treat each other,
like the way human
beings treat each other.
We barely get better at that and
we do react to things better.
Like,
if we're mad at someone for doing
something that's like more clear with like
agregious violations of our code, right?
Like racism, like this Roseanne thing,
it was a big one, right? Everybody
was like, no fucking way.
We're not tolerating that. Fuck
her. And then ABC like, Yo, fuck it.
We're pulling the plug on the show.
It's like immediate reactions. Yep.
So it's like what I, what I'm,
I don't think it was right.
I think she's got a lot of problems and
she's taken a shit load of pills and she
was all fucked up. And I know she's
not racist. At least she tells me that.
But what I do know is that racism is
horrible and people just don't want to
tolerate it anymore.
And that's what the good thing is.
The good thing is like this,
right?
There's overwhelming response from
people that they're not tolerating racism
anymore. You can't do that
anymore. We won't tolerate it.
And this is fairly new man.
I mean with the civil rights marches,
that was in the 60s right?
I mean,
think about what was going on in the
50s and the forties and fed that shit.
That was not that long ago in terms
of like how long there's been people.
So we're dealing with this
radical change in this regard,
but very little change in like
our kindness to each other. Yeah,
that's right. Did start the American
mushroom day or not the American,
the worldwide. Are you sure fear has a
holiday that he created called true fast?
Yeah. It's several days are
doesn't fuck around our,
he has had a real job since he was
the doorman at the comedy store.
He operates on its own schedule.
That's,
that's what it's going to take for
something like that worldwide to change.
It'll certainly help cause shrimp fest
certainly out she's rooms will help.
I'm promoting that.
But I feel like I'm,
part of it is because we're scared.
I legitimately feel like we're scared.
And I think when someone
like Trump is in office,
we're more scared because we
realize how easy it is for, uh,
you know,
I hate to use the term regular
person cause he's definitely
not a regular person.
He's very successful and very famous
and everybody knew who he was,
but regular person in terms of we don't,
that's not how it politician acts like
that. This is like some crazy show man.
And when a crazy show man
becomes the leader of the thing,
whether or not he's doing good is it,
I'm not even arguing politically whether
it's doing good or bad or the economy's
up because of him. I don't know.
But it's just how he behaves.
It's who he is like that
that freaks people out. That
makes people more on edge.
And so they're more angry and
they're, they're, they're,
they're more looking to call people out
on things and they're more looking to
stomp out racism.
I get it.
Imagine what people would think if
someone like Sam Harris was a precedent or
something.
He was talking about a national mushroom
day are talking about that stuff.
How bad people would freak out.
Seriously.
They would freak or are they just people
that disagree with Sam too? You know,
there's a ton of very, very smart
people that disagree with Sam, you know,
and it's really interesting
to see those disagreements.
Cause when really high level intellects
debate each other about things or
disagree on things and you get to see
not just their ideas play out and how
their ideas work against the other
person's ideas. You get to see that,
but you also get to see like thinking and,
and, and, and communicating
at a super high level, right?
They're intellectuals are
trying to outsmart each other
so that they're debating
about, you know, the existence of
God or whatever the fuck it is.
When you get really smart people who
disagree on Shit. Very fascinating.
It's like one of the more interesting
things to watch. So like in a lot of ways,
high level Jujitsu, you know, and a lot
of ways you're watching like, oh, okay.
And those guys, a lot of them get into
like, Harris is in a Jujitsu, is he? Yeah.
I think that's one of the
reasons why he's into it.
It's cause he's kind of doing Jujitsu
when he's, when he's doing these debates.