You see fit. Paris is going crazy right
now given having these crazy riots. No.
What's up?
Every time I think about visiting Paris,
there's some new shit
that goes down over there.
I know it's kind of feels
like a little like a,
like a jewel box is about to
explode all that good man.
It's not good. Is it
workers? What kind of riot?
Well the weird thing is everyone
is riding is wearing those.
I'm reflective vests. Like
see that? Yeah, that's, Yup.
They're wearing these yellow reflective
vest and lighting things on fire and
smashing store. So like who is
Gucci inch? These? These protesters.
They've been going scroll backups.
When we got violent it says 17 pictures.
Oh, it's terrible. And it keeps
getting worse. It keeps getting worse.
I mean it started November 17th when
French driver sporting yellow vests let a
demonstration apparently has to do with
oil prices rising. Rising fuel prices,
280,000 people. Four people have
died. Hundreds have been injured.
Thousands of dollars for the
property has been damaged.
The protest has started in
November 17th from French drivers.
Sporting yellow vests,
led a demonstration of 280,000 people
across the country to push back against
the rising taxes on gas and diesel at,
uh,
French president in Menu Ed crown.
I love a nice McCrone as part of his
many economic reforms announced the gas
taxes early this year to minimize
Francis reliance on fossil fuels.
That's a fucking shitty way to handle,
you know, reliance on fossil fuels.
You do the opposite. You can't face, well
actually, you don't charge people money.
You know,
you don't charge people extra money and
make it more expensive than they'll use
it. The less you give them subsidies for
electric cars, you stupid prick. Yes.
Don't you understand the American
way you piece of shit, Jesus.
I love talking like, well, they left
Arteta about things I know nothing about.
What does it say? [inaudible] black up
there. Scroll back to where it was, uh,
the price of fuel. That's it. 30
cents of gout and they went crazy.
30 cents a gallon of
trying to kill people.
Gas already costs about $7 per gallon.
What friends?
Fuck that man.
So it's just going to break people's
backs and they drive you to their bread.
Sean Bush was leaving office and they
jacked the fucking price of gas way up,
dude. But there's people that
were panicking, you know,
September 11th there's like lines
everywhere. Cause we thought right, empty.
That's right. Yeah. But
then the price didn't,
I don't think the price randomly went up.
Some places charge charging like
25 bucks a gallon. Assholes.
They should go to jail.
But that's,
that's kind of insane that people
use to have riots like that. When,
when we would spike and people
couldn't eat well looking at this,
they were like in cars. The God,
that's a shitty little car. Anyway,
I probably wanted to light
it on fire. Finally. He's
not even part of the protest.
He's just.