Her low freak bitches. Yeah.
And the idea that I know,
I know I lived in the city since I was
18 so I've been around gays for a quarter
century and I think of these guys I know
that had been together for 10 years and
I go, so let me get this straight. This,
these two are gonna break up according
to you and evangelical person.
And then they're just going to make out
with some chick with blonde hair and eat
her out and like fucker and
have a boner and pray to God.
Come on. You know, that won't happen. I,
I wonder how much of
homosexual behavior could be,
uh, induced by molestation
in early age though. Yeah,
that's the million dollar question. That
seems to be a real factor. It's not,
and this is not the nine
people that are born gay,
but I think there's a spectrum and I
think there's most certainly some gay acts
that are committed on young people and
horrifically those people tend to on a
pretty frequent basis do the same
thing to other young kids, young kids.
Really Weird in in, in terms of like
the victims becoming the victimizer.
Yeah.
I know where you're going with this.
We're walking into the elephant
in the room, but what kind of,
not even mean just just talking about,
I was listening to the George to Chi
interview today because they're trying to
pull up everybody now that
the Milo thing is out there,
they're pulling up everybody who in any
way it has condoned sex with underage
people.
And George to Kai was talking about his
own experiences in camp and it was on
stern show and he was just
talking about what he,
the way he was describing it as a positive
experience with a kid who was in his
late teens,
I think he said it was 19 and he
was like 13 somewhere in that age.
And you know, it's absolutely child
molestation. It's absolutely illegal.
But the way he was describing it,
he was pretty much describing it
as a positive experience. Right?
Which when it's your experience,
I mean it's illegal. The guy did
something that was against the law.
But boy,
that's a weird area because
it's his experience. And
he was talking about, yeah,
well here's the deal and
this is a mistake Milo made.
You have to acknowledge that what you're
talking about is fucked up and horrible
and wrong,
but you just so happen to have not had a
bad experience within those parameters.
Like say you were raped as
a woman and you came, right?
Uh, which by the way happens
for some strange reason.
So if you're one of those women in,
you're about to say that you have to
understand that we're going into a very
dangerous place right now.
And you can't say, look,
some rapes are absolutely fabulous
and women have come from them.
You have to say, this is
fucking horrible. Rape is evil.
But I buy some weird freak of nature
actually liked it. Or a murderer.
I'm sure there's times when you
murdered a guy and he ended up,
he was a mass murder and it was a
good murder. Right? And you go, okay,
I'm describing a murder.
I'm not condoning murderer.
But in this weird case it
worked and Milo's mistake
was he said it worked for me
and then he implied that it could work
for a ton of other gays to be fucked at
13. Well he did that, um,
a drunken peasants podcast and his take
on it from the drunken peasants was
different than his take on it from mine.
And on my podcast it seemed more like
he was trying to make light of something
that most likely definitely did happen
to him. The father Michael thing.
So there's two,
there's the father Michael thing and I,
I don't know if I believe that.
I think that's just a,
I've heard him say that joke
a few times where he's like,
I'd never would have given such good head
if it wasn't for Father Michael. Right.
So you think that might be something
like that he's constructed?
I don't believe it. I don't
know why. That's just my gut.
And then the other thing was condoning
sexual relationships with 13 year olds
and he said,
especially in the gay world,
now I know of straight guys
who were a straight guy.
I'm thinking of in particular who was
molested at camp and it was by an older
gay camp counselor.
This guy thinks of that guy every day,
falls him on linkedin hoping he'll
die. He wants to murder him. Uh,
so the problem with what Milo said is you
end up normalizing is behavior and say
it's okay if in the gay world,
next thing you know,
some older gay who's at Camp Goes, well
this is probably a fag that I'm blowing.
Right. So this is, okay. Yeah.
So what I say to these gays,
these 13 year old gates to go, I would
be okay with fucking a 29 year old. I go,
well, I'm sorry, but we're not
normalizing that because the vast,
vast majority of times it doesn't
turn out well. So No. Yeah,
that's a very good way of putting it. You
know, and it's, it's really disturbed.
Well, the Milo thing is so
odd because first of all,
I think he's got this act and let's call
it an act cause part of it has got to
be an act. He's got a wide spectrum of
his personalities. So on Bill Maher,
he can be a raging Liberace queen with
pearls on dress like a woman. I mean,
just like a woman. Yeah. Camper
than any woman I know. Yeah.
And then for the apology, he's the
conservative with the coke bottle glasses.
It's sort of like when a Jamaican who
goes back to Jamaica and they start
speaking in Patois, like their
grandmother and not necessarily lying.
It's just a wide range of use.
Yeah. He plays it up and there it,
there's definitely a performance piece
to a lot of what he does. What's,
what's really interesting is he's
very good at riling people up.
He's obviously very good at getting
people upset, and in doing so,
he's created these sort of false
narratives about him, that he's a Nazi,
that he promotes genocide.
I mean,
there were so many people outside the
Berkeley thing that were screaming,
calling them a Nazi and saying he's a
fascist when they in fact were behaving in
very authoritarian,
fascist ways.
That's Antifa. By the way, you
said, I don't know what Antifa is.
That's those guys antifascist is that
what Antifa stands for? But you're right,
they're terrorists and they use terror.
They use violence to
achieve political gains,
which is terrorism and a these people,
it's not like Milo ever set or Trump
even ever said anything that is remotely
close to genocide,
but those guys just go.
Anyone that wants to enforce
immigration laws is a fucking Nazi.
So I need violence cause
I'm trying to stop Hitler.
I'm around the first stages of Hitler,
so I'm going back in time and strangling
him in his crib kind of. Right.
But the problem is the way
they're reacting to it is
the absolute wrong way to
react to someone who sang something
that you don't agree with. Oh yeah.
The the right way is to say something
that you feel opposes what they're saying.
It makes more sense to debate them.
That's the beauty of free speech.
Like it has no limits. If you want to
get out there and deny the Holocaust,
you want to get out there and
sexualized toddlers all go to your talk.
I want to hear it. And then in the Q
and a, I'll shoot you down. Well, not,
I don't think it even
should just be a Q and a.
I mean I think it should
be real clear other there,
there should be someone and they,
we shouldn't just rely on the audience
to come up with some sort of a response.
I think if you're going to have someone
as controversial as Milo and you are so
opposed to it that you're willing to
throw bricks through Starbucks windows and
light cop cars on fire,
there should be someone that can speak
for your side and then you should
organize some sort of a talk.
But this is setting it up
the wrong way because you go,
it's like someone said to
me once, hey man, you know,
like we were talking about
martial arts flows, black belt,
I'd fucking kick everybody's ass. No you
wouldn't. No, you wouldn't. First of all,
you wouldn't because you'd have discipline
and you'd realize the consequences of
that. But second of all, when you
just kick someone's ass, they don't,
they don't just take it like they come
back with a bat or a gun or their brother,
you started fighting.
They want to get it back.
And it goes back and forth and back and
forth and all conflict pretty much goes
that way.
You have conflict and then
someone responds to that
conflict and it escalates.
So if you have this thing where you
start throwing bricks through windows and
light and cop cars on fire and stopping
people from talking and hitting people
that have a make bitcoin great again,
hats and just see that girl got
maced in the face by a 60 year olds.
Eventually people show up with guns.
That's what happens.
And this is what happens when you keep
escalating the violence. You become them,
you become the other,
you become the enemy and you create this
polarizing atmosphere that's so intense
that no dialogue's kind of fix
it now because you're the enemy.
We are talking about the north versus
the south. You're, you're talking about,
you know, the, the Protestants
versus the Catholics. You, you,
you create this horrific environment
where almost it's almost impossible to
avoid violence. Well, so I'm done
avoiding it. I'm taking the low road,
I'm punching them in the face. So that's
what you're doing with this outfit? Yes.
That is really what I'm doing with stuff.
But I did a talk at Nyu.
They pepper sprayed me. Did
they read, when was this?
This was a couple of weeks ago.
What did, what was it talk about?
I didn't even have a plan.
I was, they know me as pro
Trump or something and they,
they, I'm a Nazi because
of that and they should,
they don't want to give a
platform to free speech.
That's the irony of all this is they
pretend that it's gotten so far.
It's beyond debate now in their world.
We are recruiting fascists for
some sort of imminent genocide.
So we're like signing up the brown shirts
with a form at our talks and you go
say that was possible. Uh, how does
that work? Like we sign you up,
then you're part of the club. Then
you come with us on the next genocide.
The fuck are you talking about?
You haven't even played it through in
your mind because for these people it's a
religion. That's why they don't want
to debate. It's like a born again.
He doesn't want to debate
about the existence of God.
He's already on that side.
So what was your plan when you went there?
What did, what did you want to talk?
I was going to say,
uh, this Nazi that, uh,
that you made Milo and I out to be who
wants genocide and who sees nonwhites is
inhuman, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
homophobic, sexist, whatever. Uh,
first of all, that guy should be
allowed to talk if he existed,
but he doesn't exist.
Your monster is a mythical beast
and you've gone to college,
you're 60 grand in debt already to fight
this mythical beast who doesn't fucking
exist. Well, in terms of
Milo, he definitely doesn't
exist. Milo is not a Nazi.
He's definitely,
he's not promoting genocide.
And those are two things that just
get trumpeted about left and right.
Exactly who is,
but Milo has said some very inflammatory
things about and in a very generalizing
way about women and about the wage gap
and about all sorts of things that he,
he designs his words and his
phrases to be inflammatory.
So he gets the most response and
it's been incredibly profitable.
I mean up until Harper
Collins pulled his book deal,
he got a $250,000 book advance.
His book was number one on Amazon.
Just sheerly through controversy.
Yup.
I mean through presales and controversy.
So it's a strategy and a lot of ways
and it's also a response to this really
hard stance that the far left is taking
this anti anti free speech stance.
Right. But always with these cases
you go, what exactly did he say?
I always say this to people who
bitch about it. And Coulter, I go,
what sentence in what book
is factually incorrect?
What specifically are you saying?
And with this Milo thing,
he said that often sexual relationships
with 13 year olds can be beneficial for
gays. Uh, he has since
retracted that and apologized,
but that's not enough. And that's
about as, as egregious as it gets.
The other stuff that he says,
we all say in a joking way and then that
becomes pure evil and you advocate for
this, right? So the left is willfully
ignorant of humor when it comes to Milo.
And with Trump too,
you know,
within culture is doing is very similar
to what Milo is doing. You mean their,
their merchants of outrage and that's
what they're doing. I disagree.
I think they're speaking in a
hyperbolic tone. They're flamboyant.
But that's what the charter
was still there. Yes, there's,
there's definitely some truth,
especially with Milo that
some of the things that he
says. Um, but it's all truth.
What, what? Like again, I'm
saying it right now. What,
what did he say this factually incorrect?
Well, there wasn't a joke, not,
not factually incorrect,
but extremely offensive to people
like the 13 year old boy comment.
Like the thing about sort of normalizing
relationships between grown men and 13
year old boys,
you know,
I think a big part of why he even says
that is because he's in many ways like a
natural contrarian and in many ways a guy
who wants to get a rise out of people.
And by saying that he didn't feel
like there's any consequences to being
outrageous in that regard.
Right.
But I think we could both agree whether
or not it's factual. In his case,
it's a fucked up thing to say,
right. As a fucked up thing to say.
It was negligent,
which is why I apologize,
but I think the grain of truth to
that and with his other statements,
there's a lot more than the grain, but
the grant of truth to what he was saying,
his gaze have less
chastity than straights.
And if a woman is known as a slut,
she's less likely to be picked up.
And I've been sued for calling a woman
a slut. Where are you really? Yup.
Who Sued you? It was a long
time ago. Back in vice days,
it was going to do's and don'ts and the,
the way the law is,
it's kind of antiquated,
but it's like, oh,
you called her a slut now she won't
have currency in the market of marriage
because she's known as a whore,
so we're going to punish you punitively
for this sin. Did you have to settle?
Yeah. God dammit. You
can't call someone a slut.
There's no word for a man.
No,
I cad. That's a compliment. That's
hilarious. Yeah. A cat is hilarious. Well,
the fact that there's no equivalent for
a man shows you that there's a different
standard.
And then with gays it is different to
like 13 year old and an older person,
right?
If it's a girl and a 40 year old teacher,
I want to take him to the parking
lot and beat him till he has a weird,
he walks weird. He was life.
If it's a woman in a boy, uh,
I don't want to murder her.
I'm grossed out 13,
especially 14 little better.
And then with gays,
uh, well I'm not gonna make the
same mistake Milo made right now.
Don't ever do it. But if a gaze,
no one has a sled in the future,
like say a 19 year old fucks,
200 people as a woman,
no one wants to go near as a gay.
You've been around the block. Yeah,
no, there's not the same consequences for
sure. And I, I had a bit of my act about,
I don't know if you
remember this commercial,
but there was a commercial adjust for men
commercial where there was a baby that
was driving a Porsche,
a baby with a beard and there was a
grown woman next to the baby and the baby
has like a Tuxedo on and it's like
you've always wanted the biggest bet,
his beard and the baby goes to the
nightclub and a bouncer looks at him and
winks. I'm like look at this, look at this
commercial. [inaudible] see the babies.
Yeah.
So the baby walks in just for men.
I mean I don't know what
the fuck just for men,
if you don't know it is some stuff that
guys put in their yard when they're
getting old. So this baby's got a
bottle, he out to the dance floor.
There's all these girls with these tiny
little skirts dancing around him and
he's like, he's like a pimp
and he's with this hot woman.
And this to me my bit was this is
proof, positive proof, positive.
There's no sexual equality when
it comes to child molesting.
Cause if you even wrote that
down with the is reversed.
If you even wrote it down, you're
fucking going to jail. Okay.
There's a little baby girl and she
goes out to a room full of guys who are
wearing Tarzan skirts and they're all
swinging dicks around her and she's got a
bottle and they're all fighting for her
attention and kissing her on the cheek.
You would go to fucking jail.
But that was a commercial that
aired on mainstream television.
No one cared about it. That commercial
air for years, it's probably still on now.
And that commercial is proof positive
that we have a completely different
attitude towards a grown woman
who's hot as fuck and a little baby.
Yeah, well even I was watching big with
the kids the other day. Tom Hanks is what?
Eight in that movie?
Nine and then that woman seduces
him and I guess he fucks her.
He gets a boner and I'm like,
you're raping a child. Exactly.
Why are we watching? And she's hot.
She's hot and he looks like a man.
So I just let it ride.
If that movie was reversed and it was a,
a young girl that all of a sudden was
in a sexual woman's body and the guy was
fucking her. She's like, I don't know.
Are we supposed to be doing this?
You would be horrified. You would be
absolutely horrified. These protests,
especially the things
like the Milo protest,
I mean maybe now that Milo
has been humiliated and it
at least temporarily side
tracked or put down for a
bit while he has to rebuild.
Maybe someone can come along and have
reasonable dialog and do some sort of a
campus be I don't like, why is he doing
these things on campuses? First of all,
I don't think he gets paid for most of
them. What my theory with Milo is a,
I think his eyesight's getting worse.
His glasses are getting thicker
and thicker and he sorta going,
this is my moment to make an impact.
So he's just like,
you think he's going blind? I think so,
yeah. Where do you just theorizing this?
Yeah, he's only like 28 yeah,
but you look at him, he's,
he just can't read English because
they're insane. Really. Yeah.
And they're getting thicker. Maybe it's
stress, stress, making his eyes worse.
Um, I don't know. I'm not a doctor.
I can't think it would be
good. But I think he's trying
to make a maximum impact,
uh, in a short amount of time cause you
think he doesn't have much time left.
That's such a way he seems healthy
weight. In fact, when we were in Orlando,
we made out at the site of the,
uh,
you guys made out Milo to offend Muslims.
Wow.
So I said,
I did a big speech about freedom and
funny taste in this America delicious like
strawberries.
Well at least he freshens breath up
before no gaze just tastes better.
I said,
fuck is lamb.
And then we made out at the site of the
Orlando shooting to know only Muslims,
but we had armed guards and
stuff. And I said, all right,
I want to make sure these guys are scoping
out the rooms and shit. And he goes,
I don't care if I die, I'll happily die
for this. I was like, well, I do care.
Actually. I've got three kids. What
does, is it Neil Ism or nihilism?
I always say it wrong. I
always say nihilism, nihilism,
that nihilistic sort of
instinct that he has.
He has a burn it all down instinct and I
think he has that with his life as well.
And I think a lot of that,
um,
I'm playing some serious bro
psychologist here, you know,
some I armchair psychology from
someone totally unqualified.
But you've got to attribute that to,
and at least in some ways
being molested as a child.
I would imagine that his experiences that
he's calling positive experiences when
he was young,
in many ways those could have potentially
damaged him and also being young and
being homosexual and being rejected,
all of those things wreck havoc.
And you develop this, fuck
you, I want to burn it down.
And this is one of the strategies that
he sort of adopted that strategy to be
this guy who is very difficult
for like he's, he's gay.
He's um, uh, an English gay
guy who's a right winger.
I mean it's, it's so baffling to
them. They don't know what to do.
They hate it because they see blacks.
And gays as their little pets,
and they like putting them on the front
lines and going liquid who were helping.
And then when one of them
defects to the other side,
they become particularly outraged,
but very few defect at the level
that he's defected. Right. I mean,
he turned around and started
attacking direct guy.
Okay.