The Joe Rogan experience.
I remember what he went on
stage in New York after nine 11.
Who did Richard Gere did and uh,
was trying to tell the audience
that they should choose love.
And that went on state
state where on stage she,
he was on stage at some sort of a
benefit. Oh, right. After nine 11.
It was right after nine 11. And he
was saying essentially that, you know,
great message was at the time people
were just bloodthirsty and they booed him
and they're like, fuck you. Fuck you.
He's basically saying let's
not have military action.
More people shouldn't die because of
some things that these people did to us.
He's saying try to figure out a different
way to do this. Yeah. I mean he's, he's,
he's a Buddhist I believe.
I mean, he's like,
he's really close pals with
the Dalai Lama. Yeah. But, but,
but in the interest of talking
about what we're talking about,
revenge means a lot.
It's kind of hard to tell America to
not get revenge on somebody. Right.
We love revenge. Well, yeah.
Well, we love getting back.
People that have tried to fuck with us,
even if we go,
even if we go way deeper than they did
were warlike monkeys. Yeah, we love it.
We we,
we,
when we think we're being attacked
like retribution and revenge is,
well we're just talking about
earlier about like chimps.
Chimps do that too. Yeah,
natural. It's nature. Nature,
nature. You want to get revenge.
Motherfuckers like we were talking about
that guy and got ripped apart by the
chimp rent to bring a birthday cake.
Dude.
See the other chimps that did
it because they were jealous.
They were angry that that jealous of
chanting this compassion didn't get shit
and someone fucked up and left the gate
open and they came out fuck that dude up.
Ripped his limbs off toward his face part.
Just because he wouldn't give them,
didn't bring cake for them. Where
they female chimps. No, there are man,
where's my cake?
Losing it.
Cake must be so must've been good as
fucking cake to a chimp that doesn't
understand what cake is.
Like how the fuck did you do this?
But they do understand what cake is.
Why will they understand it once you get
it to them, to gem. Yeah. It's something,
it's,
that's like a powerful orb you brought
that tell you when we were in Costa Rica
and uh, there's, there's monkeys
everywhere there. It's crazy cool, cool.
Last monkeys, but they're
a little sketchy. I know.
I got married down there and oh, he did it
Costa Rica. Yeah, yeah, yeah. They're out.
They're out of their fucking mind. We
were hanging out with them and, uh,
there's a thing called a quad a
Monday. You know what that is? No,
they look like a,
like a raccoon monkey
thing to weird creature.
Runkee and uh,
they would come up,
we were staying at this resort and they
would just come right down the pathway
to where your, uh, your door to your room
was, had they just hang out with you.
Like these quad Monday's just hang out
and you can feed them grapes and shit.
They would take them right out of
your hands, but like no danger at all.
They were like super chill and friendly.
So we gave this quad on Monday,
some grapes, and then he laid down
and took a nap under my chair.
I just took a fucking nap,
like a dog, like a dog,
like the most chill dog of all time. I'm
like, God damn, these things are cool.
Like we were just sitting
there. Just check. Oh, go ahead
buddy. Tickets, take a nap.
You're safe here.
I gave him some grapes and shit.
People want them want chimps at
their house. People love the idea of,
of having them. So the monkeys
came over and we only had a,
that's what a quantum Monday looks
like, dude. They're the shit. There's,
there's such cool little animals.
It does kind of look raccoon ish.
My daughter's game of a fake name. Let
go. They were calling him a Kink, a chew.
They just decided to call it a
Kinkajou. What's more fun? Yeah,
they could choose their own word up,
I think.
I don't think that's a
real word a lot of Monday,
but that little little guy was so cool.
So she's an interesting little fella.
When you just gently take grapes
right out of your hand gently,
right the most chill dog of all time.
So anyway,
we were out of grapes and these
a monkey showed up and they're,
they're like hanging out like a little
looking like, what do you got for us?
These guys are hungry. No real month.
Oh, that's on a monkey. That's like, um,
I don't know what that is.
I don't know what it could water Monday
is what family is what is then anyway,
we gave these, uh, my, or like, I don't
know if we should give these monkeys,
these Oreos that's kind of fucked up.
Like it's not good for them.
So I'm going to look at, one of
them only had one hand. I'm like,
well that's not good for me to
fucking hand bit off. So I gave him,
gave him that,
he snatched it from me and he opened it
up and then started chewing the white
stuff off the cream. He's one of
us, but he already knew about,
he's probably begin Oreos for his whole
life from people that stay at the resort.
He knows the trick. Did he, outside of
hotdogs, he knew what the fuck to do. Oh,
will do let they make you at this.
You know, they're all open air houses.
You rent on the beach,
you know that everything,
everything's pretty open except for the
bedroom is the only thing that's closed
off.
And they had latched locks,
padlocks on the refrigerator. And I was
like, what are you guys lock that up?
And they're like, the monkeys know
how to get into all that shit.
They know how to open the door and
they know how to get in the drawers.
He's like, dude, they knew how to,
they know how to open up egg cartons.
They know how to open the lid and take
eggs and close the lid. I'm not kidding.
He's like, they're that smart.
So in the middle of the night,
the first night that we were there,
I hear that gate kind of rustling and
then I hear movement and I'm like,
someone's in the fucking house cause
it's on the beach. It's wide open.
So of course I like grabbed something is
the biggest thing I could find next to
me. I'm out there. I'm
like, Hey, hey, you know,
like a nut bag in my fucking daughter.
I'm yelling. Of course I look it.
They're just monkeys chilling,
trying to like get shit in the house.
They're trying to find shit laying
around food, drinks, whatever it was.
And of course I go back to bed and every
night I would hear them come and go.
But you'd hear them try the refrigerator.
You would hear him pulling on it to
see if the latch was like if we left it
unlocked. They're smart,
they learn, they learn,
they learn all the little tricks
of where you put stuff. Cabinets.
I could hear a cabinet opening and
closing. Yeah, there were smart man.
That's so weird. It's like a
little person. It is almost
a little sneaky. Yeah.
There's a little person fuck use.
And they,
and they put purposely up up in
this place that I was at, um,
they purposely string wire
from house to house to house.
So the monkeys kind of cad freedom to go
up above because if they would go down
by the road, it would cause more traffic
and disturbances and all that stuff.
So they keep them up in the canopy.
So they put rope purposely house to house
and tree to tree that humans put up.
So they have easier pathways to get
down to the water because they say when
they're down on the ground, it's
more distracting. There's, you know,
it's a lot harder to drive. They,
they create little message down below.
So if they keep them up high, it's
better for them. It was crazy man.
What a wild little creature.
They can swing from tree to tree and
they fly up and down the tree tops like
that. There's got him hanging from Shit.
Just one most like people. Sometimes you,
I'd see one just hang and it'd be
staring right at you. Almost like people,
they're so good. They're the right
fucking there. Well the weirdest,
the weirdest thing is that if,
if evolution is happening all the time,
let's do this little monkey.
Is this in breaking into a
house? Yeah. Watch. Watch US
watch how smart. Look here.
Give me those chips. I love
these fucking chips. I love that.
It looks like he's looking right at
the person too. Yeah, he is. Oh Wow.
And he just takes off with the chips.
Do they know which ones they feed them?
They know what you want to say.
Like guys, just be nice to him.
What happens if you feed them? You can't
know. They tell you not to feed them.
What happens?
Because while then they
know to keep coming back and
where they can get food for
like monkeys. No, they say if the
NAV and they say if you don't,
if you show when you stop feeding
them after you fed them enough,
then they start to get aggressive.
So then you shoot one and kill them,
send a message,
right.
And then they all come back and kill you
a lot of fucking 12 gauge and you blow
the little face off one of those cuts
and you make your draw and you go, hey,
you guys want free food. You'll
get it. But you get it on my terms.
Monkey go back inside. You just described
a plot for a planet of the apes.
It's literally like the plot from Vietnam.
He hooked you get them hooked. Yeah.
You Bait that I'm hooked on
food. Yeah. You Bait them.