No, it's a different era. You
have to accept as a different era.
You just, people were different. Look,
people are changing and it's a really
interesting obvious sign that things that
were super acceptable.
And when was this in living color?
I want to say it was like (929)
029-0490 two [inaudible] 94 yeah.
So that the way you could do certain bits
and what you get away with and put on
television, it was just different.
So I think that's one of the,
like probably one of the least understood
things that's happening with us with
social media is as the rapid
evolution of what's acceptable,
not acceptable anymore. And it's changing
very quickly. In terms of subjects,
in terms of the way you approach things,
in terms of like obvious
bigotry or obvious bias,
it's like it's all
getting very highlighted.
Well the,
I think the big question is whether or
not you see an artist as somebody who's
taking their inner vision and putting
it out and you go for the ride or you
don't.
Or is it,
are we supposed to be representing society
in our standup or is it all supposed
to be fair,
balanced representations of
different ethnic groups and genders?
You know, and it's like, when did it
all have to become a morality tale?
When did every depiction of every
race have to be fair? You know,
can't you have an asshole who's black?
Can't you have a killer who's gay
without it becoming a depiction of that
entire, you know, subgroup?
Yeah.
It's like w w what are our real
problem is that prejudice does exist.
So when it does exist, you kind of look
for it and things and you say, hey,
this has the characteristics of prejudice.
I see this here.
I see what you're doing here that I think
this is prejudice. And we say, no, no, no.
This is making fun of Puerto Rican men.
This is not prejudice. Yeah. This is,
uh,
an account of real occurrences
that I've turned into humor.
Yeah. The, the flamboyant
masculinity of Puerto Rican men.
I mean like in New York,
like that's if you,
if you thought of a type
of a Latino sort of, uh,
the bravado, you know, the music,
the food, everything spicy.
If you can't make fun of that,
come on.
I Know Collin Quinn does a whole
thing about how racist, right?
Puerto Ricans who never inside or outside,
they're always both.
There's always a window open. People
on the inside and outside of talking,
the car door is always open. They're
half in the car. They're half right.
This isn't racist. This is
observation. Can I take an option?
Can I tell you that yesterday,
about twice a week I go to this Japanese
market in Mar Vista and they've got all
different kinds of, uh, you know,
you can get Sushi tempura whatever the
parking lot for this place because 80% of
the people that are Asian film it and
put it on a fucking television channel.
It is, it is just people.
Why don't you produce it?
I could announce it like I was Adj Foy.
You're an Emmy award winning writer.
You could actually do something like that.
He was like a legit writer,
you could totally produced that.
Can you imagine announced it like Nascar.
It's just people like not getting how
to get out of a parking spot with us
taking like eight k turns and people on
the wrong side of the street and backing
up without looking over the shoulders
and they're all Asian and it's fucking
hilarious. I didn't, I didn't tell them
to do it. I didn't say it was wrong,
but it's happening.
Yeah. Dave explained it, um,
why it's a stereotype,
but why also why Asian people would,
um, be more likely to walk
straight. And you know,
like if you, if you go to a China or if
you go to any of those, uh, Asian company,
uh, Asian countries, when people
walk straight at each other,
they all kind of have this way of touching
and they just, there's so many people,
they're just grinding past each
other, right? So, yeah. Yeah.
So when you're in China in particular,
people are like indifferent to bumping
into you. It doesn't bother them at all.
They just bump into you.
Like if you're in the aisle of a plane,
they just bump into you.
Yeah. Like they'll do it.
The little kids just walk right through
it. Right. It's just, that's how they did.
It's not rude, just like how's culturally
different because it's more crowded.
Why can't you comment on that?
Or could you comment on that?
If that's a real thing. Cause that is
a real thing. They do do that. Yeah.
They also do a lot of great stuff.
I mean, it's not like you're not,
it's a negative judgment on the
entire race because they have this one
characteristic. But to ignore
that one characteristic
seems crazy. Yeah. It's like,
why can't I talk about
something like I'm not,
it's not mean I'm not a bad person to
talk about a real thing that you see and I
see.
Yeah. Like what is that? I get,
I can't booed on stage sometimes.
Now that never used to happen for
what? What'd he say? I did a joke.
We don't have to say the joke,
but just like, I'll say it,
I don't care because I don't think it's
offensive, but this, but this person did.
And it was, uh, you know, I, I go, oh,
it's girl, it's girl scout cookie season.
Those little horrors are out there
popping up their tables wherever you are
selling those stale, shitty, overpriced.
But you buy them cause it makes you
feel good. Like you're a good person,
you know?
And then you walk through the parking
lot in some black kid comes up with a box
of snickers gone, hey, we use support
my basketball team. And you're like,
that's a fucking scamps
guy goes, Ooh, they're
not all skin. I'm like,
that's not what we're
saying. Stupid. Yeah.