The last thing that I definitely
wanted to talk to you about,
it's one of the things that Trump
brought up recently is the, uh,
JFK case and releasing some of the
files and they wanted to redact the
information that pertained to
the people that were still alive.
Now I want to know what, what,
I don't know what you could say,
but what do you think about the JFK case?
Do you think that Lee
Harvey Oswald acted alone?
Um,
I can see
of all the,
of all the sort of incidents of all it is,
I don't mean to minimize it, but, or I
minimize it by calling it an incident.
But if all those situations,
the Kennedy assassination and Mlk,
Martin Luther King's assassination,
those are the two that I understand more
than anything else. Why they've linkerd,
why people don't believe the shit
that they've seen and why they,
why they have concerns about it. Uh,
Martin Luther King more than Kennedy,
I believe that there was something there
that we still don't understand in terms
of who else was responsible
and who organize that and
who, who assisted in that.
Right.
I just think of those two.
That's the one I've got bigger
questions on the Kennedy assassination.
I think that, uh, I think that
Oswald pulled the trigger.
I think in his mind,
uh,
the reason he was doing it
was for the greater good of,
of communism and to, uh, boost
his image with the Soviets and,
and, uh, w with the Cuban regime. Um,
do I think that he had assistance?
Um,
I don't, you know, I don't think so,
but I could be swayed from that with
better evidence than I've seen. But, um,
I understand why people are so dug in
on it, right? Because I mean, look,
it was a massive event,
right? It was a massive event,
but Oswald had sufficient training.
You did not have to be a rocket
scientist to figure this out.
It was a different era. And we don't
understand it in today's terms,
but when you get right in that position
and look out that window and look at the
shot that was taken and you know, what
was involved in that, I was not, uh,
you know, you've shot, you
know, this sounds terrible,
but you know, every, you know,
anybody who's hunted, you know, has taken
a more difficult shot in that. Yeah. Um,
so that part of it and,
and his motivation and his
past ties to the Soviets.
Do I think the Soviets were pulling the
trigger on it too? I think the mafia,
we're pulling the trigger.
I,
I haven't seen anything that
convinces me that that was the case.
I think that Oswald felt like he was
doing it for them or he was just,
he was going to prove himself in
that regard. But, uh, again, I,
I understand why people were dug in the
MLK one, Martin Luther King. I just, um,
I think that,
I don't think he acted alone.
What makes you think that?
Um, I think that, look, he was a loser,
a two bit criminal,
right?
Who was constantly getting picked up for
the shit that he was doing and ending
up in jail. Right? He was a mess, right.
There was nothing clever about him.
And then leading up to the assassination,
he cleaned up his act. Suddenly he went
from looking like a two bit, you know,
criminal and all to a
college professor basically.
And he had cash. He was able to, you know,
purchase a vehicle and he kind
of went off the grid for a while.
He went on to this drive,
right.
And sort of stayed off the grid and he
behaved in a way that he hadn't up until,
you know, months before this thing took
place. And then he ended up in Europe,
you know, and, um, I just, uh,
something tells me that he had, um, uh,
assistance in some fashion. I don't
know who right or whatever, but I just,
that's the one that more than, than any
others that I've looked at, you know,
makes me step back and go, no, we don't,
we don't know the whole story here. Um,
the Kennedy thing,
I again,
maybe there's something out there
that we just haven't turned over. A,
that's always a possibility.
But, um, yeah, MLK I think is a,
is that's the one that's most disturbing.
That's interesting.
I don't know enough about the MLK murder.
I need to go look into that now.
Especially if you think that something
was going on. Look at his behavior. Um,
what the hell was his name again?
James Earl. Ray. James Earl Ray and I,
I've talked to his brother, I've
interviewed his brother. Um, for what,
uh, for a shell, a series a
where we did a, uh, kind of, uh,
investigative look into this. Um, and um,
I there is, if you, if,
if all you do when you're,
when you're looking at this is to look
at Ray's behavior in that year leading up
to the assassination. Um, that's the,
that's the interesting for me, that's
the most interesting part. I mean,
put it in context with everything he
did up until that point, which was,
he was basically, again, just a tube
criminal, couldn't stay out of jail.
And then you get this and you get this
change in behavior and this change in
appearance in this, you know,
sudden ability to, you know, be, uh,
something that he wasn't up until that
point, I guess everybody can change.
But that was, that was the
most striking part for me. Um,
there's no obvious source of
income? No. No, just, just uh,
just to, you know, just again, just a
penny. Any criminal basically. And um,
there was plenty of information.
It wasn't like he couldn't have gathered
if you say, well no, he acted on his own.
Well. Okay. Yeah. Was
there information? Yes,
the leading right up till the day before
there was talk about, well, you know,
there were news reports showing a king
at the Lorraine Motel. Um, and you know,
coming in and out of the room,
you know, that he was staying in.
And so it wasn't as if,
you know,
you couldn't gather that information on
your own, you know, but it was, again,
it was that behavior leading up to it. And
I'm not a conspiracy guy at all. Right.
I've seen too much shit to, you
know, to think that, you know,
every conspiracies home water.
So, but this one, it was
disturbing in that regard.
What that's worth. All right. Yeah.
You should look into it and we'll talk
about next time. See what you think.
Cause I, I'd really be
interested in, I think,
I don't think we're going to this show
that we're going to get ready to do here,
start filming and next month is not going
to be looking into things like that.
What is it? What is it called? It's
going to be called black files.
They may change the number or the name
just before we go on there. But um,
you know, I really enjoyed the
shows that I did in the past.
American declassified with the,
they're looking into conspiracies.
I've really enjoyed it.
I really,
really thought it was fascinating
and I get why people feel that way.
Kennedy for sure it's Kennedy
when they're on the outside.
The Kennedy wanted to me the bullet
is the most disturbing thing. Yeah,
the pool would that just showed up on
Connolly's Gurney. Oh look where we found,
we found this spot and it's not distorted
and supposedly went through two people
and shattered bone, that magic bullet,
the magic bullet. So I don't buy it.
And I don't think that that
bullet came from there.
That's probably the most of
all things. So, cause we,
we looked at the grassy knoll issue and
the possibility of spa getting other
people on the side. Yeah. The
fuck out of here. Dot. Bullet.
The bullet drives me crazy.
It does that there's more pieces of the
bullet fragments in Connolly's body.
When you look at the,
look at the x rays of Conley's
bodies that show bullet fragments,
there's little pieces they found little
tiny pieces of metal in his body from
the bullet fragments. Huh. But you
don't see that missing from the bullet.
It's bullshit. Yeah. The, the bullet
thing is, is, and, and I, you know,
again, there's, there's
elements of it that you look at,
but collectively, I just,
you know, and again,
maybe there's something else out there.
Maybe there is and we just
haven't uncovered yet.
Or maybe this will prompt some additional
information. Who knows? But, um,
yeah. Anyway, it's, it's
fascinating shit. But, uh,
I do get it because it was
such a seminal moment. Right?
And nobody wants to think that
something that bad, that horrific.
And that's something that could sort
of shatter the country in that fashion
could be done by one, one guy, Mike
Lee Harvey Oswald, or John Hinckley.