Talking about British woman wakes up with
Chinese accent. Oh, play this, play this.
I want to hear her.
Oh, nice. Oh, it was not
have a voice that came out.
55 sweet and sour chicken Hong Kong style.
There's just been such
horrible thing to go with.
She was diagnosed with foreign
accents and keep playing.
The inquisitor reports.
Others who have suffered from the same
change in voice had severe migraines.
Only 61 cases have been identified since
1941 one explanation for the new tongue
is that her migraines,
which she experiences as many as 10 times
or more per month are leaving her with
neurological damage.
They condition usually follows
traumatic brain injury or a stroke.
Those with fas also
experience loss of vocabulary,
but Caldwell is not alone anymore.
To go back to when you
hear it again enough.
If he finds to be sweet and sour,
chicken Hong Kong style,
is that her? That's her to
welcome. She doesn't have it there.
Let me hear it again.
She was Chinese accent. She literally
woke up, opened are nice. It wasn't,
don't have a voice that came out enough.
55 beer to be so our ticket,
Hong Kong style, there's just been
such horrible thing to go with.
She was have an idea
that's not a Chinese accent. That's
the broken English accent. Yeah.
With the Chinese,
uh,
from a Chinese person at why they giving
her of all things food or the fuck it
means she got to set any bigger than
the big game or of food or the means.
I told that bitch order changes to this
sweet and sour.
I don't know if we can understand you
in any big else with a Chinese accent to
say this doesn't mean that is
kind of hilarious. Hilarious.
Like why play that play this
morning here was this lady got,
she's got a British just as a
Houston Mama at the Britain.
What happened to her that didn't
say where she got hit in the head?
The queen's Tomfoolery
well, the third asking me, um,
having my mom got the acid,
Lisa Alomia. Oh, not from
England, sorry. Is 100% Texas
people who don't know me.
Hey,
where are you from before I see my,
Oh wait, where's that? I'm like,
we're hearing right? Oh, you're
from here. How'd you talk like that?
So that's when the whole story comes up.
Six months ago, jaw surgery to fix it
all. Chaucer changed Lisa speech too.
I thought she was playing around with me.
I thought she was joking with me.
But then she showed me that like the
doctor had told her she was diagnosed with
foreign accents in gym and she searched
it and then I was like, oh Lord,
you still have to just hold up.
Hold up, hold up, pause right here.
Here's the problem with that.
I can talk like this.
It doesn't mean that I talk like this.
So if I come back and say
if I got an operation,
I wanted to get a root canal and I came
back and I started talking about this.
Welcome to the Joe Rogan experience.
People are like, what's wrong with you?
I've diagnosed with foreign accent
syndrome. Then we once just talk like,
you know how to talk. No,
because I've been diagnosed,
I've been diagnosed with a disease.
I have an issue.
Please be more sensitive
and I'm calling the news.
I'd like to get on the news
today. Please do. I can't help it.
This is how I talk now.
Do you think they still
possess the original accent
is a well or is it just that
one navy? That bitch is so
dumb that I can't go back.
She says she's got one speed,
just knocked her into second gear and
she's trying to start off the line.
And second now hold on.
I have is, what is this?
This woman says she's been
described to speaking in Italian,
French and even Japanese. Oh, she's
crazy. She likes attention. Let's hear it.
Excellent Syndrome. Kath joins us
now along with Professor Rosemary.
It's a very clear,
so it's 2006.
She was suffering from bad
health for a little while.
You'd had headaches and then you spoke
to your sister on the phone and notice
that your voice is changing. Yeah, I
started off with just the least and um,
I was a good concern and I did the ill
health, I tend to get over fatigued.
So I fought. It was that. So until that
Dutch still there the next morning solely,
this list was getting a little
bit strange. I rang a on trends,
uh, my new rose up there left
at that time I could speak,
I record a message and nobody got back.
I thought, okay, nothing to worry.
Where's the morning?
It was starting to go like an early on
and by first year to go and completely
and then I lost my
swallow at the same time.
Which stats terrified still
scare me for my family.
There were still terrified for
me but no stops tuck me in.
Why are they scared? Cause you're
talking weird or cause you can't swallow.
He couldn't swallow.
Yeah.
She's the only spitting out now I've
been diagnosed with inability to swallow.
I come on of me. You swollen. No,
I've been diagnosed and inability to
swallow. Plus I have a new accident.
All of a sudden this book and what it's
taught me an accident cannot swallow.
How does show you the paperwork.
I got a prescription for a cough syrup.
I want to cough. I never squat. What
in the fuck. But here's the thing.
Then it may be, I mean, look, some
people are barely holding on to reality.
You're right.
Barely.
You're all in it is one fucking smack one
one smack upside the head and all of a
sudden, oh no. Sweet
Utah Hot toss off tie.
You took a former beauty pageant.
Has Foreign Accent Syndrome.
Okay. Former beauty queen.
Let me hear it baby.
And I'm terrible with accents.
Okay.
So some people were wondering where I
got in the accent from. It's really,
really crazy story.
Foreign accent syndrome is a rare
condition that only affects crazy people
still speaking their native language.
Uh,
let me hear her this week. Started off
with listening to this. She's never left.
The USA doesn't last.
This was her accent. Okay.
Hold on. Hold on. Stop
backup. Backup. Is that weed?
Sure is weed. That is good. Fucking weed.
That is a gigantic, we'd plant behind
this bitch. She's high as fuck.
Playing with these people. Oh, she's
playing with his people. This lady's high.
She's barbecued term or what?
Your weekends.
She got so high she
thought she was British.
Hi.
Yesterday,
which is a September 17th,
2011 I started having problems with my
voice. Oh my God, I've got the same one.
I tried to talk and say some things
Matano fucked like it was right.
I had someone ask him again about my
accent. So I just making a new video.
I had a headache for about three
days, got arrested, emergency room,
and this was in May of 2015 and so
they put me to sleep, observed me,
stop, pause this. This is nonsense. This
is like, people think they're a Fox.
You can't,
you can't pick,
you can't stay in the one
accident cause you don't know yet.
No one can call people crazy anymore.