There's a lot of people that are dying
in Mexico because the cartel violence,
you know,
we were talking about that Jamal could
Shogi guy before the podcast started and
how disturbing this whole thing is.
And the plot for folks who don't know
what we're talking about l fill people in
on. Okay, sure. So, uh, Jamal,
because Shogi is a journalist who actually
worked for the Washington Post and he
went into the Saudi embassy in Turkey to
get a marriage license in his Stan bolt
to get a marriage license.
So for him and his wife and he
never got out day killed him,
dismembered him,
used a bone saw and then they even went
as far as to cover it up where they had
a body double go in and they gave him
a fake beard and they had him wear his
clothes and walk out. Is there video of
the body? There is, there is. In fact,
CNN had it. I know yesterday I was
looking at the CNN video that had it. Um,
so yeah, Saudi Arabia now brazenly killing
journalists. And I'll tell you what,
you came up with a bunch of different
versions of the story too. Yeah,
but why they did it. Here's the
body. There you go. Here's him.
And then the guy on the right with hair.
Why would they have a guy
with hair as a body double?
Think about how much this had to be
planned out to have a body double. Right?
But why did they give the body w bubble?
If you're going to be a body,
double shave your head dude. The
other guy's bald. That's crazy.
So they didn't even do a good
job at faking their murder,
but it's the worst fake ever. Yeah. Cause
the guys get a full head of hair. Yeah.
It's not great. No, it's
terrible. How shoes on too?
He had different shoes. Yeah,
I mean that's,
that's the worst body double.
It's got dark hair and they're
saying this is the guy. Look,
he's fine walking around. No issues.
It's a body double knot. A hair double,
I guess. I mean, if you can
have a body double shave,
the guy's fucking heads tell you walked
into a different shirt and everything.
Oh, that's a body double. Yeah, so
his hair colors different too. I mean,
he's got dark hair.
This guy's got gray here.
The thing that's driving me nuts about
this is so now this is getting a lot of
press attention and I'm happy it's getting
a lot of press attention, of course.
But the reason why it is is because he's
part of the elite class in the sense
that he's a journalist and now you have
the people from the New York Times and
the Washington Post and CNN and they
can relate and they go, oh my God,
they're killing journalists.
Now this is crazy.
Look at the precedent that this sets,
but what people don't know is
for the past two or three years,
Saudi Arabia has been waging
a literal genocide in Yemen,
and that's not an exaggeration.
So they blockaded the country.
They're not allowing in medicine, there's
a cholera epidemic happening there.
Millions of people are sick.
They have people dying of starvation
because they're not allowing in food or
humanitarian aid. They're bombing
hospitals, they're bombing schools,
they're bombing open air markets.
So they're doing a literal genocide.
And that got very little coverage,
but then with this journalist now
finally starting to get some coverage,
but I'm curious what happens
moving forward in terms
of how will the US respond
to it?
Because as I'm sure you already know this,
I mean they care more about that $110
billion weapons deal that they just had
with the Saudis and they do about the
lives of humanities or the lives of
journalists. Yeah. The, the idea
of him being really valuable.
It's not, it's not just that
he's a part of the elite.
It's that there was a conspiracy to do
so that they think came from upon high.
Yeah.
Right.
And there was 15 people
that they're saying flew in
from Saudi Arabia and one of
them was a forensics expert who
like knows how to cover up evidence,
knows what evidence is, what
it feels like a movie. Did.
The bone saw things that been confirmed.
They know they had a bone saw.
I heard that.
Now the nickname for him in Washington
DC is what they say bone saw a salmon,
his name is Mohammad bin Salman.
They're calling him bone saw Solomon or
something like that. Yeah, dude, it is.
The stuff that's going
on is just scary to me.
And then there's also some interesting
geopolitical stuff happening around this.
The head of Turkey is now using this as
an issue to try to snuggle up to the u s
because he's got ambitions where he wants
to like recreate the Ottoman Empire.
And of course Muhammad Bin Salman,
he has ambitions where he wants
to dominate the Middle East.
So you have at the same time,
this weird ego battle between a Air
Diwan and Mohammed bin Salman and they're
all trying to suck up to the
u s to, you know, basically
get it so that, uh, we can,
we do favors for them and
we allow them to expand.
And on top of that, there, the
story's changed multiple times. Right?
It's the story of what
happened five times.
First they said nothing happened to
them, to him. Then they said, oh,
you got out fight and now they're
saying that he was killed by people who
overstep their bounds. That's right.
Yeah. They keep changing the store.
And there's also stories that the,
the consulate has video and
audio evidence of the murder.
That's what Turkey saying.
Yeah,
but they don't want to release it
because then people will know how they're
spying on them when they visit the
consulate. I guess so I didn't see that,
but I'll take your word for it. Yeah.
That was to see if you can find that.
That was one of the things
that was brought up yesterday,
that they don't want to release this video
and audio evidence because if they do,
then other people will know how they're
spying on them when they visit. Yeah,
I could see that.
I mean,
they should immediately cut off
the arms deal with Saudi Arabia,
no more weapons for a regime that's
doing the stuff that they're doing.
And we already knew that they behead
people in the public square for sorcery,
sorcery. Do they really?
Yes. For witchcraft.
You don't to see for drug smuggling that
they behead people in the public square
for those things.