The joe rogan experience.
It's just crazy to me that you got so
deeply entrenched reading the story that
you started getting into Santa Maria.
I was actually until I was married
to a Brazilian for 10 years. Ah.
So they have their centers in the,
he is called Macuna.
And what's different about their version?
It's almost exactly the same and
they have all the same saints.
It's the same thing. Same thing because
of the slave trade came through Brazil,
Africa,
Catholicism mixing.
They that just the music is different
with the Cubans. It's a Roomba.
All this wonderful room
or music that you hear a,
there's a whole bunch of great
music that grows up around it.
So you were married to a Brazilian woman,
get divorced to keep the religion
cause that what happened? Uh,
yeah,
I was,
I can't go to places like Cuba and
Brazil because I get so influenced and
overwhelmed by the changes, the
direction of my life. Really.
I went to Brazil the first
full day I was in Brazil.
I fell in love with the woman that I
married and lived with for the next 10
years.
Wow.
When I go to Q a it's dangerous
to me because I'm so uh,
seduced by it.
I'm so intoxicated by Havana,
by Cuban culture. What is it? Well,
first of all,
it's the most sensual place you have
an is the most sensual place I've ever
been. Everyone flirts, the women flirt.
Doesn't matter if they're married
or not married, they flirt with you.
I suppose guys flirt
too. Um, everyone flirts,
there's like sexual energy everywhere.
The Sky and the,
and the climate is just kind of
sultry and, and, and sensual.
The music is,
makes your body move.
Joe,
would you let me play a video for you to
show you some of the dancing and Cuba?
Sure. When women dancing
Cuban, they cover that pussy
because what I'm trying to do,
the whole dance is me baiting you.
It's one of the prettiest things
you've ever seen in your life.
It's me coming up to you
with this movement. Like when
I played it like you all,
I was getting nowhere with DOL.
I was getting going with
us way before the podcast.
He was tightening up so I had to
play low Papinas. Then my town size,
and once he heard that
I could see Nigeria coming alive.
He even got up and
kicked his leg one time,
which meant we're on because
it's so embedded in your culture.
But in Cuban dancing,
I'm coming up to you. Oh.
And every time I come up and I'll
go like this and go like this. Yeah,
you got to come and put your ass.
But the whole time he'll be covering
your pussy because I'm the exchange.
I go to grab your pussy.
Harvey Weinstein would do phenomenal.
Here's how serious I take it. By the way,
what is this? Oh, I love, I love
Afro Cuban music, Latin Jazz.
So I'm hosting,
I'm curating and hosting a Latin jazz
series in New York at a bar called sync
every Thursday night,
Tj English and his Latin jazz explosion.
So I get to choose the music,
the musicians that performed there,
and I and I host the evening.
Wow, you do this every week. Yeah,
we're going to cry. Try to just
keep, keep it going indefinitely.
That's phenomenal.
So this to you was a natural subject
to sort of ink engross yourself?
Well, I had written, I had
published the book, Havana Nocturne,
which was about the mob in Cuba in
the 50s. Um, and I really got into it.
Then I made numerous trips to
Havana for extended periods.
So this book was almost
like a sequel to that. Yeah.
It was a nice way to revisit that culture.
Pick up the thread of that story.
Uh, cause this one is sort of an answer.
You get to the end of the event, uh,
Havana Nocturne. Then you, you ask
yourself, so then what happened?
What happened after the mafia got chased
out of Cuba? What was their response?
How did they take it? I want to show
you this as a Cuban dancing. Okay.
What does it say? What's the name of
the, well, I call this a little bit,
watch to see how everything
is. Look, look at this.
Uh,
yeah. It just gives a little
fuzzy. So it's watch, hold me.
Holbys about maybe watch him move
so that they talking about genes,
about what was the DOL, see
he went to grab up. Was He,
so the dancers is a seduction. The
seduction, they're both there. They're,
they're engaged in a mutual seduction.
Uh, this is a crazy dance.
Jamie, what's the name of this?
Show it to me.
Guar.
Say that Joe and Co is the
rhythm one goal is the real you a
lot more and when you're
Ketos Ketos m u n e Q.
U. I. T. O. S. D. My time's up. My
Time's, this is the province then. Wow.
Watch how she grabs a pussy
every time he comes close.
Okay.
Now that mute. Does it grab it seems kind
of grab it and she blacked it. Oh yeah,
that'll fuck around.
That's hilarious.
Drumming you're hearing and the use
of what's called the Shaker Ray.
That Gord there and the chanting
that's going on that you would all,
you would hear all that in
a Santeria ceremony. Wow.
This grabbing the pussy shit is
hilarious. Hilarious. Hilarious. Yeah.
He kept trying to kick out to his junk
to occasionally, right originally,
but he's probably just checking
how are we doing down there?
See like he's grabbing it. He's like
squeezing it to see if it's hard.
He just played with it. He just
threatened the grab and she grabbed it.
That's hilarious. So it's very
playful. Flirtatious. Right.
And this is the culture there?
That's Cuba.
Okay.