I really wonder if there's,
there's a bottlenecks for progress that
are going to be that we're going to run
into. And I think, um, uh,
ultimately inflammation
is one of the big ones.
And information also in
a lot of ways is money.
You know,
I mean when we think of money we're,
we're thinking of ones and Zeros that
are being moved around on bank accounts.
It's data.
I mean it's attributed to different people
and you get to do more things because
you have more of these numbers and more
of these things. But what is it really?
It's not gold based anymore.
It's not a physical material,
a material object that you're coveting
now it's some weird thing and it's kind
of like information on a database. And
what if we get to a certain point in time,
and I,
I sort of feel like in this weird vague
abstract way we're moving towards this
with all,
it's one of the things that I want to
really step back and wonder about this
trend towards socialism and,
and social democratic thinking.
I wonder what that is and I honestly
think that we're moving towards this idea
that, hey, you know,
we've got a lot of fucking problems that
could be cured if you move some of that
money around and, but, but should you be
able to move some of that money around?
And when,
what happens if that money
becomes something different
than what if people start
developing social currency instead of
financial currency would have your ability
to do things was based on how much you
actually put in. I mean, we're assuming,
right? We assume that the way we do
things now where if you want to buy a car,
you have to have $35,000 that's how much
a Mustang costs and you've got to bring
it to the bank and this and that.
And you can prove alone.
But what if we get to a time in the future
where it's not these pieces of paper
that gives you material objects but
rather your own actions and deeds provide
you with social currency that allows you
to go on vacations or allows you to eat
at restaurants.
It allows you to do things.
And there's this running tally that's
not outside of the realm of possibility.
No,
I think it reward systems
within everything that we're
using are gonna are gonna
rise up. I mean that, that's, that's what
we're already kind of doing. I mean, we,
we reward tokens for,
for activity.
We're going to see that rise up
in more things that we're doing.
But what I'm saying is
if we're doing it in,
if it's a social currency and that your
own personal behavior allows you to
access more freedoms or,
or more goods or more things,
it would encourage positive behavior and
community based behavior because that
would be the only way to advance.
I mean,
obviously this is a long
time down the line, but when
the first caveman, you know,
traded the first fucking shiny rock
for the first spearhead, you know,
whatever it was that they did that started
this whole inevitable trend towards
money. This is not something that
has to be this way forever. You know,
and I w I wonder when we're looking
at the distribution of information,
which is arguably not arguably,
it's never,
never been like what we have today.
There's never been a time in human history
where everyone had so much access to
information that you used to have to pay
for. He used to have to go to schools.
You have to use to have to earn your
way to the position where you could open
the very books that had
all this information in at
night, get it off your phone.
It's instant.
And I,
this is a whole different
way of interfacing with
information and I think this
is going to affect higher
learning institutes.
I think it's going to affect
a lot of different things,
but I wonder if this all can
be applied ultimately some day,
maybe not in our generation,
but someday to money that people start
using social currency and that social
currency is going to be almost
like we have some sort of a,
a database of social
currency in this country.