I understand the mindset of people
that don't want any of this to happen.
I do understand it, but I do think
that they don't understand nature.
I really don't think they understand
that this is the best death these animals
will ever experience and they're
not going to live forever.
And the wild and the wild,
they're going to be torn apart
by something bigger than that.
That's just how it goes 100% of the time.
Or they freeze to death or they
starve to death or they're starving.
They walked down on the road to
try to find some food in the town.
They get hit by a semi truck.
Yeah, that's true. Yeah.
And if I have a buddy who lives in Iowa
and when you drive in his neighborhood
at night,
you better go 35 miles an hour cause those
fuckers are just darting out in front
of this tree weapon. Right. They're
everywhere. And you know what's the,
what's the solution? Don't
drive cars. Drive your bike
everywhere man. Well, okay,
good luck with that. Yeah, I get it. I
get where those people are coming from.
They're coming from a place of,
of compassion,
but it becomes very culty and it
becomes very like very team oriented,
their team Vegan
and there's like words it we're
circling back where you know,
when you're trying to have
that middle ground, that
discussion, that conversation.
Um,
there's like this pre assigned talking
points where everybody from every respect
of side mix essentially the same argument
and you're just regurgitating what
you've heard other people say,
but there's no new thought.
There's new and there's no one taking
a step to either side. Like, okay,
do you want maybe, maybe there's
something I'm not seeing here.
Let me look at it from this perspective.
Or vice versa. Where this side,
the hunters like, no, no, you're
stupid snow flake. You know,
go get your Starbucks Latte, you
know, with your soy milk. And,
but they're never looking at it
from anything new right there.
They're just regurgitating
their talking points.
Like when you said gun control
and people freaked out,
freaked out because I didn't stay to
the script and there's a script. I mean,
if you pull up my, any of my
social, you will see that, oh,
you what you should've said was, or hey,
you know, shall not be infringed upon.
Yeah man, I got it. Yeah. Shall not be
infringed upon and believe it to death.
Have you fought for it? Have you
bled for it had been blown up for it.
You've been shot at, I have, you
know, I really believe in this shit,
but I didn't stay to the script and
then I get murdered by both sides.
So then how do we, I mean, you do
a pretty good job, so teach me Joe,
how do you bring people in to have,
there's gotta be a lot of people
that disagree with you and say,
I do a terrible job that I repeat
the same things over and over again.
And I agree with them to for for a certain
amount of the conversations like this
one.
I mean we,
I've had this conversation about
conservation and animals a hundred times,
but I think it's worth having a hundred
more because I think it's an important
that if someone has listened to this
podcast and they didn't understand how it
all works and they didn't understand
that people who hunt and eat meat,
they're not monsters.
They're not evil people.
Just like people who eat grain aren't
monsters because you callously disregard
the lives of mice and rats,
all the things that get ground
up and combines and bunnies.
Like if you buy grain, large
scale agriculture is bad, period.
It's bad in terms of factory farming, but
it's also bad in terms of growing food.
If you grow a thousand acres of corn,
you are absolutely displacing wildlife.
And when that stuff gets harvest,
you see vultures fly over those fields
and there's a reason it's because there's
a bunch of dead things.
In fact, more dead lives,
more dead lives occur in a pound of
grain then occur in a pound of beef.
Because if you think that a cow is
more valuable than a bunny because it's
larger, like you've got some weird
white thing going on in your own head.
Okay. Can you tell me how
to balance the soul's worth?
Exactly.
And how would you feel about insects?
Because they are a large scale poisoning
those fucking insects and you know it,
everybody knows it and they're grinding
those fuckers up with earthworms and
mice and gophers and chipmunks
and anything else that
gets stuck in those wheels.
That is just how large
scale agriculture works.
So unless you have some isolated farm
where everything's fenced in and you only
have a certain amount of acreage
and that farm feeds you will,
you are Karma free and congratulations
to you, you figured out how to do it.
But most of us who buy pasta, if you
go and buy bread in the store, you're,
you're paying someone who's killed a
large amount of living things in order to
harvest that grain. That's
just a fact. It's just a fact.
And it's an inconvenient fact
that they like to look at, uh,
with blinders on because they,
you know,
like I'm hashtag cruelty free not to that
fucking bunny rabbit that's a part of
your tofu cause this is, this is
what's really going on. I mean,
a good part of the B vitamin B that a
lot of vegans get us from ground up bugs
that's ground up into their grain and
ground up into their vegetables. I mean,
this is you, this is just, you
can't get away around that.
No,
I mean not if you are being real,
if you're not,
if you're being real.
Yeah.
Maybe that's the problem in the first
place is nobody is going to have the
courage to come into that
middle ground and let,
let go of all of their
baggage and all of their
bullshit. Yeah. And just cool with
eating bugs. You should eat crickets,
get cricket meal, eat cricket,
protein. Fucking good for you. Yeah.
If you don't want to eat animals,
you're like,
I'm just not into anything that's warm.
Okay.
I have a friend who only eats
fish and I go, why? He goes, fish.
Don't even take care of their
babies. I was like, Ooh, good point.
That is a good point. Fuck those
fish Fisher. Yummy too. He's like,
I don't want to kill a mammal. He goes,
I don't want to eat a mammo. He's like,
mammals take care of their babies there.
The baby's milk from their, their,
you know, their utters.
I'm like, okay, I get it.
My wife has a pescatarian for awhile.
Um, that didn't, that didn't last.
It's just not the best source
source of nutrients. Well,
it was when she's pregnant and
the doctor's like, all right,
so you're 90 pounds and,
uh,
I need you to put on like 20 more pounds
really fast and you're not going to do
it eating halibut. Yeah. So, yeah.