About the Joe Rogan experience.
All right.
Cut All this out. Right, right,
right, right. Hello Adam.
Hey, thanks for having me,
Jay. Thanks for being here, man. I'm
pretty sure I'm a giant fan of your show.
I really appreciate that.
The fact that it annoys people to it,
really a business people off, that's
the goal pretty much, you know, I mean,
I'm not the kind of person where I'm
like, ah, if you're pissing people off,
you're doing something right.
But there's some truth to it.
There's some truth to that. And also
the way you structured the name, I mean,
I don't know if you came up with the
name of it, but Adam ruins everything.
I think I might have to give that to my,
to my former boss,
Samurai Hsa college humor.
Might've might've, uh,
I think we came up with the name together.
He might've been the first
person to say it, but uh,
yeah. Thank you. I'm really, I,
yeah, I like let's, you know,
it lets you know that, hey,
this is going to know you a little bit,
but like I'm going to be telling you
shit that you don't want to hear that's
going to make everything a
little bit worse, you know?
But at the end of the day,
it makes it better. It's an optimistic
show at the end of the day where, sure,
yeah. Yeah. You give him the truth.
I think that, yeah, I mean the, the,
the thesis of the show is that it's always
better to know the truth that it's a
momentarily uncomfortable,
but hopefully for most people,
99% of people who watch the show,
it grinds your gears a little bit
to find out something like, oh,
I thought that was true with the ad crap,
you know?
But then at the end we show you why
you're actually better off knowing that
thing and you're always better off knowing
the truth and my view in my view as
well. Yeah. Is, was there ever,
and was there one episode that stands
out as being one that people got the most
upset about? Uh, there's
a bunch of 'em. I mean,
people get, people get upset with
us for a lot of different reasons.
We did one about how, um, uh,
breastfeeding isn't better than
formula feeding. It's a no,
they're both like, formula
feeding is fine, you know,
and if the promise formula feeding is
becoming stigmatized, stigmatized now, um,
and there's a lot of people who can't
breastfeed or who for medical reasons,
you know, uh, and, uh, uh,
the fact is that for me,
formula is like a scientifically
proven wonderful way to feed a baby.
And if you know someone's
choice or need us to do that,
there's no reason to stigmatize.
And we'd go through all the reasons that,
that that's the case. And yet
people get a little, you know,
there's a lot of people who sort of had
an ideology about that, you know, and, uh,
don't want to hear the truth about it.
Um.