Well for going to come after you.
How dirty is that money exactly.
It must be in a safe and it wasn't just
the safe. Only in the storage unit. Oh,
that's gotta be something bad.
And you get that handsome dude that
was in the beginning of Ozarks.
That handsome Mexican dude.
It's just a straight up murder.
He's going to come visit you all.
Oh Man. That guy was my favorite.
I was so sad when they spoil spoiler.
So sad when they killed him.
Like the dude from breaking bad. That
comes around twins. But did you see Ozark?
You ever see Ozark?
I watched like the first couple episodes
and I fucked it up for you. Yeah,
cause it was a pivotal moment
that I just gave voice to many.
There's so many shows though. There are
so many shows. But that's a damn good one.
Is it good?
That is a damn good show.
What's the guy that's the guy who
starts in that? Jason Bateman Bateman.
He's excellent. And the woman Laura
Linney Linney. She's amazing. Yeah,
the family's amazing kids. Amazing. It's
fucking show, man. It's a show. It's like,
nope, you get sucked in and that
Netflix lets you watch them all. Like,
are you ready?
Listen,
let me ask you a question I asked a
lot of people is and I said to set up a
Christmas party and I got with a bunch
of hunters and I got a couple like the
stink eye. Like what's this guy talking
to? Conservatives. I don't know if that,
maybe I'm just weird. Have you ever
seen the movie the greatest showman? Oh,
is that the, um, the musical? It is.
I've been forced to watch segments
of that with my wife and children.
It is fantastic. Very good
movie. Hugh Jackman's in angel.
He's an angel and Australian Angel. He
is. He sent down here to save us. Save us.
You ever seen him dance and sing?
He's made, he's magical. I'm a hunter.
I got a hunting podcast. But I'm
telling you, you're a manly man.
Look at that beard. Yeah, we got
this thing. But I love that movie.
It's a great movie.
I listened to it on the Pandora,
the greatest showman channel
and I sing the tunes.
Listen did my favorite comedy on TV is
the unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt. Okay.
So I can't be talking about man.
Look, things are not in manly things.
Hugh Jackman Perform Announces World
Tour set to perform the greatest showman
songs. He's going to just sit and look
at him. Look at him. Wow. One man show.
Gorgeous man. He's just,
I mean it's unbelievable.
Unbelievable. But yeah, I did.
I get, I get made fun of for this. My, of
course, my son likes it. My wife likes it,
but I enjoy, I get into like your
son, how old is he? He's too,
he doesn't know any better.
We just like the music
[inaudible] something's going
on. Yeah. He's just like,
there's something on the TV.
He's not like a crazy,
he's not writing that critique APP.
But if you put on Dora the explorer
and then you switched it over to that
bullshit, he believes this
fucking guy dancing. No, he'll
be Dora. Dora. Yeah. Listen,
I think that I watch like if you watch
things like game of Thrones where they
are burning children. Yeah.
And like it's entertaining,
but sometimes I need a break.
I like to watch a man dance around
and sing for a woman, whatever.
It don't matter. Those move those
shows can get dark where you're like,
what am I doing to myself? You
know, like narcos. Oh yeah.
And they would just go into a fucking
nightclub and gun people down just sitting
there and watching like women and
children smoked. And it's, it's,
what's the other, the show
with Anthony Hopkins on Hbo.
What's that? The robots. Oh,
Westworld. Yeah. That's the
same way they're shooting
kids on there though. Well,
the kids are robot. We
can just path. Yeah,
they shot one right in the
face every once in a while.
You need to sprinkle a little bit of
musical and your life, I believe. Yeah.
What is that do you think?
And here's the come coming from a person
that's been on a bunch of life changing
experiences. And I know you have, I want
to talk to you about some them. Yes.
Especially the one in Nepal where you
almost died and you saw children and
wolves, babies. We talked about that
on the last podcast, but it's probably,
it would be worth revisiting. Um,
what do you think this is? Like why,
why are we so obsessed with life
or death drama that's artificial.
Well you see it like in the,
in the,
in the show Westworld they talk
about like it being a game. Yeah.
It being this game of access. Like
what can't I do in my real life? Right?
So when you watch TV and you watch
murdering and you watch this,
this evil thing come to life,
you're just, you're, it's,
it really is something that
you can be transported,
can't do that in your regular
life. For sure. With Westworld,
what you're getting is basically a real
live version of that red dead redemption.
Yes. Right. So when you, when you play
that, we were talking about the other day,
how this guy got in trouble because they
have all these things in the game that
you can do to people.
And this guy like ty this hook her up,
threw her off a cliff and
shit and you can start can,
you can do whatever you want.
But they were,
they were filming this stuff and putting
it on youtube and then youtube would
get mad and youtube pulled him off.
But then people are like, well,
wait a minute though. Why? How
come? You can just do it like,
why'd you have that in the game?
But it did when my dad was my age,
30 40 years ago,
there would,
they would never have ever does nothing
done anything like game of Thrones or
Westworld ever. Ever. In fact,
there was a Westworld and it
wasn't anywhere near like it is.
You'll bring modern
day. Good moving. Yeah.
But like I think we've just stretched
out the limits to which we're willing to
explore, like really terrible and
evil things for entertainment.
We've definitely changed what we're
willing to accept and where the bar is in
terms of quality, the bars through
the roof, through the roof.
It's immersive to the point
where you can't even like,
I can't even explain what
you're experiencing when
you're watching these shows.
Yeah.
So look,
if you go and you see some great comedy
from the 1990s like you see watch a Dave
Chappelle or Chris rock specials from
the 90s that holds up 100% and Seinfeld
that. But what I'm saying is
like if that was out today,
it would be a 100% standup special.
I'd be like,
oh you see the new Chris Rock's bigger
and blacker, it's fucking amazing.
But if you tried to put some bullshit
ass 1990s TV show on on Netflix,
if you tried to like finagle
some CSI Miami type Shit,
you know what I mean? Some
nonsense. I don't know if CSI Miami,
is that even a show? Is that a real
show? There's a CSI Miami. There is.
There's several. There's many
CSI I guessed, but we'd like,
we don't order law and order.
There's so many of those,
but we've expanded our willingness
to like explore things that are,
I mean game of Thrones for example.
It's one of the best shows ever
created in my opinion for sure.
But it explores some unthinkable things.
Awful,
awful things. Well, it's the whole
show, but spoiler alert is, uh,
around a brother and sister were fucked
and had a whole family. Yeah. Yeah.
So we didn't explore these like these
things that in we would never even touch
upon in our media in the
fifties, sixties, even the 70s,
we would be touching upon those things in
a way that we do now. No, not only that,
but
here's the thing,
law and orders on a bad show. Like if
you watch it, you'll be in a, nope.
So what happened? Why, why do we go not
good enough? Like what, what was it?
Was it, did they go not good
enough or did, was it like,
like porn? Like if you watch porn, okay.
And you watch some porn from the 1980s
and then you flipped through like youporn
now that I would ever do that.
But if you did do that and looked at all
the different categories, you'd be like,
what the fuck happened?
Yeah. Like why are people,
why is gagging something people are
looking for? It's not, it's not an,
it's like a category. We've expanded
our ability to conceive of things. Yes.
In immediate space where we can create,
you can create dragons that breathe ice.
You can create. Yeah, there's,
there's things you can be
transported, like, listen,
this isn't real so I can,
I can do this, right?
I can have this scene of,
of rape or infidelity or are incest that
seems it's appropriate to me only in
this fantasy world,
man.
Sometimes I get down on that stuff like
a watch. Enough of it. You're just like,
I need a musical.
I need to be inspired.
That life is grand and that's
how I feel about it, man.
And sometimes it comes across and
like this dude washes musicals, but I,
I do for a little bit of a break.
Nothing wrong with it.
What I'm weirded out about is this natural
human inclination towards progression
in everything good or bad is that
things just keep ramping up well,
but we're progressing with our storylines
for like humanity in a weird way in
media. But we're also like
suppressing a lot of our,
we're trying to suppress through social
justice a lot of the same thing, right?
Well, some people are, but I think
it's a small, very vocal minority.
I think in reality there's,
the vast majority of people find out
about said suppression or upset by it and
they're like,
what in the fuck are you talking about
with this safe spaces and all this
nonsense. Most people that
hear that stuff are going, oh,
this is just nonsense by a few
like really loud device types.
Even though my pocket has,
it's something like as serious as hunting
is because you're killing stuff like
that's going out into the world and
taking plucking something that you didn't
put there,
taking it away.
But like I think that the core of what
I think you do well and what I think
others should try to do is ask why,
why are we willing to,
why is game of Thrones the most
watched show that's on right?
Why? Why, why? I can't answer
that question, but it's a
conversation because it's,
if it's so fictitious,
right?
It's so obviously fiction.
You're living in this fictional world.
You have fictional white walkers,
you have dragons,
you have people that can survive in fire,
but there's parallels to
real life and then these,
these ridiculous fantasies,
but then these parallels to real life
that that travel along the same path and
like you don't get to choose between
the dragons and the incest. Yeah.
Both there at the same time.
I think it,
it fulfills a lot of like base needs,
but it does.
So in this way, that's
obviously false. Yeah.
It's like why are
superheroes so huge to us?
If you stop and think about the number
of blockbusters that are superhero movies
that are comic book movies,
they're coming out like once every
couple of months now. Crazy. The,
that was a rare beast when I
was at chess when I was a kid.
If there's a hulk movie,
I have jumped for joy.
It was no god Damn Spiderman
movie when I was a kid.
There was a TV show and it's sucked.
Okay.
Was the God damn cartoon
TV show Spiderman?
Spiderman does whatever's
a spider spins a web,
any size catches these just
like flies. Look, ouch.
There comes a spider man.
It was terrible.
And I used to get up early to watch
it cause I was a huge comic book.
You've watched the Lou Ferrigno
Hawk, right? Fuck yeah, I watched it.
That was a little bit, I mean like you've
watched the Batman with Adam West. Yeah.
You watch him now and you're like,
what is happening?
So they came out with Superman.
He was like the first movies that,
what does this Spiderman, a TV show. Wow.
That's another TV show guy in the back
of was I kind of the background doing,
who's that guy? He don't look, you don't
do anything good. It's got a wooden stick.
He needs to know those
[inaudible] Spiderman can
shoot webs out of his hands and
that wouldn't sticks.
Probably not going to do much then.
Then Spiderman sorta changes
ability. Right? Because we,
it used to be able to do,
like now he could just basically fly.
I mean just hurls himself through the
air and sticks to buildings. You know,
he used to be a little harder
to swing around back. I like,
let me drop my backpack full of
textbooks, get to it. But he's, that was,
there was no Spiderman
movies when I was a kid,
and there was a superman movie and the
superman movie beget the Batman movie.
Batman movie came out, Michael
Keaton. It was a big, big success.
People were shocked at Michael
Keaton was Batman, but it worked.
Was that like Danny Devito
was the penguin? Yeah.
Everybody got a shot at Batman.