Cause all right. So for
people that know, I,
I met Mike on a flight and it was a
surreal experience, you know, like from,
from being a kid and thinking
like this is superman.
That's what I thought I was a kid.
It was just, you know what I mean?
Like seeing those when you see it as
a kid too, I think it's different.
Like you're just like,
whoa, that is so nuts.
Like these 11 second knock out
your periodic leaving to this day,
people come up to me and talk about
the experience that they feel.
How many talked about meeting
me through what that true.
It's honest. But you're telling me
it's on mostly stories that true. Yeah,
mostly stories. And it was a, it was a
surreal experience. And, and you know,
we spoke on the plane and, and then like
when I thought we were done talking,
you know, I face forward and then he came
back and like tap me on the shoulder.
I was like, Oh shit. Like Mike's talking
to me. I'm down here like the seatbelt,
seatbelt it in. But then we land and he
was like, Oh, where's your show? And, and,
and I go, oh, it's here. I gave him
the number, never expect to hear,
hits me up the next day. And he's like,
we're coming to your show. And I was like,
oh my God. And I really did say like, I'm
amazed that you're coming. And he said,
it's all love. And I just said, I
love you because I didn't know how to,
what to say. And then that
was good. He was like, cool.
He's like, all right man. And then I,
I remember I called the Pittsburgh Improv
manager and I go, hey man, I just go,
you're not gonna believe this, but Tyson's
coming to the fight tonight. He goes,
Mike Tyson, I go, no fucking
Tyson chicken. Yeah, Mike
Tyson's coming tonight.
He was like, I'll corridor off
a whole thing. And you know,
and I didn't know he was at the show
because the show had already started and I
didn't see him arrive. When we go back
to the green light after I the show,
I walk off stage and he grabs me and
he goes, let's go to the green room.
So he took me to my green room, right.
Like he would like and I was like,
fuck yeah.
And we hung out in that green room over
an hour and just shooting the shit and
talking. And when I forgot, like if at
the time had passed, I opened the door,
the entire staff,
entire staff is lined up
at the door to meet them.
Like that's the effect that
he has on the group. You know,
like they're waiting in a line for an
hour outside of the green room. And I,
you know, we talked about boxing about
life. It was, it was fascinating. Um,
one of the things I really appreciated
about, uh, you as a fighter was like,
that you really knew that you
were putting on a show. So that,
that's something that I feel
like I miss. You know, there's,
there's no one that put on
the show the way you did.
Like you knew that people bought
tickets and paid for the paper view. Um,
and then it, you know, it's still
like one of my great memories, man.
It was a thrill to meet you. Um, so I
just wanted to stop by and say hi, and
I do it.