The Joe Rogan experience. Uh, and
I go into the issue of Iowasca, uh,
in, in this book because I, first of all,
I [inaudible] is itself another
example of Amazonian Science. Um,
as you and I, and many of the
listeners and viewers know, uh,
the active ingredient of Iowasca
is DMT dimethyltryptamine,
but dimethyltryptamine is not normally
accessible through the gut. Uh,
we have to smoke it or,
or vape it to get that rocket
ship to the other side of reality.
And the journey lasts what,
10, 12 minutes, not much more
than that, and sometimes,
sometimes quite a lot less.
What Iowasca does is it makes
DMT available through the gut.
The reason it's not available through the
gut is because of an enzyme in the gut
called monoamine oxidase.
And that switch is off DMT on contact,
the Iowasca Vine, which is one of the
two ingredients of the IOWASCA brew.
The other ingredient is
leaves that contain DMT.
The IOWASCA vine contains Amano
Amy [inaudible] oxidase inhibitor,
which switches off the enzyme in the
gut and allows the DMT to be accessed
orally,
which produces a rather different journey
from the smoked or vaped DMT trip is a
much longer journey. It's four or five
hours. It allows you to integrate and to,
and to interrelate with the strange
landscapes in which you find yourself
amongst and the entities
that you encounter.
I'm not making any claims about the
reality status of those entities,
but what I am saying,
and it's a fact,
is that people who work with DMT and
Iowaska do encounter what they construe to
be entities, uh, who, who
communicate with them intelligently.
So somebody in the Amazon,
out of 150,000 different species of
plants and trees selected two that are not
psychoactive on their own,
but when put together,
create an extraordinary visionary brew,
uh,
and Iowasca means the vine of the
dead and what it's connected to, uh,
in South American religious
and spiritual thinking, uh,
is what happens to us when
we die. Uh, and, and, uh,
the Takano who are an Amazonian people
who work regularly with Iowasca.
I mean the,
no,
actually we'll give a teaspoon full
of Iowasca to a newborn infant.
They feel I ask is so important that
there is a hidden realm around us which we
are not normally aware of and
we need to be aware of it. Um,
and I'll ask it as an important part
of that. In their IOWASCA journeys,
the Tucano Schamens experience visions
and they will then come back to an alert,
normal problem solving
state of consciousness and
they will paint and depict
their visions. And what's intriguing,
and I, I go into it in the book,
is the quite a number of the tacamo
paintings of the other world of the
afterlife realm of the entrance to the
other world are geometrical and they look
exactly like the vehicle glyphs.
So I'm beginning to wonder whether these
geoglyphs we're part of a system of
spiritual ideas concerning what happens
to us after death and what we need to do
in this life to ensure a beneficial
outcome. And oddly enough,
that same system of ideas is found in
the Mississippi valley, in the Amazon.
It involves,
uh,
particularly Iowasca and the belief that
the IOWASCA journey takes you to the
afterlife realm and a journey along the
milky way in the Mississippi Valley.
Um, the mound builder sites up
and down the Mississippi Valley,
particularly Mountville in Alabama,
exactly the same system of religious
ideas associated with geometrical
constructions that on death the soul,
they're very specific ascends to the
constellation of Orion transits from the
constellation of Orion to the Milky Way
makes a journey along the Milky Way,
which they call the path of souls and
encounters challenges and or deals where
the soul must account for
the life that it has lived.
Then we got to Egypt and what do
we find the same system of ideas.
The soul must rise up to
the constellation of Orion.
There's a narrow shaft cut through the
southern side of the Great Pyramid of
Giza, which targets directly the lowest
of the three stars of Orion's belt,
widely accepted as a star
shaft or a sole shaft.
The soul would rise up through that shaft,
get to the Constellation of Orion,
which stands by the
banks of the Milky Way.
It would then transit to the Milky Way,
which they engined to Egyptians
called the winding waterway.
And it would make a journey along the
milky way where it would be confronted by
challenges and or deals,
very similar idea to the Chicano,
very similar idea to the Mississippi
valley as far as we know.
None of these cultures were
in contact with one another.
Either we're dealing with a huge,
unbelievable,
extraordinarily detailed coincidence
involving architecture and ideas.
Or we're looking at the legacy that
was inherited in all of these different
places from a remote common ancestor.
And,
and I believe that that's
what we're looking at.
What do we think the people from the
ancient Mississippi Valley though,
that culture,
what do we think they were using if they
weren't using Iowasca or do we think
that's what they were using? Well, that's,
that's, that's an interesting question.
Whether,
whether visionary substances are the
only way to get into altered states of
consciousness. And, and, uh, I would say
they, they, they are definitely not a,
of course there are visionary
substances which are,
which are used in native American,
uh, vision, vision quests. I've, I've,
I've had the privilege of Payoti ceremony,
uh,
with the native American church.
Um, I've never done that.
What does that look like? I loved it
actually. I thought, I thought it was,
I thought it was amazing.
It,
it doesn't overpower you in the way that
DMT and Iowaska does. Uh, it's, it's,
it's much gentler.
It's much more,
you feel much more integrated and
connected with, with, with nature.
Your thought processes are
quite, quite clear. It felt,
it felt just like a very
beautiful and healing experience.
And I loved the ceremony that I'm in.
I'm inside a teepee with,
with 30 or 40 other people and that there,
there are specific roles that are assigned
to those different individuals. One,
we'll keep the door,
another will be responsible for the fire,
which is a work of art in itself. Just
gazing into that fire. And the glowing,
the glowing embers is enough to induce
an altered state of consciousness on its
own. Incredible drumming, which,
which drives your state of consciousness
into a kind of peak peak experience.
This is a technology for accessing other
levels of experience and other levels
of reality.
And it's clear that the native Americans
had a number of advanced technologies
in this area. The Sundance doesn't use
a substance, but it uses austerity.
It uses pain to drive an
altered state of consciousness.
The objective in every case seems to be,
let's just for a while,
get ourselves out of the narrow, rigid
frame of the alert, problem solving,
state of consciousness. We all
need that. It's incredibly useful.
Hunter gatherer is needed just as
much as people in cities need it,
but it's not the only state of
consciousness available to human beings.
And maybe that's one of the big mistakes
that we're making in our culture. Um,
and was not made in,
in shamanistic societies.