The joe rogan experience.
Herod is right near the president's
2017 budget provides 69.4 billion in
discretionary funding. Is that,
but that's education. Yes.
This is for the education bill 139.7
billion in new mandatory funding for the u
s department of Education.
The budget's supports implementation
of every student succeeds act,
which embraces many of the reforms and
administration along as long supported to
improve outcomes for all students.
That also makes crucial investments that
build the administration's worked to
advance educational equity and excellence
support teachers and school leaders
promote college affordability
and completion. These include,
I think college should be free.
I think we could figure out
how to make college free.
I'm with Bernie Sanders on that.
It's a rare thing.
I just don't think you should
be in fucking debt up to
your ass hole by the time
you get out of school.
I think that's crazy.
It's a fucked up way to start your
life and people are like, well,
you want to make a little bit of,
it separates the people that really
want it and the people that no bullshit.
Just get stuck in debt and you
can't even get out of that debt.
It's not even a regular debt. It's
blood debt. Some weird debt but doesn't,
doesn't have a more educated society.
Help everybody. Everybody in the long run.
Sure.
How he'll make more money.
Everybody would make more money,
but you would have to like make sure
that whoever the fuck is teaching these
kids,
like you'd have to be real stringent with
what you're letting get pushed through
if you're going to throw
that much money on it.
There's a lot of shit bag and teachers
out there. We'd have to clean that up.
You know a lot of people is a lot of
shitbag teachers out there and I didn't
want to give him gun. That's the
dumbest shit of all time. I'm like,
I'm just the dummy shit.
That is the dumbest shit of all time.
Can't you can't expect teachers
to become soldiers. That's crazy.
That's not what they do. They're
not, they're not warriors.
They shouldn't be out there.
Have a firefights with
pilled up, you know, formal,
former high school students.
Yeah, it's fucking insane.
I don't know what the solution to that is.
Honestly,
I do not know what the solution is.
You know,
the NRA thinks it's having guns
everywhere. The anti second amendment.
People think it's getting
all the guns away. Um,
but you're not going to get all the
guns away. The thing about like,
people say guns don't kill people.
People kill people. I'm like, no,
people with guns kill people.
They definitely do hear exactly how much
the government would have to spend to
make public college tuition free.
How much do you think it is? Okay,
let me guess. 1 trillion
a year. Wait, wait, wait.
You left way less. Yeah. I would
say come on into this article.
Okay. What does it say on
about it, but what is, what
is the website? The Atlantic.
Okay. That's a left leaning
website but it can not ridiculous
dated.
This other article says 62
point $6 billion a mere 62
but there's updates on the
bottom of the article that said,
that's some readers say that's an
addition to what they already spend.
So that makes it maybe double,
well, you know, one way they
make it really fucking cheap,
have it available for free online.
Everybody should be able
to get an education online.
That's what I really firmly believed that
I think they should have courses that
you could just sign up and take
them like a regular college course.
You don't have to be in a physical
location anymore. That's so retro.
That's so unnecessary.
Get in your car and get
the traffic and go to UCLA.
The only thing good about that as you're
in the room with someone like a Jordan
Peterson or some really good professor
that's really inspirational and you're in
there with him and they talked to
you and like you're like, oh, okay.
And you get to like be in
their presence and see like,
oh this guy was probably like my age one
day and he figured all this shit down
and like, oh, maybe
some extra juice to that
to have a bookmark saved.
I think it was Harvard I,
it was a long list of us recorded
lectures that were from any class.
I think there's probably was a limit
to what they were doing. Right.
Definitely not accessible anymore,
especially for the public,
but it was fully accessible. Anybody
that wanted, that's why I had it saved.
Hmm. I don't know Joe. I mean, let me
think about that. Like I said earlier,
like all these formulas
fit into different things.
You say that and it's like you can be at
home while you're looking at them on a
screen and I'm learning versus being
in the same room and it's like,
yeah.
But like you could also go to a strip
club and watch strippers dance or he could
be at home watching some porn and
when you're at home watching him,
you're going to pull it out,
rip one. Hmm. You know? Right.
So you're saying, let's say it's
like if you're at home station home,
you just going to beat off.
That's, that's a real problem. You know?
Uh, Louis C K was saying once the, uh,
he has a computer that he writes on,
it's not connected to the Internet
because you just can't get distracted.
Forced himself to,
I think that's what I'm saying.
The problem is the
distraction with having,
having access to everything
right there. That's true. Um,
when you opened the window with the
teacher, that's, that's, that's the part.
It's discipline, it's discipline. And
that, that goes back to what I believe.
That ties back into what I was saying
before about all this entertainment out
there. Everybody, everybody's,
it is always like scratching
at you like, hey day,
pay attention to me.
Give me something to do.
[inaudible].