That's silly. And what would you do
without the tourist? Yeah, you should. Uh,
I think Roseanne's going to
actually fucking make money
off a macadamia nut farm.
I think she's going to be out
selling fucking nuts somewhere. Oh,
she never, she never, I think I told you,
she called me again and goes,
I am, I'm ready to do Rogan.
We've been going back and forth.
Right.
Well now she says she's gonna do her
own podcast. We're going to do it.
It's just going to take time. You know, I
told, this is what I told her. She said,
she contacted me the day says I'm ready
to do it whenever you are. I said,
you just tell me when and we'll do it.
And then we're trying to figure out,
I'm in Salt Lake City and I'm on,
I understand house.
There was a little bit of that and then,
you know,
she's just trying to figure
out when's the right time.
But she said she wants to do her
own youtube channel and she's,
she's upset at everybody and,
and I felt like, you know,
she's, there's a lot of merit
and what she's saying, you know,
I really do think she got
fucked over. I think, uh,
I really do think she made a joke about
a woman that she didn't know it was
black and a woman who's, I think
she's only one eighth black, right?
Is that what she did? I saw the picture
and I like, Oh, I get it now. She goes,
not talked to her on the
phone afterwards or she goes,
she was asking me for advice and
she said I, I really fucked up.
And I honestly didn't think she was black.
And then she goes,
did you ever deal ambien?
I go,
that's exactly why I stopped doing ambien.
And
I'm sure that's why she tweeted that.
Where I like to just talk about this
on Rogan Cause Rogan spends time,
you can explain stuff. Stop fucking
tweeting. Tweet where she goes,
hell I did take an ambien. Yeah,
you drink on Ambien and your fuck.
I can tell you a million stories
of normal people like fucking,
you know Judy Brown,
her husband,
Steve Marmel almost had a plane
grounded cause he on a flight,
he took an Ambien and had a couple of
bourbons and then just started going
fucking batch.
It has no recollection of it and I've
done stuff that was like minor where I
just had a very lucid
business conversation with
Hannigan after I'd taken an
Ambien on my,
like a light night of drinking for me,
which six or seven beers and I went to
bed and then I get get up 15 minutes
later and went out and had this very
lucid business conversation that I don't
remember it all and I brought
it up to him the next day.
Something we were going to talk about.
He goes,
we've talked about this last night.
He's like, yes, you came out.
I go, no, I went to bed.
But what you came out shortly after you
seem to vary like completely normal.
Wow. Kevin James, uh, uh, he made dinner.
He, uh, went downstairs, made
his own dinner, cooked it,
ate it, went back to bed, got up in the
morning and was like, who the fuck cooked?
Yeah. And then they're there like you did.
He's like, no, I didn't. He goes like, no.
Yeah, you did look, hey, you throw
this away like you, you cook this.
Like what the fuck are you talking to
his brother? You remember my ax Renee,
her brother and his
buddy took some ambience,
had a minor amounts of cocktails,
woke up on a lawn in a neighborhood they
didn't know where they were geniuses
and that's where it was that one lucid
business conversation where you go,
that could have been me driving my car
into someone's front fucking porch.
So yeah,
I s I s I swore it off.
My Mom said that she took it and uh,
no booze,
just took the Ambien and wound
up drawing on a, a bathroom,
a carpet, you know, in
the little bathroom rugs,
just drawing on it with like lipstick and,
and nail Polish doesn't have
any recollection of doing it.
Just drawing on it like a
little kid would, would they
pull out the nail Polish?
Just start. That's a weird
thing. It's called a hypnotic,
that's what they, they call
that, that category of drugs.
The other thing with Roseanne is like she,
well she got serious mental illness
and she's on a bunch of different
medications. Well she's got legit
multiple personality disorder.
She's talked about it and I don't
think they call it multiple personality
disorder anymore. I think they have a
new name for it, but it's just a noise.
Rebranding fucking mental
illnesses like come on man.
It's like this is what it is.
It is multiple personality disorder.
She has a bunch of different
people and you know,
if you talked to people that had been
around her and see or switch from
personality to personality,
you realize like,
Oh and you know a lot of this
also came from head trauma.
She's one of several comedians that
became a different person because of head
trauma. I think she was hit by a car
as well. Sam Kennison, same thing.
Hit by a car and also she was
in a car accident. I don't,
I don't know if it was
child molestation or
rape and disassociative identity disorder.
That's what they're calling it now.
And she also can't fucking
tell the difference between
Twitter and a green room
because if every single
comic like was recorded,
the dark shit that we say in green rooms,
because we're comics and we
say the worst possible thing,
especially to make each other laugh
cause you go to the darkest areas and you
say all the wrong words and you say the
most racist thing to your black comic
friend and he says the fucking worst
thing to you about your fucking ugly
fucking teeth or you're fat
or you're fucking stupid.
And if she walked into the green
room and said that about that lady,
we would be laughing, right?
We'd be laughing. Especially
if we know who she was.
I didn't know actually saying something
racist. You'd look at the picture and go,
I don't get it. I had no
understanding of who that woman was.
I never had heard of it until
Roseanne got fired. And I was like,
who is this lady? And she's saying
she's the Muslim Brotherhood.
And then Roseanne said, did she thought
she was Jewish? I was like, okay,
if you think she was black,
I thought she was Jewish.
And then I wa I looked at the picture.
I go, all right, well yeah, the fucking,
that's a,
that's not a cut and dry one.
If you read two years
of Roseanne's tweets,
that would not be the one that stood
out as if she just says fucking insane
stuff. That makes no sense all the
time. Did she say that Susan Rice,
she said she was a, a great big, uh, uh,
big ape with no a man.
Oh,
she's a man with giant
swinging eight balls.
This was like five years ago and then
five years later they give her that said
common can't believe she's acting crazy.
That's I completely fault ABC
seen a fucking cash cow that nope,
they,
they thought they could handle or hey,
we can make a lot of money
by giving a toddler a pistol.
We know what else she said. She felt
like she has promised not to. What?
She's selfish. She felt like she was being
removed from the creative process too.
Like there was a bunch of things going
on even before this and that this was
like one of the final steps,
but that they were,
she was having a hard time with the whole
process and she was definitely having
a hard time with being overworked.
She's like [inaudible] out about
the Illuminati and Zion is,
maybe we should get you out of
the writer's room. Would not,
wouldn't be a bad idea to do an episode
about her thinking that everything is
the Illuminati mean that's fucking gold
comedy there. There's so much there.
I had explained to her chem trails like,
but the thing is different than anybody
that I've ever talked to about these
kind of wacky conspiracy theories.
When I explained to her what, what,
how those clouds are made, she
went, oh, okay. She just let it go.
Like most of them don't fucking let
it go. If you tell them that, well,
you see those planes, they're spraying
overhead and you go, no, no, no.
It's the heat of the engine,
the condensation and the atmosphere.
It's actually creating a cloud.
It's just the water vapor and mixes
with the heat. Of this engine.
It makes clouds. It's all it
is. Roseanne discos. Okay.
Like just let it go like everybody
else, like bullshit, man.
There's fucking documents. There's
papers. The CIA's admitted it.
It's one of the hardest things in the
world when you get a stupid conspiracy
theory in your head. It's
one of the hardest things
the world is to just go, oh,
that might people shit.