They separated them. When Damien had one
hook in, he was trying to take us back.
Dude was that fucking homeboy,
the guy who kept saying got it.
You were seeing people were scared of him,
but he wasn't beating anybody.
That was world class. He wasn't, he wasn't
getting those top 10 guys. Amy, Maya,
right. Yeah. We got same to Damien.
Maia fight will forever be marred by
the fact that they separated them.
When Damien had one hook and
he was trying to take us back,
dude was that fucking homeboy,
the guy who kept [inaudible] him
up with that daughter. Oh my God,
I don't know what he's doing.
Or you didn't see who that was?
Go go to Damien Maia versus um,
Camaros.
Huseman and see who, who separated
them. Cause the Ref Matt, uh, Matt,
the Terra Sarah was going fucking
crazy about that. And he's 100% right.
Do you know how difficult it is to get a
hold of a guy like Ooh, spawn like that.
And to have one hook in,
standing up and to be working to take
us back and for them to separate him,
it is nonsense. Pure nonsense. How
much harder it is. That's hard. Yeah.
How much harder is to take
Woodley down and control him? Yes.
And then you stand them up. Yup. Yup. If
a moose man, what the fuck are you doing?
Do you mean you stop and think
that you should come down?
You stop and think about Damien Maia
his last fight. Right? Who the fuck?
Who the fuck did he just
choked unconscious fuck out
of? Who was that? Who Was it?
Who did he just choke out someone really
good, um, kid that they fed. Okay.
So here it is. That's not Goddard.
Who is it? Uh, is the bald feller.
Which bald feller? So
here's, um, so here's a,
it's hard to tell who that referee is.
I can't see the face.
So it loose man in them. They're,
they're exchanging ooze. My cracked him.
Who is it? I was it Chris Taione.
I know two referees. I know three.
No. Um, it's Leon.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well for whatever reason,
what was God thinking though?
I don't know what he was thinking. And
then he's shade online at Jon. Anik.
What'd he say in your commentary was off.
So it was annex.
You got my commentary was on. Yeah.
Okay. I don't know what I did to say.
I didn't say anything bad about
Mark Goddard. I said I don't,
I disagree with them standing up.
I don't know why he said
the commentary was off,
but Dominick Cruz did say
that he can't wrestle.
And the reason why he's standing him up
is cause he can't wrestle. Mark honored.
Yes. No, he said though he's, he was
saying that about Mark Goddard. Correct?
You've said the referee can't
wrestle. He threw shade. It got her.
I have nothing but respect for God.
Although I don't agree with
his decision in that fight.
I do not agree with standups.
I don't like stand up garden.
He's a great referee in that
moment. He's wrong. Well,
he's probably not very emotional.
Listen, your job is not to intervene.
The trajectory of the fight, right?
Your job is to protect the fighters.
No one fuck up. Ooh. Spins. Biggest
fight of his life by standing up.
Because what happens to
this and we've seen it.
Why would it be stood them up and boldly
goes, you know what, fine. I feel good.
Knocks him out. Right. You got it.
It can happen. Yeah, it can happen.
What did he say about me?
He didn't specifically call
you off. He didn't call you.
I suppose what he say but, but,
but the only thing wildly inconsistent
is your and your cocoms commentators
recollection. Observation of actual
events. I will look Joe Rogan's ass.
That's wrong. So rude. I didn't
see that. I just made that up.
The only thing wildly inconsistent
is your and your cocoms recollection.
Observation of actual events.
I'll save my side for later.
Well that doesn't make any sense.
Recollection of actual events.
I don't know what he's trying to say
there and cocoms I didn't say anything bad
about them other than that.
I don't agree with the standups
and that's not bad job.
But Dominick Cruz said that he can't
wrestle and I don't know if mark odic or
Russell, I know he knows how to
referee compared to Dominick Cruz.
He cannot wrestle.
So Dominic's fine to say that.
But also John Annika and harden
the paints. Awesome. Yeah,
I like that you are way off.
What's wildly,
wildly inconsistent is correct cause
herb dean is the gold standard in my
opinion.
And Herb Dean,
even though he did that thing with
Robbie Lawler is controversial,
kind of look at it and I go, the arm
went limp and see how he made that.
I see that. I could see I, I'm,
I think it's unfortunate and
it may have been a mistake,
but it might not have been a mistake.
I, I'm, I'm, I'm still, I'm still,
I'm not at all, not a look man. His job,
his fucking way harder than
mine a hundred times harder.
Heard Herb Dean's job is to protect the
fighters and to stop fights and to make
calls.
I don't want to be that guy that I
thought that guy gets fucking hated on it.
Never loved herb. Never gets low.
And like no one ever gets love,
but with more daughter don't be the
guy tried to, John replied, he said,
I always try to be respectful.
We just call it like we see it too.
But there's an arrogance with
which you deal with the fighters,
commentators and many in this sport.
And I find it off putting, whoa.
One man's take.
And I'm quite sure you'll give
yours to for everyone to hear.
Why not manic stone am Dan.
I'm okay.
So I believe John Eck referred to the
inconsistent between each referees
decisions of when to separate the
fighters. And John said exactly.
That's what I was referring to,
that that two of the consensus,
Beth best referees of the
game would handle those two
situations so differently.
I understand the athletes are different,
but there are parallels to be drawn.
John is 100% correct. Hundred percent a
hundred percent correct. And I'm at us,
Bro. I'm, I'm, I'm,
I feel bad that Mark Goddard responded
the way he did because it's not very
professional and I think it's very
emotional and I think he's probably just
feeling the heat. Yeah.
Yeah. Hard on them. Yeah.
You feel that heat and you get angry,
you know. But uh, I liked Mark Goddard,
a lack of Milan and I think he's a very
good refereeing top one or two reps in
the business. I love mark
daughter. He fucked that up.
My question is I wonder who is telling
them they should stand things up and when
they shouldn't stand things up.
I wonder if pressure he for pressure
you feel from the audience you think the
crowd maybe it could be that
British people are very nice.
You know sometimes an
English people that man,
when you got to worldclass wrestlers
and this guy is impossible. Take down.
He's one of the best of all time. Yup. Let
it go. Let it go. Well I think let it go.
Period.
I just,
I do not agree with standups cause I think
of a guy can hold you down like this.
What I was saying about Ben
Astron if guy look, Ben asked her,
you can hold you down and give you nuggies
until the fight's over to something
about it. Exactly. It's not cheating
if he's not cheating, keep it up.
Do you know how hard is to control
Woodley on the gown and the only outside
fucking minutes you have five
minutes to sink a choke in,
five minutes to hold onto him and
beat him up and uh, look, look,
awkward it to this man. He didn't
even fucking care. He gets to buck up,
didn't complain where right back at
them and took them down again and again.
He's a monster and cool story, Bro. He is
fucking hard to deal with man. For Colby,
for everyone on the planet earth.
But stylistically,
when you look at the fight for Colby,
I look at like Colby does well, yeah,
he does that. He does that. The thing
about loose man is he's got power.
He's got striking,
he's got wrestling,
but even maybe more
courtly Rto for days here.
Oh, it's fine. Mine's a fucking
bank fault. It's Fort Knox.
I'm so impressed. How adorable was it?
Him and his little daughter. Oh Dude,
I almost cried. Just such a bitch who
I'm such a bitch pussy that I have kids.
Me Too. Me Too. I'm like, I know.
So cute. And just how happy
mom and wife for real extra,
they're like P diddy and a bad video
extra.
Hey man, he, he's so bad the world.
Could you imagine what it feels like to
have your husband when the fucking world
world welterweight title to beat Tyron
Woodley? No, I can't block out my wife.
Take a hot bath.
The fuck out of here.
And my mom sure as fuck wouldn't
be in the case. Hey Man.
I feel like when someone wins like that,
they can do whatever they want. Me.
Carter's mom's always in the cage is dads.
That's true.
Thrown out promo codes.