Right? Here's one that people had an
issue with w and one thing you could say.
Okay. Um, like, uh, when Kathy Griffin
held up the, the, the Trump head,
remember that? Um, did she do that
on her own Twitter account? Uh, yeah.
She, yeah, she, well, I mean she
posted a photo of it, which she posted.
She posted an Instagram,
Twitter, I think it was on both.
I'm not a hundred percent
sure. Right. So that it's,
is it allowed?
It's allowed because it's newsworthy
because it's a celebrity and the celebrity
is threatening a public figure who is
also the most powerful person in the
world. So it's okay.
It's that why that is,
I think she posted it because it was an
art piece that was kind of controversial.
Oh, no, no, I know that.
And that's what I'm saying.
Why they're saying why is it okay,
why is she still allowed to be on the
platform? And Alex Jones case kicked off.
That's a, it's an
interesting question, right?
Like what do you need
to do to get kicked off?
Because that's not the only thing
that Kathy has done, um, recently.
She was one of the people that was calling
for the name for that young boy who
was, um, with that native American in
front of his face beating the drum. She's,
it's crazy, irresponsible. You know?
I'm sure she feels bad
about it now in retrospect,
especially if she's watched the video,
but she got carried away and she thought,
what we all thought when
you saw the picture,
there's smirking cunt of a kid that got
in the face of this beautiful indigenous
man is singing, is his rain dance
cry. Whatever the fuck is doing. Yeah.
That's not what it was though.
We,
we found out afterwards it was much
more complicated. What is their song?
What were they saying? It sounded
cool. They should make a record. Yeah.
Do you like that shit? That shit's
cool to listen to when you work out.
If you could get like some,
some legit native American chance,
like that puts you into a trance,
right?
If you don't know what they're saying
and you'd just go running and you listen
to that. Take a little
couple Tokes, go for,
go for a jog in the woods, listening to
native American chance on your airpods.
Ooh, that was an interesting
video though, because I mean,
I was a one 80 after just hearing
the second side of the story,
like 12 hours later, people still were
calling for that guy's head. Yeah.
And people, I saw someone who said,
um, what's his name? Ron Perlman?
No, who's the guy who was a Hellboy?
Yeah, Ron Perlman. Ron Perlman was like,
motherfuckers are telling me that,
uh, I'm not seeing what I'm seeing.
And she said something about some white
prick or white motherfucker. I'm like,
oh, okay. People try so hard. Like you,
you are seeing what you're seeing. Yeah.
You're seeing what you're saying. Well,
you're not seeing is a video that
shows how it occurred. It's all it is.
Yeah. You know? So why is that
okay? Right. Why is that okay?
Why is it okay for some journalists to
say horrible things about white people?
Why is that okay? Why is
that okay? It seems weird.
What if it encourages violence against
a innocent white person? Just one.
Should you be responsible? What if
they say, why did you do that? Well,
I read Blah Blah, blahs a tweet
and I was like, you know what,
I am going to go out and punch
a white person. Fuck that.
I just found some white
old lady not beat her ass.
Like if someone decides that you're not
responsible for that. All right. Yeah,
probably not.
But you kind of kind of feel like you
played a part in the way people look at
things, especially people that are
very easily influenced, you know?
It's just also, it's gross.
He read something really
racist against white people.
They like, that's gross. Like you
think all all people. I like that.
A whole group of people that don't
have as much melanin, they're all shit.
That's ridiculous.
You're ridiculous person.
I don't care if you're brown or black or
yellow, you're ridiculous. That's silly.
It's we have to decide
to get to decide like what the fuck
we're doing and we keep letting illogical
behavior be normal.
Like breaking us off into fucking groups
like that and thinking that, you know,
all men are great, or all women or
gray or all gays or grade and every,
all straight cisgendered man can go
fuck themselves. All right, that's,
that's silly talk. I don't care who
you are. You're not allowed to do that.
But we let people do that.
If they're a part of a marginalized class,
if someone's a part of a marginalized
class, then you get to shit on everybody.
In a weird way, you get to like
reinforce racism. It's really,
it's so fucking counterproductive too,
because if you do that,
then it just makes people just
get defensive on the other side.
They don't even want to even think
or empathize with how you are.