For me,
the only way to do that is to talk about
my life and the things that grow along
with me.
The only thing that grows along with me,
my experiences, my family,
my marriage, my mistakes,
my ups,
my downs.
Those are the things that I can talk
about forever because as you get older,
things change.
Shit gets different.
But it's all coming from
my personal opinion of me,
my view on me and how I see life.
You can't lose material in a state.
That's why I stay away from certain
things because those things can become
boring after awhile for me because I don't
have the knowledge of everything that
I should kind of, well, politics,
I don't joke. And the politics,
I don't,
I don't joke.
And anything that has to do with the
slander of others or other communities,
I don't do anything divisive. Good for
you. That's my, that's my biggest thing.
And you know, uh, this past year was,
was one that got a little
weird because I was like, Yo,
I've really dedicated myself to
bringing people together. Like,
um, I love, that was my, my goal.
That's my priority at Damn Shadow.
That's what I was doing on a global scale.
Everybody, all races, shapes, sizes,
whoever you are, whatever you are,
you can come to a Kevin Hart
show and have a good time.
So when it came off as if I
was a person that was divisive,
that was tough. You're talking about
the Oscars Oscar Shit. Yeah, like this
time where people were just looking to
be upset about things 100% they're not
looking to looking at you, Kevin Hart
as just a human being, like what? What?
Who is he overall super positive.
They're not even concentrating on that.
I mean,
think about how positive you are and yet
they tried to concentrate on some jokes
that you did what,
nine years ago?
It was a, it's a, it's a wake up
call of understanding the towns,
but then more importantly, you know,
for me it was okay, I went through it.
I made sure that the people of the
Lgbtq community really understand that,
hey guys, I apologize before,
but I'm apologizing again.
I'm sorry I'm not that guy.
I don't want you to think I'm that guy.
Then it just became the constant
conversation that never happened.
It just became a constant
conversation. And, and now it is guys.
I'm not only sorry,
I don't condone anything that
has to do with hate to anybody.
This is no longer a conversation.
So guys,
I'm going to stop talking about it because
now I feel like I'm feeding into what
I'm not.
I,
I know I'm not the world in public
should understand and know to them that
because over this time period
I've shown that I'm not.
So the apology, once again, I'm sorry,
genuinely, I'm sorry, but
it just kept, it just,
it never stopped. And at that point I
just made a decision and I'm like, guys,
at this point, I just am making a
decision to not talk about it anymore.
That doesn't mean to them
being disrespectful to anybody.
That doesn't mean to them shutting
down anything. It means that for me,
I'm going to stop talking about it because
at this point I don't know what to do.
At this point. I thought, I thought the
apology is what you wanted me to do. I do.
Uh, I made sure that you understand it.
I'm not a hateful person. I don't get,
don't hate. I did that. I stepped down.
So I don't take attention
off of that night.
And those people that are
there to be celebrated,
I don't want to draw attention to myself
and what's around me. I stepped down.
Everything I did was for
the better of good. I'm,
I'm stepping away guys,
because I don't want this to be a
negative night or a negative thing.
And then it still became a conversation.
So I waited for it to die down.
I went on my radio show,
gave another public apology.
May should have he
understand and I'm sorry,
I hope these words didn't hurt anybody.
I once again apologize.
I don't condone hate to anyone.
I hope that you guys can forgive
me for those jokes of all.
So now I say, if you don't understand
and that you don't believe it,
I don't know what else to give.
I don't know what else to do.
There's nothing else you can
do that's very wise of you.
Nothing that's very wisely to step
away, locked up. Because if you didn't,
they would probably pursue it forever.
But I mean,
it becomes a point of attention.
That's all it is.
They just decide that this is something
that they're going to focus on. What a,
I had a, I had a good talk, and I'm
talking about this for a minute.
Friend of mine, Lee Daniels, you know,
me and Lee Daniels, uh, Lee called me,
told me where to talk to them. You
know, Lou Daniel's is director,
a producer, the show empires,
this biggest shows, um,
you know, so he calls me, he's like, Kevin
won't talk to you. And, and us talking,
he's like,
look,
this is a time where you
could speak up and talk about,
you know,
the community that's been
affected by hatred and you know,
hateful crimes.
You can step up and be a voice and
say that you don't condone or don't,
uh, stand with any type of
hate or whatever. You can
take that stage and do that.
And I said, Lee, I said, let's understand
what you're saying. I said, well,
why did you expect me to know what's
been happening within this community in
regards to hate and crimes? I
said, I, I'm not aware. I said,
some people can just not be aware.
I'm not in the know.
I have no idea what's going on.
I have no idea.
Community within that community,
When you tell me this,
I'm now educated and I understand,
so it's easy to simply inform,
right?
Information is key. When people get
information, they process the information.
When you can process the information, you
go, oh, wait a minute. That makes sense.
Hey, if you guys think that I
can, don't hate, wait a minute,
I don't in anybody that does, fuck
you, man, as bad you shouldn't.
I can say that,
but instead when this happened,
it was become an ally,
become a voice and that's,
that's where there was
just a miscommunication.
That's where a back and forth kind of
was establish that I think people just
started to take things and run with it,
and I'm just not,
I'm just not one to feed into what I feel
isn't going to eventually evolve into
a positive thing in a real
conversation. Yes. Yeah. When I'm,
when I'm trying my best to,
it was becoming tablet bullshit pretty
much took a real discussion, clickbait,
clickbait.