That's an expert over there I have to
do with it. Loves it. He gets crazy.
He'll come back and tell you who's dating,
who they run the Twitter and all
the means of it all comes from,
they run Twitter.
Why do you like 25% of Twitter memes
and everything is coming out of black
Twitter, 25% did you do the
math? It's known fact Bro.
Like Bro, I didn't pluck it out of my
ass. Okay. Um, speaking of social media,
have you seen all these purges recently?
There's a new round of it that
just happened. No. Who got purge,
800 or 800 or more accounts were purged
from Facebook and Twitter and they're
all almost all alternative media accounts.
So some of the sites are snowflakes was
one I think on Facebook there's another
one called anti media that was purged.
They're an antiwar media thing.
Free thought project is another one
this and there was cop watch police.
The police was one of them
that was called. So basically,
and what they're saying is it's such
a bullshit argument. They said, oh,
the reason we pulled this is
because it's inauthentic behavior.
We're pulling these accounts because
there's inauthentic behavior on those
accounts. What does that mean?
I don't know. That's the point.
And they never clarified. So what I think
it means is, hey, these are, you know,
these are alternative media outlets
and we want to get rid of them,
so we're just gonna get rid of him.
Because Facebook,
I know met with the Israeli government
and Israel told them, hey, listen,
if you're going to be in our country,
you're going to get rid
of certain accounts.
And Facebook went right along and said,
sure, we'll do that. China with Google.
Right? But now I think they're doing
that in the u s now, I think there, yes.
I think they're working in
cahoots with the u s government.
And so you have all these alternative
media counselors specifically, you know,
antiwar, what have you anticorruption
some of these are okay,
and they're getting purged. No. The
argument was inauthentic behavior. Yes.
That was one of the reasons they
cited as to why they got rid of them.
Inauthentic behavior.
Does that mean that they're talking about
instances that they're misrepresenting?
No, I think it means more like
bots. That's how I interpreted
it. Like, Oh, you know,
you're posting it and you're directing
people to your own, you know, stuff and,
but I just, everybody does
that on Facebook and Twitter.
Is it possible that that's what
was going on? I don't know.
I'm just asking is it possible they were
using bots and perhaps directing them
towards revenue creating sites,
but my whole thing is why
shouldn't that be allowed? Well,
I'm not saying that it
shouldn't be allowed,
but is it possible that they were using
stories that were taking place in the
news,
distorting those stories to get people
to click it on things that would have
links to ways that these
people can make money.
So instead of it being some sort of
political activism website that really was
just a revenue generating bullshit site
that was trying to drum up artificial
outrage. I think for some of them it's
certainly possible, but certainly not.
Certainly not for the free
thought project. What does
it free thought project?
It's,
it's another one of these,
I think they described themselves as like
an antiestablishment or anticorruption
um, you know thing where they cover
all these stories related to government
corruption,
kind of like a wiki leaks type thing
except they don't do the Wiki leaks,
does more of the original reporting
stuff and they'll just cover it after the
fact. And how many people Facebook deleted
them? Facebook, I think I read them.
I think there was an article
in the Guardian, Jamie,
if you're interested in pulling it up,
it's um, Facebook and Twitter purge. Uh,
you know it was 800 sites.
So when you mix it was like,
I think it was mostly on Facebook,
like 600 or so on Facebook and the
200 or so on Twitter that they did.
And a lot of them were like one of the
accounts had over 3 million people who
liked it. Now the free
thought project that, what has
their response been to this?
I don't know. I don't know cause
I only saw the original article.
I haven't seen anything after it.
You know,
this is a discussion that I was
having with already the other day.
We were taught here it is.
First they came for Alex Jones.
We told you you are next. We're,
oh, we were next. We were,
this is on their website.
Um,
but they did cover it in the Guardian
and some other outlets in case anybody is
thinking that this is bs. Yeah. Good.
It is a scary time because you see
that this can impact, you know,
really anybody who's not toeing the line,
if you will, like a police. The police.
Are we really gonna like do we really
think that they pulled that down?
Not for the obvious reason,
which is that you're sowing discord and
the police don't like it as part of its
purge. Facebook has removed the pages
of several police accountability,
watchdog critic groups,
including Copblock,
the free thought project
and police the police.
They've also apparently
severely restricted.
The activity for the
photography is not a crime page.
Huh. So you think they're getting
pressure from law enforcement?
I don't,
I don't know.
But I never usually believe in a
smoke filled backroom conspiracies,
but they're starting to get hard to
avoid because there's so many of these
things, man. Um, scroll down
please. Here's what we need.
Look at this and how does this poem,
and again says first they
came for Alex Jones and fours,
but I wasn't race baiting transfer
Spirasi cultists to claims for murdered
children.
Newtown.
Where are hoaxes and admitted in court
that I'm just an entertainer who makes
shit up? So I said nothing. Yeah,
they're just trying to be flipping
about how Alex Jones was pulled.
The problem was once you bought into the
principle of Alex Jones being polled,
well then what you're saying is people
who are executives at these companies can
willy nilly decide whoever
they want to pull down.
Now my answer to that has always been
we should take Twitter, Facebook,
these giant social media pages.
They can still be private companies,
but we should regulate them like
their public utilities. Yeah.
That's the argument that our Arya
and I were discussing a hundred per,
that's the only answer because you
need to default to free speech. Now,
I'm not saying if somebody is doxing
somebody or if somebody is directly
threatening somebody and stuff like that,
there should be a process set up where
you can ameliorate that and do it quickly.
But having said that, like
people forget man, the Acl,
you used to defend the KKK in clause,
so would already brought up. Yes,
and they said, hey, in
Skokie they said, hey listen,
we know we don't agree with these people.
We think they're heinous.
We think they're terrible,
we think they're dead wrong,
but they have a right to say what they're
saying because once you get rid of it
for them,
what people don't realize though is
that these things will always come back
against people who are
powerless and marginalized.
It's not like when you censor,
everybody gets together and we all go,
okay, so it's just the Nazis, right? Yes.
It's just the Nazis. No, first
of all, who's running these?
You know these organizations,
obviously they have their own opinions
and their own vested interests and their
own power dynamic issues and they're
going to take down whoever threatens their
power
now is are all these
organizations is still up on
youtube and Twitter and Google?
I don't know it.
To my knowledge,
the only one that totally got pulled
down everywhere I think was Alex Jones.
He still has it
website here.
It says all but proving the case that
this was a coordinated attack by the tech
giant community. Shortly after the purge
on Facebook, Twitter followers out,
wiping out our profiles on there as well.
They gave absolutely no
reason for the suspension.
Said we had close to the
Freethought umbrella, had
close to 6 million followers.
Wow. Isn't that crazy? And
they just decided overnight.
What's crazy is I didn't even hear
about things. Well, that's why I'm here.
I appreciate it. Yeah. I mean I had
heard that it was 800 different pages,
but the way I had read it and I had,
unfortunately I don't have a lot of time
and I was flipping through something.
I had read that it was a lot of um,
anti-police pages.
Some of them were anti police, but
I think um, a lot of them were not.
A lot of them were antiestablishment anti
corruption like they've always had it
out for wikileaks. For
example, Wiki leaks as well.
I mean you've had Mike pump pale one of
the top Trump administration officials
because it says they're like a non
state terrorist actor. Think about that.
That's nuts.
That is because basically what they do
is what registered reporters should say,
hey,
here's what the bad guy,
here's what the people in the government
are doing and this is the stuff that
they're keeping secret that they shouldn't
keep secret and our government goes,
oh,
that's terrorism.
Now when Twitter or one of these people,
one of these organizations, bands,
something like the free thought project,
do they make any statements
or they just remove them all?
I saw what was on the Guardian article
and on the Guardian they said it was
inauthentic behavior was the reason why
they were pulling them and maybe one or
two other things that I'm
forgetting at the moment.
That is a fucking weird statement.
I know. Authentic behavior. Yeah.
Yeah. It's fucked up man. Cause they could
just do it to anybody. That's the point.
And that's what's so scary. Well that is
what's scary, right, is that there are,
they are private companies and these
people are allowed to post on them until
they decide they're not allowed to post
on it because they violate their terms
of service.
But when your terms of service are
that open ended inauthentic behavior,
like what the fuck does that even mean?
So they just,
they leave the terms of
service purposefully vague
so that they can get away
with knocking off wherever
they want to knock on.
It's just weird that they all agreed
that Facebook agreed and Twitter agreed.
Like what would be the incentive
of Twitter to follow suit?
Will it be the incentive
space back room I but what,
what do you think is given to,
if he had a speculate. Okay.
What do you think would be given to them
that would give them the incentive to
want to pull a site?
That's what I like that Jack Dorsey
guys seems pretty progressive.
I think they are meeting
just like what we said,
we know they did this with Israel where
they pulled down pro Palestinian human
rights pages to allow Facebook
to function in their country.
They said you have to do x, y, and Z.
I think that there are meetings with,
I don't know exactly who
it is. Our intelligence
agencies, law enforcement, FBI,
I don't know.
Somebody like that.
Maybe Ceos of various corporations
where they say, hey man, listen,
the these people are problem.
These people are problem.
These people are a problem.
Let's do the right thing here.
I would like to hear a contrary argument.
Well, I would like to know Emilia,
I would like to know like what is the,
what is the contrary argument?
Is there anything that we're missing?
If we want,
we could try to find the guardian article
and read what they said, what Twitter,
what Twitter and Facebook says,
see if you could find that.
You know the Guardian article. It's not
coming up. Pulled it off the Internet.
Guardian. What did, what was the headline?
I searched it and went on news and like
there was no articles from the Guardian.
By the way, the only two,
the only two things I found,
the only two things I founded on our
t and the Guardian and nothing else.
Which is why you didn't hear about it
because mainstream media didn't talk about
it. Because guess what? These outlets,
oftentimes our competition in
mainstream media, what the fuck man
that is.
So the Alex Jones thing is really like
a test run almost pretty much searching
on their website,
on the Guardian website.
We thought project it's
using Google to do it.
And the top article is something of for
for about food and 2013 well when we get
off here, I'll do a search and we could
see if we could find the statement. Yeah.
But when we get on fairs not helping
all those people that use us right now,
they saw from the free thought project,
I'll find it.
They saw the article from the free
thought project and that says the same
information.
We just don't have the exact statement
from Twitter and Facebook on it.
That's the only thing I see.
If you can just Google statement
from Twitter readout was involved.
The free thought that
wasn't in the article,
they just threw it in the
middle of the article.
It said it was like Facebook and
Twitter purges, uh, accounts for,
I don't know if it's at an
authentic behavior in the title,
but it was in the article somewhere.
So you really think that there's some
sort of smokey back room deals where they
say, listen to you, you guys
are making tons of money.
We've got a bit of an issue here.
Let's work through this.
This is what we want removed. These
people are causing us a bunch of problems.
I don't know, but I, I do
know they did that in Israel.
I do know they do that in all these
countries where the governments say, hey,
in order to function here, you
have to do x, y, and Z. Right.
So why wouldn't they do that in the u
s hmm. That's what I would say to that.
But what groups would want
the free thought project or
police the police removed?
Well, you got to remember a lot of these.
So the police accountability groups,
I mean it's pretty easy. Law Enforcement
Wa would want them removed, right?
But do you think law enforcement has to
kind of pull to go to Twitter and snap,
hey, not like the, you know, whatever
the police department in Toledo,
but if the FBI may be sure,
or the CIA or you know, whoever major
law enforcement, general law enforcement,
the thing that people kept going to with
Alex Jones was Sandy Hook, Sandy Hook.
He said
children didn't get killed.
You don't have to defend Alex Jones on
the merits of that point because he's
dead wrong.
On that point,
when you're descending is the principle
of letting somebody speak. I understand.
Yeah.
That's not what I'm saying.
What I'm saying is there's no thing
that they're going to on this.
So it's like there's already
been a precedent set that
could just remove people.
So they remove him and they got this
really clear here. It got sloppier. Yeah.
Well it got more clan to
Stein because there's no,
there's no big smoking gun,
there's no nothing.
It's just all of a sudden they're
yanked. Yup, that's right. And again,
no major mainstream media outlet
in the U S reported on it.
Our T is Russia today. Jamie's
guts on the exact article. Okay.
This is of all media by Facebook is
pushing back just to beginning censorship
insight. They may cite the Guardian
article in this article. I was looking,
I'm like, okay. They didn't worry about,
because I saw this article that came out.
It's US pushing back today from
today. This is from today. Today.
Okay.
I saw a different our tea article on
the same it down and make that a little
bigger please.
Hmm.
So that it's so people are starting
to catch on to it. Scroll left.
So we could see, there we go. Um,
the latest and appearance of an apparent
sense of ship of political speech
online us based tech giants this month
shutdown hundreds of user accounts,
some belonged to wells to abas
alternative media outlets with hundreds of
thousands of followers like
the free thought project
or anti media senior fellow
at German Marshall Fund,
a leading think tank advocating you as
global supremacy seems to have at least
partially taking credit for
this. It says in quotes, Russia,
China and other foreign states take
advantage of our open political system,
Jamie fly set.
They can invent stories that got repeated
and spread through different sites.
So we are just starting to
push back just this last week,
Facebook be can't began
starting to take down sites.
So this is just the beginning.
Okay.
So what they're saying is that these
websites have been infiltrated by people
from China and Russia, is that what
they're saying? But scroll back up again,
please
stop.
It said China and other foreign states
take advantage of our open political
system, Russia, China and
other forums. And so that is,
that is somebody from the German
Marshall Fund a leading think tank,
advocating US interests
saying that because we're so
scared of Russia, Russian,
Chinese, Russian and Chinese infiltration.
That's why we got to pull down.
So in other words, they're saying, hey,
maybe these accounts like the free
thought project are run by people who are
trying to destroy America.
So we have to pull them down exactly
beyond a preposterous argument.
This is what they're saying.
They're saying they can invent stories,
they get repeated in spread
through different sites.
So we're just starting to
push back just this last week,
Facebook again started take down to
this just the beginning. So they're,
they're blaming the influence of Russia
and China and that they're saying that
this is their excuse for taking down
these pages because these pages are being
compromised by foreign agents. It's the
oldest trick in the book to say, Oh,
these foreign entities or sowing
discord in the United States.
So therefore we're not going to allow
this dialogue to happen. In fact,
I remember they blamed Russia for black
lives matter Facebook pages during the
2016 election.
But what's fucked up about this is
there's not even any smoking gun.
There's not only is there no evidence,
they just say it, right? They're not,
but they're not even pointing to a
specific example. Yeah, that's right.
Any example, yes, you're correct.
Scroll down and see if there's
anything in this that makes any sense.
According to the account fly complained
that any person with an email could set
up an account on social media and
potentially reach a wide audience.
He predicted a long global
struggle to fix the situation.
Jesus Christ. Oh, great.
He started his career as a u s political
circles as an advisor to George W.
Bush administration also always
trust those people. Right.
Also a foreign policy and national
security consultant for the Senator Marco
Rubio. Yeah. These are the geniuses who
should regulate the Internet. Right?
These guys who've been wrong
about everything reliably.
Well, this is the thing.
If you could just say, oh, the
Russians have influenced this.
The Russians are a part of this.
The Chinese. Okay, pull it.
It's hacky and it's partisan and it
actually works on for on the left and the
right.
Sometimes it works on Corporate Democrats
and people who want to blame Hillary's
election loss on the Russians and
it works on you. That play that.
Let's hear him talk because
here we are, a little bit of it.
Can I jump? Go to the bathroom
real quick. I'll be right back.
Principles,
values as one of our greatest strengths
and therefore one of the best ways to
weaken us.
So I think that that's one of the key
things to understand here is Putin is
acting actually out of weakness.
And why have we Jamie
not come to understand,
or at least the consciousness in this
country does not necessarily view Putin
aligned with other strong men figures.
This has been a long running
problem in American foreign policy.
This is not just a problem that
started with President Donald Trump.
I served in the Bush administration.
President George W.
Bush tried to form a relationship with
Vladimir Putin to get certain things to
advance US national security. President
Obama tried the same thing with his,
his reset of Russian,
uh, US Russian relations.
So it's not unusual that you have
in administration that maybe doesn't
necessarily view Russia as the
threat that it is. Um, I think the,
the politics of this,
the public opinion right now,
it's very interesting because
you've actually seen a
shift over the last several
years. More Democrats
now actually I think, uh,
actually view Russia and
Putin as a threat, uh,
compared to where they were still here.
But
boy, this gives you, it just
leaves a bad taste in your mouth.
Is it idea that these people are just
deciding to remove pages and there
going on television giving
these interviews saying
that it's because of Russia
and Putin without any evidence.
Okay.
Oh, that's so creepy. They
didn't share the evidence.
Why you got to say something
man? I mean, if you want,
if you believe in a free society and
you believe in freedom of speech and
freedom of expression and you
censorship censor people or shit bro,
what's going on here? I'll fix it. I would
only go with that and maybe that, um,
what happened? Nothing. So
they don't have a fix for the,
for the way that it's happening. So
if you show the evidence, then you're,
you're literally like
showing the criminals how to,
how to do this and it could just run,
run more rampant and they
got to plug more holes. Well,
that would be the devil's
advocate position, but you,
in order to take people down,
the thing is if they're doing
it and no one's pushing back,
you're just going to be able to do it
with anybody that disagrees with you or
anybody that is going to be an impediment
to your political campaign or anyone's
getting the way of anything you're
trying to push through. And this is,
this is a giant issue with people
that have that kind of power that can
influence Facebook or Twitter. And if
that's the case, and look, we don't know,
we haven't talked to Zuckerberg,
we haven't talked to Jack Dorsey.
We don't know who's,
who's pulling strings or who's asking
them to do things or what evidence they
presented to them. But that's just very
uncomfortable. It's very uncomfortable.
See that guy talking and bringing up
Russia and Putin because people bring them
up like they're the boogie man,
you know,
this is what's sort of the
Russian Putin. They're, they're,
they're interfering with our democracy,
interfering with our issues
here in America and they want,
they want to ruin democracy and it
bring our country down from the inside.
Yeah. It was like, um,
the Internet went through a phase of
like it just totally free and open wild,
wild west type thing.
And uh,
now it looks like they're trying
to reel it back in and it's like,
that's the viewed as the public square.
It's supposed to be that
these social media outlets,
which are so gigantic and so powerful
that this is now the public square.
So to be able to censor people in these,
in these forums should be considered
unconstitutional, coordinated,
inauthentic behavior. Oh, you found
it, you found the article and spamming.
Hmm.
But again, the like the websites
that they actually pulled down,
that totally destroys their argument.
Even if you buy into the
premise that these are,
this is a good reason to pull somebody
down. I mean some of the people that the,
the pages they pulled down were so well
established and there are of course not
inauthentic in any way.
It's people who are running these pages
that really deeply care about these
issues and want to get
this news out to people.
Fuck,
this is a good quote here.
Drawing the line between
real and inauthentic views
as a difficult enterprise
that could put everything from impartial
political parody did genuine but
outlandish views on the chopping block
and by the way through, there are
politicians in the u s this happened
during the debate between Ted Cruz and
Beta O'rourke all at the exact same time
with the exact same hashtags.
There were pro ted Cruz
things tweeted out at once.
So at that is there are bots that they
bought to help Ted Cruz win the election.
That's election interference.
That's inauthentic behavior and nobody
is talking about pulling down those
accounts. Look at it says here in a
statement post to online newsroom.
Facebook says it,
purge those pages because they're
owners were using fake accounts,
sharing the same content between multiple
pages and linking to add supported
websites.
It calls ad farms.
So what that doesn't even,
is that even a controversial,
but this is where it
gets interesting it says,
but what the social network calls spam
the owners of these pages call standard
procedures for operating on
Facebook. Yeah. That was like,
I don't even think if the argument from
Facebook is correct that that really is
a reason to pull them down.
We could, it says here,
nearly all the page owners contacted by
the Guardian say they use backup or fake
accounts. Hmm. Along with their real ones.
They do it in part to protect themselves
from being targeted by political
opponents and having their real
accounts end up in Facebook jail,
reverb, press, a left leaning news site
whose Facebook page disappear yesterday.
So this is on the left and the right.
They're censoring people because
you've got snowflakes on the right.
There's another one right wing news that
was pulled down. Stop scrolling please.
But, but look at this. This
is really interesting there.
So they're admitting to
disingenuous behavior though
they're using fake accounts
to protect themselves from being targeted
by political opponents. Well it's so,
but that's if that's the case,
they are violating Facebook policy.
So I've seen this on Twitter.
I know people who have gotten
their accounts banned on Twitter,
but they create a new account and they
stay on Twitter and that's technically a
violation of terms of service.
But it also is something that I don't
think is egregious at all. Right.
But there's a big difference between
someone getting banned and then starting a
fake a second account.
This is not that they're,
they're using multiple accounts at the
same time in, some of them are fake. Look,
I'm not,
I'm not justifying their being banned,
but I am saying that they violated
certain procedures and they did.
So in order to public publicize their
ideas and they did it to try to make their
ideas more, just more project
them more have, have more,
more bandwidth.
But according to Facebook,
should you not be allowed to have like
three or four accounts where you tweet
the same stuff or post the same stuff?
Because it seems likes book said though,
what Facebook said.
If just scroll back up to the beginning,
scroll back up at the beginning please.
At the top, the top, the top, top,
see what it says. A coordinated,
inauthentic behavior and spamming.
So they were spamming. And that does sound
like coordinated inauthentic behavior.
If they have a bunch of alternative fake
sites and fake pages that they're using
to spread their stuff. Look,
I'm not saying that they
should have been. This is,
I think better would be to
say, hey, you can't do that.
You've got to remove these fake pages
that are publicizing your ideas and just
have your real authentic page. But what
they're saying is that they're, they're,
they're leaking to add farms and that
they use this to publicize their pages and
that everybody does it. Everybody
does it. You're not supposed to do it.
So why wouldn't they pulled out?
So let's say the free thought project
have three or four other things where they
were posting the same stuff
under a different name.
Why would you not pull down the three
or four other things and leave up to fit
the free thought project?
I think they're saying cause
the Freethought project
violated their terms of
service. You're not supposed to do that.
And they don't want them to do that.
I don't know. See, here's the thing.
Would they have pulled the free thought
project down if they hadn't engaged in
any of these forbidden behaviors?
Uh,
my opinion is I think yes, maybe
that's what I think. Maybe,
but that is gross. You're not supposed
to do that. And I'm not saying that they,
they should be polled,
they shouldn't be pulled,
but maybe they thought this is what
they have to do to get the word out.
And maybe Facebook is like, hey, you
fucked, you're spamming and you're,
you're linking to these ad farms and
these ad farms have been known to,
you know, be influenced by Russia and
China and all these other organizations.
You're doing it just
to promote your sites.
But we're saying that we can't
allow that kind of behavior.
It just strikes me as very strange that
when you have examples like the one I
just gave where maturing in the
Ted Cruz Beta O'rourke debate,
they all tweeted the same
thing at the same time.
It was obviously paid for by
some right wing think tank.
You never hear the story
of something like that.
If it's benefiting us
politician or something like
when Mitt Romney bought like
a million fake followers on
Twitter and a 2012 election,
you never hear about like, okay, we
targeted that. It's always like, oh,
it just happens to be these independent
alternative media outlets that are
spreading information that the government
doesn't want people to know. Well,
it could be that these people are
saying, hey look, everybody does this.
We're going to do this, and
they're saying, we don't like
them there. Oh, and look,
we caught them doing something we, we
don't allow. Yeah, let's sweep them.
But that's possible.
But is it possible that they wouldn't
have been removed if they hadn't done this
shit than not supposed to do? It's
possible, but I don't think it's likely.
I don't know them because
here's the thing. Look,
if it's only people who've engaged
in these forbidden behaviors
that get removed,
then Facebook has a very good argument.
But if Facebook is saying this,
but then people removed who are straight
above board doing everything the right
way, just have their own
page posted information on
their own page and they were
never removed. But these are all
political and alternative media,
which is interesting. So
there were targeted, yes. All
right, so they're targeted,
but in the targeting them they found a
bunch of shit that you're not supposed to
do and that's what got them removed.
I think that there is a good argument,
uh,
that Facebook could make,
which is very much a nuance
troll terms of service argument.
But I think it's more of a veneer or
facade than the real heart of why they did
what they did. But again, that's just my
opinion. I'm not stating that as a fact.
I agree with you. I mean, surely
what they should have done,
especially given the popularity of
these sites, is warn them and say, Hey,
you've got to stop doing this because if
you don't, we are going to remove you.
You are violating our terms of service.
You are linking to add farms and you
have posted from multiple fake accounts
stopped doing that. Just use your one
authentic account. We support free speech.
That's what we would both like.
Right? Yeah. Sure. Yeah. I mean,
it could be also that they feel
like the right wing sites do this.
We have to do this too.
This is how people do it in 2018 is how
you really get the word out. That true.
Yeah. You know, I just,
I've found it interesting that it was
all alternative media and political
accounts and restore left.
It was just the main thing that seemed
to be the connecting tissue through it
all was relatively
antiestablishment. Right. All right.