Real concern is that just like we are
an evolution of those lower primates,
it's going to be an evolution. I think
that's going to happen. I don't think I,
you know, I, there may not be any
avoiding it. You buy debate again,
we're the virus, you know, and
this is just one of my thoughts is,
and me saying unequivocably that
but are other virus just yet.
The thing is I like people to know.
I like these, the other side of it,
people are cool Trey, that aliens go
ahead and attack this motherfucker.
So white people and black people have cut
the bullshit and finally have to unite
like one great movie,
your Red October.
I think we're going to get our asses
kicked and I'm not saying we're not,
but at least at least for
one time humanity, all the
empires would have to unite.
Like that's what I'm saying. I
remember that Reagan's speech. No,
you never heard it. Reagan
actually said that in a, he was,
I forget who he was addressing. Maybe
the first person to ax it besides him.
Put it in the civil right. That, I
mean the King Day you might give me.
The only other thing I like about
Ronald Reagan was a very strange,
he said one of the things that was
really strange about it was that it's,
it's shut off this gigantic wave of
conspiracy theorist who were thinking that
they're going to tell us something
about alien contact. Check this out,
listen to this
outside universal threat.
I occasionally think how quickly our
differences worldwide would vanish if we
were facing an alien threat from outside
this word dude and yes I asked you is
not an alien force already among us what
could be more alien to the universal
aspirations of our peoples than war and
the threat of tell you what to Ronald
Reagan
knocked it out of the fucking
park right there. Straight up.
I have a song called Reagan.
Many of you know wasn't the biggest fan
of him or many of us presidents because
I wrapped it up more than him in there,
but that definitely is going to
make it on a killer Mike Song.
Really I talked to you. Got It. You got
this killer Mike and LP. We definitely,
if anybody think aliens are going
to come kill us all one day,
so I'm going to maybe suggest to ail,
hopefully we'll use it.
But if not fucking I'm gonna do it
when dat shit is amazing. Yeah. Yeah.
What do you,
do you think that it is possible that
aliens came down and manipulated the
genetics of lower primates
and creative people?
I'm willing big based on all the theology,
I'm willing to accept it.
That's a possibility because I don't
think that we're alone. I just don't.
I there's nothing,
even if there is some divine thing that
woke up and decided to make us and we
were special children and we are on earth,
the who plan,
there had to have been some other
things made her play with. Right.
I don't think that I think
is very arrogant as a human
being to think that it's
just us.
Right.
And I think that the possibility that
something made it here and something
happened exist.
Absolutely.
Cause if we're experimenting
on animals and things,
we got like where my daughters army,
their temperament is mean. They're
curiosity is me. Like I see.
I'm looking at Michael and I'm looking
at an eye and I'm like arguing with
tonight. It's like arguing with myself.
She doesn't know why she acts like that.
I don't know. Now if I can look
at my pit bull and say, well,
her mother asked it like this and this
is why I know she's coded this way.
I know her father was his.
Then I have to look at my daughter
and save on a genetic basis,
23 of my chromosomes.
I know our temperament is like that.
I know why Michael is not going to argue
she's a smart kid. She's a art student.
But the minute you put her in danger,
she's going to punch you.
You know what I mean? That's
what, that's what is going to be.
And it's not going to be anything else
because she is going to protect her and
her. So it's like, I have to think
that my curiosity, if nothing else,
my drive to do this. So if you take the
primate side, you say, well, you know you,
you know that I have to live in Marxist.
I gotta survive as wolves. Is Lions,
tigers bears out here. I have to
go high, I have to create shell.
There's something else which was a very
small input could have dropped here,
landed here and what's crazy,
if you look into nation of
Islam philosophy of sorts,
they have a Ufo type philosophy.
Something here in and buy their mind
is scientists created, you know,
all of the win, win, win a Shrek. Rain
kind of created a different races.
But something could have come here and
it and it gets here and it says boom,
if I do this and this and I create this
and then we set upon evolution and we
ended up here or that's just could be,
you know me stone having watched too
many side five movies. But it's possible.
It is. It's, it is possible.
There's zero evidence for it,
but it's certainly possible that if we
could go to another planet that we knew
how in life that it's possible if we
found some lower primates that we would
manipulate them.
It's very possible for a full survey of
another planet we got there and like,
okay, here's the good news.
Good News. A lot of life.
Bad News is the most intelligent
thing is basically a chimp.
But we've got some ideas and uh,
we're gonna do is we're going to plant
some seeds of our genetics in some of
these champs.
They're going to be smarter than the
other chimps and then we're going to
believe mushrooms everywhere. A lot of
that leave the mushrooms everywhere.
Let the chimps eat. Maybe
we're in a fishbowl maybe.
Yeah. Cause again, we're at,
we very arrogantly think of ourselves
is as top choice, but maybe,
maybe we're just a virus on this living
thing. Maybe something maybe you know,
we say anything but you make
about we could go estate a virus,
a amass virus could kill us all.
Yup.
The sure that's what we're constantly
fighting. The Earth wouldn't stop.
But the thing about viruses like get
viruses wholly negative in our eyes,
I don't think we're wholly
negative to each other.
I don't think a virus thinks his holiness.
What I'm saying is that eating you up,
you're having a good party. When
you get the flu, they're like, dude,
it's probably up if this thing
is really a living thing.
If the nerve is really living thing, we
are possibly the worst thing. Sore it. Oh,
for sure. Why shouldn't it get rid
of us other than meteors? Yeah. Yeah.
We're the worst thing for
not just the biological life,
but the particulates in the atmosphere,
and now we're creating technology that's
going to eventually kill us and get rid
of us that may be able to live in harmony
with biology maybe. So. Yeah, maybe.
Maybe it's over for us
in a few thousand years.