Yeah.
Um,
they were trying to do cowboy
versus Connor and apparently the,
the sticking point was that it
was going to be a co main event.
How dare they,
I think the idea is that they have to
have world titles as a, as a main event.
Is there a paper says Ooh that's my,
if I west DW get your head out of
your ass. You guys one the main event.
Shoot him a text set on I don't have his
number symbol heart. Did he block too?
I think so. We're not seeing that
shit. I actually like the guy.
We have no problem.
I know I tried to get you guys together.
I gave it my best shot.
I get my fucking you tried man.
Sometimes just getting my level best.
Yeah, I don't understand it man.
It's weird when you have friends
that don't like each other,
you know when you're good friends with
both of them and they're like fuck that
guy and be like all right man.
I don't have to tell you but I don't,
I don't talk bad about him.
No you don't.
I criticize some like the UFC decisions
cause I do a show but then I have no
issue with the metal. I like
that though. I mean look,
part of the thrill of these things,
it's gotta be raging owl.
Cowboy was in my office yesterday.
You know him white said he wants a fight,
is ready to fight again. Let's fight
against working another opponent for him.
Maybe rage now sit does not specify
who's her want to be fighting next.
So it says, dude, you're
telling me Connor was like, no,
I'm not taking the fight
if I'm co main event.
Why in the fuck would you
make that are coming up? Yeah.
Said he could be out of action
until the fall. Mcgregor could be,
you know the other things. But Gregor
as a fun, so long, he hasn't fought MMA.
It's so long. Good. That's fine. We'll
skip the last fight was Khabib right?
But he, ted takes like almost
to two years off, right?
He fights Khabib. He gets smoked by
Khabib and then he has, how long was that?
I was that November was a long
time off. It's not good. No,
he needs to be active,
like really act.
It's hard to be active when
you're making that much money off.
That's the problem.
The whiskey,
the whiskey and a made like $100 million
off the Floyd Mayweather fight he's
making but popo popup up buying
prop whiskey. I'm proud of him.
He's doing great type move.
Look between you and him,
I mean him while he's in the middle
of his career and you post career.
I mean you've guys have laid
some interesting blueprints
for fighters. So yeah.
The um, it was October, October of 2018.
That's quite a lot long time ago. That's
not good. If trade is not that far.
November, December, January,
February. I was like five months ago.
It seems like a long time ago though,
doesn't it? But he has nothing coming up,
so nothing. Let me fighting me another
year. That was his last fight. Yep.
In two years before that was
his previous fight. Yeah.
It's not good. It's not good. Especially
if you want to be Creme de la creme.
You just can't fight like that. I think
he's only interested in big fights.
Like things that excite him now,
you know,
because he's got so much
money and so much success.
It's just one of those things. Can
you play mum? But here, look at that.
That main event, the main event of
that fight was a non title fight.
Conor versus Nate Diaz, that was non
title. Both. Both times they fought in,
but the last one, the, the fact
that it was a non title fight,
it was also the biggest
paper view of all time. Dude,
whoever recommended that he be
co main event against Galbally,
she get their mouse piston.
That's why Dana does it like,
well,
I don't know who that was amended that.
I'm just saying say that I disagree
with your decision. You're up.
I believe I can fly. God. Ugh.