The Joe Rogan experience,
but the leg lock game so unexpected
because I always thought they were a good
technique if you can get it,
but it's not that high percentage in MMA.
That was Kinda how I felt. You didn't
see too many of them. I don't know why.
I think it was,
we didn't,
we had a few guys that were really good
in the early days like Olig Tuck tar off
and you know some other guys who are
really good but we didn't have the level
that you have. What? Like a Paul
Horace. Yeah. Dive in on things.
Transitioning from one thing to the next
and then locking you up in a position
where you had a tap quick. Cause if
you don't, you're gonna be screaming.
Do you think a lot of the times there's
always guys like the other guy's fault
or does he really just hold too long?
He definitely holds too long. He has,
there's one fight from Brazil where it's
crazy. He's just not letting him go.
He just holding onto something,
I forget what it was,
but he was not letting go and they were
trying to separate him when he was still
hanging onto it.
I think he came from a really,
really bad childhood and he's talked
about it in depth about growing up on a
farm and being forced to eat pig slop,
pig slop when he was a little boy,
that cut that he has on his chest, that
big scar here sealed that up with glue.
Yeah. Like crazy shit
man. Yeah, he's actually,
I've met him before a few
times. Like through a, yeah,
there's some friends and he
seems like a cool guy. Yeah,
he does. You know, genuine.
I just think when he's killer
in competition, man, he, yeah,
he just doesn't want to let it go. Yeah.
He wants and they make come let it go.
And He tried,
even though he knew that they were
gonna get mad at him if he didn't let go
still in quite let go. Yeah. And
they're like, get the fuck Outta here.
They kicked him out of the UFC,
the first guy ever to get kicked out of
the UFC for holding on submissions. Oh,
he got kicked out? Yeah. Oh, okay. Do
you know who he, who he held it against?
I don't know, but I'm pretty,
I don't want, I want to
make sure that that's true.
I think it is that who some are.
Paul Harris was the first guy to ever
get kicked out of the UFC for and I think
the last one that got kicked out for
was like any normal person wouldn't even
gotten in trouble for that
one. Yeah. It was like normal.
I was like maybe a little bit too long,
but it was on that borderline edge.
But because it was him,
people like he nef,
you know he's, is that what
it was? It wasn't in the UFC,
but it was a controversial
submission victory ever.
Jake shields at the world series of
fighting tie. Yeah. Jake shields, I think.
Yeah, but I think he did that too. But
that was a Kamora. Yeah, that's right.
But I think before that he
got kicked out of the UFC,
released in 2013 Oh,
Mike Pierce had a yes.
Referee intervene. That's right.
Yep. So that's what it was. Yeah.
Okay.
That's what it was.
He was released after holding onto a
heel hook of my peers in 2013 yeah,
but look, man, that guy was pretty,
she was particularly scary when he fought
because he was so strong and his body
was so well designed for heel hooks.
Right.
He just could grab a hold of you and to
rip your shit apart. Man. Look at that.
Oh my God. Look at this now
look what he does here. See,
he grabs a hold of my peers.
Don't have that happens. Tapping.
Tapping is still holding. You still hold
that. But that's all in slow motion.
But it looked to me like he was
still ripping the knee apart,
even though he knew that the guy tapped.
Yeah, he had it. He knew he had it.
He's just punishing that guy.
You know?
He makes it scarier for other people and
it's, he's probably used to doing it.
You know, he had this
psychological block. Those,
they all say that he's like a
really, really nice guy. Yeah.
You just become that guy that nobody wants
to fight. You can't get in the moment.
But I think in the Jake shields fight,
there was other shit that was happening
too. I think there was, I pokes,
I'm pretty sure he said dirty fight.
What are you here?
Yeah.
What are we hearing?
There's something bleeding through into
our microphones. I've heard this before.
I've been trying to catch what it
was. Ghost Bro. Know what it's from.
It's some interference.
I see. This is like, um,
so I don't know if the people can hear it.
Can the people here right was
known as this? What is it?
What is it? The five club.
The fight, that sound, oh,
you left now it's very low.
It's just a little bit,
we just debunk ghost bro.
Which fight was it that you pulled up?
Uh, that, that fight that took, you know,
oh, what do you group tech guys near Park?
Yeah.
He was the first guy to be like super
scary and elite modern level with heel
hooks. Where did he start off?
Do you know what promotion? Well,
he's a [inaudible] guy. Okay.
So he came out of Brazil,
probably cage warriors. I don't
know man. I don't know where,
where he was fighting and in Brazil,
I don't remember seeing cage
warriors is the UK is it? Yeah,
that's where Anderson came from.
Wealth Anderson,
when he made the jump from pride,
he did cage warriors for a while and
then came over to the UFC and I think
that's when he started working with,
uh,
the Nogueira is when he started to
keep fighting and cage fighters. Oh.
So he fought in a bunch of fury.
Ifcs fought a bunch of stuff. Storms,
Samurai 12, Tom, Tom
[inaudible], Storm Samurai 12.
I want a t shirt for Storm
Samurai 12 damn throwback.
Yeah. Real throw backs.
Yeah, he had a great, um,
it goes to show you how good Gary tone
in his as a submission grapple to,
cause they had a great submission,
grappling match put, keep,
go back to his record there because
I think that was listed there.
I think it turned out in a draw and
Gary turnon is so much smaller than him.
Draw. Yeah. Gary Tone. Oh
yeah, that was reset. Yeah,
but that really 2016 I think it was,
cause I remember,
no, that was Craig Jones. 2018 was
Craig Jones. Yeah. Cause I lost her.
Craig jumbled was posting pictures
about like how he looks now. Tokyo deal.
He's got like,
he's got a fade.
I'd like this big mustache now and he's
all jacked off £1,000. Yeah, for sure.
So he's running through walls.
Yeah. Is He fighting MMA anymore?
Is he just doing grappling?
I think he might just be doing grappling.
I haven't heard of d MMA news.
That's something extra scary about
a guy will fuck your knee up. Yeah.
You know what's up?
Let me the size of him now.
He's with hic hickey monster holes.
You saw it or not wanting to get my,
my heel caught in that armpit.
Yeah. Look at those. That
picture above where he's
screaming. Look at that picture.
Like what in the fuck man.
Oh look at Craig Jones.
Just kill that is a body
designed to rip your legs apart.