A skill for skill, ability
for ability. I think he,
if he's not the best of all time,
it's him and fade or no. And then the,
you always have to mention Verdomme cause
even though Steve Bay knocked for doom
out in the first round for
Dumas submitted, the best
of the best is submitted.
Minataro he submitted fade or he
submitted Kaine. I mean what the fuck?
I mean that that guy is just for doing it.
Volumes record it.
If you just look at who he's fine,
he's fine. He's the best. Yeah,
I in my opinion and for how long
he's been around. But it's like,
but when did he beat those guys?
Like when did he be those guys?
Did he beat those?
Like when you beat fade or fader was as
close to his prime as you can get when
you know, like it's hard to say
like the Brett Rogers fight,
a lot of people were saying he wasn't
as focused for the Brett Rogers. Right.
But he's still knocked him out with one
punch. Remember that crazy fucking chaos.
Anytime you gotta be ready for fatal.
Yeah.
But Verdomme handled him, you know, on
the ground and submitted them. You know,
I would have loved to seen what
it was like in pride if you,
he could fight him when fade war was
at his peak click back when he beat
Minataro. Yeah. But for doom,
you know, he's, he's overlooked.
And that argument of WHO's the best and
in terms of like accomplishments as a
UFC fighter,
well it's steep a cause Steve plays the
only guy to defend the title four times
and it really kind of bums me out that
he's out of the conversation right now.
You don't hear about a Steve Bay fight.
I mean he's like a two in which I feel
like he should get more attention for
this and he's just a normal guy.
Like he has a full time job
where he's a firefighter.
Like I feel like more people should
resonate with them because of that. Yeah.
But they don't,
I don't use a fucking great,
it's kind of be an asshole
to get attention these
days. I don't know. I mean,
I feel like if he had beaten DC
and you know, I mean beat Francis,
that was a big fight because Francis came
into that fight with a lot of hype and
asked the Overeem knockout.
Steve Bay fought like a fucking champion,
have really fought like a champion.
Smart. And he showed Francis and look,
Francis fought after that.
He was not the same thing when he fought
after then he fought Derrick Lewis.
You could see he was still throwing up.
He was still fucked up from that last
fight and he admitted it to his credit,
you know,
and he bounced back with the Curtis
blades fight and look fantastic in that
bigger firm. Cause blades is awesome.
Wrestler. Exactly. Clip blades.
Blades is a very athletic wrestler. He's
huge. He's big, he's fast, he's powerful.
And you know, and that's twice Francis
is beaten him twice. He stopped him.
That was his first UFC fight. So, um,
he stopped them then and they
stopped him in this one as well.
So coming into this fight
with Kane, you know, there's,
there's a lot of questions we haven't
seen Kane in two years, right.
It's been about two years. Yeah.
It may be even longer. Let's say,
when was the last time came to
Alaska? It's flat time. Yeah.
I think you might be right.
I think it might be three years.
It's been a while raise. I know, but when,
when he was at the top of the food chain,
when Kane was at the top,
he would put a fucking storm on these
people that was just like a hundred year
storm. That would never end.
It's like, how is this guy
have this kind of intimacy,
Purdue to do that to him now?
And the city was crazy.
I thought it'd be the other
way around. Yeah. It was crazy.
And just see came tired. So
here we go. 2016 yeah. July 9th.
So two and a half years. Yeah, almost.
Yeah. And that was Travis Brown,
which is just a phenomenal beating.
Um,
and that was a UFC 200 yeah.
And they did the junior dos Santos one
and the one before that was a year,
you know,
so he's like Fabricio been active.
Well he had children 2013 look
at those gaps. Yup. Yup. Dang.
Two year gaps. Yep. Two year
gaps. One year, two year again.
That's rough man. Yeah,
it is. It is rough.
Especially when this is your job and how
you get paid. Fuck yeah. Right. Yeah.
Lucky's a heavyweight and they get taken
care of a little more. But yeah. Yeah.
I mean it's just,
I wonder how,
how much you could fix all that
stuff that's going on in the spine.
You know what I mean? It's one thing
if a guy gets a knee, you know,
he's got a ACL or something like that,
you know, they can come back from that.
That's 100% possible.
But back stuff is weird once it
seems like once things start going,
it's like you like a car,
you know,
once a ball joint blows out and the acts
will start grinding and you're like,
God, Jesus, it's like a bunch
of Shits gonna go wrong.
Something that that's like your
core. Yeah. At his best man.
He was fucking terrifying.
Yeah. Cause it just,
I'd never saw a heavyweight
with that kind of endurance.
Now I remember being so scared
of Cain Velasquez and I was like,
I think I talked about this last time in
your podcast when I was a kid wrestling
in college, cause I was like this
tiny ass little white boy wrestler.
And Kate would walk around with justice
singlet straps on his shorts and he had
brown pipe,
brown pride tattooed across his chest.
He's just huge heavyweight
wrestling d one for Asu.
I was just like so scared of that guys.
Like, Damn, look at that guy, man.
Just walking around like wandering.
Probably rip my head off,
has brown pride tattooed on his chest,
just wearing just a singlet straps.
Just huge. It's funny. Yeah, I remember
him forever, man. Well, you know,
him and DC,
having that kind of a relationship is
such a unique situation for the two
fighters that they have.
You know,
another elite guy that's their size
and they just smash each other left and
right and work with each other. That's
what I tried to create wherever I go. Um,
and that's what we're doing in southern
California. I know one or two let, uh,
and Picos a cubs Swanson's we're trying
to build a room of the smaller guys that
we can, but we're a lot, we don't
want to kill each other. Right.
And that's something that we,
I've always had to control myself.
I've always gone really hard and something
that I've had to learn to control. Um,
but having that room full of killers so
that when we go to wrestling practice,
like you don't know if you're
going to have a good practice.
You might be getting beat up on that day
when you go home and be all pissed off.
Like, shit, I had a bad practice,
I got taken down with this.
But that's what makes you
better for the next practice.
If you just go to practice and
beat up on everyone every day,
you're never going to know
what you need to change,
what you need to get better
at. So I think that's why, uh,
Canaan and DC have gotten so good so
quick at MMA that each other to build off
of, you know, and see if you can survive
it. Yeah. If you survive it. Yeah.
And you know,
like the knock on Aka,
some people said they trained too
hard cause they're always injured.
But look at the amount of
champions they produced.
Look at the amount of fucking killers
that had come out of there. Luke Rockhold,
DC cane, Khabib. I mean,
get the fuck out of here.
That place is a den of assassins. You can
survive it, right? Yeah. Perfect. I mean,
yeah, I mean that's the
only way, man. I mean, look,
it's not good to spar full clip like old
school lions den days where they used
to beat the shit out of each of
the or the military days. I mean,
nobody knew a thing back then.
They didn't know the consequences.
They didn't know what it's like.