I have the probably the
most minor of brain damages.
Probably the most minor cause I stopped
when I was 21 yeah. What's your number?
How many times I got hit and I mean like
how many times do you think that you
like, oh that did damage? Oh,
100% there's a bunch of them.
There's a bunch of them
that I could think back.
Getting rocked and feeling my knees go
like getting punched in and then keeps
barring heaps barring spar,
two more rounds of that guy spar
three rounds with another guy.
He's hitting you in the face too. Like
you didn't stop. It was really dumb.
He'd get hit and you get rocked and you
didn't, nobody likes sat you down and go,
okay, let's take the day off. And
then you get right back in there, man,
you're fucking legs would go bang.
But your legs would go and you cover up
and you know people be throwing bombs on
you and you'd next day sparring again.
Could you, is there a way to detect it?
Like get at your brain scan so you can
see her ways now. There's better ways now,
but I had a limited amount of it.
I mean I had the real getting wrapped
in the head for me came when I tried to
transition from taekwondo to
kickboxing or doing taekwondo. I got,
I definitely got hit in the head for sure,
but they didn't get hit in the head as
much because it's hard to kick people in
the head.
You definitely get hit.
I mean I don't know how many
times I definitely got hit,
but I'd never got knocked
out from a head kick butt.
I got knocked out from punches before at
least Ko Tko Tko but when when a punch
hits your face,
it's like your,
your legs go everything like shuts off.
Like if you get rocked and you,
you see like a person go down.
It's not that they go down like,
oh there's so much pain I have to go down.
No,
you get hit and everything shuts off.
It just goes boom.
And then you feel your legs like rubbery.
Trying to stand back up.
Did you just watch the last UFC
where Edson Barboza head kick.
Kevin Lee see that he's spinning wheel
kicked him and you see Kevin Lee's legs
just go blank. They just gave out for
a second and then he came back and
those those ones I got way
more when I was boxing.
She got way more of those like I was,
I was not good at boxing.
When I first got into boxing, I was
learning, I was good at taekwondo,
but then I got into boxing. I was not good
at it. I didn't know what I was doing.
I didn't understand the distance.
Taekwondo,
you didn't punch in the face
and we punched the body.
So you had a real distorted perception
of how good you were with your hands.
And then once I started boxing I was
like, Ooh, this is terrible. And that's,
that's what I was taking like probably
the most damage of my life of a period of
like two years of like a lot of sparring,
did a lot of sparring.
Everybody sparred everybody's
part with everybody.
People knock people out all the time.
This just stupid.
So stupid. I see guys get
knocked out. I mean out cold,
right hand to the chin, boom. Eyes
rolled behind their head, legs give out,
they bounce off the canvas.
They put a cold towel on him.
They put some ice on his head, he gets up.
He's like, I'm good, I'm good, I'm good.
You want to keep going? Yeah, let's
keep going. Let's keep going. No,
you would just unconscious.
You would just unconscious five minutes
ago and you want to keep sparring.
This is crazy. And they'd let
them, they let them keep spar.
You did it from when you were like really
young, right? Taekwondo from one owes,
why took karate classes when I was 14
but when I got super serious I was 15 I
was like right at my,
before my sophomore year of high school.
So like I got into it from
the time I was in the, uh,
ninth grade as I was 14.
Like that summer,
like right after my birthday around
is when I started getting into Thai.
So I was probably either
14 or just turning 15 asked
like was there a point you
could tell where people actually could
be able to knock people out and give that
damage? Cause there may be 14 year olds
can knock you out or the whole time.
The thing about kicks is almost anybody
can knock you out. It's really crazy.
Like when you think of the amount of
power that you have to have like in your
legs, like say if you decide
to put a heavy backpack on,
like one of those outdoors mins,
atlas trainers put 90 pounds on.
You could walk up flights of stairs.
Dude.
Just think how much power
that is in your legs.
You could throw your body up flights of
stairs for exercise just to Bush Bush,
coach your body is whatever you weigh,
one 5,200 whatever your way,
your body's just launching that through
the air over and over and over again.
Even if you're a girl
that weighs 135 pounds,
you're still launching 135
pounds through the air.
And if that girl fucking shins you
boat Blang right on your temple,
I, it goes across the jaw,
temple area, got blind.
Your legs are going to give out,
your brain's going to shut off
if somebody hits you. Perfect.
There's a video of a, I think
the guy was shot, I think it was,
I think it was mighty Mo, mighty
moe, who's this huge kickboxer.
I believe he was Samoan and I mean
just like typical Samoan Dude,
big giant fucking powerhouse of a dude.
And he fought this little Thai guy.
This Thai guy was 175 pounds,
so much smaller than them.
I mean it was crazy to watch and tie
guys just moving away and moving away and
moving away. And then the Thai guy
roundhouse kicks him in the head.
This guy like, look at the
difference in size. Yeah.
And watch this.
This dude just comes over the top.
I mean the difference
between the two of them.
Mighty moe is a base to seriously
dangerous knockout puncher.
He put a lot of guys to sleep,
so not as this guy in there with someone
way bigger than him but he's in there
with a killer. But look at that one
head kick and mighty most down and out.
I mean backed that up again because
that is a crazy thing to watch.
You're talking about a guy who might've
been a hundred pounds lighter than him
and mighty mouse. Just
a vicious puncher. Bang.
He just claimed him right in the head.
That's what I'm talking about.
Girl does that to you?
Night night son. Yeah,
I was thinking more like two 10 year
olds like no knock each other out.
That's a good point because the thought
process is that if you teach kids
technique,
don't teach them to just go on these
wild fucking haymaker exchanges but teach
them how to do it correctly.
It's good to do it when they're young
because they don't hurt each other cause
they a little tiny arms and they just
kind of touch each other and they can't
really generate knockout power.
They just sort of,
and if they learn how to do that from
the beginning and then develop knockout
power and the pads and on the bag,
then you develop much more technically
proficient fighters rather than brawlers.
So the problem with fighting is like
most people don't fight to the physical
ability of their body.
Like they, they just,
they decide like they're
going to knock this guy out,
I'm gonna try to hit him with this.
And they think in this real
limited sort of linear, aggressive,
like almost obvious manner.
Then you got guys who see past that
who take things to a new place.
You got guys who,
who figure out that you can be like
really elusive and confusing and then you
see those guys fight like limited blocky,
like obvious fighters.
And like Anderson Silva in his prime is
a perfect example that Anderson was an
artist. I mean he would just, he would,
you didn't know what he was going to
do it study you. He'd be moving around,
he'd be standing in front of you,
he'd be dancing,
a just be following you around and
then all of a sudden he just say,
I got this motherfucker figured out.
He would just move in on your bank and
you didn't know what was coming flying
knee. He didn't know what was coming.
Roundhouse kick front kick to the face,
know what the fuck was coming, man. It
was a totally different kind of fighter.
So the difference between that and a
guy was just a like a powerhouse of a
person and can knock guys out but never,
never achieves this sort of
mastery of space and distance.
They win fights through brawling and
power and just kinetic brute force rather
than artistry and avoidance and countering
like Conor McGregor when he knocked
out Joe's a Aldo perfect example,
all of those like fuck you
charge Anam Connor slides back,
flap drops a fucking left hand on the
button, pop out and he's the champ champ.
I mean come on. Or champ then became
the champ champ champ. But that that,
you know, that thing is,
it's hard to figure out.
Sometimes guys just decided to rub,
they'd rather buy down their mouthpiece.
Let the fucking chips fly. It's not
fun. It's part of the end of a fight.
Yes. Like the last 30 seconds, 10
seconds and they just throw it out.
He could crazy cause they know
there's no more time left. Yeah.
They just try to win. I try
to try to stop it. Yeah.
Some of those fights are awesome.
Look as a,
as a person watching those things are
awesome. There's two different parts.
The way I look at fights,
like I love a good Diego Sanchez Gilbert
Melendez fight where they just fucking
go crazy for three rounds. I loved that.
That was one of my favorite fights ever.
But I also love real
technical fights where I see,
I see like two artists trying
to solve each other's riddle,
trying to figure each other out.
You know like Luke Rockhold
versus Yoel Romero.
Was that like Yo,
well just trying to figure him
out and trying to figure him out.
Maybe I move like this and then boom,
drops that left hand on him.
Same thing with him versus Chris Weidman.
He just moving around.
It's hard to figure out
what he's going to do.
Hard to figure out what's coming and then
wome flying knee to the chin or to the
head.
He's a,
he's a great example of a guy who just
figures out how to break your rhythm and
figure it through rather than just running
that Yang because clash, clash, clash,
you know Frank Mir was just talking about
that fate or fight and he was saying
that his ego got the best of them.
Did you see the fight?
It was a really good fight. Really
crazy. Until fate are Keto, them fade.
[inaudible] caught on with the left
hand and dropped him and put him away.
But before fade or cowed him,
Frank Mir had hit fade or,
and it got interesting in
the very beginning seconds
of the fight but then fade
or hit him with a perfectly timed
hip throw, which is fucking boom.
I mean sent him flying through the
air and slammed him to the ground.
And apparently frank
said from that moment on,
his ego got the best of me
is trying to get them back.
And then he wound up just getting this
crazy brawl and getting knocked out.
It's really fighting to me. So
it's so interesting. You know,
it's just so interesting when you see
all the different things that people can
do and how they're going to
match up together and out.
What one person's going to be able
to figure out how to get there,
their ideas through my ideas. I want
to kick this motherfucker in the head.
How can I do this? I've got to figure
out how to get to and his ideas.
I want to take this guy down
and punch his fucking face in.
How do I figure out how to do this?
And then the two of them are just like
trying each other's strat and you don't
really know. You don't fucking know.
You don't know until they get in there.
For the most part,
it's great a shit ever.