Rent, so I got a bunch of points
for that. It's so funny out to,
to talk about something very interesting.
It's very interesting where this
Harvey Weinstein case is going to go.
Yeah.
It's very interesting
where it's going to go.
Right now he has Benjamin Bratt as a
charity and if you see what happened,
Benjamin Bratt push for
dismissal and he didn't get it.
The lawyer said,
the judge said a trout day,
they're going to get a trial date.
Harvey Weinstein's going to go
through a more money to pay off time.
I was going to go for time.
Then he's going to fire Benjamin
Bratt and show up with two women,
primarily one black and one
Asian or one white and one Asian.
This is when this trousers
and they get very interesting.
Harvey's also going to hire billions
of dollars and prosecute in a private
investigators.
They're got interview boyfriends.
They're going to interview this case.
It's going to be very interesting.
I like the Cosby case where
cars be didn't really fucking,
how do you know he's going to do other
stuff because I know this is what I would
do.
I know if you come to me and you go home,
I'm getting busted for this.
What do I do? Because of how I grew up
around those people. This is what you do.
Benjamin breath can not ask a woman the
same question a woman can ask a woman,
so I'm going to go in there
with either a black woman,
an Asian woman,
or a white woman.
My first two choices were
black on the national month.
You want to get the diversity angle and
I got the diversity angle and I want to
get that. You can't. You're saying
that because you're a black woman,
Chinese woman.
What I'm trying to step,
did you ever really watched
the people versus Oj Simpson?
Very interesting and said, it's time
that you sat. Now the holidays they go,
yeah, the FX version. I watched
one episode that seemed very good,
very interesting. How he put
a Dream Team together. Geez,
it's going to cost you 10 mil. Listen
to me. Gee, you got two options.
You're going to like Cosby being paid
two mil and make believe you're blind or
we put together a fucking, you see
him? He wasn't there with that milk.
You should over Xyz.
Like the guy from Kung Fu,
let me when we was kids come
the food's father. Yeah.
Kung Fu followers like that blind
and shit. Yeah, I remember that.
That milk of Magnesia designed shit.
That's how cosmi willing that plane.
Like I'm sick. Routine.
He's got cataracts.
Yeah.
Oh Cosby. Yeah, but he didn't have
cataracts when he was like that,
that when he did you put the
pill in the water either.
He knows what he knows what the fuck. And
so three steps read your shit. Fucking,
you know. Yeah, he knows. But
Harvey has to play this hand.
This is what America's about the watch.
They're going to watch something
fucking crazy. He probably knows.
He can't go in there. And
Benjamin Bratt, Benjamin Bratt.
Gravano look at the list of Benjamin
Bratt has and Benjamin Bratt can attack a
woman show. You look at it
like legal cases, like sports.
He's got this one paper.
Listen to me.
John Jones versus Gustafson.
I went to New York last week and I went
to the Metropolitan Museum of art with
my daughter.
She loves art.
And while I was sitting there I was
added saying them goatee on your own,
cause my daughter didn't want me taking
pictures in front of the statutes anyway.
She's like, Daddy, get out of the
pictures of the statute. So I'm like,
what the fuck am I hanging out with
you for? She was in a Chinese wedding.
I wanted to see the Armenian wing,
but it was funny how I was thinking
about when I was 21 and 22 Joe Rogan.
I would get stoned to the gills and
go to the Museum of Natural History,
the Museum of my hobbies back then
since I was such a loan and then people
looking for me,
I was always a criminal.
I would go over the bridge to either go
to one of those museums while I would
sit in the courtroom.
I would go to a place that had a fucking
Italian sandwich and I got a bag of
wise potato chips in a 16 ounce
coke and you go to any court room.
Court starts at seven at
the metropolitan downtown.
I take the a train and I'd walk.
I forget now what you know.
This is 1983 81 I was a
kid and I would sit down,
observe night court.
I learned how to,
plus I grew up in that.
You were what?
You'd sit and watch Nightcore like
you'd watch a basketball game,
like a pick up game with a sandwich
and a soda and potato chips.
I think it was a lot of people don't
realize you could just go to court and I
would watch do what? 12 people,
how I would learn how to set bail.
Can you do that anytime you walk and you
just get in there and watch in the 80s
yes. Now this bomb detectors you up
that the reason why you're there,
do you have to if you're
interested in the case? Yeah,
he'd go down and just
watch it. If you, you know,
for whatever reason
there's a speeding thing.
Like someone lost their license and they
got arrested driving and trying to get
away from cops or you can go watch
that and go, go home support and Joan,
I would like to go and I see,
I would like to see what the fuck was
going on when those guys are trying to get
away from the cops to helicopter chasing
them with the spotlights and they just
keep going like, what the fuck
were you thinking? Like what?
I would like to get to that courtroom
here. I want to see that guy.
I want to look at that guy.
And it was like running from the cops
at the fucking spotlight from the
helicopter on me knew he wasn't going to
get away and he's gotten people off and
traveling the fucking side though.
Nobody ever gets away.
Does anybody ever gotten away recently?
The other night,
that parking garage,
I couldn't find them in garage.
They get away the percentages lemme
lemme explain something to right.
The percentages are very fucking low,
right? It's tough to get away, bro.
They got you.
Once those helicopter spot you running
through neighborhoods three you're going
into a mall, they have cameras, they
can rewind the cameras and watch you go.
If you're running into the mall,
they got over there.
He has I spot on the cards
and stuff. They, they, they,
what happens here? You want to know what
happened to see what happens to you.
All right. First of all, it's usually
spot. Skyline is following you.
So they got, yeah, they got to put
you on the floor, kick your legs,
do everything by procedure on camera
that they pick you up, they handcuff you,
they put you on the side of the car.
The guy tells you this whole white
version of what happened to the pursuit
started on wanting, yes.
Suspect was moving at a high
rate of speed. Fucking, you know,
if I just had to chase you for 20 miles,
I pissed him my you for they
put you in the fucking trunk.
They put you in the back
seat in front of everybody.
So the cameras take pictures and they put
a cop next year learning to drive day.
You got a couple back hands to your
face. You know what I'm saying? That you,
you hit the steering wheel or
something to hey a couple of times.
Then you go in there and you sit in
the holding tank and then you fucking,
if you're with one another person,
you just shut your fucking mouth.
You want to call your lawyer.
I call him glad that you want to call
your lawyer because you want one of the
other guys to get a lawyer. So then
like that you'd have to get uh, it's,
it's pump, it's, it's
conflict of interest. So me,
you and Jamie got arrested right now I'm
going to shut my mind how you want me
to call my attorney later because I
know for a fact Jamie's going to get a
public defender.
So now I can't get a public defender
because that's conflict of interest.
So the state has to pay for
a different attorney for me.
Well a lot of people don't know that.
So if you got arrested with two or
three people, you keep your mouth shut.
You had call my attorney and later you
have an attorney. Yet. I forget his name,
but Jamie cop,
public defender now to public
defenders can't represent you.
How you got a better chance
of getting a better attorney
and the state pays for it.
It's on the young.
So next time you pay for your mortgage and
go, God damn it, this state Texas side,
it's cause the jerk off like me went
with fucking Johnny run battlebots and
fucking he wants 800 an hour even though
the state will give him a 400 and now
it's like wholesale,
you know what I'm saying?
But I at least I got a better type
of attorney. You game the system,
you game the system.
It really is fucking crazy.
How I love figuring this shit
out. You'll do, you break,
you're writing things down
like you weren't even thinking.
You just automatically started writing
down numbers and percentages. Oh yeah,
I know this shit. I grew up in
this shit and it's like a sport.
So that's what he'll do
heartened by the time.
How are we bringing on a rape case?
You got to go up there and we the story
and tell the dates and if there was a
rape kit,
it's very fucking tough.
There's going to be very interesting
pro what's going to happen.
The only thing is anything he cops to,
he's going to come,
they're going to come back and I'm
like, oh, Jay. And tried to sue them.
So then he'll just live in Florida to
make them fucking super eight films down
there. Fucking Miramar, Florida,
whatever. Fucking go crazy.
When you see somebody get sued
because they work the system.
I'm not saying nothing bad here.
That's what your advisors and your
people around you will tell you.
He's in hot water for the rest of his
life because even if he gets that down to
like an assault charge and he has
to serve eight months, 12 months,
which is really eight,
once he gets out,
all the civil suits are
going to come at him
and then he has to pull an old jam moved
to Florida where they can't touch your
pension or some bullshit money.
He had something like that.
Wow.