Well, tiny women would be into a, no, just
like vagina would be like, you know of.
I know I've never,
I never thought that like Asian
pussy was that much smaller than like
stem research. You know, I have
a spiritual evidence, you know?
Well, you know, this doesn't
make 100% sense. Okay.
But I've met girls that were tiny
that you could not fuck hard enough.
Yeah. And it just open up.
Yeah. But not, not just that.
It's just like they want it like
that. They want, they want savage,
they want to get fucking smashed.
Why is that?
Is because I think they realized
that they, they're tiny.
They have small genes so they want to
get savage genetics inside them so they
have survivor children. I really believe
that. I think it only makes sense.
Oh, the horniest girls irritated
in my life weigh about 104 lbs.
And these big brand a talks, chicks want
it real soft. No one when I used to be,
they want to because they know that those
are the little girls are fucking giant
dudes making Doyle sites kid
and they're going to keep going.
It's a never ending battle
for genetics, dude. It really,
it is fun to 100% it's a never ending
battle of genetics and if she denies girls
fucking these like Beta dude's not. Did
they do, they do it for a little while.
They barely fuck them. They always
say they have headaches. Listen, I,
I know a lot of Beta dude,
the girl does like I can't sleep.
They don't want to fuck the guys.
Dude.
I had a friend of mine who was dating a
guy like that when she was a really like,
I just do not want to fuck him. And
I was like, wow, cause why would you,
I was like, that was rough. I'm
like, what are you going to do?
Just don't fuck him dude. It's,
it's dude, it's insane man.
It's like I see this all the time.
Like these like hardcore perceivably
hardcore feminist chicks. Yeah.
Here my comedy could be
the opposite of that.
And they're in the DMS, right?
Saying, I don't know why I'm here.
I swear to God it's a trap house
because I think feminism in general is
a direct result of a failure by men.
To be fair and by a failure by men,
to be actual men and to raise actual
men who treat everybody with respect.
The when men are abusing women,
those men are bullies. They're,
they're weak men.
The kind of man that would do that to
a woman that would be like physically
abused, a woman. That's a weak man, right?
That's the type of man that would eat
up a smaller man or take someone from
someone with four. Since security needs
to feel powerful, he's a bitch. Yeah.
He's a bitch. Right? The antidote for
that is to be a strong man, right?
Like do one of the things I've been
telling people like this is how you fix
bullying in school. Teach
them out of fight. Not the
bullies. I mean, not just the,
not just the victims, but the bullies
themselves. Everyone had a fight.
When they feel confidence that
they can defend themselves.
They don't have to nicest fucking people
in the world. Yeah. Martial artists,
you go and go to martial arts gyms, go
to a Jujitsu gym. I'll take you there.
All fucking nicest people as they know,
hugging everybody in friendly,
then they're going to choke each other
half to death in about five minutes and
before that, they're
all fun, happy, playful.
They're so secure and outside of their,
they're so secure and relax.
There are different type type of person,
obviously not all of them.
Maybe there's people over the
moon. We vary wildly, right?
But almost always to a human.
The mean ones,
whether it's mean women or mean when male,
weak,
weak women.
Women will tell you this.
They work at an office and they've
got a female boss. That's a con.
That is one of the worst fucking cause.
You can't even fucker nothing.
You can do nothing you could
do to make that bitch happy.
She wants to take from you.
She wants to squeeze your blood.
At least if you're cute and you're boss
is disgusting and he's a fucking asshole,
you could flirt with them a little bit
and you could like maybe get them to like
you more. Don't do it. Obviously
don't do that, but with a female boss,
you have to have a personality to
shit. Shocking what? The female boss,
not even that. A lot of women
don't like women. Right.
One of the things that I love more than
anything is when I talk to women and
they'll do this thing where they look
around to make sure no one's looking,
no one's around, and I go, look,
I would never say this publicly,
but some bitches are fucking crazy.
That's what we do with like racist shit.
It didn't burn. Have that bit of that
like I look around and then you slide it.
The thing about these,
yes,
will this women feel like they've got
momentum in this little war of ideas with
the me too movement.
Bill Cosby getting arrested.
Are Kelly getting arrested and
Harvey Weinstein? I, in my opinion,
and I bet you think this too.
These are good things. Yeah.
When shitty men get put away or they
get arrested for abusing people,
whether it's their physically abusing
men or physically abusing women,
it's always good. You shouldn't
be physically abusing it.
I'm out of here. Yeah,
to beat those guys up.
I mean this is handled in the community.
When we were younger, teenagers,
Hey, bottled blood, you know,
it was rough with this, the
whatever who was rough. Right.
And we went over there and if you were
married and Harvey Weinstein tried to
fuck your wife and she went in on audition
and you knew that there was all these
security guards and all these fucking
levels before you got to him and your wife
got into that level and he was treating
her like shit and being mean to her and
telling her,
if you want to work in this town,
you've got to suck this little fat
dick. You'd be, it's over Harry.
That's over angry.
I'm shocked.
Like someone told him it didn't Brad
Pitt try to step to him or something like
that did step to him. And did he swing
on him? I don't know what he did.
Cause you guys,
right?
Like well that's the other thing
that's fucked up about this. It's like
there's going to be Weinstein's. Yeah,
like these people are going to exist.
This man, they still
exist. Yeah, they still do.
Is hearing about one last
night someone was to,
I can't tell you the
comic cause I don't wait.
He's a television personality
who was apparently a closeted
homosexual. Oh, what?
He's out there and he's
out there like dudes. Yeah,
just going on our list.
I don't know.
He's trying really trying and making
them uncomfortable. Really? Really?
How well known. I don't know the
bullshit and later we'll talk later,
but what I'm saying
to him after it was crazy
fuckers out there, there's
still rolling it old school.
They want to get caught.
Kwame Paltrow.
V's Brad Pitt threatened to kill Harvey
Weinstein. But you got to swing on hand,
but you got to swing on him,
Bro. You got to leave some marks.
I believe it so well it depends
on what Harvey did versus what we,
if he grabbed her,
it did anything to her physically,
then you got to swing on him.
But if he just said something creepy
and you tell them I can get him,
we have word, take your fucking
life, I'll take your life.
Well I think the issue with these things
is like we know we're going to have
Weinstein's,
but the people that protected Weinstein,
the second you complain about a guy for
grope in or doing something crazy right,
that woman is doing exactly what
she's supposed to do, right?
She experienced sexual assault and she's
telling right now if you silence her
and shot her up, that's where
the system falls apart. Right?
So whoever is protecting him throughout,
he got it.
They got to go to because she then went
and did exactly what she was supposed to
do. Right. There's going to be Weinstein's
throughout life, unfortunately.
A question. What about the support
staff? All that many people,
all of them are almost, they're not
worse cause they're not doing it,
but they're so bad because they strip
the person who was assaulted from
like not only equality,
but like they stripped her from,
from life in a way like they
made that person go, oh shit.
Life isn't fair.
And I don't have a shot.
Do you know the expression
diffusion of responsibility? It's,
it comes when there's large groups
of people that watch something,
someone's going to step in. It's like
that lady, uh, Jenna vcs or something.
Remember that there was some woman who
was getting raped and queens and she was
screaming for like 40 minutes and there
was all these neighbors around like,
yeah, I heard it, but I thought Ted was on
it. Oh Jesus. You didn't hear about this?
No. Think Katie, Jenna vcs or
some shit. It's the old story,
but yet everybody was like,
oh, I'll get it. Yeah, it's
the same kind of thing. It's,
well, it's just how corporations work.
So if you're working for a corporation,
the Corporation's dumping pollutants into
the river, you know, you feel like, well,
it's not my responsibility. I just
work here in accounting. You know,
like somebody else is going to
handle this right now. This is,
and I think when you,
if you are working in like the Weinstein
Company and you knew Harvey was out
there slinging Dick, first
of all, in their defense,
you probably didn't know the specifics,
right? Because it's like, oh,
Harvey's a dog. He's always
out there trying to fuck.
Yeah. That's sort of normal.
Like a lot like people
have to understand this.
Why does a guy like that get rich?
Why does he get rich is he likes some
patron of the arts who loves creating
Nabi? There's a little bit, maybe
he likes power. Yes. You like power.
Why do you like that power?
What are you getting out of that power?
Once you have a Ferrari, once you have
a Mercedes, once you have a manager,
what are you getting?
You're getting post sandy pussy.
Pussy.
So it's about power right?