Yeah. Wait, so you, cause you were
telling me this and I was like,
he was about to tell me before you came
and I was like this sounds like this
could be pretty good. Don't tell me save
it for the podcast that cause he's done.
This is the most press Sean's done for
a film that he's put out that did you go
under? They were like let's give
you some advice on media. Yeah.
Well first of all I'm terrible at
it. There's that, cause I don't do,
this is the thing,
when you direct a movie,
especially in movies like the kind of
movies that I make comedies and you know
big broad comedies, people don't
really care who directed those movies.
And I'm good with that.
Like I'm totally good with that.
But what usually happens is the studio,
the director usually wants to be
kind of a part of the campaign.
So the studio will find,
they'll sort of throw bones at
u of like press that you can do.
And I always tell them, look, if I can
be helpful in any way, let me know.
I'll do whatever you need me to do,
but don't throw many bones
cause I don't care. Right.
I don't need it to Kinda just pump up
the ego of the director that certain
directors just really want to be the
next Quentin turn. Yeah, I can't,
I can't imagine there's some directors
they really have to do it for. I get it.
They don't want you to
feel left out or whatever.
But by my first couple of movies I
thought, oh I have to do this stuff.
And then I realized,
I actually had this experience where I
was in this red carpet thing and they
brought me up to this reporter and
they said, this is Shawn Andrews.
He directed the movie and she had this
big look on her face and then she went
like, ugh, cheese. And I
was like, Nah, it's cool.
You don't have so disappointed.
So disappointed. And that's when it
sunk into me where I was just like,
oh they don't care. They don't give
it. So that's, that's fine with me.
I'm good there.
Well there's such fame whores and
those days are those red carpet things.
There are so weird. Yeah,
those things are so weird.
And some people that is the highlight
of their life walking that carpet.
I can't chew over here. Tom
got your pose down. Right.
It's a really weird thing.
Also the Paparazzi at the
airport, you have that where,
um,
I've seen them where I'm at baggage and
they're looking around and then they're
like, hey Tom. And they'll ask me
like more thing and they're like,
they're obviously not there for
me, but they're like, they're like,
we got time till fucking whatever.
Seth Rogan gets off the plane,
so let me ask you something. And then
they're like, oh, all right, nevermind.
Here's everybody. Like, just blow you off.
I happen only one time because this
obviously doesn't happen to me.
They was flying at lax and I was getting
off a red eye and I was so just tired.
I looked like shit and that,
and this guy,
these two guys come up and they just
were so nice. They were like, hey,
you're Sean Anders. Right? And I was like,
yeah, yes I am John Anderson. Nobody ever,
you know?
And so it takes me a second to realize,
and I thought it was so weird because
they were, it was right after,
it was shortly after daddy's home.
And that was like the biggest hit.
And they were asking me about
horrible bosses too. And I was like,
why are they asking me about, of all
things horror? And I thought, oh,
because Jennifer Aniston's in it.
So they want me to say something about
Jennifer Aniston and just see if they can
catch me saying something crazy and
looking for a soundbite slip or something.
There's all they tried to do.
Yeah. It was the worst. It's weird.
And my wife is like, what
was that? I'm like, I, I,
it took me like an hour to sort of like
trying to make you click bait. It's not,
yeah.
Well,
what's interesting too is it's like sort
of an impromptu interview that you have
to do, right? Like if somebody
said, hey, this guy's name is Mike.
He lives in studio city. He wants
you to go to his house and, uh,
he's gonna film you. Uh, he's going to
ask you wacky questions. He'd be like, no.
Yeah,
but if Mike shows up at the baggage claim
and puts that camera in your face, hey,
Sean, Jennifer Aniston, man, what's up
with the Botox? You're like, what? Yeah.
Fuck. You know what I mean?
That's how they get, like,
you wouldn't do an interview with
them under any other circumstances,
which is one of like,
one of the weird things that happened
during the Roseanne Barr things.
Roseanne Barr, when her show was canceled
and all the controversy was going on,
she was supposed to do the podcast and
it became a big news thing cause she put
it on her, uh, her Twitter that I'm
going to do it. And we talked about it.
And then they tried to show
up at the podcast studio.
So they had all these news people standing
outside the podcast studio with their
microphones were out at,
out in front of where Joe Rogan does
his podcast and they thought for some
reason, just because they're there, people
have to talk to them. Right. I'm here.
Talk to me like they're made out of
milk. They're barely human. They,
the way they talk is the
most boring version of an
interview you'd ever get ever.
It's a tiny, quick little soundbite,
but they feel like, because they're,
they're like, the camera's on. I've got
the microphone. Come on it. You do it.
If they said, hey, you know, kw,
fuck yourself once you to come in and
sit down for an interview, you'd be like,
no, I don't want to. I don't want
to talk to them. I don't know.
I don't have anything to
say like, Oh, I'll do all my
talking on the podcast. Yeah,
well, but, and also if you're, I
mean, I'm in the business, but again,
I'm not somebody that does a
tremendous amount of pressure,
or at least not until
a couple of weeks ago.
And if you're not accustomed to that,
it's terrifying.
It's weird because somebody puts a
camera in your face because immediately
you're thinking like, well, if I just
go, you know what man? Fuck you. Like,
I don't have time for that. Then you're
going to, so you just think like,
I can't even walk away from this.
So you're just feeling like you're all
of a sudden somebody through a cage over
you and they're not even asking you,
can I do this? They're just doing it.
They're just, hey Sean. Yeah. Let me
ask you a question, Shawn. It's forced.
It's forced on you.
It puts you in a weird spot.
It's like all of a sudden you're in your,
you're on,
you're on your heels because
you're instinct is to be defensive.
If someone could see your, you know what
I mean? Your instinct is not going to be,
I'll give the most thoughtful
answer to this because it's, it's,
it's in the moment. Someone just dropped
it on you. So now you're like, okay,
and your, your emotions might be kind
of all over the place and you're not,
you're not stopping to like,
like having a conversation.
You're just sort of trying
to figure your way out of it.
And how many people have
ruined their careers or lives
on those things just said,
just fucked up and said one, they just
try to be funny or just that's the thing.
Cause they'll misquote,
dated and then they get ya.
And then they put it up and you're like,
fuck, why didn't I think through that?
I was coming home from the airport,
I was tired.
I was jetlagged Bordain got a shitload
of death threats because he said they
asked him if you had a serve dinner
to Kim Jong Un and Donald Trump,
what would you serve? He said,
hemlock, he's trying to be funny. Yeah.
And then you all these Manga fucking
morons protestors were there.
They were all sending these
tweets like Potus, you know,
he's threatening POTUS and it
was so strange. Like where,
where's the NFL? You know,
where's the secret service?
They should lock this motherfucker up.
And like you guys are crazy. It's a joke.
And that's the thing right there
is that clickbait articles are,
they all make it,
it'll say like so and so said this and
they make it sound like somebody like
called a press conference to say something
ridiculous. And really it was like,
like you said,
it'll be some offhand remark and then
people out there that are judging they
that they never have anybody walk up
and put a camera in their face and they
just think, well, I would
never say anything like that.
It's like you don't know what you would
say. You're never in that situation.
It's bizarre. It's very bizarre. Bizarre.
So how many of these things did you
have to do to promote this film?
Because it will, because of this
film was based in large part of it.
On your actual life experiences
of adopting these kids.
How many of these things did
you have to wind up doing a lot?
Because I did,
we did our press junket in New York and
I've done junkets and usually I do like,
you know, six or seven or 15
or whatever I did in two days.
I did like 90 95 sort of the same
questions keep coming at you over and over
again and you start developing these
canned responses. That's the thing,
you have to,
and this is a mistake,
and this gets back to what
you were getting at before,
is that when I would do press
on my movies in the past,
I go to the junket and people would come
in and they didn't ask you more or less
the same questions. And I always felt
weird because I just felt like, no,
I just want to have a
conversation with you.
I don't want to be like
this disingenuous guy.
And then I would be sort of changing
up my answers and trying to kind of,
and it just essentially just made it
boring and I wasn't really making any kind
of a point whatsoever. So, uh, on
this one, they were like, look,
you've got a message with this movie.
You've got things you want
to get out with this movie.
You've got to learn how to do this.
So I went,
I went to like a day of media training.
And it was,
I did, I did. And it was,
the worst part was I had done
interviews and I've been fine before.
I got this guy sitting
across from me. Uh, who's,
who's interviewing me
doing this mock interview,
and then I've got the publicist and my
writing partner and they're just staring
at me and now all of a sudden I can't
do it. Right. All the pressures there.
Who's teaching you?
Who is teaching this media training?
Here's what they right away like, you
kind of suck at this. Absolutely were.
I mean, they were really nice about
it. They were like, okay, all right,
well there's some, there's some room for
improvement. Oh my God. Really? Oh yeah.
I know. It was the worst. It
was, seemed like a natural,
I mean there's what is there to teach.
You well know what it was. This,
this is the thing is I'm really
comfortable with this with,
with us just hanging out here talking.
Sure.
But this is what I do is I Yammer
when I'm, I'm a nervous talker.
So you asked me a question if I'm nervous,
I just kind of go and go and go.
And people are like, Geez, us, you know
that guy talk.
So the thing is,
I got this guy sitting across me,
really nice guy and he's
The guy who's coaching me,
but I know I'm going to get some trolls,
like fake interviews.
Well he'd how they coach
you first he gave me,
he gave me a lot of really good insights
and the funny thing is every rule that
he's saying as he sang it, I'm
going, Oh yeah, I do that. Oh yeah.
Like everything he's saying
that I shouldn't be doing.
I'm like, Oh yeah, that's,
I always do. What is he saying
you shouldn't be doing? I
mean that the main thing,
it's kind of like what we were getting
at before that when somebody is setting a
trap for you,
because so much of right
now media training is just
about don't go out and get
yourself into trouble by going in and,
and just talking about some ridiculous
area that, cause that's what people,
that's what everybody's trying to
do now. Like just as a, for example,
I did a Time magazine interview about
adoption about a year before we even made
the movie. Really? Yeah. The,
and it was just because I was in the
process of working on the movie anyway,
the whole thing was just about
adoption and my family and whatever.
And it was right when the Harvey
Weinstein stuff was blowing up. So ladies,
really nice interview. And then at
the end she says, uh, hey, you know,
since I'm talking to a Hollywood director,
I'd be remiss if I didn't ask did you
know about that Harvey Weinstein stuff?
And I was like, Nah. And I mean it.
And I didn't even think about my
answer because I don't, you know,
I didn't know the guy was
never around any of it.
That's sort of like more
like fancy movies. And I was
like, yeah, I know I don't,
I don't know. I never met the guy,
whatever. I didn't think anything of it.
And I got off the phone and then
I thought, oh, she didn't say,
what do you think about this stuff? She
said, did you know about that stuff?
And it was like, and then I knew, but
I kept it a secret. Yeah. Those people.
And I just thought right away,
I just, you know, so yeah.
It's, it's, it's sneaky. That's a
sneaky way of asking. It's a sneaky,
the way to get you to yeah,
yeah, yeah. Did you know,
well if you don't enter his captors
Weinstein secret for years, I,
I'm such a dumb shit. I would have,
like you said before, I think,
I think a year or two ago I might of made
a joke, you know, and been like, oh yeah,
I was there, you know, just
printing. Yeah. Anders was there.
And then if you like what you
know, so, uh, so you know,
a lot of it is just just to kind of teach
you how to just sort of stay on point
so that you don't get dragged down these
weird roads into these things that just,
that people are looking to
get you in on clickbait.
So did you bring up that instance when
you went through the training? Oh yeah.
Did you say what should I have said?
I think I did.
I think and really what they,
what they teach you.
It was funny cause believe it or not,
he said I'm going to show
you some clips of, you know,
sort of doing it right and doing it wrong.
Oh they have disaster clips.
They say they do. And one of them, the
file that you sent to jail, the show,
and you guys will probably
all know this one.
They showed me a clip
of Quentin Tarantino,
sort of like getting really
angry with this reporter.
Does that the violent thing?
Yeah.
I thought it was kind of and kick
some guys asked that lady was like,
your films are disgusting and
violent. And he was like, yeah,
they're fucking movies dummy.
Like he gets really upset about it.
And where was this? Actually I
don't know if it's the same one.
Cause the one that I saw was a
guy. Oh I saw him with a lady. Uh,
but that was via sat like a,
okay. So this is a different one.
Then there was one where
the guy's threatening to
kick the guy's ass. I don't,
the one that I saw didn't go that far.
But what I actually Kinda liked
what he did cause he was like, no,
I'm not playing that game with you.
I'm not doing,
he got all pissed off but I
was sort of like, Eh, you know,
I liked that he does that. I mean I liked
the one with the lady. The lady is like,
your movies are so violent. Awful. And
he was like a movie, a make belief thing.
It's not real violence. Like he really
Sassy as her. It's funny as shit.
And then I also, so she, where was
she? She was doing, you know, she was,
she was like good morning Pittsburgh,
like the entertainment reporter.
And then he was actually probably doing
like satellite stuff everywhere and he
was just like, you're dumb. So, uh,
but I also saw there's that guy,
he's a Gotcha guy too.
Did a Robert Downey jr it was
like promoting a movie too.
I don't know if they should go that
one. Right. And the guy's like, yeah,
now your drug addiction.
He was like, wait, what?
Like it was totally to try to get
him to, you know, in a moment,
Robert Downey jr is not having it. He's
like, Nah, I'm here to promote a movie.
Yeah. This has nothing to do with that.
Totally. Is that what he said? But let's,
let's get into your drug addiction. Yeah.
He was like, during your darkest times,
like what are you talking about man,
iron mans out.
I'm not doing my hair for that.
Well, it's just like the ends it too.
They're so selfish. Like that thing is
so doing shit like that is so selfish.
It's such a sneaky little thing to do.
They know. What did they teach you though?
Like in that moment of like
Quintin, they're just like,
don't, don't get emotional.
Well, it's like don't take the bait
and, and more than anything for me,
because I look, I'm from Wisconsin
and I still have that kind of,
everybody's nice, everybody has good
intentions, kind of five, you know. So,
and I had this experience on my very first
movie where I talked to this reporter
because it was a movie about a,
it was a road trip. You know,
it's just a silly road trip comedy,
you know,
and I talked to this reporter and he
says, and he, and he was just being,
he was being really cool.
We were just kinda hanging out after
this thing talking and he's like,
sa and gas prices were really high. And he
goes, so yeah. You know, he's, he's like,
you feel worried about making a road
trip movie when gas prices are so high?
And I, and I said like, ah,
I don't know. I, I, you know,
maybe if the movie tanks I can just blame
it on that no one could afford to go
to the theater because the prices
were so high and I don't think,
and then this article comes out that just,
the guy literally said I was
swarthy looking and it just,
he just painted me like an absolute
piece of shit and I was like,
that guy was so cool.
Like he was like when we were having
a nice time talking and then he just
destroyed me. I've been there.
Yeah, I'm sure you guys have. Yeah,
that's all new to me. I remember
one too that like who did it to me,
like when I was just doing phone,
like a phone interview for press before
I was selling any tickets and the guy
was like,
just like a really nice guy and totally
twisted things and made it seem like
just like he knows what I was saying and
he purposely twisted things around and
then it had real no, no impact. But I
remember reading that and being like,
Oh fuck this guy and,
and be careful when you talk to
these people because he totally,
he knows what I was trying to say and
I, and I read this article, I was like,
he misrepresented everything. Yeah. Well
that's the only way they can have fun.
Yeah. And that's the only, I mean if
you're just a normal guy and you give a,
you know, normal answers and
you're thoughtful and considerate,
that's not as good for them. Right. It's
boring to them. Twist it around. Well,
it's not just, it's not as profitable.
Right. It's more profitable.
Especially if it's an online
thing with an online thing.
You need a clickbait title.
You need a bunch of people clicking on
that thing because otherwise you're not
going to get any ad revenue for it.
Yes.
It's a very bizarre model where it's like
encouraging people to be deceptive and
to make these things inflammatory.
And I got to say, I mean, look, I did,
like I said,
I did nineties 95 interviews and suck
in the course of two days and virtually
everybody was really cool, really asking,
really thoughtful, interesting question.
So I don't want to make it sound like
I'm ripping on the whole press over this.
But yeah,
there are these people and that's the
thing is that if it was every single
person that came along,
it would almost be easier because
you could just kind of be like, okay,
here we go. I got it. Right. But
you, but you get like 30 really good,
you know,
uh,
reporters with integrity and good people
and then somebody jumps in and you're
like, oh yeah. And then, then,
then they catch you not looking because
you're not looking for that guy.
It also gets super jaded,
you know?
It's almost like cops that have arrested
too many people. Everyone's a crook.
Like they just think that everybody that
we're interviewing is a piece of shit.
And it's also like they're
interviewing these Hollywood people.
They're thinking of you. You had a
big mansion and driving a Mercedes.
You got all this money. Fuck this guy.
It's like this instant take on it. Oh,
a Hollywood director. Right, right. How's
your casting couch? Yeah. Shit. Yeah,
that's true. It's true.
And it becomes the game.
I think too for them the game is like,
let's see if I can get one and we
shouldn't be real clear. This is not,
most people, most people are
nice, but it's just like one,
even if it's only one out of 10
you run into that one. You're like,
fuck these things.
I don't want to do these things anymore.
Totally terrifying because you think
about your family, your friends,
like anybody who's going to
cause now there, there is this,
and I know you guys talk about this a lot.
There is this culture out there where
people are completely reduced to like one
moment or one statement or whatever it is.
And that's all you are,
is that whatever that thing that
happened in that one moment and you know,
you see it happening to people all
the time and you think about so,
so when you're there and you feel
like you're just a regular guy,
you don't feel like you know that.
It's really scary because you think
about your kids and you think of it,
you know, it's so, it's a, it's a
scary situation. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
it's a weird time for these
publications to them and it's done.
Nothing taken in consideration.
No one's really buying magazines
and newspapers like they used to.
It's hard to sell.
And so they're reduced to these online
publications and they have to compete
with a bunch of these click baity bullshit
things. And that's where the money is.
I mean, even in New York Times, man,
the New York Times is resulting
to a lot of click baity shit now.
And you're like,
wow.
Well do you guys have that feeling like
when you're online that you're on like a
clickbait diet where you see
things where you're like, oh man,
I totally want to eat that right now, but
like I'm not, I'm not going to do that.
Let me get an ingredient.
Yeah, open it up. Oh, it's so
sweet that you click on it,
you're like, navigate it. Now you
read that title and you're like,
I know this will have no substance to
like one moment or one statement or
whatever it is.
And that's all you are is that whatever
that thing that happened in that one
moment.
And you know,
you see it happening to people all
the time and you think about so,
so when you're there and you feel
like you're just a regular guy,
you don't feel like you know that.
It's really scary because you think
about your kids and you think of it,
you know, it's so, it's a, it's a
scary situation. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
it's a weird time for these publications
to them and it's taken in consideration.
No one's really buying magazines
and newspapers like they used to.
It's hard to sell.
And so they're reduced to these online
publications and they have to compete
with a bunch of these click baity bullshit
things, and that's where the money is.
I mean, even in New York Times, man,
the New York Times is a resulting
to a lot of click baity shit now.
And you're like,
wow.
Well do you guys have that feeling like
when you're online that you're on like a
clickbait diet where you see
things where you're like, oh man,
I totally want to eat that right now, but
like, I'm not, I'm not going to do that.
Let me get an ingredient. Yeah, open it
up. Oh, it's so sweet. You Click on it,
you're like, navigate it. Now you
read that title and you're like,
I know this will have no substance.
Yeah.