There's studies that compare testicle
size of different civilizations and
different cultures.
There's a lot of argument about this.
And the problem is that the print
that it's racist, it's racist, right?
That's what underlies a lot of it. But we
get scared, right? So the thing is that,
that the, the um, the genetics,
it explain why one animal or one
species would have large testicles.
In other words,
a small testicles are not the genetics
that would explain why two different
individuals in the same
species would be that way.
Because the only way to make that
latter one work is you have to inherit a
constellation of traits.
So if I'm in a hair,
the genes for big balls
and for impulsiveness and
for having lots of kids and
not caring much about him and all the
things that are supposedly go with that,
that do, when you look between
species, there's no way for those,
that constellation of traits
to be inherited together.
Cause remember I was talking
about how polygenic everything is.
And so they'd all literally need to sit
next to each other on the chromosome if
they've got any chance of being
passed on as a package and they don't.
And you also get all the shifting
around her in Meiosis. Um,
I can't remember the term
for off the top of my head,
but where the pieces of genetic
material move around and that virtually
guarantees that you're not going to
inherit this huge constellation of traits
within a species between
species is dead easy. You know,
you're a species inherits big testicles
and inherits impulsiveness. It inherits,
you know, whatever. Uh, and our strategy
just reproduce a ton and ignore them.
You know,
all that kind of stuff's dead easy.
And so CIM fathers don't pay any attention
to chimp babies to speak of because
while that's their mating
system, right? Whereas, um,
you've got pair bonded Gibbons and things
and now parents start to play a much
bigger, even male parents
start to play a bigger role.
But there's no studies that show that
human beings with archer testicles tend to
ignore their children. Well, so this is
just it. People have tried to show that.
But here's the problem.
I tried to show that studies.
So lots of people make that argument
and it's called life history strategies
where you say,
well,
you're going to develop one life history
strategy in these circumstances and
another and these other circumstances.
The problem is that you end up with
ethnic differences in testicle size,
which we know exist.
And you also have ethnic differences in
where in the kinds of lives that people
currently lead.
The difficult thing is it's super easy
to look at the world we are in right now
and this is what tripped
me up earlier as well.
You look at the world that we
are right now and assume, well,
that's the way things have always been
and they haven't. And so right now,
you know, the uh,
mathematics used for a while,
they're the best math in the world
was taking place in the Arabic world.
Now it's not anymore. And so if you,
if you don't know that past, you'd say,
well look,
people in the Arabic world aren't as
good at mathematics and they have these
qualities and that you'd make an inference
right now the ethnic differences in
testicles,
I believe,
but I can't promise you that it's some
different west African groups happen to
have the largest testicle size on average.
Um,
those west African groups
tend to be poorer right now.
There's lots of things about life that
go with being poor that looked like and
our strategy having lots of kids
and paying less attention to them.
But what you're probably looking at is
a coincidental association between some
biology and some, uh, some way that your,
your people happen to live that didn't
exist a while ago and that won't exist a
while from now. And so it's really
easy to try to use this research,
which people have to say,
well,
you've got some primitive people who have
big testicles and low parental effort
and you've got some more sophisticated
people with smaller testicles in the high
parental effort.
But that's genetically super naive.
One of the things that I
learned when I was in Rome,
we took a tour of the Vatican
by this guy who was a professor.
It was really interesting.
It was cool because we used to have a,
a really enthusiastic guide and who,
who could explain a lot of things to you.
And he was really excited that,
you know,
me and my family were very
curious about these things too.
But one of the things that
he said that was really
interesting, I said, okay, I go,
why all the dudes have little dicks,
like what's going on with that?
And he said that they believed
that if you had a large penis,
that large penises were a
symbol of barbaric behavior
and that these were crude
or people. And that to be, you know,
thought to be a sophisticated person.
You wanted a smaller penis.
So they actually accentuated smaller
penises in their gods and smaller penises
and their statutes.
And that's funny. I mean, you can see
these kinds of things all the time.
So early pre western contact. Uh, if you
look at Japanese women, they're pinned,
they're painted with their eyes as
narrow of a slit as possible post western
contact.
Now the women want more almond shaped
eyes and so they start painting them with
the beautiful women have bigger eyes.
These things can change all over the map.
I personally suspect that large penis
sizes also product to sexual selection.
So it's more fun for her if he's got a
larger penis or having sex for longer and
more regularly because
obviously patients hidden.
So he has to be available all the time.
So she has to be available all the
time or the system doesn't work.
And that's what creates pair bonding.
So humans copulating for a
very long period of time.
If you compare us to the other primates
with the single exception of Bonobos and
we have way bigger penises than
any of the other great apes.
And I suspect that that's something
that is female. I mean women always say,
why are men subsets to the penis size?
But I suspect that there
are the creator of it,
and that's why we're so obsessed with it.
Women who say that are playing games,
they know that's ridiculous.
I don't know that they are.
They're definitely playing games.
That's like men who are saying, why
are women so obsessed with big breasts?
We don't even care. I've never met a
guy who said that. Everybody has some,
some asshole out there that's playing
games. Okay. Possibly. You're right.