This is the, the big one is immigration
to me because immigration to me,
when people take a hard line one way
or the other, I'm always like, man,
this is a weird one.
Immigration's a weird one.
You don't want to diminish the quality
of life for everyone in the country,
but you don't want to not let people in
because that's what the country is based
on. And you see these fenced in
people and is it, is it El Paso?
There was something that they had on the
news where they showed all these people
fenced in and what looks like a
dog Kennel and these, these, uh,
people that snuck across the
border and they captured him.
So they just put them in this fucking
outdoor fenced in cage. Like, dude,
we don't even do that
too violent murderers.
You'd have a violent murderer
who due process due process,
you put him in a prison man.
Right?
Like they don't have the facilities
to do what they're doing. Right.
And then people are like, whoa, they
shouldn't be coming across the border.
I guess so. But wouldn't you
almost like, who wouldn't you,
who cares? Like I, I understand,
yes there is sort of a,
but anybody who is up in arms about
immigrants coming into this country,
most of the time they're also on one
side of the political spectrum on every
other issue.
It's not like it's an independent thought.
It's like [inaudible] and everybody that's
on both sides, you know? And you know,
I just sort of,
I'm going to,
I have my own personal life philosophy
where I'm not going to solve the
immigration issue. And to be honest, as
we're talking about, I'm going to like,
I don't know. I, I have no
idea what the answer is here.
People are obsessed with being right.
People always want to have an answer.
I don't fucking know. But I do know that
I have things in my life that, you know,
I can fix. I know they're, you know,
the things about my personality and
things about me and my own, you know,
my own issues that I need to fix. So
I'll sort of start there, you know,
and I think more people need to kind of,
you know,
before they started spousing opinions,
look at themselves and figure out why
they're coming up with these opinions.
Is that what you're saying? Yeah,
just sort of, um, I just like,
it pulls on your humanity.
You see a bunch of people caged in with
their children and in some fenced in
area that literally looks like a
dog Kennel. Yeah. This is crazy.
Well, I'm not saying I don't
care about that. I just, I,
I don't care about people coming into
the country and going in these imaginary
lines. I, I, you know, it's just
sort of like, yeah, I think it's, um,
I, I think as a human being,
it's hard to see that.
And I look away from shit like
that a lot. You know, I don't look,
I don't like looking at videos like that.
I don't like watching sad things.
I don't watch any Gore Shit.
I didn't watch the video of the dude that
moved down those people in New Zealand.
Um, you know. Yeah. It is a sad thing
and I really don't know the solution.
Look at this shit.
It says they treated us
like we were animals.
A holding pen for migrant
families in El Paso. Shut down.
Shut down overnight I guess. Okay, because
people found out about it. It's crazy.
You look at that,
that's a dog Kennel.
That means people just sit
around waiting for what? I mean,
if that was murderers,
they wouldn't do so.
Let's say you're the guy in charge though.
What do you do?
What would you, I mean me, I wish that's
a good question. I'll go let him in,
but I don't know if
that's the right answer.
I don't know if it's the answer to either,
but I guarantee you all of our with your
relatives came from another country.
My relatives all came from another
country or the I'm third generation. They,
they knew that Europe sucked. They knew
that Italy sucked and say like, look,
I mean no disrespect Italy,
but they decided I've got to get the
fuck outta here and they got on a boat.
All of them, grandparents on both
sides. They both came over here.
When they were kids. Does
Italy suck? Seems awesome.
Everything I've seen about it.
Grateful. Well, the food is fantastic.
When I talked to a guy there that was
trying to get an understanding because he
wanted his kids to go
to college in America,
and what he was basically saying was
there was just not enough opportunity in,
in Italy. And that, uh,
he wanted his son to have more opportunity
and she was driving a cab. Actually,
they all speak two languages. They
all speak perfect English. Mike,
a good percentage of them are
there. You know, it's a smart place.
The Lot in the art is insane.
When you're,
when you're going through Rome and
you go through, um, the Vatican,
you see their billions of dollars,
literally billions of dollars in artwork.
You're like, Holy Shit. Like this is
what a crazy culture, this culture,
all they wanted to do was create beautiful
architecture, create beautiful art,
make wine, make great food, have sex,
fuck like crazy and kind of
take over the world. I mean,
they took over the world
for a long ass time.