The Joe Rogan experience.
It's only 30,
only 30 maybe.
What are you gonna do?
Blake Griffin's get a
murder in front of you.
It's a weird muscle
stand up to weird muscle.
Joey Diaz isn't exactly like
Joey Diaz is high by, by noon,
but he's funny as fuck it. And
Connie say before noon. Yeah.
Comedy is a weird thing.
Comedy is a very,
there are some fuckups Chilean Joey Diaz,
Mike and high all the time that mother
Fucker fucker works on this act.
Joey works on is, it's a mindset you're
always writing. You're always peaceful.
Joey Diaz is a pro. Like people see
Joey and they see that, you know,
he smokes a lot of weed
and he's crazy and they,
they assume that he just gets up there
just rants and raves. No, no, no, no.
That guy always has new material. Oh,
always. Always working on something. Yeah.
Yeah. He's, I think that's what
it takes to, I think that, um,
this kid was younger and he told me he
hadn't written a joke in two years and I
went, well, you're talking like a
loser. You know, you, you can't,
I think stand up is relentless.
Especially if you develop a following.
That's where he's at.
He's probably depressed.
There's something probably wrong with,
well, we talked about that too is like,
yeah, but I'm saying that,
you know, again, you know,
depression is a very real thing,
but I always said a kind of younger
people who seem like they're in a Rut.
I had to,
I'm a huge believer in just just take the
steps of getting better at one type of
language. Start. It doesn't matter
if it's a guitar, it doesn't matter.
Just just get better at one little thing.
Just start practicing.
It'll motivate you to do other things.
I'm not saying depression,
clinical depression is a very real thing.
I don't know enough about it. Well,
the thing is it is real. Yes.
But it's different with every
person. Yeah. It's like,
it's one of the rarest of diseases in
that like you really can't put it on a
scale. Yeah. Like use the
spectrum. You feel like shit
or you don't feel like shit.
You're depressed. You're not
depressed. Yeah. But what,
what level depressed are you,
are you suicidal? Are you
just like kind of Shitty?
Could you fix it with like running or,
or do you need like real chemical
intervention and in, do you know,
do you know the difference?
Like w what's your community like
what are your friendships like? Yeah.
What does your family life? Huge
questions. Huge questions. By the way,
how are you eating? How are you
exercising? What is your community like?
These are things where the in people
who live the longest and those studies,
what does it, Spain I heard
and I don't know if I'm right,
has the longest per capital lift people
right now and yet huge alcohol and
tobacco consumption.
But they are connected to community.
They're there and they do a lot of
that. They get nit in, you know,
taken cs as long lunches. Yes. Yes.
D and drinking red wine. Woo. Yeah.
Why not enjoying their life and dancing
salsa and sings? I'll, I, I've done,
I bet that maps to what is this Spain to
lead Japan and global life expectancy.
You go us continues to slide.
Yeah.
Cause we're eating shitty food and we're
getting fat. We're also isolated. Yeah.
There's a price you pay for as
a capitalist, as a capitalist,
as somebody who believes
in the free market,
there's a price you pay for the
praying to the god of and progress.
There is [inaudible] it as we as we are,
we're ruthlessly competitive Americans.
Rue Americans are fucking ruthlessly
competitive and insanely aggressive.
Football is a game of war. It's
simulated war. You're, you're, you're,
you're capturing territory
and everything else it,
we are so aggressive that way and
look and makes us a great country.
We also pay a price for it. No
question about it. Like I get,
I do get sort of the
notion that we need there.
There is this idea that we're the left,
a lot of the left says, look man, this,
this capitalism stuff that seems to
be creating isolation and depression.
Like how's it going?
Is there,
is there a conversation to be had about
how we figure out how we structure our
lives, where our community takes more
of a precedence where job security,
it takes more of a precedence.
All these things. Well,
the minute I start hearing socialism,
I start to freak out, but I just said,
I know what you're saying. Yeah. But
here's the thing about socialism.
Socialism in general sounds like a
terrible idea because a lot of people are
lazy and because of De incentivizes
people from action and there's a certain
thing that people should
have motivation to succeed.
They should have some drive and they
get some satisfaction out of achieving
goals.
And those are all things that I would not
want to deny any young person problem.
I think those, those are really
important things for happiness.
And one of the things that they've,
they've studied when they've
studied happiness and people,
people that are goal
oriented and that set,
they set goals and achieve those goals.
It's one of the best
markers for happiness.
And it doesn't necessarily mean money.
You know,
the problem is we like to think of
it as money as it's a money thing,
but in athletics and art,
when it without finance
attached to it at all,
when people set out to do
something and then do it,
they achieve a sense of self
worth and happiness. Yes.
And understand understanding of yourself,
who you are.
This is what's missing from a lot
of people. And, and, and again,
I'm not a clinical psychologist. I don't
really understand depression. I don't,
I don't suffer from it,
but I,
I've known enough people that have to
know that there's a lot of different kinds
of it. It's all different. And
I think some people just have,
they have a broken brain.
There's something wrong in there.
And it would be nice if there was a
chemical that could fit into that slot and
fix it.
And sometimes there is for those people
and sometimes it changes their lives.
And then I've known people
that were on the wrong meds,
like Ari was on probation. It was
fucking with him. It gave him depression,
you know, and sometimes people, they'll
change their diet. And you know,
one of the things that Rhonda Patrick was,
she posted something,
I think it was on her Twitter
account and how inflammation, um,
led to impulsive decision making,
led to cheating on your diet and lead to
poor decisions in terms of like overall
lifestyle, just from having higher levels
of inflammation. So eating shitty food,
not getting enough sleep,
drinking all those things,
lead to inflammation, accents,
all those things cause to
make more impulsive food
choices, shitty food choices,
bad dietary choices,
bad la lifestyle and rest choices.
Like they're all it almost like
inflammation wants more of it. Here it is.
Study finds an inflammation even at sub
clinical levels in healthy participants
may provoke impulsive behavior and
an inability to delay gratification.
Isn't that amazing? Yeah. I start,
I pull back with all this stuff and I
always think to myself like I think I
think what you and I are after,
like when the reason I'm happy and the
reason I feel so fulfilled is I'm able to
express myself re fully like fully.
Like I told you the other day,
like I certain developments in my life.
Like I was like I,
I want radical honesty in the sense
that I don't have to lie about anything.
I don't want to lie about anything.
I want to be very honest.
You and I have been always been
so honest with each other. Right?
And well that's why we know each other's
so. Yes. Wow. Yes. In the middle,
we start fucking bullshitting. And you're
like, Oh, why? Why do what? But that,
that's where you have your friends and
hold you accountable because they know
exactly who you are. And it's
very important. Exactly that. So,
so what that allows you to do is to
express yourself fully and completely
original self expression is my
whole, my credo, my idea. But,
but so w w eating well if eating well,
see,
I don't want my body to get in the way.
I don't want it to get in the way.
So I investigate how to feel optimal so
that I can just not have it get in the
way and I can do the things I
love. Yeah. That is a form of,
of expressing myself fully. I
always wanted a box. I was so,
it was such a mystery to me.
And I'll be,
I'm nervous today cause I gotta go spar
some fuck the whole time and doing it
now. How many years? Almost
five years now. But, but,
but, but I don't care about,
you know, I'm not going
to enter, you know,
I'm not gonna Wayne wants me to
fight and I want you to find it,
but I'm not going to do
I want to, I want to, uh,
I don't want to be an
actor who takes a fight.
It's hilarious to me doing that to you
because he's a fighter and he's a maniac.
Mine difficult to get in there. Lace
up the gloves and his one time, right.
You can fight, you can fight,
you can fight. Come on, throw
the old left, right, left.
Yeah.
And then I put,
I put on headgear and he just puts in a
mouthpiece and it's telling me you, yeah,
he puts his gloves wherever he
wants. Woo. Which is annoying, but,
but my point is that I, I feel like
I'm expressing myself in that vein.
I always wanted to do it.