But there's been such a significant
improvement in all those places that the
resistance tends to,
I mean,
how many people arguing for reversing
the cannabis legalization? Hey,
you don't ever hear it now.
Right.
And it's been a little bit of a
backlash and it kind of absurd,
but because it's come out repeatedly
kind of victor like artist Ilo,
I actually had that guy. I really
tell me about that. Why, how did,
we had a debate between him and
Alex Bernstein and a doctor,
Mike Hart from Canada.
Um, and there's some,
there's some reality to the dangers of
cannabis use as some people that are
susceptible to schizophrenia. Um,
and I think that there's also some,
at least anecdotal evidence at a points
of the fact that some people experience
these psychotic breaks and
these schizophrenia episodes
probably directly as a
result of large dose use of Thc,
whether it's through edibles or whether
it's through smoking at some people
freak out.
I've known people,
I've known of people that have
had real issues with it. I mean,
had a comedian here a couple of weeks ago,
talked about he doesn't smoke pot,
he's from Brazil. He smoked
pot, a s of use, a vape pen, uh,
took a bunch of hits and was
fucked up for two weeks. There are,
there are dangers and problems, certain
pizzas. So it's really important.
The case for legalizing cannabis is not
that there was no harm associated with
cannabis, right? In the same way the
case bill legalizing alcohol is not,
there's no homeless. I said, well,
this is what Alex Bernstein is
trying to go over in his book.
I don't think he did a good
job for two reasons. One,
because he's basically only making
the case for it to be negative.
And I think there's far more evidence
that cannabis has a positive influence on
people. It reinforces community. It
makes people more sensitive and kind.
This a thought of paranoia might
actually, it, it makes people more humble.
Um, it makes sex feel better and
fix food tastes better. There's,
there's creativity aspects
to it that are undeniable.
There's a lot of very positive aspects
to it. For some people it's not good,
but it's like saying, hey, some
people die when they eat peanuts.
Let's outlaw peanuts. I think that
one of your children about peanuts,
I think everything you just
said is absolutely right.
I think there's another layer
that's going on at the same time,
a kind of below that, which is really
important people to understand.
So there's this thing. Um, so
very often people will say, ah,
you get kind of republican
politicians like caught.
I'm a colleague Thena arena
saying it during when the
Republican debates in 2016,
2015 maybe,
um,
we can't legalize cannabis because it's
much stronger now than it used to be.
Thc content is called up.
People are smoking skunk.
It's really important to
understand why that happened.
It's because of drug prohibition.
So the day before alcohol was banned in
the u s the most popular drinks by far
were beer and wine.
In the weeks after alcohol prohibition
ended most popular drinks again,
where they're in wine as they are today.
In between,
you could not get hold of bear and wine.
The most popular drinks,
whiskey and moonshine. You cannot,
you think, well why would that be?
What's going on? And it's because of a
kind of slightly wonky and boring thing,
but I think it's worth talking about
is called the Iron Law of prohibition.
If you imagine, if we had to
smuggle the nearest bar to here,
if we had to smuggle all the alcohol for
that bar in a wagon from the Canadian
border, from the Mexican border,
right from Tijuana in a wagon,
we fill our wagon with beer, we're
going to get drink for a hundred people.
If we fill it with vodka, wigging it,
drink for thousands of people, right?
So when you ban a drug and
it has to be smuggled around,
you get a premium on getting the
biggest possible kick into the smallest
possible space,
right?
This is why mild forms of
the drug disappear before
opiates were banned in the
United States.
Most popular way of consuming
it was something called
Mrs Winslow Soothing Syrup,
which you would buy in the pharmacy,
right? Very low level of opiates.
Most popular way of consuming cocoa based
products prior to the banning was Coca
Cola, right? That's called that for
a reason. Uh, when the ban happens,
heroin becomes something from opiates.
Powder cocaine becomes the
only form of cocaine. In fact,
when there's a huge crackdown
on powder cocaine and the ATS,
the iron law kicks in even more.
And that's when crack is invented.
Cause you can get even more of a hair into
an even smaller possible space. Right?
So I think at some point to understand
if you want, it is not good.
Most people who drink alcohol don't want
to drink vodka and they certainly don't
want drink absinthe most of the time.
Right.
Most people want a mild form of their
drug. That's true. Cannabis. That's true.
Of course, there's some people
who want to get totally fucked up,
either for fun or because
they have addiction problems.
Most people want a mild form of the drug
is not good that malforms or the drug
when they're not. I don't
think that's true. Uh,
it's definitely not true in California,
in California,
what happened was medical care cannabis
got passed and what's medical cannabis
got passed.
There was a an emphasis on the strongest
possible stuff because people wanted
it.
I mean,
it was a direct result of people having
higher tolerances because marijuana was
so readily available and they,
if you have a high tolerance
and you smoke a lot of pot,
you want strong pot because
week pot doesn't do anything.
It's the number one complaint amongst
cannabis enthusiasts is someone having
week pops.
You've got a subculture of people who are
cannabis enthusiasts who you're right,
there's a subconscious just like there's
a subculture of people who want Volcker
App south. Right, right. But I don't think
it's a matter. It's not the same thing.
Like Jen obviously is more potent
than whiskey or then beer rather.
It's easier to carry gen around. You
have to carry less of it. With cannabis,
people are still buying the same quantity.
They're just getting more
fucked up because their
tolerances are so much higher.
They need a stronger and stronger THC.
So as you have a legal market,
you can have a variety of options,
right. What you have is what would,
what we'll discover. I think as time goes
by, because we know this with alcohol,
is different people want cannabis to do
different things. You're totally right.
There's some people who want
maximum THC maximally fucked up.
Just some people where there's still
a market for for lower grade we'd,
I mean they have it listed at all these
dispensaries. They have it listed,
you know,
20% 35% they have it listed so you can
choose a more mild marijuana if you like
to, but the oh gee people, the
people that do it every day,
of course they want that really potent
weed. It's not like I would say they're
more like the people in Vegas who gamble
a professional gamblers versus the
people who go to Vegas for the weekend
and just want to play a real well.
There's definitely a concentrated market,
very dedicated users who want to get
maximally fucked up. You're totally right.
I think that's what pushed the Po.
I mean it's also in botanists and I'm
friends with a bunch of people who breed
and grow these various strains.
But if you think about,
so professor David not has done
really interesting work on this.
So if I remember rightly, there's 38
active components in cannabis, right?
So cannabinoids, well there's hundreds
of cannabinoids. So I think the,
if I'm in from press and not sweat the,
that he argues this 38 kind of significant
active components, maybe other people.
Yeah, I think there's over a
hundred canabinoids I think
we just discussed this,
right? Right. Then we, uh,
so one of the things he Auggie's and
I'm happy to be quoted on the specific
number, but one of the things he,
he Auggie's um, is you've got it,
cause you were talking about
schizophrenia and psychosis.
I think it's important to understand
there is some evidence that very high
exposure to THC in a small
number of people can,
can lead to psychosis.
Right?
And that's even a small number of people
where you have a very widely used drug
is, is that's really problematic. Right?
But actually this was
readjusting evidence.
So why do people who are prone to
psychosis or schizophrenia want cannabis?
Right? Cause there was a lot of them
who want it. It's not the people,
hardly anyone wants to have a psychotic
episode. It's actually so THC,
um, uh, correlates with, with
psychosis in some people.
But there's another component cannabis
called CBD, uh, kind of a dial,
which actually we know
there's good evidence sue the
psychosis and schizophrenia,
right? It's actually given us a treatment
in some places in distilled pill form.
So actually it's a slightly more complex
picture then cannabis causes psychosis,
right? Very rich THC in some
people will cause psychosis.
That's a real problem. There are
things we can do to prevent that.
And one of the good things about
legal market is you can regulate it.
So we can limit the amount of THC that
is available. Just like we can limit,
you know, you can't go and buy 70%
proof alcohol, but also what, what,
what professor not has been arguing
is we need to be, and they exist,
but they need to be commercialized
and promoted more, um,
or promoted and public health way.
Not necessarily commercially, um,
CBD rich cannabis will actually be
helpful to people with psychosis and
schizophrenia. It's just a slightly more
complicated picture. I know that you,
you're not saying that it is, you're not
endorsing what the, tell your kids go.
What's it called again? The guy who did
your debate. Um, our experience too. Yeah.
I know you're not endorsing the kind of
simplistic view on either side, but the,
the, um, I think it's slightly more,
slightly more complicated than that.
The other thing I think is really
worth saying though to people is,
there's one thing we will do agree on,
which is cannabis is bad for young
teenagers. Right? After developing brains,
there's one person I interviewed,
it really helped me to, again,
to think about this guy
called Fred Martins who's in,
I went to go see him in
Camden, New Jersey, and Fred
was a co, he's retired now,
but he was a cop.
I was really kind of right wing.
You reminded me of the Clint
Eastwood character in dirty Harry.
He's not a liberal. Right.
And he had this, he wouldn't
use a fancy word like this.
Behind the epiphany
about drug legalization.
One day he was in a car park in Wayne,
New Jersey in 1971 it was staking out
a dealer and he's in plain clothes
obviously. And a kid comes up to him like
an 11 year old or something and goes,
hey Mr,
um,
I'm not allowed to buy alcohol where you
go into that liquor store and buy some
for me and frank guys now get outta here.
So the kid walks over to the drug dealer
and buy some drugs from him instead.
And Fred has this kind of realization,
which is, oh, he wouldn't put it this way,
but legalization puts a regulatory barrier
between kids and drugs that doesn't
currently exist, right? This is why since
they legalized cannabis in Colorado,
there's been, don't
overstate it, it's not huge,
but there's been a significant fall
in teenage cannabis use, right?
Drug dealers don't check ID
licensed legal businesses,
do they really care if they're there
because they've got something to lose?
Right.
So I think if sometimes it's used as
the kind of protect our kids argument is
used as a case for prohibition. In
fact, if you want to protect your kids,
you should be putting a big premium on
getting these substances out of the hands
of armed criminal gangs and into the
hands of licensed legal businesses.
Yeah, I don't think anybody's
going to argue that.
I mean I think that anybody
rational rather, uh,
I think that makes a lot of
sense. I think that, um, the,
the number of people that
have schizophrenia is fairly,
it's fairly stable in terms of the
percentage of it across the board,
cannabis users or non cannabis users.
And so the argument against this idea
that cannabis causes schizophrenia breaks
is that these people already have
schizophrenia and it just hasn't really
manifested itself in a, in a a tangible
sense. So this is one of things. Thanks
professor nuts says, so there's this,
there is some evidence that cannabis, uh,
in a small number of people causes
psychosis as a study in Sweden that showed
this with schizophrenia.
It's much more contested. So,
so psychosis versus schizophrenia,
what is the major distinction?
Yeah. I've not researched this in
depth, but um, psychosis involves,
is that the different,
the different paranoia.
Schizophrenia is a
subset of mental illness.
This very specific has a
significant genetic component,
although there can be
environmental triggers for it
so it could possibly trigger
both.
It could possibly trigger psychosis and
schizophrenia argument against that.
So professor, so there is evidence with
psychosis, the argument we're stress,
it's a very small number of
people but it Israel, um, uh, and,
and there are things we can do an
illegal market to counteract that,
that much harder to do in a prohibitive
market. But with schizophrenia,
the argument against that,
and I've not looked into this and a huge
amount of detail, so I don't want to,
this is not the same degree of confidence
I've been saying the other stuff,
but um, professor not argues, well,
we know that cannabis use has massively
increased in Britain, for example,
I think something like 20 fold increase
since 1916 Britain and yet levels of
schizophrenia have remained the same.
If cannabis was it causing schizophrenia,
you would it
to vary with cannabis use
at least to some degree.
There'd be some relationship and that
doesn't seem to be the case. So again,
that's what professor [inaudible],
who's the former chief scientific
advisor on drugs in Britain, says,
I haven't looked into that in great
detail. So He's basically right.
And all the things that I have
looked into that he says, hmm, um,
do they know what the mechanism would be
that would cause someone to consume THC
and have a psychotic break? Have
that, does that have an exam?
I don't know enough about it. It would
seem to be a big issue, right? Like,
find out what it is that's causing this
trigger and whether or not this exists
in these people anyway,
and maybe a stressful situation
and a bad breakup losing their job,
maybe one of those things
can also cause his trigger.