Well,
it seems complicated to people when you
try to explain campaign finance and you
try to explain contributions to candidates
and contributions to sitting senators
and congressmen.
It's,
it's complicated and there's
so many different things
to think about when you're
discussing this that to a person who's on
the outside, well, how do you fix this?
Well, what, what are the laws now
while how did it get that way? Well,
well w w how about make it so
they can't give them money?
And there's all these like real
simplistic views of it from the outside,
but it seems that it,
at the very least,
limiting the amount of
money at someone's a lot.
Like what is the maximum amount of money
someone can give to a candidate right
now in the primary and the general,
it's $5,400 $2,700 in each,
and that goes up according to inflation.
And that's pretty small potatoes compared
to what the super pacs are doing and
reflection.
So you have these people running who
expect they're going to raise the money to
run their office from
their direct contributions,
but they're counting on the super pacs
to come in and spend ungodly amounts of
money,
like tens of millions of dollars to
support their candidate or to oppose their
Optima, their opponent. Uh,
and so the supporters for
those super pacs or even tiny,
there's are the adolfs in America,
people named Adolf, this tiny, tiny,
tiny number of people who are
contributing to those, to those things.
But you're right, people. Look,
there's no reason why most Americans
should understand the complexities of
campaign finance law
and they don't need to,
what they need to ask is do we have a
system of integrity in the way we select
representatives? And if you're, if
you're not brain dead in America,
you believe the answer
to that question is no.
We do not have a system of integrity.
There's no representational integrity.
It is corrupted in all the obvious res.
And like nobody should be forced to study
campaign finance in order to have the
entitlement to say, hell, hell
no. This system has got to end.
And so I think you're
right. If we, you know,
people are forced to like articulate all
the 34 different changes that have to
happen, we're never going to get
there. But let's not go there.
Let's just start and end with it is a
corrupted system and we want politicians
to fix it.
And if they don't fix it,
we'll throw them out into a
get the politicians who do. Um,
and if we could build that as
the movement, the recognition,
the core message of 2020,
I think there's a real shot because
we've primed the Republican Party.
There are a lot of people in that
party who are now so disgusted with the
corruption of the system. Not
Necessarily Mitch Mcconnell, he loves it,
but you know,
reward Neri,
Republican voters and the Democrats have
now committed themselves to fixing this
corrupted system. It, this
is the moment to do that.
And we don't have to get into the details
of how much you should be allowed to
contribute to say there is a way to fix
this that would give us a representative
democracy. Maybe not. Again, but for
the first time wise, Mitch Mcconnell's,
so a uniquely evil,
this guy has had it in his,
uh, DNA from the first
moment he went to Washington.
Um, to end any regulation
of money in politics.
He engineered the selection of the FEC.
This is the federal election
commission commissioners,
so that they would block basically
every enforcement action with the FTC.
The FTC does nothing now because it's a
commission that has half Republicans and
half Democrats. So if the Republicans
disagree from the Democrats,
then nothing gets done.
They can't enforce the most simple
rules anymore because Mitch Mcconnell is
populated the FEC with people who don't
believe in campaign finance rules.
He has said citizens United this decision
that said corporations could give
unlimited amounts of money to
independent political speaking.
It says one of the greatest
decisions of the Supreme Court.
And he said he was going to
fight like hell to defend it.
And when this proposed HR one was
raised to him, Mitch Mcconnell said,
there's not a chance in hell. This will
ever even get a debate in the Senate.
This man is obsessed with the idea
that money should have the power in
Washington that it has right now.
And people are talking about reforming
it are the enemy. And so, you know,
the thing about Mitch Mcconnell is he's
actually an incredibly smart man and
he's an incredibly smart strategist and
he's been playing this game for a long
time. Um, and um,
and I think he's like responsible for
85% of the judicial structure that makes
it possible for this to be blocked.
There's an amazing series
to debates happen 20 years
ago between John Mccain and
Mitch Mcconnell.
So this was when Congress was passing
something called the McCain Feingold law,
which was the last great effort
to deal with this problem.
It was flawed and a bunch of ways,
but it was an important success.
Mitch Mcconnell, um, uh, stood
on the floor of the Senate, said,
Mr Mccain says that, uh, the
Senate, we can't say Mr again.
So the senator from Arizona has
said that the system is corrupt.
I want him to name the corrupt people.
And Mccain stands there and said,
I'm not talking about particular
individuals. I'm talking about the system,
it's the system's corrupt. And then
Mcconnell, almost clueless, just said,
if the system's corrupt,
there must be corrupt people.
If there's not corrupt people
and the system's not corrupt.
So the only corruption he could imagine
was corruption where somebody was taking
a bribe. And if that's the only
corruption we're allowed to remedy,
then the whole system of influence we
have right now is not to be touched.
But you know,
I think we Keynes point was,
you can have a system filled with lots
of honors Congress people and lots of Ana
senators who never engage in bribery,
but they know how to Bob and weave and
bend and speak and say the right things
to attract the right kind of money. And
that's as much corruption as bribery is.
And Mccain's view was we had to end it.
So he was the last great
Republican fighter for reform
of this corrupted system.
There'd been many,
before Barry Goldwater was an incredibly
vocal opponent to the role of money in
politics.
Um,
but I think what we have to do is find a
way to revive that and to leverage from
this presidents assertion that this is
a corrupt system and we have to change
the system into actually
building the political power
to make that change happen.