Oh, any blinded. This is how
crooked the game was. He applied it.
Ali Cassius clay.
So listen wasn't above,
you know, cheating. Yeah. Do
you remember that fighter?
Oh my God, this is so frightening. He,
he wrapped something in his Louie
Resto. Yeah, with it cement sums junior.
No, he took all the padding out of
his gloves back in the day. The,
they used to use horse hair
with the gloves and you could,
you could put a little hole in the
gloves and pull the padding out.
And Louie Resto,
Panama Lewis was his trainer and Panama
Lewis was also the same guy that gave,
uh,
Aaron Pryor,
that little a jab of cocaine right
before he knocked out Alexis Arguayo
remember, I mean they think it was
cocaine. He said gimme the other bottle,
the one that I prepared,
he gives it to Aaron Pryor.
And then Aaron Pryor goes out
and starches Aleks, SARC way out.
And they had a crazy war of a fight.
And then he gives them
something in this little bottle.
And then Aaron Pryor goes out like
a bat out of hell. And, and the,
the question was always what was in that
bottle cause there was no sophisticated
drug testing back then,
but Panama Louis,
but there was one of them that actually
puts cement or something in their gloves.
Um, there was that, that was
a more recent one that was a,
that Mexican gentleman that fought,
uh, what did he do that too?
Is that the red hand? No, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
He doesn't isn't fight anymore. Fuck,
I'm drawing a blank on his name.
But he, he beat up some really
prominent fighters that way.
Who the fuck did he,
it was a one fight in particular.
Boy, I'm seeing the guy in my face. Yes.
Antonio Margarito who pull, pull up
his record because he did it to, uh,
he did it to some like
legit fighters and uh,
really beat them up and they were like,
it didn't even make sense how
hard he was hitting me because he,
he would put plaster of Paris apparently
inside the wraps and Miguel Cotto
that's who it was. Right. And then
Miguel Cotto beat the shit out of it.
And the rematch.
Shane Mosley,
sugar Shane Mosley beat the fuck out
of him when they found this seat.
After he knocked out Miguel Cotto,
we beat him up in the 11th round.
He stopped him and was a horrible stoppage
too. He beat the shit out of them.
Then the Shane Mosley fight was the fight
that he lost. That was the next fight.
And during the wrapping of the gloves,
Shane Mosley's camp was go,
what the fuck is in his raps?
They recognized it and it had a Murray
wrap his hands and then Shane Mosley beat
his fucking ass and then he'd beat Robert
Garcia and then Manny Pacquiao fucked
him up. And then Miguel Cotto fucked
him up. Um, but the Miguel Cotto fight,
the first one, it was, it was bad.
I mean his face was busted up and
that's when people had suspicions,
but they didn't know until they
saw the wrapping of the gloves.
And then they looked at every one of his
fights before that. And then we'd go, oh,
this motherfucker had plans.
You go see the movie. Um,
that city fat city,
Stacy Keach.
It's about club fighters down at Stockton,
California.
Fantastic movie bridges.
First movies. Yeah.
And John used and directed it.
We one of the best fight movies ever.
This fight that I was talking about
earlier, the Louie Resto fight,
this Billy Collins junior guy was a,
he was an up and coming contender and he
was blinded in the fight and can never
fight again. Wow. This kid a
that he fought Louie Resto,
they pulled all the padding out of the
gloves and he just fucked up this guy's
face to the point where,
you know,
I had detached retinas and he couldn't
see straight came an alcoholic afterwards
when you're is right there, look at his
face. Wow. Yeah. And it became a, a,
a really big, a big store with
a deadly weapon right there,
I think at the end of the other guys
life or at some point he admitted that he
did it.
There was some documentary about it that
the guide finally admitted that he was
using. Oh, people have done that
forever. People have done that forever.
I was sparring with a guy once and I
want to touch his gloves and I was like,
what the fuck is in your gloves?
And His padding had all been,
it was those old style
old style boxing gloves.
The padding little putting
pushed back and it was like,
it was all like almost raw
knuckle people are assholes. Yeah,
I've,
I've experienced that before.
What's interesting now is that people
are actually fighting bare knuckle.
There's a whole bare knuckle
boxing organization out of Wyoming.
Do you have all your knuckle?
Yeah, they're all there.
They've been single in one broken up.
One note was broken. Yeah. Oh, wow.
Moves Weird cliques.
That was Bobby cell and he's knows
Bobby Salvey. Is there a more fucking
Boston named Bobby Saudi? Bobby Salvey.
I fucking hit him. What a fucking
over hand fucking lefty. Fuck.
I went down like this.