That was in a competitive fight. How
good is Roundtree look how good too. Oh,
you said something on the price
of any life. Said everyone's,
someone's booking a trip down cow. My
kids, he was right now. I was like,
where the fuck was he at?
Then they're making fucking
plane trips to Pooh cat. My,
my only thing is with that is what's
the grappling like out there? Hey Man,
I don't know man, but get somebody to
help them get somebody that motherfucker,
he throws some of the nastiest inside
leg kicks and so fast and he was total
Thai style. I wish I could lift my arms
up. Oh, she just got my shoulder shirt.
You can tell you it into style,
but he was alive leg dude.
His timing, his speed was off the
charts. He fucked his life up.
I hope that your candor is posted a
picture today about it, but um, how tough,
first of all, how fucking tough is
Eric, his coaches, what are you doing?
This is not a title fight.
There's nothing really on the line here.
It's just not his day. He couldn't ask
him game plan for financing to quit.
They just wouldn't ask him to quit.
He's so fucked. Coaches half the,
he's so tough. Crimson tide alumni
monster did cheer with Jon. Anik said,
what'd he say?
He said he goes and he loves
winning fights because then
Bruce buffer has to say
your boy. Oh really? Is he a boy? A boy.
And that's hilarious. He's
a bad motherfucker. Boy.
He's a bad mother fucker.
Cause that guy does not
have a long history of mixed
martial arts like a lot of
these guys like man, way more athletic
than the waste then a lot of them.
But look Culito's athletic as fuck too
man. You know he used to be 320 pounds.
Yeah, it was huge. Have you, have you
met Craig Guy? He seems like a great guy.
Used to train with
them. Monster. I'm just,
well I was impressed when he knocked
out. Go Con Saki and then, um,
I know he lost a Johnnie
Walker who's just a beast.
I don't know what to make
of Johnny Walker. Yeah. Ooh,
he's care. I'm on the train,
but I'm kinda like, come on, where
are we at? Fucking two. I'm on me too.
I'm pulling. I'm on the back like
Johnny. He's a bad motherfucker, dude.
He's something special. He's
a something. I'm not sure.
I'm not hope he didn't hurt his
fucking shoulder when he fell.
Did that worm thing.
I hope.
I hope he didn't really hurt himself
because if be really hurt himself and they
can't fix that,
that would be a damn shame.
If the way he got injured is falling down,
playing around after a spectacular
victory. I thought he came out,
said he was fine though. His Man
Shit. He's fine. Would say that.
I would say that too.
You gotta tell everybody you're fine.
We'll fix this will fit. He does look like
he's a freak dude. He has crazy power.
Crazy power.
He's scary and he caught collegial
with the elbow with close up when those
elbows where your hands up high
in Thai style in the clench,
but it was beautiful flatland him the
way he did it though. Like the tech look,
anybody gets flat lined with that
fucking elbow and knee buddy.
That guy hits hard.
And how about that's the site.
That was the reason why Cleo went to
Thailand. Yes, that's what I was like,
fuck this noise. It's beautiful. And now
he's all in. He's like, he's moving there,
he's going to move his family there. He's
going to do all his camps. So intense.
It's so intense. But when you have
results like that, like I love it.
I love a story like that.
Telegraph what comes around goes more.
That's cool.
Thailand riding elephants and
shit. Check this up. Yeah,
but that's what I'm worried about.
Who kept top team and a lot of those
places out there in Aka Aka Mike's squeaks
place. They must have wrestling,
I'm sure. Right. Came out of AK.
Miss Farsi Academy. But Mike Sweeney
was exactly wrestling. Well he,
but he knows this deal always with
wrestlers though. You're right.
I mean he knew how to wrestle. Sweat
could do everything. Yeah, that's true.
He's been, the gay was, I'm sure they
got a mother, but is that where he's at?
Ak it out there. Hey,
he's got his place out.
But now I saying is that we're
caleel's that I do not know.
I think he's at straight
kicking. Oh Damn. Boom.
He's doing the Reinhardt style
coconuts. He actually yelled, lady boys,
go to his,
um,
see if you can go to clue round tree
juniors Instagram page because he posted
thanks after the fight. There's
a lot of people doing it. Yeah,
well a lot of people are
going to Thailand. I think
there's something to it, man.
Learning in the motherland
with those dudes, you know,
watching those guys work out and train
and just to be in that environment.
It's good for the soul. Nobody, it
would be like, he's the nicest guy. Joe,
the nicest guy. But that's
caleel's Instagram. That's
me. And Him and his crew,
he used to work at like an MMA warehouse
and sell shirts when he's 300 pounds.
I was like, dude, I want to fight. That's
crazy. See if, um, there's a thank go,
go to the back to the, um,
oh, that's it right there.
And I'm sorry to go back to that one.
This here.
There it says teddy bear
peachy in the boxing.
See that? Click on that. That's the
dude. I think that's, that's the gym.
So he's with or that's one of his friends.
He's training with them right there.
The gym there. Yeah. Oh, that's not what
I'm thinking. It's, see I want to, damn,
that dude is in shape.
I want to see. Listen,
you want a little round
treat junior kicking you.
You're probably better off in that shady
fucking yeah, you gotta be shaped like,
it's nice. That dude was probably his
pads guy that helped him with his pants.
He's doing work, man. Damn. Look at
the legs on that fucking time, dude.
Oh Dude.
He's on a western diet son.
It's like pass on the Pad Thai and
get me the Donald Trump pad. Thai.
Fuck that noise. Ah, there's something
too. I think it's good for the soul.
Might be so being over there you mean?
Yeah.
There's something about
[inaudible] man. Oh, this is,
Tammy is doing this just to make us
laugh. Thank you, Tish. Son of a bitch.
I've shout out to that guy. Yeah. Um,
there's something about being in a place
where something was invented that must
give you some extra juice.