Or the guys like Lucy Kay who selling
out everywhere and doing great comedy.
Like he can't,
he could sell out fucking staple center
right now multiple times in a row.
What's crazy is he doesn't want to,
doesn't want to just do in comedy clubs.
Just working.
Yeah.
He could easily come back like
tiger woods easily right now.
He said that's so fucked up too because
they asked me why I did it. He goes,
I like to jerk off and I
don't want to be alone.
I like to jerk off and I don't like
to be alone. Like oh and then you know
he's great man. Yeah. I mean he always,
he did some creepy shit. Definitely did,
did some creepy shit. I definitely
approve of it but he didn't molest anyone.
I don't think we know exactly what
happened either. I don't know.
But I do know is he could
sell out staples center. Yeah.
Cause I think most guys and fans go,
all right man. But the other thing that,
and he's really good at comedy.
Yeah.
That's the other thing that we always
have to think about whenever we talk about
anything is that we're dudes.
And so when you ever to talking about
someone jerking off in front of you,
just imagine a woman
jerking off front of us.
Now you can't because that's not the same
cause it was it the only reason why a
girl could jerk off in front of you.
And it's hilarious because
she can't rape you.
See if a guy is jerking
off in front of you,
most guys are bigger and
stronger than most women.
Obviously there's some variables there,
but most guys are bigger and stronger and
men make all the rape and women aren't
out there raping dudes
show, right? It's all men.
So if a guy has his dick out
and he's jerking off scary shit,
that's why it's scary. It's
scary. It's creepy to, if a girl,
if you go over a girl's house
and for whatever reason she goes,
I want you to watch it sit down and
fucking, you know, fucking fuck.
She starts fingering herself
fucking, you know, like Whoa. Yeah,
but you wouldn't laugh.
You would laugh and you would come back
to here and we would talk about it.
Cause I know I can get out
of in time. Yeah, right.
We'd be crying laughing but it
wouldn't be like you were in danger.
But if a guy is with safety,
you have a daughter and your daughter
weighs 110 pounds different animals and
she's with a guy and the
guy in front of her. Yeah.
And he asked to do it and she
says yes cause she scared. Fuck.
Then it's like what?
What would actually happen?
And see he hasn't really said anything
other than the stories are true and you
know
yeah.
Does come from a guy that sounds like,
you know, cause you have two daughters.
Yeah.
Well it's so you have to think like that.
Well you have to think like that
as a human being, right? Yeah.
But I'm saying to you is probably the
first thing you think of because you have
two daughters. Right. But I don't
think that's what he did. I think from,
I can't say too much cause I don't know.
But I think he did some regrettable
things and I think he would admit that,
but I don't think he did what a lot of
people are claiming he did in terms of,
that's what I've heard.
How often he did it or he did
or what the circumstances were,
but it was either way.
There's no defending when it
was bad. No, it's not good.
There's no deficiency.
It's a terrible thing to do,
but what's the punishment for that?
You know how much I should punish them,
do you not pay for it and lost all
his jobs, lost all his TV deals,
$35 million in a year of work and people
still were say no, but he's still,
he's fine. I've heard that
argument that he's fine. Like what?
These are also, these are also things
that he did like more than a decade ago.
Right. What, when do you
offer someone compassion?
Like when do you, when do you let
them explain themselves? When do you,
when is it enough is enough or it should
he have to do something like what would
people like someone to do?
Well,
I think they're coming because something
like this, there's only a year.
And then he's back and killing it
because he's so good at comedy.
Cause like with tiger woods, right.
People hated tiger. Well there was that,
but there was also the material
that got leaked when he came back.
So people were upset at the jokes.
The parkland joke. Yeah. Not the best.
It's that shit falls in line with
how he's always done jokes though.
I told him whether he did this or not.
He says the fucked up thing to say,
it's part of what makes him really funny.
And he does that in real life too.
It's not,
it's a style of comedy man.
I mean it's just like a Quentin
Tarantino has a style of making movies.
His style of comedy is
to say fucked up things.
So that compounded the fact that people
were upset at him that a year ago,
you know, he said he was going to take
some time off, but it's, um, I don't,
you know,
I think it's really important to know
that I don't know what happened and,
and you know,
he knows and they know and it's,
it's never good when someone's upset
that you jerked off in front of them.
That's not a good time.
It's is never good for anybody,
but also him losing $35 million
in only been out a year.
I think people are upset. That was
such a quick turnaround. Like Tj,
is that a quick turnaround,
man? I mean, not as a comic,
but for, to the, to the, uh,
normal person like a year. That
ain't shit, dude. But as a comic,
not to be able to do, let's imagine that
he's going to live another 50 years,
right? A year, a year out of 50.
It's like 2%, right? Yeah. It's a lot.
It's a lot and a lot of money. Yeah.