Weird. And to your point about going up
and cleaning up, clean out, you know,
an impoverished area at least then you'd
get to meet the other people. Yeah.
People outside of your circle in your
bubble. I mean the amount of times, Hey,
when you talk to people about Muslims,
LGBT, whatever it is, and you think, oh,
it's because you've never met anyone,
right.
You've actually never met anyone
that is x, y or zed, which is, I'm,
I moved to Brooklyn five years or six
years ago and I moved to Clinton Hill,
Fort Greene and I got a few friends that
had been there forever and I said, let,
this probably sounds like a
really stupid thing to say,
but it feels kind of segregated here. And
they were like, Duh. Of course it does.
And I couldn't believe it.
You know,
I'd grown up on the spike
Lee movies and I mean,
I guess they do show a kind of
segregation, but I thought, you know,
this was the place where everyone
lived together on the same,
I went to each others,
but then he goes and restaurants and I
lived on the dividing line between the
bit that was getting gentrified and the
projects you go two blocks that way,
pretty much all black.
You got three blocks that way.
Pretty much all white with yoga studios
and Boujee coffee shops and pet spars
and,
and the two communities just did not mix.
It wasn't necessarily they hated each
other or they just did not make different
language, different everything. Right.
This is Utopian perception that there
is a place where everybody's cool. Yeah.
Yeah.
And I thought it might be New York,
it might be Brooklyn or it's
probably the only place that's close.
Right. At least it has the reputation for
it. Yeah. Because at least in Brooklyn,
people walk around. I mean, yeah, but,
but talking about the amazing pieces
of journalism over the last few years,
there's Nicole, Hannah Jones wrote, wrote
a piece about New York school system,
public school system,
the most segregated school system
in America when New York really,
and she had to get her daughter into a
public school. And the choice was the,
the very good,
well supported school in the gentrifying,
mostly white area or the bad failing
public school in the non gentrified,
mostly black area where her
kids education might suffer.
And I think I'm remembering
correct correctly,
but her and her husband had a real
fight about it cause she said, no,
we got to put our kid in the,
in the bad failing school and help it
get better and it's gonna take years and
our daughter may suffer in the short term,
but that's what we have to do if
we're living in this neighborhood. Um,
it's an incredible piece.
Wow. Yeah. That's a, the, the
real conflict as a parent.
Do you have children? No.
When you're possible each. Oh
yeah. I'm sure. Right. You're,
when you're thinking of your children,
you're,
you're always thinking of their safety,
you're always worried about them
and you want to protect them.
So putting them in a situation where they
wouldn't be as protected is never your
first instinct. Oh, she, she was in,
in town hall meetings where, you know,
progressive white liberal parents who
would be very left wing on every other
issue.
We're really fighting to make sure their
kid went to the good majority white
school. Um, and you know, they
want a bit of diversity but not,
not too much diversity. Right.
They want a black friend. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. That's when
people think of Brooklyn,
they do think of it as being like the
most diverse place. Yeah. And it's, yeah,
I mean, street by street segregated
it land is pretty diverse.
Atlanta is interesting, you
know, because Atlanta has, um,
a lot of, there's a,
there's a lot of um, pose.
It's a lot of everything in Atlanta,
but it's a very black city and a lot of
ways, but it's also a very white city.
You see a lot of black and white people
hanging out together and clubs and bars
and restaurants and stuff. And it's
really like much closer to like a 50,
50 split than a lot of places,
at least in some of the neighborhoods
that I've been to when I got back to
London. That's why. That's one of the
few things. Um, I'm proud of about,
about London and certainly New York.
It said it's not a big deal for a group
of friends, a family, and trying to be,
to be genuinely mixed.
He sites that
you would know.
Um,
I'd ask you is that because London didn't
experience slavery the way the United
States did? Um, yeah, I mean
obviously we have a, you know,
colonial history, right? Of course.
But that wasn't in the country
itself for a very long time.
We've had a huge Pakistani Bangladeshi,
Jamaican community and it's, it's,
you know,
I mean here,
if you have black friends or you date
a black girl or you know, it's, it's,
people think you're trying to prove your
work right there. It was just normal,
normal [inaudible] in London.
I'm not saying England, London.
I experienced that when
I was in London as well.
It seems like way more integrated.
Yeah. Yeah. That, and that's, I mean,
still five, six years after
I moved to New York, it's,
it's still a surprise every day to
reinforce a different animal. Now,
New York is so fucking expensive.
It's so strange. And, uh, my friend,
uh, Judah who, uh, Judas Freelander
who lives there, said he's,
he's lived there for a long time
and he's like, it's so changed.
It used to be like a lot of artists and
a lot of creative people. And he goes,
it's now tell finance people
like every go to finance.
Everybody just wants the most expensive
suit and the most expensive watch.
And they live in this
ridiculously expensive apartment.
And I thought that went out in the 80s.
I thought that was like Wall Street and
Michael Caine still very much exists.
That's still prevalent.