How about your boy, Tj? Dillashaw both
our boys. Yeah, that's fine. Good.
Do you see his apology? Yeah,
I did. What'd you think? Well,
I mean at least he's a just straight up
admit and I think that's what you have
to do because then you're kind
of like, yeah, I fucked up.
Then people can't really come at you.
Yeah,
I mean he's being honest about it and um,
oh, I do have to correct something. He,
someone wrote an article that said that
Cody Garbrandt found out the TJ tested
positive for his fight too.
And Cody went crazy.
I think I got duped by a click
baity articles. We all got duped.
Everyone thought that.
And actually that got us with a
click baity articles in one day,
but I should have been more responsible.
So my apologies to Tj. So they had,
I don't think there's a been another
one that they tested them on that he's
positive, but they're looking into it.
Now here's the thing. Well we have to,
this is something that I know,
um, EPO is not always tested for.
Correct. And you see, Dana, what'd he say?
Cause you saw it as expensive as fuck
you. Hold on. You guys, aren't he at?
He didn't know.
He goes,
you guys aren't tests for EPL every
time we paid this much money for,
you know not to show up guys at three
in the morning and test them and you're
not testing every time and we pay this
much. He was, I had no idea. Yeah,
well time to cancer you saw. Thanks boys.
Thanks wise. Thanks for playing. See Ya.
Everything's been looking good. You
have to take it from here. Come back,
be cool bro. Yeah, next thing you
know, everybody's back looking thick,
picking, choosing now,
but they still, I see.
I guess what they're gonna do is they're
going to go back and see if they still
have the samples for when he did
beat Cody and test those for APL.
Well this is what you and I were talking
about where we're at the store when
you're like, how far do we go
back? Dude, I'm telling you, Joe,
you don't want to go down
that. Oh, you're crazy.
What's real? Why? Why you want
to do that? You're crazy, dude.
You can't do it, you're gonna
ruin the foundations of see UFC.
This is an intellectual exercise. I don't
really want you to test them all. Yeah,
but if I was going to argue and I'd
say test him, I I think line it up.
What's fine? What's up? We've always
wondered half. We'd not be shit.
I've never wondered. Do you want to test
Forrest Griffin and Stephan Bonner? UFC.
Oh, the fight. That
catapulted the freaking test.
UFC this,
but then again test all the
football players test all
the on everyone's feelings
hurt because you watch screw ball. Did you
want screwball? No, I have it. Holy Shit.
Is it good Billy Billy Corbin document?
Yeah. Do you know what they did? Yeah,
they had little kids play a
writer's again. It's crazy, right?
It's hilarious story.
The story is nuts because
it's in the people who are
actually there narrating it.
They're,
they're telling the story and they got
these little kids playing a rod and
playing the villain. It's fucking
great. It's crazy story though.
It's a crazy story. I
feel bad for Tj, man.
You know what, man, when everybody
makes an agreement to not cheat,
they're testing you all the time to try
to make sure that you're not cheating.
Don't you think that the environment's
different now than it was before you saw
it? It was was initiated and don't
you think that's a good thing?
I'm putting words in your mouth. Nose,
highest phrase. That question. Yeah.
Yeah. As I am on five politician,
I know. No, you're right.
It is better overall for the purity
of the sport. I think it's better,
but I still assume guys are going
to figure out a way to cheat. Yeah.
Because PDS in sports is no different
than than a referee or a judge or gloves.
They go hand in hand.
People have always done pds or
enhancements in every aspect,
whether it's football, basketball,
and music, surfing, sex.
It's just what humans do.
Especially when the odds are so high that
this little thing can help you achieve.
Maybe it gets you a victory,
but you know,
and then also with with Tj
Dillashaw is thing. Granted,
we know epls illegal, but this, uh,
this one's a little different for
tested positive for like steroids or
never like straight up steroids because
if you and I engage in a fight and we
have eight weeks of training and you go
to Mount Everest or where the fuck you
want to get your red blood cells higher
and then fight me back at sea level,
but I just stay here and
Jack those red cells,
you know the difference is that if you
operate at sea level and you are taking
EPO,
you will be able to work much harder and
get more rounds in and you will recover
much better if you are up at altitude.
The problem is living in
training really at high out to,
you can't put out as much output,
but the night of the fight we're
going to have the same. No. Why?
The EPO will have more, not even
close. No, you're gonna you,
you could have a stroke from that stuff.
I mean it doesn't have to do it. Right.
It depends on how much you're taking.
Yeah.
That was one of the things Novitsky
was telling me about her young cyclists
thick. They were just
having strokes. We your boy,
I think it was Lance Armstrong
that maybe was on your show,
but he would wake up and midnight and had
to have to ride a bike because they're
so sick. That was my friend's
Salami. Do I know slummy? No, no,
I'll explain. Okay. But
you know what I'm saying?
Like you can't actually
use it for long bike racer.
You'd have the talent to get up in
the middle of the night. Yeah, right.
Lance did discuss how guys think.
That's why I got it. Yeah, it's been,
we've talked about it.
Maybe Lance [inaudible],
lance talk about having to get up and
where did you and I talked about that?
I talked about getting up in the
middle of night riding a bike. No,
I'm just kidding. No, I'm
just kidding. But anyway,
obviously look that with
the Lance Armstrong thing,
I feel like everyone was doing it and
you don't anyone you don't think you have
seen, you think Tj is the only one? No,
I think other people are taking EPO and
they're hoping they don't get caught.
That's what I think. I think it's still
cheating. Correct. And I think, um,
I don't think everybody's doing that.
I think there's a lot of guys who
were doing it honorably. I agree.
All those guys are doing it honorably.
You know,
I think you could get it in
your mind. Look, I don't,
this is just is what to take from Max
Holloway. It is what it is, right?
It is what it is. What it
is. It's cheating. Right. He
would, TJ would admit that.
I'm sure he did a minute. Yeah
he did. That's what it is. But
I mean I don't even know of have a point.
I don't know if I do either.
But it's put,
it's the guys trying to,
I was going to say the guy's
trying to provide for his family,
but so is everybody else.
Cody Garbrandt so his cardiogram ramps.
So is Henry Sudo. So is
everybody. Everybody. He fights.
But I would like to sit down with Tj
and I reached out to him since he's been
suspended. I want to sit down with
them just like, why would you,
why did you do it?
Like what led you to this?
Because his card has been great since
he was a child with his wrestling
background. At what point along the way,
was it six years ago, six fights ago.
Did you think you need to do this in
order to beat these guys? Well, let's,
we could look at one thing that
we know that he's been doing.
He has a rigorous strength and
conditioning program. That training time,
that drink conditioning program
that he's doing. You have,
I have an issue with that.
I understand your issue,
but that shit is off the charts.
Crazy difficult.
They're doing wild stuff and medicine
ball work and plyometrics and all this
stuff and Tj looks like a
fucking beast when he's doing it.
Have you seen Brian Ortega's
workout with, with, with Mike? Yeah.
They do crazy shit too. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. I mean, I'm not justifying it,
but what I'm saying is that in
order to do that kind of work,
like to put out that kind of pace,
your body's going to have to have some
time to recover in between workouts. Well,
if you take EPO,
that time of recovery is diminished
quite a bit according to Novitsky.
I'm saying it allows
guys to put in more work.
So it doesn't just give you more cardio.
It allows you to recover faster so
you could train harder. And you know,
as well as anybody that sometimes the
difference between victory and defeat is
just having a little
more in your gas tank.
Just having special at that little
longer camp Humphreys not being injured.
The last couple of weeks we
lost some cardio. You know
those awful feelings. Well,
if you had the opposite of
those awful feelings of now,
instead of being compromised,
being his hands to two,
it's going to help you then please
was going to help your head.
You're gonna come in there
like a fucking champion.