The joe rogan experience.
Y'all deviate.
But what I don't want to do,
I don't want to work out
brand new material in front
of three trials of people.
Fuck that
one night.
Well I think what came to watch your show
at the store and this was like a year
ago and you had to jet right after the
set and go to Pasadena for another set of
me. My buddy that I brought with me,
we just look, we're going to hang here,
see who comes out and like Jeff Ross or
somebody comes out and he's doing his
bit and right in the fucking middle of it,
the back curtain opens and Chappelle
walks out and just kinda like taps were
also on the corner on the shoulder.
Like fuck off. I got this, you know,
and just jacks the mic.
I pretty much everybody else has set who
was supposed to perform that night and
stands there for like three hours. Man.
Just sitting there. I was like, dude,
this will probably never happen again
in your lifetime so I'm not fucking
leaving.
And we just sat through the whole time
and he sat there rocking Tequila bombs
and get drunk and just really talking.
There were times where it was the
funniest thing I've ever seen, literally.
And there were times where like it Kinda
got dark and you're like where's what
the fuck's happening?
Where's this going?
And he was working things out and then
later on those Netflix specials land.
And I realize I've already heard like
90% of these jokes and cause the guy was
just saying I'm going to go hijack
the main room, work my shit out.
Cause I got it like that.
I'm Dave Chappelle, you know,
but it was fucking amazing.
Yeah he does that a lot.
We'll,
he'll just drop into place
and just do a set and that's,
that's how he kind of works
as material out. You know,
he just kind of drops in and
keeps tweaking it and it, it's,
it's if he has a structure,
right?
Like if he has a few ideas that he's
talking about, he can just riff.
And especially if he's drinking,
just go on stage and then the trigger and
then he's always got dudes behind them
that are taken down notes, letting them
know like all you talked about this day,
and I'm sure they record it too and
they'll go over it and eventually boil it
down to like what that Netflix special
was the two Netflix specials that shows
you how prolific that duty is to put
out a sniffling special and then a year
later put out to Netflix Passion, right?
And then Netflix is like, we'll take it,
what do you got? And he like, Hey,
I wrote this one this month and I'd
like to put it down for all eternity.
He cool with that.
But most people like you write something
and it's a good solid year before you
even consider putting in a special,
you know,
some guys were doing like a special year,
but too much of it was like half cooked.
It was like if you just
waited six more months,
this thing would be like
an all time great special,
but instead you're banging
them out one a year.
You never get the essence of the thing.
Well
thing too.
He part of his thing I think is is making
it look like it's so easy for lists
because the night at the comedy store to
just like it did feel like he was just
sort of making the shit up on the spot
and then you see the Netflix specials in.
It sort of feels the same way.
Like he's just being Dave and be like,
he would with a little subtle things
that I noticed like probably 10 times
throughout the night.
It really awkward moments.
He would call the waitress to get
him another drink, but he would,
he would only say bar whore and every time
you say it you get a little,
a little more awkward,
like a little less appropriate each and
every fucking town. We're probably like,
eventually everybody in the room was like,
that's not really cool.
At the end of the night. He's like, the
last thing he says like, I'm really sorry,
I called you bar Raj, don't
have any fucking jokes. And
he walked off the stage.
I was like, yeah, that's how Dave writes.
That's one of the ways he writes. But
he's, um, he's got it down, you know,
he's got it down to a science.
The other thing he does is
he just travels to towns,
just decides to travel to a town
and then go on stage, show up,
show up for three nights at the Fillmore
with, yeah. But I mean, he doesn't even,
he'll do that,
but that's booked.
He books that you have to craft a book
that shit nine months. Right. It's like,
what if he worked somewhere else?
He just shows up.
Like he'll work at a comedy club
and just show up. Gotcha. You know,
I was in Denver wants
and he just showed up.
I came in the green room after the
show. It was a, after the late show,
Friday night, I went backstage and
Dave's in the green room. I go,
what are you doing man? And,
uh, and he goes, Hey Joe,
I'm just in town fucking round or you want
to go on stage? He's like, should I go?
Fuck yeah, I grab them.
Bring the people back in.
People already getting up and
leaving. I said, date, ladies
and gentlemen, get back.
Dave Chappelle's here anyway.
Of course he wants to go on stage.
What else is he there? Like that's why
that's what he does is he does his thing,
you know, but it's just weird to say
like, oh like this guy is so free.
He could just fly into a town where
he knows his friends are going to be,
he doesn't even have to call
you in advance, you know,
he just flew in and I see him like,
Oh yeah, get up there. Like he's,
he's as free as a bird.
He does whatever he wants and then
he does these Netflix specials,
they pay my ass load of money and then
he just does shows whenever he wants to.
But his creative process is like,
almost like engineered around being loose,
like doing whatever he wants,
go on where he wants to go.
Doing one every once and then writing,
you know, and then figuring out on stage.
Then riffing and then just fucking around.
It's fascinating. Fascinating to watch.
It's like jazz almost. Oh, it's very
much like, yeah. I mean he's, um,
he's also got B and Dave
Chappelle down to a science.
Like you were saying that you are
in the Sturgill Simpson business.
He's in the Dave Chappelle
business. Yeah. Yeah.
It does what Dave Chappelle wants
to do. That's the key, I think.
I think that's the key.
If we could all be in the business
of whoever the fuck you are,
whatever you do well is I like to write
songs and make Rutgers and pretty much
say no to everything.
Okay.