Well you can say people of color,
the same words just twisted around dude,
I had a um,
it's messed up.
It's like you can just be like labeled
a racist or sexist or whatever for like
saying like the Oh yeah,
yeah, it's wild. Um,
I had 23 and me DNA
tests done and the lows,
they're pretty good and I was hoping
if I was, if I was more than 10% black,
I was going to start dropping n bombs,
but a 1.6,
so 1.6 1.6% African pretty strong.
It's all Dick.
And I thought,
well when they did that thing about
Elizabeth Warren or I did find out what
percentage she is,
uh,
Elizabeth Warren who claim to be
native American and she did a test,
she's like one,
one,
100th of what I am.
Like,
it's literally like her saying she's,
yeah,
her saying she's and a native American
is literally like me saying I'm African
American,
but I have more of a claim.
I have far more like more than
I think some some insane number,
like a factor of more African in me
that she has native American and I'm not
even remotely native Americans are
not remotely African rather. Yeah,
I'm 1.6% I have 1.6% African in me and
she has like some fucking really stupid
number.
What is the dumb,
it's like 0.01 I don't even know
how to make sense of all that stuff
she had.
That was how it happened was a Harvard
researcher looked into it and gave a
number that was very vague.
That would be like one and
512th two one and 1020 fourth
something like that. That sucks
dude. It's so crazy socks.
That's the thing like something I Google,
it gives a shit,
but she got into Harvard because of this,
which she claimed she was
native American when she got in.
That was claiming that she was a
minor one was Harvard, right? Correct.
I'm being honest with that. What
was it? Cambridge, whatever.
The university is showing him some
university by claiming that she was native
American, so she got a special
scholarship because of that.
The whole man literally lasted like
me going to Morehouse and saying,
I'm African American,
except I have a far better claim.
You have a much higher percentage,
much higher.
That's so crazy. Wild. Meanwhile,
she's so nuts like because Trump was
always calling her Pocahontas and Trump
said that of shit.
How is it that you can't,
if you said the wrong thing on your
podcasts, people will be up in arms,
but it's unreasoned. The president can
say whatever the hell he wants to say.
He's making fun of her shit ever
tending to be a native American.
He was joking about heart.
She's not really native American and he
called her Pocahontas and he said if she
took a DNA test and showed
that she was native American,
he would donate $1 million to a
charity of her choice. So she,
after this fucking test that basically
showed she has these smallest measurable
possibility,
native American in her
was requiring him to pay.
You should pay Harvard for what?
You fucking the money
back built from them.
Where at school that she go to trying
to find the actual thing it seems,
I think she actually got a job at Harvard.
Not,
didn't go there for your education.
Oh,
she got a job there and because of trying
to find out, okay, we'll figure it out.
But that's hilarious.
I the I the idea that that is something
you can lean on is so god damn crazy.
Listen, you're a white
lady. I'm a white guy.
Shut the fuck up. Okay.
You're not, there's no,
there's not a part of you that has been
discriminated against because of the
fact that you're native American. It
just doesn't exist. It's not true.
It's just us. So fascinating to
me. Oh, people love to be a victim.
They'd love to say,
you know,
it was my life growing up was hard
because I'm one 150000th native American
busy. Crazy. And where does it
stop? Like is it, is it, is it,
is it cool to say that if you're 2% or
10% or 50% like where is it? Where is it?
That's what I'm saying. At 1.6% I really
don't feel like it could drop n bombs.
Right?
10 it's not 10% like I'm mostly Italian.
I'm like three quarters Italian so
I can call someone a Guinea Guinea,
no problem. But get the times, don't give
a fuck if you call them guineas. Yeah.
Like,
okay.
Like just know Bailey is no
good slurs for Italians work.
You know, they've successfully
integrated into society.
But when my grandfather
used to tell me about,
he came over here when he was a boy from
Italy and he would tell me about how
bad it was about how much they were
discriminated against. You know, I'm just,
it was, it was hardcore. I mean they
were treated a lot of the same way.
Racist People Treat Mexicans today. And
Irish, same thing. Same thing. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's,
my background is Italian and Irish mostly,
but someone got fucked by a black
person somewhere, somewhere.
1.6% I don't know how
many generations there.
I guess the claim is that she used her
claim that she's native American to get a
job. Yes. Not, not to get it out to
go into school, get a job at Harvard,
at one at Harvard, one at
Pennsylvania. So she did it twice.
Give that money back, bitch. I love the
DNA test though. I love the DNA test.
It just proves it. We're all
like something. We're all a
bunch of shit like, yeah.
You know what I mean?
I'm like 30 things.