The joe rogan experience.
I also want personal neat for me to
achieve something that is unique,
that is rare, that maybe that never
been attempted before. You know,
that would be something that excites
me and I'm not only driven by money,
you know, like, like, like I, it's
good to have money, like money. It's,
it drives us all,
including myself,
but it's not the unique
thing that drives me.
It needs to be more than
money and they need,
need to be some kind of achievement that
comes with it. That would exciting me.
So what would that be? That would be
155 pound title. They, they uh, they,
they offer me Nate Diaz known.
Yeah. And, and, and uh, it was, uh,
it was a rumor.
It they said it was a done deal.
It's not a done deal if not on my part.
And I don't think it was on Nate Diaz part
as well, because from what I've heard,
his brother Nick set, and even
Nate says, that's his big brother,
his fight.
It's not his fight from
Nick, Nate, Nate Diaz's.
There is that incredible fight fighter,
a very well rounded.
However,
from if you put yourself in my shoes,
there's nothing good that can come out
of it except money and money is not the
only thing that really drive me.
If I beat Nick Diaz,
Nate Diaz decisively,
some people will say, ah,
most people would say, oh, you took an
easy fight or whatever. Like the, the,
the criticize them, we'll say, we'll say,
oh yeah, he uh, he's a bully, you know,
155 he fought a smaller guide
that compete at a smaller,
maybe it's not even smarter than me.
Maybe we're about the most fifth one.
A lot of one 55 or the guys are bigger
than me right now. It's a big guy.
He's a big guy. He's about
that same size. I mean,
but because I compete at one 74 most of
my carer and you won the title of West,
it wouldn't make me look bad.
They will make me look like a bully
and this is if I win decisively. If I,
for example, if I win, not decisively,
if I wouldn't get savoir back and forth,
but people was high, you suck. You
cannot even, you know what I mean?
And if I got beat, oh my God,
if I get it, this format,
this is the end of the world is all the
work I put in is finished and I could
have a bad day.
Yeah.
Something that I discovered during my
career is being the strongest men in the
world. That's my, that was my dream when
I was young and that's why I did UFC.
I want it to be this stronger men in
the world and I realize over there this,
it did not exist. You cannot be
the stronger men and the world.
This is an illusion. I love the
younger guy. They say, well,
the bad ass man now you're not man,
it doesn't exist.
You would be strong.
You would be a better fighter than this
guy and that particular day at that
particular location at that
particular moment, maybe in an hour,
if I would ask her an hour later or an
hour before or maybe in a different place
where they, the altitude desire or
lower or the different scenario,
different environment, you will lose
that fight. It's always that question of,
you know what I mean? So being a
stronger man, they're, well it does.
Its style makes fight. Maybe we're
three guys. I beat you. You beat him.
He beat me. Who's us? It was the best guy
is no bad guy. Right? That's MMA math,
right?
It is like this as the way to see it.
There is no stronger man in the
world. You can't. You'll say, oh,
I'm the baddest man on the
planet because I'm champion.
Like the belting is is an illusion.
The belting belting is assemble,
but it's an illusion. It doesn't exist.
You're not the stronger men in the world.
I know a lot of people will disagree
with me, but is it is what it is. I said,
if you ask most experienced fighter,
and most people would think the same
way because we realize at one point like
when we're young because of our confidence
or maybe they are the cockiness or
confidence after it.
Not that it fades,
but we we we see we have more
experience with knowledge. We rise,
they tell it's all bs. It's not true.
So the UFC offered you, Nate Diaz,
did you consider it at all
or was it like I consider it,
I consider it however AA I analyze it.
I talked with Ferris would what my trainer
and everybody we were all on the same
page on death is say say it's not
what it's not, it's not worth it.
But did the UFC announce it? Did they say
that they were working on it? I think,
I think they had say that. I'm not sure.
I think they said there was a done deal.
Look, it's not that first time
it happened and, and I'm not,
they have a business to
run the UFC and they're,
their biggest fear is someone take that
title and run with it and has been,
I've been doing it two times with Johny
Hendricks and with that and Michael
Bisping like I run, they say I run.
But it was for the reasons, you know,
there's always a reasons and, and
that's their biggest fear. Sure.
So that the, and I understand that they
have a business to run. It's, but it's,
it's like WWE when
g three the giant passed the torch to
all Cogan he passed that doors because
it's four and a business and he
agreed to pass the torch. Yes.
But the thing in this, in this,
in this part, we're nothing.
Wwe is my life on the line here.
I don't care about the business.
I do what is the best of
all my end threats to me.
Sure. You have to. I have to,
I have to be selfish and I am selfish.
I say it open the I am I say it to the
fan to every I am selfish because it's a,
it's a sport that I can die,
man,
you can die in this sport and this is
the truth can get or not. Maybe not that,
but it could create,
create at your death in there next
time to come in the next year.
Maybe you get at below that messed up
something in your brain because of a
trauma that create the something else.
So it's a very serious sport man.
Is is not like a, you play hockey,
play baseball, play football. You don't
play finding. So you do it for yourself.
You do what is best for yourself.
The organization will do what
is best for the organization.
They are not your friend,
right?
So that's why the relationship with
Dana and some of the guy in UFC,
it's a very special relationship.
Maybe one day we'll sit down and we'll
talk about the good old day then and have
a blast. Have a laugh more. Right now
we always am always on the defensive.
When my phone rang,
I see that no way.
Like God damn like then
I say what I should say,
what I should not say then and then,
uh,
and I'm completely honest about
it is like some virus or no man,
I just as I, if you do that because
you are in need yet, if you do that,
if you just take any fight that fight in
that name. No, I mean it doesn't work.
Like that isn't the ascension
to be champion is not a
straight line is this all
is a nap stucco there, you know,
then you come back and that is it.
It is what it is.
It is what it is and you need to be
surround by smart people and if you don't
want to have smart people,
you need to be smart enough to find
those people that are competent,
that will help you in particular domain,
that you are not competent to make the
job for you and complete your circle,
you know? Yeah. Dana was saying for a
while that you didn't want to fight.
He was saying George doesn't
want to fight. He's Seth. Before.
I didn't want to fight before I fought
Bisping. You know, he said that life. Why?
Why do you think you were saying that?
Do you think he was putting
pressure on you psychologically?
It was fucking with your head. Yeah,
so I'm so by ego. What made me,
I'll show you that I couldn't
fight. Bring me those guy. Right?
That's where it is bad. It's I
freaking game. It's all a game.
We say it's not a game. It's real out.
It's all a game. It's all business.
It's all a game. I like Dana, Dana Man.
Thus part was nowhere.
That sparked was government.
He didn't go nowhere because of Dana.
We hold Dana,
my living,
I hoe it to Dana white when I do the UFC.
Wayans when I introduced
everybody, I pointed him, I
say, Dana White. Without him,
none of this would be possible and you
write a hundred percent a hundred percent
ease that best pound for pound
promoter of all time of all.
I don't care about dunking. Wherever
you, Dana White is the best.
He's better than all sport. Include
it. I'd never seen anything like this.
He can sell ice to an Eskimo if he want
to ease an incredibly good fun and he's
good at messing up with my head too.
Because even though I
sometimes my ego was like Nate,
Nate Diaz it because of the stuff
he said to and the way they try.
I don't if the UFC tried to make him
say stuff because some fighters are more
like pond on a chest on a check
Cherchez board than others.
Me, I'm not, I don't follow
when everything analyze.
I'm thinking, I was like,
why you say that? Why? Okay, that's big.
So a lot of stuff I've been
selling my ego somewhere like, man,
why didn't I want to say alright you
think my, my schedule is too busy.
I'll dark dark forest there. No, I
kicked her out. You know what I mean?
But I shall not do it at this as Tupin
move. If I start acting like this,
I'm Barone and I lot of guide,
they don't have that self control
and self discipline in them.
It's all that game, man. That's all
that game there was. It's not, it's all,
it's bs. It's all a game,
man. It's all a game.
What did Nate say the fucks with you.
Oh, okay. Made the eyes and, and Nick,
nick is that I kind of together.
And then when they say that I took
steelhead when I fought this brother, uh,
sorry, I messed up my
glove, my, my rap. Um,
I didn't make weight. And uh, what did
you say? Oh yeah. Put something in the,
in the ivy of his brother. So he said
if I want to take care of it, like if,
I don't know, I, you said it in his own
like word, like in English slang, like,
oh yeah. If you want to take charge
of this, I'm there. You know,
said someone poisoned him.
Breathe. Yes. Who was, was
that for? Which fight was that?
Is that Anderson Silva? Okay, I got
to confess the Joe, I gotta confess.
I got to confess. Okay. I was,
I was so scared during this,
this fight.
So we tried to poison,
I was so scared of fighting Nick Diaz.
So we poison is ivy,
but the survived,
so it was even more terrify, you know, so
all the athletic commission
was on my prior role.
So they treat their way and then I made it
and it went through.
So I was even more than RFI.
So the Elio and abduct me
and they put the Gamma Ray.
Do I increase my strength like the og,
like I performance enhancing drug and
ended the fight was still happening.
So right before I put some
glass and cement and my gloves,
make sure and still add a
crazy hard fight, you know?
So I got to confess with Nick Mile, but
it's completely insane. You know, fight.
You said all that you said, you said
for my fight that I present is ivy,
that I was unstable aid, that I, my my,
my rap was wrong. And,
and you said also what,
what did you said that
you said? Yeah, Dad, Eh,
the way and like I didn't make weight.
Like I w I tricked the athletic
commission or a, they were on my legs.
It's all like, it's just funny.
I think easy. He has that.
He has that problem of constipation,
transpiration, eat to eat.
Take everybody's against him.
You know, paranoia. Yes. I
think that's the way it is.
That might be the weed. It could be
weed. They said, hey, I don't want to,
I don't want to say nothing bad
about the way that they get.
Yeah.