What you're saying is one very important
point that we need to move past the
military gatekeepers of technology,
right? Though it's, it's big tech,
which are at advertising agencies,
things that are constantly
predicting your next purchase,
right? Yeah. Cause if you,
if you think about it,
and I'm in even in a semi democracy look
like we have in the u s I mean those
who control the brainwashing of
the public in essence control who,
who votes for what and who controls
the brainwashing of the public is
advertising agencies and who increasingly
are the biggest advertising agencies
or are the big tech companies who are
accumulating everybody's data and using it
to,
to program their minds to buy things.
So this is what's programmed the
global brain of, of, of the human race.
And of course there are
close links between big tech
and and the military. Look,
look at how Amazon has, what,
25,000 person headquarters
in Crystal City, Virginia,
right next to the Pentagon.
And then I'm in China.
It's even more direct and unapologetic,
right?
So it's a new like military
industrial advertising complex,
which is his guiding the
evolution of the global brain on,
on the planet,
which
not with this past election,
right.
With all the intrusion by foreign entities
trying to influence the election that
they've,
these giant houses set up to write bad
stories about whoever they don't want to
be in office.
Yeah. In a way, that's almost
a red herring, but I mean,
the Russian stuff is almost a red herring,
but it revealed what the processes
are, which, which are used to program.
Oh.
Because I think the,
whatever programming of the American's
minds has done by the Russians is many
key minuscule compared to the
programming of Americans' minds, by, by,
by the American American corporate
and government elite. Right.
Say That anybody's even
jumping in as well and elite.
Sure. It's, it's, it's, it's, it's,
it's interesting if you look
at what's happening in China
that's like, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. They're, they're
way better than the, than we
are as much more horrific.
Right. It's more, it's more professional.
It's more polished. It's more
centralized. On the other hand,
for almost everyone in China, China's a
very good place to live. And you know,
the level of improvement in that country
in the last 30 years has just been
astounding, right? I mean, you can't,
you can't argue with how much better it's
gotten there since Deng Xiaoping took
over. It's, it's tremendous
because they're not,
they embraced capitalism
to a certain extent.
They've created their own unique system.
What labels you give it is,
it is almost arbitrary.
They,
they've created their own
unique system as a, you know,
crazy hippie, libertarian,
a narco socialist, freedom,
loving maniac.
That system rubs against Migraine in many
ways. On the other hand, empirically,
if you look at it, it's improved the
wellbeing of a, of a tremendous number of,
of people.
So hopefully it evolves.
And the way it's evolving now is
not in a more positive freedom.
Love. Well, it's not in the more
freedom, loving and an archaic direction.
One would say it's positive in some ways.
Negative and others like most complex
things. Why do you live there? Um,
I fell in love with a Chinese woman.
She's amazing.
She has great reason. We had a baby
recently. She, she's not from Hong Kong.
She's from mainland China.
I met her when she was doing her
phd in computational linguistics.