The joe rogan experience it. Exactly
right. I need three, four, you know?
Yeah. That's weird. It hurts us.
It's weird. Like the UFC could just,
did they just decide who's fighting?
I mean it's the whole thing.
The business is so interesting because
it's like they decide who's fighting.
They decide who's champion. They decide,
Tony, you're not champion anymore.
I'm going to strip yet. It's
like put it, I fucking fell.
I don't want this to, he's up
at Fox studios. I twist my knee.
But he was working for the UFC when
he fell. I mean he's doing his,
his obligations, his press
obligations. Very strange.
A strip him of a belt when he never lost
it and he the longest winning streak
and then and mean.
But also he has no belt could because
there's no belt can be what's going to
take the belt.
They're going to make up a bell.
And then Connor has the belt at 55 so
what do you do with that belt? Well,
what they were planning on doing,
I believe,
and now they've kind of let the cat out
of the bag cause they said it's going to
be for the world lightweight title.
They were going to strip Connor
the moment something happened,
like the moment the fight started. That's
when they were going to strip Connor.
Yeah,
because if they'd stripped him beforehand,
then what happens if Tony doesn't make
weight or something totally mixed with
out of could be,
doesn't make weight.
Then what the fuck do you have
a concern then you have nothing.
You already stripped him.
We're going to give it back to him.
I'm going to give it back to him.
So if he wants to fight again
now he's not the champion.
He more the fuck kind of shit is strange.
So they waited and the idea was to wait,
but now they're in a desperado situation.
Rato still belt on the line.
That'll yet fucking April fool's.
April fool's day, it happens.
I didn't believe a God damn word of it.
Jimmy Smith's starts texting me. I'm like,
fuck that dude. I'm not falling
for it. Jamie texted me. I'm like,
I'm not falling for it. You texted me, you
go, Bro, it's April fools. I'm like, no.
But Dana, I sent dated, released
a video and he's listening.
I'm sure he likes a
good April fool's joke,
but what he likes more his money and
pay per view buys. You can't honey dick.
The fans are like psych.
It's back on, right.
People are going to be pissed and
not be biased. That's a good point.
I didn't buy it. I still was like,
maybe it's just an elaborate PR scam.
I didn't even tweet about it
until the next day. I know.
I was tweeting about other shed.
People were like, what the fuck, Bro?
This is go jog or not even tweet
about it. I'm like, I'm not. I'm not.
I'm not going to do it. I checked it. I
checked with you and then I checked with,
uh, Josh Thompson who works
closely with, uh, could be,
and then so boom, there's my two main
guys and I went, all right, Ariel,
that's all aerial tweet. I'm like,
God, he's a journalist. I'm a,
I'm an ass clown. He's a legit journalist.
Like [inaudible] he is the, you know,
credibility. So I went, Bro,
is this real? And he goes,
I would never joke around like that.
Brendan. I'm like, he's right. Well,
I went straight to his Jujitsu coach. I
called Eddie, talked to him on the phone.
Yeah. So an Eddie gave me the full
rundown on what happened with Tony.
It's like he saw somebody and
he turned to say hi to somebody,
didn't see some wires on the ground,
tripped over some wires
and just blew his shit out.
And Eddie was on the podcast yesterday
and Eddie was saying that Tony wanted to
fight or day before yesterday. Tony wanted
to fight. They wouldn't let him fight.
Yeah. His, his ligament is torn
from the bone, which is rare,
which is hard to do. I don't
know. Where's that one?
Lateral lateral whenever collateral
ligament, some shit. Anyways.
But do you think, uh, it would, uh,
if, if, if it went tripping off that,
is that a freak accident or do you think
it would have went during the fight?
It's hard to say. Oh, I bet it was a
freak accident, right? To associate LCL.
I mean the way they said it, but first
of all with Dana said was very savage.
What'd he say? Dana said, uh, he
wears those sunglasses indoors.
That should happen to everybody
that wear sunglasses indoors.
That's the letter I have
your glory David quote.
Cause there's only two types of
people that wear sunglasses indoors.
Blind people and assholes.
It's true. So true.
It's so dope there. Those weird
thing man, especially at night,
like what are you doing so hard to
see? What is this? What are you doing?
I've seen a guy in a club
when I used to go to clubs,
he does his glasses on and
then people walk, laid,
lift them up to look around and put
it back down. You can't see shit.
The biggest tools wear glasses,
sis to fights and wear sunglasses and they
sit there with her fucking sunglasses.
I'll especially celebrities that too,
that it's like flurries do it.
It's like get, get a grip. However mean
that's like when you know you fucked up,
you got two famous,
you have to wear sunglasses at a fight
that sit in the front row. It's Sunglass.
And your boys are just like, no, I like
it, man. Yeah, we're those indoors.
That makes complete sense.
It same if you were like a peacock coat
and your boys like, that's all good.
I'm gonna Start Doing podcasts.
Like that stresses me out for now.
That stresses me out. Sam trip. We did a
podcast like this. Did you say something?
What did you say something to them like
what are we doing? And I put mine on,
I put mine on and we've,
we've done it before with a sunglasses
with NASA outfits. That's hilarious.
Deleted. Did our, did the fighter and the
kid with sunglasses. I don't, I go, Bro,
you got to take the sunglasses off. He
goes, my future's too bright. Too Bright.
I'll fuck mine too. And
the calendars. Shit.
I'll have my sunglasses. Yeah.
It's a weird thing. Sunglasses.
That's a hilarious quote by Dana
though. Yeah. Hilarious. Hilarious.
And especially considering how much money
he's losing on this. Can you imagine?
Can you imagine, you know, call
that close. We were like, what?
What keeps happening and keeps happening?
It keeps happening.
Does it tap into this Mac Times? It's
happened a bunch of times. Just one lemon.
May God like you morons.
I'm trying to do your favor.
Who was the most recent
one where that happened?
Where cyborg stepped in last
minute. This close. The last one.
Cyborg stepped in. Who? Oh, that
was Max Holloway Holloway Hallway.
But then there was the Ferguson one with
Khabib or could bebes liver shut down.
They had to take him to the
fucking hospital. It was a bummer.
That was a bummer because this happened
a ton of times. It was the worst one.
Jon Jones do UFC 200
DC mayor the the right,
literally the day before.
You're like, what?
But I wonder if that's better for
the UFC shitty business either way,
but is it better for
the UFC because people,
we've always seen the hype
where a bought in. Yeah,
and then like the next day like what
the f where's John like, oh yeah.
You didn't hear that. Like does that
help them more or does this week yet?
Lisa can promote a little
bit with Max Holloway,
you could promote a little bit with Max
Holloway and it's an interesting fight.
It's a very interesting fight.
Yeah.
There's a lot of those men
that happen to you. Like what?
Which one was the Jon Jones DC one.
You'll see 200 and that will,
what was the thing that John did? Which
one was that? Remember that a coq one B,
I think there was a coke. Coke was,
he goes, this was Dick Pills. Oh,
you remember the, he was like, hey, we
got strip up, pull them from the car.
And then DC fought dash in Silva. That's
right on like today's rounders, Anderson.
And then DC didn't when he fans that
cause he just Kinda, yeah. Yeah.
He just wears fly. He just
wrestled him in his, whatever.
It's still one the front kicked him in
the gut too. And I think you heard him.
Yeah.