Are applying.
I mean even just yesterday,
I think some journalists got banned
from Facebook. Where the store,
yeah. Let me, I'm going
to send this to you Jamie,
cause it's a really crazy one because
they wanted her to show who her funding
sources were and I didn't even know that
there was an area where you could show
that. So it's almost like they're
making this up as they go along. Yeah.
Kyle Kalinsky sent me this today. I want
to send this to you right now. Jamie.
Hang on one second.
Hold on. I'm very quiet. Unfortunately.
This is an audio show. Live there.
Yes. Not Dead Air. There you go. Okay
Buddy. I just send it to you. Okay. Uh,
Facebook suspended in the now tweets,
uh,
page at the behest of CNN and the
u s government funded think tanks.
Says we had almost 4 million subscribers,
did not violate Facebook rules were
given no warning and Facebook isn't
responding to us. So yeah.
What is, what was the,
what it would actually started
this off. I mean, who knows?
They don't communicate with anyone. They'd
been banning legit accounts for years.
They,
you cannot even send a minds.com the link
through Facebook messenger right now.
Blocked. What? Yeah. Why's.
If you post in the newsfeed,
it says careful,
this could be an unsecure website.
Oh,
just clicked on a link from TMZ yesterday
and got the same thing from on Twitter.
Twitter. I said this might be malicious.
They're spam. They're could be from minds.
No, that's from Tia. TMZ Link.
It was clicking this like this
story is on Tmz here to see the,
the rest of the story. So they're trying
to keep you from going to TMZ. Yeah.
I don't know why it was the first
time I've ever seen that, eh,
it's probably caught up in some algorithm
and I sent an actual written letter to
Facebook about it.
Obviously I don't get back.
And then there's no human written letter.
He wrote it with a piece of paper
known now that would have been cool.
I sign it with ink. But really we
had no, cause our lawyer said to,
you know, that actually proves
that you sent them something,
some sort of diligence, but
there's, there's just no recourse.
It's their lost. So explain.
So if someone is trying to say
on Facebook messenger, hey,
you should go check out minds.com they
won't let you post that link. Nope.
And what is their excuse? They
don't tell you. No, don't.
So is it because you're competing
social media network? I don't know.
I don't want to get into, I
don't know. You don't know?
I'm not going to say no. It does.
Yeah. Yeah. You don't know why it does,
but you know,
it doesn't,
they're calling us unsecure and I'm
pretty sure that Facebook got hacked.
You know,
they compromise everybody's data.
Like do you want to talk about unsecure?
There's no more unsecure site that exists.
It is kind of funny, right? I mean
after those and after all the, uh,
the Russia stuff, yeah. It's um,
it is kind of funny calling somebody
else on secure. Yeah. They're insecure.
Mark Zuckerberg is very insecure.
Well, he's also stupid rich. He, um,
he seems like he's too rich. Like he
fucked up. Like he's there sipping water,
like a robot trying to figure out what
the fuck he's doing with this life.
I think that they're scared because they
know they've betrayed everybody and so
it's hard to get them to, to speak.
You know, it's interesting with,
with Dorsey here because I, you
know, give him credit for speaking,
but the fact is that he's not
answering the question well,
he's bringing someone else in to answer
the questions in the next go round.
And so that should be very interesting.
He actually didn't know the
answer to those questions.
I think he probably doesn't know all
the specifics because he's a CEO of not
one, but two different
corporations. He's busy shit.
And also we're but true.
But I think that when we look at the
policy that exists on these networks,
like he is in control of the policy
to large degree. There's a board,
I don't know if there's a decision
making process, but he has a large voice.
I don't know how large his voices,
I assume that's probably true.
But one of the things we did detail on
the last podcast with Tim Pool was how he
wasn't the CEO for quite a long time fired
and then rehired at that point. Yeah.
So, um, obviously there's some contention,
there are some issues and you know,
there's a,
it's a lot of money involved in these
things and I think that plays a giant part
and how they decide to make decisions.
And,
but do you think that an
advertiser in reality doesn't like,
say you're an advertiser and you want
to advertise your computer. Okay.
And there's a video on youtube that
is about something controversial.
Does it actually make sense for that
advertiser to not show their product on
that controversial video? Don't they want
to sell computers? Uh, well it depends.
I mean,
if the controversial videos are about
how Jews are evil and you have this video
about Jews being evil and then you know,
like by Razer computers come
on tucked on at the right.
But do you think that people actually,
I can understand not wanting to support
certain types of content and maybe
advertisers feel like they're supporting
that content by advertising next to it.
But I also don't think that people,
when they're watching a controversial
video on the Internet say,
oh my gosh,
you know,
this advertiser is completely out of
line for being next to this controversial
thing. I, I don't think that's a, a
healthy direction to move. Well, okay,
that's one way to look at it.
Another way to look at it is if you
are a giant company that sells things,
let's say you're Toyota
and you're selling Tundras,
you don't want your Tundras
to be associated in any
way with something that you
might think is negative.
It's their prerogative.
If they're paying for advertising,
they can kind of decide.
This is one of the things that's
leading, um, youtube and specific,
and I've had
a ton of conversations about this there.
It's leading them specifically to try
to de monetize things that could be
considered distasteful or
insensitive or controversial.
And it's very frustrating to content
creators when you talk to them.
They're essentially saying that they need
to do better and that their tools are
very blunt,
that they don't really have the correct
computer learning tools to figure out
what is offensive and why.
And then there's a human review system,
which is very weird. And we've run
into that many times where like,
we'll have like a podcast
with like say Tom Papa,
who's an uncontroversial
fantastic standup comedian.
And it's like demonetized and then we're
like, why? What happened? And then we go,
what the fuck can we talk about?
We didn't talk about anything crazy.
And it's really damaging for brands
when it gets demonetize right away.
Cause it's that initial time period
that generates the most revenue. Yeah.
Said when you have to go back and do it.
I mean,
so I agree with that,
but,
so we built a tool that's like a peer
to peer advertising tool. So it's not,
there's two options.
You can,
so you earn crypto for your contributions
and then which Cryptos do you support?
We have an ethereum based token,
but we're going to support all of them.
So what does a theory on base token? So
it's an Erc 20 token. What does that mean?
It means that we basically reward people
for all of their activities. Okay.
So like say if Jamie's posted on
mines and uh, people love his posts,
he gets rewarded in some, yeah.
How much? How much again? Well,
can I go buy one token will give you a
thousand impressions. Oh, so you, it,
we're not focused on like, oh, you're
going to make money from this. Wait.
[inaudible] we're saying one token will
give you a thousand impressions or you
get a thousand impressions from,
you get a token from 1000 impressions.
One, when you use a token
to advertise on mines, Oh,
you get a thousand impressions
when you boost your posts with it.
So if you use the Crypto,
you use a token,
you guarantee views. Yeah.
That's weird. And it, why?
Well, you're guaranteeing
people see something. Well, we,
when you boosted, it gets fed to people's
news feed chronologically, right?
I say so there's just a backlog.
So sort of like when Instagram
has a sponsored posts,
except we're not spying on people to,
when we send them Instagram Spaz on
people to mine. Yeah. I don't know, man.
I'm stupid. Help me out. It's.