When I heard that Adam and Eve
story, I was like, yeah, right.
Maybe Adam was a bitch and maybe
blamed it on eve and he wrote,
he was the guy who could write. So he
wrote things down. He's like, either drop,
well I don't do shit. Well good.
Listen, he probably ate the apple first.
He probably gave it to eve. You know,
history's written by the winners.
This is correct. And a lot of
women just, they let that shit go.
There's like let them talk. Yeah, right
down. Then I ate the apple. Fuck you.
And he's like, fuck
you. Yep. Adam and Eve,
I don't see Adam and eve
having that New York accident
where the hell they get it
in New York wasn't there yet.
I feel like Adam and Eve would talk
like British people because anytime they
have a movie where people talk like old
timey, whether it's gladiator, whatever,
everyone talks with an English
accent. You ever notice that? Like if,
if we have to, right, if we have to, uh,
there's like the suspension of disbelief,
like we don't know Latin to talking Latin.
Who the fuck knows what that
sounded like? Right. So when,
when you watching some old ass
movie about people talking Latin,
they'll speak English but they'll
speak it with an English accent. Right.
The only speak proper.
They always have some weird old timey
way what's ever watched the movie
otherwise. Right, but you
right. But why is that?
Because it's got to make a watchable.
That's why they ruined stories.
What ti to English people is that played
out like Eleanor's are played out to
him. Do you know what I'm saying?
Absolutely. Like to English people,
they hear that accent every day. That's
a normal accent. But to us it's like, oh,
this is like an old time
language English paper.
Like why is Russell Crowe talking
like he's from fucking London?
This is bullshit. Yeah. I got
a friend of mine, a big Chris,
and he likes to say, well, we invented
the English language and I'm like, yeah,
and you fucked it up. Yeah, you guys made
it to the people don't understand it.
That's stupid. That's not smart.
We've made it better. We really did.
I just say that Matt rebuttal
to him was like, oh yeah, well,
somebody from your town is still trying
to be a rapper and their defense though,
they will always say to
you like, yeah, but listen,
you guys respect our language more
than you respect yours. And it's true.
Like American English is not
as respectable as English
English because that's
why they use those English people to sell
like late night mops and shit. Right?
Oh, the dude, they do
fucking nonstick frying pans.
It's always a man with a proper accent.
You look at this,
I can just find these eggs and
they slide right onto the plate.
Unbelievable. And Hook on to throw a bag
of nickels in there and scratch it up.
Nope, not a scratch. If that was a guy
from Jersey that was selling you that,
you'd be like,
look at this asshole trying to lie to
me about his bullshit frying pan. Right.
And it's fucking shitty mop.
But something about like
English accents get us for sure.
They have a better, they have a more
respectable version of our language,
but our sounds better. You could
say it easier. I understand it.
They understand us.
We don't always understand that.
I was literally just a phone call with a
lady in Europe before I got in here and
I couldn't understand a word she
was saying. The thing is though,
here's where I'm wrong, here's where
I'm wrong. Dan Understand each other.
They fucking dealt. They'll
start. I was in Belfast,
Northern Ireland,
which is you might as well be in
the Cantina scene in star wars.
These mother fuckers,
they barely speak English.
They speak English for sure.
They understand each other 100% but to me,
I was talking to this guy and he was
drunk out of his fucking mind and we were
drinking dark beer.
Just me and this dude,
this is like early 2003
early UFC and UFC in Dublin.
I all, I remember this guy saying
how to fight any man who's hammered.
How have high tiny man,
I'm telling you your challenge,
rocking your fucking how the fuck
I showed him how shamrock nowadays.
Yet he says,
hey to him he was making perfect sense.
All I caught was I'll fight any men.
This motherfucker might've
said that a hundred times.
He just kept buying drinks hammered
with me and some dude from with Belfast
where we understood like 20% of
what each other's was saying.
You got to use the translate thing
on your phone. Wouldn't work.
I had fight any mine.
Oh, what is this color?
This Guy
Shane who you want to skip to kill?
This guy is so cool to fight me.
You want me to kill? Same be
skipping is a kill to the hospital.
If you put knowledge on her
passenger side to see if I can,
I ain't finished with,
if you're promoting,
pause it.
Now imagine being hammered post UFC event
trying to mingle with the locals were
drinking dark beer and whiskey.
There's maybe 30 people around me that
are yelling like that and I'm talking to
this dude, so all the people around
me, who are your allies? If I go drunk,
no one knew. No one knew what
anybody next to him was saying.
Everybody is loud and hammered and this
guy is fucked up and he's telling me
this, how does high tiny mine? And
I'm like, okay, you go fight him.
Funny, we've, we've pulled up
the video before that exact guy
video a long time ago. What is
this one? This is really old.
You talking about this. Oh, let me tell
me about this guy that's hilarious.
Right here.
Eight years ago or some shit.
What does that from two things play at
the same time and that's from an old,
it's two things going on in the
background. Did you hear it?
Damn, I had a beard back then. That's
the same guy. That's hilarious.
Now that's like pikey
language, right? I guess.
I mean it says he is the first video
I pulled up and said he was from,
I think I typed in Belfast or something.
But here's the thing,
here's where I'm wrong.
They fucking understand each other 100%
they understand every word they say
wrong. I just, I'm just
not in that environment.
What do you hang out and you'll get it.
It's got a flavor though.
They have a flavor that we
don't have, right? That's a
dark old world flavor. Hey,
listen,
mate,
that's a fucking dude who just came over
on a boat and he's shooting arrows at
people.
They kept that same language
and they're always
looking to fight out of.