The Joe Rogan experience. Okay. So
time out real quick. Okay. Real quick.
Quick story of time with rich.
So I landed right and you know,
if you know Boston and the deal in Boston.
Yeah. Uh, so I landed and you know, I uh,
a buddy of mine picked me up from the
airport and I got to where I was staying.
I was saying in the mission district,
glued all the sun. First of all,
it was fucking great. The Sun was
awesome, right? I was like, oh my gosh,
some gray skies.
And then I looked down literally
homeless people everywhere.
And what is going on with that?
Like it just,
it blew my mind because it literally,
so I went to the gym in
the morning and I was like,
there's like a 7:00 AM and I saw probably
just as many homeless people living in
tents next to buildings as there
were people commuting to work. Yeah.
Like thousand it. Oh yeah.
It's, it's amazing. Have you
been a skid row yet? No. God,
I'm scared.
You got to go.
You should go while you're here
because it's like the Grand Canyon,
like the Grand Canyon of homeless people.
I want to go there because just you can't
believe the, it's like, did you watch a,
the battle of Winterfell game of
Thrones? No, don't tell. No spoiler. No.
Won't give any spoilers. I'll have to
have come with a better. Okay. Yeah.
Here's a better analogy. Did you
ever see a I am legend? Yes. Okay.
Remember when all the fucking crazy
Zombie before running at once. Yeah.
That's what it's like. Are
you serious? I'm telling you,
you can't believe the volume doesn't
someone even like in Boston, listen,
they freeze to death and
die. Yeah, exactly. So No.
In Boston we, we hide our homeless
people. We have like shelters and stuff.
We hide them. Yeah. For the most part, you
know, downtown crossing area, parks sheet,
whatever. They'd like to junkies that
like have that be the whole gangster lean.
They just lean in, close their eyes and
stuff right there. Most part. Right.
And then we, you know, it gets cold,
they scatter. I don't know where they go,
but you don't really see them that
much, you know, I'm not being rude,
like I don't mind her seeing
just straight, but like insane.
But they're in your face,
man.
If San Francisco is the craziest,
it's, it was insane. So like, honestly,
and I know one of my friends, he said,
listen, you know, um, come to my house,
you know, whatever, we're gonna hang
out for a bit at school. No problem.
Went to his house like,
Hey, you know, small place,
not batting a thousand square
feet. I'm like, pretty nice.
He goes, yeah, you know,
I'm kind of, you know, things were
a little tough. Can I, you know,
can I borrow some, uh, some money?
He's like, borrow money from me.
What are you talking about dude? This is,
you live in, you know, you're doing okay.
He's like, yeah, we're living
paycheck to paycheck. I was like,
what are we talking about? I'm like,
this is a, this is like a, you know,
you got a decent place.
The house we were in was a one point
$6 million house and it was this big,
and I'm like San Francisco,
so let's do things expensive man.
And then another friend of mine said,
listen, Hey, come to my house. You know,
and I pull up to the house.
It's a warehouse.
Like you live in a warehouse
that's actually cool. You
can live like blade. It's,
it's clearly snipes lives with Kris
Kristofferson. It's, yeah, you're right.
You're right. Have the motorcycle. He
had the fucking charger, dodge charger.
But it sounds cool when you have kids
living in a warehouse and isn't that great
know? So, so that's
the thing is that like,
it's a common thing I've noticed for
people to live in either abandoned
buildings, warehouses and cars. Yeah.
You don't have people that live in cars
and the amount of smashed windows that
I've seen here, it's, I
couldn't believe it. Well,
most of those people living in cars
are actually stand up comedians.
Everybody has a fucking story.
Like so many comics come
here and before, you know,
when they first settled in,
they live in the car. That's
super normal. Yeah, that's,
that's just crazy. Like modest. 10 of
my friends really lived in their car.
Do they live in cards?
They're used to at least and then
got an apartment bigger time.
Well that's an issue
we're having around here.
We're having around here with
these people that live in caravans.
They live in these mobile home
types. I've seen them. Yes.
There's like if you drive
around this community, yeah.
Go down certain streets and you just
see these mobile caravans. Yeah.
And they have like, like towels over the
windows. And I saw the math and science.
Yeah. Yeah. These are dirty people. Some
of these fuckers I don't. So how come?
So again, in Boston we just kind of say,
hey, there's no likely of loitering. Well,
they're kicking people out now because
businesses are complaining because there
was one business where this guy had
parked his caravan right in front of it.
That's where a buddy of mine works.
And this dude had laid out his,
uh,
like a blanket on their front lawn
and was sunning himself in front of US
Caravan. So the front of his
building became this guy's lawn.
So this guy in this caravan was
literally using, they were sharing grass.
So he's got this multimillion dollar
building and he's sharing it with a
homeless guy who's cooking meth
or I don't know if it's math,
but some white noxious smoke the place.
Yeah, it's, I couldn't so it, it's, it was
different for me. The weather is awesome,
but like that was a big thing. And I
feel like as I'm walking around more,
if I see a large standing body of water,
I'm like there's a homeless guy living
there too, that people just everywhere,
everywhere.
I'm telling you what you saw is nothing.
When you got to go to skid row, it's
what does, this is a skid row, skid row,
Google maps, skid row. I
just started snooping around.
They must've cleaned it up right before
the drugs. Really. Cause usually, yeah.
Yeah. That ain't shit. Let me tell
you something man. It's, look at that.
Look at all that to the right and
to the left. It's fucking gross.
So how do people have businesses there?
They don't or they just deal with it.
They just deal with it.
Most of them,
most of those people that just put
all like gates and locks and shit,
what's on skid row. But that's why
it's can you where you just were Jamie?
We just were, um, well it's a
lot of warehouses and shit and,
but the interesting thing is this
area is getting air quotes gentrified.
So this is where a lot of
businesses are going now.
They're opening up apartment buildings
and a buddy of mine has lived there.
My friend Magnus Magnus Walker,
he's a famous car guy too.
I don't know if you know who he is. He's
got all these videos of Porsche's all.
He rebuilt old Porsches.
He's got this crazy dreadlocks
and beard and crazy Englishman,
but he's been living down there forever.
He,
and he has this warehouse where
he has it set up where, you know,
his living space is one, one part of
the warehouse. Then down below, yes,
these cars. Right. And
he has it all set up.
But if you drive down some of these roads,
you'll see like these super expensive
apartment buildings that are going up now
and then a block over.
You see these homeless encampments and
people think it's like cute to be around
like all this dirt. What does this, there
we go. Nice. Look here, look at that.
So that's someone's apartment.
What's going on here? Yeah,
they just set up tents and then the cops
kicked them out and they just come back
and they move and then they come back.
But they,
they make these encampments and you just,
you just have to deal with it.
So it's like if you live in that area,
you know,
you just have to jump over needles
and try to figure your way through it.
I feel so I feel terrible because,
no, I, it's, it's most of this,
most of this is either drug addiction
or mental illness. Those are the real,
real problems. Do you guys have no
drug addiction or mental illness,
like places that you could go to for
help here? I don't know what it is, man.
I don't know enough about it. Um,
um, um, entirely ignorant about how,
what's going on.
I know that if you talk to people that
work in the field that work with these
folks, they say that it all really started
to happen. Look at this guy, he's like,
run over my leg. Oh my gosh, I need
disability. Oh my goodness, man,
that's crazy. Crazy. Honestly,
if you were to take a screenshot of what
you just showed me, I'd be like, okay,
that's some third world country,
right?
This is la people can't even
afford to live in La. I know.
I might as well be a third
world country though.
I mean it might as well be the apocalypse.
It's the apocalypse for those folks.
I mean at least there they're
around all these cars and shit,
but I mean there are thousands of homeless
people in that whole skid row area
right next to the mission
there. Yes. That's one of the,
is one of the things
that keeps them there.
I guess we'll have like a mission beds,
three beds in the whole thing.
I don't know. That's wild that they, uh,
they uh, allow most of this to go on.
I don't know. Like how often they
break it up and make people move.
But this did not, the numbers are so
high. There's not much they can do, man.
That's cray. It's sad. Sad. It's
Super Sad. Like, but what do you do?
How do you fix that? Like,
I don't have any solution.
You can't tell people they shouldn't.
What are you doing?
What does that actually documented?
You have a problem. Yeah. Yeah.
Product went and spent three days down
there like undercover and filming him
experiencing,
and then he'd come back and do like an
interview or like what are you just went
through? And it's, it came out 10
years ago. So it's, it's different.
I don't know if I'm, I'm assuming it's
worse now, but it's definitely not good.
And this and this. So it's crazy.
So, uh, I was on my one wheel, right?
Just right riding by. I was commuting
back and by the way, the thing is bad ass.
It's pretty crazy, right? Yeah. I've wrote
it. I wrote yours today. He did ride mine.
It was good. And after watching you
scoot around effortlessly, I was like,
how hard could it be? Do you
need one? You should get one.
I also don't need broken elbows
like, honestly, it's good
for, it's good. It's good.
It's a good core workout. I'm sure
it's a great word. You sit ups.
I think it's a better core
workout. Yeah. Sit Up, Michelle,
show you this hip and glute machine from
rogue where you put your ankles in this
thing and you lean all the way back and
go all the way up till you have some
next level shit here. By the way. I got
some cool stuff, man. That's awesome, man.
Warehouse. It's really, it's this place is
fucked. Can I live here? Sure. All right,
cool. Plenty of room. Bring it 10.
Can't battle the Jujitsu bad. Um, but,
but yeah, so I was writing my one wheel,
uh, pass this, uh, past like
this is kind of overpass. And uh,
there was a tent there and like a,
a lady sticks her hand out and
she offers me a chocolate. Uh,
what was it? I think it was
a chocolate lady bug, right?
It was a lady bug wrapped in like that,
that, that, that 10 mixed chocolate,
whatever. I'm like, oh. I'm like,
no thank you. No thank you. Right.
By getting next day offers to me again.
I was like, no thank you. No thank you.
I was like, you know what, I'm going
to, I'm going to like, you know,
do something nice. Right. So I get
five bucks and I was like, I'll go,
I'll give it to her. You know, it's
a nice gesture. I write up, you know,
I give her a hand, are the five bucks.
As I start slowing down on the one wheel,
other people should are popping their
heads out of the tents and they actually
saw me give her the money and immediately
a guy runs out and like snatches it
directly out of her hand,
snatched it right at hand.
Someone else comes around the corner,
takes it from him and they start getting
into the scuffle and I'm just like it.
I've never seen anything like that before.
I know I'm really passionate about it.
I just, it's just, I just can't
stop thinking about it. It's crazy.
It's really crazy out here, man. Dude,
that's crazy. And everyone comes,
everyone comes to to,
to La,
California to get there at
their big break. Like all in,
I'm going to be like a famous, whatever,
famous, you know, actor, singer,
exotic dancer, a porn star, whatever.
And it's, the struggle is real out here.
It's real. It's real everywhere. But when,
whenever you get giant groups of people,
you're going to get,
you know,
a higher percentage of people that are
out here that are homeless or struggling.
Right. Um, again, I don't know what the
fuck, what's the solution? Yeah, no,
yeah.
[inaudible].