Her low freak bitches.
Is He,
what is he like when the lights are off?
I wish I could have a fucking a feed of
Trump's brain when the lights go down,
that's probably CIOs. What
is he thinking? Is he like,
I'm killing it or is he like, what have
I done? I think there's gotta be both.
Yeah. Or there he's gotta be, uh, well
he doesn't drink and he doesn't do drugs.
Right. And I think there's gotta be a
part of his brain that's pushing down the,
what have I done and it reinforcing,
doubling down on the,
I'm the greatest. I'm the best. I mean,
that's why I kept saying about
his inauguration numbers.
There's so many people were there.
And even when they told him that
it wasn't the case, he fought it.
Then when he kept parroting,
not just parenting to friends,
but doing it to the news,
doing it to the press,
that he got the largest number of
electoral college votes. That's crazy.
It's psychedelic narcissism.
It's like, it's so far out there.
It starts to seem like,
Whoa,
you're bending reality and actually
is bending reality. He's done.
He's done a fascinating job of just
making people not know what's real anymore
and no one knows what's real anymore and
Syria as the ultimate example because
it's unclear what Israel,
they're like,
no one knows what the right thing to
do is. Who are we attacking and why?
What are we trying to stop?
You sent bombs to the people that are
fighting isis to fight those people from
doing chemical warfare
on their own people,
but then we also are fighting isis with
them and then it's just the whole thing.
You're just like, I
give up. You will have,
when Ron Paul was saying that the
chemical attack doesn't make sense,
so certain Soton Republicans are actually
looking at me as Ron Paul Tech and the
Republicans more
libertarian than anything,
but they're looking at it and saying
like this, this might not even been real.
I mean, I just, well,
I heard this great thing about how no
one in Israel believes that Rabin was
killed by Yigal Amir, the Jewish guy
like that. They, they believe in that.
Basically hearing a conspiracy theory
that widely believed in a country that
isn't my own made me realize how wildly
desperate for conspiracy theory everyone
is. Right? It like somehow the distance
where it was like, oh it's Israel.
It's not really me. Made me go
like, oh this is so interesting.
Like everybody wants to believe it wasn't
one hour until they were saying that
the chemical attack by Assad was not real.
Even though Assad has done
gas based chemical tests on
his own people before and
his father did before him. Somehow this
one was like, no, no, this is fake.
It might be fake. That's what's so crazy
and mind bending. It might be fake.
And yet I don't buy any
conspiracy theories anymore
cause I knew how desperate
people are to believe them.
Well this was the same scenario that led
Obama to make that speech saying that
we need to go into Syria and the
whole American people went fuck that.
Cause we were deep in the Iraq war,
deepen the Afghanistan war
and that was when this,
I think that was 2013 or
14 but Trump made quotes.
It's crazy that he tweeted like,
what does a u s have to
gain for going into Syria?
We should be America first and then
winds up acting almost instantaneously.
Yeah, I know. It happens. People keep
dropping these, like you said, this, yeah.
Bombs at Trump's feet. Like he cares
about intellectual coherence or hypocrisy.
He doesn't care.
He's a fucking rat trapped.
He's trapped in a corner of amaze and he's
going like, what the fuck do I do? Oh,
I'll just do this. It's so, it's so
transparent. Like 35% approval rating.
Everything is, you're, you're
collapsing under your own weight.
You have the house and the Senate
and you can't get anything done.
No one likes you. You're the
worst. So what do you do?
You fucking make something explode.
It's just such a terrible recipe of
something actually goes wrong. Oh yeah.
Like Syria is a minor issue.
No one died. Totally bomb.
Some airfields, they ruined some,
you know, some ground, I agree.
Ruin some air ships. Um, some, uh, planes.
But what happens if something
really goes down and that guy is,
that is the figurehead.
That is the difference between the
Roman Empire and this empire is that the
Roman Empire didn't have the power
to press a button and destroy,
like path the countries on earth.
And we do. So that's the scary part.
Oh, come to the comedy
store. The Saturday night.
Yeah.