It's what a lot of people think is
wrong about the trash talk of this era
because there's, this is, there's
an error right now, right? Is this,
we're in the trash talk era.
Absolutely.
Some people are really good at it
and some people are terrible at it,
but it seems like everybody's
trying Mazda doll. Um,
recently when he just beat Darren till
it was very interesting because you know
his take on it before the fight
was, why am I, why, why trash talk?
Like what are we doing?
What do you know why we're going to fight?
Like what is all this bullshit about?
Like he doesn't like it. He was like,
I don't like where this is going. I don't
like where the sport is going. Yeah.
I mean it was,
it's one of those things that I had to
adjust to because I wasn't brought on
those principles. I don't, I'm not,
you know, cause I'm not here. Yeah.
I wasn't here for a salesman. Like people
ask me all the time, why do you do this?
And I chose to do this,
like I'm college educated,
I can get a fucking job.
And him sitting in an office
and punch numbers and all that.
But I chose to do this because of my
burning desire to compete. That's when I,
even now when I compete with guys,
I'm not competing angry.
I only to kill this guy. I'm not
Robert. I run all that shit. No,
it's competition for me. My mind is I'm
going to beat you. And which is partially,
which goes to test with the, how I fight
and how I compete. I'm not like that.
This is not the only thing that I can do.
And so this Eric came about where
now everybody, you gotta Talk Shit,
you gotta sell,
you gotta do this and do that.
And so do you feel any
pressure to do that? Initially,
at some point I did because it was,
um,
I was fighting the way I was fighting.
I was dominating guys and I was getting
nowhere. It was like no notoriety.
They were kind of like just kind
of putting you on the wayside.
They would always tell him, oh, you get a
top 10 guy, you'll get a top thing. Yeah.
But they wouldn't happen.
He was like, Oh, you,
you fight this guy and you can't really
argue with them because this promotion
has given you the opportunity to even
really make money at all for the career
path that you chose. So for I, for a
while I just felt like, man, this is not,
I guess I just got to do this because
you saw it. The other clown Covington it,
he had to do that.
He actually had,
nothing has changed with
the way that he fights.
He's done the exact same day
since he'd been in the UFC,
but after the first couple
of fight, no one gave a shit.
So he felt, you know what?
No, I'm just going to have to start doing
this. Everyone knows it's fake. Right.
Because he just one day woke up
and started doing it. And that's,
that's the thing now you have to do,
people try to say you have to do that,
but for me is when I'm not going to do
is I'm not going to just sell my soul
just to,
Oh yeah,
I'm just trying to earn a couple of
bucks because I'm not going to do that.
I'm going to do it the right way. George
did it the right way and, and, and I,
I'm a firm believer that
when you do it the right way,
you will earn what you deserve.
It will come to you at some point.
I don't think that you have to, I
really don't. He had something, I mean,
Colby Covington does because
I do freaking sot he, he show,
look, you got to give it to
him. He did beat those on Joe's.
That was a big victory. He did beat Damien
Maia. That was a big victory. Those are,
those are two legit victories
over to very dangerous guys.
He did beat those kinds of, and he's
got skill on top of the trash talking,
but the trash talking bumped him ahead
of you in line and a lot of us were
surprised. I was surprised. I was
surprised that he had to, he had to do it.
And I mean it's gotten them where he
has and I mean look what he did like two
weeks ago when I fought his whole,
his whole deal with,
for me to create an uproar to
get my name back in the picture.
And he did a wonderful job. This
is one thing that I will, I will,
I would say is that he has
done a wonderful job at
having people talk about him,
whether you hate him,
which,
and even the bosses have said the exact
same thing is no one has done what he's
done.
No one has ever created the persona
that is unanimously hated worldwide.
Like unanimously, there's not
even heal. Like literally it,
like those guys, they still had fans,
you know, that wanted to see him succeed.
Like nobody likes it. He's not
safe anywhere. No. You know,
you don't even have to be, there's
flyweights that want to hurt this guy.
So if you, Nana Nestle has, he's
done a good job of creating that,
which I love and I appreciate that it's
going to sell a lot of paper views,
but I'm not, yeah, I'm not
a hater. I'm not a hater.
Like I give credit where credit is due.
I appreciate the fact
that he has done that.
And that's one day net Rashad taught
me over the years is that you have to
appreciate certain things like that. And
I, and I do, I always wanted this moment,
I always wanted that Connor and
could be that, that, that adversary,
that Rashad and rampage, that
Hughes and, and George St Pierre,
like I always wanted that. And, and
he's done a good job of creating that.
So you're not just an adversary in terms
of like a legitimate worthy opponent,
but uh, do that you want to
fuck up. Absolutely. I mean,
I haven't, I haven't been in a fight
yet where it was like a malicious,
like I was maliciously trying to hurt
someone. I haven't been in that fight yet.
Yes, I don't. That's the thing, my
amazing with my mind. My mind is strong.
I don't compete.
Oh yeah,
I'm trying to kill this guy and then
you swing five punches. You Miss.
Now you're dead tired.
I don't compete like that.
This one I'm still going to compete as
myself but there's going to be a little
extra on behind these,
these elbows.
Now I'm going to fillet your face with
the little longer cuts. I'm trying to,
this one is going to be one that I,
I really enjoy.
Well there was the same with could be
even Connor when he said I want to change
your face. Yes. When he said that
I was like damn, that's deep.
I want to change your face.
And you saw that even with when
could be was like that is um,
because he was never out of character
and it can be never was like, oh yeah,
I'm just going to go out there
and try to kill this guy. Right.
There's a certain level,
there's a certain mentality then
certain fighters have to add.
It could be was a another guy that I've
seen that competes similarly to the way
that I do as far as his mind, where it's
at. Like I don't give a shit what you do,
talk about me, do all this. Try
to distract me like they tried me.
This will come leading up to the
tire and fight. They did everything.
What are you going to do?
And then you had his,
his little psychic that
looked like sideshow Bob that
was was talking and doing
this,
trying to distract me and this and then
Colby popped up trying to distract me.
Dad didn't change anything.
That's not going to do nothing to
me like my mind is own competing.
I'm going to compete to the best of my
abilities and I'm going to embarrass you
and then this guy is going
to be even more worse.
Big Change in your skillset from your
first fight in the UFC to now as you're
striking, you're wrestling
has always been outstanding.
Your cardio has always been excellent,
but your striking is much
more fluid and much looser.
You're you, you're much more efficient
now. You was, you were always powerful,
but it seems like now
everything's phone together.
Like you don't have any holes in your
game anymore. It's a different thing.