The joe rogan experience. Oh yeah,
a lot. Of course. Edge it bra.
Also known as Eddie Bravo.
It's your pride.
That's what they taught when we were
in Brazil. That's the calling me.
Hey is Joe Moran?
Were those the first giant tournament
that there was an la Joe Moran was,
he was the main promoter
and in my division that was
45 guys were all blue belts
in my division. He's, and you got
to sit there and listen to him.
Call out everyone's name and I'm sitting
there. I'm waiting for him to call.
My name is, he looks, he
looks at the clipboard.
Then he looks up because here's your bra.
I'm standing right in front of him.
I'm like, man, when are they
going to call my dad? Like fuck.
And then someone say, dude, I think he's
saying you're in hand. No Way. Yeah.
Where's Rick Story?
Ben? It's a long story.
I [inaudible]
out of the park.
It was the weed
dive in
that ball landed in the bed of my cup
and he probably just went to Pete's.
Fantastic. He gets so worked up.
I was hoping you'd jump over
here and choke the shit out.
He loves conspiracy theories
about nine 11 inside. Y'All are,
I don't know man. Don't answer
that. You're already smart.
Get Eddie another beer down real quick.
Real quick. Chemtrails
yesterday, a killer or an aid?
How many, how many towers went
down on nine 11. Oh my God.
I know.
He knows my brothers crazy like you are.
Oh Shit. Donald Cerrone's that happy.
He knows the three towers went down.
Means that, uh, you know,
most people don't know.
They'll say to most people don't know
when that a press conference with Nist,
the National Institute of
Standards and technologies,
they're the ones that came out
and explained what happened.
Tower some when they asked him why didn't,
did you guys check for a
really simple,
it's like kindergarten shit when
they asked the head of kindergarten,
why didn't you check for explosives?
Why didn't you test for
explosives on tower seven?
They said there was no reason to
witnesses.
Meanwhile, there's about an hour
of witnesses, firemen, policemen,
sane bombs went off.
There's video of what's
going on and the guy said,
we didn't check for bombs
because there was no witness.
What about that frowning? Who
flew those planes? Exactly.
Nothing. Anybody can
say. I can say to you,
there's nothing I can say. I provide
a complete video evidence for you.
I broke it down for you.
You're still saying
how much I can say to me.
I hadn't said anything.
Let me play devil's advocate momentarily.
Some guy asked me the other day if I
wanted to have someone who's a lot,
a flat earth proponent is apparently the
best argue or for a flat or I want to
hear that argument. What could
they possibly say? No fucking way.
Either trolling or retard.
Yes, of course it's Trump,
but the one thing that's fucking
weird is you would think with all the
satellites we have going in and out of
our solar system and how come there's no
pictures of the earth and like,
Hey, I don't know. It's
a fact. I'm Brian Cord.
Meyer was one of the top
CIA guys back then. JFK.
This was Kay was banging cored wires wife.
So when you listen to this,
he Howard hunt concessional.
He said Lyndon B Johnson work a
straight at the whole thing. He lives.
He's telling you a CIA agent
famous on his deathbed saying,
you look at wait was cord
Meyer cord. Meyer wanted him
dead, so Lyndon B Johnson,
he had cord. Meyer did look
how much at the time was that?
He Bravo spent smoking weed, peering
out curtain senior first play that.
Are you shocked or something? Dude.
Now people are dying all the time.
Did you know this is some wide open?
She did.
You know how many astronauts died in 1968
to eight and then two more in 69 what
happened when they doing flying
in this space? Accidents.
His Father Prescott Bush started the CIA.
His father,
Prescott Bush finance the
Nazis through union bank.
That's not a conspiracy theory that
you know in Sweden for many years
they sterilize kids that didn't have
symmetric, perfectly symmetrical faces.
Is that a fact? It's actually nice.
That's why they're so good looking
because they stay. I don't know.
I'll look into it. You think you
think that's crazy? When, when?
When when you say look into it, did you
look into it? I got to meet her now.
Everything that's coming through the
major news that works all have an agenda
behind it. Whether it's district,
because if I was running shit I would,
if I was running shit and they said, hey,
what do you think we should do? I'm like,
wait a minute. Are you guys controlling
the media? First of all, if they say no,
we're not really controlling the media.
They do whatever they want.
I would say control the goddamn media.
What the fuck are you guys,
how would I get my information
at the library guys?
I go to the library as apple bottom.
I'm so fucking Internet.
Who goes to the library?
The library.
You guys get your information from
the Internet. I go to the library.
How I love how you say the Internet
is if it's all the same source he did.
He was in this amazing documentary and
just a fucking changing documentary
called the principal. Have
you seen that? No, I have not.
Fuck Emmett Chicago's in at a bunch of
physicists, like professors from Mit.
That's so funny. I just saw
the documentary sugarcoated,
Dan. Have you seen it?
It's terrifying. Holy Shit.
Real quick documentary. This is,
this is one that I've watched over
and over. It's really, really good.
You said it's the festival. No,
it's not. It's not, but it's really,
really good because especially
for conspiracy, there is type,
it's called how big oil
conquered the world.
There's a documentary called the
fence will blow your fucking mind.
They never finished that. They
abandoned it. It's deserted.
Mexican dudes are going,
what are these Americans doing?
They're interviewing Mexicans.
I'm just like, this is easy.
This documentary's called about the birth
of oil and how it came in and infected
all our lives and how John Rockefeller
monopolize fucking everything to find
that dude. It's an incredibly,
and it's free on youtube. Yeah.
That's a big red flag there. Hey, there's
a documentary you can watch on Youtube.
Oh, Jay, the untold story.
Untold Story. Oh No,
it's at the library, Bro.
In America.
The Sugar Association,
they didn't want it to be labeled
as for what it really was, uh, uh,
an addictive toxin.
They wanted to keep it.
It ain't that bad in moderation and ain't
that bad. It makes things taste sweet.
It's about love.
They tell you,
they tell you lead on no shit.
We're looking at a bunch of
lights and the Goddamn sky.
You're going to tell me that that light
and that light that's 200 and 5,000
trillion light years away.
How the fuck did you figure that out?
And you don't have an explanation
for that shit. No, exactly.
That's what every would
you just send it right now?
But what you just said now is
what everyone's natural reaction.
Cause anytime someone
says anything about space,
you automatically think
someone figured it out.
You don't know the guy's name.
You don't know the name of the experiment.
You didn't look into it yourself.
You just think when someone tells you
how far is the earth from the sun?
Oh say oh 93 million miles away.
Like you just,
you.
Everybody relies on someone figured
that out and someone double checked it.
Dude, it's math. It's science. It's
math. But no one really knows. So they,
they paid according to this documentary,
they paid out Harvey. You know,
cause everyone's like, I'm
science, I'm a science. This,
I'm science that it's beautiful when
people do that because then all you do is
buy off all the scientists and you got
everybody. I love some sugar though, man.
We can all be bullshit.
Those documentaries key
so juiced up. They're so,
they're so juicy. They seem
so good. They seem so real.
You get fired up and then once you get
fired up, it's tough to get unfired up.
I want to be in the Goddamn Illuminati.
If they'd got down and listening. Yeah,
that's the wrong,
except the military credit for all the
great music that came out of the 60s you
fucking military scenario.
You are a fucking just shit
to start my own false flowers.
Jones,
he's get a call you a shell Monday morning
we got an disturbing turn of events.
Eddie Bravo I've had on this podcast.
I did not know he was in an
Illuminati Shit. Fuck yeah,
he is on the Joe Rogan
experience. Yes. Yeah.
Trails proven to be false. Fuck yeah.
Fuck yeah. Fuck yeah. I want to fucking,
oh my God, you're in. If, oh, please let
me, let me work through my own fault.
I talked about this, the phone, I would,
if I would get that fucking oil from
Alaska, I would go in there and make it,
make it an elect. Trump make it
look like the Isis is, uh, uh,
Eskimos are trained in
Isis. I would, you know,
you're a national treasure and
[inaudible] was a national trend.
Now these things are true.
It has to be frustrating.
Ready to believe something go.
He's constantly have to back.
Here's a sauce and this is very exhausted.
When I posted a meme,
I can see like people,
I could see my, uh, followers
rise. But what I post,
anything like anti vaccine,
any kind of dude,
hundreds,
70,
2000.8 and then it goes,
well,
it's 7.6 reach to,
they want, people don't like
conspiracy. I know so many.
I lost. You know what? I
cleaned them out. It's a filter.
I needed to clean those fuckers out.
Someone did come up to me and say, Hey,
have you heard that conspiracy
theory where there's no forests,
there's a conspiracy theory where
there's no chorus. Look into it.
No forest, you love these things. I'm
like, I don't know what that is. Really.
I didn't even look,
I watched 30 seconds cause someone
that had an in class told me, right.
A Ziggy came across your, that
conspiracy theory about Noah. I go, Whoa,
what is that? When all of that, but
no forest, and I was 13 seconds.
I used to stopped it.
Have you seen the one with this?
The due to the dinosaurs aren't real.
Have you seen that one that I don't have?
I don't know. I don't know. That's like
some other shit where I'm like, I don't,
I don't believe any science.
I don't believe in the only science.
I believe that is a,
you rub two sticks together and there's
fire that's other than that science,
you've got to prove that.
It's just like a boy scout.
I'm going to ignore that shit. Hmm. Oh,
you gotta just tobacco science. What
about that, that you think that Shit gone?
Yeah.