Things was like,
I,
I had tried to encourage Phil Hartman
to do stand up several times because he
would do standup where he would
warm up for the, you know, the,
the crowd would be there for the show.
And in between scenes,
there was always some downtime and Phil
would take the warmups microphone and do
bitch riff. And I do like,
is Bill Clinton impression?
This was during the whole
Monica Lewinsky scandal.
So he had like all this material
about Bill Clinton and Monica and his
impressions were amazing.
Yeah. Yeah. No, he's like,
he's one of my favorites of all time
on that show. Yeah. He was amazing.
And so he was thinking about
what is this two shows?
Where is he Huntsville,
Alabama still doing stand up look. And
then he didn't give a fuck. Look at,
I'm out there with those glasses
is great. Hey, looks happy.
He looks back at 14 likes.
Hey,
I'm Jon Lovitz get out the
likes looking on my legs.
Yeah. So he's still doing it. Interesting.
Yeah. Good for him. Good for him.
Like I said, I always liked
him. Great Guy. When I did SNL,
I think it was the first
season where he had,
he had just left I think because I did
it pretty much probably if I had to pick
a season, I would been, that
would've been that when I did,
cause he still had Carvey
and you still had, you know,
Hartman and Victoria Jackson, like
the whole kind of group. But um,
I forgot him of Victoria Jackson.
She was fucking hilarious. Yeah.
What happened to her? She's a
hardcore conservative now. Yeah. Huge.
Like right wing, right winger. She's
put on a little weight, you know,
but I haven't wheel and uh, yeah, no,
she's actually a hardcore
conservative. No, like she,
she shouted from the mountaintops,
what was she like when you met
her? She was fine. I mean, listen,
when she conservative back then I was
busy doing the show kind of thing,
you know what I mean? Cause it's a lot of
work. And in which war? No, he, that I,
I had to do,
um,
I had to do it without cue cards because
my father didn't want me to use cue
cards. So I don't like to
memorize all that stuff.
Plus Fuck Dad plus plus the skits.
That didn't even make it into the show.
So like I had to memorize like
schizo didn't even end up in the,
this kind of Shit is that
dad, you know, I, like I said,
I had a good memory and he didn't
want me reading. You know, cause it,
you can see it,
they can see it when people are reading
and he didn't want me to do in that. So.
Wow.
So Nokia card,
but also that means the other actors
do cue card for them either. Yeah,
of course not. You know, like, yeah, no,
I'm sure my father made a lot
of friends looking at like,
you know that that weekend.
Well that's fucked up.
Like how can he dictate whether or
not the other actors get cue cards?
I don't know. Because it's
because he apparently he could.
Victoria Jackson's a
hardcore conservative. It's
so straight. Like I said,
she shouts it from the, from the
mountaintops looking again active. Yeah.
So she was like, you know, so
it was that whole kind of group,
that kind of late eighties group. Uh,
but then also it was a, it was my,
a second season, I think, you know, it
was, it was like, you know, Schneider,
Sandler Rock.
It was like that kind of overlap year.
So I actually got like a really kind
of like really good group that Leanne,
I'm so, no, that was
awesome. That was neat.