Hello Freak bitches when they were Amash
essentially Democratic Party was gone.
Come on America, like let's
vote a woman in. Come on.
Like we just had the black president.
It was amazing to have a woman president.
And I think if they'd gone with almost
any other candidate that didn't have as
much baggage,
it'd be a different story.
But they were asking you to like
somebody who I didn't have an issue with,
but a lot of people have
got a big issue with,
if she was a man it would
be a giant problem. But we
gave her, what do you mean?
Well, if she had all those problems,
if she, you know, all the, you know,
[inaudible] all this shit.
I mean we saw a guy with a lot of
problems and you seem to squeak through,
but I'm saying if he was,
she was a man and she was up against
Trump and she had all those problems. Oh,
I see what she was crushed. She would have
no chance. But because she was a woman.
Oh, you think she got further
because, oh, 100% yeah.
They wanted to make history.
They wanted to make history because look,
from a social standpoint,
Barack Obama was very important because
here was a super articulate guy who's
really calm.
He just,
he has a very even a
presence about him always.
He never seen him riled up. You'd never
see him crazy. Even like he gets heckled,
you just see that thing with a Trump
supporter was heckling him and he,
he handled it with grace.
He has a graceful God.
That's like probably the best
way to describe them. You know,
like that was important for the
country because that represented like,
wow, hey, here's this black
guy who's super articulate.
It's so calm.
And so like the way he expresses
himself is so perfect for a president.
So presidential, like there's a what a
what a perfect example for our country.
This is us.
And then I think a lot of people felt
like Hillary Clinton would be another one
of those things. Like, look, we can have
a woman running things. We're not sexist.
Like, look, we look, we
are a really articulate,
incredibly well experienced woman who's
been in business for a long time with
the government. She's deep
inside the public service
and she was a teenager. Yes,
but it was just too much.
It was just too much shit for people.
But I think if that was a man and
she had all those same problems,
it was a man and tied to some foundation
that was getting all these people that
eventually got arms deals
and they donated and the,
they're all part of this weird
sort of incestuous political world.
A man would be skewered with that same
record because Trump was running as an
outsider.
You know what he had going against him
is he's borish and he says ridiculous
shit and you know, they could,
they could point to that,
that recording of him talking
about grabbing pussies and
they'll look, look, look,
look, look. We have here like that.
That was like the big thing against him.
But at least to these people that
hate the system, he was an outsider.
If she was a man, she would've represented
even more of an insider, you know,
to I think to a lot of people.
I think her,
her actions and what she's done
in the past versus her as a woman.
That was like sort of a
situation there because like,
do you ever see the video where she was
talking about a Kadafi being killed? No.
Crazy video man,
because she's joking around.
It's before they interview her and she
goes [inaudible] before the official
interview starts. Like she, yeah,
she had just found out that Kadafi had
been killed and she was like laughing
about it. She goes, we came,
we saw he died. Ha ha ha.
And she throws her head back and she's
laughing. She was kind of hawkish. Ooh,
she was hawkish. If that was
a guy, if a guy did that,
he would have been thought to be a
fucking serial killer. A sociopath.
Right. If a guy did that, like
say if Joe Biden, like we came,
we saw he died.
People would be like,
do you want that guy in charge of
the fucking nukes? But we let her go.
We'll give her a pass.
There's a lot of stuff that she's
done where people give her a pass.
They put a more interesting
cat in charge of the dukes. Oh,
there should be no president. This is
what I say. Everybody's like, well,
who would you think should
be the president if you
have a problem with Trump or
if your problem,
no human being should be in control
of 350 million human beings.
It's a pro posture. His job. Explain
this this way. Too many of us.
It's impossible. Would it be done?
Can we don't have to do it this way?
The road down the idea.
I don't have one,
but when we can't have an Alpha chain
to figure it out right here were smart.
The Internet. What about, what about
education? The Internet, mind reading.
Well essentially it does it
come down to, uh, what was the,
was that movie with the girl?
Shoots, bows and arrows and shit. Oh,
a hunger games or games.
Can we district the country and then
their heads of district or same thing.
We'll go to war with each other. You
can't do that. All right, so that's gone.
This is the think tech is, he's out.
Happened like every idea to get there.
He was one dates states are problematic.
So then what does people like? Fuck Utah.
This is Texas Sun.
That's true. Gosh, this,
I grew up in New Jersey and New York
hated us and fucking everybody hates
everybody. Hated the Banya. Oh yeah, you
hated Pennsylvania. New York hated Boston.
Connecticut got a pass. Okay, so it was
like some little kid with a limp, like Ah,
don't pick on let's Connecticut doesn't
get mentioned in the tri state area.
Whenever they did credentials it would be
like New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania.
Exactly. I didn't know. I thought
Connecticut was New Hampshire, Ohio.
It years and years like Connecticut is
a highway to highway between Boston and
New York, but we were like
a poet, Connecticut Psi
where everyone could I get,
it's like fuck you.
They are like fuck you.
But you know want to talk to them
about bitch bitch. You know I'm right.
All right. Wait no states cause
we'd war with each other. Yeah.
Can you something that
somebody has to govern? No,
they have to be police and shit like that.
I think the best way to probably handle
it is let every human being have a say
every human being that's of adult age
and I think registering to vote should be
just as fucking easy as getting an email.
It should be just as easy as doing
everything else that you do online.
You had a Twitter handle,
you should be able to vote.
You should be able to use your id,
like whatever, whoever you are,
whatever your name is, you know, call
yourself who are the fuck you want.
That is one individual vote.
That's what I think.
And I think as long as we could figure
out how to make that system pure where
people can't hack it through it, he
can't log in from 15 different computers.
If you have a fucking birth certificate
and your birth certificate aligns with
this number and that's
this and this is you,
as long as they could figure out how to
make it so people don't hack into it.
Everybody who's an adult should be
allowed to vote and voting for the people
that have gone to jail.
I think people that have gone to jail,
the idea that someone goes to jail for
four years and now they can't vote for
the rest of their life. I think that's
fucking crazy too. That's ridiculous.
You paid your debt to society back and
you should be able to reenter society.
Exactly.
You're telling me you can't be a 20
year old to do something stupid and rob
somebody or something and then I'm
supposed to think of you a certain way for
the rest of your life.
You're 80 now.
You robbed somebody when you were 20
that's still you. You're dangerous, man.
Talking about tearing down institutions,
but institutions are a problem no
matter what. There always a problem.
I think the real issue is
government, right? Governing us.
So the real issue is what
everybody wants is safety,
security, protection and unity.
That's what everybody wants.
All the other stuff in terms of
like restrictions on your behavior,
we have to just figure it out.
Cut it down.
The middle between hurts other people
and hurts yourself. It hurts yourself.
You're on your own, just like you're
on your own with rock climbing,
just like you're on your own.
Would Bungee Joe Open. So wait,
give me an example of exercise.
Like you're on your own hobbies in
high school they'd call them elective.
Yeah. Yeah. How come you could
just go to the roof and jump off,
but you can't do heroin
like no one will stop you.
You can go to your roof and
practice backflip. Megan.
So much science and ready to boot.
Dude,
I'm ready to fucking Jack a needle
in my 12 gauge it right now.
You have people tickets telling other
people what to do. You've got a tyranny.
Yeah,
you got a fucking problem.
Even if even if they sort of can get
away with it because it's written down on
paper. Did you agree
to it? No. You weren't.
Nobody asked you about like child labor
laws, do you haven't? You've never,
no one's,
no one's pulled you aside and saying
that for years since I was a child. No.
It's pulled you aside and
decided, well, you know, and you,
you've decided with them how old you
should be when you drink, right? No, it's,
it's, it's all been done. It's
all, most people don't have a say.
It's all written down somewhere and
the mat of people that vote versus the
amount of people that are affected by
that vote. Completely disproportionate.
It's fairly weird, man. It's really weird.
We have a ton of systems that are
set up completely to do two things.
One,
to control people and to,
to ensure the survival of these systems.
And that's what bureaucracy is.
That's a giant problem with government.
Like the Dea.
The DEA wants so badly to keep arresting
people for marijuana because if they
don't, they don't have to shut up.
I'm like, I better not light up.
Perfect timing again. Would you and I are
in sync? Um, what do you mean? Why? Why?
Cause they their jobs, they're
jobs are gonna go away. There's no,
there's plenty of other drugs.
Hold little 46% of all arrests.
They said,
what was the number more people or
arrested today or have been arrested today
for marijuana.
Then all other arrests combined.
You see me smoking,
man,
you want me to the door for the next hour
to hour where I'm like, what is that?
I heard a noise. What are you doing? But
we live in the correct state, right? Yeah.
Tell me I'm right. Well, we're,
we live in several years.
If you're going to scare me. Hmm. Then
throw me of, uh, Dick tickle a little bit.
Like, tell me everything's
gonna be okay. [inaudible] okay.
We're here. Uh, Washington state,
Oregon with the west coast in DC.
Large Smoking section,
Washington DC and Boston now
Massachusetts and my state.
Florida is Lee as medical,
medical, legal. Yeah.
Bunch of medical step though for Florida.
What are the other legal state? Alaska.
Alaska's legal. Fuck Ya'll asco.
So are gangsters to the north,
do you believe the, just not in
love Alaska. Um, Gee Gee, gee,
you believe the theory that as
goes California, so goes the union,
like for years they said if
California goes legal, there you go.
Ah, that's interesting. I think there's
going to be states that resisted still.
There's guys like that, Jeff
Jeff sessions guy who's, um,
coming into office with Trump who's,
who could be an issue,
but I don't think it will be because I
think Trump is a business person. Yeah.
He's a business person. He's not just a
business person. He's a populist. Right.
He's going to, he's going to want
people to like him and you know,
and it doesn't make sense. It's
not a logical move, you know? Wow.
It's weird as he is,
he's not illogical.
Like Hillary Clinton was illogical and
this is why I say that. And people like,
cause I've got a lot of shit from people
that are like Super Pro Hashtag I'm
with her. And I'm like, look man,
she didn't support gay
marriage until 2013.
Do you know how crazy that is?
Until 2013 Hillary Clinton was saying
that she believes that marriage was
between a man and a woman. It was a
sacred union and it should be protected.
So it's one of two things.
Either she actually believed that or she
was in bed with people who were forcing
her to behave that way or say that,
or she thought that she had to
say that in order to get elected.
Did Ordway you're not
getting either way? No. No,
you can't. You can't. You can't be a part
of that. I attended my first gay wedding.
Okay.