I think there's a big
problem with education.
A big problem with the
education that edible marijuana,
as we talked about before,
I think you were in the bathroom,
the 11 hydroxy metabolite is
it's processed by the liver.
It's radically different truck,
radically different,
and it's really a psychedelic in a very,
for me personally,
edible marijuana and flotation tanks,
I might as well be taken a
fucking bucket of assets.
It is crazy God damn experience.
Now,
I personally enjoy being paranoid
and I know this sounds crazy,
but I think with me it gives me an,
I think I live a pretty
blessed life and I like,
I liked the feeling of paranoia because
it allows me to explore maybe some area
like maybe it's just a constant paranoia.
It's a freak out man.
I think I have maybe an
abundance of confidence.
Maybe I have too much, right?
Maybe I'm too successful.
What I like about the paranoia that comes
with edible marijuana is it allows me
to check myself.
It allows me to put myself,
examine all of my behavior in
the darkest recesses of my mind,
my thoughts, and, and gives me a
purpose. And it makes me a nicer person.
It might not go just a little tiny, just
like the other psychedelics with thing.
It just, it gives you just a
little knocks, an ego, just little,
I mean some people use it and like at the
end of the day and then you know, like,
like Joe said,
I think it makes you reflect
sometimes better and more objectively.
Meaning that like,
you know,
maybe you had an encounter with someone
early on the day and then you know,
late at night, maybe you talk up
a bit and you're like, oh man,
I probably should have done things that
a little bit different that, you know,
like that happens to people
all, all the time. It just,
it forces you to reflect
in a different state.
And sometimes when you reflect in that
state, you come up with thoughts that,
that you just went to come up with before.
Yeah.
Like my patients say to me all the time,
like it just kinda breaks this
like negative state that I have.
I'm just able to, to, to, to break out
of a negative state and think logically,
you know, people say that to me all
the time. Let's see. You're, to me,
you're talking about something different
and it works for you. Right? Your, your,
your paranoia is,
it sounds more almost existential.
It's how can I be a better person?
What am I doing wrong in my life?
It's not my wife is poisoning me,
don't you?
No shoe. Like this is funny. Yeah, no,
I understand.
Or you know,
or the cops aren't going to bust through
the fucking door and shoot me different
thing.
And that's why,
that's why Marin marijuana drives
this extreme violence in some people.
Or those people need to get
their fucking shit together.
Well that's possible too.
They may need to go to,
those aren't really coming bro,
but they may need to be intervened before.
And to Joe's point though, they
have shown in studies that, um,
if you make an intervention other
outside of the a psychotic symptoms,
you can actually reduce the
incidence of violence. And also too,
I think it's a good point.
I was going to mention earlier to bring
up genetics because we are teasing out
genetics for people and we are discovering
that certain people do have certain
genetics that do predispose them, uh, to,
to certain cannabis disorders. Right? So,
you know, I'm involved, um, with, with,
with the company that's doing that right
now and we're trying to create, um,
cannabis genetic tests for people,
right.
And there's three genes that
we've identified so far, you know,
and one of them is that
Amy p k 14 genotype,
and that has been shown to
be associated with, um, a, a,
a deficit and brain volume
when you do use cannabis.
And then there's two other genes
that att one and the cad and,
and to genotype.
You know,
both of those have also been shown to
be associated with cannabis. But again,
you know, how many people have them. Um,
BMAP k 14 is roughly about
8% is what we're seeing. Uh,
the Akt one is around 4% and the
cad m two is around is around 5%.
So that's almost 20% of the
population. But, but, but we're seeing,
but if we can identify, um, I love
that stuff. Lion's mane. Yeah,
that's wicked. Um, so if we
can identify, you know, the,
the people who are at risk, then we can
maybe Billy, uh, potentially, you know,
you use the medicine in a way where
only the people who don't have these
genetics are using the
medicine. And then, you know,
for the people who do have these genetics,
you know, they stick mostly to CBD.
I just think, you know, that that's a
better approach than, you know, just,
just Kinda, um, prohibiting cannabis
are saying that we shouldn't,
we shouldn't use it at all,
are saying that it's not medicine.
I think that it should be held to the
same standard as any other medicine.
And I think that if we had an incredible
medicine that worked for some people
and that didn't work for others than what
we would do is we would try to figure
out why. And you know, I, I've been doing
that. My companies have been doing that.
It's called a net life. You know, full
disclosure, I am on the board, um,
and that left at.com and you know,
um,
and when we use these different, uh,
these different strategies, you know,
then we can actually
reduce the overall harm.
And that should be another thing that we
can add into the mix. Because for sure,
there's people who are definitely
more predisposed to mental illness and
definitely more predisposed to,
to a psychosis.