I said, I have mental health
issues. And you know, I said also,
I thought that woman was white
and it wasn't anything about race.
It was about Iran. And it was like, well,
we'll see how this washes
out. Ben Sherman. Yeah,
we'll see how this washes out.
And then 20 minutes later,
Wanda Sykes tweeted,
let me off this show.
And then Sarah Gilbert tweeted
shortly thereafter, uh,
something about she was
ashamed of one cast member.
And, uh, with that one
blew me away. And, uh,
and Michael Fishman tweeted,
uh,
he was ashamed of my racism
or some shit. And, uh,
that was hard to take. But,
uh, it, it's because it was so,
it seemed orchestrated because
they use the same words, you know,
a egregious and forgivable.
But in fact,
it might've been offensive. And like
when I was talking to Mike Today, I said,
you know, we all say things that
are racially insensitive at times.
All of us do that. I'm a Jew.
I've heard everything. And, uh,
you know, or, or ethnically
offensive to somebody.
But that doesn't mean where the KKK,
okay. That doesn't mean we're, uh,
you know,
fascists or you know,
and especially if we apologize
because most people who are offensive,
they mean to be offensive and they don't
apologize. And I think that's when,
you know,
there was a difference.
And if you don't have the discretion to
understand that something's wrong with
you,
and I think something's wrong with
people that they're so hateful and so
unforgiving,
and if you don't vote the way
they think you should vote,
that they feel justified in
being so, um, what's the word?
So sanctimonious and self righteous
and when they themselves are,
you know,
kind of saying far more offensive
things about people's children and such.
For instance,
I think people are just cowards.
And I think when things like this happen,
they want to separate themselves from
controversy and make sure that they're not
a part of that. I can understand
that. I can understand that.
I can kind of understand it, but I don't
get it. But that's what they do, you know?
And you know, I'm like,
wow. They also get really,
really upset when a few years later
somebody does the exact same thing to them
and go,
what goes around comes around,
and that's true and
especially true in Hollywood.
That guide that fired me just was
fired a couple of weeks ago for what?
I don't know. His contract wasn't
renewed and his last words were,
well, I didn't know I'd be forced
to cancel our number one shell.
It wasn't forced to do anything. Well, he
might've been forced. They're all fools.
They should have just, first of all,
they should have let the dust settle.
Second of all,
they should have examined
what you actually said and
what your intentions were
and let you apologize and then have a
conversation with you on one of their
shows in long form,
in a teaching moment,
such as not Valerie Jarrett
would've accepted that. I said,
I would like to debate her on the Iran
deal and explain what I what I said. Well,
even that's not necessary. I mean, look,
the Americans should know about
that deal. Well, maybe they should,
but I don't think that's
completely related to your tweet,
but it would have been a
teachable moment maybe.
But it also would've been a distraction
from what you were trying to say. Well,
they didn't let me say it
right. And, uh, you know, um,
but to get involved like
openly, politically, uh, the
television show dangerous,
but Taylor swift just did it. But what
did she say? Just get out and vote.
But it's really for the Democrat.
Yeah. But though it wasn't that like,
it's almost abstract. Get out
and vote. You know, she's not,
she said vote for the Democrat. I don't
like the Republican. Marsha Blackburn.
She didn't like her.
Although Marsha Blackburn has been the
author of a lot of great anti rape laws
and all kinds of stuff like that,
but she didn't like her because she's
a Republican, says she took a stand,
a political stand, I guess. Uh,
you know, some people can do it,
but some people can't.
And the political stand I took,
which I just want to remind people
is that, um, I'm, I'm an independent.
That's my stance.
And I just thought both sides had gone
too far out and need to talk to each
other.
So I came back and did a show about that.
That's a stance you took with your show
and in my life it's like if we can't
even discuss things that's really,
really bad. That's not American.
We we discuss and debate.
We don't label and blacklist,
which we certainly can talk things and
maybe that's something that you could
have done once they had a conversation
with you about your tweet.
But I mean I just think that what
they did was just very hasty and very
foolhardy and they should have
known who you were beforehand.
They should have known about your
mental health issues. They should know,
they should have known about a medication
issues, all those things they know.
But this is what my point was.
If you have a person with a broken leg
and they can't run and you get mad at him
cause they can't run the,
isn't that ridiculous? Well,
if you have a person that has brain
issues and then they do something that's
erratic and you're mad at him for that,
well you're a fucking idiot.
That's stupid and you,
you,
you call them a racist or chastise them
in front of the world so that you remove
any possible
any,
any possible negative opinions that
could be cast your way when that's what a
lot of it is,
is deflection.
They're worried about negative opinions
and negative feedback that's going to
come their way.
So they immediately turn on you.
They turn on you in a
disproportionate way. Well,
they did cancel the show before
even one advertiser had pulled out.
It reminds me of Sarah Silverman's Bet
I'm for or against it. I remember that.
I'm for or against it. Well,
there's a lot of cowardice going on.
There's a lot of people trying to save
their jobs and people panicked because
people are aware of the outrage
culture that we live in.
This is an outrage nation right now.
It's one of our number one,
the forms of recreation.
People love it.
They love getting mad at
whoever the fuck it is.
As long as you react the way they
want you to react. Ooh, they love it.
It's an inquisition. Well, it's,
it's the understanding that people
have way more power to affect change.
Whether it's good change or bad change.
They're pushing buttons with social
media and with outrage and with their
ability to express themselves.
It's unprecedented.
There's never been a time like this in
history where people can Salem witch
trials. Right. Well that
was just like, okay,
well if you swam that proves you're a
witch and then we have to drown you.
There's no, it's no, uh, it, it
has said there has to be a loser.
There has to be the two
winners. Well, there,
there has to be an understanding
of what's happening here.
And then people have to
have an understanding of the
power that they're wielding
and what they're doing and did it turn
back on them and it just never just stop
at line person.
That's why I said I'm surprised that a
lot more comics didn't defend me because
you know,
this means that anything they find
in your timeline that they think is
offensive,
they can mischaracterize and bring a
whole a battle against you that you can't
possibly win and take your life's
work. Well, how many did defend you?
Um, nobody defended me, but I did.
You did. Thank you Stan. Hope.
Did I stand hope dead? Yeah. Um,
there was [inaudible] that
we're working with. No,
none of them that worked with
you. Well, everybody that works,
you wanted to keep their job. Yeah. And
I don't blame them. I don't blame them.
They pray, you know, needed the money
and probably already spent it. Well,
the other thing too,
the Sitcom life that,
that fucking schedule is ruthless.
It's great. You know what?
I think it was a lot of it was, um, you
know, I gave him the gun to shoot me.
I mean,
I wasn't a helpless victim,
although I think my explanation,
you either make sense or
doesn't make sense, but uh,
well if you're compassionate
it makes sense. But a lot
of people aren't. But, um,
you know, uh, I forgot what I was getting.
I don't even know if they're
not compassionate. Roseanne.
I think they're scared,
I think to just chicken shit.
I don't think they're looking
at it from an in terms of like,
I can't win here and I can't lose here.
Let me just look at what's right. See,
I didn't have anything to win or lose.
So what I looked at it,
I looked at you as someone that I admire.
Some of that I think is one of the best
comics ever who I think I know that you
have mental health issues.
I knew from talking to you that you were
on Ambien and I knew you had alcohol as
well. I know that does.
My mom took ambien.
She woke up in the middle of the night
and drew all over the bathroom rug,
drew over it with lipstick and,
and, and um, and nail Polish.
She said like a little kid. So
Shit, you woke up in the morning.
She had no idea she did
it. She's terrified of that
shit. She won't take it now.
I have many friends, many friends that
have had bad experiences on amputee too.
And I thought, well they shouldn't have
shut down that conversation like that.
They shouldn't have.
It's a fucking dangerous drug to for the
wrong people in the wrong situations.
Especially when you mix,
mix it with alcohol.
I mean it's beneficial to people that
need sleep in certain situations.
I don't recommend it, I don't take it,
but some people like it, that's fine.
But to ignore what the
actual pharmacological effect
on the human body is is
ridiculous because there's studies on
this shit and that people understand the
interaction between chemicals and the
human brain and there are erratic and
especially when you mix them with things
you're not supposed to mix them with.
Weird Shit happens.
I thought it was going to,
I thought I was going to expand on
it in the morning and uh, you know,
talk about that movie and uh,
too late.
It's too late. It put the whole
thing is just fucking crazy. When,
when was telling me not to tweet.
Yeah. Well, it's probably a good idea.
But now honestly the,
the problem also at Twitter is fucking
text is just too, it's too simple.
It's too crude a way of
communicating. It really is. I mean,
you can get across some
ideas. Like you can say, hey,
I went to see little foot's a great movie.
That's a good thing to tweet.
Real simple shit like that.
But I don't want to talk about like
political things or things that involve
nuance or seeing things that are complex.
I just don't think it's the way
to communicate any more. No,
it's terrible way to communicate, you
know? And I think it's not communicate.
It's like a, what did he say?
A search and destroy. Well,
for some folks, yeah, people,
well there's gonna be people that always
want to make things crash and burn.
They like it. They like like buttons.
They like hitting the buttons.
They like to see people suffer. Well,
they definitely are suffering themselves.
Look, there's a giant percentage of
our population that lives in misery.
I know they do all day long and
they have mental health issues.
They're exhausted, they're depressed,
they're there. They have despair,
they're overwhelmed with bills,
they're in shitty relationships,
they're overwhelmed and they're angry
and they look at someone like you,
a rich white lady, and like fuck that
bitch. And they just want to attack you.
And it doesn't have to make sense
because it's a reflection of their own
personal pain as much as it's a reflection
of their irresponsibility with this
power that they're wielding
through social media.
And then there's the mob mentality
cause a bunch of people that are already
going after you. Good. I'm
going to go after her too.
I'm going to show the world that I'm not
racist and you know how I'm going to do
that. I'm going to shit all over
this racist, this racist Roseanne.
They don't care if you're really racist.