Hello Freak bitches.
He was willing to keep the MOOC.
I mean the MOOC.
The butchers only ousted because of John
Kelly and the Mooc is what did the MOOC
say? What was his, I was about Batman
and sucking his own cock. Yeah,
that's exactly right.
About him performing.
Why would he think that he could say
that once he's in the office? I mean,
first of all, I was thinking to see band
and could even possibly do that. I mean,
Ban is not that flexible. I
know Steve, that's, that's not,
that's not something gets repertoire
a giant unit, but it doesn't matter.
Just the idea that he would think,
I mean he must be emboldened by the fact
that Trump has said so many outrageous
things. I mean their reports
from the New York Post that,
that he actually had the Trump liked it.
Then all that happened is that there
was so much blow back that he had to
replace Kelly. You need puts Kelly in
there and Kelly's like, you can't do this.
And Trump's like, okay, fine,
but doesn't it seem more crazy
to fire a guy after 10 days?
And it does to sit him down and
say, hey man, don't say that again.
Let's move forward. That's what
they should've done the next day.
But the problem is he'd been doing
it for a week at that point, right.
He was out there like saying that writes
previous was leaking on the president
and was an enemy of the president for a
week and you're saying that he was going
to get him fired and at the same time,
remember this is the same week that Trump
himself is tweeting out that attorney
general sessions who is his most loyal
supporter for a year and a half that that
guy has like a trader and that he
wishes he would go away cause he recused
himself. First of all, Trump can
fire any of these people at any time.
Like this is very passive aggressive for
a guy who made his living saying you're
fired on TV.
It's amazing that all the people that
Trump has fire had been fired actually
through surrogates.
Mike Flynn resigned and James Comey was
fired basically through Rod Rosenstein
and sessions.
And then Rosenstein had recused himself,
which is how you get the special counsel
and Comi found out on television. TV.
Right. He's just like an
emissary to go to La and,
and give him a letter and like everyone
he fires it has to be fired in the most
roundabout. I think that Trump actually
this, I think the dirty little secrets,
I'm not sure Trump actually likes
firing people. I think, I think he,
I think he kinda like towards,
I think he likes torturing people,
but I'm not sure that he
actually likes firing them.
Well he maybe doesn't like people
being mad at him face to face it.
I think that's a, wants them to
love him in front of his face.
So like when he's not there, you know,
you can make a phone call, fire him,
hang up the phone and you don't have to
actually see the guy you w wants that
guy that liked him.
Yeah,
I don't to call me thing was really
bizarre because it was like, oh,
you can do that.
Like there's this guy is looking into
improprieties and you can just say,
no, you can't do that
anymore. You're fired.
You can't look into the things I've
done wrong. Yeah, it was. Well,
the way he did it was the stupid part.
So I was calling for coming
to be fired since last year.
I thought the way he handled the whole
Hillary thing from beginning to end was
terrible. I thought that Trump should
have replaced him before he became,
you know, as basically day one, here's my
new cabinet. Call me. You did a great job.
You know, usher him out the
door, bringing somebody new.
He kept him around and then the first
thing he said to call me, you remember,
was when he met him, he said,
you're more famous than I am. Well,
when Trump says that to you, that's
the writing on the wall right there.
First of all, it's not
true, but second of all,
I think maybe there was also a part of
the problem was [inaudible] is a giant.
Yes. You know the chunk colonies will,
but what is he, six eight six eight six,
nine yes. Giant dude. Towered over.
Traffic is such a comedy and comb.
He Sang, he was trying to hide in
the curtains. It was wide Trump.
So you just see Herman Munster
over there hiding and the goons.
It's weird. Now. What did you enjoy,
Michelle? I mean it's, it's if,
if I didn't think that
nuclear war was a possibility,
but if I see a fucking Korean missile
headed our way, I'm going to be pissed.
When Colby was handling the email thing,
what specifically did
you not like about it?
What I thought it was was crazy was when
he restarted a reopen the case because
of whom?
A having used her clean shoes,
wieners all that stuff. I was like,
that's not enough. Like that seems crazy.
The deleting the emails to me seemed
like I had Mike Baker on from the CIA and
he said essentially anyone else would
be in jail for what she did. For sure.
For sure. Sure. Right. Well, call me.
He screwed it up and then
he really screwed it up.
So when he originally said publicly,
we're not going to
prosecute Hillary Clinton,
he was doing something he
didn't have the authority to do.
The FBI has not decided
whether to prosecute people.
They refer the information to the DOJ
and then the DOJ decides whether to
prosecute people.
It was Attorney General,
Loretta Lynch's decision whether to
prosecute or not. The statute itself, man,
I'm a lawyer.
The statute itself did not say,
do you have intent to commit espionage?
Do you have intent to,
to to make classified secrets public or
expose them to the possibility of being
made public intent is not an element
of the crime. Right? If you do it,
it's a crime.
So my wife as it,
I should a doctor and that means
that she is under HIPAA requirements.
There's no element under HIPPA that
says that if she reveals somebody's,
you know, proprietary medical information
by accident, well there's no intent.
So she's okay.
That's not part of the statute.
If she brings some of these medical
records out to her car and somebody steals
the medical records, you know, she's
working at the VA or something,
that's a crime.
It doesn't matter if she intended to
do it and just left it in her purse.
So Komi read the element of intense
into the crime to get Hillary off.
And then he said, okay, we're
not going to prosecute this.
We're going to leave it
alone. He shouldn't have
intervened in the first place.
Remember he made an entire case basically
for why she should be prosecuted and
then at the end he goes, but we're, you
know, but no, we're not going to do that.
He also said, we're going to keep Congress
updated on any future development.
Well you get to October and
there's a future development.
They found this laptop with all sorts of
information on it with new emails from
Hillary Clinton that
they haven't seen before.
And now he has an obligation to inform
Congress because he told them that he
would.
And so he screwed the pooch again because
he's afraid that if he doesn't reveal
that information, Hillary goes on
to win. And then it comes out there,
something criminal.
Then people are willing to blame him for
Hillary winning and putting a criminal
and the White House. So instead he said,
oh, well I'll be fully transparent.
I have to honor my institution. I'm
going to put this out there. Of course,
then Hillary loses and now he screwed
up twice and then he gets into the White
House and now he's supposed
to be investigating the
Trump Russia stuff at the
same time.
So now he's investigating basically
both candidates in the 2016 election.
He handled this the wrong way every step
of the way because he was so focused on
what will uphold thee in of the integrity
of the FBI and the integrity of,
of the investigations and the integrity
of the DOJ. He was less worried about,
okay, what do I actually
have to do under the law?
What's my obligation under the law is
obligation under the law as to shut his
pie hole and the
information over to lunch.
If Lynch wanted to kill the investigation,
let her do it.
So in a sense Trump was right and saying
that he's a grandstander. Yeah, for sure.
I mean,
I think that part was right,
but that the problem remember
was not the firing of Comey.
It was the two days after he fired Comey,
he went to Lester Holt on NBC and he said,
the reason I fired Comey was not all
the excuses I gave about the the Hillary
stuff.
It's because of the Russia stuff.
I was angry about how he
was handling Russia. I mean,
that's really stupid. That's intensely
stupid. It's intensely stupid.
But it's also strange that it didn't
go anywhere. Right? Like that.
Was it like that? That's against the law.
Well it's so it's, you know, obstruction.
So obstruction,
looking at the statutes obstruction
is a little bit more than that.
So you have to actually obstruct
an ongoing investigation
into criminal activity.
There's a counter intelligence
investigation going on,
but not necessarily criminal one.
So not to get too specific about it,
but you should get specific about it.
Yeah, I mean the obstruction laws,
I mean I've looked into kind of the
statutes that they've used to suggest
obstruction.
And it's not clear that there's any
statute that specifically govern something
like this.
Plus it is true that Trump does have the
power as the chief executive to fire as
the commander in chief to fire the FBI
director for any reason he chooses. Now,
all that said, he can be impeached for any
reason, criminal or noncriminal, right?
Impeachment is not a,
you don't actually have to have
committed a crime to be impeached, right.
Most people don't even
understand what a peach means.
They think that some are another impeach
means that you kicked out of office,
right? That's not right. It is.
There's the house and they
have to vote to impeach you,
and then there's the senate and they have
to vote by a two thirds majority or 68
yeah.
I think it's two thirds
majority to actually convict
you of a set of crimes that
they come up with, but these are
all political definitions, right?
When it says high crimes and misdemeanors,
it doesn't mean they actually have
to prosecute you like they would in a
criminal court and you'd have to go
to jail or any of that kind of stuff.
Like they could impeach
anybody at any time.
Clinton didn't even have to commit
perjury if they didn't want,
if they wanted to impeach them,
they could.
They could have peach w every president
you can impeach. It's just a vote.
It's just about, so all the talk about
what's criminal and what's not criminal.
The problem for Trump,
there are two ways of reading Trump's
behavior in the whole Russia thing, right?
Way. One is he's got something to hide
and that's the most obvious way he's got
something to hide.
That's why he gets rid of Flynn.
We don't know why he got rid of Flynn.
He gets rid of Comey.
We don't really know why he got rid of
Comey and then brags to the Russians that
it's a pressure off him on the Russia
stuff. Yeah. So it's a way, one is,
he's hiding something and now he's
firing everybody who gets in the way.
And there's, you know, the
chain of evidence doesn't not
fit that. I mean, you know,
he, he's the people he's anchor. Yet in
order, our attorney general sessions,
the Deputy Attorney General Rod
Rosenstein, the former head of the FBI,
James Comey, the acting head
of the FBI McCabe, uh, and uh,
and the special prosecutor Robert Mueller.
So those are all people
involved with Russia.
Those are the only people
he's really angry at.
So there's something to be said for
the idea that maybe he's trying to hide
something.
On the other hand,
we haven't actually seen any hard
evidence of collusion itself.
So we saw an attempt to
collude by Donald Trump jr,
but we haven't actually seen any
evidence that the Russians were providing
special information to
the Trump administration,
which was then being weaponized
for use in the campaign.
We haven't seen any of that stuff.
So here's the other plausible theory,
and this goes to Trump's personality.
He's so petty and he wants to be loved
so much that he is angry that people keep
saying he run because he
won because of the Russians.
And so now every time people say that,
he just gets pissed and he fires people.
So Komi I mean this is totally plausible,
right?
Komi comes to him and has said privately
that you are not under investigation.
And Trump says to him, well why don't
you just say that and call me says,
well I can't say that cause if I say that
I'm going to have to update congress.
If you do fall under investigation
and Trump doesn't like that,
he wants the public to
know he's free and clear.
So if fires coming and then
he goes up public and he says,
I didn't like how he was handling
the Russia thing, I'm innocent.
Why won't these people leave
me alone? Right. So he is.
So there's two ways to read this.
Either he's totally innocent but stupid
or he's trying to hide something.
Those are the only two plausible
ways of reading the situation.
The Donald Trump junior thing was really
bizarre because he released all the
emails. Like I just, yeah, it's
like, look, I've got nothing to hide.
Like you aren't supposed to
do any of these things you're
saying in these emails.
Yes. That was, it does not a good moment
for, for Trump. Jr Do you think he got,
I mean, and then you hear that he was
coached by his dad again, you know this,
none of this is good stuff. I had that
thing that Donald Trump jr releasing the,
first of all, it is imperative
to note eight minutes later,
the New York Times released
basically the email chain, right?
So he was meeting his, beating it out of
the gate. And so he puts that out there,
which was a smart move. I mean
it, it would be smart if you,
it'd be smart if he had found
a way to spin it, right? Right.
Like if you had done it,
if he had done,
this is the thing in politics and now
the way politics works now is your
smartest move.
If there's dirt about you is to be the
first person out the gate with it and you
put a spin on it, right?
So like Barack Obama,
imagine if Obama hadn't said anything
in 2008 and then we found out a week
before the election that
he did coke in high school.
Now a lot of people wouldn't care. A lot
of people would write in 2000 George W.
Bush was hit with a DUI charge from like
1973 and it probably lost him a point
in the polls.
So what Obama did is he wrote an entire
memoir and he just kind of dismissed it
right in the middle of an he goes,
you know, when I was in high school,
did a little blow, no problem.
Did a little blow. Everybody
would. And Everyone, oh,
okay. Did low blow. All
right. You know, cool.
So if you're going to release this kind
of stuff, you have to put a spin on,
it trumps in your,
didn't he just put out the emails and
the emails themselves contain the damning
material, right? It says right in there,
there's a Russian government lawyer,
the Russian government sees this as
part of its effort to aid Mr Trump's
campaign. And Donald Jr is like, thumbs
up guys. I love it. Sounds awesome. Right?
And so that does not look good.
It's not quite as much as you know.
People on the left want to say it as
meaning that there's no evidence yet that
any information was actually exchanged
with the Russians or that anything came
to the meeting. Most of the people in the
meeting who have said something, it's,
and nothing came of it,
you know?
But we don't know whether
Trump knew about the meeting.
I find it kind of hard to
believe he didn't, you know,
considering every major campaign
figure was there but, but you know,
then then they, then they
just keep lying. And this is,
this is the part that's proud.
That's a problem.
Are they whining because they just think
they can get away with it and they're
stupid or they're lying because they're
actually being meticulous about their
lies. You know, I tend
to think the former,
because this isn't a
professional administration.
I think these, I think Trump,
you know, fibs a lot. He says things
that, I mean, like on stupid things.
He says things like,
the leader of the boy scouts called me
and told me that he loved my specialist
and then the leader of the boy
scouts, like, uh, what? So if it,
so is that a calculated lie to hide
something or is it just the Trump lies by
nature and so he does it a lot? Well, I
think he's just so used to putting that,
that spin on things that publicity spin.
Right.
And the thing that he said about this
was that this is what politics does.
What happens in politics.
You get dirt about your enemy
and people exchange information.
It's just what happens. It's just you're
seeing it now. So a lot of people like,
yeah, well that makes sense. Right?
And, and this is something that, again,
I think that were shaped by Hollywood
a little bit. Politics is dirty,
but some of this stuff is not usual.
Right?
It's actually not particularly usual to
meet with a government that is really
not friendly to the United States to
receive information about your political
opponents. But if you've watched
house of cards, you think, well,
I mean it's like two steps down from
throwing somebody under the subway. So he,
the big deal cards. Uh, I don't,
because I work in politics
and when I go home at night,
the last thing I want to do is watch
entertainment about politics. Now,
watch game of Thrones.
That's his political
Gotcha.
[inaudible].