Happen. The Joe Rogan experience.
Do you a I used to live in, in La.
Where are you at now? I moved back
to Hickory, North Carolina. Damn.
I was out here 18 years. Just
couldn't do it anymore. No,
well it was a couple things.
You know,
my career has always been like a roller
coaster and good years, bad years. And um,
I actually just add miss, I miss
my family. I haven't, you know,
I missed out on a lot growing up, you
know, so, and the market was really good.
I had this condo in studio city.
I bought it for a certain amount and
then it's, it's, it gained value.
And I thought, well, this
is, if I'm going to do this,
now's the time to pull the trigger.
And I think I saw you at the,
I'm probably not saying I'm Outta
here. I'm bouncing and I, uh, my goal,
the road so much. Right? Yeah.
Well that's the thing too.
And the industry's
changed. Like, you know,
I already have a manager and an agent.
It's not like I need to be here for
every little audition, you know, I'll,
I'll put myself on tape.
I got eastbound and down on a tape,
I got Harold and Kumar on a
tape, you know, and then now
the second audition, yeah.
You flop for it. But like,
you know, getting your foot
in the door to that tape.
But I can do that now later.
It's just changed so much.
That's if you want to act and you
do so much stand up on the road,
there's really no reason to be here unless
you just want to perform at the store
all the time. That's
right. Yeah. Yeah. So, uh,
and I moved back to Hickory and I was
going to get myself a nice lake house in
Lake Hickory. Yup. Still want to do that.
But then as soon as I get home, you know,
thanksgiving dad has a stroke.
So I see that happen that you ever seen
someone who had a stroke there when an
APP, I was looking right at him and it
was weird because my dad's a funny guy.
Like I thought maybe because we were
going to eat Thanksgiving dinner late,
like it was like a 6:00 PM thing we were
doing to get other people in the house.
And so he was complaining all day about
not eating like I'm hungry. We were,
we were, we going to eat,
we're not going to eat.
And I'm looking around anatomy sitting
next to the fireplace and he just like,
he just like nose dives but just head
first right into the hardwood floor.
And it was like pumped. You hear
like a thump. And I was like, Oh,
dad's making a joke. We haven't
eaten yet. It's a, you know,
he's making the thing about like
a low blood sugar or something.
And I was kind of laughing at my
brother's like, no, he hit really hard.
His head hit that floor way
too hard for that to be a jug.
And then you walk over to him and arms
curling up one eyes going like that and
it's like, this is a stroke. And we called
nine one one they came pretty quick,
but they suffered some serious brain
damage right here. And so he's paralyzed.
Was left side now,
but I was in a weird way,
happy that I was at home
when this happened because
you know how was still out
here and that should happen.
Right? Be Be hating life. Yeah.
But the fact that I'm there and
able to help mom out, you know,
going through it all of this,
this whole thing,
because she's got glaucoma and
she's got brittle bones, you know,
she can't physically
lift him up and do stuff.
And the fact that we were in the
house and able to help, it's crazy.
It was, I didn't see the drooping of the
face. I didn't see that happen. You know,
that's what people say when you see a
stroke. You see like the drooping happens.
Yeah. Like that, that fat
chicken total recall. You know,
let's see. We're at explodes.
Get rid of her. I was surprise.
I thought that I thought
that that was why it was,
but no,
he just hit the floor.
So have you toured it all since that or
have you just been small places? I can.
I didn't take on extra gigs. I,
but I didn't cancel the ones I had.
So the ones that I could drive
to definitely as well. Let me go.
I have a brother who's
there as well, so, um,
but I definitely didn't take
on anything for, you know,
since Thanksgiving that
wasn't already there. So yeah,
it's uh,
but he's,
he's at a skilled nursing facility now
and they showed us the X. Right. You know,
the, the, the Mri of the brain damage
that happened, he had a collided artery.
He's got,
now he's keeps getting UTI infections
because he has a catheter because it also,
it doesn't just fuck with your muscles.
It's the organs on that side too.
So his bladder has got to
relearn how to operate.
So he's got a catheter,
you know, and that,
that that's just opens you up for
Uti infections a lot. And those,
I don't know if you know, they're
like Uti infections when you're older.
Like it really devastates you, cause you,
you hallucinate. So you see shit. Oh No.
Yeah. And it's weird being in there
and you know, he would like, uh,
I make sure that bears don't out there.
I'm like a bear,
like he keeps hearing or think there's
a bear outside the window. So yeah.
That, that was happening
back home for that. But um,
are there bears where you live? Not, no,
not, not the skilled nursing facility.
I mean, there might be some
tweaks. Yeah, no bears.
I allowed to say twink trouble.
He used to be able to just
make a joke about that. What's
dangerous? Yes. Yeah. No,
but uh, yeah. Hoping for the best. Still
going through Rehab, occupational therapy,
physical therapy.
Do they think that he'll be able to
recover some function on this left side?
I think you know,
that they always want to get dangle a
little bit of light of hope at the end of
the talk. I'll Chase's but uh, you know,
some people recover quickly,
some people not at all.
Some people three years later can
recover. You need a, here you go. Yeah.
Three years later. I mean,
you know, so we're just still,
we're still doing all of it.
John Singleton just died from a stroke.
That's Rad Shit. Yeah. And
he was, was 51 51. Yeah.
It can happen to anybody at any age.
Luke Perry, same thing. 51 stroke.
That's right. Yup. Yeah. Crazy. The
lot of strokes or happened. Fuck man.
I wonder if those folks smoked cigarettes.
Well, my dad definitely did. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. They send in cigarettes,
contribute pretty heavily to strokes.
He used to smoke a lot when he was
younger and then quit, you know,
when he was in his late forties.
Um, but that was a lot, you know,
in fact in where you'd smoke at 12
years old or something, a whole pack.
I don't know if singleton smoked, but
I do know Luke Perry did. Yeah. Yeah.
And this woman that I talked
to who is a neurologist,
was telling me that that's
a significant factor.
It raises your chances of stroke
pretty significantly. Yeah.
So I'm back in here, cream, but I came,
I'm going to come my
ideas to come out here.
You know how that season
keep doing it, right? Yeah.
Right. And then hit the store.
I was there last night was fun. It was
good seeing you, man. You too, man.