That was a Turd, Megan. Another one? No,
I think it might've been John Wick or
they're going to be doing a third one of
course at 200 right on WIC. Yeah.
Yeah. He got killed. I repeat.
He was in was an awesome movie.
I think they changed the name of,
but I don't think that's what it
was originally called. But you know,
we have to keep redoing the scene.
He goes back and they ended
up like killing everyone.
What's my anatomy tomorrow? That movie
the day after tomorrow. Oh right.
Wasn't that the name style? Remember
we used to be called kill, die,
repeat edge of tomorrow. Edge
of tomorrow. That's right.
That movie was fucking bad ass.
That was a reasonably solid,
really good science fiction movie.
But it was one of the ones that came out.
What year did it come out in?
14 2014 was just a few years removed
from him being wacky when he did that.
Uh, Matt Lauer interview on the today show
where it was like you being Glib, Matt,
you're being Glib.
What he's talking about.
Brooke Shields taking psychiatric
medication, and I understand this.
Scientology is highly critical
of psychiatric meditation.
They prefer you stay crazy. They don't,
they don't know what medication out. Matt,
have you done the research? I've done the
research. You're Glib, man. You're Glib,
but Lowery didn't handle it that good
either. Now you're supposed to go.
We'll explain to me the mechanism of the
what's happening with the psychiatric
drugs and what do you pose?
Yeah,
and why do you think that you understand
the biological makeup of all these
different human beings and that none
of them should be taking psychiatric
medication?
Yeah.
That's a crazy thing to say that you're
smarter than all these biologists and
medical scientists and all these people
that have concocted these SSRI is and
different. Have you done
the research? Have you done,
you've done the research or you
Glib or making topcon too right now.
Did you ever tell you the first time
I did Letterman when Cruz was on it?
Did I ever tell you that story? No.
I was doing my first letter, man.
I'm super nervous and I'm just
trying to tell myself, you know,
just like any other show, it's just
like any other show, right? Tom Cruise.
It's his first time.
He's on the show and like 10 years,
15 years and he's on and I'm
watching through the monitoring,
he's running up and down the uh, he's
running up and down the hallway there,
the theater, like saying hi to people at
during the break. Yeah. He's like, hey.
And he's like running up and down and
having the screen time. Like it's just,
it's just another shoulder.
It will, it'll be okay.
And then they bring you down stairs
and you're standing outside this door,
like to go onto the stage and he says
good night during the show and he,
the door swings open and a very sweaty,
Tom cruise is like nose to nose
with me and he's like, you're next.
And he hugs me. He's like,
whew, it's great out there.
And it goes bouncing up the
stairs and I'm like, oh,
what's going to happen to me out?
This is terrifying.
He totally took all of my coolness
and just chew on a strange guy.
Yeah, but the energy just, he was like
all an electric eel and I'm just like,
it's all right. I can get
through this. Be such a strange,
strange guy when he into that,
like I'm laughing.
Thing is just gets weird.
Well,
it's funny now.
It wasn't such a high altitude
that it would have to know.
Sure. That guy's death.
Three
standing in the wings right now.
What are you thinking?
Like what am I going to save first?
Yeah, just I think with those things,
those things are such a little
weird sprint. How's my tie?
How's my tie? Right? What's my
first line? What am I going to say?
Did I go out casual? Yeah. Gets it.
There's a heated interview for Matt Lauer.
Play that. It's right there. I was
coming up next. Here it is. Here's Matt.
Matt had a full head of hair
back then. Yeah, we'll get back.
He's got all that hair in 2014 I'm
looking at my handsome bastard.
It was radio play was my first exposure
to this story. Just an alien movie.
Th th the story breaks down on a lot of
different levels and in one each other
already. Yeah. Not the best father
in the world. When we are working on,
on the story, originally, three years ago,
Steve and I came up with this idea
of making it amount of family.
It's okay. That was a good
movie. Love Dot. Yeah, me too.
Okay. You go ahead and want to
go inside. Of course you'd do it.
That real sense of like, where
are we going to go? Well,
that's what I think it would probably
be like if we did get invaded two,
there'll be robots like that.
Yeah. That'll be cool. Yeah.
Play some of that. Before
I was a scientologist, I
never agreed with psychiatry.
And then when I started studying
the history of psychiatry,
I started realizing more and more
why I didn't agree with psychiatry.
And as far as the Brooke shields
thing, he's, look, yeah, I understand.
I really care about Brooke Shields.
I was a wonderful and talented woman
and uh,
I want to see her do well.
And I know that a psychiatry is,
it's a pseudoscience,
but Tom,
if she said that this particular
thing helped her feel better,
whether it was the antidepressant or
going to a counselor or a psychiatrist,
isn't that enough?
You have to understand this.
Here we are today when I talk out
against drugs and psychiatric abuses of
electric shocking people against their
will of drugging children with them not
knowing it's good, good, good effects of
these drugs. Do you know what Adderall is?
Do you know Redland? Do you know
now that Ritalin is a street drug?
Do you understand that the differences,
and this was not a matter of mathematics,
wasn't addressing your question,
Matt, I'm asking a question.
Abuse of all of these. Now
you see, here's the problem.
You don't know the history of psychiatry.
I do.
Aren't there examples in my book,
shields being an example of someone
who benefited from one of those drugs?
All it does is mask the problem, Matt,
and if you understand the history of it,
it masks the problem. That's what it
does. He is pretty aggressive. Yeah,
you're not getting to,
it wasn't being shitty thing.
He said it's like intense on balance
while he's right about a lot of it.
He's definitely right about Adderall and
Ritalin that some people would abuse it
but abuse.
Just because someone abuses it
doesn't mean it doesn't have uses.
You know it doesn't,
I don't.
I've met people that are on
Adderall and they say they need it.
I don't know if they're right.
Yeah.
But the guy who developed Adderall
says that it should be, uh,
for about 4% of the population.
That's a lot like a four people out of
a hundred and a room full of a hundred
people.
Four of them are cranked out and doctors
are cranking it out like 30% patients.
They say, yeah, it's
like super high that he,
the guy who made it said it's
being abused. Well, I'm sure it is.
And Amongst Journal, if you've done the
research, Jo, have you done the research?
Well, I know I understand about
it. I understand. I understand.
But he's right about little kids
and Ritalin and I had a neighbor,
they drug their kid up the
fucking Ritalin. It was
weird and wrong with the kid.
He just had energy and the
parents were working all the time.
They just didn't want to deal with
it. Put the kid on Ritalin. Terrible.
They were bad parents. That's terrible.
It was. I was watching it happen.
I was like, whoa. And then
they, they zoned the kid out.
They got him on some shit
and he was just like,
like a weird little Zombie kid after that.
Oh Man. Say Hi to him. He's like, hi.
Oh my God. It's terrible. It was,
we could have been an artist.
It could have been something great.
Take it away from him.
You put a kid in a classroom and you
make them listen to boring shit all day.
They don't want to do it. You think, well
there's something wrong with this child.