Try My day,
Joe Rogan podcast by night all day.
But for people that don't know what
we're going to about to be talking about,
you had one of the most horrific injuries,
streaks in the sport in your prime,
you know,
you were considered to be one of the top
pound for pound fighters in the world
and then you had a series of
catastrophic injuries and surgeries.
So for this is for a lot of people
listen to his podcast and aren't really
hardcore MMA fans.
That makes so you like talk us through
it because you went through like one of
the most difficult trials in terms
of recovery from injury. Any, no,
the most difficult I've ever seen anybody
go through in the entire history of my
time of colon fights.
Well for fighting.
I definitely agree in the sport of then
it fell off cause I researched him.
Oh okay.
These guys who went through three ACL
reconstructions came back and compete it
and one of them was just competing.
Uh Oh.
They almost made it to the Superbowl and
he had three ACL reconstructions in the
game of football and came back,
was still playing and he was like over
there over 30 miles and people like that
need to be around in this world. Sure.
Just to let you know that it's possible,
you know that it can be done and
now it's kind of what I what gay.
That mindset right there when you make
it bigger than yourself is the only way
you get the power to get through stuff
like that and that's what got me through
is understanding that I go through
this, these knees, surgeries, I I,
I become, it becomes bigger than
me when I come back and succeed.
It's not just about me coming back
and get my belt. I already had belts.
I already knew what it felt like to be a
five time world champion. By that point,
at the age of 26 before I blew my
knee out, I was on top of everything.
I had everything that I thought I
needed and wanted, blew my knee out,
get my belt stripped,
go through three ACL reconstructions.
You soon find out that you
actually have no idea who you are,
what, no. What was the
initial injury? Uh, ACL, MCL.
What, what, what happened though?
I was a training while I was getting ready
and the ultimate fighter back in 2012
or 11 for Faber fight. We're getting
ready to compete at the end of the show.
And I was training with a guy and it was
just a hard week. I mean we're, we're,
we were the first show that ever went
live and was training for the fight at the
same time. Uh, being tough.
We're the only first and
only live show that they did.
So that meant that Lao we coached,
we were also going to
compete at the same time.
So like I had to do my fight camp while
I trained the ultimate fighter guys
simultaneously.
So I was doing four practices a day,
two at the tough guys and two with myself.
And that work load was just insane.
That was a hard heart training camp
and ended up breaking me down, um,
hurt my knee,
just sparring.
It was a spine day guy went for grappling
transition and my and a Sagd on my hip.
Weird and just blew my
knee out a crappy takedown.
You know where they sag
instead of actually get the
take down and it just blew
my knee out. When I blew my ACL MCL,
I was. I was like, it's all right.
You'll be fine. I fought it. I almost
literally fought the injury like,
you're too tough. You're too strong.
You're too young. You can do this.
Let's go fuck the injury. Meaning
not get surgery and try to rehab it.
You just heard what I just said,
like it didn't mentally right.
Did the surgery I did. That wasn't
the problem though. That's my point.
The problem isn't if you're doing
all the things right to get better.
It's understanding that it
was understanding that I
didn't need to fight to be
better
giving up on it was when I
finally got better understanding.
I didn't need fighting to be who I was.
When you say get better,
you mean get better emotionally,
psychologically walk physically,
even physically. Physically. I didn't.
I did not get better until I
gave up on fighting the injury.
And what I mean by fighting the
injuries saying it's, you'll be fine.
You'll come back, just keep training, keep
training, keep training, keep training.
And I, and I trained, but in the, in the,
the logic that I was given with my,
uh,
with what I'm allowed to do according to
my physical therapist, Gavin Macmillan,
he would say, you can do this, this and
this. Don't push it. I wouldn't push it.
I would do the things aloud, but I'm
telling you, like that wasn't the issue.
The issue was surrendering the f the,
the issue is knowing that fighting was
the only way I was going to be happy then
it was being able to compete with
the only way I could find peace.
Being able to prove that I
was as good as I always was,
even after the injuries became
everything that I was trying to do. Um,
it, it was just a nonstop
fight to just get healthy.
And I get through my second
ACL reconstruction on the
same knee and then I blow
my quad out before I was
supposed to fight him.
How did you blow out the second one?
You had the injury,
you had a reconstructed and then
how do you blow out the second one?
It's the same knee and I was training
on Christmas how many months after the
initial surgery? Six. So it's real
reason. It's probably not 100% healed yet.
It's not 100% healed yet.
Nine months is supposed to be full,
full strength,
but that,
but six months is when you get to
start pushing it to get ready to fall.
So now you're like six
months to six months.
You're not allowed to do any kind of
cutting Connie meaning lateral movements
just straight down the line. No,
nothing risky. Uh, keep your brace on.
When you trained out in a six month
mark, they're like, take the brace off.
You've got to start getting
the stabilizers strong.
You can start testing it more.
You can start doing things,
but you still got to where, where
your brace when you do live scenarios.
But you can drill without it.
You can, you see what I'm saying?
So you're actually pretty strong,
but now it's supposed to be strong
enough that it's not going to tear.
But that's when I had a cadaver ACL.
So it wasn't as strong as it should have
been at that, at that six month point,
because it was cadaver tissue.
My Body did not adapt to the
tissue as well as it could have.
So do they do an Mri to see where it's
at or did they just kind of base it on
how it feels?
They base it on the endpoint and the
stability of your knee and they manipulate
it when they manipulate it.
At the six month mark,
you're going in every two to three weeks
for six months to double check with the
doc. I've had to have a
two reconstructions. Well,
I was doing that at Kerlan and Jobe and
they were good doctors and they tried to
stay on me, you know? Um, so
you've had two. So, you know,
and you know at the six month mark it's
like you can push it but you don't want
to overkill it cause you to tear it. So
the second one, I wasn't over killing it,
but I was doing what I was
allowed in my brace and I made it,
I made a cut like a turn and
it just popped it just like,
it wasn't anything like, oh I
shouldn't have been doing that.
It was kind of like, you know, I was
boxing in my brace. I had it taped,
I warmed up, I, I was uh, doing
drills, boxing drills, those drills.
Yeah, boxing drills. But you just pivot
wrong then and it just pops. And then,
you know, like I remember
sitting there and I'd just,
the pain is very specific and then it goes
away too quick. That's when, you know,
cause it's their real,
real, real, real hard pain.
And then it goes away in like two
minutes because the ligaments like,
so now you don't have pain anymore. And
I'm like, oh no. So I sit down and I go,
all right,
my is torn.
And that was when I hit like a
real bad rock bottom on that one.
That was like that one.
Like oh my gosh.
When I went to the MRI and got home,
I literally like called my friend and
I told him to come over and I just,
I mean I pretty much just drink as
much of a bottle. It's that good.
Cause I was in pretty good shape
at that point. So I put me out,
I passed out of my head was I woke up
in my porch with my head on the grill in
the morning, just a mess. It
was not, it was not pretty,
but I didn't care cause I was
out for nine months, you know.
So everybody hits these
lows, you know, it's normal.
What were you doing financially back then?
Because that's where it gets rough.
Right. That's another part of it. I mean
us athletes, we all know, or you know, uh,
we, we only make money when we, when we
fight for the prize, you know, and, um,
thank God, you know,
Lorenzo and in the UFC,
they gave me a decent chunk of money
for a good part of time while I had the
belt.
And then once they took the belt,
I stopped getting that chunk
of money even when I was hurt.
So they were paying me a little
bit a stipend while I was hurt.
And that helped me.
And then when I lot,
when they stripped the belt and gave
it to Brown, they stopped with that,
you know, cause I'm not the champion
anymore. And then it was kind of like,
that's one, that's what I mean.
That's when it kind of went,
got turned me out here. Like, you're
not the champ, um, on paper anymore.
He didn't really lose it, but that's
it. So what are you going to do?
What is this it, you know, how you gonna
make money? How are you going to do this?
How are you going to do
that? And I panicked. Um,
but I knew that I was going to still come
back and fight cause I was still young
and so I hadn't given up on fighting yet.
Still only in my second ACL surgery.
So I'm still not fully admitting
that I'm not that I'm a mess.
Right. I kind of not really like
admitting it to myself yet and it's,
screw what you're saying everybody
else's what I'm trying to say.
It's what you believed yourself
is all that matters. Right.
Period. And I was like,
I'll be fine. This isn't that bad. I,
I can do this. I've gone through worse.
So in doing it, I still hadn't really just
given up yet and that's, so I'm still,
I'm still competing in my mind,
which is the problem.
And that's when you just,
you're overworking and not
just doing things you're not
supposed to on your knee.
But just in general in
life on just overworking.
I'm doing my Fox stuff now to make money
and then I'm trying to do my rehab five
days a week because I have to come back
and fight for the belt when I come back.
And that's another thing people
don't equate is I was the champs.
I got to come back and fight for the belt.
When I come back after this injury,
I don't just get to come back
and fight somebody three rounds.
I got to come back and fight five rounds.
Never been done before.
I had nobody to bounce this thought
off of. Um, I just had to wing it man.
And so I was, and that caused, I think,
a lot of problems with me cause I didn't
have the mental capacity to deal with
it at that point with all the things that
I was doing. So I just kept grinding.
And then I finally get back to
health after the second ACL,
six months, nine months goes by. All
right, let's take this brow fight song.
I'm ready. I'm training and
camp about a month in, um,
I th I have like a
weird pinch in my groin.
It turns out to be the exact same injury
Daniel Cormier just pulled out of the
fight for it's the extensor tendon
in your or no, it's the, um,
uh,
I forget the name of the,
there's a tendon in your groin area that
pulls and then you got to just rest it.
I tore the, mine was a little
bit worse. I tore the bone,
the muscle, the quad muscle off the
bone, so it like separated from the bone,
but it wasn't all the way.
It was just enough that it was,
I could still like think I was okay,
but it would just fail on me occasionally,
so I could tape it some days and it would
be all right. Shoot a bunch of Toradol,
which is a, for anybody
who's curious. It's a natch.
It's a legal anti-inflammatory. A
lot of football players take it. Um,
toradol. Toridol it's uh,
yeah, I think that's, yeah,
I think that's what it's
called. But anyways, it's,
it's a natural urge to anti-inflammatory.
None natural one,
but it's like Ibuprofen, but stronger.
And I would take that and that helped. Um,
but it just, it wasn't right.
I remember I was sparring one day and
I went to throw a right hand and my leg
just gave out and I fell on the floor
and it wasn't kicking, I wasn't shooting.
I just threw her right hand and the
feeling of falling because I threw right
hand made me know like
something wasn't connected.
Like it just didn't feel right
because it just failed me. It wasn't,
it wasn't like it hurt and I stopped it
just literally there was no pain and it
just failed. And I was like, something's
way mechanically wrong with me.
I can't fight mechanically
wrong like this.
And that was about four weeks
out of the fight, three,
four weeks out of the fight. Why had
already done a month camp, this injury,
trying to tough it out.
So my camp was rough.
It was a heart camp and I didn't want
to pull out, obviously naturally.
So I ended up calling Dana fee and,
and this one of the few phone
calls I've ever had with Dana,
unfortunately in this, probably one of
the Times you remembers telling them,
I'm sorry I've got to pull out.
But I remember not wanting to
have my manager column this,
this goes back to what my mom,
how my mom puts something in my head
where you deal with this face to face or
talk in cycle. And I said,
look, I don't want to do this,
but I got a plot of this
fight. I need some doc. I need,
if you got any doctors you can have him,
the Mri me whenever you want,
but I'm telling you something's wrong
with my leg. So he's like, okay, I'll,
I'll do it. I got, I got guys on
it. We can't have you pull out now.
I'm sure you're fine. Check it out.
Get the doctors, check it. Yeah, your,
your quads torn. You can't fight.
So the UFC pulls me, you know,
Dane is naturally pissed, but then
that slide's a favor in there. Boom.
Favorite gets the shot with,
with brow ends up getting knocked
out in that match up. But um,
I pull out of that fight and
that's when they stripped my belt.
And then that was the beginning of me
giving up on fighting to an extent.
And what I mean by that is it's different
than you think. It sounds negative,
right? When you say that
I'm giving up on fighting,
but it is actually the building point
in my life where I finally let go of
control.
I always had this thing up to that point
where I wanted to control everything.
It's just something that I,
I always had to give to being able
to do this last one after the two ACL
reconstructive surgery is coming back
and then tearing my quad after that.
I said like,
I don't know what else you want me to do.
I've gotten through two
ACL reconstructions. Uh,
my higher power is God.
So I'm praying at this point saying,
I don't know what you want me to do.
So you're talking to God. So yeah, like
what do I gotta do, man? I'm you want,
I'm, I'm in this for for
reasons bigger than myself.
I want to come back and show
people that this can be done.
I'm not the only one that can do
this. Anybody can do this, right?
I'm here for you doing bidding your wheel.
God,
this is my talking and no answers,
no nothing.
And I said,
maybe that's the answer.
I remember thinking maybe that's the
answer is just you might not ever fight
again. Are you okay with that?
And now it's something that my,
I never allowed my brain to even go to
ever until all these injuries hit me and
I would have never been able to
unless I went through all that.
That was literally all this stuff because
I'm so stubborn and so just tough that
I had to go through all that
just to mentally say, okay,
you might never do this again.
It could have been if to the first one,
I could have done that, but
I didn't. When I did that,
my health skyrocketed immediately.
I started,
I just went to therapy every day
knowing I was trying to get better,
but I didn't care if
I fought again or not.
I focused all my energy and Fox and
coaching the guys at Alliance Training
Center and make them better and uh, try
to make the team better so that when and,
and feed off the thirst and the hunger
that those guys had to be the champion
that I still wanted to be. And I, and
I, I decided that if I focused on Fox,
focused on the positive energy
of these guys at the gym,
kept training and kept
my mind in the sport, um,
my body will be there because my
age is compliant with my body still.
I'm still young enough that I'll be okay.
So I just needed to get my mind wrapped
around the sport, stay in it immensely,
but understand that if I never
have it again, that's okay too.
And when I did that,
it took away so much importance off of
needing to fight as have the title as my,
as the person that I was,
that it allowed me to open up and say,
if you never fight again and
you're still a great person,
you still did great things. You still, uh,
laid the tracks for the Bantam Weight
Division and a lot of ways, um,
you did this, that you, you
had a great career. Dumb,
like it's okay if this is it.
And I kept that mindset,
kept focusing on the things that I could
control instead of the things that I
couldn't,
like the fact that I wasn't competing yet.
And as I did that I got
healthier and healthier.
Came back thought Mizzou Gawky that
set me up to fight Mizzou gawky then
destroyed misery gawky while your best
performances over where I found great
first round destruction,
that was a most at peace I've felt
in a long time walking into her and I
remember interviewing you after
the fight and you were like,
I don't even remember what happened. He
just went like, you went into a trance.
It was weird.
It was one of the weirdest performances
in my whole career easily because the
walkout was different.
Just I was so, I had no,
no connection. I was, I had no connection
to the win or the loss at that point.
There was nothing.
It was just,
I was just there to enjoy being there
again after three and a half years and all
of these injuries like I can't believe
I made it here. I'm not injured.
And I remember thinking like,
just you're in front of these people.
Enjoy the limelight, man. Enjoy
this ride. Like this is incredible.
There's people that would pay millions
and trillions of dollars to get this walk
you're about to get and go fight
somebody in this octagon. Just enjoy it.
Don't worry, don't connect. And by letting
go, man, by letting go of the injuries,
by letting go of the wind,
by letting go of the loss,
by letting go of either mattered.
I was in the,
I was in my zone and it allowed
me to just be free and I was,
that was the best performance of
my career. But more than anything,
it showed me a mental thing that I'd
never opened up before and it was letting
go of the things that you can't control.
We'll give you actually more peace because
it disconnects you from what happens.
So you feel like that piece was a
significant factor in your body recovering
cause the pressure and the
stress and the anxiety,
all of that was playing.
It was,
it was wrecking not just your mental
state but also your physical state.
100% every piece of it. That's really
interesting. Every piece of it.
And that's the biggest thing I
learned is, uh, that is like,
it wasn't my physical body, it was
my mind doing it to my physical body.
So it was initially a physical
injury and then it was the cascade of
psychological issues that came with the
physical issue that was more physical
issues.
It was the cascade of trying to figure
out why I was so sad with all these
things that I earned around me that I
already had everything that I thought like
when you grow up in a trailer like I did,
and then you go to winning a Gtr,
the car you wanted since you were a kid
in a prize fight and having a home that
you bought with your own money that you
never thought you'd be able to own a
home in California. Cause you live in
a damn trailer park in Tucson, Arizona.
It kind of like, um, makes you feel like,
like that's it, you know, like you, you,
you've done crazy great
things and you've, um, I,
those were all just dreams to me and they
happened so quick, like at 20, you know,
I mean, I didn't get my house till
later, but when I got those things,
it's like I really, I, why are you
so I was still sad as my point.
Like I was still, I had my
depression that was hitting me and,
and that's so many people in this
world are dealing with depression.
Like it's a huge catastrophic
problem across the planet.
And um, I definitely, it's
in my, it's in my blood line,
on both sides of my family.
And it's something that everybody,
not just myself deals with on a daily
basis, I think in certain people's lives.
And that hit me very hard and I didn't
understand why it hit me so much harder
now after I stopped competing.
Like, why am I, why is,
why is it so much worse now?
While.
The reason is my body was used to
the active, the activity just go, go,
go. And I, what I realized is
I turned off all my emotional,
spiritual and mental issues with
exercise to where I never ever,
ever dealt with them ever.
I only physically worked them out.
So my physical was perfection.
I was a, I'm a world champion,
monster, killer, whatever you want to call
me in your own respective mind, right?
But emotionally,
physically and spiritually,
I was at cricket and I never
understood that until I was hurt,
trapped in my own body like a prison
cell, couldn't train, couldn't run,
couldn't walk, couldn't bend my leg,
laying on the couch, eating pain pills,
realizing, man, unless you train,
unless you compete, you hate yourself,
you hate yourself. You're, you're
a piece of shit in your own mind.
Without those things,
without the beautiful girlfriend,
without the beautiful house,
without the Nice cars,
without them big money to
show people you hate yourself.
So what am I really doing?
Why am I doing this?
I lost sight that the whole reason
we're fighting is, is it's a spiritual,
emotional,
physical,
mental battle that helps you grow as
an individual and as a human being.
It's not just to have these things
you think will make you happy.
You have to learn those
things through the process.
And I didn't know that until I was trapped
in my own body and I literally felt
like I was in a prison cell
and I knew that wasn't right.
We shouldn't be in our own body alone
without people around us to keep us
company and uh, on a couch feeling
like we're in a prison cell,
should we? No, definitely not. No we
shouldn't. But I did for three years.
So how did you get yourself out of it?
By just accepting it and you, you ma,
there must have been some sort of a
mechanism that August I have people that I
talked to, professionals, um,
obviously like sports
psychologists or wall,
a sports psychologist and then you got
to get a psychologist in general to deal
with the depression, whatever. When you
hit your lows like it's okay to, to get,
you know, if you're bench pressing 350
pounds, it's okay to have a little touch.
It's okay to have a little
spot here and there, you know,
and then after you get a couple spots,
now after a while you can do it yourself.
You don't need the spot anymore.
That's how I look at psychiatric
help to an extent. For some people,
especially if they're battling depression.
Sometimes you just need a floaty and you
did and then you can take the floaties
off after a year. See what
I'm saying? It's a mental,
it's a mental floaty and it's okay cause
we all hit low part low points in our
life where it's unbearable and you either
allow it to continue to be unbearable
and just deny it.
Or you deal with the task at hand and say,
I'm a little low right now.
I need the floaties. It's
okay, I'll get through this.
And then when you take the flood is off,
you realize I only needed them for a
little bit of time and now I'm okay,
I'm here.
And that's kind of what it felt like.
It's like I just needed
a little bit of a push.
I needed to get through this and
learn some things about my own,
my own mind and understand my own emotions
and understand that I didn't need all
these things that I was
thinking where it real.
It was me not being in
control of my own emotions,
your own emotions or your choice, and I
chose to feel trapped. I chose to be sad.
I chose to feel like I was Jack Shit.
I chose all these things and it's like
you don't need fighting to be these
things.
You need to,
you need to let go of fighting to learn
that you are something without it,
and that was actually a gift.
It became a gift because I learned so
much in life now bigger than fighting.
I look at the things that I went through
as a gift because I have gotten the
gift of feeling
retired during my career.
Who else gets that?
Some people retire for five years,
lose their freaking mind,
ended up in the bar and come back and
try to fight again 10 years later with a
weakened body. A mess. Why? Why though?
Why are they doing that? They're not doing
it because they're physically capable.
They're doing it because they never
dealt with their life away from fighting.
Fighting was there like fighting is who
they are. Fighting is their persona.
So take away fighting. What are they?
They're in the bar drinking away with.
They're not.
Instead of drinking,
putting the booze down and knowing what
you are without fighting, being happy,
that chapter of your life and
being able to live who you are.
I've gotten to feel that and now
I can fight with a peace of mind,
knowing how good I am without fighting
and how great I am with it too.
And um,
that's,
that's what this thing's about.
All these fights,
all these me attacking those challenges,
coming back and winning and
getting my belt back. Um,
that could only happen because I let
go of control of the things I couldn't
control.
[inaudible].