The joe rogan experience.
Um, in your UFC career,
you had one very controversial
fight with the Tim Kennedy.
That time where you sat on
the stool for a long time,
like an extra 30 seconds in between the
rounds. What's, what's your take on that?
Okay. Can say that he get Tim together.
These have been gold. Get
follow, get bustle, Metta
and they call you call it ego [inaudible]
he call you or they bought deal.
He has two colleagues in his life.
College colleagues from the street
and colleagues from the sport. Okay.
You looked at and kidding and [inaudible].
Both of them have to go hand in hand.
Okay.
You could all get Nadia in England.
[inaudible] he doesn't
think he has any of those.
What does that mean?
Hello? Good to see that.
No lose one. He was holding
onto his fingers and he go
out and grabbed your glove
for that. Before. For that? Yeah. And
when they were against
the fence and Mcdonnell,
he was cheating.
Yeah,
but it's my fault.
It's his fault because he didn't have
to let him grab his fucking clubs.
Do you want me to organize a father?
He let him grab your shirt
and then he grabbed his ear.
He take my glove. He turned my golf. He
eats. He's holding a mom to my glove.
He's holding on to my clothes. Grabbed
his glove. He told the referee, he, yes,
yes. Hey, stay like this
yellow thing, right?
He's got him up against the wall.
Thoughts.
Let me,
if you remember
second, now they're against
the fence. Okay, equal
guantee. He grabs his hair first. Just
Swipe grip you. I said, all right.
He grabs his lady. Saturday.
Friday he came my gloves.
Yes, I was right. That hobby.
He lives it. He lets it go right away. Say
he went up and down. They can apply it,
right? Thanks. Second.
Ben took 15 seconds left.
He now had grabbed it. Boom, boom, boom.
You have the West said I'm not,
but they won't that Yo,
he's going to ask you a question.
See if they met us. Downloads Song.
If he sticks his finger in
your fucking I get goes to.
So what it is that it's a foul foul.
How many minutes [inaudible] you recover.
It's a good question.
Depending on how bad your eyes or hurt
it might be over cause they see that
brand, then that brand, they're
going to want to know my mentee.
How long would it be?
He took a few minutes on a quantum told
me no she did it ain't no [inaudible]
glue. If he kicks you in the balls, take
a few minutes, take a few minutes. Okay,
I got it.
I said the one thing and they got
in there grabbing gloves is illegal.
Okay. She tell you in
garb. Paid call. No one to
Cabasa if he punches you with your gloves.
I want me holding on to your gloves.
If I'm punching you and I'm holding onto
your glove. Is that legally illegal?
Illegal. Okay. Okay. [inaudible] how
much time should they have taken off?
So
what you're saying is you sat down for
extra time in between the rounds because
he committed a foul right before that.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no. Get him against him.
[inaudible] he's asking you a question.
[inaudible] if they would
have stopped it but see it,
I'd be through [inaudible]. If
she had, I'd been to SMEs to,
if the judge would've seen that,
seen him ripping off his glove,
he came to me and said,
I was so hoping he would've seen
him punching him. Liked, Huh? No,
my mentor went to the input
and the organization's got you.
How much time would he have taken?
Well, he should take points away.
I said, this is what I think.
I think anytime someone does a foul,
you just take points away on the
I the file kicking the balls,
poke in the eye, point away. Because
even if you don't mean to do it,
lots of Saint [inaudible],
it's still does damage
and it's a foul foul.
So I think you should
get a point taken away.
Okay. Thankfully my Jamaican,
he didn't say it. She,
she knows me. I see.
No, he, I said, listen,
now the APP,
I don't,
the fight ended poke a like I
want gimbal because at the time,
and she know [inaudible] he
would've lost the fight. Right,
right. Cause you were hurt. Ooh,
he's getting up in front of AA
or na, he punches him, my boom.
She not by their name and it's like, oh,
did you already said lose it? They fight.
If he wouldn't look at the time when
the end that he would've lost the fun.
Right.
So the
round was over. You sat down
between rounds. What happened?
Mccarthy,
Mary,
me stay here and clean on New York.
It's how I get book and manage it.
Are they lean pillow?
Stay right there and clean them.
But my gut is intelligent.
My could you say, I know can't
do it. No barley and bellow.
So your coach bought you extra time,
bad or Norfolk go by and
I said, dude, I made out.
Okay, watch it. No, come into
North Memorial yelling pyramid.
His trainer couldn't clean them,
couldn't wipe him. And they said,
uniporter condiment. And I listened
the protocol. He said, no, no, no.
[inaudible] [inaudible] it
okay to Cookman like Emma.
Oh, the guy that was supposed to
wipe him down was to cut math,
but the cup man couldn't do it.
So then the other guy had
a company that out of Yale,
the cup man had left already. [inaudible]
rd. Just the only two that were in the,
in the ring with the two trainers.
[inaudible]
I try.
You even got him.
So did they cover you with water to give
you extra time that they don't want to
show up out there? My Tempo? No, no,
that was [inaudible].
He's always done the water exclusively
in his trainings and crusade and I will
see him, you know, joking
[inaudible] recover.
He likes the water for recovery,
but again, then he got to them.
Ilene Peng play tells
people to wipe them down.
Right now I am proud of my
temple and put out your record.
It's not for more time.
It's for him to recover and could see
that y'all ain't get it done. Dot.
Then they got on to nodded Don, Don,
Don, Leo [inaudible] recovering Mandarin.
I didn't hit him. I ain't get to the
side of my thought here. I said, did I,
that I work on after Wyatt,
who's taught in, in Baghdad.
I meant more and with the towels on them
and to wipe it down at the same time to
cool him off and call them off. Right. So
at the end of the round, the round ends,
you're sitting on the corner of the round,
supposed to begin.
Tim Kennedy standing up and he's like,
what is going on here?
He thinks maybe the fights over and
you're still sitting here, you know,
he wanted to fight to be over.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Okay.
[inaudible]
no. Getting up early. I come
with Tim Kennedy and modify them.
[inaudible] you UFC then she had,
I'll take it.
They fight that made
the three, uh, the UFC.
Matt [inaudible] and
I'll let you all know.
Getting up earlier first he said he
had an injury, they want to fight.
So it took the UFC three months for him
to fight EOL but he could have had an
injury. [inaudible] injury
is possible. Pool Dot.
No,
he's not saying it [inaudible] on up in
there because they gave him the fight
three times.
You didn't want to,
they always something always I can feed
on [inaudible] until he finally took the
fight. Nope. Two, sorry. I tell you,
[inaudible] persona,
15 years dealing with
people said [inaudible] you,
he knows how they're going to manifest.
He ain't [inaudible] let me
toss it in the beginning.
He was very nice.
Uh,
[inaudible] Quando I'm
going to send a lot. Um, uh,
I went in a bizarre way in the
land. Just don't, don't kill him.
He's standing in their mind his
business, but oh, can I? Okay, good. Oh,
get up and epilepsy by let 'em [inaudible]
the main car was poor ea McGregor
stock. [inaudible] it was hot.
Yeah. Fuck what y'all reporter?
Yeah. Ba Ma. Hey Yo. Hey Yo,
please, please no do this. Can we
see? Can you share it on Trump?
Who said that to you? Then
let's be professional, right?
Hey, hey, hey, what's up?
Please not do this. They said, well,
no, this a hygiene. I don't do it right.
[inaudible] I said, all right, so see you.
[inaudible] [inaudible] why would he
come up to him and say that if the whole
time he's been very respectful to
Tim candidate, right. I don't know.
Because he wanted to talk,
you know, like if a friend,
some weight loss, can I say
it was [inaudible] games?
Are they used in sports?
You know, I try to be your friend.
Yeah, that's it. [inaudible]
when we were in the fight, she
threw me off. He ended up in there.
If you watched the fight,
came around,
know an FRC the first round he wanted
easy say well no longer took that under
the wrong. I thought he's in
the second round. He's fight.
He's willing to fight for the right.
She knows.
She knows [inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible] that
wouldn't have happened with the grab
glove.
He would've won the second round.
And also him grabbing your glove
is how he was able to hit you.
Yeah. And No [inaudible] he didn't
touch him in the whole fight. Right.
That's what I meant.
Thinking.
So who do Melissa one just in those
last ten second, he the we golden.
Do you get them real fucking hard?
So when you were sitting there,
what was going through your mind when you
were sitting there and Tim Kennedy was
telling you to stand up and you
knew that the round was over.
The rest period was over two thousand
seven thousand eight Tim Keller Valley
shut off the pilot they buy today.
You can look at the top and so panic
domain don't get out. My wipe out there,
I him and MP to relax. I'm going to get
up as soon as they fucking wipe me down.
Saint Paul,
can you look at,
they come up in Sando [inaudible]
not [inaudible] Sandal.
Give him a guy that got sent out. He
and, and then reality and think that Tim,
can you,
y'all make it.
He had guys in your three pence on the
way that he was thinking, Hey guys.
[inaudible] now he wants to come
out to finish knocking me out.
You know, they all got them. You know,
how come I didn't let me dry me
off and then we'll fucking fight.
Right. But there was only,
you only get one minute rest.
You were hurt at the end of the round.
There's only one minute rest,
but you took a minute and 30 seconds.
That extra 30 seconds had to help.
Cause he say [inaudible]
but [inaudible] has,
I don't know, cause we'll tend to
us. I will not [inaudible] why not?
[inaudible] yeah. Fuck yeah. Yeah.
But in my, for me, good pop his fault.
It's not your fault. Let me go,
Bro. C C C who is a third lien bill,
if he will have been cleaned up,
McCarthy condition [inaudible]
it was a go out and fight going.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
and he stopped and told him to slow down.
So you're saying that that was not a
ploy in order to get you more rest x when
we went on a whole lot of that by no
mother? No on, no, no, no. For sure.
Yeah.