That's the ideological point that
right here, this is a new thing though,
right? I mean, relatively
speaking, this, uh,
this hard nose stance from the left
of the equality of outcome and,
and the only reason why there wouldn't
be 50% women or 50% black or 50% in it,
you just pick any marginalized group.
The only reason why it wouldn't be even
across the board with all other races is
because of discrimination. This is a
fairly new stance. And then there were,
there were moments that were fairly
well publicized that I don't forget when
Larry Summers got fired from Harvard.
So let Larry Summers with the president
of Harvard and he's a famous economist,
uh, and he gave a speech
for which he was fired. Uh,
there might be a little more color
as to why he was fired. I mean,
it was more fire because he, he wants the
wheels started to come off. He didn't,
he had alienated enough people that he
didn't have friends to kind of prop him
up.
But,
but the thing that pulled the wheels off
was that he gave a speech and he said,
we know there are are differences in,
in the the bell curves that describe,
you know,
mathematical aptitude
between men and women.
And this explains why there are many
more top flight male mathematicians and
engineers than women. And it's not
that they even, it's not that the,
uh, the means of the, uh, the, the,
the of the bell curves are different.
So the,
the means could be the same,
but there could be more variants so that
the tails are thicker in the case of,
of the male bet. Bell-Curve. So at the,
at the absolute ends, both the, that, the,
the low end and the high end, you have
many more people. So you know, if you're,
if you're going to ask, you know,
what's the, in the same size population,
how many people do you have
at the 99.9, nine, nine,
nine percentile of aptitude in math?
Say it could be that you have,
and there's,
there's a fair amount of data to show this
many more men at the tails than women.
Right? And, and that's true for
grandmasters in chess, right? It's just,
it's just this is not a, uh, and it may
be true for something like, you know,
playing pool, you know, I mean they're,
they're, they're just differences.
And that may not be
entirely environmental,
almost certainly are not entirely
environmental. Uh, that is one, right?
It's a big issue in the world of pool
men and women play separately and there's
no reason physically why they
should. Yeah, they're not,
it's not a strength game.
Right. But women are allowed to play in
men's tournaments, but they never win.
Right. Jean Bill Lucas
was a woman who was, uh,
she was like one of the only
women never compete and beat men.
She's like an extreme outlier.
And this was like,
I want to say it was in the late seventies
and eighties. And other than that,
there's been a few women that
have done well in tournaments,
but when they come to major league
professional pool tournament's,
they're almost always one by
men. Um, and when I say almost,
I mean like 99.9%.
So there was a commonwealth
games have been happening as we,
it was just over the last couple of
weeks and there was a male to female
transgender athlete in the weight lifting.
Consequently,
that's a whole nother ball participated
in the women's competition and the
Commonwealth Games at the time of her
joining hadn't yet put down a rule as to
testosterone levels in
the females competing.
And so this male to female transgender
person qualified in the female games and
was as you'd expect,
um,
winning in all of the Games and was the
front runner and destined to win the
competition as a male to female
transgender person. And the only reason,
and it would have led to a huge crisis
in the Commonwealth Games because there
was some resistance to this notion.
Um,
and of course the questions
that arise is this fair. Um,
men are born naturally with high
levels of testosterone. For example,
the only reason it didn't
lead to, to crunch time, and
that was a huge scandal of,
of, uh, of her winning is that she
injured herself in the competition.
And by sheer accident,
I saw that. Well, I can,
I can expand on that a little bit
because I've actually gone through this
extensively because there was a
woman who was a, used to be a man,
was competing in mixed
martial arts against women
and just beating the shit out
of them. And I was saying that this
is, this is a mistake and that you're,
you're looking at something whether
someone should be legally able to identify
as a woman portray themselves
a woman. Absolutely. Yeah.
Do you have the freedom to become a
woman in quotes? In our society, yes,
but you can't deny biological nature and
there's physiological advantages to the
male frame. There's, it's specifically
when it comes to combat sports.
That's my wheelhouse.
I'm an expert.
I understand there's a giant difference
between the amount of power that a man
and a woman can generate.
And if you're telling me that a guy living
30 years of his life as a man, that's,
that's essentially like a woman
being on steroids for 30 years,
then getting off and then having regular
women being forced to compete with her
and try to pretend that this is
a level playing field. It is not.
There's a difference in the shape of
the hips, the size of the shoulder,
the density of the bones,
the size of the fists. Yeah.
That's a giant factor.
And your ability to generate
power is the size of your fists.
It's also an ethical problem.
And it's not just a competition here.
Girls getting beaten up by
someone who used to be a man. Yes.
But people came down on me harder than
anything that I've ever stood out for in
my life.
Never in my life that I think there's
going to be a situation where I said, hey,
I don't think a guy should be able to
get his penis removed and beat the shit
out of women. And then people are
like, you're out of line. But that's
the summary of the [inaudible].
What happened?
This is a conversation that
I had with a woman, uh,
online as well during this whole thing.
Uh,
she said she, this person who had turned
into a woman has always been a woman.
And I said, but she was a man
for 30 years. She goes, no,
she's always been a woman.
I go even when she had sex with a
woman and fathered a kid and she says,
yes, even then I go, well,
we're done because you're just
talking Nazi ideology can,
that's ideology covering Zap.
The fat,
so as they are is that she had a male
physique and the person who was arguing
with me wants to claim this moral high
ground of being the most progressive and
they're always looking to step on top
of anybody who's less progressive than
then and complain and and
proclaim superiority and this
is the ideological sport.
This is the idea support that that you
see with when people are playing ping
pong with our ideas and not listening.
You need to listen to experts in,
in that when you're,
especially when you're talking about
martial arts, there's a, the the,
the difference is so profound and the
results are so critical because you're
talking about a sport where the
objective goal, the goal is clear.
It's very clear. Beat the fuck out
of the other person in front of you.
So anything that would give you an
advantage in beating the fuck out of that
person should be really looked at very
carefully and not thrown through the the
lens of this progressive ideological
filter that we're going through right now.
Because that's, that's what it is. I mean,
that's how people are looking at it
and it's with weightlifting as well.
When transgendered athletes going
to weightlifting competitions,
the male to female transgender athletes
are overwhelmingly dominant. Yeah.
I mean, is this, is this
a coincidence or it's, no,
it's someone who had fucking testosterone
pumping through their system and n and
a y chromosome their whole life and now
all of a sudden we're supposed to say no,
she's a woman. She's a, she's
dainty, she's got size 14 feet,
she's got gorilla hands. Like,
what in the fuck are we doing?
So I think as you said earlier,
she is a woman,
but for the purposes of competition
against other women, you know,
legally she's a woman at that stage,
right?
If she goes through that
identity transition.
But I think we have to recognize it.
I think even many traditional feminists
are making this point much to the anger
of the Trans Community. They're saying,
hold on you what you're doing in this way.
He's actually,
we fought so hard and so long for these
female spaces where we have a space of
our own people that used to be men are
coming into those spaces is actually
quite literally beating the crap
out of us. Yes, yes. You know,
whether it's in boxing, uh, whether
it's in weightlifting, in martial arts,
they are, by definition, they're
dominating on this. Of course they offer,
what were the reasons you've said
experts that they're calling upon are all
malls,
all transitioned doctors,
surgeons or people that have transitioned
themselves when they speak to actual
board certified endocrinologist.
And some of the only do it off record,
but one of 'em, um, I forget her name,
she was in one of the big mixed
martial arts publications.
Ramona [inaudible] I believe is her
name. She's saying, no, not only does it,
it, it actually doing this
transition, like from male to female,
you're forcing your,
you're putting estrogen into the system.
So the bone density change that would
ordinarily take place if you remove
someone's testicles and stop that
does the production of testosterone,
estrogen preserves bone density,
so you're actually retaining
the male bone density.
There's so many problems
with this and that,
and then the one of the other things
they say, well, oh, the Olympics,
the Olympics allow it.
The Olympics are very ideologically based.
There's not a whole
lot of science to this,
this transition thing of allowing male
to female athletes to compete in the
Olympics and there's a extreme amount
of corruption in the Olympics as it is
with the IOC being in bed with Wada,
the world anti-doping agency and the
way they handle this Russian scandal.
I mean this is Russian scandal that
was highlighted in that fantastic
documentary. ICARUS, yeah,
they're fucking crazy.
They're the Olympics or not to be trusted.
That is a gigantic multibillion dollar
business where the athletes get paid zero
money. It is inherently corrupt from
the top down. No doubt about it.
So to to call upon them is to see
who should be competing as a woman.
Fuck off. They, they, they're
not the experts. This is,
this is not something that's been examined
and this is coming from someone who,
one of my jobs is examining
and commentating on fights.
That is a big part of what I do.
I understand fights and I know what it
looks like when a man's beating the shit
out of a woman.
And that's what it looked like when
this person was fighting women. It was,
there was a massive physical advantage.
Massive and not a skill advantage.
What was the way you mentioned something
that the reaction that you got to that,
what was the trouble you go to the top?
People are so mad at me.
I mean it was just so many. Not only
that, they took my words out of context,
they quoted all these different,
uh,
gender transition doctors.
It's saying that there's no science behind
this and the science behind it being
totally fair and totally equal.
It's just not, and people know it.
Everyone knows they couldn't put cris
Cyborg against this guy and give him a run
for his money the wrong way class.
Or that's the other way.
That's the other thing,
and we're dealing with a similar
situation like that in Texas.
I don't even know about the girl who was,
she was born a girl.
She's transitioning to a boy in
high school taking testosterone,
but in Texas they only allow
her to compete as a girl.
So she's dominated the Texas
state wrestling championship
two years in a row and
it's horrific because she's on steroids.
She's on testosterone.
He now doesn't matter because
they're testing chromosomal. Yeah,
she's a woman. She was born a
woman, right? She was born a girl.
So because the fact that
she's transitioning to be a
boy, they don't give a shit.
You're a woman. You're not going to
wrestle against men. You're a girl.
You're not going to wrestle,
wrestle against boys.
So they have allowed her under
extreme protest and it's terrible.
She wants to compete or he, I should
say, wants to compete as a boy.
They won't let him. They say,
no, you were born a girl.
You have to compete as a girl. So when
he competes everybody booze, it's offer.
It's fucking awful. I mean it's,
it's, it's really devastating.
A question for you that way around
if it's female to male transition,
uh,
somebody that used to be a woman that
transitions to a man and wants to compete
with the men, they don't have an advantage
to tone. No, they don't allow to write.
They're at a disadvantage.
If they win in that context,
they've actually done really good.
Yes. Look, women can beat men. Yeah.
I mean it happens all the time at Jujitsu.
There's,
especially in Jujitsu in
particular because it's such
a technique based art. Uh,
but it is possible.
There's,
there's also a woman named Jermaine Duran
to me who's a worldclass mixed martial
artists whose multiple time world Moy
Thai champion of Fatah man and knocked
them out. It's crazy video. A real man
Kao them when the straight right it's,
it is possible for them to win if their
skill level is so far superior that it
overcomes the inherent
strength advantages.
But a woman to male transition would
be at a severe disadvantage against a
natural male. Would you be so in that
Texas case, they clearly have it wrong.
They should. They should allow him to,
to compete with this and would you be,
whereas I can,
I think all three of us
probably instinctively would
resist the notion that a
female than a male to female athlete
competes with other females because they'd
have it. One can resist that. Yes.
Would you be for a female to
male athlete competing with men?
Yes, because I don't think there's
no honor. There's no event.
But here's the problem and the,
and the consent is sort of running
in the other direction. The marriage,
she is continually putting herself
or he's putting himself in harm's way
knowingly. And I'm not opposed to a
woman fighting a man if she so chooses.
Like I'm not opposed to
bull riding if you want it.
I'm not lobbying to get
bull riding outlawed,
but if you want to be so fucking stupid
that you climb on top of a 2000 pound
angry animal, go for it. And you
should be able to do whatever you want.
I think you should be able to jump out
of fairly good air on airplanes. Know,
if you want to parachute, you should
be able to risk your life. Parachuting.
The difference lies in just massive
advantages and that there's a massive
advantage in transitioning from
male to female, female to male.
Here's the other problem. Female to
Male, you have to take testosterone.
You can't legally take
testosterone and compete.
It's been a giant issue in mixed martial
arts because for the longest time there
was a loophole and the
loophole was testosterone
therapy and they were allowing
testosterone replacement therapy for
male athletes that were either older or
it's, it was, uh,
it was a symptom of having
pituitary gland damage,
which comes from head trauma,
which comes, which means it really,
essentially your career
should be over your,
your body's not producing
hormones correctly.
And that's a very common issue
with people that have been in war.
People that have been blown up by IED
is people that have been hit a lot.
Even soccer players a lot of times show
a diminished levels of testosterone and
growth hormone because of
pituitary gland damage.
So you wouldn't even allow that.
So a female to male would be in a whole
nother problem in combat sports because
it's not legal for you to
take testosterone and compete.