Sushi gear for less.
Are there more or less of them
than people that are in cults?
Uh,
there are vastly more paying attention
then people in cults. Yeah. Well,
yeah,
that's way off cause I think there's
like a billion Catholics. Well,
if you're going to call Catholicism,
I grew up in it. Okay. 100%.
It's just a cult with a billion people.
Whenever you got a guy who dresses like
a wizard and sitting on a golden throne,
oh boy.
We're talking about me.
But that is why this is a problem,
is that there's many people that live
their lives by these ridiculous ideologies
that are illogical.
Okay.
So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna Challenge you on this tech them
from predators and Facebook likes. I,
I'm going to challenge you on that.
Please do. Catholicism is not a cult.
What is the difference between a
cult? Here's, I had a bit from my act.
Let me just,
uh,
call his bullshit and it's created by one
person and he knows it's bullshit in a
religion.
That guy's dead.
Okay,
so let me, this is, boy, this is
rough territory, but for you. Okay,
let's say for me, this is
everyday say, yeah. All right. Uh,
let's say Moses comes down the mountain
with the tablets. Oh, that dude. Okay.
I don't know if Moses did come
down the mountain with the tablets.
Don't think he did. Let's say
you did. Okay. Um, did he,
did he know he was bullshitting
people? Well, do you know
religious scholars actually
believe in Jerusalem? Actually,
believe that was all about now the whole
burning Bush tell me they believe in,
there's the acacia butch,
which is rich and DMT and they think
the metaphor of the burning Bush was
actually a psychedelic experience and
that Moses during this psychedelic DMT
experience came back from
the other dimension that
you go into when you go into
the DMT trance with all this.
Yeah,
really standard.
The standard messages that I have
myself have gotten from the psychedelic
experiences that you have to treat each
other as if we're all one and that are a
separations are all illusions.
That you are literally living a life
that if I was born in your body and a had
your genetics,
I would be you and you would be me.
Cause we are all the same
and our differences are
really what the illusion is
when we were these temporary beings.
And that negative thinking and negative
feelings and all these things manifest
themselves in the negative
actions and negative thoughts.
And you can change that and you can
change the frequency in which you exist in
this world.
Like this is essentially what the 3000
year old version of Moses or more than
that Moses has tablets were that they were
the god was the burning
Bush. Perfect. Perfect.
Let me ask you a question. You've done
some holistic hallucinogens. Oh yeah.
And you've had some insight and that
insight has something to do with treating
people. Yes, it definitely
did. Okay. Was it true?
Well it definitely has benefited me.
True or false? I, if you asked me,
is it true that you have had a positive
experiences from psychedelic drugs where
you have interpreted those
experiences and improve your life?
Yes, that's true. Okay.
So if you now go and you convey that
thing to somebody who hasn't had the
experience themselves,
is it bullshit?
Well,
here's the thing about psychedelics as
opposed to all the other ideologies is
that they're very repeatable. You don't
have to believe in DMT. If you smoke it,
you're going to experience it with yeah.
Believe in it or not. Right. And
actually I think this was, I mean,
I am a cautious fan.
I say cautious because I don't think,
I'm not a fan of the idea that these
substances should be used recreationally.
I think that's a mistake.
I agree with you.
I think it's fine to have a great time,
but that these things are so powerful
that one should be deliberate about it.
And you know,
don't do it with a TV.
I like about doing it recreationally
as it's gonna get more people to do it.
And that if you think it's
recreational and then you do it,
there's going to be a certain percentage
of those people that go. What was that?
That's not what I thought it was.
I thought it was going in
there and have a good time.
And I just communicated with God.
Yep. Um, air quotes. God. Yeah.
Air quotes. Well, but air quotes,
God is marvelous because air
quotes God is the real deal. Yeah.
Right. In other words, it's not a
dude on a cloud. It's something, uh,
it is a metaphor for something lodged
very deep in the mind where you can't find
it directly.
And this is a hack that many cultures
have used to access that layer.
And it's all very familiar to us.
And when you talk to people that
have studied DMT in particular,
one of the reasons we think
it's so familiar to us when you,
when you have this experience,
one of the first things that happens is
you feel like you've been there before
and they believe that this is because
during rem sleep your brain produces DMT.
Yup.
It's very difficult to monitor.
But they have been able to through the
Cottonwood Research Foundation, uh,
which all started from the work of Doctor
Rick Strassman out of the University
of New Mexico who wrote a book called Dmt,
the spirit molecule,
which was one of the very
first times with a DEA,
allowed them to do clinical
studies on people with intravenous
dimethyltryptamine,
which is like fucking serious shit.
So instead of like this 10 to 15 minute
trip, you're gone for a long time,
half hour plus and deep deep experiences
that a lot of these people mirrored.
They all, they, they, they had
like super similar experiences.
But through the Cottonwood
Research Foundation,
they've found that live rats are
producing DMT in their pineal gland.
This has been proven now, which it
was really just speculation. It was,
there was anecdotal evidence,
but now they know that rats produced this.
So they don't know exactly when people
do it cause they would have to do the
same thing they do.
Their wrath would have to open your
brain up until they develop some sort of
sophisticated detection methods.
It's just speculation as to when the
brain is producing this incredibly potent
psychedelic drug. But it's
there, right? No, it's producing
it. We know it's produced in the
liver. It's produced in the lungs.
It's endogenous to the human
system. And we don't know why. Yeah.
Well I'm pretty sure I have a good insight
into why. Okay. But for the moment,
let's pursue the issue of what the
implications are. Hold onto wild.
Cross my fingers. Cross your
fingers on that one. Um,
the story you've just told,
it's perfectly plausible whether it's a
hundred percent accurate or not and we
don't know,
right?
But the idea that your mind contains
mechanisms that go into some sort of
psychedelic state without your conscious
mind being able to tap into it.
So your conscious mind
walks around during the day,
not realizing that you're tripping at
some other moments for some purpose.
It's all very interesting.
You're not tripping and you're
sleeping mind for no reason at all.
You're doing it for productive reasons,
logically speaking.
It has to be the case that if you're
burning energy and going through the,
um, costly exercise of thinking
even in the psychedelic way,
that it's happening for a reason.
Right.
And that means that we have carried this
with us from an ancestral state into
the modern state and we now have molecules
that we can trigger it when we want
to.
Um,
that gives you access to
a style of thinking that
you're telling me has altered
your understanding of your relationship
to other people and that it
metaphorically lines up with what you
often hear delivered in religious terms.
Right? That abstractly. Yes. Right.
And so when you say Catholicism is a cult,
I don't agree because Catholicism
historically must have been delivering
messages that caused people to correct
their thinking in ways that made them
collaborate more effectively,
that made them better able to find the
opportunities in their environment.
I'm not advocating that,
um,
we should sign up for belief systems
that are at odds with our modern
environment.
But one thing we can say,
I believe for sure is that religions
that have stood the test of time did so
because their value to the
people who believed in them.
It was so great that those,
the disbelieved were out competed now.
So we get into trouble in
the modern circumstance
because we can look at many of
the teachings of any of these ancient
religions and we can compare them to what
we learned scientifically and detect
that there's something not right.
Can I stop you there? I'm sure
I'm Scientology. Is that a cult?
Too early to tell. Okay.
But let's stop. Well,
oh, the guy who created it. Well, we do,
but we all have. So let me drag you back.
By the way, I'm very uncomfortable
with Scientology and what it does,
but the problem is, um, as
Scientology itself points,
if you looked at the inception of
something like the Catholic Church,
you might be equally troubled. Sure. Which
is why I think they're both colts. Well,
but let's be careful about that.
So what do you think a cult is?
What do you think would call it? Well,
I think a cult is the predatory version.
It is tapping into people's natural
tendency to believe in what I call a
metaphorical truths.
And it is using it very often to
extract resources from them. The church,
well, no, not like the Catholic Church.
The Catholic church is so long
standing and the population that has,
I guess what I would say is if a
population succeeds by believing in these
things than cult is not the correct.
Uh,
I think you and I have different terms.
Were we using different definitions of
the word cult done? But let me, let me,
okay. Take theirs. There's a
very interesting comparison.
So Joseph Smith who started the
Mormon church had a ahead return,
right? He had a competitor, uh,
at the time as a book called
the Kingdom of Mathias,
right about his competitor at the time.
And to me,
the two looked equally plausible. The
story that they were selling. Now,
Mathias never had more than 30
followers and his religion died out.
And Joseph and Joseph Smith one and
in the Mormon church is obviously a,
a real thing.
Um,
but these sets of beliefs
are advanced by somebody,
whether those somebodies are cynical
when they do it or whether they are
earnest.
I think many of these,
the ones that we have that have lasted
for long periods of time have been
advanced by somebody who
was in one way or another,
conscious or not DMT or not tapped into
something that when delivered to other
people actually constituted a kind of
insight now as opposed to being a con man.
Right.
Okay.
And so,
so the origins of the Catholic church
most likely came from some desire for
order and a,
a scaffolding of how to behave and to
give people rules and structure for how to
get through this life with the
most amount of positivity and love.
And by disciplining them and having
these grave punishments being held over
their head,
burning in the fires,
the pits of hell if they decide to
have sex with another man or where two
different types of cloth or whatever the
other silly things that were in the old
testament by doing this,
what they've essentially tried
to do was offer people's trucks.
Um, no, it's, it's not
really structure. It is a,
an analog for truths that can't be spoken.
Um,
literally because nobody knows
how to phrase them. So let's,
let's deal with the church on the one
hand and Moses on the other. Okay.
Moses is obviously important
in, uh, in Jewish history.
If Moses
ate some DMT from the Acacia Bush,
I think it was smoke and we smelled squad,
the whole thing.
And the burning Bush,
let's say he smoked it and let's say he
was super savvy and farsighted and you
know, obviously he didn't know
anything about molecules, right?
Suppose that he had some ancient
model of something and he threw,
there must have been something in that
plant that caused crazy things to happen.
Let's suppose he didn't believe that
he had contacted God or that God had
contacted him, but you woke up from
the thing and was like, wait a minute.
I know what these people are doing wrong.
I'm going to write it down
and tell them came from God.
Is Judaism now a cult?
I think they're all cults.
I think all ideologies are cults.
I just don't, I don't know.
I don't think there is
any one person who wrote,
first of all, when you're
dealing with a Christianity,
you're dealing with translations,
right? Or Judaism, you're,
you're dealing with like ancient
translations of languages that aren't even
spoken anymore. Right. And
you're also dealing with a,
an oral tradition of who knows how many
years before it was ever bothered to be
written down,
but write but written down by people
and then people decide what stays in and
what doesn't.
They changed the rules like the priests
used to be able to marry priests in the
Catholic Church. The pope, you, Steph
wives, sure. Now they ran armies. I mean,
this is clearly something that human
beings have a hand in manipulating and
changing. And they do it for the
benefit of the structure itself. Well,
they're not doing it for the benefit of
the human beings that are a part of it.
They're doing it for the benefit of the
structure itself. Oh, that I don't agree.
Well, what's, in what case? The money and
the, the, the, the amount of, I'm not,
I'm not saying you don't have corruption
in all of the structures you do. Um,
but I am saying that there is it,
I mean this is exactly parallel to
what we were talking about before.
There is the predatory version,
which I would call a cult, right? Um,
and there is the earnest version,
which I would not call a cult.
Now I'm very uncomfortable with any of
these things governing policy in the
present because none of them have a
literal relationship with reality that
allows them to deal with the fact that
we've got all these new problems for
which there are no,
there's no religious wisdom.
Maybe there's a problem in
the word called maybe, uh,
maybe we should just say
a structure created by human beings,
which is basically all
structures, all structures, all,
all models of behavior where you
have to adhere to certain things.
But the problem with religion and even
with a lot of cults is these supposed
grave consequences for Dva.
Right? Well, so, all right, let's,
let's,
let's pick up Catholicism.
It's easy because so much of the
structure is visible to us. Okay.
I would argue that Catholicism
is going to be true of all
of Christianity. It's going
to be true of Judaism,
but Catholicism is,
it is easy to see how it would facilitate
collaboration that effectively it
would recreate in some sense the insight
that you're talking about from DMT and
that it would instantiate it in the
population in a useful way that would
facilitate collaboration and disrupt
processes that cause infighting.
So spending before it
might be a structure,
it's a scaffolding for human behavior
and ethics. Right? But imagine, I mean,
we can see it in Catholicism.
I know where it is.
So every week you have to go and confess
the shit you're doing wrong to the dude
in the box. Okay. That's how they
used the spine, you know? I mean,
that's what that was for. Well,
but why are they spying on you?
I mean knows they want to make sure
that they don't get overthrown. I don't,
I think, I think you're too cynical. Yeah,
because what do you think they're doing
well? So, first of all, I'm a biologist.
Okay.
How are these priests who don't marry
passing on their genes? They're not. Oh,
they are. Oh, what are they
doing? They're sneaky. No,
they're facilitating the stability of
the lineage that they are in charge of.
So the point is they don't
pass on their genes directly.
They're passing on their genes
indirectly through the population.
Their interests are synonymized
with the population that they are.
Um, they are preaching too. And
so you tell the dude in the box,
which you've been doing wrong. Imagine
it's adultery. Okay? Oh God, I'm,
if I die before next week and I haven't
confessed my adult, you go to hell,
I'm going to go to hell. That dad had very
unpleasant place. I'm telling that guy,
it doesn't get to have
someone to tell him.
So now the person had been committing
adultery with his thinking. Oh Shit. Well,
I was going to keep this a secret,
but now the priest is going to know that
I've been committing adultery because
he's going to hear from the other person.
And so I better confess too.
So now the priest has a sense of like,
oh, there's an adultery problem in the,
in the congregation. And
the priest is, you know,
flipping through the book and thinking
how this week, what should we talk about?
And so, you know, the priest then gets
up at the pulpit and, uh, you know,
turn your book to it's all and whatever,
um,
and starts going on about adultery and
the people in the congregation who are
engaged in adultery or thinking, Oh
shit, this is god talking to me directly.
God knows what I've been
up to and he's not happy.
And that's why we're reading this psalm.
I better cut it the fuck out. Right?
So my point is,
the dude in the box,
he's taken a vow of poverty.
He's living in the church.
He does well when the
town does well. Um, he,
he's not having babies of his own,
so he can't really get ahead by himself.
He gets ahead genetically speaking
when the town does well and he's in a
position to spot what's
going wrong in the town.
And he doesn't have a dog in that fight
because he's not involved in business.
He's not involved in mating and dating.
If you don't know saw relatively recent
when it comes to the Catholic church in
the last couple of hundred years.
And I would argue if you look
back at any of these traditions,
any of the ones that worked
well successfully have
addressed the question of how
you prevent corruption from emerging.
Well apparently it was sexual corruption.
These guys were rock stars.
Like the priests were essentially the,
the guys who had the direct line to God
and just like professors have been known
to do, not you, but you know, some
have sex with their students, you know,
and cause the students like
look at them like, oh my God,
I can't believe that professor sitting
down here with my work. And even mean,
it's like that's a very minor connection
in comparison to the connection to God.
Anybody who's going to have anybody
who's going to have power is in danger of
abusing it.
Sure.
I wouldn't say it's interesting that
in the Catholic church and in other
traditions where, uh, uh,
marriage and making money are impossible,
that these appear to be, uh, evolved.
Um, what's the word? Uh, it's like, um,
error correction or, or
protection from, from a virus.
So an outbreak of corruption in the church
is a bad thing from the point of view
of the wellbeing of the congregation.
And, uh, something that says, well,
if you're a priest and you're
spending money in town,
people are going to look at you funny
because you're not supposed to have money.
And if you're, you know,
hanging around with cute girls,
people are going to look at
you funny cause you're not
supposed to be having sex.
Um,
so this limits their ability
to get away with stuff.
I'm not saying it's zero,
obviously it's not.
But the idea that there
will be protections in, um,
in each tradition for this that
religions that don't successfully protect
against abuses of power,
um,
will succumb in competition to
religions that do it effectively.
And so you're absolutely correct that
all of the changes in a religious texts
that people believe in this,
that's all human beings making decisions
about what to keep and what to throw
out.
And I'm not arguing anything else.
What I am arguing is those that have been
insightful about what to keep from the
point of view of the particular problems
faced by the population that they are
in,
we'll have a competitive advantage
because they will function more cohesively
then a population of atheists who doesn't
have somebody looking out to prevent
outbreaks of competition inside the,
the lineage outbreaks of infighting.
So if you were looking at
it in an objective way,
like say if you were an alien from
another planet that didn't understand the
language and you just observing
the structure, you would
see as error correction.
The structure would say, oh, they realize
that there was an issue here with power.
And so they error corrected by making
these priests be celibate and then they
figured out a way to keep them from
having money and that'll keep them from
being invested in, you know? Okay,
yeah, I see what you're saying.
And I think it's very misleading people
who analyze things the way you and I
would because there's so much hocus pocus
associated with the structures that,
you know, it's like constantly
putting a finger in the,
in the eye of an analytical person. Of
course. I mean just the way they dress,
right?
I mean just the wearing the wizard costume
and holding the staff and sitting on
the golden throne and, and all of
it. I mean, all the pageantry to it.
It's all preposterous. I mean, I agree.
Looking at it as a modern person,
it looks preposterous to me. On the other
hand, there is no way I'm telling you,
I mean, most of my colleagues
I'm sure would disagree
with this, but I hope to um,
to show them to be wrong on this front.
The,
there is no way that the huge amount of
effort and resource that is invested in
these structures was an error,
cannot have been an evolutionary error.
Because if it was,
the huge investment that population's
put into these structures is an
opportunity for some population that
behaves in exactly the same way.
Except it doesn't make that error to win,
right?
But when you get power and then you
have the momentum of that power, um,
overcoming the, the population and
then you have positions where the,
the,
the behavior patterns are extremely
restrictive and you have to behave inside
these behavior patterns or there's
grave consequences. I mean,
you could conceivably run
that for a thousand years
without any error correction
and that's what you've got with Islam,
right?
You've got a very ancient form of religion
that Michael Shermer wrote a piece
about it that's pretty interesting where
he was talking about how it's the only
religion that didn't go
through the enlightenment and
he makes these comparisons
to like the corrections that have been
had with other religions as time's gone
on that haven't happened there. And you
could equate it to resource management.
You could create it to the part
of the world in which they live.
You could equate it.
There's a lot of different ways that
you could try to figure out why this
happened. But the reality is
that that thing has not changed.
That structure has not
changed for a long time.
I think you've hit on exactly the,
the right point.
Um,
Islams mechanism for preventing
outbreaks of chain parasitism was to,
to hard code the thing.
And this is a tragedy because it,
what it means is that where Islam needs
to update it doesn't have the mechanism
for doing it. So, uh,
but also has a built in
way to keep people a board.
Like if you become an apostate that you're
allowed to, you can kill them. Right.
And kill apostates which is there is no
other religion that we have right now
that operates like,
that has draconian commissions.
If Scientology did that
right. Well, I mean,
Scientology obviously has a huge number
of completely unacceptable mechanisms to
keep people from leaving.
Well,
but how is that not a cult since it was
created by a science fiction writer?
Literally out of nowhere.
I'm going to be horrified if I said
it wasn't a cult too early to tell.
Right. How's that possible? Okay. So that
could be some benefits in the future.
Scientology continues to
evolve and self correct.
It could get to the point where it's
a behavior pattern that could be
complimentary.
And perhaps even beneficial to people.
I do not believe that this
is where it is headed.
But if a thousand years from now it
had flourished and the population that
believed these things was
successfully, uh, growing,
you'd have to say, well, there's
something in that set of beliefs.
It's working for these
folks. Um, so anyway, I,
I'm not arguing that it isn't a called,
it has lots of hallmarks that
make me think I'm troubled by
much like Mormonism. You know, the guy who
made it, but this, and unlike Mormonism,
which was an 1820,
we have video,
we see l Ron Hubbard is bad teeth and
his fucking captain's outfit on with the
metals that he gave himself.
Hey, what is this? Right. Oh, right.
Oh, you get a planet when you die,
or something like that. It sounds like a
cult to me. On the other hand, you know,
I mean, we've got the Mormons get
a planet when you're dying. Sorry.
Cytologist don't get a
planet. No, no. The Mormons
do. And it was in one of the,
uh, Osman brothers albums.
They all went to these planets, like in
the album. I forget what the album is.
It's a hilarious album. But if
you open it up, it's all planets.
And the album,
the name of the album is this concept
that you get a planet when you die.
This is something that's believed to me
because I am universe is so big we can
each afforded
it is the plan. That's it. See that, uh,
that is some Joseph Smith Shit.
By the way. It's a wonderful book.
If you, if you read the, the
actual origins of Mormonism
people to listen and go,
wait a minute, what do they
believe? Wow. Did they believe
some wacky stuff? But, uh,
he,
uh,
he had a golden or a seer stone rather
that allowed him to read the golden
tablets.
The seer stone was a special magic rock
that allowed him to read these golden
tablets that contained the last work of
Jesus cause at the inside of the album
with all the planets.
So I, I believe he was actually
illiterate and that was a con man.
He was murdered,
put a sheet over his head and dictated
what he was supposedly reading to
somebody else. That's my
understanding of it. But, um,
it was a charismatic person. Like many
people have created cults. He was, um,
I think what they did right. Mormon. Yeah.
Are some of the nicest
people I've ever met.
They have an amazing sense of community.
They're super nice.
And I've always said that if
I was going to join a call,
I think I had joined the Mormons,
but where they fucked up as
they regulations came in,
they started restricting the market.
They started,
the regulators came in and stop these
people from having nine wives and then
they're not going to be so nice anymore.
The reason why they were so
nice is because they have
these crazy relationships.
There were having orgies every night.
We had nine people living in the house.
Then they allowed to have sex with.
There's a problem with your, they,
because for everybody who had nine wives,
they were eight dudes who had not.
Those guys got to get their shit together
and start their own coal gas where you
know, well, maybe they are gay. I don't
know. Um, what about the women too, right?
Well. How about a woman who
has 10 husbands? You know,
this is bullshit for her.
That doesn't happen. Yeah, it should
right now be possible. No, no.
See there's a really good
biological reason biologically,
and it doesn't make any sense, but
you were digging deep. Oh Man, don't,
don't,
don't go polyandrous on me.