Like we were talking about before,
when you meet someone who can give you
a lesson and express something in a way
that makes you reconsider your own
ideas that you hold sacred. I mean,
I'll give you an example.
When I,
when I met my wife 30 years ago,
I,
I wasn't pro death penalty,
but I was,
I would say I would say neutral to the
death penalty. I would be like, you know,
ted Bundy, the state can
put him to death. Uh,
and I had all the kind of conventional
reasons or I didn't really care.
He's a vile person. He killed all
these people. He tortured them.
If the families will get any
relief, whatever, that's fine.
I had some concerns because I was this
statistician about a conviction of the
innocent and I support
the innocence project.
And I am very concerned
with police brutality.
I have for years been
advocating the racializing a
police brutality is vile and,
and uh, uh, porridge and must be
firmly resisted. Uh, I think that,
um, I think the, the,
the prosecutorial misconduct to people
are prosecutors lie and put people in
prison. Uh, you know, there've been many,
many cases of people on death row who
are innocent that should offend our
conscience.
So even back then I had some concerns
about the death penalty because I, um,
because I, I recognize that,
you know, we can't be perfect.
We're going to convict some innocent
people and also let some guilty people go
free. That's not as bad as killing
the, putting to death, the innocent,
but they're both bad. So I had that
concern about the death penalty,
but otherwise I was like, it's okay.
My opinions have totally changed.
I'm completely opposed to the
death penalty now for many reasons.
Not just the statistical reason,
but also I think it's immoral.
I don't think the state
should put it down.
I think we can deprive you of liberty.
I think we can make sure
you're not a threat to society.
We can lock you up for the rest
of your life. But I think we, uh,
the state should not be taking
people's lives in that way.
There's something extraordinarily
strange about locking someone up.
It's very strange. Well, we have a
carceral state. I mean, you know,
we lock up a higher we have is,
we are fraction of people incarcerated
I think is the same as Stalinist Russia.
And we have very long prison sentences,
which are nuts.
You don't need them for deterrence
actually for nonviolent drug,
especially for non all nonviolent
offenses should have much shorter prison
doesn't, we should have more, we should
have higher certainty of punishment.
Higher fraction of people
who have actually committed
crimes should be punished.
But I think we should,
we could cut in half or less the,
the duration of the senses.
I think you'll be able to deter criminals
from doing things with a three month
sentence if they are very confident
that they will be convicted if they're
caught.
Whereas now we have a system where
most are not convicted like this Jesse
Smollett thing, which is just
ridiculous in the news and uh, uh,
and which therefore, and only a
tiny fraction are convicted and,
but they're giving huge long sentences.
It's like they're paying the sense
for everyone that didn't. Yes.
It doesn't make any
sense and it's expensive.
It ties up our prison
system actually. Um, can I,
can I go to tell you another story?
True.
So it was a situation a few years
ago when there's a fairly famous, um,
uh, director and writer by the name of
David Simon, who I consider a friend.
He did the wire, he was a show runner
for a bunch of other very famous, uh,
wonderful, uh, TD programs.
And he started his career actually
as a reporter in a, in Baltimore.
He was a beat reporter and then
went on to become a writer,
did the wire and so forth.
And he told the story, uh,
actually at Yale to students about how
he had just come back from a summit.
President Obama was still president where,
um,
he was trying to help the students to
see that you can find common ground with
your political opponents and that you
need to listen to them and talk to them in
order to find that ground. Uh, if, and
so he told the following story, he said,
I had, I just came back
from Camp David where, uh,
there was a meeting about how to
reduce incarceration in our society.
And he said, the Koch brothers were
there and the students all hissed,
and Newt Gingrich was there,
and the students all hissed and a
bunch of liberal people were there.
And the students were really happy
about that. And then they said, well,
why did you go, how could you associate
yourself with those evil people?
And he said, look, he said, the,
the conservatives want to reduce
incarceration because it's expensive.
The liberals want to reduce
incarceration because it's unjust.
And the libertarians want to
reduce incarceration because
the state shouldn't be
depriving people of Liberty.
And I can find common ground with
these people and reduce incarceration.
Why would I not talk to them? And the
students didn't seem to understand that.
They were like,
they couldn't get it.
That's why they shouldn't
be able to vote it to be 30.
There should be 25. I mean, and so the, I
don't know how we got onto this, you know,
like talking to you is so much fun because
it's like we're all over the place.
But, um, how did I get a
come up with this example?
We were talking about talking
to a political enemies,
was it or something else?
Yes. We're talking about people telling
you that you shouldn't associate yes.
People that have varying opinions.
Yes, yes. And you know, Oh, I know.
We were talking about incarceration
and prison sentences and so forth.
So we have a horrible problem in our
society with, with incarceration,
a larger fraction of our
populace as incarcerated.
We deprive after you paid your debt to
society, we often have these, these, uh,
we deprive you of your right to vote,
which I think is wrong.
You've paid your debt to society.
You should be able to reenter society.
That's appliances. Exactly. Yes.
Exactly. You were in prison for 10 years.
That's enough. You know, now you,
we want you to feel a part of society and
we want to welcome you back if we have
that vision of justice.
How about the registered sex offender?
That's a serious problem, especially
for, uh, crimes. You know,
these crazy cases which
offend my conscience.
I know a guy who got
charged as a registered sex
offender because he urinated
outside. Yeah. That's not caught in the
south. Urinating outside. That's nuts.
That's just a prosecutorial abuse.
Or you know,
you have these Romeo and Juliet laws,
which are not in every state now.
Thank God the alas, they are not
in every state. Uh, you know,
you have a 16 year old boy
and a 14 year old girl.
There have to be exceptions for that
kind of sexual practice. You know,
they're exchanging a
sexually explicit images.
They should not be considered sex
offenders for the rest of their lives.
That's nuts. So, um, so
yes, so all of those things,
but the problem is not only do we have
a huge fraction of people in prison,
we have extremely long prison sentences
compared to any many European countries
for the same crime. And it's costly.
It's unjust, it's ineffective.
I think. I think we should change the
policies on this and maybe we will. Yeah.
There's also the idea of
reforming them. It's, it's,
they're not using all the
tools within their disposal.
They're not really doing
a good attempted it.
And I just don't think it does anything
other than make their life hell for a
short period of time,
which we're hoping we hope deters
them from doing future crime.
Well, they're different. There's the
justice, there's deterrence, their safety,
right? Like so violent criminals that
we put in jail. Uh, we need to do that.
I mean to, I'm not interested in being
killed by somebody who, you know,
could it killed someone else? She should
have been you in jail for a while,
20 years. So I'm not at a
time. People, yeah, for murder.
I think 20 years is enough.
Well a European,
a European standards are
about 20 years actually.
And that there are different things,
like if you wanted to pry them, if your,
if your vision is they're being
punished for the killing of a life,
therefore they've surrendered their life.
It's sort of eye for an eye
kind of justice. You would,
they would be the rest of their
lives in jail. And you know, I,
we can debate whether that's
reasonable or not. If you,
if you want to provide a public safety,
we is.
And people often age out of their
violence. So a lot of men, typically,
these were talking mostly about men
who do these things. Uh, you know,
by the time they're in their forties
or 50s, they're much less violent.
Testosterone declines. They get older
and wiser. Uh, they're not interested in,
in criminal, in that kind of criminal
behavior. Many of them are not. So that,
does that suggest you don't
need life sentences for murder?
And I think it also depends on we have
for gradations of murder, you know,
we have like the impulsive stuff that
intent matters of planfulness matters,
that depravity matters.
All of these things are,
are factors and I don't think we should
have a one size fits all incarceration
for murder. Yes. That's my
opinion. What do you think?
I think it depends entirely
on the circumstances.
If two men are engaged in some sort of
a dispute and one winds up killing the
other one,
that's a big difference between that
and someone breaking into your house and
killing your daughter.
Yes. A correct. And I also
think even in that, like I,
I really am opposed to these stand
your ground laws. I think those are,
if you have the opportunity to avoid
conflict and to avoid you or not,
uh, it, I would prefer as a state
to require that you walk away.
Uh, even if it makes you
feel embarrassed, uh,
then give you the right to kill
someone for offending you in those,
those videos of the, of the guys in
that shot, the guy on his knees in the,
in the parking lot in the,
I forgot what state it was like a,
not a year or two ago, they got into
an altercation in the parking lot.
Like if I have words with someone at
a party shot a guy on his knee. Yes.
There was no threat to him and he was,
he was not prosecuted on the stand
your ground argument, which is nuts.
Why was the guy on his knees?
He was, I forgot. I see.
Don't shoot me or something.
Oh, Jesus. So it was, it was crazy. He
didn't get prosecuted. I don't think so.
We can look up the facts
that were several cases.
There were several cases like this,
but you know,
like I remember when I
was doing shotokan karate,
my Sensei Kazumi Tabata,
this was years ago, uh,
30 years ago now. And he told
us the following story. He,
he said there was a Sensei in this village
in Japan and the students were coming
to the Dojo. And, uh, there was
the, the, the best student that,
you know,
and then all the other students,
and they were walking through the village
and they passed the approach to horse
that was on the street from the rear.
And it startled the horse.
And as the horse reared up and
kicked his leg, the, the, uh,
the best student instantly did a,
a kind of a avoidance,
kind of a twisted his body and avoided
the kick. And the, and the, and the, uh,
the horse's leg went right in front
of him and all the other students were
amazed at his ability and they get
to the Dojo and they tell the Sensei,
this is my sensei telling me this story,
telling all of us this story. And they,
those students get to this,
the Dojo and they tell the Sensei
the story marveling at the,
at the ability of this master student
to definitely avoid the strike.
And the Sensei is very angry and they
don't understand why, why is he so angry?
He said if he were a really
good student of mine,
he would have walked on the
other side of the street.
He would have avoided
the horse all together.
So the real wisdom is to avoid avoidance
of conflict in the first place.
There's no reason to seek out conflict.
And so on the stand your ground laws,
you know, if the choices ether you just
avoid the conflict, you know, someone,
someone swore at you or called you an
asshole or was an unreasonable jerk,
that doesn't give you the right to
kill them. Right. Um, so anyway,
I don't know how we got onto this as well.
How are we going to the penalty for
Kaiser murder. Exactly. Exactly.
So, so, so different
gradations. Yeah. Yeah.
I just don't know how much of a
deterrent it is locking people up.
I just, I, I'm not sure.
I'm not really sure if that actually
stops people from doing things.
I think it stops some people. I think
there've been academic research on this.
I just don't think there's any real
rehabilitation other than personal choice.
I mean,
I think the real rehabilitation comes
from someone making a personal choice to
never be that person that way. Again.
Yes. For most of them you're, you're,
you're being locked up with a bunch
of hardened criminals and you, your,
that's your,
your company.
But you're not suggesting we have a
society in which when you commit violent
acts, we do nothing. No, I'm
not. No, I'm not. No. I'm,
I'm suggesting struggling with this is
what you're saying. Yeah. The, yeah,
the concept of nuances. Yes. This is,
this is applied here than anywhere else.
I think I got the impression looking at
your face a moment ago when I told my
sort of sweet Sensei, Japanese
karate story that you didn't
agree necessarily. No.
That's a very wise way of
looking at it. Yeah. Don't,
don't be near a fucking horse that
wants to kick you. Very smart. Yeah.
Get out of there. I'm a big believer
in avoiding conflict. Yeah. I'm, I'm,
I'm the first guy we use. It'll conflict
on intellectual conflict. Exactly.
Physical words and violence are different.
Extremely different.
Yeah.
I mean,
intellectual conflict at that is actually
important and you learn from it. Yes.
Very rarely do you learn too much from
you. You learn, don't do that again,
that's what you learned
from physical conflict.