Yeah. Like I think Robbie Lawler stopped
doing it. I think cowboy, I think,
oh these guys,
Robbie stopped sparring completely for
years while he's fighting for strike
force. But then when he
moved to a American top team,
he started sparring again and it was
training really hard and that's when
actually he became the welter weight
world champion. He's so fucking tough.
Like I want to see that ask
and fight again cause he,
I put my money on Robbie Lawler
that he does not care about.
He looked better than I've
ever seen him as crazy shape.
I've gone back and forth about five
times on whether or not that was a good
stoppage,
but Huseman convinced me after we watched
the footage that was a bad stoppage.
I think Robbie was okay. I think, uh,
he just relaxed. He was there. He had,
what have I done? I mean how many more
seconds, but that bulldog just time or,
but yeah, but for Robbie Lawler, I think
he was all right. But it's hard to tell.
It's just unfortunate.
And again,
herb dean is as good a referee
as there is on planet earth.
There is no one better than him.
There's no one better.
Herb Dean is as good as it
gets. Yeah, he made a mistake,
but it's hard to say if it was a mistake
because I wasn't even sure it was a
mistake.
We were not sure better to err on the
side of caution because he couldn't hear
him. He couldn't talk.
But here's the thing,
he's only getting choked out like
if it's been aspirin, it's only,
he's only get choked out if it's
Frances and Ghana and he's
fucking punching you in
the head and you think your
unconscious then stopped the fight.
Right. But if it's just a choke,
like Ben asked her and is not
known for being in any way,
shape or form of power striker.
No,
and he's not hitting them now he's only
holding onto his neck and I think that
shows have been how tough bad astronauts.
Cause he got his head bounced
off that fucking, I was like,
you're getting crushed here.
And he was just like, whatever,
I'm going to stick to my wrestling.
Yeah, he was getting fucking pounded,
but he figured it out and he,
even though they disengaged,
he managed to get ahold of Robbie again
and get them on the ground and get that
choke on. Yeah, look, it was,
it was fun while it lasted,
but he doesn't want to fight Robbie again.
I think if I was the UFC I
would be absolutely trying
to make that fight again.
Do you think they will know? I think they
want to, that's what Dana White said.
But Ben said, why would I want to do
that? I already went already. One quote.
I want to do that. But the thing about,
you know, like Kamara was saying like,
you don't get a choice. Like the UFC is
going to tell you who to fight again.
Maybe they just offer Ben good amount
of money off from Robbie is Robbie is,
uh,
you know,
he deserves that privilege and I think
he's easily up there and he can always be
the champion again, that got more
on his clothes. He looks good.
He looks as good as he's ever
looked. Yes. It looked amazing.
It looked amazing physically. He looked
amazing when he was fighting. Um,
even more importantly,
I think that's the fight that makes the
most money because people want to see
that. I want to see it. You
want to see it. All the real
fans want to see it. Yeah.
I think I'm doing enough of that in USA.
They do sometimes.