Her low freak bitches. It's like
there's no, there's no respect for like,
like what we have, how much different, how
much higher standard of living we live.
Then the vast, you know, uh,
most humans that are alive today and the
vast majority of humans who have ever
existed. I mean, it's like, what is, I get
this from a Jordan Peterson lecture, uh,
but he said, uh, it was an 1895.
The average American lived on a dollar
a day adjusted for modern inflation.
So in 1895, you know, it's like,
like central Asia level poverty in
America and that's just everyone.
Before that living in backbreaking
poverty was like just life.
That was just all of life. And it's like
we figured something out in these last,
uh, uh, less than 200 years, you know,
like we figured something out
a little more than 200 years.
We've figured something out. Wait, what
am I saying? No, no, no, let's listen.
200 years.
We've figured something out
in this industrial revolution
that like now lets us
live up here on this end.
It's like, we can lose that.
And a lot of it has to do with freedom,
but the whole thing to me is freedom.
The whole thing is that we
embrace, look, if you look in
in the year, um, uh, and uh,
that you had on your show,
Thaddeus Russell, who's great,
I just did his podcast recently and
he put it this way, uh, where he goes,
you know,
in the year 1800,
cause I was talking about
what an incredible thing
the 19th century was and how
it transformed humanity.
And he goes to the,
in the year 1800 Americans are all making
their own clothes in the year 1900.
Uh, Americans are shopping
at Macy's. Like we,
if you had said in the year, you know,
in the year 1845 and been like, dude,
in the next 65 years,
slavery is going to be abolished in
the West and we're going to have an
industrial revolution.
You know,
it's like magic happen and that's
why we live the way we live today.
And no one is even interested
in that story, right?
Like why do we have this much wealth?
I like what you said.
I think it's all about freedom and when
you have a guy like Bernie Sanders who
harps on and on about income inequality,
I have a real issue with that because
it's one of those blanket statements that
sounds really good at a campaign speech,
but freedom itself breeds
income inequality. Yes,
because freedom means you
can do whatever you want.
You can do very little or you
can work like a maniac. Well,
if you're going to work, like if
you're, if here's the game, okay,
you do something for that.
Something. You get currency,
you use that currency to buy things or
to make sure you don't have to work again
by food and goods and take trips
and travel. The more you work,
the more you decide that you
want to pursue something,
the more chances you have to acquire
their currency. If you do it correctly.
That is income inequality due to freedom.
I mean take away all the other factors
that might be, you know, in play,
whether it's racial discrimination
or sexual discrimination.
I'm not denying that those things exist.
But what I am saying is that the idea
that you are going to have income equality
in a capitalist society where anybody
could do whenever they want, you know,
people that is so counter to what we
know about human behavior. This is,
you're talking about a
fantasy person who exist,
who has motivations outside of
wealth outside of, uh, you know,
that most people want some sort
of reward for what they do.
And if everybody gets the same amount,
there's no fucking reward
for working extra hard.
And that's going to where you're
not going to get Microsoft,
you're not going to get IBM. It's
going to get just, I mean, it's not,
it's not just, I mean they
talk about fairness a lot,
which is a strange concept,
but it's not just that somebody works
twice as hard and doesn't get more,
I mean that's, that that's not
the right thing to do anyway.
But like what you were saying,
and I just think it's like
they use the term so much,
but what's misleading about it?
You're absolutely right,
that freedom breeds inequality.
But what's misleading about it is that
people think like the poor get poorer.
And that is objective. That is a,
a you like objective lead false,
demonstrably false.
It's not that, you know,
they make it out like the rich get richer
and the poor get poorer like that old
saying, but it's like that, you know,
if you think it through like that
can't really continue like that. No,
but the poor guy was going to have rich.
But if the poor work hard and figure they
haven't possibility to escape whatever
economic situation they're in,
it is possible with freedom and
homeless people here live better than,
than rich people in Third World countries
or I'm certainly at least better than
average people in third world
countries. Uh, so it's like,
it's not just that the inequality grows,
it's like everything moves up
and the inequality grows up here.
And this is like what I just, what
I can't understand. And, and again,
it's like why I was saying before,
like if you have any concept of the fact
that we're by far the richest freest
human beings who have ever
existed in recorded human history,
at least recorded human history. Who
knows what is going on in ancient Egypt,
but like a pro before in Geneva.
But uh,
but if you realize that we have this
incredible amount, then it's like, yeah,
it's like just being like,
oh,
we need all of these policies to like
give handouts to poor people. It's like,
well actually let's continue this train
of getting richer and richer and richer,
which is not at all, you know, like what,
what people like Bernie Sanders, man.
It's like, well, it's a hustle.
Bernie's got a hustle going on. Yeah.
And just find out a shell.
So you find out it's a hustle when you
find out he's got a bunch of houses and
his wife tried to buy up all this fucking
land to expand a university that she
was running and she killed the
whole fucking school. Like you.
How about the fact that the motherfucker
and we haven't seen, so first off he,
he made $1 million off a book on how it's
wrong to be a millionaire. I mean it's,
it's like how are you not,
how can anyone look at you like as
a serious leader when you did that?
So you know saying what people want
to hear and there is something,
some truth to some of the
things that he's saying.
I think that the world would be a better
place if we had more social programs in
place. I think the world be a better place
if college were free. If we, I think,
I mean I don't disagree with
like the thought behind that.
I think that all of these things
would be better suited in voluntary
arrangements then some
force government monopoly.
But I do agree with you that like sure.
I'd like great schools to be very
affordable or free if possible.
I'd like everyone to be [inaudible] and
Bernie Sanders certainly addressed some
very real problems. Like he would
point things out that were very real.
Like he would be like, you know, they
claim it's a great recovery, but you know,
90% of the new wealth has
gone to the top 3%. You know,
like he eat up some points.
I only do one or two and that has to
apply to every New York Jew who's out
there. Uh, but like,
so like there is some,
and I don't care if Bernie
Sanders makes $1 million,
but there is something like number one,
making $1 million while claiming it's
kind of a moral issue that some people
have so much. What others have so bad.
All Endorsing Hillary Clinton. I mean,
I just don't know how you can,
how you can look at the guy who goes,
the problem is incoming inequality
and these [inaudible] and the banking,
you know, cartel. But I'm going to vote
for the candidate of the big banks.
Like to me that's, that's
insane. It, it would,
to me it would be if Ron
Paul endorsed McCain.
Well don't you think the big banks sort
of were on both teams? Yeah, well not,
I don't know if they were on Trump's team,
but they've certainly been on.
Every other team decides that now. Yeah.
Yeah. No, certainly. I'm absolutely,
it's only like the team. They
run the Treasury Department
in the Federal Reserve,
like they run the whole system,
but the fact that Bernie Sanders never
had like a fiery speech about what
happened at the DNC about
how they literally conspired
to ruin him and to take
him out of the race with
Hillary because they,
the DNC wanted Hillary
to be the candidate.
Okay.