The Joe Rogan experience.
So what would you think about if they
abandoned weight cutting [inaudible] they
just opened up more weight classes
and abandoned weight cutting.
I mean I wouldn't mind it. I
would, I would like to see that.
Don't think it'd be
better for the fighters.
I think it'd be better for the fighters
and [inaudible] really cool matchups
yeah.
You know what I mean?
Cause there's some guys that cut a lot
of weight and there's some match ups that
would be really cool at
different weights too.
I think it's one of those dumb things
that's existed in the past and we never
corrected. Yeah. I think,
I think we should stop it.
It's not helping anybody to lose weight
for a fight so that you can be fit and
in great shape. Yeah. F okay,
sure. But how do you go about that?
But I mean losing weight,
like losing weight and training,
not like massive dehydration.
Yeah.
For weight cut day and then rehydration
the next day for fight day. I think it's,
it's a crazy strain that guys are doing
to their kidneys and their bodies.
I mean many fighters have told me that
they don't feel like they can take a body
shot as well when they cut a lot of
weight like that. Sometimes the your head,
my head, I remember on the Johnny
Walker fight, I'd cut, excuse me,
it could have been from the Weight Cup,
but that morning,
like if I've been tapped on my jaw,
I just felt like my head was just like
off like rally, you know, like yeah,
it felt very sensitive and he does from
the weight and the same night I get
knocked out.
I don't know what it was from,
but I remember feeling that morning
when I woke up. Cause usually I like,
I'll shake everything off. I'll like, you
know, like punching myself in the jaw,
all that stuff just to
get ready for the fight.
And I remember that that morning when
I was like tapping myself on the jaw,
my head just didn't feel right.
Dude. That's not a good feeling. No.
But I gotta checked after I didn't
have any like concussion or anything.
Did you have some particularly
hard sparring session or
something close to that?
Uh, I don't think close to
it during that camp. Uh,
like I said, I didn't feel it all the
way until I didn't have it. The only,
the only time I ever felt it
was like after the weight cut.
So it could have been
from that. Right. Yeah.
And I think that morning I actually ended
up cutting the last little bit of my
weight, the morning of weigh ins
too, which is not usually like me.
I'll usually cut it the night before.
So you said you like to start
your day off with a run. Um,
are you doing that every
day? Yeah, definitely.
So that's one thing that I learned too
is just training every day. Not Learn,
but it just feels different.
Now I have to go and train every
day when I was in Vegas, like, ah,
I've got to drive 30 minutes,
you know, all of these things.
I had a lot of excuses to make up.
And now with the convenience
of how training is now,
I don't even make up excuses. I'm like, if
I'm tired, I still, it's two minute walk,
get your ass to the gym. You
know, and so yeah, every,
every single day training and
then weekends off for sure.
So you're running every single day,
then you're training every single day
before Moitai it's mandatory. You run.
But like the train, train, train and
real, she ruined first. You show up,
you run the day. The first
day I showed up, uh, at,
at Tiger's Moitai class, I
didn't even, tennis shoes.
I just showed up with my flip flops
because I was staying right across the
street and I showed up. I start wrapping
my hands in the trainer. He's like,
are you going to train? And I was like,
yeah, I think so. He's like, you think so?
We'll go run. And I was like, I don't
have shoes. Only had my flip flops.
And he's like just pointed like so go run.
And I had to run like,
I think it was like eight kilometers in,
in flip flops before I even trained.
Yeah, that's like four
miles. Yeah, somewhere around
there. Five and a half. Yeah.
It's like four, like four miles, something
like that. We just had to run, run, run,
run, run, run. I asked the girls
like, how long do we run? Four.
She's like usually like five to six
kilometers or something like that. Yeah,
it was like five ks. Like
three and a half months. Yeah,
I'd say like just cutting
it short. Five K. Wow.
And then in flip flops and I was
like, okay, cool. Yeah, I never,
I never forgot my shoes again. I would
always show up at that. Fuck your feet up.
It wasn't too bad actually now because
I wasn't wearing shoes a lot anyway.
Oh yes.
Thailand.
Sometimes you had to take off your
shoes before you enter the store. So,
so they're,
they're hard assed in their discipline
with the wanting you just serious about
very serious. Yeah. They're just serious
about it. They're like, show respect,
you know?
And when you're running,
you're running with a group of
guys or everybody, guys, girls,
whoever shows up to class. But is it
is like, okay, so when they're running,
are they running, like organize
like in a group or are they just,
is everybody running a few miles
before class? Every time. The first,
the first Muay Thai gym that I trained
at the straight Moitai Jim in Bangkok,
they run as a unit every
day 5:00 AM. Wow. As a team.
They live at the gym, they eat at
the gym, they sleep in the gym.
They are like,
they don't have homes there.
Home is the gym and their job
is just fight and eat, sleep,
train, fight. That's it.
It's crazy when they even take on the
name of the gym. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
And that's a whole different life.
Like that is what made me respect and
learn and love Moitai so much as how these
guys trained in just they live
together, everything. It was amazing.
So they run as a group,
but the other like the other place,
we all start off,
but if you,
if someone's laughing you and they
just want to run fast, like it's,
it's totally fine. But before the
class everybody has to go. Yeah. Wow.
That's a smart way to do it,
man.
I mean if you could really convince
them to be conditioned all the time and
there's no like you have no option.
You can't be out of condition if you're
going to run five miles every day,
no five miles. And then hitting, kicking,
hitting and kicking pads for five to 10
rounds a day, clinching 45 minutes a day,
like clenching at after every session.
It's like you run knee bag, sit
ups, all that stuff. Second,
second session is,
um,
kick the bag three to five rounds until
a trainer picks you up. Like for me,
I had to wait for a trainer to actually
even like want to hold pads for me.
If you just show up, you'll
just be hitting the bag
until the trainer was like,
Hey, okay, I'll hold for you.
And then once you actually find a
trainer that wants to work with you,
then you kind of,
whatever their schedule is for you that
they'll create it though you'll hold the
whole pads, you'll kick
the bag, you'll do pushups,
he'll do sit ups and then clinch 30 to
45 minutes after and it's the same thing
every single day.
Wow.
And do you ever worry that this might
be something that would be monotonous
because you're doing
the same way every day?
Or did you think we just concentrate
on excellence? No, because it's also,
uh, like going to the fights and
there's so many different styles.
So like people are doing the same
thing every day. The repetition,
but the styles are completely different.
You know,
like nobody fights like
sand Chai. Right, right.
He does the same thing everybody else
does. But he has his own style. Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Or some guys will do the same thing,
but they don't even like to kick or knee.
They just like to throw elbows.
I know plenty of guys like that where they
just like, you know that when he goes,
he's just throwing elbows all five rounds.
Yeah,
this guy's just going to throw knees.
So it's just like,
which tools do you use the, it's like,
are you a near, are you at a kicker?
Are you an elbow guy or you left cake?
Are you a low kicker?
It's kind of like what's what
strikes are your, are your thing.
And then you go watch the chaos and
these guys are getting split open every
night fucking on the stretchers. They
take them stretchers on the rig, man,
it's amazing. Wow. It's like not to see
someone get hurt, but like just the,
the fact that like these guys
are all out brawl every night.
Every single night there's a
fight at the stadium. Sure.
Thursday nights are the
nights that like the,
like the higher guys go and they're
packed with people. Thousands of people.
Like the one I went to, there was a few
thousand people there for the stadium.
It looked pack and
everyone's betting like, ah.
And then when the kicks land, I'm like,
Oh hey, I just, the energy is crazy. Wow.
They never showed up, man. I'm
getting hyped thinking about it.
Going back to Thailand right now.