All right.
Anyone with 18 of anything,
unless you're like a salt and you probably
don't have a ton anyway unless you're
Jeff Bezos. Yeah. Well that
was uh, yeah, he could,
he could marry a hundred chicks
and give them all a billion.
That's how you still that 50
leftover. What? Yeah, he's doing good.
He's doing good. But that whole thing
with him, that was an interesting thing.
The uh,
the pictures being leaked and it turns
out that the brother that leaked the
pictures,
I love the brother immediately as soon
as I read the article because I'm like,
this is Trump's daughter,
not only is a Trump supporter,
this is a guy who's tried to leverage
himself forever and he found out his hits
was fucking Jeff Paizos. Can you
imagine the night he found that out?
The night he found that out?
Where was he? What was he doing?
He was somewhere thinking,
this is it. She's fucked.
A lot of people that are good now.
She's fucking basis now. Some cash in.
Now it's time to think of something good.
How do we do it? This is a plot in guy.
I wonder what they inquire gave him how
much money you get for something like
that. Half a mil. Bayzos Dick. I
want more. I want a solid mill.
Solid mill. You think that's kind
of the life he's going to kill you.
You think he will? If he doesn't, I'll
be disappointed. It's a good point.
And make it look like an accident.
If you're a fucking, you know
he's, he's like daddy Warbucks.
Yeah, he's the guy. He's the guy.
He's kind of hundreds automated.
Everything's automated.
Everything and Amazon's like
notoriously like he's an alien.
He looks like he's artificial
intelligence. He's Ai.
He has that look already.
He's super smart and he can
play it real slow. Yeah.
Helen slave the world and you know what?
Let him,
he's probably going to hire somebody
to fuck up that guy's life slowly.
I'm sure you're ready. Has real
slow. Oh yeah. This is your new job.
Your new job is to slowly make dark guys
lodash. Yeah. Everything. Everything.
Flat tires every day.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I love the henchman that's going at
nailing flat tires. Yeah. Set up.
He's going to check for cameras. That's
amazing. Yeah. The at the base offices,
those are the new type. Like cause I
studied a lot about like Rockefeller,
Carnegie, guys like that. And those guys,
nobody say amassed a fortune of those
guys had Rockefeller had like 336 billion
in today's dollars. Good Lord. Yeah.
Carnegie at 372 billion. I mean these,
these were the first, how much
do they have in their time? Ah,
cause the questions and there are times,
I don't know, but in, in it was millions.
Well I don't think it was billions,
but in our time it's about,
it's the over 300 million. Both of them.
These were the first generation of B, B B.
This was the first
generation of Robert Bat.
Like the first generation
of entrepreneurs, you
know, the country was new.
All of these industries were just
emerging and these guys took it over.
Bayzos tech is, and somebody
said this on my podcast recently.
Tech is the closest thing we have now
to that where you have these, you know,
masters of the universe that are going
to be, I mean those guys were big.
Jp Morgan was like bailing
the government out.
These guys had an insane amount of power.
Um, they know what's really helpful.
Really interesting
figures. Yeah. I was just,
when I told you I was doing this chariots,
the gods lunch today with a bunch of
very influential people and one of them
said it's really ironic that apple used
to be think different and that was the
whole thing about silicon valley.
Think different now.
It's don't think different right now.
Streamline everybody into
one acceptable thing. Yeah.
Now it is literally you have to think
the way everyone else is thinking.
You have to believe what everyone else
believes, even if it's ridiculous.
I think a lot of that is they want to
just make money and sell things and they
don't want any discord. They just
want to sell, make money. Sort of.
But it seems like,
I don't think,
cause they don't band people after they
do the things they banned him after.
There's a public outcry. So to me they're
not, they don't have any real value.
It's their values are tangible and the
values are influenced by public opinion
and where media is, the values aren't
like when somebody says something,
let's ban,
and right now this goes against our thing.
A lot of it is if you wait until
there's enough dust kicked up,
then they will ban somebody.
Right. That's true. So to me,
I get in arguments with friends when
they're like their ideological, I'm like,
they have an ideological bet certainly.
But the profit seeking enterprises
that just want everyone to be happy.
I think if it was up to Twitter, every
tweet would be some type of branded ad.
And on top of that,
now the ideology is skewing and leaning
in that direction in terms of like tech
and sure, there's money in that.
There's money in holding that line.
And those guys are the ones that are as
powerful as Rockefeller and Carnegie and
JP, like all, all of those guys,
they are the next, you know,
generation of people who will,
their amount of power is,
is unmatched anywhere in society.