When you die, what's going to happen is
you don't know. You don't know. And the,
the reality is, look, maybe
there is an afterlife.
Maybe when we stop living,
something happens and are essential.
Energy goes into another dimension.
It's possible, but you don't know. Look,
being alive is so titanic bizarre.
Just being a human being,
looking through eyeballs at each other
across from this wooden table that was
cut down from living organisms that turn
into hearts sir surfaces Santam and saw
him and then he put it in a building
and it's got electricity rolling through
the walls. And if you stuck a fork in
there, you die. All of it is crazy.
The fact that we're in a planet,
I mean the fact that the universe is,
at least as far as we can tell,
infinite, all that stuff is crazy.
The idea that your essential energy
doesn't transfer into some other state.
Why not? Yeah, the whole thing is
crazy, but you don't know. That's right.
Know you don't know.
And to you,
whenever you say something that
you're not sure of and you say,
this is what's going to happen, but you
don't really know you're a huckster.
That's right. Yep. Absolutely.
No one knows. No one knows.
And that's the conclusion of heavens on
earth. I don't know. And you don't either.
I saw a bumper sticker that said
militant agnostic. I don't know.
And you don't either. Uh,
so I mean we have to. Okay,
so here's my bottom line on this
yet. I don't know. You don't.
No one knows for sure.
I'm happy to wake up in some great
place and there's all my friends.
It'd be awesome.
Unless,
unless God was mad that you didn't follow
the rules of the law. That's right.
Christopher Hitchens called the
Christian Heaven Celestial North Korea.
It's like,
here's this dictator that knows
everything you do and controls everything
forever. That's hilarious.
The less you'll North Korea,
but he doesn't tell you anymore.
I told you already,
I told you 2000 years ago this dude
wrote it down. Pay attention to that.
But then it's not even that.
Right?
It's like one guy might've
write it down a long time ago,
but then a bunch of other dudes
got together and how to revise it.
They had like a new draft and the
new draft, they get to decide.
People got to decide what goes
in and what doesn't go in.
And some of the stories are based on right
accounts from hundreds of years after
Jesus's death. Like the Bible is
a Wiki. It is like a Wiki. Yeah.
People contributed to over the
years and it's on Hitchins, uh,
at a great analogy with when he was dying,
he wrote a series of essays
for Vanity Fair. His column,
which you can get as a book now,
I think it's called mortality or something
like that. Anyway, one of them was, uh,
people think dying is like,
you're at a party and someone
tapped you on the shoulder and says,
you have to leave now. At
worse, the party's going to
go on without you. It's like,
oh no. He goes, okay, so let's play
this out. You're at the party, uh,
and you get tapped on the
shoulder and said, uh,
you can never leave. The party, you have
to stay here forever with these people.
Like when a Julie is funny lines is
the Mormon boys were telling her like,
in heaven, it's going to be great.
Um, uh, you, you, you get you,
you're made whole again,
like the blind shall see and the deaf
shall hear again in the crippled,
she'll be hold again. She said, well, um,
I had uterine cancer and I had my uterus
taken out. Do I get my uterus back?
And they're like, you can imagine these
18 year old guy, what's the uterus again?
And they're like, yeah, you
get your uterus back. She
goes, I don't want it back.
And then she said, what if he
had a nose job and you liked it?
Do I have to have my old nose back in
heaven? That's a good point. Yeah. So, uh,
and then they said,
uh,
and you get to spend the rest of eternity
with your family. And she went, oh no,
that would not be good in my case.
Maybe there'll be cured though.
They'll realize the errors of their
ways. There'll be all enlightened. Well,
here's the problem.
So this is called the problem of identity.
Who are you and you know the,
you know that Theseus the ship,
you know the Greek men guitar slayer
Theseus comes back and is a hero and they,
and they preserve his ship
and the museum forever,
but the wood rots and they replaced the
ship and over the centuries there's no
wood left from the original,
but it's still cherished is I call this
Schirmer's Mustang because my first car
was a 66 Ford Mustang, a classic. And I
had there for 19 years when those cars,
it's like it was a great car,
but I banged it up so much I
replaced this and that. And you know,
every pretty much by the time I sold it
as a classic and made it a nice little
chunk of change on it, there was
very little of the original left.
But it's the pattern,
not the material and accounts.
So this whole debate about when you're
resurrected in heaven with Jesus,
what's up there? Is it your physical
body? If it cause some Christian sex,
say yeah. It's like, okay, how
old are you when you're in heaven?
30 this is the year they came up with
because that's the age Jesus was when he
was crucified. Okay. But if Joe
Rogan or held for 40 something,
51 [inaudible] 51 okay. So if you're
resurrected at 30 year old Joe Rogan,
what happened to the last 21 years
of Joe Rogan's body memories?
I don't want to go back to that dude.
That dude was dumbing down.
You don't know you're happy where you
are in your life at this point. I'm sure.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Well that
means you a well live life.
So what's up there with Jesus?
Uh,
or it wouldn't matter having that body
30 year old body of like most problems.
I've been beaten on it for
21 years since then. Right.
It's like when I was 30 is when
I got hardcore into Jujitsu.
So that's a 20 years of getting choked.
But of course the,
the Christian would say,
well God makes you whole again,
you'll have no injuries but
that's not really part of you.
Part of you is your injuries, your
muscles. What I was going to say those,
but all those, the, all the
stuff that I did that hurt me,
I also learned from, that's
right. Maybe stronger.
Learned the straw. I think through
incremental struggle. Well,
whether it's like rigorous exercise or
learning something or I think everything
that I do that's difficult,
it makes me just a little bit more aware,
a little bit better at other things.
Just a little bit,
a little bit better to talk to a
little bit easier to deal with,
a little more friendly
and all those things.
I think I wouldn't give up for anything.
I think that's more important than
whatever injuries I've got with. I think,
you know,
I wonder if how you're going to feel
when you're 80 I wonder if you feel like
that, like there's gotta be a point
of diminishing returns. Like, look,
I'd rather be stupid and 40 then to be
enlightened and can't get out of bed very
well.
My older athletic friends tell me it's
about mid eighties when things drop off
fairly quickly. You know, they can
stay pretty fit into their seventies,
maybe still racing,
bike racing at 80,
but 85 or so things drop off pretty quick.
That's where he got to go to a
hormone replacement or whatever. Yeah.
Or the ice pledges or the, the, the
young person's blood or something.
Okay. So I deal with it. You know,
there's no breakthrough miracles yet. Uh,
but again, I'm not against any of
these things happening. You know, when,
when someone like Jeff Bezos puts
$100 million into an aging company,
I hope he's successful as you have
$100 million in an aging company. Uh,
he and Peter Thiel and the Google guys
through Calico and a few others have
invested many hundreds of
millions of dollars into cutting,
like Calico for example.
These are companies that are trying to,
their big goal is to defeat aging
through reengineering cells.
And, um, that,
that's the sort of philosophical goal
behind it is we have to defeat aging so
people can live for centuries
or forever to which I say,
let's not worry about living 500 years.
Let's,
let's worry about like cure prostate
cancer and breast cancer and Alzheimer's
and dementia and so I just,
the little incremental medical problems,
quality of life things were the things
that take people out young. Yeah.
And so that you can live a longer,
higher quality life.
Imagine Michael Shermer at 300 years old.
If you can keep this body,
if you can keep the body that you
have now, you're moving around great,
everything's well, you look really
healthy. How smart would you be? How much?
How much more enlightened or
wise maybe is the best word I,
I'm not against that. I'm happy to live
as long as I possibly can. There are with,
there are people that go, well that's not
right. It's not natural. It's like, okay,
what,
what's natural?
There's surveys on this people and
people's answer is whatever the current
average lifespan is. So, well,
80 seems about right. Okay.
Fast forward to your, uh,
the day before your 80th birthday.
Tomorrow you're going to go,
you want another week? Yeah,
I'll take another week. Okay.
Then fast forward six days I
would you like another month.
I'll take another month. Thank you. And,
and that would never end. So of course,
if you're healthy and happy and you
don't want to off yourself or whatever,
cause you're super, super depressed
or something like that. Yes.
You're just going to want to keep going.
Nothing wrong with that.
If we can do that.
But what if you die and it's way better.
What if you die and you really do,
you leave your physical body.
There's no need for emotions and all
the entanglements of human existence and
you go to this beautiful place
of bliss and life and love,
and it's just pure love without
a body and an unhindered.
I don't know what, that'd be fun. I don't
know what's, is that what we're here for?
We're here for fun.
First one.
We're doing a shitty job to the
channel going crazy right now.
She'd be in a like a party
Van and the way to Vegas.
I had a college professor when I was in
my Christian days who asked me when I
was pitching him the Christian story.
Uh,
he says are their golf courses
and tennis courts in heaven?
Because I like physical challenges.
Yeah.
Want to get out there and push myself
like, I don't know. You know? So I mean,
we'd haven't been no challenges,
no working out,
no physical tensions and true,
right? Yeah. Maybe you don't need it.
So you'd have to remove that part
of humanity that we'd no longer want
challenges and to be pushed to better
ourselves. Do they play chess and heaven?
Right, right. When
you get to win in heaven
or is everybody a winner?
Everybody gets a gold medal
and a Nobel prize and whatever.