So we should talk about this,
uh,
the Jack podcast cause
everybody got so upset about it.
And let's clear up a few things.
First of all,
the guy seems to be willing
to talk about anything.
It's not that I didn't want to talk to
him about those things is just he was
being, uh, I wouldn't say he's evasive,
but he's basically just saying what
he knew based on the company policy.
I didn't know what else more to ask him.
And people felt like I didn't press him
hard enough and he to his credit reached
out to me and said that he would offer
to do another one to ask more questions.
That's cool. And I said, that
would be awesome. So I said, well,
this is the thing that people
seem to be upset about.
They seem to be upset about very
specific cases where people showed,
um, like if, if people were right
wing and they were posting things,
they were banned.
Whereas people who are left wing or maybe
a people of different races or allowed
to post racist things or more offensive
things and even docs people and didn't
suffer any consequences for it.
This is the argument.
My problem is I don't spend enough
time reading this stuff. I don't know.
Like this is like when people get banned,
like Anthony Cuny is a friend of mine.
I don't really know why he got banned.
I don't know what happened.
There was that incident with that,
that woman that punched him
and he wound up getting fired.
He was drunk and he said a bunch
of really stupid shit and and,
and Twitter and then
later apologize for it.
But I don't know if that's what
got him fired. Kicked off Twitter.
But he's my friend.
So what I'm saying is all these
other guys that have problems,
I don't know what the fuck happened, man.
I'm busy. I really don't. I don't know.
I don't even know what
got Alex Jones kicked off,
which is why I asked him because that
was one of the last platforms for Alex
Jones was Twitter. But something got
him kicked off their take on it was it,
they never kicked him off before
because he didn't violate their terms of
service. And another thing that's
very encouraging that Jack said,
and I know it's, it's fun to get mad
at things. It's fun to get mad at him.
It's fun to get mad at me for it. I get
it. I'd probably do the exact same thing.
I totally understand it,
but one of the things that he said was
that he believes that the ability to
communicate on the Internet through
Twitter or through these platforms is a
basic human right. That's
how he looked. Like I said,
do you think of it like a network
like NBC, like if you're an NBC,
they can decide what's on and what's not
on, or do you look at it like a utility?
And he specifically said that
he looked at it more like that,
that he thought it was a basic right.
That's very encouraging.
He also said that he would
bring on whoever it is in
his team that's responsible
for these things.
So we could hear from the actual person
who decides who's getting banned and why
they're getting banned and what,
what is,
what's the decision making
behind all of these things?
We can go over all of them. Um, I didn't,
the podcast would create
such a controversy,
but that's probably poor prior planning
on my part because my thought about it
was, hey, I want to say like, it's
fucking crazy to be running Twitter.
Like it's crazy that this thing exists.
The president uses a platform.
I want to talk about the dude who created
this and what does this like to have
this thing evolve to
become what it's become.
Because it didn't start out that way.
It started out like fun shit like, uh,
at Brian red bands going to the movies,
you know what I mean?
Like that's what people used it for.
And then along the way became this
global method of distributing information
where people use it in warzones man.
They use it to,
to tell people where attacks are.
These are for all kinds of crazy shit.
It's like a,
it's a really powerful but strange medium.
I didn't think about getting into the
weeds with all the very specific people
that got banned. I just wanted to
find out why they banned people.
That was my take on it.
I know there's a lot of conservative
voices that have never been banned.
I don't think Steven
Crowder has been banned.
I don't think Cernovich has
been banned as he'd been banned.
There's a bunch that have not been banned.
Right.
So it's not like they banned all
right wing voices. So what is it?
I don't know what it is.
What he said.
People reporting the tweet and then
somebody's looking at it going,
well this does violate our policy and
maybe you know all these people that that
got banned thigh lated the
policies somehow, you know,
it's probably as simple and cut
clean is that, you know, it's,
it's not that simple.
Right?
Because they make their own policies
and it's also not that simple.
If people are allowed to say similar
things that are very racist in an in vast
generalizations about white people,
which seems to have been the case and
at least a few instances where people
reported that people said fucked
up things about white people,
but there was no repercussions.
And you know,
that's where the argument becomes these
people are more oppressed and so the
white people were thought
of as the oppressor.
So you have this white privilege thing
that people like to use now as a reason
to, to decide to like silent someone like
check your white privilege. That's a,
that's an interesting thing
that's happening. So if,
if there's this genuine movement where
people think that it's okay to say things
about one race, whether you
like it or not, that's racism.
And if you're allowing that from any one
side and not allowing it from another
side, it seems hypocritical.
Look, it's very distasteful.
The idea of racism against black people
in this country is very distasteful to
everybody. Almost everybody
who's not a racist, right?
Because of the history of this country,
because of slavery,
because of all these things.
It's a different connotation,
but if you just allow people to
say terrible things about any race,
it's racism. You are allowing, uh,
like a predetermined
attitude about a race.
Some people have done this, they have
made generalizations, generalizations,
racist statements about white people.
The really weird thing that people were
thrown around these days is that you
can't be racist against white people
because racism is about power and
influence.
It's about using your,
you're in the booth at that
black people are not powerful.
The white people power from the white
people, the ones who are oppressed,
so it's impossible to be racist against
him. That sounds like horseshit to me.
I'm not buying that.
That doesn't make any sense.
It's not beneficial to
anybody to generalize.
This is what we got to get in our head.
It doesn't matter if you're black
or if you're white or if you're,
whatever the fuck you are.
It is not beneficial to generalize,
to take a person out of the group that
we think of as just human individuals
that you, you have to be
an individual. I mean it.
I acknowledged the fact
that people look different.
They have different heritages, they
have heritage's, they have different,
different ancestry,
they have different occupation.
There's different parts of the world.
There's all these differences,
but at the end of the day,
the only way we're all going to get true
equality and true kinship and comradery
as human beings is if we recognize
we're just all a human being. That's it.
There are very big differences in the
way we look and the the things we like.
That's cool,
but as soon as you say,
you can say shitty things about
white people or white men,
that leaves everybody who doesn't fit
that description guilty in this weird way
or presumed guilty because of a
racist statement. That's all it is.
It's not good for anybody.
I get it that it's different than
racism against black people in America.
A country that was built essentially
in a lot of ways by slavery.
There's a war for slavery in this country
and that is a crazy reality that it's
not your responsibility. It's not
mine. I didn't do it. You didn't do it,
but it's real.
Therefore,
as a person who is aware of his history,
the history of this country,
racism against white
people seems different,
but it still sucks to be racist against
racist against black people rather seems
different. But it still sucks to
be racist against white people.
Sucks to be racist against Puerto Ricans.
It's not good.
It's not good for anybody.
It's,
that's what we have to understand
about this social media thing.
What actually did happen
and what is happening,
why is it happening and if it's just
some social justice warrior ethic that
you're not debating,
it doesn't seem fair.
It seems like there should
be a conversation about
this and I bet they're super
reasonable,
really intelligent people and
it's possible they can come to a,
a good place that we can all
agree to that is possible.
I'm not a cynical person, I'm sorry.
I know a lot of young folk him,
they just want those to just want,
guess what? They already have it.
They have more money than
they could ever spend.
And my dealings with Jack as a person,
he seems like a very nice guy
and a very smart guy. And,
and a very empathetic guy.
I just think he's in a crazy,
unmanageable situation to be
running something like Twitter.
Yeah.
And there's probably people that did
something that they should have done in
terms of silencing people moving
things around. It's probably happened.
It's a weird thing when people have
influence over people and there's,
there have been videos had been proven.
We're executives from a bunch of different
social media corporations have talked
about how to silence certain voices,
how to push down certain voices.
Um, this is something that needs to
be discussed. Like is this, uh, uh,
as a policy as a whole, is
it, you know, because you,
you think you're pushing
the right message.
Like as soon as someone thinks
they're pushing the right message,
but they don't have it, there's
no debate about that, right?
They just decide our way's the right way
and they're pushing this and there's a
radical opposition to that message
from half the country like that.
Like, but you'd be like, no, no, no, no.
But this is the one that's
in control of the narrative.
This is the one that's in
control of social media.
It's this far left leaning ideology
and the other part gets pushed aside.
That's a very bad situation for all of
us because there has to be conversation.
There has to be debate
because if there's not,
it's just shores up the differences
between two people and they fucking hate
each other even more. I did not take
that into account and I fucked up.
That's my mistake. That is my
mistake when I made that podcast,
but it didn't take it easy on him because
I didn't want to discuss those issues.
I just didn't think
enough of it in advance.
I'm not as involved in
it as other people are.
I'm aware that there's censorship
and social media. I'm aware my,
my ideas going into that conversation
were more about how insane this method is
for distributing information for the
people that have been banned and for the
people that were fans of
the people that are banned.
I can understand whether
it be upset at me.
It has nothing to do with any preconceived
notions that I had is just how the
conversation took place. It's all it
is. And if you felt left down by that,
you didn't feel like it
was an is extensive enough.
I'm more than willing to do it and go
further into it and we're going to,
and Jack offered it and he's going to
bring someone else who's gonna explain
things to us. I think this would
be very beneficial for everybody.
I also think that there should
be a road to redemption.
I think if you've got something that's
important as Twitter or Facebook or
Instagram, if you're not stealing
someone's stuff, like, you know,
using copyrighted music or something on
an Instagram page where you get banned
over and over again for doing it,
but you keep doing it.
If it's not something like that, if it's,
if it's, uh, an ideological difference,
if you, maybe you crossed a line
that they decided was a line,
it should be able to work your way back.
You see the shoe,
there should be a way where
you can sign up again.
Me and I get a new email address.
I don't mean that,
I mean be the same person you should be.
You should be able to be the same person.
There should be a way what?
There should be different levels.
Definitely everybody. People fuck up, man.
They they fuck up and they make
mistakes, right? And people also grow.
I mean there's this a guy that
was on Sam Harris' podcast, um,
Christian peak.
Eleni I think is his name.
He was a fucking white supremacist to
full on white supremacist and now he is
the exact opposite.
He's,
he's like this very progressive
guy who gives speeches on the,
the dangers of racism and that and the
ideology, how it caught up with him.
Now if he got band when he was a young
man and making terrible decisions and
then became a better person,
shouldn't we give it a guy like that?
A chance to get back in a platform,
right?
And without making a
whole new screen name,
like maybe it would be,
and I don't think there's anything
wrong with the anonymous model.
There's some things that are
really good about it, right?
Like people like Jack
even talked about this,
that people can report news stuff and
not worry about fear of retribution that
they can,
you know,
they can whistle blow and not worry about
fear of retribution if someone's life
is on the line,
but they're trying to provide a service
to the general public or they're trying
to give people information that maybe
might even save lives but could put them
at risk, especially in like third
world countries or war torn countries.
That could be a huge problem if you
have to post, you know, Brian Red Band,
if there's the only way you
can get this information out,
you have to use your whole name.
But it probably be better
off for everybody if people
had a way of communicating
with each other.
Like it's just person to person.
And I think the real problem
is when people try to
engineer these conversations,
and this is another
conversation about youtube.
People have said that we're
deleting comments on Youtube.
We're not deleting anything.
We haven't deleted any comments.
I don't know how it works. I don't read
them. I'm sure people say mean things.
Have a good time. The thumbs
up, thumbs down thing, look,
we don't have to have that on there.
You don't have to have comments on their
youtube gives you the option to have
comments on and to have the thumbs up,
thumbs down. I'm not taking those off.
Have a good time with it,
but we're not fucking with that.
There's something that they're
doing that's not, it's not,
I post at three 41 and Jamie posts it
three 42 and this is the line of the
comments. It's not like that. They've
got their own way of doing it.
The question is why does youtube
do it? What's there? What?
What are they trying to do is are
they trying to block out spam?
Are they trying to block out hate speech?
I tr are they trying to
engineer conversation, comment,
order comments on no comments disappear.
They go away.
A lot of times it's automatic.
If somebody flags a comment that will
just take the comment away until it's like
looked over upon only one person.
Yeah.
On I think on youtube that
that happens quite often.
Probably be as little as
one or two people. Yeah.
So that is probably what's happening to
all you folks that think your comments
are getting deleted. No one is
deleting shit. Yeah. Look, I'm,
I'm not attached to what I do in the
sense that I'm unwilling to look at what I
do wrong. I tried to look at everything
that I do wrong, including this.
So if you were upset at this podcast
because you thought somehow or another I
sold out cause I didn't
ask him any more questions.
I just asked him the questions I wanted
to ask. I understand you have more costs,
more questions. And I do too.
I have more questions too,
especially upon seeing people's
reaction to it and upon,
you know, making myself pay more attention
to all these various stories. Uh,
Matt sent us a list of them.
Some of them are really fucking crazy.
There's some crazy things people have
said and not gotten in trouble for.
Whereas other people said things that
really weren't that bad and got in trouble
for it. Why is that? That's a
good question to ask. So we'll,
we'll concentrate on that.
We're just going to work out a date.
So my humblest apologies to all of you.
Don't not trying to let anybody down.
I always tried to do my best.
That's it. And, and also,
here's another clear one. No one
tells me what to do. There's no one,
there's no secret person behind the
scenes. If I fuck up, it's because of me.
It's my fuck up. I should have prepared
more. I should have thought about it more,
but I didn't realize like how upset
people would be. I think you did a great,
I thought it was a great interview
and I didn't even think of that.
I thought you kind of touched on it a
little when you were talking about Alex
Jones and I think that was like, okay,
you know, this is what happens. Well,
it's a very specific group of people
that are upset. Right wing guys, right?
There's a lot of American flags, a lot
of pepe the frog. It's all right people.
Which luck man easily could've been
me at many points of my life easily.
Especially being a troll online, you know,
if you're working in some fucking job.
And you're making pepe the frog memes
and you're fucking with people. I get it.
I get it. It's one of the things I
like about the Internet. Like I don't,
I don't want to be
comfortable. I'm like, I don't,
I don't want to be comfortable
all the time. I want, I
want a little bit of chaos.
I like the fact that just people like,
they're like that fucking,
I was upset that that radio,
that podcast,
they took it down where they were fucking
with Shiloh laboo with those guys from
four Chan. And the way they took it down
was they contacted radio lab and said,
those guys are white supremacists and they
support white supremacy. You know, and,
and you just, you know, you made
these people that are awful,
terrible people that write terrible
things. You, you, you gave them props.
But the thing about something
like four Chan is no,
you might read some terrible things,
but you've got to realize you're also
reading terrible things from anonymous
people that are working at
their jobs most of the time.
And they're trying to fuck with people's
head and the trying to get people upset.
They're there. They're having a
good time fucking with people.
If you want to take them as that,
that's like them. You like giving,
giving a talk to a dear friend or them
giving an affidavit in court. Well,
you're missing the whole thing.
It's entertainment like half of the
whole reason why they're doing it as
entertainment.
They didn't go steal Shiela booze flag
and go and go right to the camera.
Go Fuck Shiela Boob by using coordinates
from photographs of the sky where they
figured out where the fucking with the
constellations lie and then drove around
honking their horn so that they could
locate where it was by using the Webcam
and listening to how close they got to it.
I mean it's fucking genius shit.
And he got taken down just by this
accusation of them being racist.
But the thing about a forum like
four Chan or Reddit or anything,
you have so many fucking people.
You have thousands and thousands
and thousands of people.
If you just have 10 cunts
posting jokes about black people,
that's all you need to ruin the
reputation of thousands of people.
So for someone to say that everybody
that was like Fuck Sheil Abou is some
racist and the white supremacists, that's
a cheap way out. That's a cheap way out.
I bet. More likely it's some duties board
and he sitting in front of his fucking
computer and he works all day
and this is where he escapes.
He escapes and types and writes things.
Then check some later and then it goes
back to it and type thing checks and it
keeps him sane and does
stupid fucking cubicle.
That's a lot of the people.
So they pulled that whole amazing
podcast down because of that.
Look what he would, the Shiela booth thing
was ridiculous. He will not divide us.
Come on, stop. Stop. We get
a chance that everywhere.
It's funny what they did. They mock
something. That's their way of mocking it.
Nobody got hurt. They made it out
like it was as like awful crime.
They committed on this,
this amazing person who's just trying
to change the world. No, no, they,
they prank Chai laboo and they said,
Fuck Shaya Laboo is that
the buff?
Whatever it is. Shilo Lebouf at
that. Sure. He's a nice guy too.
He probably did something silly. It's
a little silly. He will not divide us.
What they did was funny. It's
a funny reaction. I liked that.
I liked that this is is
important part of this thing.
If it wasn't for people like that,
there would be no podcast.
Now the like to dislike ratio that you
see on youtube videos is fascinating,
right? Because it's weaponized and they're
thinking about trying to ban that now
because so many people use
it to fuck with people.
I hate to say this about you folks,
but every time we have a check on here,
they get fucking torture.
The like to dislike, right?
Like it's ruthless except Rhonda, Patrick,
Cep, Rhonda, Patrick. But it's just a,
it's weaponized. It's the, they're
just going to dislike it because,
cause it's fun. It's fun. It's also fun
to throw a rock at a window. It's fun.
Yeah.
I mean,
and some of them probably didn't even
wash the podcasts like thumbs down.
It gives them a low disliking.
It gives a little bit of power
in the algorithm of d ranking.
It affected something.
And then people who liked it,
there's probably a lot of them
that didn't even watch it.
It's a button you can press. People
are weird, you know, but it's clearly,
it shows by the amount of dislike the
people moved on it and they were upset
about it. Um, so that's basically it.