Felt like one day where I did,
I got 935 points in one workout and
then another hundred points afterwards.
I'm like, one day like that was
separate me from the pack. Just one day.
Just put fear in their home.
He just asks you something just to be fair
that everybody here. What about stuff?
Some of the stuff doesn't that kind
of, you mean like testosterone? Yeah,
100% helps. I told them, I told them,
this is a fucking shoot.
Shit. All those mills shut.
I gave them my doctor's information.
I told them what they should do,
but I'm also at least eight
years older than all. Right.
How old are you? 41 41 I'm 51 now.
I'm older than all. Yeah,
but the testosterone.
Oh yeah, you should. I'm
failing all those tasks. Yeah.
Testosterone replacement therapy,
hormone replacement therapy.
I started doing all that when
I was 40 so that's their age.
Yeah, it makes a big difference.
Makes a big difference.
Fuck yeah. It look, listen,
everybody,
everybody listen to this.
There's a stigma attached to that
in a lot of people like you know,
where do you get your testosterone
from or get it from my balls.
All that matters is that
you have it in your system.
If you don't have it in your system,
you're not going to feel as good.
It's real simple. If you're fine with
not feeling as good, good, go ahead.
Stick with that,
but if you're not fine with it.
This is 2018 hormone replacement therapy
exists for a reason and that reason is
it makes you feel way better.
It makes your body work way better.
You can avoid a host of ailments and
conditions that are related to your body
breaking down due to age with
hormone replacement therapy.
The key to doing it though
is to do it correctly.
He's supposed to go to a doctor that's
going to test your blood levels,
test your nutrient levels,
and adjust your diet first.
The first thing that happens is they,
they want to find out how much you're
sleeping, how s how stressed out you are,
what are you eating?
How much water are you drinking?
Are you getting the proper amount of
protein and vegetables eating correctly?
Let's get you off of this sugar.
Let's get you off the booze,
let's get you off cigarettes or whatever
the else is before they do anything.
So they put you that.
This is a many,
many month process that
I went through with a,
they get you off all these different
things and you make these adjustments and
then they start adding a little stuff,
add a little bit of growth hormone,
add a little bit of testosterone.
First it was cream and
then it became injections.
It takes a little bit of time to figure
out what works best and then you get to
a point where you're, you have the
hormone levels of a healthy young man.
You don't want to elevate.
You don't want to be higher than that.
That's when you run into problems.
You don't want to be in like some crazy.
Vito Belfort, when he got
popped from, you know,
Nevada and he was like some
superhuman levels that was 80 over,
but my mother Sunday night against,
he was supposed to fight rumble Johnson
once the African done the Christian nice
guy named Mark Mark.
Mark.
Quite levels are really high in
Pittsburgh that night. That's right. Yeah.
He was in danger. He was like it was
there is dangerous to his health,
the levels, but he says that was his
doctor, his doctor fuck them. The the,
the whole idea. Well this is a
difference between, first of all,
there's a big difference when someone
who's competing in mixed martial arts.
Obviously you have to worry about your
opponent getting hurt because of the fact
that your enhanced,
and these are young guys are doing this.
When Nate was doing this, he
was like 30 years old. Right.
When you are talking about just
general health and wellness,
testosterone replacement therapy,
hormone replacement therapy,
there's a reason why a lot of older guys,
especially guys who can afford it,
they have money. They're doing it. It
makes me feel better. It just does.
And if you don't want to do it,
that's fine.
There's ways of elevating
your testosterone natural.
They just don't work as well with whether
it's dead lifts are running hills,
doing sprints.
They work a little bit better.
It works a little bit better than nothing,
but it does lots of very good. Yeah,
they release but not enough
for what you're saying. No,
there's going to be a difference. I just
get a raise him through acupuncture.
I know that she's discussed raising,
but it was at this tasco acupuncture.
I would like to see studies on that.
The problem is it's really painful at
some just painful for that. Really Nice.
It sits in your feet. Yeah, I
like to see studies on that.
I don't know if that's really been proven.
If that was really proven like there's,
there's ways to raise it. You know,
the chick I was with for years told me
different case studies that she had been
involved in.
Yeah.
She told me a guy came in once
then found the younger girlfriend.
His wife passed and they found that he
had a girlfriend and he couldn't keep up
and he couldn't keep up.
So he came into the CEO and she did
a bunch of stuff and put them on a t.
He came back a week later and said,
turn that shit off.
Dick will not shut down like,
but she told me, she goes,
I could raise your testosterone levels,
but it has to be neatly into your feet
and you got to find that a little bit
uncomfortable. And I was
like, leave it alone then.
I don't want to fucking walk around all
this stuff that we're talking about. Um,
whether it's hormone replacement therapy
or squats or dead lifts or all these,
all these things will help.