The Joe Rogan experience.
Oh. Um, do you do,
what kind of diet do they have you on?
I very clean man.
Um, I guess, uh, um, I had my, uh,
my kids crack up. I tell, I said I'm
a Presbyterian, but actually, uh,
there's Pescatarian, I
fish a fish, you know,
and vegetables and um,
it's no bullshit. Yeah.
No bullshit. No time for bullshit all the
time for bullshit. That's exactly right,
man. Cause time, coffee time is precious.
Don't used to but the caffeine and,
but doctors don't like the mad,
the caffeine. Yeah, I would
imagine. Yeah. So, um,
rest must be very important for you to
yeah. God thing. I get plenty of it.
We haven't, it is what other things
that make sure that you do? Um,
the Diet has to be on point and
have to take my medication. Uh,
they didn't want me, um, to, uh, you know,
do too much strenuous
activities. Um, they,
they had limited me.
I wouldn't,
I was not able to travel out
of the country until yesterday.
Um, so yeah. So at one year anniversary,
that's when they give you the green light.
Yep. Man, I can go all over.
What did they say when they saw you
run in the parking lot and fall down?
All my doctors and um,
you know,
they all said,
oh,
let's see t what we think except
one except one my cardiologist.
And he said, you know what,
I'm not going to wreck.
She's like everybody else
did you already know that?
They just shouldn't have done that.
But man, I am so proud of you.
He said, you have inspired me
to start working out again. Wow.
Yep. That was doctor Salaam.
Doctor, if be listening.
Thank you. He was the only
one that didn't condemn me.
How far out was that?
The surgery when you fell down?
Three months get so crazy.
Yeah.
I felt like I can do too.
Mine was like,
oh well that's that mentality
that you have, you know?
I would imagine it's very hard to adjust.
Yeah.
Is Big turn from being a vet?
It would be the same for you.
So your active guide,
kicking the shit out of bags and
stuff. Oh, Lightman foot over there.
And then even maybe you think it
would not be able to raise your leg.
Yeah. Yeah. Or throw a punch, man.
I'll be walking around in the grocery
store. I'm like, man. Or with my wife,
and I'm like, man, I hope nobody fucks
with me. Oh, right, right, right.
Oh yeah. How would you feel
if somebody, he thinking, man,
if somebody fucks with you can't even
punch him. Yeah. You do anything.
You can't do math.
You'd be helpless.
That's man that it's hard to
little old ladies have told you.
Yeah, super hard to, I'm like,
man, somebody fuck with me.
I'm just going to get beat up.
I got no defense.
That's a terrible thing. It's a
terrible thing, but awfully humbling
Tam. Then you realize,
you realize that you know,
just town your whole life. You
live for strength. You know,
I've been a strong man my whole life
and then all of a sudden all of that is
taken away and you're just,
you know,
a fucking envelope with me
and you're just weak is shit.
It's very hard mentally to deal with.
But you're past that now.
Yes.
Now you're just in, what, what,
how would you categorize like how you
feel right now? Um, I categorize my,
my,
uh,
emotional feelings as being
probably better than ever.
Really? Yes. Uh, asked,
see things in such a different light,
uh,
after coming that close to dying.
Things that I thought were
important or just don't even matter.
Like what? Give me an example. I used
to, I give you one example. You know,
people I used to tell,
okay,
you asked me about this last time I was
on the show and I tell people, they say,
well, it's about to steroids and steroids
and a, he didn't take it serious.
And I tell them the same thing that I've
been saying for fucking 25 years and
magazine articles and stuff.
I tried them. Yes, I tried it.
And when I was young
and then worked for me,
I stopped taking many, many, many
years with nobody. Nobody. Like,
people don't believe they don't
believe that. And they'll tell me, oh,
you're full of shit. CT, you're lying
and out of like that are there. And Joe,
that used to bother the fuck out of me.
People who applied.
I'd be arguing with people online and say,
fuck,
I'll take it Goddamn drug test anytime,
24 hours a day, you could test me.
I fucking, I'll tell you what I gave you
10,000 bucks. If I fail your drug test,
all you gotta do is get off fucking social
media. Nobody ever took their brain,
but, but uh, I don't give a fuck if people
say I take steroids now. I don't care.
Who Cares? Right. I don't care. Now
it's a fucking compliment. Do you a,
you don't still go back and forth and
argue with people online? Oh, no, no,
not anymore. You know, I sure
did. I, Oh shit. I would,
I would jump on him in a mini.
Today's to see doing it.
I shake my head though, man, Joe,
because that was my mentality.
I attack, I attack back. He hit
me. I'm gonna hit you back, man,
and try to hit your heart. And if you hit,
that's glass. All cops. Oh yeah. You know,
I do the all caps. Can you talk to me
about, you're yelling, you're yelling. Cc,
but I can't have seat. So I make it all
caps so I can read what I'm what saying,
right, right, right. Yeah. I
said, can you actually hear that?
Can you actually hear that those words
for about a year fucking loud.
You got spidey sense, man.