Hello Freak bitches. When are we
going to Musso and Frank's? Oh yeah.
We got to keep talking about
how we do keep doing that.
We should do that before a set
up the store one night. Yeah,
let's do that as the move. Like gentlemen.
Yeah. Should we wear suits? Yes.
100%. Yeah. Can I have the
lighter please? I have a suit now.
You do? Yeah. And I get a suit for a
school function for my kid. Oh really?
What do you mean? What kind of
question one? I always have one, um,
that I wear for the UFC, right? Yeah.
But the UFC one stays at the EOC so
that I don't have to do anything.
I just go there. That's smart.
I like a nice suit. Okay.
He just looked good. Do you wear a
pocket square? Always look good. Now.
When I hosted this TV show I did. Yeah.
It was always a pocket square idea. Yeah.
They made me, they forced that useless
piece of cloth. Right. There is a funny,
and I know when you need a tourniquet,
it was a little pocket square and a
Madonna came in to do the show and uh,
the whole building was like electric.
It was like Madonna is coming
and it really was like energy.
Like you could feel energy in the building
because Madonna was walking into your
color Madonna. So I came
in. Yeah. And I was like,
I got to go meet her before the show
or I'm going to be too freaked out.
So I just walked into the dressing room
and I'm like, Hi Madonna. I'm, I'm Tom.
She's like, nice to see you. She walks
up, she goes, this has got to go.
And she took the pocket
square out and tossed.
It was like, that's it. I'm not
wearing it. This Guy Ritchie,
her ex husband is a proponent
of the Pocket Square Guy
Ritchie was on my podcast
talking about the importance of
the suit and had about square.
That's hilarious. Cause she
immediately, I just met her two seconds.
She whipped it out of my and
tossed it there. Yeah, she was,
it's a little kid. A young Tom Papa at
face, son of a bitch. Yeah. Look at that.
Mr. Steal your girl. You fucking
do. I read a lot different now.
Barber shop. Do I look from that
shot? It'd be honest or what
we might to Delhi. You gained a couple
pounds. Are you making delicious bread?
I am. Did a Ricky Gervais' laugh
hard at everything. Uh Huh.
This is move.
It seems like a jolly fellow,
especially when Jerry said it. Yeah, it's
good move. Yeah. I always make Jerilyn.
Ah,
say it louder.
Okay.
Yeah.