Okay.
Oh God. That's another thing.
Not to talk about calling.
Oh, my books were banned
so many places and uh,
and sometimes I think that maybe
that's a good thing because they don't,
aren't reaching the psychos. My books
are abandoned prison systems. Why?
Because they are enormously popular.
These prison librarians tell me,
but the books are considered
way too stimulating. So wow.
People in prison cannot read
my books. Oh, Holy Shit.
All prisons,
I don't know if it's all,
but it's Texas and a number of
other really big states. So I dunno,
that's kind of a badge of honor.
Yeah.
But it doesn't equate to the like the uh,
the immortality of being banned.
Like a how or a tropic of
cancer or Salman Rushdie. Yeah,
exactly. Yeah. Oh God.
That fucking struggle.
Men,
this struggle of wanting
to express yourself as,
as freely as possible,
but being limited even by your own peers.
That is, um, that's unexpected to
someone as in the outside of literature.
Someone who just reads it
because it's not in the comedy world,
what is in the comedy world, but
not amongst good comedians. Well,
another aspect of that is that so often
people aren't censoring it because it
offends them. They're censoring it because
they're afraid it will offend someone.
They know they're doing it.
They're kind of white knighting on behalf
of someone else. David Sedaris, uh,
told me this story about,
uh, telling a joke, uh,
or something very funny about a girl in
a wheelchair and how he looked out in
the audience and no one was laughing.
They were all looking at
a girl in a wheelchair.
And the moment she started to laugh,
the entire audience started to laugh.
Oh yeah. And so, so often
people in the workshop,
they might not personally
feel offended by the word,
but they're thinking how that word
might hurt people. They know. But yeah,
that's a fact. Yeah, that's a, that's
a giant issue in comedy. If you,
if someone's telling you a
joke of someone's on stage
talking about someone is
fat and there's a fat person in the front
row, that joke will bomb. Yeah. It just,
yeah, but that's because people are
good people overall. You know, they,
they recognize that they
don't want to cause pain.
Another really odd comic David [inaudible]
story is that he always told me,
uh, when you're on the road,
don't read from your current book.
Always read from the next book pieces
it's way of road testing the stories and
finding out which ones work and
should go into the next book.
And in doing so, he was telling the story
about being in this, uh, this forensic,
uh,
laboratory isn't an as an autopsy was
taking place and this autopsy table was
adjacent to dis this huge indoor window
that separated the autopsy suite from
this lunch room and in the lunch
room where the rest of the, uh,
the forensic staff and they're
all eating their lunches.
They all had tuna sandwiches and, and
cans of coke and barbecue potato chips.
And they were watching through the
window as this absolutely perfect.
12 year old boy was being autopsied
and just hours before at this kid,
like two hours before this kid had been
riding his bicycle, he'd fallen over,
he'd hit his head on the curb and now
two hours later he was dead and dead
without almost a scratch on him.
Just this perfect naked,
dead 12 year old boy on the autopsy table.
And as he,
the, the technicians eating their
lunch, watching it through a window,
they watch as the, uh, as the, uh,
pathologist in sizes around the top
of the kid's face at the top of the
forehead, the hairline, and
then peels the face down,
like peeling an orange peels the entire
face off of the skull of this little boy
and leaves the face around the neck
like a mask, like a rubber mask.
And this exposes this liver colored
dark red musculature of the child's
underlying face.
And this one guy watching it
with a mouthful of tuna sandwich,
he points this out and he
says, see that? That there,
that's the color of red that I want
to paint our rec room. Holy Shit.
And when's the Darice told that
story in front of 600 people?
It was dead silent.
And you could hear people weeping.
People were crying and they were hating
David Sedaris in that moment and so on.
I had to laugh.
I laughed really loud like a donkey.
And it was amazing how that hatred in
that auditorium swung from hating David
who they did not want to hate to hating
this jackass over here who was actually
laughing and so I threw myself on the
sword for David and that story never went
in any book.
Wow.
Did the story not go in any book just
because of the reaction by the audience or
just an uncomfortable moment?
He just decided he would
speak to him about it. No,
I didn't. I'm not afterwards. It was
just such an awkward, painful thing.
I would never come to throw it back
in his face. Right. To my knowledge,
that was the only time the story was told
to have those like scattered about are
there,
there's,
are there scenes what you wrote and you
just sat and looked at him and went, no,
I just got to put that one somewhere else.
Oh,
there are set that aside jokes that I
told where I got hist by 800 people and
you know as you can live to those
model and then you realize you can live
through a lot.
If you can be hated by 1100 people at
a Barnes and noble on Union Square.
Oh yeah. You can be hated
by your mother. It's okay.
I know when those people come to see you,
how many of those people
are fans of literature and
how many of those people are
specifically fans of your work? Like
there's, there would be a difference.
Like the people were fans of your work
would at least expect some uncomfortable
moments.
And for the most part they tend to be,
uh, more or less just fans of my work.
And still it's still his.
Oh yeah.
But again,
they're hissing on behalf of someone
than I hissing for themselves.
You know, I made this horrible, cheap
shot and they always know a cheap shot.
People always know a cheap shot. I, uh,
I was commenting about how
in breakfast at Tiffany's,
Truman Capote had made this observation
that Americans don't like true beauty,
true classical natural beauty.
They want to see a very plain person
who has been so groomed. So exercise,
so made up so style stylized that
she can kind of pass as this,
this amazing,
strange beauty.
That's what Americans want because
natural classic beauty is not egalitarian.
You're either born with it or you're not.
They want to see a plain person
who has been transformed.
And to make my point at the end of the
story, I made a cheap shot. I said,
and that's why we have
Sarah Jessica Parker
and I said this in New York
and in New York,
Sarah Jessica Parker is worshipped like
a god and that whole crowd hissed and
booed and did everything
but throw excrement at me.
Wow. But then later in line, half
of them came up and whispered.
That was really funny.
Yeah, that's, well that's one of
the things about dark comedy clubs.
You want them dark? No, you don't
want everyone illuminated like the,
when the,
the crowd is like the one that,
this is one of the real issues with
doing a comedy special is that uh,
especially the old way
they used to do them,
they still like to light up the audience,
which completely changes the dynamic of
the room changes what you'll laugh and
what you won't laugh at.
You know,
in a scene like this could Sarah Jessica
Parker choke. It's perfect example.
If you don't want to be caught dead
being the one person that throws her head
back.
And how's it that,
you know, cheap shots or just to stay
away from them. But that's another,
I'll ask you, ask you
a question. You know,
with so many colleges becoming these
kinds of strident safe places to demand
their own aesthetic, what is
it like doing comedy? Well,
it hasn't
changed that much.
People getting a little got a little
bit more sensitive because they're aware
that other people are more sensitive
without the audiences that come to
nightclubs, which is primarily where
I perform with, I do a theater.
Those people were there to see me.
So that's there.
They're usually pretty loose, pretty
fun, but if you're in a nightclub,
they're there to see,
especially the comedy store.
I'm one of the good things
about the comedy store's.
There's literally two
dozen people in the lineup.
They're not necessarily just here to cu
did there to see Anthony Chesil neck and
Chris Delea and all these other
comedians that are also there as well,
so you get a a really a much
broader comedy audience,
but their nightclub audiences,
they have a few drinks in them.
Maybe this smoked a little
pot before they got there.
Those people are there to have a good
time. Colleges are a nightmare now. Hmm.
It's a nightmare because
it's recreational outrage.
It's it's kids who have been under the
control of their parents for most of
their life and haven't had their own
sovereignty and identity and now they're
free and they are very
quick to be outraged.
They want a porn out there.
Moral superiority.
There wasn't virtue signal
and every opportunity they
want to shut down anything
to think is air quotes problematic.
They don't want things to go on a bad
when they think for some reason that
comedy should be uplifting
and it should only punch up.
Like I had this conversation once with
a professor who wrote a book on a comedy
and he said all great comedy punches
up. And I said, that's bullshit. I said,
one of the greatest bits of all time
as Sam Kennison spit about starving
children in Africa about watching those
commercials were starving kids in Africa
and you know,
couldn't you please help?
And he goes in kinnisons like he
just want to grab the guy, hey,
why don't you help them? You're right
fucking there or send someone like me.
He goes, sends, send something like me.
It's going to take these people go, hey,
we just drove here 5,000 miles with
your food and it occurred to us do you
wouldn't be world hunger,
have you?
People would live with a fucking vote
as he goes. Can I hear you say that?
That Sam, we got sand in America too.
We just don't live in it, asshole.
And he's,
he goes and one of the greatest bits
of all time is literally about starving
babies in Africa.
It's one of the greatest
bits of all time and he
didn't have anything to say.
You didn't know where to go
with it. I'm like, don't,
don't say comedy is only about
punching up. That's crazy talk.
That's what you're doing
is you're, you're, there's,
there's this moral thing that they're
trying to achieve that it literally is
completely independent of humor.
It's not what's funny. It's
like there, they want to,
they want it to be a multipurpose tool.
They want it to be funny as well as
morally uplifting and great for people who
discriminated against and amazing for
folks who are marginalized and uplifting
for those who are disenfranchised.
Well that's not what comedy is.
Comedy is funny.
Those things are wonderful in and if you
want to do a spoken word show or poetry
or writing or you know,
a one person play those,
those are great, but that's
not funny. Comedy is funny,
so it's either funny or it's not funny
and some things are funny that are fucked
up.
You know?
Kennison had a bit about
homosexual necrophilia acts
or paying money to spend a
few hours undisturbed with the
freshest male corpses. And He,
so he would lie down on his stomach
and he goes, you imagine these people,
they're on the slabs are like well,
went through life and had a good time
and everything and now I guess I'm going
to go and be with Jesus and Hey,
what the hell is this?
And he's rocking back and forth.
It feels like some guy's
got his dick in my ass.
He made live keeps fuck you in the ass
even after you're dead. It never ends.
It never ends.
Oh he would close on it cause it was the,
he couldn't follow it.
Who was such a powerful bit. It was about
a dead guy getting fucked in the ass.
There is no further down that you could
punch other than starving babies in
Africa.
You know, and I'm not sure
about it, this is punching down,
but do you remember the s the routine
that kind of put Whoopi Goldberg on the
map a million years ago about being a
black surfer chick? No. Oh, you know,
she did it on television.
I must've seen it on cable
when I was like 19 years old,
but she talks in valley speak.
Nobody's seen this will be person before.
She's brand new.
Nobody's ever seen her on television.
She's got this funny name and she's doing
this valve speak about being the only
black surfer chick on the beach.
And she loves surfing and she
loves this one white surfer guy.
And she finally hooks up with them and
then she realized that she's pregnant and
it's all very funny.
The whole front end,
you're just roaring with laughter and
then she's pregnant and she doesn't know
what to do.
So she gets a rusty wire coat hanger and
she goes into a public bathroom on the
beach and she gives herself a coat hanger
abortion and it spills out there on
the concrete floor
and everything's okay.
And now I'm back on the beach
and I'm just doing fine.
And why don't you come on down
and see me here on the beach?
It's great down here.
It's great. Holy Shit.
It's a fantastic piece.
And she did it on television and she
did it on TV and it started so light,
like an IRA, 11 novel, and then I
went to such a dark, horrible place,
and then it came up with
just this kind of token.
Everything is okay ending every,
I'm going to be all right.
Don't worry.
This is just something that happened.
Yeah, dude, dude
just leaves you shaken.
And that's the kind of comedy I love.
It goes to the that dark or
that sentimental place and
it breaks your heart and
then it kind of comes
out of it a little bit.
But I were 11 did that so well.
Nora Ephron in her books,
she was so good at doing that.
Heartburn,
heartburn is fantastically funny,
but by the end you're just weeping.
The book is so sad.