What keeps you up at night?
Yeah,
well it's quite hard to run companies.
Yeah. Especially car companies. How?
Say it was quite challenging.
The car business is the hardest
one of all the things you do. Yes,
because it's a consumer oriented
business as opposed to like space x and
not that space x. The space x
is no walk in the park, but,
but a car company, it's very
difficult to Kiva car company alive.
It's very difficult.
You know,
there's only two car companies in the
history of American car companies that
haven't gone bankrupt and that's
Ford and Tesla. That's it.
Yeah. Ford road out.
That crazy storm. Huh?
They're the only ones by the skin of
their teeth. Shout out to the Mustang.
Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. By the skin of their
teeth. That is interesting.
Right? Same with Tesla.
We barely survived.
How close did you get to folding?
Okay,
very close.
We uh,
okay.
Or 2008 is not a good
time to be a car company,
especially a startup called company
and especially in electric car company.
I was like stupidity squared and this is
when you had those cool roadsters with
a tea towel with a target
top. Yeah, we had like a,
he was a highly modified Elise chassis.
The body was all completely
different by the way.
I was like Super Dom strategy
that we actually did.
Yeah.
It was based on two false premises.
Uh,
one false premise was
that we'd be able to uh,
cheaply convert the Lotus Elise,
um,
and use that as a core platform and that
we will be able to use technology from
the store company called AC propulsion
for the electric drive train.
And the battery problem is,
yeah,
the AC proportion technology to not
work in production and we ended up using
none of it in longterm. None of
it. We have to redesign everything.
And then the,
once you add a battery pack and the
electric motor to the cart got heavier,
cut 30% heavier and validated the entire
structure, all the crash structure,
everything had to be redone.
Okay.
Nothing like that.
I think it had less than 7% of the
parts were common with any other device
including cars or anything?
7% yes.
Everything including tires and wheels.
Bolts.
Okay.
Breaks even every year. And we'll
see. The steering wheel was,
I think the steering wheel was
almost the same. Yes. The, the, the,
the windscreen windscreen, right? No, I
think the windscreen or is the same? Yes.
I think, I think we were able
to keep the led screen 7%.
So that's basically every
body panel was different.
The entire structure was different.
The uh,
w we couldn't use the h like the
HVAC system that the, you know,
the air conditioner was belt driven,
air conditioner off.
So now we needed something
that was electrically driven.
We need a new AC compressor and all
that takes away from the battery life as
well. Right? Yeah. We needed small,
highly efficient air conditioning system,
um, that fit in a tiny car and was
electrically powered, not belt driven.
Very difficult. How much do those
weigh those cars? The roadster,
I think it was about 2,700 pounds.
That's still very sound depending on
which version, 26 50 to 27 50 pounds,
something like that.
And what was the weight distribution?
It was about 50 well,
there were different versions of the car.
So is about 55 on the rear because we're,
we're,
we're bias but not bad like
considering like a nine 11,
which is like one of the most
popular sports cards of all time.
Heavy rear end bias. Well, I mean, yeah,
the nine 11 I think the joke is like the
[inaudible] despite Newton not being on
their side. Yeah. If you're fighting
Newton, it's very difficult. Well,
it's like you've got this,
the moments of inertia on a,
on a nine 11 don't make any sense.
They do. Once you understand them,
once you understood,
don't want to hang the engine off the ass.
This is not a wise move.
You don't want to let up on the gas.
When you're in a corner, you're the
problem with, with, with uh, with,
with something that's where the engine
is mounted over the rear axle or off the
rear axle towards the rear is that you
pull a moment of inertia is fundamentally
screwed. You cannot solve
this. It's unsolvable.
You're swoon pull them over to
nurseries, you're screwed. Right?
Like essentially if you
spun the car like a top,
that's who Paul moment of inertia.
You're just,
I promised, I wouldn't swear on
this show by the way, really who? I,
so it was my friend.
Tell that friend to go fuck himself.
Who told you not to swear a fried,
a good friend of when I went to realize
your fucking Ilan Musk can do whatever
you want, man. If you ever get confused,
call me elsewhere and private swear up
a storm to say frickin it's fun way.
There's like old house moms,
wives that have children. Oh,
that's fricking thing. Yeah.
But anyway,
like the Porsche,
it's kind of incredible how well
Porsche handles given that, uh,
it's the physics moments of
Adair Scharf so messed up,
uh, to actually still make it
work well is, is incredible. Well,
if you know how to turn it into the corner
and once you get used to the feeling
of it, there's actual benefits to it.
You know, there, there are some benefits.
I enjoy. I, the car I had
before Tesla was a nine, 11,
nine, nine, seven or six
[inaudible] 97. Yeah. Yeah.
Um, great car man. Yeah.
I mean particularly what the on the porch
tower when they had the variable veins
turbo and yet doesn't have the
turbo lag. That was great. Yeah,
that was really great. The turbo
lag was, is like, you know,
your Florida like phone home,
call your mom, the older one,
but an hour later the car accelerates
and super dangerous too because in the
real wheel starts spinning. Yeah. Yeah.
There's something fun about it though.
Like feeling that rear weight
kicking around, you know, and again,
I could feel to it. Yeah,
I agree. But that's,
that's what I was talking about earlier
about that little car that I have,
that 93 nine 11 it's just
theirs. It's not fast. It's not,
it's not the best handling car,
but it's more satisfying than any other
car I have because it's so mechanical.
It's like everything about it like crack
holes and bumps and it gives you all
this feedback and I take it to the comedy
store because when I get there I feel
like my brain is just
popping and it's on fire.
It's like a strategy for me now that I,
I really stopped driving other cars there.
I drive that car there just for
the brain juice. Just for the,
the inner,
the interaction.
I mean you should try model s p 100 day.
I'll go blow your mind.
[inaudible] skull. Okay. Yeah. Tell
me what to order. I'll order it.
One less p 100 d. Okay. Jamie,
what car that I drive? Okay. Okay.
I'll get with the car you drive. Okay.
It will blow your mind out of your skull.
I believe you. How far can
I drive? How far in miles?
That's good for la regular days.
You will never notice the battery.
Never.
How hard is it to get like one of them
crazy plugs installed in your house that
difficult? Now it's, it's super easy.
It's like, yeah, it's like a dryer plug.
It's like a dryer outlet.