That's out to Wiz Wiz, Wiz
Khalifa, cousin Bri. Yeah.
Shouts out the breeze breeze got into
Jiu Jitsu and it's brought whizz into it
and it's now shamed me into going to, so
at some point I want to pop up in a gym.
I got to get you and Joey Diaz and a
Jujitsu class would be the greatest.
I've got to get this stuff.
The shoulder I to finish rehabbing Cara,
it's going to clear me when I don't know
what your shoulder rotator cuff surgery
on both shoulders. Jesus. Yeah, but I can
do this again now. Okay. Yeah, I can grab,
but I can't think got you're doing
those elastic bands. You'll exercise.
Got those in the room. Did those this
morning. Wiz put on a ton of muscle. Doug,
there's a photo of him pre and
post and it's truly impressed.
I would not want to fuck with Wiz
Khalifa right now. He's not just a thin,
tall kid rapping. He is. He is ridiculous.
I will give you kicks and take your bitch
at this point. Have you seen his abs?
They're wood. There's huge like, look
at that. Look at it. They're not just,
they're not just ripped,
I'm going to stop slobber and soon they're
not just rip their big like look how
much power advantage of going from
skinny to big though versus me.
Why this time times a muscle under here
but got to lose a lot of Chubby to see
it baby,
your legs carrying around all that weight.
I always thought if someone could
lose weight once they're really heavy,
they would have an
advantage of their legs.
Calves are still good but the legs are
constantly used to moving around with
much more weight and now all of a
sudden they don't have that way.
It's like you've been backpack training
like any of the difference. Well that's,
that's not as good a difference. It's
hard to tell them. No big difference.
Still a difference then for sure.
Which was a great human being.
He goes to that a place
in um, in Hollywood, um,
Jay's place performance. Uh,
what is it called?
Unbreakable. The places,
the shit supposedly it's like a semi
private place and you go in there like
chuck Liddell's working out and that
makes sense cause we is like really rich.
Yeah. Yeah. Like at least you're
getting the black community.
He's like white people rich as
well. We call it white. He's on,
he's on a very high level right
now. God bless. I like with,
well if you did that to your body,
that dude works hard while I'm doing it.
I'm doing it slower. I need to pick up
the pace and go full 90 days like you say,
but I feel a lot better. I just did
a fucking Zappos running commercial.
I felt like the king of the
world. Did you? Yeah. Yeah.
I mean I've been working out.
Miss shouts out to Al Clay,
barred from play more fit effects
now former professional bodybuilder.
Just teach me how to retrain my brain
and when I'm not being lazy and really on
it feel great sweat today
so you don't regret the day.
The good thing about it
too is with a guy like you,
if you continue and you continue
to lose weight and get healthier,
you're going to inspire other
people to do the same thing. Eh?
People that are your fans
that go, fuck man, I've now,
I want to get my shit together.
Yeah.
Cause what you don't want to do is get
rich dad. Have some young Wiz Khalifa,
like I fucking on your wife. That's
my daily mantra. That's a good,
I got a hot red hair wife and I
don't want to die all my money.
Go to some young Steadman light.
God fucking honor.