And laying up and paying attention
to online for a long time.
One of the things that you do a great
job with is just calling bullshit on.
I mean,
you loved called Bullshit clearly,
but whenever people are overstating
claims or people get ridiculous,
and I think this is one of the things
that is a problem with any diet where
people get really enthusiastic about it,
that becomes an ideology.
Whether it's the ketogenic diet or
the carnivore diet or the, you know,
fill in the blanks, Vegan Diet. People
decide this is the end all be all,
it's going to cure cancer, make you
smarter to Dick's, going to grow a foot.
All of these things are gonna happen and
you do a great job of calling bullshit
on that kind of stuff.
Yeah, I mean I, I'm not anti
Quito, I'm not anti pagan.
I'm anti bullshit.
And one of the problems we
have is nutrition is replacing
religion for a lot of
people.
So you find something that you identify
with and then people start to try to
say, because they identify with that
movement or like for example, vegans,
they identify with many of them,
uh, protection of animals. Uh,
not my job to judge their
ethics on that sort of thing.
But then they kind of try to backtrack
to find the science to support them as
well. And they, they pick and choose.
And this is guilty of all groups,
not just vegans. This is also a
lot of key digit Dick Diet cell.
It's a carnivore diet, whatever
have you. If it has the word diet,
they're zealots out there who are going
after it. And I will stick up for,
I've stuck up at a scientific conference
for the Ketogenic Diet. Uh, you were,
we were having a round table
about something different
and somebody said, well,
we know that the
ketogenetic diet in prayers,
exercise performance and
endurance athletes. And I said,
I don't think that's necessarily
true. Uh, you know, the,
it's pretty and ambivalent. The
ambiguous as to whether or not it does.
It seems to be kind of
individual. Um, but on the whole,
on the average it doesn't seem
to impair exercise performance.
So it's kind of what you like. But when
you have people who you know, like,
like a Gary Taubes who says, well calories
don't matter, it's all carbohydrates.
Um, that sort of thing of the
carbohydrate, insulin model, obesity,
I mean the research is you're able to do
a lot of hand waving about insulin and
you know when you burn so much fat
when you're on a high fat diet,
which is true by the way,
you, you burn a lot of fat.
But what they don't talk about is
that it's, it's overall fat balance,
how much fat you store
versus how much fat you burn.
And when you're on a high fat diet,
you store a lot of fat,
you also burn a lot of fat.
The overall caloric balance
is what determines whether
or not you will have net
storage or net deposition. And it's
same thing for high carb diet as well.
You know,
this idea that with high insulin it just
completely shuts down all fat burning
everywhere. That's just not true.
Now if you have high carbohydrate,
you will burn less fat, but you're also
storing less fat as well. And again,
the net caloric balance is going to
be what determines how much you store
because you don't really store
carbohydrates as fat for most people.
They did a study,
uh,
overfeeding women where they overfed
them 50% above their caloric maintenance
and they found that of 282 grams of
fat that they store during the day and
Adipose, only four grams came from
carbohydrate. 278 came from fat.
So
Glucose. What about fructose? So
fructose causes, we think, you know,
non alcoholic fatty liver disease.
So that could be, you know,
that that's a de Novo de Novo lipogenesis
is higher with fructose and you think
about people consuming it in liquid
drinks a hundred to 200 grams a day,
which is not uncommon even for my wife,
not uncommon.
So fructose does seem to have a little
bit of different hepatic metabolism.
But I was actually across the hall from,
um,
a professor who was doing
a lot of the research on,
on fructose and obesity
and fatty liver disease.
And even he came to the conclusion that
if you overfeed fructose and it creates
a caloric surplus and
you're overfeeding for dose,
then you can have some wonky stuff start
to go on relative to other macros dies.
Try to keep this, try to keep this
right next to your face. Sorry. Got It.
Because that's what she says. So powerful.
I talk loud and a lot. It's good.
Um, so if you're, if you're doing that,
if you're creating that caloric surplus,
what you find is when you're in net
storage, when you're driving more,
uh, nutrients into adipocytes
and sometimes liver,
depending on metabolism, but it takes,
it takes a lot of fructose to do that.
And a caloric surplus, you start to
create a lot of wacky stuff going on.
Um, the Mitochondria starts to
become dysfunctional. And you know,
people make a big deal about,
oh well you have,
we have claimed now that
everything causes, uh,
obesity and type two diabetes for, for
first it was fats, then carbohydrates,
and there's actually a professors out
there who actually will claim the protein
gives you diabetes and it's type,
can I stop you for a second?
What you mean the Mitochondria becomes
dysfunctional? How does the Mitochondrial,
how does that happen?
Okay,
so I'm going to state for everybody
that I'm going out in a limb.
This is my opinion. Okay? Um,
if you look at the research
on obesity and diabetes,
what happens is you have everything
start to elevate in the bloodstream.
So if you measure,
like there was a professor who thought
that branch chain amino acids were
causing obesity because they were
elevated in the bloodstream during, uh,
or sorry, during type
two diabetes. Well, yeah,
branch chain amino acids are elevated.
So fatty acids,
so triacylglycerides so as glucose.
So is it really those things causing
it or is it possible that when you are
overfeeding relative to what you
burn relative to that turnover,
that Ma Mitochondria start
to become dysfunctional?
Probably a lot due to inactivity.
Um,
and the Mitochondria is, as we call
it, the powerhouse of the cell.
As you probably learned in high school
biology or whatever they taught it to you
as that is where
everything fluxes through.
So that is where you're
creating ATP. That's where
you're burning through lipids,
carbohydrates,
that sort of thing.
If that becomes dysfunctional and
you're not getting enough flux,
enough pull through that Mitochondria,
what happens is you start to
back up every part of metabolism.
So all the metabolic byproducts,
almost all of them inhibit
everything within the cell.
There's a metabolomic signature
for that and, and Epi phenomenon,
if you want to call it that,
would be elevated branch chain amino
acids because the consequences of that and
in some people, yeah. So these
things start these byproducts,
these metabolic byproducts, because you're
not fluxing enough through the cell.
They start accumulating within the cell
and start to inhibit the Kreb cycle.
Glycolysis.
And so everything starts backing up to
the point where you also start inhibiting
the insulin receptor.
And now you have glucose,
fatty acids and amino acids also backing
up to the point where they start to
overspill into the bloodstream.
And you see these,
this accumulation of all of them in
the bloodstream in type two diabetes.
And I actually think that again,
me going out in a limb that
obesity doesn't cause type
two diabetes and type two
diabetes doesn't cause obesity that
they develop in concert from the same
problem,
which is overfeeding under activity.
So a lot of it is about how much nutrients
you're fluxing into cells versus how
much energy you're creating fluxing
them through the cell and out.
So when you're overfeeding,
whether it be carbohydrate, fat,
you're fluxing more energy
in than you can dispose of,
and now you have to do something with it.
Well when you run out of,
when you do that much to it and
Mitochondria start to become dysfunction,
dysfunctional,
you start to not have enough places to
put it away and it starts spilling into
the bloodstream and now you
cause all kinds of problems,
problems.
So one of the things that we really
wanted to talk about here is high carb
versus low carb.
Yeah.
Cause this is a just a giant point
of contention today in nutrition,
especially in terms of uh,
athletes with performance in mind.
That's a big factor. Whether or not
high carb or low carb is the way to go.
And there's a lot of zealots on both
sides and there's a lot of bullshit and
there's a lot of, you
know, online experts.
And one of the great thing about bringing
you two guys in here is because you
could really actually explain
the science behind it.
Now you've been great lane
at pointing out that there's,
it's not a magic bullet and you know,
and so many people like to sort
of stress it that way, that they,
they, they like to portray
ketogenic diet. Is this is it,
this is the end all be all.
I figured out what to do.
This is the way everyone should be eating.
You don't think so?
I don't think so because
if you look at the,
the weight loss problem in
our society, uh, and I'm,
I'm writing a book called fat loss
forever. I talk about this in detail.
We don't have a weight loss problem.
Six out of every seven people are able
to lose a significant amount of body
weight in their life who
are obese or overweight.
The problem is the weight regained
statistics are absolutely terrifying.
Uh, within one year, 70%, we'll put
it all back on. Within two years,
it's 85%. Within three years, it's 95%.
So that means diets have a 95%
failure rate. And of those people,
one third to two thirds will add
more than they originally lost.
And this gets kind of into Yoyo dieting
and I talk about that as well. But the,
the real problem is that people don't
stick to pick something that's sustainable
for them. All the research. If there's
one bit of research out there that,
that we have that shows how
to create lasting weight loss,
and you look at the people who are
the 5% who actually keep it off, uh,
it's that they pick something that's
sustainable, whether it be key to genic,
whether it be low carb, high or
low fat, whatever it is, Vegan,
something that they can sustain
and make a lifestyle. If,
cause if you look at
Meta analyses, uh, uh,
for our listeners met analyses are,
are kind of a study of studies.
So they take,
researchers take studies that have
similar parameters and they kind of lumped
them together and they look
at, okay, what's the consensus
amongst these studies?
And they have advanced statistics.
They used to run this.
If you look at low carb versus low fat,
there's no difference
in adherence overall.
On the whole there's no difference and
there's no difference in weight loss.
There's no difference in a blood lipids,
even glycaemic control.
So there was a study where they met
analysis of, I think it was 23 studies,
over 3000 people where they looked
at, okay, if you control calories,
so calories are acquainted,
does low carb versus low fat
make a difference on weight loss,
glycaemic control,
those sorts of things,
leave the ketogenic diet.
So by definition we have an objective bio
marker that defines the ketogenic diet
is the only diet that actually
has something that you, you know,
you can measure in your blood that say
you're on this diet and when your ketone
levels are elevated, that confers
many different benefits, uh,
that I believe can enhance
adherence to the Diet.
Before we get into the woods here,
I want to clarify one thing,
the difference between someone being on
a diet and being able to sustain it and
not being able to stand in
gaining all that weight back.
Isn't that a discipline
issue? Well, partly,
but we kind of had to start
looking at, okay, if we,
if we go in, let me
read, let me re circle.
We have to find what requires the least
amount of discipline for somebody to
stick to. Because discipline is
is while some people have more,
some people have less,
um,
it is a finite resource.
So when doing only find that people like
kind of drop off whatever they're doing,
it's when they're stressed out,
work stressing them out,
they're going through a divorce,
those kinds of things, right?
That's where are our discipline kind
of wanes because we're trying to be so
disciplined for this other
thing and it's draining us.
So what happens with,
with diet is it in people who are busy,
people who have a lot
of stress in their life,
that's where they really start overeating.
So we have to find
something that requires,
I look at it is let's find something
that requires the minimal amount of,
of discipline for a person so that
when your life goes to absolute shit,
you can still stick to it.
And so for some people that is a very,
very individual thing.
And they see this in the dietary studies
that what works for one person to
create a deficit and sustainable
isn't the same way for another person.
And Dom even commented on this
about his wife Chella. Um,
she does much better on a higher
ratio of carbohydrates to fats.
Yeah. I mean, early on it was obvious that
she wasn't going to change her diet. I,
the time that we met like
10 years ago, most, we,
I was really getting into this and I
really felt that for me at least. Uh,
but she would stop at checkers and,
you know,
get a burger and with the sugary
drink and she's in tremendously carbon
tolerance. She was very skinny as a
kid. And, uh, she taught me tolerance,
carbohydrate. She's very carbohydrate
tolerance. Did I say intolerant? Yeah. Uh,
yeah. So, and, and you know,
if the Diet low carb I feel,
and maybe in ketogenic putting
in an under that umbrella works,
I think for up to 25 to 30% of people,
uh,
especially at their
carbohydrate intolerant.
And I believe that it does that
by virtue of elevating Ketones,
shifting, you're a, the neuropharmacology
of the brain, for example,
it works through Ghrelin.
It works through,
there's new science emerging right now
showing that appetite regulation is
influenced positively by,
uh,
nutritional ketosis in ways that were
just starting to learn now. Well,
you can certainly feel it. It's one of
the things about the ketogenic diet.
When you're in that state, all of a
sudden you're just not hungry. The same.
There's not a, an overwhelming
need for food. Yeah, I'm,
I haven't had anything to eat today.
I mean,
when I was eating massive plates of
Pasta 25 years ago and I went to this,
this long without food, I would
start getting shaky. I would,
I would have a hypoglycemic response
and I'm completely resilient to that.
And that has major implications for
military personnel being keto adapted,
not just for performance,
preventing seizures.
And I think for a cognitive function too.
But you, uh, it's very liberating.
So meal frequency is not an issue.
So if you're in austere environments
where you have limited food availability,
that becomes a major issue. And if you're
working as a scientist and you can't,
you know, you're working with
animals, you're doing experiments,
you don't have time to eat. I need
to maintain that cognitive function.
I needed to be sharp,
you know, with limited.
So it worked very good for me
throughout my professorship. You know,
getting tenure and things like that where
I could just put more time and energy
into my work without having to stop,
prepare a meal, eat a meal, cleanup.
Like I think I wasted a lot of time
doing that when I was eating five to six
meals a day.