There was a funny story that I heard
about a DEA undercover DEA agent who,
uh, moved in to try to harass another
undercovered DEA agent and they're playing
each other back and forth against each
other and they didn't know that both of
them are cops entire time.
If fucking assholes just wasted money,
just wasted money
investigating each other.
So fucking stupid.
Both sides undercover
like what the fuck man,
if,
if Trump started talking about that,
if you really want her
to keep people around,
if you really wanted to
get people on the side,
I think what he would do is start
making drugs legal and started saying,
listen folks,
there's a reason why it was a problem
in Mexico and when you talk to real
economists, it really blows.
You were talking about that
on stage last night. Yeah.
Yeah. The real problem is the
drug war make drugs legal.
I wish I was thinking about that,
but uh,
well first methods of fucking,
it's just such a fucking horrible drug.
Ruthless.
They make a lot of that in Mexico as well.
It's a ruthless drug.
But I think part of the reason why it's
so fucked up is because all of it is
illegal.
I mean,
that's a big part of why it's so fucked
up is because it's not regulated.
It's not measured.
It's the doses or not.
It doesn't say on the box
what will kill you. You know,
you can go and buy this old camp
whiskey at any corner store, right?
You just go in there and buy it, drink
that whole thing, drink that whole thing.
If you weigh a hundred pounds,
you're dead. You're dead.
We all know it's thinking about that. If
I did run for mayor, I'd have a, uh, uh,
like they have the gun exchange
programs. You have a meth exchange. Yeah.
Meth for mushrooms. Ooh, that's a
great exchange. Give them good drugs.
They're doing this because it's cheap and
available. Well, get them on good drugs.
That's, that's actually a really good
way to approach the subject. He wasn't,
one of the things in
hunters Thompson said,
but he's running for sheriff a pick and
county. He said, a, any drug worth taking,
she'll never be sold. And we'll, uh,
put a stocks in the middle of the seat
in the middle of the city to lock up
dishonest drug dealers. It's
like, drug should be free, a good,
we're going to rest drug dealers.
I think if we made everything legal,
we'd have real problems for sure
for quite a long period of time.
The question is whether or not you have
enough resources to parent your kids to
keep those problems from
happening to your family,
whether or not you have enough self
control to keep yourself from being one of
those problems and drugs
become legal and accessible.
But then once it's settled down from
there forward, we'd be moving in a way,
healthier place. And you essentially
take all of the money out of the cartel.
They're not making any money anymore.
And then they're not going to be
this murderous gang of suck you in.
It's going to take a while
for things to dissipate.
But look what they did to Columbia.
I mean,
Columbia used to be fucking crazy and
now you can go there and it's supposed to
be really nice.