The joe rogan experience. Future
Science. Yeah. That's what you're into.
I'm way into future science.
I wish we lived in the future,
so that's where it goes. Fit in.
I just go, I mean future science.
I think I just think time.
I think time is an illusion.
I think that I'm more, did you
ever see interstellar? Yes.
I'm more in that zone.
That's that smacked of good science
to me. Like I was like, yes.
When you say time's an illusion,
you mean like the watch is real?
Like if it says four 30 that's when the
movie starts, right? That's all real.
No, that's just coordination. That's
it's, it's within our species.
We're coordinating together.
We're working as an ant colony.
We are sending signals,
which happened to be time signals
were using math to coordinate,
but if you go underwater and hold
your breath for five minutes,
that's real five minutes. No, that's
just when you run out of oxygen,
so that five minutes,
that is the counting of that time.
Doesn't mean anything. Doesn't mean
anything. No, it doesn't mean anything,
but if someone's five minutes late, you're
like, bitch, you're five minutes late.
Well, I'm never mad about
that because I'm always late.
That's interesting.
Um,
well the only time supposedly is now
and everything else is just are pathetic
attempts at measuring it and trying to,
that's just coordination on like, you
know, people like that's all we're doing.
Like how old are you? Um, you know,
and then that just means how crispy
you are from going around the sun.
That's not like really anything.
Sorry. Yeah, you're like, sorry.
Right skin.
Cracklin you know,
like it's just kind of that and to me
like time is just, it's just space.
It's like how far are you away
from this gravitational pull?
I think gravity is way more interesting.
I think time is just us
coordinating with math.
Well, we definitely are, but it's
also like when the sun's coming up,
like check your watch, six 15 sun's
coming up. That's a real thing.
We're just clocking a spin of an earth.
It's the same thing with the
lungs under water. The earth spins
disagree with you at the same time.
Yeah. That's fine. I think you're right.
But I also think the fucking
movie starts at four 30.
That's another human putting on a movie.
It's true.
Coordinating with giving me an example
of time that is a manifest thing outside
of human coordination.
Um, well you could the
oldest, and I don't mean
like things happening, right? I mean time.
Is that helpful in any way?
Other than for us?
I don't think it exists
in the universe really
well. If the universe had a big bang and
that was a point, I don't want Starbucks.
Sorry. What do you think?
I think we're looking at,
okay. Black holes, you know,
say there's a train, right?
We're at a where the depot.
Okay. I love that word.
Try to depot depot or home
depot or a train depot. Okay.
And there's like a giant but of
a train. Right? Huge. I Dunno.
20 feet tall.
18 feet wide.
Yeah.
Filled with that. Likes that,
that feeling of like, oh my God,
there's great mechanical power.
And then it leaves the depo,
but you're still there. You
didn't get on it. Right. And it,
it just travels in the distance
into a Tinier and Tinier, Tinier,
tinier speck until it's just a little
point. They, you can't see it anymore.
Did the train shrink? No. Okay.
So when you see all this
matter going into a black hole,
is it really hitting a singularity or
we really condensing matter to that
extent?
Or is it just condensing to a certain
extent and traveling in the distance?
Is it going somewhere?
And that's why we perceive it as gone.
It's, it's basically a run
this by an astrophysicist,
then they break out the worm hall.
But that's not the same thing.
That's not what I'm saying.
Like,
and I think the big bangs or
the other end of that process,
the under end of the process of coming
out, that's a, that's a real, uh, thought.
They think that, well, every galaxy
has a super massive black hole,
black hole that's in the center of it.
One half of 1% of the mass,
the entire galaxy. So the
larger the galaxy, the largest
supermassive black hole,
the prevailing theory is that,
or one of the prevailing theories I
should say inside every black hole may be
another universe.
It's entirely possible that
there's another universe
of hundreds of billions of
galaxies, each with supermassive
black holes in center of them,
and he'd go through that one you go into,
it's fractal and it just goes
on forever and ever and ever.
That's entirely possible
philosophy. And I think the
whole Universe is spinning.
I think the whole thing's
a spiral. Yeah. Mm.
I think they think that don't pay them
within the spiral. You get the eddies,
right, which are the galaxies
and the irregularities and stuff,
but the whole Shebang is also spinning
the multiverse ideas
like legit scientists.
Talk about that now that there might be
different for that number of universes.
Yes, I agree with that.
There's so much more sense.
What makes some kind of like the people
that go, wow, that's crazy. Well,
the universe is crazy.
It's crazy.
It's crazy that you look out and
you see forever. That's crazy.
That's fucking crazy. And when
you look up, you're looking out,
you're sitting on the side of a planet,
like in the middle of the whole thing,
right? Yeah. You're in the middle
of this soup of, of reality,
but to think that that's crazy, but
that's as crazy as it gets. Like says who?
Why would,
why would you think this fucking infinite
numbers of these things out there that
were just a part of
something that's so big.
Like if you looked at all
of the Zeros on that number,
you wouldn't even be able to wrap your
head around it. You'd be like, what?
What's a billion? How many? How many
zeroes is that? How many billions is this?
How many trillions is a billion and
what? There's no way. It's too much.
There's this thing, I love it so
much and it's talking about it.
It has to do with why we haven't
seen aliens yet. The Fermi paradox.
Yes. Yeah. I think that's it. Yeah. The
Fermi paradox is like questioning why?
Because there's so many different
life. I mean, some different plants,
it could potentially support life because
like if there's 100 billion galaxies
or hundreds of billion, and each one
has a hundreds of billions of stars,
how many of those have habitable
planets and the if the, if so,
why haven't they contact? Yes. Yeah,
and like the math is overwhelming that
either we're the first or they kill all
the comers or,
or there we're like,
or we turn inward
and go into the,
what's the turn inward
turning inward is the,
the idea that we all go virtual and
then we become some sort of a symbiotic
thing connected to this,
this hive mind,
this real electronic reality.
Okay.