So, uh, apparently Ron, why you have a
mugshot that we can add to our collection?
Yeah, I'll get one over here. I'll have
it framed and sent it on up. Uh, oh,
I made, we'll make sure it's a small
enough to put on that wall out there,
you know?
So it'd be a pretty big one.
I'd like to have a pretty
dominant spot over at the, uh,
tell me what you need experience.
I'll give you a fucking six foot tall
one brother. All right. All right.
So that's it. Six foot tall life
size. Yeah. Get a free fuck it.
Yeah, it was a bad picture. Yeah, they
were really bad. So, uh, this, we're,
we're talking about this, this
is a, you got busted for weed.
Somebody ratted you out that
there was weed on your plane that,
that they didn't say there
was a weed on my plane.
They said it was a drug smuggling plane.
Oh.
And so there's a hotline that you can
call and they just pilots that had fired
and,
and uh,
and so I'm just sitting on the plane
looking out the window and there's drug
dogs and people in invest and
machine guns and I'm like,
what's going on out
there? Well, but you know,
as soon as they determined
that that's not what it was,
that I just had some personal,
we'd that obviously somebody called
in and allied instead of going in and
arrested that guy, they took me to
jail then it makes no sense at all.
And then the, in the
newspaper, the sheriff goes,
well he might not have had much pot with
him, but who knows how much he did have.
And who knows,
I didn't kill somebody.
How about we just put me up for murder
right now if we need no evidence at all.
You know, is he didn't steal larceny.
How about that something site.
Then they went, they drove by in a pit.
They drove by three meth labs in a
dead hooker just to get to my plane.
And they're really,
the funny part of it was the next day we
were going to go somewhere else and I'm
in Louisiana and uh, but then now
I've got to, you know, just we,
we can get rid of, that's
all we can do. Cause they,
they might do it again next night,
the next place more dry.
So now we've got an apple
were smoking out of there.
There are two of them on horseback and
Alex feeds that one of the horses as he's
walking by here, take this little apple
tried, you'd check your plan again.
They did check it again. But we, we just
had come up with this little plan that,
uh, you know, we would just would end,
he also had to eat a little bag of
weed and he was really stoned onstage,
really stuff. But we, you know, we, we
didn't go to jail that night. If you eat,
just eat weed will get you
high. Yeah, absolutely. Will
it take, it takes a while,
but it was a big old Chawla of it. I mean,
he do a big old lip, full cheek full.
I'm surprised people don't chew. We'd
like. There's no one out there chewing.
It tastes like ass dude,
which is why nobody eats.
We'd even the cookies, you know they gotta
they gotta watch it to keep in place.
There is a growing number of people
who juice the leaves and drink it.
Yeah.
You know like wheat grass juice.
They do it with the
leaves of cannabis plant.
I've seen people squeeze it to make
the Gig like the concentrate out.
So I think they're a, they're sticking
in one of those mass Decatur's.
Is that what they called?
Those things that make a,
you know the wheat grass like he had,
they can get juice at a fucking grass. It
makes sense. If you could get it out of,
I mean you might get a grass,
you could get it out of any plant right
behind. You don't get high though.
Like getting a CBD out there. What's
the point for Health Ron? Oh yeah.
You know, it's like Oh duals pot
to tell you what's not bad either.
The Heineken Shit that we got,
we have Heineken zero, zero,
whatever the fuck it is. It does not
taste bad. It's what areas go, uh,
no alcohol in it, but it tastes so
you don't get that annoying buzz.
I know. No, you don't get down to that.