Well, what, what, what do you
do with them specifically? Well,
I've been with him since 2004 and
recently became his coach right before the
first Denesha Johnson fight.
And I'm going to head coach for Nma and
you're in disguise in case some other
athletes try to swipe it and it's
Halloween. Happy Halloween. Everybody.
Happy Halloween folks. So, uh, first of
all, man, congratulations on your victory.
Um, what does it feel like?
Oh Man, it's uh, uh, it uh,
it feels good. It feels good. Try to keep
this silly a fist away from your face.
Yeah. Uh, it feels good because it's um,
[inaudible] I think as a competitor you,
you, you live for these moments. You live,
you live for these fulfillments, you
know? Yeah. I think somebody like,
and then I told people since the
beginning, it wasn't so much, you know,
the UFC belt,
but it was because it was it.
I made it about Demetrius and it was
about Demetrius, you know, cause I was
mean. He is widely considered to be
the best pound for pound fighter ever.
And you're the first guy, not only
to beat him, but the first guy who,
not just to beat them,
but mean beat him in like 11 years,
but the first guy to win an Olympic
gold medal in wrestling and a UFC
championship. I mean those are
two gigantic accomplishments.
Yeah, no, for sure. It's
almost like a god, it's, it's,
I'd beat the greatest to me the greatest
of all time. And then on top of that,
I be, you know, I can, I can
make the run for, you know,
who's the greatest combat athlete
of all time. Yeah. Like it's a,
I'm a two sport world champion.
Just like,
yeah, Dale. I mean, you're absolutely
in the running now. I mean, if,
if he's not the greatest of all time,
I think he is.
But the argument is that he didn't face
people as good as John Jones faced and
then fade or is the other fade or an
Anderson silver or the other people that
are in consideration for the
grace of all time. I mean, it's,
it's just a subjective argument.
I mean, who knows who's right,
but obviously you beat without a doubt,
one of the best ever.
Yeah. Yeah. And, and, and like, I
would, I would tell people there's,
there's a bit of a of admiration that I
had for Demetrius Johnson. Like I was,
uh, it was, it was like, you know,
you're fighting the dude that's, that's,
that almost seems untouchable that
you see a guy that makes you question
yourself like, Whoa, this is, this
is this, this guy. Is that right?
Good. Well, what's crazy is you
beat him after he had stopped you.
Just how long was it?
Two years.
Uh, but close. We're about two and a half
years ago now. Yeah. About, I was like,
I think two years.
Four months.
That's,
that's an amazing turnaround
between getting stomped in
the first round and then
coming back and beating him and beating
him in the championship rounds is really
where you pulled it off.
No. Uh, and that, absolutely,
I had studied Demetrius Johnson like
as soon as a lost on the first time.
What I pretty much did is I got, I got
rid of a lot of people, including my,
my MMA had coach. I just,
my whole philosophy was,
if I can't be the best and there's
something wrong, you know, emotionally,
physically, everything. I was just
invested. And when I, I'm just like, man,
I need to, I, I'm looking for
a better leader, you know? And,
and that's kind of what I
did. I ended up, you know,
letting go a lot of my cornerman, you
know, started traveling the world.
W went out to Singapore, went out
to a, to Thailand, went out to, uh,
to the Netherlands, spend months
and months at a time out in Brazil.
Like I, uh, I was on a quest. It was
like the, I kind of remind myself,
literally like ash catch him from Pokemon.
Like I was just on a venture
vision quest vision quest.
It was Matthew Modine move.
I, even, Swain, Swain
has to watch that movie.
And that's, and, and, and, and, and it'd
be, like I said, it became in a session,
I knew that if anybody could do it,
it'd be, it'd be Henderson who to,
like I really did it. And even after
the first time, Joe, when he beat me,
I still, when they asked me, it's like
Henry, you know, like I would, I was like,
guys,
I don't know,
but I still know that I could beat him
even being knocked out like two minutes
and 36 seconds.
Like I still knew in my heart and UFC one,
I sat there press crop that says,
I know I'm still the one that's,
what was it about him that made
you think that you could beat him?
What was it about you specifically
in relation to him and his skill set?
It was a, um, I, if you're
asking me what the difference,
what was it that made you think even
after he stopped you in the first round?
Oh God. Uh, I think it was
more so just believe in it.
My, and my abilities. I think
me just believe in more.
Okay. Henry, you need time.
Like I was only doing MMA for three
years when I fought him the first time.
Yeah. A lot of people
don't know that. Yeah.
The Sears you see you fighting
for the title, not once,
but twice that you probably had
been doing MMA for a long ass time.
But when you find them for the first time,
it's a very,
that's a very short amount of
time to be fighting and MMA.
It's especially again to caliber athletic.
Demetrius,
what year did you win the Olympics
and, oh wait, yeah, that is,
I mean when you're doing that you're 100%
dedicated to wrestling. You have to be,
right. So were you doing any striking
training at all back then? Um, I did.
I did. What happened was once I
won the Olympics, almost kind of,
I fell out of love with the sport.
I fell,
I fell out of love with Russ
and I remember being at the
Olympics and being like,
man, I just, I don't know if I have it in
me no more just cause you're burned out.
I was, yeah, my whole childhood was
gone because of the sport. You know,
like crazy basketball further.
What are you doing? I mean, anyway,
I've been waiting for you to say that.
We'll do it in stages.
So you, you fell out of love
with it. I fell out of love with,
is it just because your whole life had
been dedicated to wrestling and you'd
finally achieve the greatest,
so great goals. Yeah.
Olympic gold medalists is the top of the
mountain. No, but check this out Joe.
And it was like
in the year of 2007, um, bad I
went through the worst year ever.
Like I was ready to become a world
champion and I went out to the world
champions in 2007 and I didn't even
score a point like in the first round,
like I got put out by, by Iran. And uh,
for some reason that whole year, man,
I was just going through freaking
struggles like left and right.
You're talking about just that versus I
couldn't want to turn him in to save my
life. What was it? Um, I
don't know. I don't know.
I truly, truly don't
know. I think I was, uh,
I think I probably begin kind
of fallen out of love with it.
And I remember there was to me,
there was only two tournaments that
everyone had to win and that was,
that was the Olympic trials and
eventually the Olympic Games and,
and somehow like,
cause I'm correlating this with the,
with the fight with Demetrius
Johnson and uh, I remember,
you know, just, just
almost being in tears.
Like I just don't know if this is for
me and the, but I just stuck with it.
I stuck with it.
I ended up putting in the Olympic trials.
I ended up going to the,
you know,
the Olympic Games and ended up pretty
much fallen behind in every single match,
uh, that I was wrestling in. So the,
these are kind of the adversities
that I was going through,
like leading up to become
an Olympic champion.
You know, it's interesting
when you were fighting, um,
Demetrius for the second time, Daniel
Cormier said something very interesting.
He said, most guys, he goes, I
would never give a chance. You,
you get stopped by Dj.
And then a couple of years later
you're fighting him again. Like he's,
he's going to have your number where
he's going to be better in the rematch.
And he goes, but Henry, so who chose
a different kind of athlete? He,
and he talked about you competing and
then coming back a year later and being,
he goes, he was many times
better. He goes, the,
the amount of improvement that he got
in just one year was just unbelievable.
Yeah. I think, you know, I guess she
couldn't hold that teacher. Netics no,
I think you could talk a lot about desire
to just having the only get you so far
what it taught, he had, the Olympics
has, has g great genetics for sure.
But it's almost, it almost becomes a, uh,
a mentality on, because of a philosophy.
It's like you almost start doing things
almost like two to not feel the H to,
not to not feel the pain of losing.
Hmm.
Like that's a motivator to
not feel the pain of losing.
And I remember when Demetrius Johnson
hit me, hit me and hit me in the leg.
And I had literally,
I don't think he put your how severe it
was like I literally spraying like a,
a severe low ankle, spend those first
30 seconds and the second fight.
So I fought Demetrius Johnson like that.
But it was,
it was to me the motivator was like,
man,
I don't want to feel that pain
of losing no more. I hate it man.
I hate feeling second place.
I hate feeling Kinda Kinda
somebody looking over me.
Someone's a almost like
a manhood challenge and I
hate that. Was it a low leg
kick that uh, that been
made your, your ankle go
go? Like what was it? It was a,
there's a nerve that you have
behind that like the bonus up PR,
I think it's the premium peripheral
peripheral nerve p. E. R.
Yeah. And I got hit there.
So I put my foot to sleep.
Just like when Michael Chandler happened
to him and bell tours. Same thing.
Exactly. You stepping on it. It's just
not working. And the pro and the reason I,
the reason why everybody kind of got
scared. I mean, cause I was, I was hurt,
but I remember before the fight,
I remember,
I remember I saw my cornerman like
kind of wait for, I fought the meters.
I remember I saw him all. Uh, I
saw him on nervous and never see,
I remember grabbing my cornerman is
team putting them right in front of me.
I remember telling us, hey
guys, I've been here before.
Like I was ranked 31st in the
world. I'd be, I know, I, I,
I became a world champion in wrestling.
Like guys,
like I want you guys to
have a little faith in deed,
but I'm going to ask you guys one
thing and I'm going to ask you guys,
I'm going to ask you guys to be composed.
I said, the key to winning this fight,
this for me to be composed. And then
pretty much there's six hours later, they,
uh, right before, you know, walk
on this are playing my song.
I looked back at my corner and I
said, uh, and I said, guys, I said,
the key to this fight,
remember I said it'd be composure.
So when Demetrius Johnson kicked me,
like I, I believed in my own philosophy,
I went back to, all right, my
composure because I was hurt Joe.
Like he could've stopped me that that
first round I was forced to switch south
South Paul, which I never fight in south
Paul, you know, so now I'm kind of,
I worked with me and Demetrius
Johnson or playing poker,
my whole philosophy and the key to this
victory was a composure part. And uh,
when he hit me, I, uh, I really did.
I was like, oh my God, not again,
not again. I'm not going to last two
minutes and 36 seconds. Not Again,
but it again, the motivator was
not to feel the pain to lose again.
Like it wasn't the desire to win.
I was like,
I just don't want to feel that pain
anymore as a competitor, as somebody that,
that, that that's on a mission
to that sacrifices life.
Explaining to someone who's
never experienced that before.
What is that pain like?
You train for how many weeks and then
you find mighty mouse with the title.
You get stopped in the first round.
What is our pain? Oh Man. It's,
I think every fighter has a spirit.
Like what is the spirit?
The spirit is your spirit is your
dream. This bird is that, you know,
you've watched somebody become a
world champion. You want to be, hey,
I want to be just like that guy. Your
confidence, your self esteem, that's the,
that's your spirit.
And you will also,
we also have a spirit of a war
that's like the man has side of it.
And what happens when I got stopped
with Demetrius Johnson's to,
I almost felt like,
and I've never gone through this,
not even in wrestling in my life,
like I was like,
my spirit was shot and I had to kind
of pick up my pieces to kind of start
healing myself, like mentally.
And I feel like it. And if it,
and if you look at a job
with somebody like Roy Jones,
jr he got knocked out one time
and it became a domino effect,
you know, because he never, he
never picked up those pieces.
He never started healing that spirit.