The joe rogan experience,
kind of weird how they cited some of
those same parts of the code of conduct
where,
Oh yes,
every employee should do their utmost
of reducing bias and harassment and
illegal discrimination.
When really my document
was about illuminating the
bias against conservatives
and the harassment against them and the
legal discrimination that we're doing in
multiple parts of our pipeline.
There's no room for conservatives today,
sir.
I mean I'm uh, you
conservative. Do you feel like,
because I,
I'm pretty much just libertarian but
that's thought of as conservative cause
it's convenient. Right. You just
immediately pushed off that right wing,
angry white male group.
Yeah.
Everyone that's in the center or
right of that is all right. All right.
Yeah.
You favor of smaller government,
less intrusion. Yeah. I,
I'm not super libertarian.
Like I obviously believe that there's
places where the government should be,
but just I do my,
yeah,
my like internal leaning or in
philosophy is more like that.
Yeah. I think socially I
lean more left like socially,
like in terms of like welfare
and things along those lines.
And you know, obviously this, um,
protected status is driving me crazy.
This, this thing that
Trump's doing with, um, uh,
children that were born in this country
are born in other countries and then
brought over here as children and then
they're talking about deporting them.
That drives me fucking crazy.
That kind of the hard right version
of that is despicable. This,
these people that I see online, like why
didn't they apply for citizenship? Oh,
who knows? Maybe because
they're fucking 13. You know,
like you out there applying for
citizenship if you were 13. No, I mean,
when you're 13 years old,
you're playing games and hanging out with
your friends and then you find out you
were born in Guatemala and
you're like, what? I'm like,
you have to go back to Guatemala.
What? Yeah, it's crazy.
I lean way left when it comes
to those kinds of things.
Gay Rights and things like, um, you know,
a social programs for disenfranchised
people and disenfranchise communities.
I W I lean way, like if I want
my tax dollars to go to anything,
I want it to go to making
people's lives easier,
whether it's socialized
medicine or whatever.
Whatever we could do to make people like
have an easier path to success and to
not have them so burdened down by their
environment and their circumstances.
That I think is like our responsibility
as human beings to try to,
I don't want to say even the playing
field because there's never going to be an
even playing field, but to give
people opportunity, that's it.
Just give people an opportunity to do
well and not have it so completely stacked
against them. So in that sense, I'm
not very conservative in that way.
Like I'm not one of those pull yourself
up by your bootstraps thing because
that's just, that's so
delusional. Like some people are
just fucked, you know, they,
you know,
they,
they're born with a terrible hand and
it would be nice if more of us were
charitable that regard,
you know?
And some people think that that charity
should be a personal issue and that we
should all just do it. You know, as
part of our community and our society,
maybe that's a good argument and,
but maybe the argument is
that our government should
be a part of our community,
you know, and that we should
think about it that way.
Instead of thinking of it as,
as,
as this overlord that decides and
designates where our money should go,
then maybe we should have some more
say in it. It should be some sort of a,
a more, uh, you know,
just, just a, a more,
uh, more kind approach. So in that
sense, I leaned pretty far left,
but I'm also pretty
pragmatic, you know, and I,
and I also know that if
you give people too much,
it's like sort of that winning
lottery ticket thing or that
you know,
that
if you, if you make things too easy
for people, they don't try hard.
It's just a natural part of human nature.
So in that sense,
some conservative and a lot of ways,
yeah,
you definitely need some sort of safety
net and to ensure that people can
actually achieve the American dream.
I'm like,
I'm,
I've been bleeding more and more towards
universal basic income than anything.
I think universal basic
income at a certain point
that look good enough that you
can just eat and survive and then maybe
that would open up a lot more people to
pursuing dreams to going after
things. I mean, I don't, I don't know.
I mean there's arguments for and against
and I think it's debatable. It'll
be interesting to see, you know,
Finland I think was proposing start this
because we don't really know what will
happen.
Right.
And maybe people will start doing their
hobbies and really find their passion.
Maybe they'll just sit at home and
watch TV and die. Yeah. I, it's really,
these are the problems that we as
a society we'll have to overcome.
And of course these are just
first world problems, but that's,
that will be what the world is like.
There was another country today.
I read about it on Google,
uh,
another country today that's
considering a universal basic income,
but fucking, what was it? South Korea.
Oh really?
Um,
see if he could find it. It's,
it's Scotland. Is that what it was?
Hmm.
Um, I think there's many,
many people that are, I mean,
Elon Musk has been promoting this lately.
Scotland will be game funding,
universal basic income experiments.
Yeah. Hawaii. That's what it was.
Hawaii considers universal basic
income as robot scene, stealing jobs,
fucking robots running around the streets,
stealing jobs. Yeah. It's Hawaii. Um,
I think there is some real
arguments to be made and I think,
um, Elon Musk, who is of course
a part of this automated,
uh, car revolution and he's,
uh, he's creating these,
these trucks that they're gonna start
using to haul things and they're going to
be, and it's going to remove
a lot of jobs and they're,
they're starting to talk about
universal basic income is, you know,
a real solution to that. I mean,
it's entirely possible. It's,
it's certainly an argument, you know,
it's certainly worth discussing.
Yeah.
Something like that.
And hopefully the incentives will be
better than some of the current welfare
systems where, you know, you're not
incentivize to get off of it. Yeah.
If you start working,
then you'll lose all of it while universal
basic income can be made such that
you start working on,
then you'll lose a little bit.
But it's never an actual
incentive to not work. Yes. Right.
It's not an incentive to not
work, but it's an, it's a
gives you food and shelter. Right.
So then you could go pursue a dream,
which I think it would be
wonderful. I mean, look,
if there's anything that our tax
dollars should be going towards,
it's creating less losers, right? Less
people feel disenfranchised by the system.
You know, if you're, if you're, if
you can pay x amount of tax dollars,
but live in an exponentially more safe
and friendly and happy environment,
I think most people would be leaning
towards that. I think it would.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and we'll
see this, we see it too. And um,
people that start companies where
it's a huge risk to start a company.
Most people fail.
And most entrepreneurs in silicon
valley are men who are much more,
uh, willing to take risks. But if we
do have some sort of strong safety net,
then it won't be so bad if you fail,
and maybe that'll help address some of
the gender gap too. That's interesting.
[inaudible]
okay.