Through the fucking Tsa thing on your
right. Yeah, I'm sure they must be wreck.
Really worried about people
walking in that store.
You got to get buzzed in and Oh
fuck you.
He sounds something dude.
You could smash and grab
like $6 million crazy.
Somebody just did that recently.
Um,
in England they smashed and grabbed
a watch store with machetes.
Yeah. Cause you know there's this
thing in England going on right now.
I don't know if you know it,
but they have,
London has for the first time
ever passed the United States, uh,
passed a New York City rather for
the most murders. Really? Yeah.
Ever since he was stabbing each
other and stabbing each other.
So the London mayor,
mayor of London on Twitter wrote a
tweet that has been getting him tortured
online saying there is no reason
to have a knife. If, well,
I saw that knife, you will be PR.
We catch you, you yo regular guy,
regular guy dive. I open packages, I carry
a knife. I want to cut a piece of rope.
I have a knife on me. He said, okay. Not
Anymore. No. In London, this guy saying,
if you have a knife and
you're caught with one,
you'll be prosecuted to the
fullest extent of the law.
And of course United States were
going crazy over here. Like oh it's,
I thought it was a gun problem and
that was a fucking gun problem.
You got a band nine is what's next
steps fucking scissors we need to do.
Where are you going? Where's
this going to end? Yeah. Yeah. I,
I do have to think that. I think we
have a little bit of a gun problem.
We definitely had an issue problem.
We definitely have something going on.
But this smash and grab
these motherfuckers use
machetes. That's gangster.
That's game. Cause they
need, nobody had a gun.
He tried to use a machete and dudes behind
the counter of shotguns. Real problem.
There's a homemade machete. A
homemade machete. Yeah. Wow.
How do they know it's homemade? Cause they
call it, the guy says quotes, homemade.
They caught them in my house right here.
Good for, good for you. I guess he
didn't get away. No. Good attempt. Yeah.
But it's again,
watches,
like when you think about something
small like jewelry and watches,
something that's this little on something
you fit in your hand could be worth $1
million.
It's one of the only things in life or
something that fits in your hand is worth
$1 million.
Yeah.