There's some scientists making weed now.
I mean they've gotten,
they got real botanists involved.
There's money in it now and now
that it's opening up in Canada,
it's going to be really weird because in
Canada they're making it legal, right?
It's legal now.
So um,
I'm pretty sure RJ Reynolds is that who
it was and we just dumped a shit ton of
money and did some marijuana production
in Canada that's going to file suit in
the United States.
It's,
there's too much money involved in it
and it's going to be good for everybody.
It's going to be good for capitalism.
It's going to be good for people getting
marijuana as long as regular people can
sell marijuana to let fucking Rj Reynolds,
as long as they don't put some
restrictions like they were trying to put,
was it you Jamie?
They told me about what they were trying
to do in Ohio where they were trying to
make it set up where you could,
you could grow weed but only a couple
companies could grow it so that we would
be legal, but only a couple
of companies would monopolize.
And then everybody was like, fuck
this. But Dad ended up passing it.
I believe that's terrible. It's sad
that that mean that's such a corruption.
That's like saying, okay,
you could have tomatoes,
but we're the only ones who grow these
fucking tomatoes. Like why? It's a tomato.
That's a law against nature. So you're
saying that nature can't take place.
I can't put a seed in the
ground and grow my own shit.
Get the fuck Outta here is
illegal. It's illegal. Okay.
How's it different than corn? How's it
different than a fucking, uh, a pear tree?
It's not. It's a legal life form.
It's a life form. It's a plant.
You're allowed to grow it.
And if you say you can't grow it,
you got a corrupt system.
You got some bullshit law that you
weaseled in because he greased up some
assholes and the other people
don't have as much money as you do.
So the only reason why that ever happens
or people are so desperate to get legal
weed that they let some dickhead dominate
the entire industry. Some greedy. Fuck.
Now the deal is it's
legal or it's not legal.
Otherwise we're in some sort of a weird
dictatorship. You know, this is not,
you can't just decide it's
legal, but you're the only
one who gets to make money.
Fuck you. It's a plant. That's crazy.
Imagine if you owned all the pine
trees in the country. Donald Dominique,
my country, my pine trees. You want
to buy pine? You buying it from me?
I find you in a fucking Christmas tree.
I'll take you out crazy though.
What happened last week? We call
[inaudible]. I don't know. In New York.
You said he's wants to legalize weed.
Oh yeah.
He wants to make it recreationally
legal in New York. Stupid to shoot down.
You should be making money off of
it. It exists. No matter what you do.
If you're a capitalist, if you're, you're
a person who believes in a free market.
You already have whiskey, urea,
half pills, people can get high.
They're not so just, they're just
not. Stop with the childish arguments.
Give the fucking people freedom
and make money off it. You dummies.
That's what everybody should be doing.
They should make it legal and
profit off it and it will.
It shouldn't stop with that either.
It should go to mushrooms should
go to a lot of different things.
They should set up clinics.
She set up places where people
can go through mushroom therapy.
People that suffer. They're coming
back from the war. PTSD. You know,
there's, there's so many different
benefits for depression, uh,
people that are getting ready
to, to, you know, to pass away.
They have extreme anxiety.
A lot of that is alleviated by mushrooms.
People that have gone through extensive
cancer treatment and realized their
terminal.
One of the best things for these people
as mushrooms is that it helps them ease
their pain and suffering.
And they'd last dying days.
And it doesn't seem to have
any negative effects, you know,
other than the occasional person
losing their fucking marbles,
which is going to happen
no matter what you do.
It's something that should be studied
and it shot something that should be free
and it could benefit people.
So it should be fucking legal.