Okay,
you gotta be tall. And here's what
the craziest shit about the wall.
I'm sure you've seen where
it goes into the ocean. Yeah.
Was there like how are you going to
stop people from going around that?
That is the silliest thing ever that is
like having this gigantic huge wall that
is like having like a gigantic,
huge impenetrable boundary.
But on one side there's just
like a door. Yeah, that's a door.
You go right around that. I mean
it'd be hard to bring all your shit.
So what happens?
These guys right there on the Mexico
side and those guys over there on the
California side, like that is the weirdest
shit ever. ABC Ball with each other.
Do they? Yeah. Really? Wow. Okay.
So they added another piece to that
wall right there. So that wall,
that's an old wall. See that? The
construction of the wall that I saw now?
Yeah. Wow Man. He goes to a
swim, but as soon as you swim,
you know the part of the coast colors,
we'll come get you. That is so crazy.
Just what a strange and people would
go. You don't want a wall. Relax.
I hadn't said any of that.
Not saying that.
I'm saying just look at this just as a,
use your brain.
Just look at this objectively and
see how bizarre it is that there's a,
a gigantic physical boundary that keep
certain people from going into a certain
area. I mean, I,
I think that that one day that has
to not be a thing anymore, right?
Wouldn't you say?
Yeah.
And that is a crazy thing to justify.
Like you can't come to the good spots.
Like the good spots are limited. Well,
if they let people in and there'll
be no more, no more good spot,
it'll be just like the bad spots.
That's the, that's the fear.
And here's the thing, man, that
ain't none uncommon. That's not a,
it's not an imperfect, it's
not a fear that's not totally
illogical either. Right?
Like you would be worried if
you lived in a sweet place,
like a name,
a city.
Not Too many people perfect size
boulder, Colorado voters. Cool.
Yeah. Ben Was Fun, right? Everybody. Nice.
What if a million more
people moved into boulder?
Now all of a sudden it's 1,000,100
thousand and you're like, what the fuck?
What the fuck is this? You can't
go anywhere now. Everybody's rude.
He will start getting antsy that the
way they drive, they drive faster.
That's what happens to be more,
more gangs.
How do you fix that? That's
how, that's what we need to fix.
Not like whether or not there's
a wall. Okay. Do you fix?
How do you fix people from getting crazy
and no man shooting a little bolder.
Colorado probably have a subway system to
get other people off the streets. Yeah.
Yeah.
If they did,
if they did have like a couple million
people move, they're like, Bam,
start moving shit and sentence.
She would change radically.
That's what happens to places. You get
too many people. They just fucking change.
It's uh, it's still
strange fucked. See a wall.
It is Monday your house.
I'm not saying that I can,
but it gets so big.
It's so right when he left with a dude.
What'd you just stick to comedy?
Yeah. All I'm saying is it's weird.
It's fucking weird.
It seems to be something that should
be perhaps reexamined. It's idea of
like,
it's almost like we have weird parents
that we have to listen to for our whole
life and that those parents
are the government I know.
Look at like when I was,
when I was a little boy, I was
living in Mexico and um, my mother,
she to tie me up to a stump runaway,
Holy Shit. That glade to follow my dad
to work every day. My Dad was like, uh,
I think he was like a steel worker
or something. He worked on a lathe.
So he worked with metro at the time.
Yeah.
And I would follow him to work every
day because I was a board little kid I
guess.
And they could,
if I would run away every day and my
mind were tied me up to a little street,
stuck with a rope. Wow. I was
her pet, basically. Jesus Christ.
Holy Shit.
That's a weird memory. I know,
right? I lived it. I lived in, um,
I remember I lived in Mexico for a
little while, try with three or four.
Then my dad took off. Do
you remember? Mexico at all?
I remember a bathroom was outside
like an outhouse and we have to use
a flashlight to go outside and wow.
I remember mosquitoes everywhere and my
mom's family are living in like in one
big ranch with different houses
and it was fucking dusty.
I mean it was dusty. I was living
in them. Sinaloa Mexico. Right.
And they used to be a
truck that were water the,
the ground every day because it was
too dusty and there was no cement.
But then my dad took off to the
United States and we followed him.
We came here. We, we, we
were living in Tijuana,
Mexico for about two years.
Do you remember how you got
through? Yeah, we've got,
we're all,
my dad made it through first started
another family then came and got us. No,
but that's what I thought. He
was gone for a long time, man.
We, we went, we were living with my aunt,
her name was [inaudible] and she lived
in Tijuana, Mexico, right next to that.
Where that, where that gate is Colonia
three. I say what's up? And, um,
we, we went across with a, uh, like
a coyote, you know, a smuggler.
My mom pay the money and we got in his
car, we crossed and we made it through.
I remember we made it through,
but there was like a checkpoint
back in the day in San California,
the California Sheriff Department,
we'll just, the county sheriffs,
they will randomly stop cars,
you know,
like too many people in one car and his
car too heavy. So they got us and he,
they put us in there like in a
holding cell. My mom went one way.
We went the other way.
Wow. And how old were you?
I was probably four,
maybe or 500 member throw
three of three little brothers.
I have my little brother was like
three and another one was one or two.
Why would they separate you from
your mom? Um, I don't know. That's,
I guess that's how they process
where bags are illegal people.
That seems kind of crazy. She went
to one when I don't know what, um,
I don't remember crying or being scared.
I just know that we were watching
cartoons, you know, American cartoons.
That's how you remember.
And then they caught us.
We went back again and they cut it again
in another car and we got separated
again. But this time we were held for
a longer time. And I remember my aunt,
when she saw us a Mexico, she said,
ha, they caught you guys again.
Just jokingly. Wow. But the
third time was like my add.
And my mom came over this crazy
idea because we have brothers. No,
we had cousins in Sunny California.
And my mom said,
you know, why don't we just borrow
their passports, you know, to cross.
And, and I, I don't remember this,
you know, I just found out recently,
that's what happened. My brother
told me, my little young brother, um,
we dressed him up like a little
girl, like a fall lawn, little girl.
Um, because we had like three
passports and two were boys.
One was girl and we took straws
to guests and my mom and my aunt,
they forced my little
brother to be a little girl.
How did it make him look like a girl?
They just hit my little girl for two
weeks just to play around, you know,
they give them a fake name and so and
so, and he was playing, you know, dance.
He know why Noah, you know,
dancing, getting ready,
playing with the Little Barbie dolls.
And so he was preparing,
preparing broker dinero bro. Wow. Getting
rid of it for that row of his life.
Wow. How old was he? He was
two, at least two or three.
Manual young.
Wow.
Though we crossed and we
made it all the way and um,
I remember that, um, some
of the car picked us up.
We jumped into another car right away
and then we jumped into another car and
then that car drove us to
come to southern California.
We were like in Compton somewhere.
And Carson,
we're in a house that had the, it
was like, it was funny when the car,
it was like a hub for illegal immigrants.
Like everybody,
they will go in different places. Okay.
Hawaii, you're going to go to St Louis,
this guy, you're going to go to San
Diego, the lady, her three kids,
they're going to go to Boyle heights
because that's where the father is.
So that we ended up Guerra,
Boyle heights and um,
didn't speak no English at all.
But um,
I picked up English right away,
you know,
cause you're little like
watching bionic woman and Shit.
$6 million man.
Incredible hog to say hazard.
So you basically picked it up
from TV? Yeah, we'll them dukes,
but like what kind of,
what kind of like lessons did you take?
Lessons were in English
or none. Zero. When I was,
when I was in elementary school,
it was different from now.
There was no like separating these kids
who don't speak Spanish and put him in
an English as a second language class.
I started, I started, I'm kindergarten,
so, so you just picked it up?
I picked it up. The teacher,
the teacher never spoke Spanish to us.
She never said I'm okay. Hawaiian Europe,
you know what apple is? That
it wasn't nothing like that.
It was, um, it was like,
I don't got time for you. You,
you're going to pick it up or not.
Do you think it was because you were,
you were so young,
your brain could pick up
another language really quickly.
Isn't that what they say?
Like young people,
their brains pick up languages quicker.
I think I picked it up really fast,
but to my pronunciation,
we're not there.
Like I didn't know how to stay Baiada
and ain't going to say [inaudible] that
kind of makes sense,
right?
That a part of your brain would really
develop and make it real easy to learn a
language when it's real young, you
know, like, okay, how do I say this?
What do I you like give more of a
desperation for figuring it out.
But I bet you a little kid that comes
from another country like you did. Well,
you're a perfect example. You
learn from TV. That's crazy.
So you learned from just talking to
people that are around you and television,
television. Nobody is saying this
is how you say this is a pronoun.
This is a noun. This is a verb. No telling
you any of that. Nobody told me that,
but later I had a cousin who
lived there at Santa Paula and um,
she taught me that stuff. Like,
this is what you're saying,
this word [inaudible] we're playing,
we'll play that school together. Yeah.
Or she'll give me assignments and we
were just, she pretends to be a teacher.
And then I'll read.