You're a funny guy. Yeah. But outside of
that, I, I'm not lacking in confidence,
but leaving my house is like
I said, uh, uh, quite uh,
what I'm saying is like,
by whose definition is enlightenment?
Because like say if you wanted to go to
a concert or you wanted to go to a great
movie, what an enlightened
person. Enjoy a great movie.
I would think my version of an
enlightened person. What in fact,
enjoy a great movie. I, I've
been enlightened to the concert.
I saw James Brown when he first
got out of prison and I found that,
that that performance that he gave was
the most enlightened performance I'd ever
seen. Was this when he was in the car
chase, was that that prison? Yeah,
it was the way it was the last prison he
shot at cops because I believe so. Yeah.
That one was someone else used his
bathroom, right? Isn't that what happened?
Someone took a shit. Don't know. I know
that he got in trouble with the cops,
but maybe it was that, I
don't know. That's a big deal.
But to someone using this tool during,
is that a,
he had gotten out of prison and just
the idea that James Brown was in prison.
I think maybe I remembering
this incorrectly,
but I think someone used his toilet and
then he got mad at that person and shot
at something like either
shot the wall or something.
I don't remember that story, but I assume
that you're looking it up right now.
So we'll find out. Like he was in a high
speed chase. They shot his tires out.
They shut. I remember it this way.
Show something in a car though maybe.
I'm pretty sure they shot his tires out
and he was driving around on my rims.
He had to him and doing a lot of blower
or something, make him that agitated,
you know what I mean? No normal human
Doug. And we're talking about James Brown.
Is that agitated? I mean, who gets
that? And he was fucking phenomenal.
When it's you.
Who's young to state chase?
I went up to 85 miles an
hour and fall 14 cars.
He said he didn't stop because
he feared for his life though.
I don't try to see why it
started and I don't see that.
I feel like that that's what started it.
He was,
he fired off a gun because someone used
his toilet, by the way, a two stage chase.
I'm guessing he lived near the border.
Probably live in one of
those wacky states. We live
it. We live in Georgia. Oh,
okay. Well maybe he's like
Georgia, Florida. Yeah. It
could be close to each other.
Georgia, Florida line. It's not a
band. It is, right. It doesn't know.
Wheeler Walker make fun of them.
Failed a a Beta pullover.
That's all it is,
but I'm pretty sure that's why
they were pulling them over.
I think they were going after him.
I'm, I might be wrong about that.
Maybe that maybe I'm confusing him with.
Okay.
Chuck Berry was the one who was filming
people going to the bathroom. Right.
I think he, he liked to go in the piece
like the PN ladies. I'm pretty sure.
Interesting. I'm pretty
sure, interesting, genuine.
When I enjoy James Brown's music,
I'm not thinking about his car.
Thinking about his other side.
You know your story. Oh really?
Oh, here it goes. Yeah. Okay.
He carrying a deadly weapon in a public
gathering and attempt to flee Perise
driving under the influence of drugs.
Okay.
He reportedly stormed into the insurance
company next to his office waving a
shotgun and complaining that strangers
we using his bathroom as time reported is
Tad. That's it for six
miles. There you go.
Are you kidding me?
Years later this episode would
frame the 2014 j brown bio pic.
Okay.
80 get on up.
I'm guessing that I saw him after
this cause it was right after that.
It would be,
it would be late eighties early
nineties Jesus Christ. He did six years.
Yeah, he was in there for
a while. Six fucking years.
How about just sober him up?
He was on PCP. They gave him a year
for each mile. He drove on his Mac.
Rumors of a PCP habit already surfaced
by the time his erratic behavior came to
a head in September. Wow. Pcps a tricky,
we sang in the prison
choir. I bet he did. Shit.
Imagine you'd go to jail for like
stealing the car and you're fucking,
Sally is James Brown. Like, hey
buddy, what do you want to do?
That's something that's a hell of a
story. Yeah. Help him write some songs,
you know, get on up. Yeah.
Did you ever see, um,
when he opened up for,
um,
the Mohammed Ali fight with George
Foreman documentary? Holy Shit.
Was that incredible? That was
incredible. Yeah. Incredible. Yeah.
He had so much power. There was something
about him, man. He would get on deck.
It was just power.
Give you an idea.
How much power prince wished for
that power yet? Well, prince had it,
but he had another way. Never way,
but prince looked up at Howard.
Didn't know James Brown was ridiculous.
All I looked up to it. Yeah.
I don't have any musical talent.
It just tells you what a waste all of
this was because Elvis had that power and
he didn't use it.
He had it early on and then he could
never dance like James Brown though.
Or if he did, he never showed
it. It would be different.
It's a different kind of power. If
he just took an harness. Here it is.
Look at this.
Look at his dress too.
Just looking at the fucking
pants and the Shelia's. God Damn.
Drop it down doing splits. I know. No,
he was not human. And by the way, he,
he's not even really flexible enough
to do a full split and yet he's still
dropping down on stage.
You know,
he was wearing a turtle neck
that night and I said to him,
cut that baby out.
Let's leave a little bit.
Let's put your initials on there.
I think that that was done in advance.
What was the girls was hanging
around with James Brown. Yeah.
Look at these giant ass band.
I don't envy those people.
Do you know when you see people
with bands, Torin, all those people,
all those working pieces have
to fall into place. Yeah.