Yes.
It pulls out a man got married.
Wait, when is a fighter going
to come out with a, I mean,
is there ever been a time where you
get more shit for liking the president?
Never even close. Not even close. I mean,
at the very least,
even if you didn't want him to win,
now that he's the president, would you
not want him to succeed? What do you want?
Why He, if he succeeds,
it means we succeed.
You want everything to be a catastrophic
failure because your guy didn't win,
or do you want him to get better at the
job and be really good at what he does
and be the best president that he can
be and pull a bunch of shit they do in
North Korea? What's up with that? Maybe
he did. I mean, maybe he was a part of it.
We're both North Korea and South Korea
giving Donald Trump all the credit.
That's amazing. If that's true,
that's amazing on CNN. He,
that alone shows you that his unorthodox
style that you might be terrible if
you're married to them or terrible if
you're doing business with them are
terrible if you're as
lawyer or terrible whatever,
but that unorthodox style
might have value to it,
but no one wants that value because you
don't want him to win because it's a
fucking weird time. It's like Joe, Rudi.
It's almost like you're rooting against
America because you feel so strongly
about the present. Like to your
point, would your rather have him out?
You want the economy, you
better. Here's the other thing.
You want Mike Pence to be president.
Are you sure you don't
know what you just said?
You don't know what you're saying
like that is not a smart choice.
That's not what you have voted for.
It's not what you want.
What you should want is even
if you don't like Donald Trump,
what you should want is that
he does a great fucking job.
He turns the economy around.
He goes after child pedophiles.
He goes after like whatever,
whatever, fill in the blanks,
whatever thing you would like them to do.
Even if he talks crazy shit about and
it gets on Fox and friends and says a
bunch of nutty shit,
wouldn't you still want that guy to
do the best job running the country?
This is where things get weird cause I
think most people say no. I think in,
if they say yes, they're lying what
they want and they want them to fail,
they want them to be the worst
ever because they watched.
That's what they want.
That's what they want. It's a flaw.
That's a crazy way of thinking.
But I didn't vote for Donald Trump,
but I want him to do great because
he's the fucking president.
Like either someone else comes along
that's better and wins and takes over.
Or why would I,
why would I want everything to go bad
even if I didn't vote for so retarded?
Everybody, if you had a doctor,
this is a good example, not not me,
but maybe it sucks, but if you had a
doctor and the doctor was a Dickhead,
the doctor's fucking annoying,
but he had to fix your knee.
But you know he's the best at fixing
knees. Like this guy's a dick at.
I hope he fucked my knee up.
You never say that.
It's only hurting you is the only guy
who can do this operation for anything.
You got to listen to me.
I know the guy's an asshole.
Let him operate on your knees. Going to
do a great job. He's going to talk shit.
He's going to try to fuck your mom,
but he's going to do his job.