So then you don't have to do the
leg work of the arguments. It's,
it's a lot harder to take a position that
says you should be who you are and you
have to fit that into
society rather than saying,
this is what the moral imperative is,
this is why we need those laws.
And if you deviate from that,
you're the bad guy.
So unfortunately they've just embraced
that, I think too much. So it's like,
it's like one of those things like when
I go to these colleges and I'm usually
invited by libertarians and
it's like the returns point,
low taxes and limited government and
live how you want to live, right?
That's the basics of it. But
they'll often say, you know,
I talk about low taxes in a college
class and people say I'm racist.
And it's like,
well how does race get into that?
But what they will say is that what
they'll say is, well, wait a minute.
If you want low taxes,
that means you don't want money
going to people who need it more.
And often it is people of color who need
it more. So you inherently are racist.
You have to think on how to make
the counter argument to that. The,
I think there's a very valid
counter argument that I buy into,
but you have to think it's very easy
to just take somebody who thinks the
reverse of you and go, you're
racist, you're racist. Such a thing.
Such a lazy way to approach an
idea. Yeah. Yeah. It's so lazy.
The only thing I have a problem with,
what Jordan has been saying lately is
this idea of enforced monogamy being the
solution to insoles, these involuntary
celibates that's not going to help.
So what do you think I become men?
Well,
what do you think his definition
of enforcement argument is?
Just to be clear with the force.
Monogamy were people, you know, the,
the culture encourages and supports
the idea of monogamy. Yeah.
In effect he's talking about Matt,
he's just talking about marriage and that,
but that's not going to clear the way
to people that no one wants to fuck.
It's just not going to.
The idea is that there's a bunch of men
out there that are taking up all the
viable females because no one's
getting married and it just,
there's no room for these insoles.
No,
they are not attractive to women,
whether they're not physically attractive.
You tell me Harvey Weinstein
was physically attractive.
Fucking disgusting pig.
Forget about what he did to those women
are the rapes or the sexual assaults.
He had a gorgeous wife.
His wife was gorgeous.
That was a voluntary relationship.
Okay, so how did that happen?
It happened through success.
It happened through success and confidence
and whatever the fuck else he's got,
Eh, you know, intellect. I don't
know what his mind's like. These,
these insoles, they have
to become men. Okay.
And there's the Jordans all about that.
I mean, his whole message is that,
I just don't think that enforced monogamy
has any factor whatsoever in this.
So he, I think he would say
this, but I'm not as lawyer,
but I think he used the phrase,
all he meant was marriage.
That generally societies that more
people are married and let's just remain
married. Right? So I think I can help.
I think perhaps if he was being
interviewed again by, by her,
he would use a different phrase. Even
if they, if even if he says marriage,
marriage is not going to help in cells,
these guys that are involuntary celibate,
they have to become attractive
so they have to become men.
Well the rest of his messages about that,
but they have to do difficult things.
That's what they have to do. They have
to, they have to build your confidence,
get your shit together.
And martial arts I think is one
of the best ways to do that.
I've seen so many men that were like sick,
insecure and Dorky and w they become
fucking nerd assassins through martial
arts.
And it's,
I think it's a great way
to build confidence and I
think there's an extreme lack
of adversity, physical adversity
and a lot of people's lives.
And overcoming physical adversity is
what leads to a lot of confidence in men.
And I just think that there's a lot of
men that are just have no idea whether
they can or can't do anything difficult.
And they have massive
insecurity because of it.
I think he would agree with every word.
I think he went to everywhere
that you just said there. Yeah.
I just think that marriage is not fixing
it. You know, culturally enforcement,
it's not going to fix it.
They have to become men and they had the
woman has to have a reason to want to
have sex with you.
Yeah.
So I think he would agree with that.
I think he would say that
once you accomplish that,
that that's when you will find
more women and that the next step,
the next natural progression in life is
that you will find someone that you want
to be partnered with and that that
then has the best value for society. I,
but I don't want to completely state his
case. Hmm. It's an interesting case. Yeah.
But,
but he completely,
I mean look why is it that for the
little bit that these articles get right
about him. It's that he's
helping men. He is, yes, he is
also helping women, but yes,
he is helping men to,
men need their shit together.
Need Framework for sure.
I mean people need this,
this thing about discipline and you
know, are you, are you, are you aware of,
you know, you're aware of Jocko, Jocko
Willink. Discipline equals freedom.
It's like one of the best catchphrases.
It's so accurate. It's empowering.
It's so empowering.
Get your shit together and then you,
the time that you have for recreation,
you'll appreciate it so much more.
You don't appreciate rest when
you're fucking off all day.
You're appreciate rest.
When you've worked hard,
that's when it means something to you.
When you've accomplished goals,
that's when this celebration is,
is something that
you,
you get a good feeling from it.
Do you have a part in your
life that you feel like
is lacking in that department?
In what department and just
like getting your shit together.
Like not slacking on snow.
Yeah, that's what I do. Yeah.
I mean I do a lot of shit.
The only way I could ever do as
many different things as I do,
as if I just get after it. Yeah. I
get after it pretty fucking good.
Yeah. I'm not, I'm not an
insecure in that. I mean,
whether it's through martial arts
or any kind of exercise or work,
I just, I take pride in getting things
done. I take pride in working. Yeah.
You know, especially working towards
things that are important to me,
whether it's working on my sat,
working on my stand up,
whether it's working on a podcast,
whether it's working on my martial
arts or my fitness or yoga or whatever.
I get after it. Man, did
you got to, and for me,
it's not a matter of whether or not it's
an option. It's like brushing my teeth.
I don't decide one day own
want to brush my teeth today.
I just fucking brush my teeth.
And when there's days where I'm doing
fasted cardio, when that alarm goes off,
it's not a matter of whether or not a
shut the alarm off. That's not an option.
You Get up,
you put your fucking shoes on,
you get the dog and you go running
because that's what you do.
And if you just decide that's what you do,
then you get things done.
And then a month later you're
like, oh, we did this all month,
and then six months later it's
like, oh, I did this half a year.
And then if you're doing Jujitsu, you're
like, oh shit, look, I got a blue belt.
Oh Shit. Now I'm a purple belt. And that's
how you become a black belt. He just,
you know,
and I got the good type of progressive
cause it gets progressively easier too.
I told you I'm doing that. It doesn't
though. It doesn't get easy. You know,
think so fucking hard every time
that alarm goes off like fuck,
but you don't get it for you now then
right when you started, I don't know, man.
Do you know the reward of it? You know
that that reward is some enforcement.
There's some enforcement in
the success that I've had in,
in completing these tasks, but every
fucking time I go to yoga class, I'm like,
oh Jesus,
90 minutes in 104 degree temperature
with these all these women that are going
to humiliate me, they can definitely
do things that you can't do well.
This is their tough man.
There's a lot of these older ladies
that are fucking tough, you know,
they just gut it out.
I was just one lady that goes there.
She's like 60 years old,
she doesn't even bring water and this
lady's in there for 90 fucking minutes,
sweat it out. She's there every time I
go, I'm like, she's not bringing water.
You sure?
She's 60 she could be like 20 and just,
Oh she's gray hair and tough as shit.
She drinks water before she drinks it
after. But when she's in that class,
he's just tough. It's just, you know,
it's never easy to do. You know,
it gets a little bit easier
when you get better at it,
but then you just try harder
and it makes it more difficult.
If you're always giving 100% effort, it's
always going to be hard. You know, you,
you take some pride in the fact that
now I can go two miles through the hills
and you know,
and reach the point of exhaustion
where before it was one or whatever,
whatever your little little
progress markers are,
you get some satisfaction in that.
But it's always difficult to get going.
The the,
the hardest step is the first step is
not the 30th staff or the hundredth step.
It's the fucking first one. It's
getting on the trail, getting going.
It's the hardest thing.
The hardest weight to lift is the first
one because once you get going like,
okay,
I'm a half hour into my workout,
I'm writing things down and I'm supposed
to be doing now I got, you know,
20 Chin ups and then the burpees and
then all these days you have to do it.
You just have to do it. And so many
people have a hard time doing it.
If you would have ever been moving.