I mean when I laughed so hard when a
guy goes, my balls got hot and you go,
there was the best company. The best
thing you could have possibly said was,
I understand. Love that
guy. Oh Man. Louis is,
he's a, he's a genius. He
figured out a way to be himself.
He forgot his Instagram page. No, no.
If there's anything fucking
crazy going on in the world.
Derek Lewis has it on his Instagram page
is Instagram page is the best people
found out about it.
I gave him a shout out to his Instagram
page on one of the UFC broadcasts and
now it's got like, what does he have? How
many falls do you have now? 1.6 million.
1.6 million. It's not good
though. It's fucking chaos.
He always gets videos deleted and removed,
but apparently they leave him up there.
I mean,
they're not threatening to take them
down, I don't think. I hope not every,
it's where I go to any fucking
dummy that's trying to like,
like light a bomb under a tire and fly
through the air and smash the roof of a
fucking garage with his face.
He's got all that shit.
Motorcycle accidents or people
trying to do wheelies and they fall.
It lands on them. Anything fucked
up on the Internet, dairy know.
It's funny he's got it all. Anything
crazy fucking, he's a hilarious guy.
But the fact that he could say
something like that, you know,
like right after a fight, why is
taking shape? So Paul's was hot.
He starts selling tee shirts afterwards.
My balls aside tee shirt so they don't,
I got one.
I don't think people listen to anything
that's being said about the, let's say
I need one. Derek, please. I
need one of those shirts I need.
I need one of those shirts
please. Derek. Oh my God.
He's the best. He such a
character. Fight his ass off too.
So do what the, I know it's
your show, but uh, what,
how many fights do you do now?
And does anybody care about a fight?
You don't announce childhood for
sure. Care. Yeah. I do a 10 a year,
10 or year events a year. I'm doing
like a big paper views, like 10.
There's a lot of them that are overseas.
I just
want you to be the voice right time.
I just don't have the time.
I don't have the time with
all the podcasts with doing
stand up and, you know,
making Netflix specials and shit
just don't time. Right. We have,
fuck now I know there's not like it better
when I do it once a month, like once,
like 10 times a year is basically
once a month or I liked,
I liked that better because
it seems like that's, um,
and it's the higher profile stuff.
I don't mind the aisle.
There's a lot of fights that are
not that high profile that I lost.
Like their Crosby, stills and
Nash and you're young, right?
You just pop in and do the big shows.
And that's funny. People, you know,
you don't care as much. I love it, man.
I love doing it. I still do. But, um.