The joe rogan experience.
I'm going to do a podcast which subtitles
in Spanish and I'm bringing them up
here on Friday. Why? Yeah,
please do it for me in
Spanish with subtitles.
And then I'm going to bring him up here
on Friday and we're going to have a
three way about Cuba.
Well it was like to rest on the
whole thing if you don't mind.
Well you mind so I'll
do mine about subtitles.
Justin at Barnyard cool work
or more total. Yeah. So no,
we will not clash with you dude.
The three of us together would be the
greatest podcast cause I could interpret
it and you would be, would be,
uh, it would be a real MMA.
You could really talk to him
about the hooks and to Russia.
That's a fantastic training.
Even the Cuban where they shipped them
cause they shipped you off when you were
young kid. They did. A lot
of people don't know. Yeah,
they look at you on that ain't go uh, I
looked at him. You don't have a choice.
They look at you and they go do us a
little, try that on. That's it. Now,
and then they'd take her to a certain
age and that or the 80 to send you to
Nicaragua or Russia and you train.
And that's why a lot of Cubans that you
docus because they go to rush and learn
judo.
Wow.
So he's going to tell you how they
shipped them off and they don't just tell
your mom would take him tomorrow.
It's always been interesting to me
because the Cubans and the Russians in
particular were always thought of as being
very technical. Really. The Russians,
Russians are super technical.
That was what a lot of people attributed
George Saint Pierre Success in
wrestling, you know, George's didn't
wrestle in college or in high school, uh,
but he trained with a bunch of Russian
nationals and Montreal and apparently
phenomenal wrestlers and they have
this incredible wrestling program.
Like when you see,
when you see Norma Madoff,
the way he mauls people inside the
octagon, like what in the fuck?
Like that is like a,
a perfect example of that.
Like style of super hard,
super technical wrestling.
They're so good at it. There's
so many. You see? You know,
see Loma Chanko used to be a wrestler
because a video of La Loma Chanko.
It looks like he's doing sambo.
It looks like he's got a like a g on
and it's him and some other cat and he's
like 11 years old or something like that.
So his father put him in everything.
His father made him. You know
Loma Chanko is, yes, yes, yes.
One of the best boxers ever.
Like literally one of the most technically
beautiful to watch boxers it's ever
lived. But this guy he used to
wrestle too. Like is this is a,
I don't think this is,
it is. It does him. Okay.
Is this him wrestling with somebody?
Yeah,
this is one now or he can still do
this shit. This is like pretty recent.
Like he showed some of his wrestling moves
but the other one was him when he was
a little boy. Like he's really
tactical man. He knows how to wrestle.
This is legit. Like when you see
the way he's moving his body,
he's not faking that. He's done that
a bunch of times and yeah, this is,
this is one when he's a
little kid, man, it's crazy.
It says Greco Roman wrestling,
but they're wearing a Geeky,
so I'm not exactly sure what it is,
but he gets his kid and a gets
behind him and sends him for a ride.
So he was, he's always been an amazing
athlete, like an area. I think there's,
there's something to that.
There's something to,
his father had an idea to crazy ideas.
His father took him out of boxing and put
them in a dance for like several years.
Uh,
Ukrainian traditional dance style.
Apparently they were talking about it
on one of those HBO shows for like four
years, I think it was the HBO show, but
for four years, I think he just danced.
You imagine that his father's like,
you want to learn how to box,
you got to dance and now
nobody's got footwork.
If you've seen him, Joey, you've seen
like his highlight reel. It's insane.
It's insane. It's insane. Jamie,
pull up allometry highlight reel because
my daughter goes to ballet and 80% of
the class is Russia.
So I was thinking about it yesterday.
I was watching the movements, the last
parade movement. I'm like, Jesus Christ.
If people did ballet, could you, and I was
thinking of the GSP, like, you know me,
I'm like, pre probably fucking
does ballet and give them that.
You would would be good.
It's great footwork.
This guy is the wizard or footwork.
It's crazy because he was
like right in front of you,
but he's one step ahead
of you at every turn.
Like he knows what you're going to
do, right? While you're doing it,
he's moving in a way that you can't move.
He's in front of you and then he's not.
It's crazy.
Like he's the one of the most technical
boxers I've ever seen and it just an
amazing stylistic achievement.
Like what he can do with his body.
His style is totally unique. I mean
every, but a lot of guys have done it.
A lot of guys that moved in and out,
a lot of guys have done it,
but he's doing it at such a high level,
such a high level that it makes people
confused. Guys quit in their corner.
They're like,
what in the fuck?
And I really think a lot of it probably
had to do with his father's cross
training and particularly with the dance,
I mean think about how effortlessly
he goes, like steps around guys.
I mean he's got some
incredible control of his feet,
but it makes sense that like you would
learn how to move your feet in a specific
way that the way you weren't learning
how to move your hands in a specific way.
Right? Like think about a guy
like Floyd Mayweather, right?
His hand combinations with his upper body.
There are so precise. It's like that,
that, that, that right? But with his legs,
is he as precise as he as precise
moving with his legs, his,
but his hands Rizzy 60% or 70%
or 80% lama chanko is probably
perfectly proportioned for his style,
with his ability to move,
but also also his ability
to box and hit you. Well,
he's got both things going on at the
same time with next level angles.
So that's what I was saying. Fuck. When
you're younger in Cuba, they picked you.
It's not like you wake up and
go, I want to be a wrestling. No,
they look at you and go, you look
like he could go, go, go wrestle.
And like what I was hearing back
from them in the early seventies,
it was like they just took you
away from your family. They uh,
that was part of your training. You
know, your, then they put you in a go.
We had no, you know where you
train them like their army. Do you,
have you talked to Y'all about this?
Like no,
we've discussed what this thing is.
I already have graphics on the podcast.
Well,
so I figured that I put them up and we'll
do a podcast in Spanish with fucking
subtitles, like an English film, like
a, like a Giulini movie, whatever.
One of those movies people think are
unique. Okay. I have it because his,
his English is too rough for me and I
know what he's trying to say and the
frustration in his face.
So now he did a tape the other day of
him in Cuba waiting for Bisbing in Cuba.
Cuba, no Romero's back. See if he's fine.
But what is the, see if you
can find he's, he's nuts.
He's nuts. He's nuts. He's
fighting Rockhold now,
which is a tremendous ride on the
10th all right. That's a crazy fight.
That's a crazy, very good
fight. Very good fight.
[inaudible].