I feel like my enemies the clock and I
was a lot of stuff I want to do in my
life and my enemy is the clock. Do you
feel like you live in the moment enough?
Absolutely. You do. I do. Because
that would be the worry, right?
Like if you're constantly
worrying about, damn, 20 years,
I'm going to be 70 30 years, I'm going
to be Haiti. If you keep doing that,
like there, there are people that look
ahead too much and don't just, I've,
I've talked to people that are 20 like,
fuck, I can't believe I'm 20 and like,
listen Motherfucker, you just
turned 20 dude, relax. You know,
just 20, you're a baby. Naw Man, I'm
going to be fucking 30 and 10 years.
Like you shut the fuck up.
You're 20 now.
I use it as a motivator and I remember,
I remember when I was,
when I was starting out, I was 21
years old. This is a crazy story. Uh,
I just got dropped from our record label.
I was signed to a record label called
delicious vinyl. How did you do as a,
I had a rap record on tuition rapper.
I was a rapper signed to delicious
with Tone Loc and Young Mc. Oh,
get the fuck out of here.
So my album doesn't get picked.
I don't get picked up for a second album.
And I moved to New York City.
I have two things on my resume.
Kiddie pool attendant,
cause I was a Kiddie pool
attendant and rapper.
So I'm staying on my friend's couch,
living on his couch with his roommate and
he tells me on Monday I got to get out
of the apartment.
So instead of going to look for
a new apartment over the weekend,
I go to my friend's Bachelor
Party on the Jersey Shore.
I'm at the Bachelor Party, I'm getting
a drink at the bar and I see this girl.
I started chatting with her.
She asked me where I live.
I told her actually as of Monday, I have
nowhere to go. She takes out a Napkin.
She writes her address on the Napkin.
I'm 21 years old and she says,
if it's an emergency on Monday and
you're stuck, you can come live with me.
Monday comes, I get kicked out of my
friend's apartment. I have nowhere to go.
I'm like,
this is an emergency.
I take out the Napkin and I live with
this girl and her roommate for six months.
It turns out that her father is
a big entrepreneur business man.
He owns a piece of the Yankees,
dislike monster mogul.
I write this song for the New
York Knicks called go New York,
go and it becomes a big success. You
remember that song? No, no, no. Okay.
That's okay. That's okay. I'm
not a sports fan. That's fine.
It becomes a big hit and I just realized
that there's an opportunity to write
theme songs for all these
professional sports teams,
but I don't have a penny to go
in the studio to do the demos,
to shop them to the team. So I need money.
So I go to this music guy and he says,
I'll give you $10,000 to go and do these
songs for 10% of everything you make
for the rest of your life. He wants to
buy me like a style the rest of your life.
I'm 21 he's like, the rest of
your life. Everything you do,
I will invest in you own an airplane
business. He owns 10% yes. Forever. Yes.
You have to kill him then. Yes.
Yeah, you have to kill that guy,
but I need the 10 grand. So I say,
I'll take it. So before I take it,
I go to this girl's father for advice,
this business mogul.
Then I'm living with her and I sit down,
I go to this guy's apartment again.
I'm 21 he's got in his apartment,
he's got a swimming pool,
artwork, like fancy fuck
women. He's macked out, man.
It's like I'd never seen
anything like this in Manhattan,
in Manhattan.
I'm just setting the stage
of the conversation and I
go in and I tell him the
story about the 10 the 10
grand and he says to me,
I would trade,
this is exactly what he said to me.
I will trade everything that I have for
you to get out of my daughter's life.
Exactly. Outweighed everything I
have for the one thing that you have.
And I'm like, man, I'm fucking broke.
What he taught me, I go, what's that?
And he said, youth, because he had
already gone through the journey,
even though he had everything,
he already had gone through the process.
He wasn't that 20 year old that you're
talking about that whatever he had gone
through it, he had it all. He
he will. He missed the process.
The journey of being you coming up at
20 and not know like you know here you
are. But it was the, those were
the years man. The first fight,
the first this like that.
That's what,
that's what makes you like so
and that stuck with me man.
At 21 years old. It stuck with
me and realize that like, man,
I got to enjoy the process and it's really
never rubbed off on me in front of me.
Oh, well why didn't that guy, how old was
this guy at the time? The old rich dude,
he was, let's see, he must've been in
his sixties. Why? They just do shit,
do a bunch of shoot day lounging around
his fucking swimming pool. Did he did,
he had an amazing, he was 20. He had an
amazing life. He had an amazing life.
So what did you wind up
doing? Uh, he said the SEC,
the second part of that
conversation, he said, do you, um,
will you make this work on your
own? I said, I think I can. He said,
I didn't ask if you can. He
said, I, I said, he said,
will you make it work?
I said, I will. He said,
and then go tell the guy to fuck off and
make it and it goes and go make it work.
And I did. So how'd you
get it funded that? Uh, I,
I somehow got,
I went to the Dallas Mavericks after the
Knicks and told them that I convinced
them to give me a $2,500 the next pay me,
this is the crazy part of my life,
but they gave me $2,500 to do the demo
and then they bought the song for like
$20,000 and that funded the rest of the
business that I ultimately sold to a
public company. Wow, that's crazy.
And you almost gave away
10% of your whole life.
That guy wanted 10% is a piece of shit.
What a mother fucker like.
That's a city like just business draws
prisoners and I had no one to go to.
I know he's taken advantage of a 21 year
old kid who's just got some dreams and
need some cash and 10 grand to him.
It's probably nothing.
I called my father and my father owned
the plumbing supply house in Mineola Long
Island and I during this time in my
thing and my father said, you know,
I love him to death, but he's like, you
know, do it. Do what you think is best.
Don't, he just didn't, you know,
I didn't know where to turn to.
I had no one to turn to. Yeah. Don't,
don't give up 10% of your life. Right.
That was just crazy that someone asks for
that. But you hear things like, I mean,
this is similar to what they
do in the music business,
like how the music
business treats artists.
They essentially sign you
to these contracts and then
take a piece of everything.
They take a piece of,
if you do a movie,
they take a piece of
your live performances,
your merchandise sales, everything.
They just say, look, we'll,
we'll help you out a little bit,
but you know, we want you, right?
Yeah. I mean, at least you
were in a contract though.
But there's some creepy contracts that
they used to do in the old days of
Hollywood that were similar to that.
Right? They just take a PCF forever. Yeah.
But you know, when I signed my music
deal, I didn't care. I was like,
you can take whatever you want,
man. Get me on MTV. Right?
Of course. Yeah. Because,
well, that's the whole idea. The word,
the reason why these exploitation
contracts work is because in the beginning
you're just so desperate and what
you have is what they don't have.
You have talent, right? You
have, as you're creative,
you're young and full of energy and
you've got something exciting that people
want to look at. And so what
they do is they go, oh, you,
what could we gotta fucking,
we got to wait through the door,
but we want 75% of the profits.
We want a little bit of this and,
and you don't get any money back until
we recoup our money that we spent on
executives and parking and car leases.
And they calculate all that shit.
How much the fucking building costs,
how much the electricity, all that stuff.
They that you've seen those I'm sure.
Oh yes. Contracts. They're fucking,
I've signed them. I've sat, you know,
in my own way. Yeah. But um, you know,
it's part of the process and no
leverage, no leverage. That's the thing.
They've got the leverage,
but now and now they don't have delivered,
but they still figured
out a way to pull it off.
It's really weird because who the fuck
is buying an albums now? No. Right?
No one.
Right yet these record companies are
still figuring out how coiling on do you
like a lamprey suck blood out.
There's still staying alive and they're
fat fingers driving their fat Mercedes
Benz.
They know how to do it.
They just figured out a way to grab
people that are just just getting poppin,
you know,
and just sign it and then figured out
a way to get in with these fucking
streaming companies. Have
you paid attention to that
shit? A little bit. Yeah.
That's the darkest.
It's even darker than the
music distribution because
the artists get like no
money point. Oh, oh,
Steven Tyler was talking about it with me.
It's just,
he was explaining it and there's a,
there's, it's the company's actually,
or the organization's actually called
M m. A what is it? Something, what did,
what did it stand for? Musicians for, uh,
some,
some sort of an act where they're trying
to stop the streaming companies from
ripping off these artists'
music modernization act. Yeah.
It's dark. Yeah. But it's
along the same lines.
It's like people figuring out a way
to just take something from somebody.