The joe rogan experience.
Cause some ideas just go away.
Like they're so profound,
there's so profound.
But then a couple of
hours later you're like,
what the fuck was I thinking that always
used to get me or I'd have this amazing
idea what I thought was an
amazing idea. And then I go, ah,
that's such a good idea. I'll remember
it in the morning and I go to sleep.
I know I still pull that shit. I've
never remembered it. No, no, never.
I still pull that. I go, what
are you doing if my phone,
if I didn't have my charger now I finally
got a cord and it's next to the bed.
So I always have a cord to plug in my
phone. But uh, never. Why do I not?
Not half the time. Never. And I
still have dinner. I'll go out. No,
cause that's a good idea.
Never Hedberg had a joke about that.
Too Lazy and too lazy to get up to
get a pen to write something down.
So I just convinced myself it wasn't
that funny in the first place.
But what's great is that that was a
bit he did on stage and it would kill,
I mean, I didn't do it. Well,
I don't remember the way
you got to just, you know,
the used to, we were thinking, okay,
I used to do drugs. I still do,
but I used to too. Yes. So
last night we were saying,
I used to do Mitch Hedberg.
I used to do drugs. I still do, but
I used to too. I mean, I still do,
but I used to do too. Okay. I know
I, let me back up for a second.
So I do Mitch Doing Rodney Dangerfield.
You know, I do Rodney, if he did, Mitch,
I'll be like, I'll tell her the other
day guys, I used to do drugs. I still do,
but I used to to, you know, do,
do any Mitch Hedberg joke is Rodney and
it's, and it's killed the other day.
It goes from, if I wanted a
banana, you know, I said, no,
I want a regular one later.
So, all right. You know? Right. You
know, what are you gonna do, man?
So I do the use too.
I hope this goes somewhere,
so I used I,
I did the Altoid.
I used to do drugs so my friend
asked me if I still do that. He I go,
I used to do the Mitch Hedberg. I still
do drugs but I used to too. I still do,
but I used to to do something in that.
It's amazing that you
kept it all together.
I did for somebody used to to use to
sense it makes sense, but you nailed it.
You dismounted.
I shouldn't try feet flat on the ground.
It's a solid this mountain.
There's no stumble. No, it
was good. That was very good.
Thank you. That's very good.
Thank you Mitch. He's like,
to me one of the more amazing comedians
ever because what he would do was a
complete nonsequitors. He would go from
one non sequitur to another non sequitur.
Nothing connected together other than
here. Here's some other shit I thought up.
You know, here's what the Shit I
wrote down and even know not through.
Probably a good idea for everyone
to know that does one liners,
that there still has to be
an essence of you and them.
Like even though he's jokes didn't segue
together like they seem you're still,
you knew who he was, but his jokes
obviously like, oh, he had, you know,
he definitely had, they're not just
individual jokes just glued all together.
They were all so silly too. Right,
exactly. That's the thing about,
I've said the best
way to describe him. He's like one of
my favorite silly comedians. I know.
It's funny, a lot of people you
don't hear always complimentary.
Of course it's silly. And that's
what I realized later after he died.
Like how silly. He was. Silly, so
silly. That was who he was. Very silly.
So that's what you know about him.
You know,
he was the type of comedian
he would get into his rhythm.
Like I would listen to him a lot of times
on the way to the airport because uh,
I was,
you know,
that traffic on the way to the airports
and knowing he just wanted to just chill
out, giggle. So I'd put on some Mitch
Hedberg I just be fucking giggling like,
and when you're just smiling when
you're not, when he's, you know,
in between punchlines and just have
a big smile on your face. Cause he,
he would put on this silly vibe and you
would get caught up in it cause it was
really fun. And then he had
such great writing too and
playful. It was, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
And
I think in Rodney had a lot of that
too. You know, Rodney's seriously,
seriously underrated
comedian and his style.
There was a great article
about it recently,
didn't we talk about this on the podcast?
That Rod,
there was an article that was
written recently about Rodney,
I forget who wrote it,
like Esquire or one of those things,
but they were talking about how long
it took him to become a good comedian.
That it wasn't until he was like in
his fifties that he figured it out.
And it's like talking about him boiling
down his act and talking about how many,
cutting all the fat out of his act.
If you go back and listen to his early
performances and you could see is more
meandering and then
towards the more standup B.
I realized that a few years ago and
he listened to the old ones and uh,
he would like, in other words that
Joe could be, it was still Rodney,
but it would be like, this is more
of a joke. A comedian would tell,
not really one line, it'd be
like, you know, like, you know,
you're getting old when your family
tells you, you know, when you,
when they're friendly
talks in front of you, hey,
you know what pops in the garage.
We've got people coming over, you know,
pop just sits there and drools you know,
but that was more like a piece
and I forgot about that, Rodney.
And then there's a lot of, you know, just
a short little stories, but they're not,
and then all of a sudden I saw him,
my member Bob Nelson. Yes.
God, Nelson Open for him.
And then I got to meet Rodney
backstage through Bob. And you know,
it is when you think, you know something,
it plays with everything. Sexism,
you think you know what it is,
but you really don't.
There's still a lot more to learn.
Of course,
I knew what timing was
before I saw Rodney.
I could tell you I was a comedian for
10 years at that point, but I know it.
Timing is, but then when you saw right
now when, oh fuck, that's timing.
It was like, I knew what it was, but I
just got a doctor in and what it was.
I just saw it delivered like the
best of the best of the best and it,
and I go now that I like, I, I
mean it was just crazy with the,
to every turn and every, and
then just, just when you think,
how can he take you anywhere? And then
the band kicks in and then he's sharks,
like, you know, doing bedding
music and all this the other day,
and my wife was shoot on and then
the pump, they got bigger and bigger.
Then he started singing this
song because everybody sang them.
But Rodney did it in his own way.
He starts going, you know, uh,
something about to dream that
whatever the song is. And then he,
he does about 10 seconds of it. And then
he goes, what the fuck am I singing?
Four, I'm watching them. I'm good. Oh
God to you that just a bed. But, uh,
he goes, I know that it's bad to you.
They're just a band. But to me
they're a bunch of fucking idiots.
And then the band has their taught,
cause they're all, you know,
Pete Musicians from that city, obviously
they're taught, you know, he goes, no,
don't tell you what they are. They're not.
And then they all stand up and they go,
we're fucking idiot.
I got to see Rodney when
I was 19, when I was, uh,
working as a security guard,
a great woods.
Great Woods is a concert place
in Mansfield, Massachusetts.
And Rodney was there in the bathrobe era.
Did you see bathrobe? Ron Rodney. Oh,
he went out on stage in a bathroom naked.
The bathrobe on the Improv,
you would show up. You see,
he was doing this arenas.
This place is big break.
Great Woods is like thousand people.
Isn't that great in a way that he was a
fucking maniac. He was a fucking maniac.
He was amazing.
He was so free.
He was hanging backstage and
apparently his caucus, enormous,
his cock and balls were just hanging out.
He didn't give a fuck.
He's just got this bathrobe on and he's
got his legs crossed and his fucking
sack is hanging down and the
security guards would be like,
what the fuck do, I didn't
see that. I only saw him,
it's like a big foot siding. And I met
him later in life. But to me like in 19,
I hadn't even thought about doing standup
yet, but it was such a huge fan of it.
He walked from, you know, like,
like you're looking down the hallway to
where his dressing rooms and he walked
from one room to another. It
was like, what big foot side?
And like I always saw him for a second,
but I saw Rodney,
it's like that. It's, you know,
I said seeing Rodney was like,
it's not like seeing, uh, the,
the, you saw Paul Mccartney.
Yeah, you'd freak out. But seeing,
Rodney was like getting to see
if you saw Fred Flintstone,
you can't see Fred Flintstone.
He's a cartoon. Rodney.
So larger than life that
it was overwhelming.
You weren't just going,
taking in someone that was a celebrity
and you see on TV and there he is.
There he is like three feet from you.
And you'd be like,
fuck, that's Rodney. What does
that between his legs? No,
shut up balls. It's kind of being covered
by something. Is that real? Yeah. Oh,
that's his balls. That's a sack or
his dick or both. He's an animal.
I would have bought, Nelson would
have great stories about like,
and they were so specific and you knew
Rodney said them and it was just so a
couple came up to him after their wedding
and they go, do you know this one?
No. And they go, uh, uh, [inaudible] he
was trying to gamble. You know, Rodney,
we just got married. What do
you think? And he goes, uh,
you both could have done better.
What do you think is done better?
Huh? That's a welded sky's insult.
I'm telling you.
That's a beautiful Joe goes.
People won't know that it was an Esl till
they get in their car. Wait a second.
That means he says, we're poet. What?
We're both ugly. It's get cancel now.
That's playing ping pong in their head.
Don't talk to you both good and said,
is that an insult to the wife?
Goes, it's an insult to you.
I think it's both of us.
You Moron.
Okay.