What do you think you're
going to do when you retire?
I don't know yet. You don't think about
at all? I do think about it. Um, the,
the main thing is make sure that before
I'm retired and my kids are set for life,
went through universities or at
their houses, all that stuff.
That's number one goal. Then
when I retire, I don't know,
I got a lot of options I could do,
you know,
I'm going to see which one
I'm going to like the most,
cause whatever I'm going to do. Obviously
nothing I love as much as fighting.
Nothing will make me wake up at six
in the morning to go fucking run.
No nothing I'll have that love me.
When you asked about the longevity's
just cause I love it so much,
I don't have to work for it. I
just, I love it. I love what I do.
Even hitting the bag for 35,
40 minutes sometimes it's so
fucking boring and monotonous.
If I've got the right music going on, I
mean a little bit of water. Let's do it.
You know, I'm gonna have fun
doing it. You know? So, uh,
I got to just find something that my
heart is solely in and I'm having fun.
I still haven't figured out what that
is. You know, maybe skiing, you know,
every time I go skiing, the skews are
trying to recruit me. They're like, Oh,
who is this guy?
We need this guy over here and our team
to maybe scheme and that she gets my
blood pumping. You know? Really. You
like skiing? I love it man. I hate it.
I love that she was worried about
falling to, that's your problem.
That is my problem.
Fucking snowmen and is going to happen.
You've been kicked in the head.
You've been [inaudible] forever.
Had their fucking ACL torn apart.
I've already had two knee reconstructions.
So when I go down the hill, I'm
like, don't get hurt. Don't get hurt,
don't get hurt. Didn't get hurt. That's,
that's so crazy how I'm bringing thing,
cause I'm thinking there's no way I
can get hurt when I'm on those things.
I'm just fucking going as fast as I
can. Oh, you're one of those guys. Yeah.
There's no way I could get
hurt. It's fucking snow. You
could definitely get hurt.
Yeah,
definitely.
I've had fucking now while I was
standing still like pass my fridge.
Hey,
slow down to to say what's up and just
like some seven year old man Dean and see
that I'm starting up moving here and just
fucking loud plow mean to the kneecaps.
Good thing. There's somewhat
flexible, nothing torn, nothing.
It was like a good hit. Do you know, like
a good little low kick outta nowhere.
You know, I worry about that
with my kids some clodhopper oh,
but if they start young though to
forget about. Oh yeah, no, they're good.
They're already doing black diamonds.
Oh, fuckers. Yeah. Yeah. But they, they,
they're so low to the ground.
They're tiny.
The little skis and shit had no fear
that age easier once they are already
funding in once or twice.
Like, Oh dad, it's just snow.
I watch some of those fucking men going
down those hills though. Oh, just shush.
Shush. When they like, when they drop
them off in the helicopter. Oh my God. Oh,
that's ridiculous. I watched a
video the other night of, uh,
a guy went down this mountain that
no one's ever skied down before.
They dropped him off at the top and he
had to climb the first couple of feet
down with the skis on before he
got to this open shoot. I was like,
what in the fuck are you doing? He's
climbing. Like you can't just ski.
There's rocks everywhere and shit. That's
great. Fuck you. I blows my mind. Yeah,
go get better. Hobby is ridiculous.
Sliding down a mountain.
I might end up in there one day.
Nothing in no time soon.
Cause those guys are a lifetime of
skill. But I wouldn't, I wouldn't, uh,
take it off.
You know,
like I'd love to ski one of those crazy
mountains that are just fucking super
duper steep and just rebut.
You know,
one thing about skiing is you
could do it when you're old. Yeah.
Cause this lady who was
teaching my daughter,
she was giving my daughter
lessons at the ski play.
She was like deep into her sixties
and she's skiing great. Wasn't it?
Got Technique technique. You know,
they probably grew up in the snow.
I started skiing when I was like 30,
you know,
so I got a lot of catching up
to do. Yeah. Yeah. It's uh,
I just know to my Ari,
my friend Ari,
he broke his wrist last year and
he broke his ankle two years ago.
He's always fucking himself up. He's that
guy. Balls to the wall. I don't know.
He probably has done mushrooms. The
that's a good time to ski, man. Fucking,
that's the best sentence. I know a couple
people that have done it on mushrooms.
They say ski. Really?
Yeah. You like it. Oh,
what's the best thing about
skiing on mushrooms? Well,
it could go both ways because it fucks
up your depth perception. You know,
they don't know where the trees are.
So the first time I did it,
I was like super grandma. You know, like
everybody's like, what's wrong with him?
Like, no, no, no, no.
Just leave me the fuck alone because
the snow is all the same too. Right.
So now it just fucks.
Are you depth perception so bad?
You could see the divots
in the snow books.
Everything gets pixelated, right? Yeah.
And you are really tripping hard then.
Oh man,
everything is like the same and I can't
really see the bumps and then I don't
see the bumps. I just feed him and
not whoa, Whoa, whoa. All right,
I'm going to need a tough this
one out and let's do it. You know?
And then the next time
I did at the letter,
literally less of a dosage had a
blast, you know? Yeah. They say it's a,
it's a micro dose thing. Yes. Just
like don't take like three grams,
take like a half a gram. Yeah. Something
like that. But the first time I was,
I was doing the Bro Science
and it was like, oh yeah.
I think it's like for grabs is cool man,
let's go on a fat and
I'm like a slight fast,
you know the problem with it that
the vision thing when things,
when you do the mushrooms and things
get pixelated where you see like almost
like a matrix around you.
Yeah.
I would imagine that that
would fuck you up skiing.
You wouldn't be able to see all
the creases in the snow and shit.
And then you just feel it.
All of a sudden you're like,
what the fuck have you ever snowboard?
I did it for like half a day.
That was pretty cool. But I, uh, I used to
ski like inline, like in a park, you know,
like on ramps, on half
pipes. Rollerblade yeah.
So I could like jump on
rails and halfpipes and uh,
I could even do like a front flip on my
skates. But this one, I was like 13, 14.
Yeah. So skiing came very easy to
meet and snowboarding that so much.
Cause I didn't skateboard when I
was a kid. I skateboarded as a kid,
but I've never snowboarded but uh,
the people that do it,
they say it's easier to get better at
snowboarding than it is to get better at
skiing. I said it's like, it's hard
in the beginning, but once you get it,
it's easier to get better at. Oh,
okay. But when you fall a lot,
a latitudes fall, this, the
snowboard goes up in the air,
you're feet are stuck on it and
land right in your fucking head.
A lot of people get knocked the fuck
out because you can't move your legs
individually like you can if your skin
and you land on the tailbone a lot to a
lot of people tell me. Yeah, and if
you're skiing and you land funky,
the ski snapped loose and you
can move your legs around.
Board is shoved in there. Yeah,
he's trapped in the snowboard.
Is this shit too that people go to the
trees like fucking silver surfer. Ah,
that's fun man. Yeah, but that's not rush.
This low and down part
with those seems different,
like less options to slow down.
I love all that shit.
Anything he gets my heart pumping,
do a skydive or anything crazy like that.
I haven't done the sky diving
because I'm afraid of the law.
I've heard bad stories about the landing,
how you are with the scheme that you
got a couple buddies. He got hurt.
I got a couple of buddies that got in her
on the landing of skydiving. I'm like,
I can't do that. I'm fighting. So
she loved them fighting. Whew. Yeah.