Four three, two, one. Kelly Slater,
we've been talking about
doing this for how long?
Couple of years while makes for having me.
Thanks for being here.
I'm glad we finally got a chance to do it.
What are you in California for?
I know you broke your foot, right? I broke
my foot real bad. I had to do that. My,
well my girlfriend's phone, San Clemente
and her family lives there and uh,
so we kind of live here when
we're not moving around too much.
So I'm just going to here right now.
I'm not competing. I broke my foot.
I was surfing in South Africa about,
um,
15 months ago and I was just on a wave
that I wouldn't consider a very big wave.
Nobody would really consider dangerous
and it all kind of closed out, which is,
you know,
when it all breaks at once,
I just pulled into thing cause I was going
to sort of wash in on the rocks right
where that was and change boards and uh,
I was practicing,
I had to compete in about
two hours from then.
So I was just testing
out different boards.
For some reason I wasn't riding the board.
I was planning on riding competition.
So I was going to come in and change
and switch to my norm board and I just
pulling this wave and just,
I kind of hesitated like usually you
either ride those out and stay on your
board or you jump off.
And I was kind of a between the two and
I kind of lifted my front foot off my
back foot. My leg was straight
cause I was kind of going to,
I would think I was going to jump off
and as my foot got my leg got locked back
straight.
The board flipped in oh against the toes
and it just broke the top of my foot
and a half. Oh like immediate
like there was my God, yeah.
We're looking at a photograph of the
extra right now and it's like every bone
it's snapped. Well what you
can't see. So the, do you know,
are you aware of the Lis franc joint?
Which is like,
that's where the first big
metatarsal comes together.
So that first big joint
on top of the foot there.
Why is it called the Liz Frank joint list?
Frank was a doctor I think is what I am.
I could,
we could look this up. I think that was
the person that did the original surgery.
When you used to break your foot in
a stirrup back a hundred years ago,
they said cut your foot off.
Oh God damn ass.
So that was what, what it, uh,
that was kind of how this
sort of joint got famous.
But normally what happens is those toes,
those two bones right there,
the first and second metatarsal can
either spread or converge one way or the
other. And that's usually
what a Liz frank fracture is.
I had the best of the three,
which is, I had a crack.
You can just see on the right side of,
yeah,
if you go down with a cursor right there,
just a little lower,
there's a little crack right there,
uh, right there on that corner.
And then the next one broke across.
You can just see right there,
it's cracked across. And so it kind of
went in to line up and across the foot.
And then the other two are just a straw.
Yeah.
The third one displaced the fourth
one shattered into about eight pieces.
The doctor said he lost count and putting
them back together. And then you know,
you, you would know from injuries. The
problem with when the shatters of bone,
they're not getting the blood flow.
So it's not like a four
or five week repair job.
It's like that was like nine months before
that thing was back together properly.
So when they do that, how do they piece
that shattered one back together again,
a delicately and they
put like a mesh over.
So I've got to kind of like
figure out how to, well I had,
I had a plate on the list,
frank and then it had a plane play,
a kind of a bridge across
the third and fourth.
And so they kind of meshed it
all together. And then, uh,
I think I had 16 screws
combined in all that.
God Damn it, it was, it was brutal.
The problem with it was I did it in
South Africa where I wasn't going to get
surgery.
Um,
so I had to wait for the swelling to go
down for about six days before I could
fly.
Oh God.
Cause they thought the was going to swell
too much cause it was already swollen
from the event. So I used to shit
on my foot for like, you know,
five days and sat there and watched.
Unfortunately the waves were perfect,
so I was sitting on the beach is watching
perfect waves, you know, it's like,
that's like as painful as the
injury to a surfer, you know,
it's like watching a bunch of elk walked
by in front of you and not scary to you.
Right, right. And uh, um, so I,
I sat there because the whole time prior
to me being injured while was there for
like two weeks,
the ways weren't very good.
So I broke my foot in the way he's
got great. Oh. So I did watch it,
so that's painful for us. But, uh,
so then wait for the swelling
to go down and then I,
it's too red eyes to get back there.
No way you could get it fixed in
South Africa. I maybe could have,
but then I was probably looking at staying
in Africa for a month or more. And,
and also I didn't know that the quality
sort of level of quality of doctor I was
going to get there.
And I,
I got a doctor I work with here and I
called him straight away. I said, look,
it's my fourth broken foot,
but I've never broken it like this.
Usually it's like let it heal for four
weeks and you're surfing and it's all
from surfing. Yeah. And in
the same way I'll really,
really pretty much the board going
back against the foot fuck. Um,
cause and usually it happens when I'm,
you know,
I don't know how well
versed you are in surfing,
but when I'm tube riding and
usually with my back to the wave,
which has happened two or three times,
so I'm in the wave,
the lip pitches over and lands.
But when that lands,
it sends a shock back into the way,
like,
you know when the lip
hits flatwater that lip,
some of the energy goes down and some
disperses out and up and some comes back
into the tube. So if does that
and you're in the wrong spot,
the board will flip into your feet. But
oh wow. Normally what we do is we're,
we're,
when your backside barrel ride,
a lot of times you're grabbing the rail
so you kind of have both your feet and
your hand on it so you
can handle that shock.
But if you're just going no hand backside,
it's usually a pretty big intense barrel.
And so that lip has a lot of energy and
it shoots a ton of force back towards
you. And if, if the hit
your board just wrong,
it can flip in your foot and break it.
Do you know anybody else who's broken
their foot? Like you, like that?
Not this bad. Um, one guy
on tour broke his foot.
Pretty bad knee requiring surgery this
year, that looking at, I'm horrible man.
How long was it before you can walk?
You're walking. Totally normal now.
How long has it been since
the surgery? Yeah, so,
so I had surgery in end of July
last year and then walking normal.
It wasn't til maybe December, January.
Wow. Well December I competed again,
but I probably shouldn't have.
But we were, we were at
pipeline in Hawaii, which is,
you're not doing maneuvers.
It's not a small wave kind of comp.
If the waves are small,
I wouldn't have served.
Since it's bigger,
it's a little easier cause you take
off and kind of trim a straight line.
So you're kind of going
straight, you know, even though
you're riding the barrel,
you're kind of going straight.
But are you conscious of your foot being
compromised? Yeah. Wow. I don't know.
I just, that's my favorite event in the
world, so I just didn't want to miss it.
But fuck if you broke your foot
again. Yeah. But then, you know,
the bones were pretty
good back together then.
And I could walk somewhat without pain.
And if I put myself in a real vulnerable,
vulnerable,
vulnerable position on a wave, I would
kind of maybe jump off. You know,
I wouldn't really push it. It's not
worth winning a contest foot again,
but I'm sure to be able to surf pipeline
with no one else is kind of worth the
little risk now.