I want you to just to fucking hold nothing
back. And then I went up after him.
You know how I did fine,
didn't do good then do did fine
because I knew how to handle myself,
my professionalism,
the craft of what I know one out.
But there's no following that with
what I do, which is totally different.
And having the audience go, oh this
takes it to a whole new place. No.
Did you ever listen to the
day the laughter died? Rick
Ruben with them? Yeah. Yeah,
yeah. Fucking phenomenal.
Great album. Just eating shit.
Right until hours. He showed up at
danger fields for people who don't know.
It's literally, I will never forget, I was
just starting out. I think he did this.
Look this up when that was,
I want to say it was like 1989 1990 no,
it was after that.
It was fairly early.
It was fairly early because I
was very young in my career.
It might've been then cause I was
still living in Boston. No, no.
It might've been then because 89 yeah,
because I was thinking about
me living here now. But it was,
it had came out the first
time I lived here. Well,
I was living in Boston and I was just
starting out and there was a great
comedian named Mike Donovan,
who to this day is one of the funniest
guys I've ever seen in my life. And uh,
Mike Donovan was laughing to the point
where he couldn't breathe at dice doing
this set while he was doing
fucking stadiums. I mean,
dice was doing enormous Nassau Coliseum.
What's in the bowl,
bitch? Oh, 20,000 people.
He was the biggest comedian of all time
and he just decides to show up at danger
fields in New York city randomly on
like a Monday and a Tuesday night.
It doesn't tell anybody he's
going to be there. I mean,
there's 1320 people in the crowd.
He records two different
sets and he has no material.
I mean fucking none.
He's making things up as he goes along
and people are getting angry at him and
they're walking out and he did a bit
about Richard Nixon about how he eats ass
and when he eats ass he does it
like Richard Nixon. He was like, Oh,
I love this fucking house.
He was doing this Richard Nixon impression
of eating ass and for whatever reason,
Mike Donovan thought it was the funniest
thing he'd ever seen in his life.
He was wheezing, like couldn't breathe,
talking about dice doing this impression.
And I was like, wow, this is
like comedy for Comedians.
But for the people that were in the
audience, like a guy got up, he goes,
you're about as funny
as our glass of milk.
The Guy said that to him and then left
and that's one of the best things on the
album. These people from like
Kansas getting your about.
It's funny as our clause on milk and
walking off and dice shitting on them,
but the two to have them
mindset to be at the,
not just the top of his game,
but literally the top of standup ever.
No one before him had ever sold out
Madison Square Garden multiple nights in a
row the way he did.
I mean you guys have done it since then.
You know Dane and Louis and this
been a bunch of guys who've Aziz,
but no one did it like he did. Then.
He was the first ever to do that.
And to do that and then to record these
fucking awful sets and then put it out.
We're gonna fucking pull.
I guarantee that was Rick Rubin's
idea. Do you think so? Without a doubt.
But you know, does dices like
Dyson? I know Rick Rubin.
I bet it was both of their ideas.
Well maybe you didn't fight Rick Ruben.
I'll have to ask for a group of
next time I see him. Yeah, asked,
never asked him that. But that sounds to
me like Rick Rubin going, let's do this.
Interesting. Yeah, but it
was such a crazy bold move.
I remember thinking at the time because
I was terrible in 1989 when it came out
and I was just like confused.
Like how does one do that?
One is so confident they
released something that sucks.
Cause I had as I was when I was
19 it's me and my girlfriend,
Mark De mi and Marta were sitting in
my car and I had a cassette player and
we're listening to dice. It was just
called dice and crying, laughing,
crying, laughing. It was before I'd ever
done stand up. And I remember thinking,
Wow, this guy is fucking something.
Like what? What? Like the, the,
the amount of power that he had like
onstage and these roars from the crowd and
we're sitting in my car laughing
our asses off to this seat.
This cassette wasn't even CD that couple
of years later he decided I'm just
going to put out something that's sucks.
The day of the comedy died.
Did they? Laughter died. Yeah.
And he's got like one of them fucking
paper Boi hats on the cover. Oh,
it's a old man. Black point. And there's
the little picture of him on there.
Is that what it is? I can,
yeah. Small picture I think.
Or maybe it's a big picture of him there.
It doesn't really remember.
Oh that was a big picture.
We should get up. Oh yeah.
So it is small in comparison
to the actual CD. Yeah.
See if we can get Jamie,
let's get a framed copy of that
and put it on the wall somewhere.
Was it released as an album
like, I dunno, guarantee image.
I guarantee there's vinyl
guarantee. Yeah, let's get find it.
See if we could buy it.
And Vinyl.
Look on the very right now for
the day that they did it again,
get it three years later.
I've seen him do that at the store.
I seen them go up late night at the store.
I'm like, look, good.
You look at you over there and just
start talking shit to people like me.
What does he wear?
Weightlifting gloves whenever
he's like touching people's hands.
Is that what it is? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And Big Jay Oakerson whereas weightlifting
gloves in Omaj to guys. Yeah,
no, that's great. Yeah. I was trying to
get the two of them together in a podcast,
but scheduling wise, it never
really worked to shaking the dice.
Doctor's hand photo on the final,
Oh for 400 bucks on Amazon.
Oh, by that shit. No, no, no. We're gonna
frame hundred bucks. I'll go to dice.
He might not have it. Yeah, I guarantee
he's got it. Yeah. You pay for lunch.
I'll give you the, the, uh, the album.
Have you ever seen his Instagram?
If we go to dices Instagram? No,
it's hilarious. It's just so random.
It's like an older rich,
famous guy who does whatever the
fuck he wants. Opposed to IV,
had coffee or lunch with
them a million times.
I had never had one of those
things. Never happen. Yeah. Yeah.
He um, he used to, I miss him like with,
with a gold's gym tee shirt on with
crazy sunglasses and he'll do like these
little sketches, but they're so random and
weird. Like him talking to a girl, look,
maybe we should do something later in the
girl's like, okay, like click on this,
play this, this is like
his, this is his whole thing
like skateboarding.
I was thinking about it.
Maybe we should do that.
Can you cook dinner for her? Here's
the question. What are you? Stay on
the phone. What's your name? Nicole.
Nicole. All right. I'll call, I'll
call you. I've got to go take this.
Oh, it's the end of it. Afterwards
he goes and he's got another one,
a follow up when he gets mad at himself
for not doing anything about it.
Like go to the next video
that's sided.
There's another there. Play this
one. What a beautiful night. Huh?
Beautiful.
That's it.
It's out in the Lord.
It's just this little beautiful
Eleanor Kerrigan. Yeah,
they're so random. The videos,
I guess the text in that video was like,
I should've done something.
What's wrong with me? Yeah, but this
is him. Why did I leave? I'm so dumb,
but they're so random. It's like,
what is he doing? He's just been dice.
He used to do that at the store.
He used to have comics do
these little sketches is, okay,
you're going to run through the door
there and you're going to knock him over
and you're going to go,
what the fuck? Okay,
go and the guy would do it and you run
into the door and knock the the guy over
and go, what the fuck? Go. Perfect.
Do it again. And he would just,
he would just film this with
like VHS tape, you know,
like an old school one and then
he would edit it together himself.
But he did nothing with it.
And this was like dice was giant,
just fucking top of the world.
China.
And this is what he's doing to
amuse himself and love comics.
The comics would just do it. Oh
Jesus Christ. You're just so happy.
Dice is talking to you. He's the
reason why I started doing the road.
I would just do the store all the time.
It was constant.
The store one time were in the bag goes,
oh you're funny.
You know you should do the row.
I go, yeah. He goes, Eh, it was,
you don't want to rely on these
fucking assholes for money. He goes,
you could fucking do whatever you want.
Go through the road. I was like, yeah,
why don't I do the road? Cause I was
just doing TV shows and then you know,
do you, you're doing TV shows,
you kind of trapped in this,
this is how you make your living.
You got to kind of always be acting and
always be going on auditions. I was like,
yeah, I was cause I wasn't making, you
don't make real money at the store.
You make like 15 bucks a set or whatever.
We make, you know, I, I've spent.