The joe rogan experience that you think,
why am I asking you this?
But I think you might have an answer.
So, but I'm being totally honest,
I am exhausted from dealing with like I,
it's,
it's not like it's a big deal,
but it's like the first time you,
whether you can admit major
things in your life, like, oh,
I have a drinking problem,
but to be stupid little
things. Yeah, mine is eating.
Like I'm exhausted from doing it the
wrong way and everything comes back to me
for self control. So when people want
to tell me about a diet, I don't,
it's not portions. I know a portions
are, I just want to eat more.
So it's all down to how do I fucking
get self control? I have zero.
I mean if I'm not going to
call it zero self control,
then I don't know what the hell I'm
going to call it. But as you now you're,
you're not, you're hard on yourself.
I think you have self control.
Todd think you're a wonderful
man, but you're, you're hilarious.
And one of the reasons why
you're hilarious is because
you're so, you're free,
you're impulsive and that sort of debt,
it's very difficult for that to lend
itself to dietary discipline. It's like,
how can I eat it? Fuck it. Hey, that's
a fucking eat it. Right. That's you.
But it's also part of what makes
you such a hilarious comic.
It's like you have these impulses.
It makes me feel better.
You don't want to split the difference,
at least with what you're saying,
discomfort and you want to have fun and
it's like it's right there that want he,
I want to eat that food. Fuck it. The
thought of me like picture me at the,
at the uh,
shoving cheesecake,
him in my mouth and my friends are
like looking at me like Todd and I go,
Joe Rogan said that because I'm creative.
Good.
I should eat whatever I want. He said
it and you can go listen to his podcast.
He said that I should eat. He goes, Joe
Rogan and you can go listen. He said,
clear up the minibar before you
get in your hotel beds. Even,
even if you're not really
hungry, does some creative, okay,
so I don't have control over this.
There's also a problem.
There's another problem with discipline.
This is a pro and disciplining that
hit me already. Yeah, for sure. No,
that's probably just the we'd hit yet.
It takes a little while
for the spray again. Yeah,
usually a few more minutes than that.
Um,
I forgot my point about, um,
the self control. Oh, that when you
really disciplined people and comedy,
they don't go well
together that much either.
Because if you're too
driven and too disciplining,
that's almost always Dickey.
You know what I mean?
I'm saying like you'd be
able to disciplined, too
rigid, too determined and,
and, and, and to like too
enthusiastic about success.
You get Dickie, let me ask
you this and I'm not, I don't,
this thought could be wrong.
Like I'm okay with thinking
something and then maybe finding out.
But whenever it comedian, and I bet
there's funny ones out there. Definitely.
Cause over the years I remember my,
can't think of which ones,
but they definitely exist.
They are funny, they are funny,
but they've never smoked. Drank, oh,
can you be a good comedian if
you haven't done those things,
I think you'd be a good
comedian. If you're a man,
you could be a good comedian.
If you're a woman, you could
be a good comedian. If you're
gay or trans, you just,
you are a good comedian. If you're a good
comedian. Is that, why do I ask that?
Because I'm,
I should be embarrassed to ask that too,
is a lot of people that are really good
that don't do shit and never, yeah,
they don't, they don't
have a desire to, you know,
it's just everybody's
brain works different.
And some people like the idea of losing
control with a substance is not not fun.
Right.
They don't like that feeling and it's,
but they can keep their shit together,
you know?
I know a lot of people that don't drink,
they don't do anything,
but they keep their shit together
and maybe that's better for them.
They feel like it is. I
don't know. I, you know, I,
as I asked that you gave me the answer
that you know to go, you're right.
You're right. Yeah. But like I s it means
that I had a question about that and I,
and that I think I've talked about
this in the past and once I was like,
somebody was saying, well, they may be,
what if you're not experimenting? But no,
there's a billion ways to,
uh,
to do those things that you use pot to
do without the pod. Obvious. I think I,
you edit that out. I use
yoga for that too, man.
I love going to a hot yoga class
fucking hard. And it's like a drug,
like you get a lot of
thinking done in there, man,
when you're just holding these poses
and there's no, no music, no nothing,
just everybody in the class.
Breathing is a 90 minute class.
There's some sort of
psychedelic effect there.
Okay.