Yeah.
I think it's like that with the anything
where you're moving your body is a unit
martial arts stuff or anything you better
as you, as you get older in particular,
you'd better be really aware of all
the moving parts. When you're a kid,
you could just fucking hit the gas.
When you hit 50 you better be,
you know you're swinging a tennis
racket or something like that.
You better be aware of your
shoulders and your knees.
He got where have all these moving parts.
How old are you?
51 51 well,
why wait for 62 I'm not waiting.
What's up? Here's Tiger Tiger's
back injury or back surgeries.
Oh No. He had another one. I, this
isn't like yesterday or anything,
but it's from a year or two.
Why is announced that he had undergone
anterior Lumbar interbody fusion?
Oh, that's fusing his Dick's. Many
thought. Many thought his disc, excuse me.
Hello Roy in jail.
Many thought that is competitive golf
career was over and his fourth surgery
since March of 2014 which
involved removing the l five
s one intervertebral disc
fusion material to connect the
l five and s one vertebral.
What?
Oh my God.
All those apparently recovered
quite well from the operation.
That surgery is quite rare
amongst professional golfers.
One of the PGA player
deadly heart had also had,
had a fusion in the same location
as woods fucking fusions. Rough man,
that means there's no disk
left. Right. And he won the uh,
uh, uh, the whatever
they call the Fedex Cup,
the last tournament of the
year, last year, tiger wanted.
And so he came back from that and
that's incredible. Oh, it is amazing.
And I was there, uh, is it
East Lake and Atlanta and uh,
and I do all their, uh, all
their charity stuff. Yeah.
That's the footage of him going up the
18th green. He's about to win this thing.
And this is the,
the top 30 golfers in the,
on the PGA tour, which is the toughest
tour. There is all these people, Jazz.
And now it's a major in sport that
everybody gets some run on the field and
follow him. Right. Walk right
next to them. There's no
crowd control there. Have No,
I was right up there that was right
up there above this green. Uh,
cause I, I walked with him cause I
get to go inside the ropes so, and uh,
and I followed it. A couple
of choked. It didn't matter.
This is the one who needs right
here, the Shortland. Yup. Yeah.
They get a two shot lead
going into that and that's it.
And they won and he won the whole thing.
Yeah. And that was the comeback. You know,
that was the comeback that people said
would never happen that you would never,
not, especially at this level. That's a
hard tournament to win. I mean that's uh,
that's tough. Tufts up
tiger's back tiger's back.
I love it. The require a lot
from people. You know, if,
if they get some strange along
the way that guys, he's, he,
he got it rough after his whole
divorce and the sex scandal. Me,
he had it rough for long time.
People were coming after him.
But the thing is about those
back surgeries is a wonder
why they did the fusion.
Cause I think they do
articulate and discs now.
It seemed to be very effective
at I, you know, I think he tried,
we have to get yet,
well he had four so
cause people are uh, I know a few
people that are doing those. Um,
they've got those discs down.
They put like a titanium movable disk
basically takes the place of the disk
that's in your back. Eddie Bravo
had that done. What is it that,
you know, I play all these um, okay.
Pro Ams increasing golfers performance
via via and anterial approach is that it
spares the large muscles of the back
that are critical to golf swing,
which potentially makes the recovery
for athletes athletes a bit easier. Huh.
I would imagine whoever was looking at
Tiger's back was about the best person in
the world to be looking at it.
So I'm sure they would have,
he had a pretty big budget for
it. Yeah. I mean you would want,
I mean they must've like really calculated
it. That was the best move was maybe,
um, if they put an artificial disc, you
would, he would move funny. I'm good.
I don't know, man. That whole
the back things were rough. One,
you ever had any back problems?
I don't have a lot of any kind of problems
except that little alcohol thing that
I got going that little squeaker and uh,
and,
but I play golf with guys in these pro
am's and most of them are, you know,
football,
basketball players,
and most of them are around my age and
most of them are in pain. You know,
it what? It turns out, smoking pot,
watching cartoons. Good for your knees.