The joe rogan experience or who knows,
they might be pro Trump.
Trump just sold off the loss of
national parks grand staircase,
open it up for oil and gas drilling.
They probably liked that shit, man. Yeah.
That's an interesting thing.
Like I've heard very different versions
of that from z Zinky when that guys,
what does he, secretary of the
interior. What does Zinky yeah,
when he was talking about it,
he's explained to us not what happened
and that essentially went right back to
where the way it was
before Obama changed the,
the legislation changed the rules.
I don't understand.
It was protected under Obama for a
good reason. There's dinosaur fossils,
they're native Americans
have monuments there,
but of course we don't care
about native American monuments.
We just care about confederate monuments.
We don't care about abolishing all the
native American land and all the treaties.
We just care about protecting bizarre
confederate statues around the country.
I don't think we should
protect confederate statues
and in the sense that I
don't think they should be in like the
middle of fucking times help squares and
shit like that.
But they should do something with them
the same way they should do something
with Gingiss con statues,
Thrombus Museum.
Do you know that most of those
things were made during the um,
the Jim Crow era? That's a
relational Swain constructed.
That's an amazing point.
A lot of people think that it was right
after the civil war and in fact it was
like in the 60s it was during
the civil rights movement.
There was a protest to the civil rights
move. A little Donald doing here. Yeah.
Well here, here's a statue and they're
shitty statues to a lot of them.
Like really poorly constructed
there. Made him quickly. Yeah,
it was a protest to the civil rights
movement. A lot of them. That's crazy.
But the thing is like they are
a representation of history.
Just like a Gig is con statute would be
a representation of that monster. I mean,
we think of Gingiss ECON is
a guy who opened up trade
with China today. You know,
you vaguely understand that he was
responsible for the death of 10% of the
population of the world back then.
Change The fucking New York Times had an
article about how he changed the carbon
footprint of the earth.
They,
there's literally a difference in the
carbon footprint because 10% less people
were alive during Gingiss Khan's
reign because they killed everybody.
They fucking quit killing
millions of people.
There's a great Dan Carlin series
on it called the wrath of the cons,
but I've talked about it way too much.
But today,
youngest comes not offensive like you
could bring up getting those comp.
Nobody cares.
Me waiting more horrific than anything
that happened during the civil war.
They had slaves and they,
they did everything they used.
They would capture people and use them
as the front line and they'd push them
towards their own people.
So they would get shot.
They will be the first people
to get shot with arrows.
And I mean there's some horrific shit,
but I think,
I think we should melt
kingus Khan statues.
I think the confederacy is just
so much more recent and yeah.
Was mines do something with it though?
I mean I don't think it should
be in town square for sure.
In anybody's Townsquared.
Yeah,
but I think they should do something
with them instead of melting them are
smashing them.
They should put them somewhere at least
for the future lease for future people
to like look back.
Like look,
this is how fucking wacky people were in
the 1960s they construct these Omadjela
has to the 18 hundreds
and slavery was legal.
They constructed these statues to sort
of paint these people in this heroic
fashion that we're fighting
to keep black people slaves.
That's part of the thing.
There was,
this is all right there as part
of the history of this country.
We've got to put it somewhere. I mean,
I'm not saying it should be worshiped.
Definitely shouldn't be
prominently featured. So yeah,
there should be something like
that. Right, right. Yeah. And,
but it should be like detailed description
of when it was constructed and why
was he instructs exactly who made it,
what was the political affiliation of the
people that created it? Totally. Yeah,
totally. It stopped this
whitewash and bullshit like that.
Every time MLK day comes around,
I'm always just like,
did you know MLK was like a rabid
anti militarist and anti imperialist?
No, because they, he was the most hated
black man in America. Someone said,
do you know that he used to
fuck all these white women,
like who does only fucking white women?
It gives us a lot of fun.
He did this person.
We had a good time.
That's going to be the bad thing. Oh,
well you just turned it around for me.
I'm okay that I have a dream speech.
It's so strange.
But people how they turn on things.
Yeah.