Go active drug.
So there's a lot still to be discovered.
Now Canada has just recently
legalized marijuana as of today.
Yes. Yeah. Um,
did they have any plans or do you know
of considering the legality of other
substances? As a matter
of fact, they do. Um, uh,
there is there, I can't really
talk about it that actually I,
I shouldn't talk about it cause I
don't have that much information.
But there is a gentleman who
came to one of my retreats.
I meet the most interesting people at
these retreats. You wouldn't believe it.
This guy is, uh, uh, of
aspiring young politician,
Canadian politician from Ottawa.
He's talking to Justin about legalizing
psychedelics for therapeutic uses and
he's, you know, working with some,
some lawyers and so on and
putting together a proposal
to do this MTMA assisted
psychotherapy trials to begin final
phase in Vancouver. Well, letter you go.
But that's maps, right? That's
the catalyst behind that.
He wants to change policy.
And the thing is the Canadians
are reasonable people.
That's the big difference from
America. It was, you know,
you can propose this kind
of thing and they'll,
they won't dismiss it out of hand,
lol, you know, what's your evidence?
Why should we do this? So Justin's a
very young guy. I mean, he's young, 40.
I imagine he's been beyond the
chrysanthemum a timer to I do.
Really? Sure. I think so.
Wow. What makes you say that?
Because he's spoken about it. Hi.
I'm sure he wouldn't speak about,
I guess just to guess he's the right age.
Um, he, well,
I can't say it's just pure speculation.
LE, let's put it this way. I,
I wouldn't be surprised for people who
don't know what we're talking about.
Beyond the Cassandra means there's
this thing that you see when you break
through,
when you do DMT,
that's very bizarre geometric pattern
that resembles a chrysanthemum. Right,
right. You know, the, the
Canadians, I mean, for instance,
to get approval for these Mtma trolls was
a lot more straight forward in Canada,
you know, and, uh, now, and,
and they've done some clinical
studies with Iowasca and they're,
they're on board with that.
Uh, they've done some,
some studies with the indigenous people
in Canada. They call it first nations,
but they have, they have done
that and it's been pretty, uh,
it's been straight forward
to get that work done.
That would be really the drug
hysteria that we have, you know?
So I think it's a good place to
produce, pursue this research. Well,
in many ways.