I,
I'm a fan of the best fighters in the
world getting together and whatever we
have to do to facilitate that,
that's what I want to see happen.
You know what I mean? I, you know,
I just think that there's gotta be a way
to make this happen. There's got to be,
what are you talking about here?
Yo Mother fucker. Hey Man. I mean,
I'm just, I'm, I'm going,
going day by day, you know,
I'm enjoying the process. I mean we, we're
in talks right now. Things are going,
things are going smoothly,
things are going, things are
moving forward. We'll see.
Uh, we'll see what happens. I mean,
I know you have to say all this to say
all that. No, I mean that's, but that,
that is true. I mean, I want to fight
the best guys in the world and know, oh,
there's not a day. There isn't a day that
goes by that I don't get, I mean shoot,
you posted that thing this morning and
there was 287 likes and 30 or comments
and, and you know, five minutes
and it was all like, finally, hey,
when are you going to go?
When do you guys like I and
I get that every single day.
So there's not a day that goes by that,
that I don't,
it doesn't get talked
about or thought about.
But especially after anyone over there
became the champion. Yeah. Right.
And everybody knows about,
I mean that's one of the things that I
talked about when Eddie first came over
to the UFC was go,
I was telling people,
go watch the wars that he
had with Michael Chandler.
And then I've said that also too,
when I've seen you coaching people or
being in someone's corner, I'm like,
that right there is one of the best
lightweights in the planet. Yeah.
And I just really would love to see you.
I mean,
I don't want to undercut Beltour. I don't
want it to bell toward, you know, no,
I mean it's at the end of the
day, I mean there's, there's,
it's a competition between the two.
You know, the two organizations,
there's guys in both organizations that
are great, like you said, Lima and,
and all these guys course correct
off. I mean there's, you know,
and the pit bull brothers or whatever.
I mean there's,
there's some great talent in both
[inaudible] and you saw it back in the day
with Strikeforce and now all of a sudden
a lot of these Strikeforce guys are,
you know, UFC champions as well, you
know, so it's kind of interesting,
weird the way fighting is today
as opposed to the way boxing.
It's like a perfect example is like,
like the Gennady Golovkin
fight this weekend. You know,
we went to see him and you know,
you go to your,
you're basically going to see one
of the best boxers on the planet.
You're not going to see him because he's,
you know,
the fucking WBC guy or
the IBF guy or the Wbo.
Oh yeah. People don't really give a
shit about that. He's a world champion,
but the the war, the one, but it's
versus Bella tour versus the UFC.
It's a big difference in
the way people look at it.
Like the average public,
the people don't give a shit if you're
the WBA champion in boxing or the WBC
champion, they don't give a
shit. They just want to know
who's a bad motherfucker.
Like is it,
you know,
is it Deontay wilder is an Anthony Joshua
who these are heavyweight champions.
Let's see him fight.
They don't look at it that way.
When it comes to Bella tour in the UFC.
I don't know why I have my,
my speculation is first of all,
because UFC has been around
forever and it's like the NFL,
it has that name value tips and they've
done a good job of building the name
value. It's also a really good name.
Yeah, UFC is a great name. Bella.
Tor is a shitty man. It just is.
It's just, you know, you go to the,
the average person like, oh, I'm going to
watch Bella tour tonight. They're like,
the fuck is up to her.
They don't know what a Bella Torres,
but ultimate fighting championship
makes sense. It makes sense.
I just wanted to just call it
paramount MMA, I think. Uh, yeah.
I mean I think there,
I mean there was all kinds of new branding
going on with the whole new paramount
stuff and all that kind of stuff.
I mean there,
if there was ever a time it would have
been now, but I mean, I think they're,
they're stuck to it. They like it. I
mean it's kind of one of them things.
They should get their money back from
spike Lee and when they had a pay spike
Lee, did they? Yeah, they paid them
off. He was crazy. No, he was sued.
He sued them. He said that you stole
the name from me and they're like,
what the fuck is basically just one of
those frivolous lawsuits that you have to
settle and they fine take bike wanting
some cactus Gash, take this money.
I want to how much they gave him. How
much do you think they gave him? Let's,
let's say, guess how much you think
they gave Spike Lee? 3.2 million.
Really that much? No, I don't
know. I made that a million.
If they have to give him a million,
I bet they gave him a meal.
I bet you're right.
I'm going to go with 1.2 I'm going to,
I'm going to be in the middle.
I'm going to be the middle
guy and see how much the guy,
do you think they disclosed it?
You think? Yeah, he did. He did.
He like actually trademark spike TV and
like someday he might actually have his
own TV channel type of
his, his thought was, well,
what about Spike Jones? Is he like,
where's my fucking money? Yeah.
I think he just was felt like his name
was so not like the named spike was
synonymous with him. I don't know. No.