No, he's, he's wicked.
He made one for my dog.
It did John Wick and as fuck too. Oh
he did? John Wick and his daughter.
That's from John Wick dose. Not
John Brick. Uno twisted [inaudible].
Can I get a couch surfing from
John Wick? One ran was, I'm wrong.
Well it's from John Wick one that he had
the pit bull. Yeah, it was, yeah. Yeah.
John Wick two.
They killed the Beagle and then he had
the pit bull and they started going to
killing spree. It doesn't have a three out
now. They're another one working on it.
Yeah, it's coming out
soon. Yeah, he's cool cat.
I ran into him at a deus
ex machina down and uh,
Santa Monica Venice area and he was
on one of his bikes and it super cool.
Rad Dude. Just, hey, what's up man?
Keanu Reeves must be one of the nicest,
coolest people in the planet cause no
one has a bad word to say about that guy
ever. He might, he might be
what we should all sprite or be,
we should all aspire to
be Keanu Reeves who are,
you might have some really crazy secrets.
No, I don't know that he's the nicest.
It seems like everybody runs
into him, you know, like,
I'm sure there's some people that ran
into you where they caught you the wrong
way and they're all went sideways
for a little bit. Nah, not really.
I mean I,
but no fucking Keanu Reeves. He
got it going on. But the point,
what I was going to get to is one of the
things that those movies did was they,
they elevated the profile of those muscle
cars because she saw that movie and
they went, this guy for this, something
about him. I know he's murdering people.
I know he's the best at murdering people.
I know he killed three guys in a
bar with a pencil. I know that.
But look how fucking cool he looks.
He's got, he's got the dopest suits.
He's killing people. He's
not killing people. And An
underarmour rash guard. Okay.
He's killing people in the dopest suits.
He's stabbing people in the neck
and he's driving a 70 Chevelle ss.
But the trick is unlocks your
fore mentioned and loved Eleanor.
It wasn't plasticized.
It was a real fricking muscle car.
Didn't have shit hanging all over it
and extra side pipes. You're right,
you're right. But you're also wrong
because Eleanor, look at that.
God dammit, I forgot to kill
somebody. I'm doing it just like that.
God, come on, it gets out of a
shit. He's got craters on it.
A Chevelle ss from 1970 with
Craig's. It's Torque for us. Look.
Yeah, look how good he
looks. Well that or style,
um, that, that's a classic white
wall tire. I mean, come on man.
Or white letter tire raised white letters.
That's class and you can get your
own now you can get your name on it.
You could do anything.
You'd have gas.
There's a team that sells like
see stickers, monkey tires.
I should fuck Keisha.
You can actually order stickers now that,
that are the rubber letters that fused
themselves into the rubber on your tire.
So you end up with a white letter like
that and you put anything on there. Wow.
Like Joe Rogan or
constantly.