Think about it as those are the people
are taking something away from you.
Think about it as they're giving you an
opportunity to look at what's possible.
If you really dedicate yourself and you
should choose that as a valuable life
lesson, like, wow,
look at that guy doing so well or look
at this girl like kicking ass and doing
all this. How does she accomplish
that? I should write all those things.
How does she make all these movies?
How did she do all these things like
fuck that. People don't do that.
The natural instinct is to look
at someone who's like some crazy,
like super competitive person,
like the rock or something like that.
Like you see the raw, he's in
everything. He's in everything.
You want to shit on him, but
he's such a nice guy. You can't.
It's a real problem like he could do.
That guy could do terrible
movie after terrible movie.
No one cares because he's such a good guy.
He could,
he could do whatever he wants. He seemed
like a nice guy. He's a very nice guy.
He's and he's the real deal.
That's really what he does. I mean,
that guy really does show up in a
fucking hotel room at four o'clock in the
morning, flies across the world and
immediately starts working out. Wow.
He's an animal like a let go.
You want to be inspired.
That guy's worth more money than everyone.
He makes more money than anybody
that's ever made any money in movies.
He's a fucking junk or not.
He's so out of control.
Every movie does is a blockbuster.
Meanwhile,
he still shows up at a place
they got to fucking dig out.
One of them elliptical machines waiting
for him. The guts, weight, weights,
weight and form.
He goes to town to do like 45 minutes
cardio when he fucking lands flying across
the world. Lift weights for an hour, like
he just keeps going. He just keeps going.
He finds a way to not complain, stay
positive and just keep going. I read it.
I read half of his book and I'm very like,
that's a lot for you and I remember that
when you have p he was third string and
playing football in Canada.
He was living up.
It will share the mattress with the,
with the last guy who,
who got kicked out of a team, Jesus
fog to be now a superstar. I mean,
I don't even know how many
millions he makes a movie,
but everybody sees his movies.
He's such a good guy,
but he hears be really clear that kind
of genetics like what that guy is that is
just like we were talking about
with Iceland. That's the same shit.
That's the same shit with the Pacific
islands, man. That's some warrior DNA son.
That's a giant man.
That's a huge,
super powerful man who
fucking is so driven.
Like we are lucky.
We are lucky.
That dude is not on the biggest fucking
horse he can find with the biggest
battle. Battleaxe. I mean that's
what these people come from, man.
You don't get to be that big if
you don't have like some sort of a,
a great lineage of warriors behind you.
You mean this debt so much bigger than
most people because it's Schwarzenegger.
He so big.
But all those guys,
like that guy that plays the
mountain on game of Thrones.
Like what in the holy fuck,
that guy's so big.
You know that that dude came
out of some war, your bloodline,
some crazy viking blood
line because before guns,
that was what was most important.
So when you see a guy like the rock
or you see it, God, you're like, wow,
that guy looks like a conqueror.
Yeah,
because that's what he comes from 100%
like he's the lorry warrior that due to
place door. What's that dude's name? Chris
Hemsworth isn't worth that. That dude.
Listen
that he's a goddamn specimen or aqua man.
What is this Jamie body comparison
of the rock to the mountain.
Who is the mountain mountains behind
him? 150 pounds on him. Oh my God. Oh,
the mountain from game of Thrones.
Oh, sorry. Holy Shit. Put that again.
Look how much bigger he is.
That's like,
that's significant in a
good like six seven inches.
He's so big it guy so big.
I'll tell you the six,
nine or some shit. Six nine.
Dude, that is so crazy.
I weigh more than both of them.
That's not true. Oh Wow. No.
The mountain weighs like 390380603 86
he's six foot nine he weighs 386 pounds.