I always wanted to ask you one thing.
Uh,
it's completely different
subjects. Can I ask you, uh,
when you're doing interviews
at the end of fights,
did you ever feel trathen
somehow no wait list once I'm,
no, no, no, no. I,
one thing that I hope the
fighters realizes that what
I'm trying to do is only
get them to express themselves.
I want them to shine.
I really genuinely want them.
They won this big fight. I want,
I want them to express themselves. I want
them to maybe maximize their marketing,
perfect their marketability and just
like tell the world how they feel.
Like that's a incredibly
unusual experience to win
a big fight in the cage on
paper view in front of millions of people.
My goal is only to try to get them to
communicate the better and to let them
know that I'm there to support them.
That's all I'm ever trying to
do for forfeit, you know? Yeah.
Like I was saying before,
before we started talking to,
I have a lot of fat friends in MMA,
sweetest guys as people consider what they
do for a living. It's crazy. So crazy.
Yeah. Damn young from the lay.
Yeah. Ninja Shogun. They are.
Oh, how is Ninja doing these days?
Man? Add less time. I talked to him,
he got some, he got some, uh,
I don't know if it was because of
the fighting and I cannot say that,
but his speech,
it's a little slow.
It is already hard to understand.
Even Shogun, they have this,
what they call the whole nace,
which is the way of speaking.
They come from this state,
which is very hard to understand what
they say from Queer TB. Right? Yeah.
I'm good at Chiba in people.
We don't from color chips.
Sometimes Wednesday speak to too fast.
You don't understand that much,
but Aneesha I think he got some,
some injuries in there.
Got some scars on his head.
I think he got some surgeries and yeah,
I think he had surgery on, it was fine at
the time. People are kicking people in,
in soccer kicking. Yeah. And he was
one of the best. He was good. Yeah.
He was an animal.
He was really young too.
And at the end he was like getting
knocked out with slaps. Yeah,
that's the scariest thing is
when you see their chin go,
when their ability to take upon,
what's crazy is shogun seems to be
making a resurgence. It's crazy.
He amazing.
He W I w I,
we used to be very good friends with
one of his coaches and after the fight
would Handerson the first one,
which was like a crazy fucking chaos,
that was a chaos. And I was
talking to him in, he was like,
you don't even imagine
how talented this guy is.
But uh, he got a focus. If he was focused,
he would kick his ass and like
fucking two minutes. So he just,
that's the way they do it in the shoe box.
They like to fight. They like to
fucking just go at it. Yeah. He,
him and Sidebar Org and a
[inaudible] Les Anderson,
the same thing. But the way they do,
it's just like, let's go to war. Yeah.
And sometimes the, the, the game
changed in, but shoguns like learning,
you can see that he's like
improving, still improving. And like,
I think it was like 36, 34 his last
fight, he looked sensation. Amen. I mean,
he looked like a fucking killer to phrase.
He can take a shot again now.
It's weird.
It's like,
I mean he got knocked out by a few
different guys and he's lost some fights,
some tough fights. But his last fight he
looked as good as he's looked in years.
It's, it's sad for me when I see like, uh,
I don't know why he's always with
Brazina's, but when I see like an old,
an old fighter getting his sp two quick.
Yup.
I remember his fight with Sonnen. That
was, that was, yeah, well he got caught.
He got caught on the guillotine,
but it's fast.
The guy framed for like six months
and that's very frustrating.
Remember when Royce he went back to
five with huge down was like, yeah,
well Matt Hughes was in his
prime and then, you know,
and he was so strong
and hoist just wasn't,
he wasn't physically capable and do it
right. He didn't look the same, you know,
it just didn't look like he was
physically capable those same way.
And you know, Matt, he was his
fucking talented, unbelievably
talented. And when he,
when he got on top of hoisting, it was
smashing them. I was like, oh yeah,
that's hard to watch. It's not a wash.
Yeah, but that's the life. I mean,
that is the life they chose,
you know, and chocolate.
Dell just got knocked out by Tito Ortiz
and that was hard to watch because you
could tell he just can't take a punch in.
I wasn't that five that went there to
watch it. It was, it was bad. It was,
it wasn't,
he wasn't moving right either.
The thing about when fighters
take a lot of knockout losses,
one of the things that's very becomes
a parent is there balance looks off and
their movement doesn't look the same.
Like their neurology, their, they don't,
the body doesn't move. It's not the
same. Yeah. You can look the same,
but there's react the same way.
Right. I mean, even Anderson,
when he lost his style bender,
I think style bender would've been a
tough fight for him at any point in his
career because style bender is
just fantastic, super technical.
But Anderson looked like he was a
step behind the Anderson of old,
like the Anderson that knocked out v
tour or the Anderson that, you know,
you go back to the early days,
the Anderson that knocked out Chael
Sonnen that Anderson was a fucking,
he was just in a Sasson.
Yeah, he was so good.
He just knew what to do and when to do it.
And when the style bender fight,
he just looked like he was a little
off little office, but he's also 46.
I don't know. He's, I think he's won one
year older than me. He's 43. He's only 40.
Yeah, we do. We do. We
did a show together. Uh,
we do a show this show on Netflix
called the old tomato bisque master,
which is a Brazilian
Netflix is here as well.
Terry crews did an American,
we do,
we do like all holes from all different
countries and we meet and it's like
American Ninja Warrior
for Netflix. Oh, okay.
And they have like hosts from different
countries and we have the Brazilians and
the Italians and the French guys.
Uh, and I did this show with Andrew.
So he's a sweet guy. He's a great guy,
great guy. He's a great guy. I mean,
he's one of the all time greats.
I mean,
I had the honor of calling a lot of his
fights and it's crazy because, yeah,
and it's crazy. [inaudible] when
you're talking about the guy,
the guy is getting older. I remember
I had a talk with Minataro. Uh,
he was like three or four,
like it was like two, two,
two fights after he actually retired. And
I asked him, why, why you keep doing it?
You don't have to do, you don't, you
don't have to prove anything to no one.
And what he said to me, I think
it was so fair. He was like,
I fought when this thing wasn't giving
me any money. Right. So just give,
let me lose the fight or two and get some
money at the end of my career because
I deserve that. He wasn't like, of
course he was going there to win,
but it's like I want to take the risk
because I was fighting in Japan getting on
on old $5,000 and now that the game,
it's like bringing you so much money.
I'm gonna retire.
Let me just do a couple or,
well Minataro not,
not only was he a pioneer and one of
the great MMA heavyweights of all time,
but he is so important for MMA because
he showed that heavyweights can fight off
their back and then heavyweights
could win by triangle.
Like when he triangled Mark Coleman and
was tapping guys with armbars when he
beat Bob Saget.
Bob Sapp on his fucking crazy though.
That is one of the greatest MMA fights
in the history of the sport. 375 pound.
Bob Sapp submitted guitar only,
probably weighed two 30 and he
wound up tap it in with an arm bar.
It was fucking Creighton
after get spiked on his head,
which still apparently
fucks with him to his day.
His neck was fucked up permanent because
of that. Yes. I didn't know that.
375 pound guy who doesn't even look
like a human. He looked like a,
like a comic book.
Yeah.
He smashes him on his head
and metatarsal recovered.
And I mean he was one of the
toughest guys of all time.
But she was run by a truck when he wasn't
there at, yeah. That's that scarring.
So it's run by a crazy. Yeah,
that's crazy. I mean, he's, um,
he's one of the most important
figures in the history of the sport.
And then I think Fabrisio took it to
another level because for [inaudible]
probably has the best guard in the
history of the sport is history.
The heavyweight division.
I mean,
when he caught fade or when he had him
in his triangle and he had them locked up
like that,
you don't get away with that guy like you,
you might get out of some people's guard,
not Fabricio that mother fucker
locks people up. Ain't, yeah.
And I got to thank you, man. I'm here
just because of him Gal for that. Well,
my respect for him, you know, when he
reached out to me and was like, okay,
I'll get your friend on
100% and he is a great guy.
And that's what I, well,
that's why I asked you if, uh,
if you'll kind of feel threatened because
when people get there in the fight,
you don't know what it was
going to happen. And when
you goal over there to talk,
we don't want,
you can see a wrong thing at the
Romano or maybe you can make mistakes,
you should stay. So my, my intention is
always to just to make them look good.
That's all I'm trying to do,
I'm trying to do is just get them
to express themselves and, and, and,
and also put some emotion to how great
their performance was. Perfect. Yeah.
But it's a weird job, you know,
to also be a comedian, you know,
it's a strange combination. The,
yeah. Do they go watch you sometimes.
Sometimes. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That's good. That's very good.