Well,
it should be a comfort that there's
people smarter than the people that don't
think that we're doing it.
That there are people that can possibly
consider some sort of way to mitigate
this. Yeah. And what, what are the,
what are the ways that are being proposed
and how seriously are they being taken
other than this, um, the idea
of building these machines,
extract carbon from the atmosphere.
I'm sure you're probably aware of. Um,
there's some of the programs that they've
talked about a suspending reflective
particles in the atmosphere to,
to minimize the amount of
solar radiation we receive.
Yeah.
So it's interesting,
this guy who I mentioned earlier who like
done the most sort of most innovative
carbon capture machine. I talked to him a
few weeks ago and he was like, no, no, no,
but we shouldn't be using carbon capture.
We should be doing solar geoengineering,
which is what you're talking about. Um,
and that means probably suspending sulfur
is like the most useful thing in the
atmosphere. I'm great. We're
going to smell like sulfur.
The Sky would get red. Oh,
Jesus. They're all of these aesthetic
effects too, which nobody talks about.
So like trees are going to just turn
immediately brown or not going to turn
color.
There was a study a couple of weeks
ago that the oceans are going to change
color. Um, there, this is, if we
do that, if we suspend this for,
this is just pure warming
just from warming.
The ocean is going to change color to
what I think just from more green to more
blue. But uh, I mean
Nice. Yeah. Um, but yeah,
so the sulfur thing is, um, so we could,
you know, we could suspend these, um,
basically an umbrella of sulfur
around, um, in the atmosphere,
which would mean that it would,
some of the sunlight coming to the
earth would be reflected back into the
atmosphere and that would mean that
the sun would absorb less sunlight.
I mean the earth would
absorb less on sunlight,
which would make it a little bit cooler.
Um,
the problem is that would have some
crippling impacts on agriculture and we
basically don't know other
side effects that would have.
And how would you take that stuff out?
Well, you could just stop doing it.
It has a shelf life of, I don't
know what it is, 10 years,
so you could just stop doing it.
And that's a big concern actually,
because if we did that just to mask the
amount of global warming that we were
doing,
then whatever program was responsible for,
it would be really vulnerable
to terrorism, um, to war.
Because if we,
if we were,
if the planet were functionally warmed,
say five degrees,
but we were suspending enough sulfur
that it was actually only two degrees
warmer than if we just,
for instance,
like somebody bombed the
facility that was doing it,
the planet would be immediately
tripped into a much,
much hotter state and that would
be completely catastrophic.
Even more catastrophic than a more slow
approach to five degrees because we
would adjust to it. We, over a
century or several centuries,
we met in ways we'd be able to adjust to
it. But if it was immediate, immediate,
yeah.
Why Sulfur?
I think it's just something about
that particular characteristic of it.
I don't know.
Wouldn't it
smell? Hartman would literally be
like hell. Like, that's what you yeah.
You always hear about with
the horror movies, right?
The devil smells like sulfur.
Yeah.
And I mean it's the, um, it's what farts
smell like. And the reason that we would,
the reason we're able to smell
farts is because sulfur is also,
I mean some related compounds,
hydrogen sulfide are um,
are really toxic. And so that brings me
to methane. That's another issue as well,
right? Yeah. Cows producing methane
gas, large scale agricultural. Yeah.
Wait, let me just say one more thing
about shortly. The solar geoengineering.
So the thing about that, that's real,
this sounds horrifying. This program,
people are excited about it
because it's really cheap.
It's way cheaper than carbon capture and
um, but so there's a positive for it.
But it's also,
um,
we are basically already doing this.
So we have what's called small
particulate pollution. Um,
that's or aerosol pollution. I'm stuffed,
suspended the, in the atmosphere.
That's why like Delhi is really hard
to breathe in cause we have a lot of
particulate in the atmosphere that is
already suppressing global temperatures by
as much as a half degree or
maybe one degree, which means,
and that's the reason that those 9 million
people are dying every year from air
pollution. So if we solve that problem,
if we solve the air pollution problem,
save those 9 million lives,
we,
every year we would immediately make the
planet at least a half a degree warmer
and possibly one degree warmer,
which would put us at the threshold
of catastrophe or above it. Um,
so we're sort of already doing this
program, just not in a systematic way.
We're doing it in a haphazard way.
Um, the methane you mentioned,
they're basically two big issues
with methane. First is, um, cows.
Um, so yeah, cows
produce a ton of methane,
which is depending on how you count
about 35 or maybe 85 times stronger,
a greenhouse gas than carbon. Whoa.
Yeah, it's really intense. Um,
but there are also these like small
scale studies that show if we feed cattle
just a little bit of seaweed there,
methane emissions could fall by 95 or 99%.
So we could if, if that was scalable,
which is not clear it is, but if it was,
we could immediately eliminate the
entire carbon footprint of beef,
which people talk about a lot now.
That's incredible. Yeah, just,
it's a reminder to me that
like, you know, you get told,
oh you should eat less
hamburgers or whatever.
But obviously this is like a problem
that's too big to be solved with like
individual choices.
We need some kind of global policy
or national policy about it.
But the scarier methane issue is,
um,
there's all this carbon stored in frozen
permafrost in the northern latitudes.
Um, that permafrost is
melting and when it melts,
that carbon will be released
into the atmosphere.
We don't know the proportion that it
will be released as carbon dioxide versus
methane,
but um,
there is in that permafrost twice as much
carbon as now exists in the atmosphere,
which means if it were all released
possibly in a relatively sudden way,
it could make our carbon problem
immediately, three times worse. Um,
and it could be even the effect could
even be more dramatic than that if it was
released mostly as methane because
methane is stronger greenhouse gas.
Most scientists think that that's not
something that we need to freak out about
in the short term,
but it's there,
it is melting and methane is
being released at some rate.
So craziest solution than I ever heard
for that one was to bring back the woolly
mammoth. Yeah, yeah. They're
trying to do that. Yeah.
And did the idea that the woolly mammoth
is going to save us all by releasing
them throughout Siberia. Yeah.
That's crazy, right? I mean,
I think that we're going to have a whole
a century of shit like that and shit,
like cows eating seaweed,
that everything, you know,
we'll have our global politics will be
reoriented around climate change so that
you'll start to see sanctions put against
nations that are behaving badly. Um,
NBS, the guy who's, you know,
the like kind of thug who's
running Saudi Arabian assets,
he needed Saudi Arabia's economy
to be totally off oil by 2050.
And I think that's cause he knows that,
you know,
the global community will not tolerate
someone producing more oil and, um,
as recently as you know, as soon as a few
decades from now. But the impacts are,
you know, everywhere. So that like, um,
yeah, like in California now you can,
you know, during wildfire season
you can buy, um, masks to, you know,
to shield yourself from the smoke,
which is really, really damaging.
Its Effects on cognitive
performance are really dramatic.
Can lower cognitive
performance by like 10 or 15%.
It's effect on the development
of kids is really dramatic. Um,
there was an incredible study a few
years ago where if you looked at places
where they instituted easy, do you have
easy pass out here in California? No,
we don't. We don't have tolls.
Oh, right. So amazing. Yeah.
You guys think what one or two places,
depending on where you live, do,
you'd have to take that every day. Dude,
in New York, they're everywhere. Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
So it used to be the case that cars had
to like slow down and pay a toll and
because they were slowing down,
they produce more exhaust when they
instituted easy pass cars could just drive
through and that meant they produce
less exhaust and the effect on the,
on premature birth and low birth weight
in the areas where they instituted these
new easy pass toll plazas,
it reduced them by like 15% each.
That's how dramatic just the exhaust
effect is on development of babies. Um,
how much is an effect of
electric cars? Yeah. That, I
mean, that, that will be right.
You know, it hasn't had enough of an
effect because there's not enough of them.
Yeah. Um, and, but yeah,
I mean that problem on the,
unlike at the technological
level has been solved.
We know how to replace
cars with electric cars.
We can make them even pretty affordable,
not quite as affordable as they need to
be, but the new Teslas are like 35 grand.
I think if you get it down to
15 grands, that'll be, you know,
that'll be a huge solution.
But then there are a lot of other
problems that are more difficult.
Like air travel,
you can't,
we don't have electric plans around
the corner. You can't fly planes.
Is there anything like
that on the horizon? Is it,
there's some people who are,
who are trying to develop it,
but it seems like probably it's at
least like a decade away. And you know,
one cross country flight in the u s is
the equivalent one seat on one Costco
cross country flight is the
equivalent of eight months of driving.
Every time you fly from New
York to London and back,
you melt nine three square meters of ice.
Every single seat on every flight from
New York to London melts three square
meters of ice, um, of articles. Yeah.
That's insane.
That's right.
Real. Yeah. Yeah.
I think it's time you fly
across the country. It's
like eight months of driving.
Yeah. Whoa. So globally,
air travel is only 2% of the carbon
footprint. So it's relatively small,
but for people in especially
rich people in rich countries,
it's a much bigger part of the folks.
They fly around all. Yeah. But yeah, no,
the average American,
I think the stat is the average American
every year admits enough carbon to melt
10,000 tons of ice.
Jesus Christ.
That's just the average American.
And if you're a person like me who
flies like every other weekend,
it's way worse. Way Worse. Yeah. Oh.
So Holy Shit,
you put it in that perspective.
It's how much fucking eyes is there?
I mean, there's a lot of ice. Yeah.
But it's gonna melt. Well,
that's how you get, you know,
the out the outside projections,
the high end projections for sea
level rise are 260 feet. No. Um,
the plus sign is it's way better to
get hotter than it is to get colder.
Right? Like ice ages kill everything.
Well, the, you know, the, each of the,
so there've been five mass extinctions
and planetary history in Earth's history
before one of them was killed,
was caused by an asteroid,
but the other four were um,
were produced by global warming
related to greenhouse gas. Um,
and one of them the ice age when the
ice age doesn't count, it didn't,
didn't kill as many know really the,
the biggest mass extinction,
the end Permian extinction, which
is 250, 2 million years ago,
90 to 95% of all life on earth died.
When was that? 250. 2
million years ago. God.
So each of these mass
extinctions basically is like
a complete slate wiping of
the evolutionary record. It's like
we're starting over from scratch.
So we want to think that the,
the asteroid that hit the Yucatan did
the most damage in terms of the fossil
record. Is that not true?
Is the one that was the,
the global warming was that more?
Well this other,
there are five and four of them were
from global warming and the worst,
the worst one was just from, from
greenhouse gas warming. But yeah, the,
the one that killed the
dinosaurs was also really bad.
It was something like
70% of all life on it,
but it's less than the one where there
was a temperature rise. Yeah. Wow.
There was a, um, a volcano, this
is a little bit sketchy science,
but there was a volcano explosion,
um,
something like 30,000 years
ago or something. I don't
remember the exact dates,
but that um, volcanoes can cool, uh,
global temperature for the same reason
we're talking about with suspending
particles because it basically
clouds the atmosphere with, um,
and it dropped global temperatures.
I think it was two degrees and the human
population at the time then shrunk to
7,000.
There's this incredible bottle that a
bunch of times that's the less people than
live on Nantucket.
And it just,
it just makes you see like everything
about the way that we live on this planet
is dependent on climate
conditions. Yeah. Like,
we'll figure a way to like have a
civilization, but it will be transformed.
It will be very different if the
world is four degrees warmer. Um,
and you know,
everything about the way that we take
for everything we take for granted today
is like a permanent feature
of the modern world.
I think we're going to learn is much
more precarious, much more unstable.
Um, and yeah, like I
said earlier, you know,
climates were stable for
all of human history. That's
how we were able to evolve.
It's how we were able
to invent agriculture.
The part of the world where we did
invent agriculture in the Middle East,
it's now getting almost
too hot to grow crops.
It's also going to be too hot to go to
Mecca for a pilgrimage in just a couple
of decades, whether like we're
entirely outside of that, um,
window of temperatures,
which means we're functionally now living
on an entirely different planet than
humans ever lived on before.
And it's going to keep changing.
So by the time we get to two
or three or four degrees,
will be a living in a climate that's,
you know,
two or three or four times as
much different as the one that,
where as now from the one before
the industrial revolution. And yeah,
it's like those impacts could be
totally overwhelming and catastrophic.