Hello Freak bitches. So, oh,
when you look at that as a
comedian is like, wow, you know,
that was good for me and that was
good for me in a certain way of,
first of all it's, it's great
jokes too. It's like it does say,
are we becoming too fragile
when it comes to our race?
Like black folk, like I say, yeah,
some people are racist and some people
are perceptionist now what that means. No,
the perception is, okay, the perception
in America was the white man.
Donald Trump can be president.
The woman can't do it.
Perception doesn't mean that if you
vote for Ronald Donald Trump that you're
racist. I don't think everybody
does it cause that was a big thing.
Sometimes this perception I'll,
I'll make, I'll make it clear. Okay.
I do a joke in front of all black
people and I said black people are very
interesting people because we deal
with racism and perception ism.
I said because we were very
nervous flyers, right? We
don't like to get on planes.
First thing we do when
we get on the plane,
we see who's flying this motherfucker.
We look in the cockpit,
if we look and see a black
guy, we will stop and go, hey,
how long you been flying?
Uh,
you got your hours with you.
And it was the perception.
And don't let a woman sit
next to him. Oh Shit, we good.
It could be a bright sunny day is
a how's the weather? We're good.
And then as you're sitting in that seat,
anytime you hit a bump bump, my brother,
we straight, same situation.
You go in the cockpit,
you see that white guy with his salt and
pepper hair and those aviators and at
forum hair like this and
it's storming outside. Shit.
Fly the ship through a hurricane.
So it's the perception that we
have to talk about sometime.
Does that make sense? Oh, it
definitely makes sense. Yeah. You know,
there's definitely that.
You don't like the,
the Donald Trump thinks funny know who
had it, said it best. Alonzo boating,
you know Lonzo? No, I would say funny
comedian. Yeah. He said, he goes,
not all Donald Trump
supporters are racist,
but all racists are
Donald Trump supporters.
That he definitely awakened that side.
But I will,
but I will say this, like I said, the
perception gets us all to, you know,
cause like my, my daughter,
it was interesting, my
oldest, my oldest daughter,
like when when the,
uh,
when the election happened and
when the results came in, Dad,
I'm so mad I can't take it. I said, well,
what'd you were going to go March? I said,
what did y'all vote? Not all of us,
but you know, I said, well, you know,
you gotta get out there because their
perception was she had it in the bag.
You know what I'm saying? So you
gotta get out there and be, you know,
whatever that is. Yeah.
Whatever that is. Indeed.
This is a weird times for everybody,
you know,
because I think social media is
allowing people to express themselves.
Everybody's expressed
themselves and forming groups,
you know, they're just like,
you know,
they're progressive or they're there,
they're liberal or they're
conservative and this,
everybody has a voice because everybody
has a voice. There's so much voices.
I'll say this, maybe you can appreciate
this because we've, we've lived,
we're living in two worlds. We lived when
it wasn't here and we live in an exam.
It's discretion.
Social media allows you
not to have discretion.
You're able to go in and type whatever
you want to say and that usually that's
what we pay attention to.
Discretion is this.
We're sitting at the dinner table and Yo,
I said something that you did like,
but the discretion was, I'll
address that later. Right?
So now that you don't have any discretion,
anybody's voice can be heard.
Not Everybody.
How do you say it?
Not Everybody has a point that we
should hook all of our wagons to write.
What I notice is that we will hook our
wagons to the most extreme point and that
may be only 2,500 people. Like when
my homies with him, he said, man,
you would they say a man about songs.
Like I said,
how many of you use it to get 80,000
views as is 8 million people in Philly
alone. Why are you just
listening to those 80,000 people?
So you sorta have to put balance in
a way you saw the sift through it.
Does that make sense? It
does make sense. Yeah. Well,
the way I tried to put it out to people,
if you run into a room and there's
a hundred people in that room,
what are the odds that one person is a
fucking idiot. 100% right? One person,
almost almost every room of a
random group of a hundred people.
And I'm being very, very polite person.
That means probably a few, probably a few,
but let's go with one.
One out of a hundred.
So that means there's 3 million
fucking idiots in this country, right?
Just straight idiots, right?
Non fixable idiots. Yeah. Yeah.
So if you're gonna read comments,
you're opening yourself up to that.
If you're going to get your opinion swayed
by people who just want to just want
to see if they can affect,
you,
just want to see if they can
just fuck with you and touch you.
Just see big change. You get you
to change the way you're dressing.
Like that's part I don't like. So I tell
all of my artists and all my friends,
don't change.
Don't read it.
Because what happens is everybody
starts coloring inside the lines and now
nobody's dangerous anymore,
right?
Because you remember back in the day
on Madonna, dangerous, right? Donna,
come out naked. You know, just dance
into the grand. He's like, it's all good.
So what I hope will want to always say,
just don't Tuck your art in.
Don't take your Rdm foot for the,
for the comments,
because we'll end up not having anything.
Not having anything to celebrate that is
bet is good.
Like having something to sell,
but somebody did a song that was
dope or movie that was doable.
Got Outside the box as opposed
to what we love celebrating,
which is the crazy shit.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
Yeah.