Bless that guy. So no flame to
bring it. I thought it was silly.
But you know these fans fans want,
cause Ben is a
representative of the trolls.
Like most of the trolls look like Ben
asked her if I could give you any infant.
That's hilarious. Hilarious.
If I could give you any advice,
please don't pay attention.
I don't get any shit.
Don't pay attention to comments.
You know that glass jar? Yeah.
Once you smashed that thing too. Don't
even put anything in there anymore, man.
Don't do nothing. I, and I've, I've heard
you say that so many times. Like I, um,
when I started paying
attention to the show,
I started watching the show and I watched
the one you did with Tyron when Tyler
was up here and, and
you so right. Like some,
cause that's the one thing that I always
felt like so unfair about Tyron is a
lot of people just gave him shit because,
and I think it started because
he didn't take that belt.
They didn't dethrone George Saint Pierre.
So I think a lot of it stemmed from
that. So where do you go about that? Man,
I know it doesn't, it stopped Robbie
Lawler if that didn't give Hendrix.
I understand,
but,
but George Sand pure still looping around
as the was a big champion but sort of
not because he retired. He said I'm
going to step away. Yeah, but he,
he stepped away. Yes. I
understand. For you being the,
obviously you know so much about the sport
[inaudible] being in the sport for so
long. Yes. But for these fickle
fans that don't know shit,
that's why he can't listen to all they
know is George Saint Pierre worship here
was a champion.
He never lost his belt.
So I felt like tiring and forgot
his fair share necessarily.
I feel like the same because,
because they're like,
oh he never took the belt from George
and he always wanted Wonderboy fights.
I think the Wonderboy fights were so
fucking hard. Yeah. But even before that,
fight Wonderboy that way, that is
the way you fight that guy. Yes.
You know, unless you know someone
like me comes in and does it,
what would you do it? What would
you do? I don't know. I just do.
I just do me cause he's still in the
mix. How would you do me? You know,
I will eventually get ahold of him.
I will eventually break him and you know,
eventually make it look easy and then
people are going to just complain.
So you know it is what it
is. Yeah. The, the, the,
the problem with him is he's so
difficult to get close to. Yeah.
He's a different guy because
his style is so different.
He'll stand totally sideways on you.
His hands will be down and he can wrestle.
I mean in terms of takedown defense,
he's got good takedown defense and his
strikes come from fucking weird angles,
man. He moves like a snake. Like he
bends at the waist and pops forward.
Ever watched him kickbox and African
war. But I saw that, you know,
I knew it was a problem when he threw
that one kick that came over the fucking
shoulder and smacked question
mark. Kick. Yeah. It was weird.
It's not the front leg. He's
very good with it. He just,
you don't even know what's going on.
He think maybe he's going to
kick you in the body. Yeah.
Around surround comes over. The
top x smacks you in the fet. Nah,
he's very talented. Like I like
wondering what lot, you know,
but like I just felt like when I
saw that show with tiring, I said,
and you said the exact same thing to them.
And that's what I said too.
And that's where I was thinking too.
But it's easier sending nut
because partially what I,
I got into this and why,
why I appreciate the platform that I
have right now is the fact that you can
affect so many people at
such a rapid amount of time.
Because there's been an instance to where,
I don't know if you ever
remember that movie,
what women want and Mel gifts met
Mel Gibson. I didn't watch it.
And basically he could hear women's
thoughts and things like that.
And then there was a,
there was a girl in the office,
Girl in the movie who she was planning
to kill herself because no one really
paid attention to her. She
was like, no one would care.
And she's walked around with books. I
applied for a job, everyone blew me off.
No one cares.
I'm going to kill myself this day.
So she was planning to kill herself and
he heard her because he could hear what
women think.
He heard a thoughts,
but initially they didn't really pay
attention to it until later on he realized
she was missing from the office and
then he like ran to go find her and
essentially saved her life.
But my thing is,
and that's a quote that I live by with
great power comes great responsibility.
Like what if there's someone
that's dealing with something
in a certain time and
yes, I didn't ask to be put in
that position, but they, you know,
they just decided, oh, I'm
just going to reach out.
I send a message before I kill myself
this day. One was going to respond,
no one's going to care.
And I happened to read that message and
talk to that kid off the ledge and that
kid becomes fucking,
you know,
wins the Nobel peace prize
later on in life. Like,
that's a responsibility that I have that
I didn't, I didn't put that on myself,
but that I have with the gift that
I've been blessed with to touch so many
people.
And so how am I going to know that
if I never read any of my messages or
comments and things like
that? Yes, of course. I, you
know, all the negative ones.
Yeah.
Blow and blow it up.
But how do I know it's negative
if I don't read it and all,
so that's what I'm saying. It's easier
said than done. It's like I read this.
If now what I do is I read, if I even
feel like it's getting negative, dilly,
dilly, dilly, I can't read them all. Cause
after that five fucking, I got thousands,
I'm sure. So, you know,
I can't read them all.
But every now and again when I'm
bored enough and I have time,
like I'll read some of it because
sometimes it is good, good things,
but you know that [inaudible].