Hello Freak bitches. A amazing
pace. Sodas. You look at guys,
you know Jon Jones has good cardio.
Very good cardio. Yeah. Might be EPL.
We'll figure it out.
I was on when you're talking about that,
can't trust anything disappointing.
Was that how disappointing that
broke my heart. John John's dude,
you broke my heart, dude. Jamie
sent it to me. I was at a universal,
my wife and my kids. I know Dallas,
Texas with you because what was I doing?
Uh, I forget. Oh, I think, oh,
I was working for showtime and I
have my phone and then I, I look at,
I have 70 Miss Techs and 23 minutes
called like, what the fuck out?
It's someone that likes
own, died. Oh No. Who Died?
And I look and it's like John Jones,
like someone might as well go, hi.
Jamie sent it to me. I
thought it was a show. Me Too.
I thought the people were messing with
me. I looked at my phone, I was like,
this is no one that you sent to me. I,
you're the first one I take someone.
Is this real? You went? Yes. Well my
heart John Snow. Once you start talking,
once he started talking back and forth
with the golden snitch that gone snitch,
there's zero jokes there.
And listen,
when the golden snitch comes out with
something Dave brand that pisser through a
ton of tests. It's not
like a, it's not fake news.
His was his shit. Apparently
a court, well hold on.
I don't think I can say this
right cause I had an expert.
I talked with an expert about this drug
and he fucking dropped some knowledge on,
okay, this is what I've
heard. This may not,
may or may not be true because this is
the reason why I don't tell you to say
this cause I'm, I'm
not, I'm not 100% aware.
Maybe we can find some
information online available.
What I had heard is that this
drug is not detectable in blood,
that it's a drug that's detectable in
urine and they have to in a new test,
right. The test, is it a new task?
What from what I heard too is the
Usada is they have a new test.
I'll see the on announcing,
hey, we're doing this now.
Everyone welcome to the party.
And this drug was also, it's,
it's very common around power lifters
cause you can use in competition and by
the time you get tested after
it has, uh, hours, a half life.
So shelf life is super short,
but you take it and make you super
aggro and strong. So they, and they go,
it's so hard to obtain legally.
Most everyone gets a black market.
And when you get a black market,
you don't know where it's coming from.
And a lot of time,
and this happens with a lot of
power lifters in their athletes,
when they test hot for this,
it's because they got a bad batch
or something else mixed into it. Oh,
this is gone from my super knowledgeable
dude who knows about it. Oh,
it makes you anger all huh?
The confidence. Yeah. Oh,
and he goes in it, it lasts maybe
an hour, maybe two hours Max.
And that's how your
system, he goes, he goes,
so that makes sense by some
would fail directly after
cause it, no, no, no, no, no,
no. He, he, he failed after the weigh in.
Okay.
That's when he failed. This is after
the weigh in? I don't think so.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We'll either way. Yeah.
Well maybe it's like lingering.
Well that's what he's saying better
what he's saying. He's saying well,
but also I heard that they would use
a new test to maybe someone gave him a
tainted sandwich. Maybe some tainted take
pills. Either way. You broke my heart.
I'm off. I'm off the train. I'm off the
God damn train and I'm sick of though.
We have no idea what happened. It was just
Dick Pills. I'm like, I'm out. I'm out.
How dare you? Well, is he offering up any
possible scenario for what happened? No.
He tweeted out like, this is when
I find out who my real friends are.
Hashtag blessed boy, fuck that noise.
That sounds like you're feeling sorry.
She's just ain't helping me out of
this one. So much to be grateful for.
Well have seed money, but yeah, that's a
good amount. Yeah, he's got a nice family.
It's true. Good friends. Hopefully
whatever. Whatever the fuck is happening.
But here's the thing, man,
they have a second fire. Joe,
listen to it multiple times.
Sada,
since the golden snitch has been around
and he's a motherfucker. I liked the guy.
But if you're a fighter, he's
a motherfucker. Well, hey,
he's doing exactly what
he's supposed to do.
[inaudible] circle doing
the sport baseball first.
Now you're hitting all the fighters are
ruining it because they know what the
fucking parameters are. Now let's have
some fun. I agree. I agree. I don't look,
look, here's the thing about this fight.
Do you think Dana's ever like God,
what kind of testing was done for this
boy? Maybe where the Conor McGregor fight.
Okay.
I those new lights. What do you, what do
you, I like what you're doing the place,
man. You know what man? I
like the curtains, right?
When I pulled the new studio,
I'm going to do the curtains.
Yeah, you should, man. Uh, yeah,
but Novitsky is a guy that you
don't want on your bad side. Oh No.
But do you ever think days like,
Damn Bro, relax me. Hired Joe.
But Jesus, they knew what they were
getting into. And you know what,
they just decided, this is only
one way to clean up the sport.
Bring in the guy who was the very best to
catching people for doing drugs. Ma'Am,
ma'am, ma'am, did they do? And
here's the thing, Jon Jones,
since you saw us coming in,
he's failed three out of four tests.
The only one he did a full line
was a co Osp. Coke is coke.
Coke is coke pro. Once,
Oh, so that's fine.
Okay.