How many people told me, hey, I, we'd
been hanging out with George for a week.
I got fat again. 10,000 my, yeah, that's
George, man, that's George. Don't,
don't eat like he eats.
You won't, it won't work.
And he has his whole theories and
philosophies all about why he's lean.
It's like, dude, no, you're just,
you're just born this way. You,
he just doesn't get it. I've tried it.
I've trained thousands of people. Okay.
He's trained himself like he thinks the
way he did what he did is we're going to
work for everyone. I love
Georgia, Super Intelligent Guy,
but I tell him towards the way,
like,
he's very gifted when it comes to
food and he does a lot of things.
And like now he's doing it a lot of
fasting and he's getting even leaner,
but it'll be a long time for Georgia's
fat. You see, there's, there's,
there's various body types. You know,
you do have ectomorph, Mesomorph,
endomorph and we're, we're, uh, we're
on the continuum of these three.
Georges on the Ectomorph side and in a,
in a strong sign of ectomorph is a
small waist. And George has a Mesomorph.
No, Mesomorph is cause he's very muscular.
He is, I would say you'd be more active,
more Schwab. Muzzles sorry, go ahead.
George was very skinny and
scrawny when he was young,
so he went crazy on the weights. He
turned his weakness into a strength. He,
that's so much weight, weight training
and exercise because he wanted to bulk up.
So he's a bulk ectomorph now.
He's not a perfect that Kumar,
he's not a 100% up to more,
I would say it's between
Ectomorph Mesomorph but
endomorph the other end of the
spectrum. You eat a little bit
of carbohydrates to get fat.
You lift a little bit of muscles,
your muscles explode in size.
George wasn't like that. George is on a
bit on the other side of the spectrum.
So a real mesomorph would
be like Melvin Manhoef. Uh,
yeah, like that, you know, I think I'm
kind of, no, no, no, no. That's more, uh,
uh, endomorph. Endomorph it's fat. Yeah,
but you could also be very muscular and
more, yeah, you can be very muscular.
I thought into morph is like,
like people that have a really
hard time not being overweight.
You can gain fat and muscle really
quickly as an endomorph. Yeah,
but ectomorphs from what I've read,
I might be wrong.
Neither one of us are
biologists. Exactly, exactly.
I always thought ectomorph was really
skinny and morph was they'd tend to lean
towards being overweight
and then Meza more.
For someone who's like really
like a Francis and Ghana,
not super or Brock Lesnar like super
muscular fic like just look like they like
naturally would pack a lot of moms.
I'm sure you could pull
up a chart if you can.
All these pictures just show both of
them from what I, from what I've read,
see them as amorphous
kind of in the middle.
ECTOMORPH is Ilene and hot pack on muscle.
ECTOMORPHIC skinny,
dark and Mesomorph. Looks like you
super jacked and endomorph looks like,
well endomorph endomorph does
not look fat in that picture.
It doesn't have to be fat. That's
the thing. Now here, here's,
let me tell you something ladies.
When you look at those three pictures,
I go with endomorph all day.
Exactly. Those three pictures.
We love the other words,
if that's what an endomorph is,
let's take the in the
morning. Yeah, because marks,
they need a lot of naps and they're always
tired. And those mesomorph their egos.
Goodness,
they want to choke you.
The mesomorph shoulders want to
fucking strangle you. But uh,
endomorphs that's a woman.
God,
you can have a riff endomorph
anybody can be ripped.
That's the guy's an endomorph. Maybe think
about it in the morph is like a short,
stocky hulk. Should be fat. And he
could also be packed with muscle.
Calvin, Kelvin, guest alum,
Kevin Gasoline. And he would,
I would put them on the end of the moves
and the more site, yes, definitely.
Because he's never really,
totally ripped. Well,
dolce when he had him and he was
getting them down to a real one 70,
he, he really had, I'm pretty ripped at
one point in time. Just really low body.
You can get ripped. It's just not as easy
to get there. Anybody can get ripped. Um,
but uh, an Ectomorph so think
about a basketball player. Okay.
What are the signs they
say is small waist?
The waist and shoulders are quite similar.
Now George has a v going, you know,
is very broad shoulders,
which is great.
He's perfectly built for fighting that
allows him for reach and his Aa cause
he's got incredible, like, it's like
he's wearing shoulder pads almost.
And you know, he's blessed with many,
many, uh, uh, genetic gifts for fighting,
no doubt about it. And endomorphs
are naturally predisposed, excuse me.
ECTOMORPHS are naturally
predisposed to endurance sports.
So you'll see a lot of marathon runners
or whatnot. They're tall and lanky.
They're not short, bulky, uh, you know,
Mike Tyson type look athletes,
that's a real Meza. More real.
That's what I would say.
Endomorph endomorph because he's so short,
short and stocky and bulky. He could put
on a lot of muscle, a lot of fat Nasco.
Is he a little bit, I don't wanna
I don't want to say he's fat. He's,
he's put on some fat since
he's retired or whatnot. Right.
I don't know how much it
works out anymore, you know?
Exactly. But an Ectomorph,
even when they stop working out,
they're still,
they're less likely to put back on fat.
And I have a little belly, you know,
but it's not as as pronounced.
It's not as pronounced as an Endomorph,
nm mournful pack on fat and muscle
real quickly and they're, they're more,
they're more, um, they gravitate more
towards power sports so they can explode,
but they have less cardio.
Where's the ECTOMORPH is like,
you'll see a lot of running backs.
There's short, stocky, endomorph man,
they have to explode for three,
four seconds.
Is there a best body for
fighting or is there a,
do you just adapt your style to
whatever body you had? Exactly.
I think there's the best body for
basketball, the best body for football.
While it depends on what position
you're playing, but fighting,
everybody has an a fight in their DNA.
So all styles,
excuse me, all body types can fight and
that's what's so amazing. You got it.
You got to Paul Harris.
He's an endomorph man,
but he found a way to fight
that make sense for him.
That's what I always tell people.
You got to fight according to your,
your body type.
And people think that's crazy.
No Muhammad Ali fought a certain way
because it has certain attributes.
He had certain, he had certain
uh, a certain personality.
Even your personalities were important.
If he tried to fight like Tyson,
it would backfire. If Tyson tried to fight
like Muhammad Ali, it would backfire.
I think everybody has to start with
the basics. And then after three,
four years of training,
even maybe up to five years now
you've got to specialize for what your
temperament is.
What's your body type is,
what's your personality is because not
everybody wants to get it done and run.
And not everybody is the type of person
is going to take it to the cards.
And not everybody has a reach and speed
to jab in and out. Lucky and think, oh,
I'm just going to jab in
and out like I'll eat. Dude,
do you have the attributes that Ali has?
He was born with certain attributes and
everybody's born with an attribute for
fighting. In my opinion, everybody
got this far because they can fight.
Nobody got here, uh, this far without
having some innate ability to fight,
you know, to defend themselves. So all
our body types can defend themselves,
but you have to discover what works
best for that body type. Right.
Tyson's a perfect example of exactly.
They thought you couldn't
make it in the pools. It's,
I know he's going to get
killed in the pros. Right?
There's never been a short guy. When when
Ali was dancing around, people are like,
no,
that's not going to work.
He's going to get tired when
he goes to the heavyweights.
Heavyweight shouldn't bounce around,
and at least to spar a
lot with lightweights,
he sparse six rounds with light weights,
then six rounds with a heavyweight. Why?
Because he would play tag
with a lightweight. It just
about speed and movement.
You move twice as much with a lightweight.