I was in,
Oh shit.
For Breezy over doom got flat and he
was just going to fight in Russia,
I think against all neck. Yeah, yeah, Yup.
Well that's not happening. It's a wrap.
That's a wrap on that.
Well,
he's 40 years old trying to him to
compete in something that's a young man's
game. That's the thing.
It's like you can get mad,
you can get outraged and
that's a reasonable result
are reasonable response if
you want. But if you
rationalize, if you have empathy,
it's like this guy still wants to do this
thing that his body won't allow him to
do and so he's willing to,
to bend the rules to attempt it.
He failed and now he's going to
have to pay the consequences. Yeah.
It's a month after his knock
out. Lost a Volkov. Right.
Volkov fuck to mom.
Dangerous there guys.
Fucking dangerous be a long tall knockout
artist to heavyweight thing is a whole
other thing. I hold the thing, man.
And when you get these seven footers
that can kick ass like Volkov.
That's a fucking nightmare. What does he
like? He's at least six 11 right? Scary.
He's a big guys bigger than than for
doing by a, lots of call it six, six, six,
seven, somewhere in that range.
Right. For Dumas, let's six four,
somewhere around that.
And have you ever met Brett Rogers
who's Brett Rogers and now Brett Rodgers
fought? Uh, uh, Brett Grim
Rogers, yeah. Yeah. Was a fire.
That guy, that's the biggest
person I've ever met. Really? Yeah.
Like I don't know what
it was about his frame,
but I was trying to interview and it's
only six, nine or six, eight or something.
But it was the physical frame of him
and I was just like, it was so wild.
It's a triple h and a restaurant one time
and I was like, whoa, like giant dude.
He's big,
big athletes like this.
Like what the force that they can
generate like in Gannon, that ability to,
to create that type of power and impact.
This is a crazy picture of Afghanistan
and extra professional basketball player
and a god who looks like a tiny person.
So weird. It got who it looks like.
I look when I stand next to him.
Not quite as much contrast,
but pretty ridiculous, but there it
is. Look at that. That's, I mean,
that's fucking crazy. We just,
there's, there's more always,
but I have a Chihuahua and a
Chihuahua, and you have your, your doc,
you put them beside each other and you're
like, that can't be the same species.
I know. It's weird. Right? Then humans
are just like dogs and that way, you know,
we vary so wildly in her size.