The Joe Rogan experience.
No, it was a fun show, man.
I went into the mosh pit Israel before
that song before they called the stuff
for that song for most of their settles
in the mosh pit and there was you, USC,
uh, frontline men down
there rec and in the mosque.
I was in there with them.
They were protected me. I
was like, Oh shit, be real.
You're up it up. Like, yeah, were good
shop together. It was. It was awesome.
There's a video of Dana
white in a mosh pit once.
I don't know what the
fuck he was thinking.
He must have been truck jumped
in the mosh pit like years ago.
He's a big dude though.
He's a big dude.
But he's jumping around and their
motion around. Yeah. I dated a girl,
got killed in a mosh pit
once. It's, it's crazy man.
I used to go into a lot of different
mosh pits in there. He's in the rage.
Mosh pit. Yeah, the rates is
safe, but every now and that,
and you're running into a Dickhead,
I'll tell you man,
that the craziest mosh
pits, you know, that I saw,
well the craziest mosh pits I've gotten
into, there was Olympus get mosh pit.
That was crazy. And, but the
craziest was was the rage mosh pit.
But the ones that I seen from outside of
it not being in it that were crazy was
there was a sound garden
mosh pit then. Yeah. At,
at Lollapalooza early on it was, uh,
when they had bad motor finger out.
Oh Man.
That fucking mosh pit was
like a whirlpool of chaos bro.
I was loving it. And that was
on mushrooms watching this shit.
So fucking amazing.
And then,
and then a slayer mosh pit man.
They're fucking shit is brutal. Yeah,
that sounds like they're just
the pace of slayer. It's crazy.
But I got to tell you, since joining
profits of rage in us, you know,
when we tour Europe and stuff like that
and we'd do a combination of, you know,
uh, rage against the machine songs, public
enemy and Cypress Hill along with our,
our own material,
the mosh pits are fucking crazy.
But you know, there was one, one, one
thing that I saw that was not brutal,
but it was cool as fuck. And it was in,
um, I think, I believe it was weeding or,
or Switzerland, but they,
you know, out of like the 60,
70,000 people that were out there,
there was like maybe 5,000 concentrated
people who sat down on their ass.
Right. And we're like, the fuck are
these people doing? I don't know. Like,
are they protesting? Are
Separate, fuck is going on. Right.
And what was crazy is, you know, you,
you're not going to stop playing.
You just keep going.
So we start on, on, um,
I believe the song was going real gorilla
radio that we were playing at that,
that point. All of a sudden we see
him start doing this. The Rowan,
they were wrote it. It was like a
viking row. It was a fucking move.
It was a move that the crowd was doing.
So there's five,
5,000 people out of the 30,000
that are sitting in, you know,
like next to each other
lines, rows, you know,
just fucking of people rowing on beat dog.
It was the
fucking vikings man. How crazy that
the DNA just stuck with those people.
And that was just the little section of
it, man. If you were to see from stage,
Daryl was like,
it was spot like spotted groups and
they sat down and they sat down and were
rowing. It's so fucking crazy. Yeah.
Have you ever seen the,
there was a,
they did a viking chant once at a
soccer game. Crazy. Aw Man. It's wild.
Cause a whole fucking arena did it and
you feel it. You like Yo, that shit.
Whoo. You gotta think man, when
they were going to wars back in the,
they rallied all their guys
up just like that. That yeah.
Fuck fucking roller out of tune though.
This fucking bolt's going to go sideways.
You don't, I don't, I don't know
where that moved comes from,
but it looks cool when he sealed as fuck.
It's gotta be an old school viking thing.
They'll probably do it when
they get drunk. Yeah. I mean,
you know, think about it.
You know they used to
conquest motherfuckers so
they're were like fucking row
and throw it around.
Imagine here it like,
see if you can find that the Viking
one at a soccer game. Cause it's like,
I think it's at a world cup or something
like that. But they're like, no,
you hear it in the crowd and he like,
oh my God.
Imagine hearing that shit over the,
when they're coming to get you towards
your village, like grabbed the baby.
We're going to live in the woods. Fuck
you. Gotta get Outta here. Yeah. Yeah.
And those are big
dude's. Yeah, here it is. Oh
look at that dog tuned in it
together, man. They're all insane.
Look at the hands.
That's spooky.
Yeah man. His mother fuckers,
if somebody reignites them,
imagine that they would take over
the world. There's enough of them.
Imagine that Hoard Cup and that shit
on my fucking crazy line of DNA.
You know a line of people that just
were conquerors, sturdy motherfuckers,
sturdy giant motherfuckers who
did mushrooms. Yeah, they would.
They would glaze up mushroom,
their fucking heads into oblivion and
just COPD slash people go get him.
It's crazy, man. This is
another one sitting. Other one.
So that's like
thing.
I guess the NFL Vikings sort
of adopted this recently.
They do it in their football games.
Yeah.
We'll look at that dork with the glasses.
Put Your fucking hands down, man. Stop.
Listen Bro. A Viking breach
had to figure out who beat you.
Stop that. Sorry. Look. He's
like, Oh, you, he'll hire you
like at it. He's a spiking.