Are Robots going to destroy us?
That's a very good question and that's
something that Elon Musk is actually
scared of. Really? Yeah. He stopped a
little, Deval says it's going to happen.
He's a very intelligent guy to just,
besides making a good record,
he talks about us essentially
replacing each other where robots soon.
It's entirely possible. The Way
Elon Musk looks at it is that he's,
he was trying to warn people,
but they weren't listening and that
there's no telling how powerful they could
get once they become sentient,
once they start taking control of their
own destiny and creating new robots and,
and just deciding whether or not we
live or die and how they're going to run
things, they're essentially,
they're going to become a life form,
an artificial life form that's way fucking
smarter than us. Yeah. And he's saying,
do you think it's smart to
army things they've seen?
It's smart to make this like
he's looking at in terms of, uh,
he's the tip of the spear.
Right.
And it comes to technology and
an implementation of it. I mean,
think about who this guy is,
right.
If he's the one who's telling you
everybody's kind of slow the fuck down.
This is dangerous. You literally might
be making a terminator movie here.
You literally might be making
a terminator movie. Yeah,
we have to worry because we,
when were you were saying that
you think we evolved from monkeys?
We evolved from some lower thing. Well,
the idea is that we got to keep going.
Well,
if we might hit a biological bottleneck
and that might be the whole convergence
of humans and technology,
that might be what it's all about.
Like biologically this system
doesn't move fast enough,
but if we can transcend this and move
into some sort of a digital life,
that life,
we can accelerate all of the innovation,
all of the improvements in insane
numbers like years traveled through time
change the fucking,
the nature of life itself.
That's going to probably be one
of the stages of our future.
Whether it's a thousand years from now
or a hundred thousand years from now.
It seems to me like with this adoption
of science and into our daily lives in
terms of like the technologies
that we're all addicted to,
phones and tablets and all these
different things often say,
he says that we're a Cyborg is
already in your extension. These are,
this is just a rudimentary way.
Yeah, he's ready for sure. Right.
You already living people already
living through this. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
And he's also coming out with
something called neuro link.
I don't exactly know what it was.
He was very vague about it,
but he was saying he was going to
change the bandwidth to change your,
your like your ability
to access information and
people are going to wear it.
You know where this thing on your head,
it's going to literally charge up your
fucking brain. Some strange, strange days.
He couldn't,
he couldn't explain too much about it,
but he was saying it was gonna
come out in a few months.
Like what nef fuck man were we were,
you know,
30 or 40 years away from being
unrecognizable. That's what I think.
I think we're 30 or 40 years
away from being living in.
What's it look the time
living in a virtual world,
half the time live in an augmented world.
I think people are going to exist in
these weird worlds where it feels real and
isn't. I think they're going to come
out with programs that are fun at first,
but then become life consuming.
Where you put on these fucking goggles
and this suit and you go into this world
and you live with these in and interact.
We touch each other,
but no one's there physically, but you
feel like you are and it's magical.
You're like, you're living
in Avatar, you're on Pandora.
You're hanging out with the blue
people. Gotcha. Yeah. You with the Navi,
that shit could happen.
You could literally get to a point where
you believe you were there or we could
be there now. We could be there. Yeah.
That's a sneaky, sneaky argument,
right? Yeah, but that, that's, that's the
truth of it all. It is a truth. Right?
It could be. We could be there. We
could be a part of a simulation. Yeah.
That's another thing that you want
on my son. I'm like, God damn it.
You're supposed to say no. You're
supposed to say no. It's impossible.
It could all be fake. Yeah. Deja.
Could peach us a glitch? Yeah, sure.
So I just try to live
like my grandpa's said,
just enjoy a regular
shit as much as you can.