Be so good. He's so good in
everything. Looks so young there.
While he was man, man. Oh Man.
What a fucking movie this was.
Cause I wanted to believe so bad.
Yeah.
I so wanted to believe they got me.
Hey, did you talk about Spielberg?
Did you talk about that alien craft
that came into her? What happened?
We tend to our galaxy. It did then it
won't the Hawaiian name. Oh, so it's over.
You didn't hear about that one. The
one that looks like a joint. Yeah,
it looks like or a big piece of poop.
Yeah. That's just a real big duty copter.
It's just a weird rock. I
think. Now they said that, uh,
some like legit people said that it
changed speed and went in different
directions and people, legit
people. Scientists. Oh,
them guys said that it was a, it
could be something. Mm. Could be,
what does Neil degrasse say about it?
He's not talking right now.
Yeah. He's in a little bit
of a kerfuffle. Kerfuffle.
What's his Jame Harvard scientists say
aliens makes plain bizarre interstellar
object. Yeah. I saw that. And then I
saw someone refuting the scientists.
Harvard. Nobody wants to believe more than
me, bro. Come on Joe. It's real. Well,
if I was going to mask my spaceship
to fly through the galaxy,
I would definitely make it look like a
big rock. Like a big asteroid. Right.
Why wouldn't you driving through space
may. Maybe what they were like, look,
if we just make this thing drive
by them and don't change speeds,
they'll now have no idea.
They just think we're in the store and
they'd be psyched that we miss them. Okay.
Yeah. Good call. Good call. Someone just
hits the gas. I'm tired. I don't want it.
It's fucking taking too long.
Which he just decides. You got it.
The fucking cops are behind is
Dave Shit. God dammit. Dave,
you're not supposed to just
take off 65 you fuck that.
Start throwing this weed out the window.
Why would it be so hard to believe a
space rock traveling through space?
That would be the move, right?
I mean if they are so advanced,
they can travel through galaxies.
They can make the shit look
like anything they want it to.
Why when you doll it up,
radiation pressure.
The only thing separating Thor's would be,
well there's no air and space,
right? So it wouldn't be aerodynamics.
What would it be? Momentum. No,
go down a little bit.
Take it answers your question.
If radiation pressure is the accelerating
forest then own Mo Momma represents a
new class of thin interstellar material.
Whoa.
It has a different thing for energy.
What as to what may have produced
this previously unseen material,
it could have emerged naturally from the
debris of the planet forming disk in a
distant solar system going
through yet an unknown process.
They've got a whole nother way to makes,
we went from Toyota
Corollas to this thing.
Imagine if that's what we find. The only
thing that I think what it does, the um,
the like a rock, right? Rock hat is not
smooth, but it doesn't necessarily need,
this is where I'm stupid. This is one
of one of many places where I'm stupid,
but it doesn't necessarily
need to be aerodynamic. Right?
Cause it's not going through air. It's
called you the vacuum of space. Right?
Exactly. So I'm not wrong there.
It could actually look like a rock.
It could be the only issue would
be getting it into space. Right.
The aerodynamics is assuming that
you shooting it from a planet with an
atmosphere. Again, gravity not be talking
about this way too stupid. No, let's go.
Let's keep, let's keep going on
about if you shot, if you'd like,
if you're launching it from
Earth into space, right? Yeah.
What if you had it in cased
in like this outer area,
sort of like the space shuttle is,
but then once you get to a place you
could jettison the outside of it.
Just like they get rid of
those booster rocket fall off.
They just fall into the fucking
land on people. Whether fishing,
that's has to happen. Right. When she
getting killed by a booster rocket,
flat space, even in the face it didn't
do great, but then they could do that.
They could release the shell and then
they would just have the rock and the rock
would move through space.
And it didn't matter what shape it
was cause it's in the vacuum of space.
We just get it up into orbit,
orbit like uh, the space station.
Go and build it in pieces
and then launch it.
Do you remember when that Commander Chris
Hadfield gentlemen was on the podcast
and he was talking about some kind
of magnet that they have that uh,
collects subatomic particles out there
in the galaxy and that we only know 5% of
what the universe is made out of?
Oh my God.
Talking about things like
dark matter and he was 5%.
It's the guys scientist space,
a real legit astronaut coming back from
six months in space or whatever the fuck
he was there for. And telling
us this, we're like, wow, what
we've talked about that like you can hang
with those guys for a little while and
then you're like, I don't understand
what's happening now. Well it's also the,
I mean it's amazing what we do know,
amazing that they can send a guy to space
and have them fly around the ISS or,
yeah.
I mean,
we'll talk about what you were saying
about why are we here and what are we
doing?
Like we haven't developed yet.
Something that you can go the uh,
the speed of light we haven't like,
but if we do, then the whole universe
is open to us. Maybe that's what it is.
Maybe the struggle of developing all this
stuff is to get to a scientific level
where we can really go.
I don't think they think the speed of
light is even good enough. Really. Yeah,
I think, damn it, that was my goal.
I think that like if you wanted to have
options available as to what planet
you're gonna colonize, you
going to have to, who knows?
Like what have you landed on the planet,
what did he land on a planet?
And it's like, Hey, it's 74 degrees out
guys. Guys, it's all oxygen and nitrogen.
It's just like earth. Come on
out here. Come on out of here.
But it's only been like that for
10 years and then it's a cycle.
It's really fucked up. Like 30 years
from now it's going to be a nice age.
And then all of people have moved there
and they're going to freeze to death.
It's going to be no food at all plan.
It doesn't give a fuck.
My Dad does all our science led us to
that. I don't even know if we can predict,
here's my question.
Can they accurately predict the atmosphere
and the conditions and like what the
temperature would be if
a planet is from a son,
like do they have a
calculation where they say, oh,
this sun is this amount of big and
this planet, it was this far away,
so it's definitely going to stay within
a certain temperature range for the
entire time that the planet, did they
know that like within like a death range.
I don't know greys. That
range is 40 degrees, bro.
Yeah. You get to 140 that's a
wrap. Yeah. You're done. Yeah,
so like hundreds would make
it 140 everyone's dead. Right?
You live in in a sauna,
you're going to run out of water.
I just don't think we're going to make it.