But now I'm more the,
uh,
thing I've become obsessed with lately
is there's a skepticism about Ufos.
Yeah. That's why I want to talk to you
about this because you told me that you've
become obsessed with Ufo is recently. Oh
yeah. Completely. And it's like, yeah,
totally. Really? Yeah, totally
believe the UFO phenomenon is real.
I don't know what it is, but it's totally,
it has to be real. Some things happened.
Why is that? Because there's just way
too much evidence that it is real.
What evidence? Uh, well, uh,
radar evidence, uh, that the,
the f 16 locked on a Ufo, that
footage and also just, uh,
like I know that friend of ours,
I don't know if she wants to say it,
but her father was an air
traffic controller and he
told her, they said, yeah,
every air traffic controller
has seen something. Yeah.
And I had another friend whose father
was in a commercial pilot and she said,
yeah,
my dad said every single pilot has seen
something and they've all been told not
to say anything about it. We got a couple
of friends that say they were a like,
yeah,
you know,
the abducted one is a little easier to
wrap your head around because when you're
sleeping, your brain is producing all
sorts of indogenous psychedelic chemicals.
Yeah. Almost all of these experiences
happen when you're sleeping.
Almost all these experience,
when these people were abducted,
they're taken from their beds, which
is when they're dreaming. I mean,
it's just like there's some real clear,
easy steps to follow up on a fall Ockham's
razor and not, you're not get crazy,
but it knocks those out,
but it doesn't knock out like Barney and
Betty Hill and all the people that are
abducted will fully conscious and that
and that remember it without hypnotherapy.
I'm like, I'm not sure about
the abduction phenomenon,
but I don't know Barney and Betty Hill.
I know the story, but I don't know them.
Yeah,
so I would have to know them because
there's a lot of people that I've taught,
like I did a show for Scifi,
I called Joe Rogan questions.
Everything that cured me and show
cured me of a lot of my nonsense with,
with conspiracies when we used
to talk about it. Yes. Yeah.
That stuff all the time. All
the time. Yeah. Yeah. But I,
I needed to actually study it. So for
six months, that's basically all I did.
I interviewed people and
I like big foot believers,
Ufo believers,
and the one thing that they have in
common is they all seem to be kind of lost
and dependent upon this thing being
real. Yeah. Instead of being objective.
There's only one lady that I interviewed
that saw big foot that really seemed to
be telling the truth,
but I think she saw bear bear's
walk on two feet all the time.
They do it all the time. It's video
footage. You can find it all the time.
And she was in the Pacific northwest,
which is incredibly dense woods.
You see something, you'd glimpse
it. Look, I was hunting once in, in,
in Canada and Alberta, and I thought
I saw a wolf for like two seconds.
It was a squirrel. Okay, I understand
this. This is what does that note,
squirrel? Yeah. No, I just saw
far. Right. I saw it for and I was,
because it's really dense was cause I was
looking for fucking wolves cause I was
like,
cause I know we did see one wolf.
It crossed the road is either wolf or
coyote was hard to tell cause it was
at dusk. It was very dark out. But
um, when you're looking for something,
you think everything is that thing
you're looking for. Yeah. So for like a,
for a second, a huge thought that fucking
squirrel was a wolf. That's funny. Yeah.
Well the expectation and perception
are very linked. Yes. Yes.
Well this is also that they've found that,
uh,
that 50% of everything you see is
a product of memory. Yes. That,
that when you observe something,
they've done FM,
FM ris and that most of the activity
in the brain is in the memory centers,
not in the, uh, visual speakers.
Only about 50% of the activities
and the visual centers of the brain.
That's crazy thing is
very, I, when I was a kid,
I went and saw Carl Sagan speak at u of
t at the University of Toronto and I was
like,
you know,
14 but he did an equation on the board
of the possibility of an alien life other
than us in the universe.
And it came to the smallest.
I mean he spent the whole time writing
on this chalkboard. It was fascinating.
They actually came up with a number
at the end and it was such a small,
he says there is,
there is something out there,
but they are so far away that they'll,
that unless they can go faster
than the speed of light,
which he said was impossible at the
time. Yeah. The Seventies. Yeah.
Uh, there's no way we've seen
them. That's what he said.
So if some other beings have
conquered the speed of light thing,
then maybe we could see them.
Yeah.
But that's a thing with the exact problem
with his skepticism in general is like
that it, you know, like,
like the skeptics, skeptics
of the, of the 19th century,
the ones who said germs don't exist.
Right. Because we can't see them.
And people who've said germs did exist
were ridiculed and laughed out of the
trade. Right. And, um, I, I
agree with you completely.
Just because you can't see
it or it isn't happening.
It doesn't mean it can't happen.
And even since sagans day there had been
no exoplanets discovered then we now
know there are literally trillions and
trillions of sure planet earth like
planets.
Yeah.
Well they just speculated as to the
existence of them outside of our source
system before the, the real problem is
that if some, there's a leap and a leap,
a technological leap that opens the doors
to massive innovation that once this
happens,
once this happens in this,
and then all this stuff sort
of exponentially expands
in terms of technological
possibilities,
all you would need is a few hundred years
and you have an unrecognizable set of
technology. Yeah, sure. I mean
we were talking about certain,
I mean the whole anti matter idea that
they're still trying to figure out,
uh,
that's an insane sorts of energy.
You have never even experienced,
you know,
with them with a grain of sand. And
you can run a city and it was that big.
Yeah. And then there's also
the theory, there's reason one,
that space time itself doesn't exist.
So the,
the speed of light barrier
becomes moot because that is,
I guess it's the holographic
quantum hologram theory,
quantum holographic theory of
the universe, Talbot's book. Uh,
I can't remember holographic
universe, but it's, yeah, I think so.
But the idea that the universe is
basically just a geometry that,
that when you look at it from a certain
angle seems three dimensional and it
folds [inaudible] folds into itself.
So you could, and it's travel.
That's the wormhole thing. And it's not
even that, it's the idea that, that,
that space time is an
illusion is, uh, and that,
that it doesn't really exist. And
that's why, uh, you know, like, uh, uh,
entanglement is possible. You know,
the idea that, you know, spooky,
spooky action at a distance that
a quantum entanglement. Yeah.
But the reason that you know,
you know, uh, these, you know,
Adam's on opposite ends of the universe
can be affect each other instantaneously,
is cause they're not really at
an opposite ends of the universe.
They're really right next to each other.
It just seems like they're at opposite
ends of the universe because our ability
to perceive is basically based on what
we have to do to stay alive on this
planet. So our meager little
chimp brains, you have trying to,
trying to quantify all of these things
that are around us all the time.
So we put them into this sort of three
dimensional box of movement and distance
and that the entire,
the entire universe could be a
compact thing that projects itself,
like a hologram onto a screen.
I love these kinds of conversations
because I'm clearly too stupid to really
understand what I don't
understand anything I just
said and I don't understand
you too. So how stupid does that make
me? Well, we don't understand each other.
We're all the same.
Yeah, that's what I like.
I think it'd be interesting to do a
documentary or something about, uh,
about Ufo ology.
Cause if one thing is the assumption
that they're extra terrestrial is an
assumption,
but I think it intrigues me is
the power of ridicule to silence.
Even the most intelligent people in our
community from examining something like
the ridicule kept doctors
from accepting germs. Sure.
Because they didn't want to, they didn't
want to be ridiculed by their peers.
And even now you've got people that will,
like Michael Shermer will cling to the
most absurd explanations for phenomena
like the f 16 a radar
footage. Uh, what did he,
what was Michael Shermer, I can't even
remember, but it was, it was pretty,
it really went to great lengths
that entailed having to basically,
uh,
diminish any respect you had for any of
the people who reported on the events.
It had to go and had to go into character
assassination in order to eliminate it.
Yeah.
He was the best way to kill an idea.
He's a professional skeptic and I like
Michael a lot and he's been on the
podcast may times.
I actually had him debate Randall Carlson
and um,
Graham Hancock about these ancient
civilizations and it wasn't very good for
them. Like there's some clunky
moments cause skeptics are believers.
Well the problem is, Scott, the
problem is being a skeptic itself,
it's a stupid way to look at the world.
You're actually sure about something.
I mean, you shouldn't be objective,
right? It wouldn't, don't be skeptical.
Being skeptical is like, I don't know.
But I know for sure that that's not true.
But it serves a massive purpose for
people that really don't understand things
and he can explain it to you.
And with actual science,
as long as the actual science
is being used and it's not,
character assassination is not
mockery. It's not, it's not.
There's certain people
that are just debunkers,
they can call themselves skeptics, but
they're not looking at things like, oh,
maybe that is effective. Maybe that is
healthy. That is interesting. And No,
they don't look at it that way.
They're looking at,
they're trying to pick it apart.
And that's fine if you can pick it apart.
But if you cannot, you have to be
objective about the fact that, oh,
well this is a very interesting
phenomenon and this is what we know about
science is that, and this is what we know
about this thing. And right now we have,
we have a weird conundrum. Chariots
of the gods. And did he end up on kid?
Was He, was, he believed
that hundred percent.
He's all is still in all in. I asked
him, the first thing I asked him, I said,
what is desperately have to go
pee go. The first thing I, uh,
asked him was what is the most
compelling piece of evidence does that,
you know, and he pointed to this, um,
a Mayan stone plaque
that's in [inaudible].
I'm gonna have you ever seen it? It's
a, it's in the book. Yeah. It's a, God,
uh, one of their, um,
one of their former kings that
is lying on his back and he's,
it looks like he's moving some, see
Jamie, see if we could find that thing.
It's just really cool,
uh,
carving that they found that looks
like there's a guy who is in a seat.
And it looks like there's fire
behind his back. And you could say,
you could say that he's manipulating
controls on a ship and he's, you know,
shooting a rocket into the heaven.
I would like to see what the s,
the mainstream version of that is. Because
it also, it could just be art, you know,
I'm imagining being, yeah,
it could be that they,
they knew about certain things being
propelled by fire. There it is. Yep.
That's it.
So if you see this,
I mean that's a big ass stretch
to say that guy's in a spaceship.
I don't know what the fuck that is. He's
sitting down Altera kind of. He could,
yeah, but it doesn't look
like he's looking through
an ips. Right. What's true,
but what does that mean? Is
it a telescope? Maybe he's
just kind of telescope,
but maybe they just an
astronomer. Yeah, it is possible.
I don't think they had telescopes.
I don't think it telescope
was even invented till, no.
Do they even have a glass
at that point? Oh No. Well,
I don't know if the Mayans did. Wow. But,
but that was his number one piece
of evidence was while Alan was like,
that's kind of silly when we were
kids in the seventies the, you know,
big foot,
you know,
and cherry to the gods and everything
was so new and look at this image,
look at the bottom of it.
Even the part where the flame supposed
to be coming out from below him.
Which Flint, where's the flame?
The flame is the shit. The very,
very bottom.
But I mean I'm not even sure I buy that.
If you were going to draw fire, you do a
really shitty job. If that's your fire,
that doesn't really look like fire
to me. Could be anything. Right?
If, if that's fire, like what is all the
stuff around them? What's all that stuff?
Is that, that looks kind of
mechanical though, right?
It looks like there's bolts does.
If they have a fire,
God maybe they drew the fire.
God,
it looks like a monkey kind of face
with titties. Monkey's got some titties.
Oh now I get it right. And then
the monkeys, is that his teeth?
It's the first tutors arms.
Actually it does. It could be armed.
But th that's the point is
it's so open to interpretation.
There's so much that you could
see if you're looking to see.
But what I do see is this guy who's,
he's reclining and chilling and it looks
like he's looking through something.
What's that thing hanging across him?
You see that thing across his arm.
But here's the thing, I don't think
anybody knows what the fuck that is.
But so for him to say that this was the
number one most compelling evidence,
I mean, where people getting
high at this point? Oh yeah.
So I mean that could be just some guy
got high and LSD. Yeah, they were,
they were taking different kinds of
plants that had like search like acid in
them. So what is this
obsessing? What is your,
your more recent obsessing about Ufo
is, what's the origin of this? Well,
part of it is just the fact that,
that the evidence,
just the evidence itself says you have
to take this seriously and yet no one
does a, or very, very few people
do. And even like I, again,
that f 16 footage that even Neil degrasse
Tyson who is a great skeptic said,
uh, on one of the late night
talk show, he said, well,
if you really want to look
at the possibility of some
a non human intelligence,
that f 16 stuff is pretty compelling.
What is the fcoe STD stuff?
That's the stuff that, uh,
to the stars academy put out. It
was the CIA Tom Delonge. He's crazy.
I had never met on the podcast.
Yeah, very nice guy. What do you see?
And he said she's a very nice guy and a
brilliant musician and he's a loon. Yeah,
I've never met a fucking full on believer.
He left blink one 82 to go do
this to the stars academy. Shit.
He's the biggest goddamn rock
band on the planet. Okay.
Here's something interesting about
this and this was pointed out like by,
um,
okay.
Film video film by fighter jet shows
an unknown object near San Diego.
Video from 2004 was released by
the US Department of Defense. Um,
while the way it moves, there's something
about the way it moves is really weird.
Huh?
Jet Though one of the pilots told the you
immediate the object was not from this
world. Hmm. Yeah. And here's the thing,
it's like the skeptics in order to
dismiss that, they have to go, well,
if I have to make arguments like that,
jet fighters are not better
observers than anyone else.
Pull up Mick wards take on that mic ward,
the guy who he runs deep,
um, uh, what does it met?
A bunk metabolic can runs a debunking
site and he's another one of those guys
that is all in with the,
the conventional explanation goes way
out of his way to not look at anything
that could be yes, yes. Comes Razor says,
you know that if you have to go to great
lengths to dismiss something, right,
that's not falling.
OCKHAM's razor razor says if
the jet pilot says he saw this,
he saw it. I think he had an
interesting take on it though.
And one of the things is there's a time
during the video where the pilot shifted
from one x to two x,
which makes the image a move more
because you're, you have magnification.
Like have you ever use
magnifying glasses by knows?
Like if you use a 15 x by knows it's
very difficult to hold on the sec yet,
but six six you can kind of look at
things in the distance. Yeah. But that's,
if you don't have about about $3 million
worth of stabilization equipment on
your jet and walked onto this object,
right. Which is why that stays in Loc.
He had an explanation then that was kind
of interesting and when it breaks free
of the lock and how does
that got unbelievable.
But can you just take off or something
like that? It just, at one point,
just the opposite, just breaks free
the lock. And that's almost impossible.
I have a clad sound possible for
anything that manage bills to do what?
The quality of cameras today.
Why is this footage so shitty?
Uh, that this is infrared footage?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, do you need this?
When you're shooting at things in the sky,
you can't rely on [inaudible]
when you're looking at heat.
We can't heat signatures visually.
It's so far. It's so far.
It would be gaming the rabbit hole.
How to debunk conspiracy theories
using fact logic and was just so,
what is he saying? What is he saying? Uh,
the program [inaudible] a little
larger for my stupid dies.
Said a for all. He made sure you
were talking about the right video.
There's two that are confused here.
We're talking about the gimbal video,
which is not from the Nimitz incident.
Just discussed here.
So scroll down a little bit.
Uh,
the gimbal video is an okay. Yeah,
that's the one we're looking at.
It's an unknown date and location
from an up from unknown pilots. Nope.
The tick tock one. Some cells
pilots. Yeah, that's 2004. Okay.
That's David Fervor of the media
is discussed. These videos,
Tom Delonge to the stars. The link
contains the frames. What's he saying?
Keep going. Keep going. Keep going.
Uh, the black shape on the object.
Some kind of infrared flare
glare. We know that the shape of
a very bright infrared source,
like the engine of a plane can be
much bigger than the object itself is
explained here. Okay, so this is like a
flare. That's a little, explain the mood.
It doesn't explain. Again I'll
comes razor is, okay, so this guy,
this guy is saying it
looks nothing like it.
Well even if it is a jet, a jet is not
capable of breaking free from the lock.
Right? So lock onto it.
And if you look at that,
you can see the jet and his own example.
Debunks is debunking need not be moving.
Yeah.
The video need not be moving.
The assumption that that this guy doing
probably a few hours research has come
up with something that is more credible
than a trained fighter pilot who was
there and visually seeing it.
What do you think have been tracking?
If you had to guess? I don't
know. Let's get crazy. Oh I
would. I think it is. It is.
It is an intelligent craft is a
craft being piloted intelligently.
Why aren't they talking to us?
We're fucking apes.
And why would you go and talk to us?
We're assholes when you look at it. Yeah,
I forgot. You're right.
Leaving fucking plastic straws
everywhere. Oh, we cured it.
No more plastic straws. When you're
a kid looking at a, an ant colony,
you didn't go listen to me aunts. Yes. You
just looked at them, you know, there was,
and they said, why? Why don't they
go to the White House? We said, well,
why would do when you look at an ant
colony go, I must speak to the queen.
Yes. No, I've always said he
was looking at ants. Yeah.
That's what the most ridiculous
thing about like the old movies,
like the old movies, it would land on
the White House lawn, right? Yeah. Yeah.
That's it. Yeah. Burrata nickname,
whatever that thing was. Yeah.
Clock Lot to burrata. I'd like to
talk nick too. Yeah, that's the, uh,
a day or two still was like,
is that 1940 or 50 50 50 50 fucking great.
Great movie. I watched it really recently
because it's a terrible variables.
A little bit, right. The stories are
great. He was a Christ pair of, well,
his name is John Carpenter.
Oh, I see. That's right.
It was a carpenter shoot
that object out of his hand.
The first second he pulls it out.
I remember he has a thing that's
going to cure cancer. They shoot him,
they shoot him, they shoot it
out of his hand to meeting him.
And then at the end of the movie he is a,
he is killed and resurrected.
That's right. Right. Yeah. They
shoot him. He's taken the robot.
The robot. That robot robot.
Yeah. Very tall. Yeah.
And like he looks like you would
want a robot to look in 1950.
Yes. Yeah. All metal and shits
moves. Yeah. Chrome. Yeah.
Those,
those were the days we thought that they
would communicate like it wasn't there
a whole rash of them that we're seeing
over Washington DC. Yeah, there was, yeah.
There was dozens,
dozens of Ufos tracked and admitted by
the government that they were tracking
them and watching them.
But they, uh, essentially,
and then at the end of their
explanation was, yeah. Nothing,
nothing particularly important.
You know,
we have a mutual friend who
claims won't say her name,
but she called and I wrote her off as
a lunatic when I first started. Yeah,
well she was claimed to be adopted and
then I was doing a show with her years
ago and she just telling us
the story. We're all like
a, Huh, that's pretty funny.
And she says it and they took a scoop
out of my back and I'm like a scoop.
They took a scoop out of your back
and she showed on her back shoulder.
There was a hexagon,
old diamond shaped scoop out of her back.
Uh, a divot that hexagon.
Yeah. That was clearly,
clearly and no scar tissue. Maybe she's
a crazy bitch. No scar tissue, man.
Yeah, give myself a little punch,
but I hole punch back there.
Worked at a bookstore at the time years
ago and I went into the alien section
was the world's biggest bookstore
in Toronto. It was the name of it.
And of course I went to the alien
section and just look all this crap up
immediately.
And there are other people with the scope.
Well there's a lot of other people with,
you know,
abduction stories and some of them have
like little pieces of something in their
body. I remember you talking to me about
this many, many years ago. I was like, oh,
well Dave's interested.
It was like implants.
You're talking about people that have
alien implants in their body. Yeah.
And that's the thing is,
to me it's just,
I guess the thing that I'm kind of
obsessed with now is just the cause we're
comedians. Yes. And the
power of ridicule, uh,
to silence, debate is
unbelievably potent. Sure.
And we're part of that. We're part
of the machinery that was used very,
very consciously by the
government to silence any inquiry.
You know, it was like, you
know, feeding it, you know,
feeding the story the right way
to late night talk show hosts,
made it so that nobody
would talk about it.
So do you think that the government
consciously fed those ideas to like Johnny
Carson and those folks? There's
documentation of a, of a pro, you know,
of that they, you know, to, uh,
to make the UFO phenomena ridiculous.
Do you think they did that to avoid
mass hysteria? Like if you are,
you're the government and you know,
there's nothing out there,
but you see these people freaking
out and go, okay, look, we've looked,
we've used all of our military might,
all of our scientific power and we
don't see shit. I'm not buying this,
but these people were freaking out.
This has the real potential to get
out of hand and go sideways on us.
Let's just start making fun of
this. Yeah. I don't know. Cause, uh,
I think it's more likely that there's
something there that they feel powerless
to control.
Do you think Kennedy was taken down into
the basement of whatever and shown the
alien sitting there and what I say
about aliens with in regards to Trump,
if there's anybody that would
fucking tell us it's hair,
he tweeted it tweeted immediately
tweet it. Tweet economic aliens.
You Fo's are real. But
CNN is fake. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
It's still the failing New York Times
sales define you at Bose right back at
area 51.
If the government does have the evidence,
they're never going to show it to Trump.
That's the problem.
Like what the fuck's the point being
president if you can't find it. Yeah.
If I knew that to become president
meant you get all the access to Ufos,
I might go. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So
very good. I'm going to try for that.
The presidents who have tried haven't
gotten there. No, no one gets it.
Like Jimmy Carter, Jimmy Carter
said he was, he, he's, he
had a Ufo experience. Yeah.
He saw something, right? Yeah.
He said he saw something,
but see that was back in the 70s
where everybody was seeing shit.
They were all talking about things was
part of the zeitgeists people were legit,
like after close encounters
of the third kind,
especially people who legitimately
thinking that aliens were going to come.
Yeah.
He proposed such a possible
scenario and that movie was so good.
Yeah. Anything you expected it was going
to be. But like I was going to say,
here's like another example
is like the Rendlesham, like,
like that explanation of the
sixteens locked, you know, footage,
uh,
like Rendlesham forest where the,
they claimed that these American
soldiers in the woods, out in England,
uh,
mistook the light,
a light house light for a spacecraft
that they were within 20 feet of a craft
that they saw and took notes on
different lines of yeah. They walk,
not even like right up against it.
And he wrote down notes all like different
set of hieroglyphs on the ship itself
described it's, you know,
described the, the feel of it,
this electrostatic feel
of being around it.
And the official
explanation was they missed,
took a lighthouse several
miles away for this spacecraft.
So I'll comes razor against us.
That's hard to believe that these trained
observers and that's the other thing.
They always tried to dismiss the idea
that trained observers are better
observers. Um, but they
are better observers. Sure.
In the age of today where everyone has a
high definition camera in their pocket.
Have you taken, have you taken a
photograph of the moon on your,
on your phones comes out sick? It doesn't
look like the moon. What's true, right.
There's no details. It comes out of
the lung. The lenses are too wide, but,
but I'll comes. Razors has all right,
they saw something but they, you know,
cause what is the likelihood that trained
observers who have been on this base
for years on this night would mistake a
lighthouse that they've seen every night
for the entire time they've
been on this base for a Ufo?
I mean, what is the likelihood
that that explanation is correct?
I'm not aware of that store. Oh,
Rendlesham forest. Yeah. How'd he say it?
Bent Woods. Uh, Rendlesham and r. E n d.
L. E. S. H. A. M. Rendlesham
forest bandwidths.
It was two nights to get character
actor on Colombo. Where are you up for?
You have an of his own and
it's a nuclear installations.
Rendlesham forest and nuclear
installations are always
ripe with Ufo stories.
Yeah. What year was this? Ah,
this was in the 80s. Yeah.
Mm. Interesting. And it's,
you know, and it said,
obviously the obvious explanation
is we're not the expert. You're,
the only thing you can accept is that
these observers saw something. Right.
You described it accurately.
Is it something that had crashed,
if you want to say that? No,
it came down was, was, uh,
landed in the forest and,
and took off.
What do you think of the [inaudible]
case the night before that? Roswell.
I think it's probably true where
he'll, you're all in. Yeah.
Well David on about it.
But I mean, because the
interesting again, because the,
because the cover stories for our so
much less believable than an alien. Yeah.
I just, I would joke about it. Yeah.
They put it on the paper that they've
recovered a crashed Ufo and alien bodies
and the next day set up,
we made a mistake. It was
just a balloon. What about,
what about the aliens? Those Mexicans,
Mexicans, they were drinking,
apparently they thought the
balloon was opinion, Yada.
They got a little crazy in right now.
But, uh, we just invented some new stuff.
Yeah. Out of nowhere. And then 30
years later they go, oh, we were,
they were high altitude a dummies
that we were dropping. That's right.
To test how they would fall. And that
was, we have lasers and visibility cloaks.
Well the, they showed up again the next
day with a bunch of weather balloons,
scraps and they're like, look,
this is what the guy holding it up.
Like what they don't tell you is that
they flew the wreckage out to Wright
Patterson air force in two separate planes
and the Truman met them there. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I mean, yeah,
the more rational who separate planes
because they were worried that one would
crash the,
the weather,
the weather balloon thing is not as
rational as something weird happened.
I listen to, I want it to be alien
so bad. Oh, I questioned myself.
So that's my problem. I want to do that
stuff. But I again, I, I won't, like,
I'll be skeptical about stuff that just
seems crazy or people that, you know,
Billy,
you know,
sort of ascribe some sort of metaphysical
explanation for all of his, uh, my,
my thing is just,
well,
if the preponderance of the evidence
says something happened but doesn't tell
you what happened right, then you still
have to believe something happened.
Not knowing what happened isn't evidence
that it didn't happen and yet you're
still a flat earthers. Yeah.
Have you looked outside?
It's seems fly.
Yeah.