Her low freak bitches. Yeah. Steven
Crowder wanted to sue me too.
Why do you want to tell you he wanted to
sue me and we were on the same network
for a while on Youtube and it was
called poly pop. And the guy that was,
uh, like my assigned, I forget
what the position is called,
the fucking facilitator or
whatever the fuck he had,
the same one as I did. And
he told me, you know, uh,
that video you made about Steven
Crowder and that, that shit,
cause he got in a fight with some
union guy on footage and he was like,
I was attacked by this union thug.
And I looked at him,
I looked at the footage and I'm like,
wait a minute,
this guy gets up from the ground.
He's facing away from you.
It looked like someone pushed him from
behind because you see the whole video.
Yeah, the beginning of it. The
guy threw a punch at him. Well,
the guy was on the fucking ground.
Uh, one point. Yeah. Like, but he's,
he,
you don't really see what happens with
them when you see the guy threw a punch
at him first. I'm very familiar with the
video. I don't know. I don't, I don't,
I looked at it, I know the
guys in his face. Can we,
can we maybe see the guys in his face?
The guy comes close to him to get into
some sort of a grappling situation with a
guy like physically manhandled
them. I right hold, hold on.
This is on Crowder's channel.
I want to see the,
there's like an unedited
version of this somewhere,
but you could see the full of
altercation when it does happen.
Let's take a leave it on Crowder's
channel. Go scroll ahead a little bit.
I want to get to a,
I'll tell you what.
That's the guy that's the guy that
gets the guy hits him. Oh wait.
It's the guys tell him to back the fuck
up. So he puts his hands and hold on.
And that, that's the guy that fights and
right there, the guy with the mustache,
which guy? The mustache dude. And
you see this guy. Okay. You see that?
Like we don't, there's like a
missing piece of footage there,
but in the footage I saw the,
you don't see that guy attack him first.
You see that guy get up from being
on the ground on his stomach.
I see what you're saying.
So something,
and so when I was thinking is through
the guy that it's Steven Crowder pushed
this guy. I don't know cause you don't,
there's no, there's no footage on there.
But I,
I surmised based on what I looked at
in the footage that this guy was maybe
pushed and then got up and then started
wailing on Crowder. Mm. Interesting.
And I put that out there and
here's the interesting thing.
He said he was going to sue me
for what I said about it. Uh,
he then later went to court and a judge
looked at the footage and kind of came
to the same conclusion I did and said,
I don't think that this went down the
way you're saying based on the footage.
I see.
He lost that court case and then he had
to drop any sort of idea of a lawsuit
against me because the judge had already
ruled that the tape was bullshit.
Didn't really show what
he thought it said Shit.
This is also instances where I challenged
him to debates back in the day.
Not recently, but he, he
would never acknowledge me.
I mean at one time he did send his like
little brother after me. His brother?
Yeah. Like I don't know if it was his
younger brother, his older brother,
I think it was his little brother was
like, you're a fucking faggot or whatever.
I'm like,
why won't your brother debate me?
Because we were at the
time on the same network.
You're saying he's sent them
after you physically? No, no,
just on Twitter. Oh, okay.
You got to get specified.
Sorry.
He didn't get to David's looking at each
other outside of Barr. He didn't come.
He didn't come and try to
fucking fuck me up or anything.
He's just talking shit on Twitter.
Say Talk Shit on Twitter.
You share that Steven's brother. It was
okay. Yeah, it was Steven's brother. But,
but Stephen himself has never taught.
I made several videos about him.
Maybe not several like three. Mm.
Uh, but he's never confronted me.
Poly pop tried to get us to do a
debate at the time. He wouldn't do it.
That seems weird. It's weird because like,
he's mister like, I'm going to go, like,
he just patrolled Janky Burger
the other day, you know, it was,
I thought that was funny. His, his
impression of Janky Yoga is fucking fun.
It is pretty spot on.
The one that he did where he played
Anna and Jank back and forth.
I didn't see that. Oh, fuck it. Pull
it up. He'll let us use it. Look,
I like Steven Crowder. I do. I really do.
I think he's a good guy. I just, you know,
he's like, he's a little bit heavy on
the right wing. He gets a little silly,
but he does some funny shit like this.
And when he crashed genx thing,
like with this, the saddest thing was
how Jank was responding to it. Like he,
he didn't have any sense
of humor about it. Uh,
well Jank obviously takes himself
very seriously for some reason.
I didn't mean any. Do the research.
That's not totally correct.
We'll have it listed a Goc yes,
I agree with you.
Cenk so king much.
That's absolutely right.
When you use the f word,
you know it's real time.
So we have a bunch of people anyway,
you could see it online and he at one
point he's pouring bacon grease down his
mouth. I just thought it was funny. It
was pretty fun. It's, it's, look dude,
I reached out to be able to make fun
of yourself. I recently sat down, uh,
we did this SPEC.
We went and watched a bunch of young
Turks videos so we could put out this
special drunken peasants
versus the young Turks.
A video we shot about five hours of us
watching young Turks videos and just
tearing them apart. And one of the things
I noticed is what Jank we'll do and,
and watch for this, if you've
ever watching this shit, uh,
he'll have his panel say something
that's like super crazy left wing.
Like someone will say it, like animals,
say it or one of the Steven o or whatever,
whoever he's got on, then
make a wits, whatever.
They'll say something that's real far
left wing and then it'll cut to Janke and
Jank.
We'll have more of like a a moderate left
wing opinion and then it'll go back to
them and they'll immediately capitulate to
Jank like, oh yeah, Jank you're, you're,
you're,
what you're saying is way more sensible
than what I said a second ago and I just
saw that pattern recurring
over and over and over again.
So I don't know if that's like
by design or if they're just,
they feel like the need to capitulate
to him because there they'd be scared of
him or something, you know, or,
or what it was definitely a lot
of emotions going on there too.
There's a lot of emotion in the way they
describe things and some people I think
at least initially connected to that,
but then they see where
it gets problematic.
If you're dealing with any like really
serious issue and you want to debate just
the facts like and have your
ducks in a row. The wool,
the wool over my eyes was the,
the Harris debate of course.
I think most people exactly.
That was like the first like major
chink in the chank Ugur armor.
I never know how to
pronounce his first name.
So when you said it that way I was like,
thank you.
You kind of think it's been changing Cenk
in the Jank you've chink in the Jank.
Yeah, there we go. I think he's a
good guy. I like talking to him too.
I just think people handle certain types
of confrontation and disagreements. Um,
and they don't handle them
the best way they could.
And then those things escalate and they
compound and then it becomes who you are
and then you defending who you are and
then you're always trying to argue with
people about who you are and what you've
done. And like that's when you're gone.
Yeah. It's when you're over the
top. It's like we've done that,
we've done that and we've done
this. We've done that. Like, Hey,
you're talking about shit that's happening
in the world. That's all you're doing.
That's all any of us are
doing on anybody's doing it.
Unless you're out there digging
wells in the Congo with Justin wren,
what you're doing is
you're talking about shit.
So if you've got a bunch of people
listening to you talk about shit,
it's just talking about shit.
The end of the day you don't get any
extra points because more people are
listening or more people are watching.
Your point isn't more valid.
Your point still has to stand up
in the marketplace of ideas. Yeah,
and yours is just as valid as his
is just as valid as mine. It just,
if the delivery system is
a bigger delivery system,
it doesn't mean that like
everybody has to stop.
I'd take you into account because
you've had more success in this market.
That's a crazy way of looking at shit.
Sure.
And when him and Alex Jones battle back
and forth between who gets the most
viewers and who has the model like, Holy
Shit, this is ridiculous. Like what,
when did you see when Alex went onto
the stage at south by southwest?
Is that what it was south by southwest? I
think so. Yeah, last year. It's hilarious.
Oh yeah, that was, that was one of the
greatest, uh, uh, trollings of all time.
But a Jen got so mad. I was furious
and a yellow and then that little,
they oppose Saudi Arabia.
A little weasel. Uh,
Jimmy Dore Spitting on,
that's so unfortunate.
And Alex Jones did,
you know,
it's unfortunate that Guy Jimmy
Dore does some good stuff. Yeah.
We've seen some of his stuff too.
If this is a really good to put
some really good videos up, but he,
he's done some really good work.
Yeah, I can't, people aren't perfect.
I don't really care for him. But um, but,
but you recognize that some of
the stuff's really good, right?
I've never seen the stuff that's good. And
maybe, maybe that, maybe it's out there.
I haven't seen it. I've seen him make
some good points. Very good points. Uh,
you know, I, he when he was
covering the whole Milo thing,
he played a very deceptive version of the
Milo clip and he credited us basically
as a podcast and well that's talked
about us is like we're doing this podcast
from a basement somewhere or something.
Meanwhile, isn't it funny that uh,
podcasts like yours, which gets hundreds
of thousands of downloads, I'm sure,
right? Like you, if, if
it was more than that,
he would have to say the
name of the podcast. Right.
Like if it was he was on
the Adam Carolla show,
he would say the Adam Carolla
show. Sure. Cause it's yours.
Even though he knows what it's like,
like I'm not going to give
these guys credit. And you know,
a lot of the media did
that to us. I was, I was a,
there was like transcripts of the
Milo episode where it was like,
and then unknown host said
this, it's like, fuck you,
I'm not in a bunker whites.
You guys can't just look it up.
Aren't you supposed to
be like journalists?
Can't you figure out what
the fuck the podcast was?
And I saw ones that
attributed, um, stuff to me,
but then had stuff of yours
where they didn't even,
I didn't even know that
you guys had them on.
I thought that all the shit was coming
from my podcast because I got a text
message from my friend Chris
Mcguire informing me of all of it.
And so I went and I said, well,
this isn't even my podcast.
And then I realized like, oh,
he was on your podcast too.
And they combined the two different
things. I even saw people say like,
he was on Joe Rogan's drunken
peasants podcast. It's like,
wow, people are supposed to trust
you for fucking information.
You're supposed to be a
fucking credible source.
You can't even get this basic shit. Right.
So the media is a fucking joke. Well,
the media now is,
it's total fucking joke.
There's like a few places we
can still trust like wire. Um,
I'm hoping you around the answer to that.
Cause you know what?
People come to me all the
time and they're like, Tj,
what news media outlet do you
trust? I'm like, none of them.
I don't trust a single
God damn fucking thing.
Any of these institutions have to
say whatever Megan Kelly has to say.
I'm lessening Megan. I'm in Megan. You're
right about everything. Make it a lot.
That's what I like. Like
ice princesses. Yeah.
I don't know why I like a main,
like Amina mean and smart. Really?
Not really. No. I'm like, no,
but I'm fascinated by people who must.
Yeah.