Her low freak bitches. Um,
speaking of mushrooms is,
this is something that I
get wrong all the time.
It's one of the other things I
wanted to ask you. What, what is, um,
there's some very close relationship
that mushrooms have and the absorption of
mushrooms have to DMT.
What,
what is the chemical
differentiation? Okay. Very,
very slight actually.
Um,
the temptation to start drawing
structures is almost irresistible.
Write some stuff down. Go ahead. I'll draw
awesome. Here. Do we have a visual? No,
we don't, but I'll save that
piece of paper. Okay. Well, uh,
I don't want to get too far
into it, but basically, okay,
so you've had organic
chemistry. Yeah, no, no.
Okay. Well then this spam
organic chemistry. You are,
you are organic chemistry. Well, this
may be a useless thing, but it the,
here we go. We could see it up on the wall
here. We've got it up on the screen. Oh,
there you go. Oh, okay. Well there you
go. Yeah, we don't have to draw struck.
You could look at it right here so you
don't have to turn around and look to
your right. Dennis. Turn and
look test. Okay, so right.
So you can see if you've,
so there's Serotonin,
silicon and dimethyl trip to me.
Wow.
You can see that silicon and die muffled
trip to me and I were very close in
structure. The only difference is
that hydroxy group, that Oh h group,
that's the only difference.
So Allison is exactly the same thing
as an end dimethyltryptamine that's
correct.
Why single trivial difference is
what makes silicon orally active and
dimethyltryptamine is not. Wow. Wow.
Because what's going on with that?
This the static diagram,
eh,
different molecular model would show up.
Well what's going on the is that
that nitrogen there in when sums and
physiological solution,
the nitrogen is charged,
has a positive charge. They oxygen,
it doesn't have the h there.
It has some negative charge.
So the nitrogen curls back and is in
close association with the oxygen.
If this makes any sense,
the enzyme can't get to it.
That's why it's orally active because
essentially it can't get to that nitrogen.
What that enzyme does is cleave off
that nitrogen model a mean oxidase.
It takes away that nitrogen and
it can't do it with awesome.
So that's why cellSens orally active.
It doesn't require an they mail inhibitor.
It's just in some ways it's the
perfect psychedelic because you know,
no preparation needed. You'll just
bend over and pick the mushroom.
They'll preparation is required,
which is probably why very ancient
man knew about suicide cyber,
and they couldn't,
they couldn't not have if they were living
in an environment where it was found
[inaudible].