Well. So, so one really important thing
that needs to be stated is that Twitter by
definition is a bias to platform in
favor of the left period. It's not,
it's not a question. I understand you
might have your own interpretation,
but it's very simple.
Conservatives do not agree with you
on the definition of mis-gendering.
If you have a rule in place
that specifically adheres
to the left ideology, you
by default are enforcing rules
from a biased perspective lets him,
there are a lot of people in the left
who don't agree with how we're doing our
job either for sure.
And those people think that we don't
take enough action on it and use her ass
spent far too much behavior
go. And I think that's what
a radical example though.
I mean what he's talking about,
I mean in terms of generalities,
the in general things lean far more left.
Would you agree to that?
I don't know what that means,
but in this particular case it's
a hell of a speech is being used.
This is a new vector of attack that people
have felt that I don't want to be on
this platform anymore because I'm being
harassed and abused and I need to get
the hell out.
Well people harassed and
abused me all day and night.
You don't do anything about that?
I I my my notifications permanent
locked at 99 you have a worse than I do.
I mean you got substantially
more followers and I don't
click the notification
tab anymore because it's basically
just harassment and I even when,
so this is a really funny anecdote.
I was a covering a story in Berkeley and
someone said if you see him attack him
like it was, it was, I'm paraphrasing,
they said basically to swing at me,
take my stuff,
steal from me and Twitter told me after
review it was not a violation of their
policy.
Somebody made an illusion to me being a
homosexual and I reported that instantly
gone. So when I show, so, so for me
I'm looking, I'm like, well of course,
of course Twitter is going to enforce
the social justice aspect of their policy
immediately,
in my opinion,
probably because you guys have a PR
constraints and you're probably nervous
about that. But when someone actually
threatens me with a crime and insights,
their followers to do it and nothing got
done and I'm not the only one who feels
that way,
that's a mistake.
If someone acts in that manner
and threatens to hurt you,
that's a violation of our rules.
Right?
Maybe there was a mistake there and I'm
happy to go and crack that and we can do
it offline so we don't fear any
sort of reprisal against you.
But that's a mistake. That's not an
agenda on my part or in the team spark.
Would this be PR constraints?
I said, why did you ban Alex
Jones? We're going to get her that.
You want to get into that? Absolutely.
Are you ready for us? Alright. Oh,
I've been ready for, um, well let, let,
let me say this. The reason I
bring him up is that Oliver, Darcy,
one of the lead reporters covering
Alex Jones and his content set on CNN,
that it was only after media pressure
did these social networks take action.
So that's why I bring him
up specifically cause it it,
it sort of implies you
are under PR constraints
to get rid of him.
I think if you look at the Pr,
that's what her went
through and that incident,
it wouldn't be that we looked good in
it and that's not at all why we took
action on it.
You have to look at the full context
on the spectrum here because one of the
things that happened over a weekend
is what Alex mentioned on your,
on your podcast with him.
He was removed from the Itunes
podcast directory. That was,
that was the
linchpin for him because it it,
it drove all the traffic to what he said.
Basically zero immediately after
that we saw our peer companies,
Facebook, Spotify, Youtube
also take action. We did not.
We did not because we,
when we looked at our service and we
looked at the reports on their service,
we did not find anything
in violation of our rules.
Then we got into a situation where
suddenly a bunch of people were reporting
content on our platform,
including CNN,
who wrote an article about all the
things that might violate our rooms,
rules that we looked into.
And we gave him one of the other warnings
and then we can get into the actual
details. But yeah, we did not follow, we,
we resisted just being like a domino with
our peers because it wasn't consistent
with our rules in the contract
we put in before our customers.
So what was it that made you ban them?
So there were three separate incidents
that came to our attention after the fact,
uh, that were reported to us
by, by different users. Uh,
there was a video that was uploaded that
showed a child's being violently thrown
to the ground and crying. So
that was the first one. Um,
the second one was a video that we
viewed as incitement of violence.
I can read it to you. It's
a, sure it's a little,
it's a little bit of a
transcripts, but, um,
but now it's time to act on the
enemy before they do a false flag.
I know the Justice Department's crippled
a bunch of followers and cowards,
but there's groups, there's
grants, juries, there's, you
called for it. It's time,
politically,
economically and judiciously,
illegally and criminally to move against
these people. It's got to be dumb now.
Get together. The people, you know
aren't traders, aren't cowards,
aren't helping their fricking bats.
Hedging their fucking bets,
like all these other assholes to
do. And let's go, let's do it.
So people need to have there.
And then there's a bunch of other stuff,
but at the end,
so people need to have their battle
rifles ready and everything ready at their
bedsides and you've gotta be ready because
the media is so disciplined in their
deception.
So this is you,
you're saying that this is a call
to violence against the media.
That's what it sounded
like to us at the time.
And there've been a number of incidents
of violence against the media. And again,
I take my responsibility for what
happens on the platform and how that
translates off platform very seriously.
And that felt like it was
an incitement to violence.
If he only tweeted the
incitement to violence,
he would have been fine if he only
treats, only tweeted that trans, uh,
posted their transcripts saying,
get your battle rifles ready,
you wouldn't have deleted this account.
I, again, context matters to him.
It's not about one thing.
So we'd have to look at the
entire context of what's going on.
So I'm asking was that, was that egregious
enough for you to say that alone?
That wasn't, that wasn't, that
was your number two. Right, right.
So then I guess the question is what
was the video context of the kid being
thrown to the ground? Was it newsworthy?
We obviously didn't think so.
In depicting violence against the child
is not something that we would allow on
the platform, even if it's a
news content. Um, if it was, uh,
there are certain types of situations
where if you were reporting on, um,
you know, war zone and, and
things that might happening,
we would put an interstitial on that
type of contents as graphic or violent.
But we didn't feel that
that was the context here.
Well there's a video that's been going
around that was going around few four or
five weeks ago,
the one where the,
the girls were yelling at that big giant
guy and the guy punched that girl in
the face and she was like 11 years old.
I saw that multiple times on Twitter.
That was one of the most violent things,
overseeing this giant man,
punched this 11 year old girl in the face.
And that was,
was that removed from Twitter?
I don't know. I would have to go
see if anyone reported it to us.
I think one of the issues here is too is,
you know,
you want me to get to the third
one. The third strike, um,
that week we looked at was a verbal
altercation that Alex got into with a
journalist. And in that altercation
there, which was uploaded to Twitter, um,
there were a number of
statements using eyes of the rat,
even more evil looking in person.
He just scum,
you're a virus to America and freedom
smelling like a possum that climbed out of
the rear end of a dead cow.
You look like a possum that
got caught doing some really,
really nasty stuff in my view. So
there was a bunch of, that's it really,
that's hilarious.
Pattern and practice.
But it was a verbal altercation
that was posted on our classrooms.
So we took the totality of this having
been warned that we have rules against
his abuse and harassment of individuals
and we saw this pattern in practice,
one strike, two strike, three
strikes and we made a decision.
And so that last one was on periscope.
Is that what it was that he uh,
broadcast through? Um, I think it
was, uh, originally on periscope,
but it was also re posted from
multiple related accounts onto Twitter.
So we can, we can agree with you when
you say these things. Like, you know,
Alex said this,
it sounds like a threat.
He was berating this
person saying awful things.
But ultimately your
judgment is the context.
You say we have to pay
attention to the context.
We just trusting that you made
the right decision. Well, I'm,
I'm giving you as much facts as I can
give you here and I think that this is the
real hard part of content moderation
at scale on global platforms.
It's not easy and I don't think jack
or I would tell you that it's easy.
That's a preposterous volume
do you guys have to deal with,
and that's one of the things that I
wanted to get into with Jack when I first
had them on because when my thought,
and um,
I wasn't as concerned about the
censorship as many people were.
My main concern was what does it like
to start this thing that's kind of for
fun?
And then all of a sudden it becomes the
premier platform for free speech on the
planet earth.
So
it is that,
but it's also a platform that's used to
abuse and harass a lot of people, and,
and used in ways that none of us want it
to be used by you molested. It happened.
So, and I think it's an enormously
complicated challenge, uh,
for any company to do
content moderation at scale.
And that's something that we are sitting
down thinking about how do we take this
forward? Because this is, it
doesn't scale. Yes, yes, yes.