Wow.
Do you like roast battle?
Do you like a judging that I get,
I cringe sometimes cause
they're so fucking mean.
Yeah. Sometimes people
are so mean, you know? Um,
uh, but I do like it. I do
love the writing aspect of it.
I love the fact that it's a joke writer's
forum but I don't want to name any
names or this one comic that I'm friends
with that does really well on roast
battle and I said, hey man, how come you,
when you roast you have all this good
new material but you're doing the same
stupid shit when you go
on stage all the time.
Like you were doing the same
set for years. You're not,
you're not advancing cause you're not
writing a lot but you're writing a lot
when you write for roasts and I'm like
you should treat like your material.
Like the same way you treat your
material when you have to roast.
The thing about the roast is like say
if a you are going to roast with Tony
Hinchcliffe, you guys know each other,
you know who you're writing for. I Tony,
what does he look like?
He looks like, you know,
you start fucking around with all I know
this about Tony and that about Tony.
This is going to be funny.
And it forces you to be creative.
Whereas I think there's so many
guys that they, they develop, um,
a framework of a set, and then they just
kind of like that. That is their comfort.
The comfort is in the fact that they know,
even if it's not good,
they know that they can go from
this to that and that to this,
and they know where they're going and
they don't, they're not lost. You know?
And I think that the beautiful thing
about the roast is none of that material
you can do in any other place.
You can only do it right there.
So you have to work on.
And so oftentimes you see like what a
comics capable of when they're roasting
versus what they're doing when
they're actually doing the real set,
which seems stale.