The joe rogan experience.
So there's very,
very few fake Jujitsu,
black belts,
but occasionally there are some and they
get outed and there's some hilarious
videos online. If guys go,
where is it? Where does Steven
Seagal fall in that line?
He is a legitimate I Quito black belt.
In fact,
he was an instructor,
one of the very first Americans to
teach at a Dojo in Japan. I know shit.
So Steven Seagal.
But the martial art is
the questionable thing.
It's the martial art of Ikea.
Edo Is,
it's really a martial art that was
created to disarm people with swords.
The idea was that you lost your sword
in combat and someone was coming at you
with a sword.
Last ditch effort is you had to be able
to use someone's momentum against them.
You gotta be able to use,
some guy comes at you with a sword.
You have to be very adept at catching
their arm and flipping them over.
Here's the golf. Very subtle,
right? Let's, let's not use
this because it's, it's,
it's easy to poke fun
at him when he's old,
but let's go to that black and white one.
You see that black and white one down
there. Go to that. If you go back,
see that one right there.
Steven Seagal. Go to that one.
Now there's some some footage of him
when he was young. Yeah, this is a go.
Fullscreen is legit.
He is very legit and he was thin.
It was a different thing like,
but the thing is nobody comes at you like
a fucking NCAA wrestler would shoot a
double on him and take him down
faster than you can possibly imagine.
I mean this does not work.
It's a dance. Well it works.
It works.
If someone does know what they're
doing or if you have a lot of physical
attributes,
like the Gauls a huge guy.
He's a very big guy and he probably could
pull that off on a lot of people who
don't know how to fight. Yeah, I
hear this is what it was about.
What I keo was really about, this is
Kendo though. They're using swords,
which maybe they do use
some of that and Quito.
But what a kito was originally
created for, I hope I'm not mistaken,
was learning how to disarm like that.
The guy comes at him with a knife and he
flips the guy and takes the knife away.
He's using the guy's energy against them.
That was the original intention of Ikea,
but in terms of the Japanese martial arts,
I Keanu was never thought of as the most
effective judo is far more effective
because judo involves people grabbing
people and flipping them and slamming him
on the ground. Like there's a
great video of an old judo master.
See if you can find this video.
There's this guy,
he looks like he's about eight years old
and he weighs about 13 pounds and he is
lit. You can tell, especially
someone who knows martial arts,
you can tell when someone's just giving
in the problem with a lot of these
demonstrations of my kidos guys are just
giving in like this old dude watch this
old dude,
the old dude and the right hand side is
so much bigger than the other guy and
they're the guy around and like
he's really throwing this guy right.
This is legit.
Like this guy's trying not to get thrown
and he doesn't know what to do when he
trips him to the ground there.
But this old guy is tiny,
but he's using perfect leverage
in perfect technique and fuck.
He looks really old in this picture.
Like the guy's trying to throw him there
and he can't pull it off and he can't
pull it off because the older guy
has perfect position and perfect.
What does the name of this
video? Perfect leverage, right?
Whoa.
Nine years old. Judo master is
the name of the video online.
And I don't know if he was really 90 but
he certainly looks like it could be 90
but this old guy just knows how to,
you notice also the back of his heels
are always like lifting up. He's moving,
but this guy's trying to
throw him and he's just,
and the guy who is trying to throw
him appears to be a black belt.
At least he's wearing a black belt.
Fucking incredible men.
It's really amazing.
So judo was a much more effective martial
art and judo was actually what was
taught to the Brazilians.
Um,
when count my ada went to Brazil and uh,
taught people,
um, in Brazil PR, particularly the
Gracies, they taught in Brazilian Jujitsu.
The Gracies took Brazil what was judo
at the time and they took the ground
attacks of judo and just perfected them
and then hone them and changed them and
made them more technical and really
worked on utilizing leverage and utilizing
submissions. And they, they turned
that into Brazilian Jujitsu.
So Judah was standing as well
as ground? Yes. There's a,
a ground aspect of judo,
obviously,
like Ronda Rousey's probably one of the
most famous submission artists in the
UFC. And her background was in judo. She
was a judo player and very good at judo.
She was a bronze medalist.
So when she would get ahold of people,
she would just fucking throw them on
their ass and flip them and toss him and
slammed him to the ground.
She just had phenomenal judo,
but also a wicked arm bar. And
that was because the Ne Waza, the,
the ground attack version part
of Jujitsu, uh, comes from judo.
So there you go.
Yeah. My father did judo and he
taught it to me and my brother.
And then I remember my brother was bigger
than me and he used to flip the fuck
out of me and then he did it to me one
day and my father grabbed him and flipped
him down on the ground. He
was like, this is not good.
This is isn't like passing on.
No,
this is just a violent family attic
control. Who's his dad? Drunk.
He was six foot two six right
in his hand. A cigarette? Yeah.
Oh fuck yeah. Judo is legit. Judo
is way more legit than a kito.
It's not an Ikea does not legit
I.
Quito is like,
it's a lot of pressure points and
holding the wrist in different ways.
Yeah. Most of it is throws and
learning how to take an attack or look,
if you just charge forward and
an Akita guy and you have your,
your right hand come on like cocked and
ready. Just run out and throw that punch.
A really good a kito.
I was going to grab that and flip you
and slammed me on the ground. Right.
But you know, how often does that
come up? Yeah. You know, most,
especially today when people actually
know how to fight, it's just a diff,
it's too limited. Yeah. But there's
a lot of martial arts like that.
Like there's certain aspects
of karate that are applicable,
but there's a lot of it
that's really limited.
Okay.