The joe rogan experience is that we live
into it and you're like, Yep, yeah, we,
I wish we could start this show
off with flavor and you're here.
Where do we get kicked off of Youtube?
Craig Mack died. Yeah. That's such,
that's just a shout out. I know.
I feel like we should be able to,
just as a kicking shout out playbook.
It is a great fucking song,
man. It was such a good song.
Dude was only 46 what was that?
I didn't even see what he died of a
heart attack. Yeah. Heart failure.
46 fuck man. Major, but we start
off the show a major bummer. Yeah.
We're going to go, we would get pulled
by youtube. Right? If we did that,
we played it for sure. We, I'm sure for
sure we won't play it won't play it.
Let's just shout out to Craig back.
You know what you could do?
You could play like someone else
who did their version of it.
It should have been even then you'd
probably get there he is. Yeah. Oh,
this might be hard. Oh, Biggie's it. Now.
This is the, this is the, yeah, I dunno.
With notorious lol and bus
a bus. No, Shit. Awesome.
Yeah. Don't, don't,
don't put that up on youtube is it already
had been up all my shit audios. Huh?
Okay, good. Ah, everybody's dying for,
everyone's got 46 is so young to have
a fucking heart attack heart stuff.
Yeah. That's a, that's everybody. I guess
I should have just guessed hard shit.
Well,
especially in this day and age,
the way people eat terrible. He
wasn't, was he that heavy of a dude?
I don't think you have to be that
heavy with dude. No clogged arteries.
But then there's super, super heavy
dudes that just had nothing fun.
Nothing phases them.
Yeah.
There's some guys that just
keep on trucking that's like,
we're not in from Chicago where I'm
from. That's everybody I know. Oh yeah.
Nobody skinny is offensive.
Well, not only that,
it gets zero degrees all day long.
Yeah, so fucking four months. Yeah.
You need the padding.
They need something he needed to sell.
You need somewhere to hide all that
sadness, shove it underneath all that.
Scott has gray. You hear bullets from
the south side. And so when I got,
when I got in a little bit of
shape and I went back to Chicago,
I caught this like so much
shit for that from everybody.
You sell out Mr Hollywood. Oh, you look,
you look in lane eaten, eaten. Well,
we eat an avocado. Karen,
about your future. What does
it say, Jamie? What'd he say?
No, cause of death was immediately
released. Yeah. Oh No. For Awhile.
So that's what I saw. I saw they didn't
figure it out yet. Oh, I saw something on,
yeah. See that's a
problem. When someone dies,
you get a bunch of different
versions of the story. Yeah. Um,
I went down an internet
rabbit hole last night. Man,
this is a very disturbing one.
Okay.