I find that a lot of people that are,
um,
that are steadfast in their
resistance to vaccines, they,
they also believe in a lot
of other questionable things.
It seems like these things get lumped
into these groups of things that they
don't trust the government about.
Right, right. Yeah. I think that's part,
I think that's probably true.
Yeah.
That's what it slash which
was she government, which
was, which was inch. Well,
you know, it was interesting.
So, you know, I said,
we know we need to hear from the Centers
for disease control and more than the
surgeon general. Now they're
starting to speak out. But you know,
the people counter that said,
well part of the problem is people
don't trust their government. And I say,
well that's true of some, but I think
most people, if you know, with the,
if we had a,
you know,
a more visible public health force
out there, people would listen to it.
Well,
I think that what you're talking about
in terms of these poor neighborhoods,
in these parents' sides,
getting into people's system and affecting
cognitive development and what it was,
the other one besides Chaga
was that toxic. Uriah says,
what's the cognitive development?
The fact that there's actual
cures for these things too,
that I estimate an an a paper.
There are 2.8 million African Americans
living in poverty with toxic horizons.
Wow. This is not a rare disease, Joe.
This is, this is a common disease,
but it's so unknown,
but it's occurring among the poor and
it's chronic and debilitating affection.
It's not dramatic. It's not an 90. It's
not killing people. Is this mostly,
and this, the climates
as well? It's probably,
it's more in common in the south and
the north. Is it because they've long,
longer time to do this because the eggs,
the eggs are in the environment and
the worm develops within the egg.
Is there any other diseases that are going
on that we don't know about? Um, yeah,
yeah, sure. Um, there's other,
there's a brain parasitic
infection called cysticercosis.
That one is from eggs.
Um,
often from individuals
who have a tapeworm. Uh,
so that's where we're seeing
cases of that. Um, there's, uh,
some of the viruses
transmitted by mosquitoes.
One of the ones we don't talk about a lot,
which is a very serious infection,
is West Nile virus infection.
That's got very high rates of
not only encephalitis, but also,
uh,
one of our faculty members,
Christie Marie is showing very high
rates of depression and other neurologic
debilitation four. And that's another
one we could probably use a vaccine for,
but there isn't the
market incentive to do it.
West Nile virus does come up though the,
at least that's discussed in the
news and people are aware of it.
You said it right, but there's no vaccine,
there's no vaccine. But there could be,
what does it there could
be holding it back.
What's holding it back
is lack of market forces,
lack of financial incentive
for the pharmaceutical
companies to take it off. Um,
so if there's an extremely
large investment to develop
something along those
lines. That's right. I mean, and vaccines
are for an investor's perspective,
tough sell because you know, there's
a possibility, you know, first of all,
you need many years of clinical trials.
It can sometimes take two decades from
the original conception of a vaccine to
actually going through a clinical trial.
So the hook where vaccine,
I've been working on a,
we've been doing it since the 1990s.
So we're talking decades
long time horizons.
When you talk to an investor about
something with decades long time horizons,
you figure it out, right? The light,
the lights go out. I mean the, uh, very,
very quickly. So we're, it gets
gross, right? Because this is all,
we were relying on these
private businesses to invest
money to cure a public
health issue. That's right. That's
right. That seems kind of crazy. Well.
So in response to that,
what happened was after the Ebola fiasco
in 2014 where we didn't have any bowl
of vaccine and Guinea,
Liberia and Sierra Leone,
a group of individuals came together
at Davos, the World Economic Forum,
and I'm including the gates
foundation and they put around,
they put developed this concept or
which at an organization called Sepi,
the Coalition for epidemic preparedness
innovation to incentivize a biotechs and
pharmaceutical companies to embark on a
diseases for which of pandemic potential
like Ebola, like last of fever,
like mayors, corona virus infection.
And that was great.
But the problem was they didn't
address these poverty related diseases.
So those of us who are working on poverty
related diseases are still kind of on
the outside looking in.
It just seems like having everything
managed by private companies that need to,
they,
they need to have some sort of a financial
incentive to attack these diseases.
That seems like a crazy way to deal
with health crisis. That's right.
That's right. And so what
I've recommended, as I said,
the set that organization Sepi
is great for what it's doing,
but we need another mechanism.
What I've proposed is that since these
diseases are so common among the poor and
the g 20 countries,
these are the 20 largest economies to
put together public sector funds for that
purpose.
Public sector funds for investing in
developing vaccines and treatments for
poverty related diseases, these chronic
debilitating diseases. And in fact,
you know, we can show that the using
working with health economists,
we actually work with a terrific health
economist. His name is Bruce Lee.
Evolve all names.
He's a professor at Johns Hopkins
and Ai Right now. He loves it.
Um, um, and he's able,
he's been able to show 'em that our
vaccines are not only cost effective,
there cost savings, meaning that
they're economically dominant,
that they'll actually save money.
The problem is you still doesn't help you
with the fact that you still need some,
but the return is on public health.
You still need somebody to come along and
provide that investment. So, you know,
so what's happened is our,
our technical ability to develop
vaccines has outstripped our,
our, our financial instruments
that we have to do it.
So I get a stream of young people,
uh,
in my office wanting to
go into global health.
I mean the commitment for this next
generation and know they get a lot of bad
press, but my impression is this
next generation, their commitment,
the public services and an all time high
and they say, you know, Doctor Hotez,
I'm all in,
I'm going to go into global health.
And there are a little bit disappointed
when I tell them get an Mba or get a law
degree because where we need
the innovation now is in the,
it's in the finance sector,
there's a,
there must be a business model out there
that would work that would figure out
how to do this.
I just don't have the background to do it.
It seems like once the momentum is in
the corner of this being handled by the
private sector and that the private
sector has to develop these vaccines and
these treatments and they have to do it
with some sort of financial incentive.
If they don't have a bucket of
gold at the end of the rainbow,
they're not going to take a ride. That's
right. That's right. So that's crazy.
It's crazy. The reality. And so, um,
what the exciting thing
about what I do is, you know,
developing these vaccines for poverty
related diseases as there's no roadmap
right now,
there were in clinical trials,
I don't know what the roadmap is to get
to licensure and getting these vaccines
out to the public.
The terrifying thing to thing it keeps
me up at night is there's no room. Right.
Both good about good. Yeah. There is.
How much does it cost to get
a vaccine? I mean, in general,
from developmental period to actual app?
Well,
the pharmaceutical companies
have traditionally said billions,
but I don't think that's the case.
I think one of the reasons, um,
why they're doing that is because they're
also recovering their r and d costs.
You know, they're putting
money into R and, d that they,
that they re that they charge in order
to either make a profit or at least a
eve. And so for instance,
the cervical cancer vaccine,
the HPV vaccine that,
you know,
when I last look was
$420 for the three doses,
it doesn't take cost $420
to make that vaccine it,
it's just that they're recovering
their r and d costs, which is,
which is fair enough.
So one of the things that we're
proposing to do for our neglected disease
vaccines is we'll d link the
R and d costs. In other words,
if we've gotten grants, whether it's
from the gates foundation in the past or,
or the Nih or the European Union or
the Dutch government or the Carlos Slim
Foundation, we're not going to pass
those costs on a, we'll just, you know,
that was used for r and d and we
would just cost for the cost of goods.
So at least we can get it down to
just a couple of dollars, a dose,
a few dollars a dose.