I want to shoot with that. Oh No, I
don't have to wear a backpack though.
That's where it's weird.
What's this Mickey Rourke.
Oh, we'll leave it Tom. Yeah,
he's got a, what are the school
that was called a clutch? Yeah.
Yeah. It looks more like a clutch.
Yeah, but he's so eccentric.
I met him this past weekend.
He had a crazy cowboy that's,
we're looking at a
picture of Mickey Rourke.
He had a crazy cowboy hat on and he's
just, yeah, he's, he seems like a cook.
I mean, you can see that belt buckle,
like really like just, you know,
that's something I'm looking at like
good on him and he's just an odd duck.
I little round,
I for some reason it reminds me of,
it was an old onion article and it's
one of my favorite headlines and it was
Johnny.
Jeff found to be 90% scarfs.
He count like way scarfy after the whole
pirate movies, it went straight scarf,
like where are the rest of his life kind
of thing. He's like, yeah, he, he really,
he really committed to that scarf thing.
When you're a beautiful man like that,
it's an odd transition to
being like a 55 year old.
I like what's up with Johnny Depp
lately? Not good things. I, you know,
it's, it's really strange actually.
They just this morning, um,
they delayed or like
actually like or canceled.
He is a notorious B I g movie looking at
that. He's in with forest Whitaker, uh,
and it was suppose to come out next
month and they just pulled it from the
schedule and they haven't
leg even said that the,
it's ever going to come out or something.
And it's like,
and even just like looking at pictures
of him, like, it kind of just like,
there's something off about him, like
how you sucks, Dan hope he used to be,
he used to be really great. You
said, what'd you do to him? You fuck,
I don't even know who that is.
Doug Stanhope one of the best stand
up comedians ever. Uh, there you go.
He's a, I'm more of a Steven
Wright fan myself. Me Too.
Yeah. No lumps even. Right.
But I think, uh, I
think Johnny's just, uh,
he hit that weird spot where
you're just too fucking famous.
You can't go anywhere where you
were when you were little, I'm sure.
But you can coast now, right?
You can to go places like how,
how rich is rich enough? Like, dude, like,
like, yeah, like that's what it means.
Not just that, but he
spends, he only 14 houses.
He owns an island.
Millions and millions of dollars.
Did he spend like $5 million
shooting? Uh, uh, uh,
a hunter s Thompson's the Canon?
Yeah,
but they estimate that you spend
$1 million goes, no, of course not.
I spent $3 million. That's what
they asked him about his wine habit.
They said, uh, your attorney said that
your wine habit is $30,000 a month.
And he goes, that's an insult.
It's far more than, it's
far, far more than that now.
That's what I mean, like how,
and I'm like, all right, cool.
Like I guess he has to maintain it
and you know that lifestyle, well,
that's what he wants for himself.
That's what he's doing. That's his life.
His life is spending all that money.
Yeah.
Like his whole life is doing movie that
you know people though also when they're,
they're involved in laborious projects
that they're not really interested in.
You know when you're,
when you're doing something all day,
and I say this is a guy who
hosted fear factor, something
that you really enjoy doing while
you're doing it. You're like, ah, okay.
Time to go to work. I mean it was
very thankful to have the job.
Don't get me wrong,
but the reality is it was not enjoy.
It wasn't a fruitful endeavor.
It wasn't like working for the UFC are
doing standup comedy or even doing a
podcast. It wasn't a passion
project. Exactly. So when
you do something like that,
like people on bad sitcoms in particular,
they spend all their fucking money.
They go crazy.
Yeah.
Because the only thing that they look
forward to is what am I going to do with
this money? It's reward a buy a
Ferrari. I got to buy a mansion,
I'm going to buy an island. And that's, I
think that's what Johnny got into. Yeah.
I couldn't see myself like doing a sitcom
or a television show kind of thing.
Like what about a good,
a good one?
I do like news radio is a fantastic
show look like. He must have been,
that must have been like a
fruitful endeavor. Reason
why I never did another one.
Yeah, yeah, exactly. I don't
want to ruin that experience.
Every other one that came along
was like, this is shit go. They,
they pursued me for, for me for
a big bang theory. Oh Christ,
you got lucky to get that. And
I said No. I said like, no,
cause it was kind of like the way
that pitch was was Kinda just like,
all right these two like astrophysicist
nerds and then a pretty girl lives with
them. He links like, you know, and like
that, that was the pitch. And it was like,
yeah, it was just look at
it and they're like, oh,
we're going to get some real like
physicists to like, you know, do the math.
And I said, look, yeah, no. I
said, I'm, I'm cool. Like thanks.
And then they came back at me again and
I said, no, no, no, look like again,
flattered but link. No. And then like,
then they came back at me again
and like even my manager was like,
twisting my arm and come on, I
want a piece of this, but listen,
I'd have hundreds of millions
of dollars right now.
I feel like if I did that
Gig at the same time,
I'd be bashing my head against
the wall. That's the thing. Yeah.
I think that's what Johnny Depp's doing
and we can't really be into those pirate
movies. Yeah, no, he's just,
he's interested. And that's
the thing is that like,
he wasn't always like that. Like
it, it's all about the money thing.
I read an article, an interview with
him, it was about two decades ago,
and he was talking about,
you know,
he was in his thirties and he was
doing a lot of weird, obscure movies.
Like what's that movie? Dead
Man, that black and white? Yeah,
he did a lot of weird shit.
And he said,
this is kind of what I really like
and I don't, I'm not blockbuster. Boy.
Which is what he said. It's so
ironic. It's just so ironic.
They pull quotes and blockbuster
boy. Yeah, no, he goes, yeah,
if I ever like if you're,
if I'm ever a part of like a franchise,
like just shoot me or something like that.
Yeah.
They're pulled up these weird
like old quotes. It was a, um,
it's like the George
Lucas, like when he, uh,
he testified before Congress about the
colorization of movies and talking about
how movies are or are part
of our heritage and you know,
they shouldn't be
tampered with or anything.
He goes back and there's like 25 years
later he's going back and redoing his
movies. Yeah. It's like, yeah,
no, like once you put art
out there, leave it alone,
leave it alone. It's not yours
anymore. Like that's the thing,
like once you show like your paintings,
like that's not yours. That's the worlds,
that's an interesting way of looking
at it and you don't think it's theirs
anymore. Imagine, imagine you've
really already divinci like,
like just all of a sudden came back
into existence right now and he wants to
change the Mona Lisa. She's fat. Yeah.
Cause I like, I kind of didn't get there.
You know I didn't get the
smile, right. Yeah, exactly.
What her hair, it's all pulled back
and shit. I want to see a show.
Should he be able to change it?
I want to give us some fucking jewelry.
I never finished the eyebrows.
Don't want to give a big tits.
I'm going to push them together. God,
come on. It's my fucking painting.
Yeah, exactly. I met
Devinci is a modern Italian.
Big tits would fucking glitter. It's
like he's like, you're living in,
I'm like Mulberry Street and
like in Little Italy. Hey Pizza.
Yeah, like a fake lips. It's where
I want, give me some claims casino.
Hey, this fucking broad. Look at her.