You know what the best ones, like
all of them. Most of my friends,
we all got busted for drinking
and driving. The best one
was a buddy of mine. Uh,
they read his, who's like, you know,
approximately four in the morning,
we noticed a Maroon VW, Fox blowing
its horn trying to pass on the right.
We pulled the defendant over,
uh,
after repeatedly asking the defendant to
stay in the car. He got out of the car,
threw his keys at my feet and uh,
repeatedly stated, lock me up.
I'm fucked.
And this was funny was my buddy was a
good look can guy and though the judge was
a, was a woman and when the
guy read that, you know,
lock me up, I'm fucked up. And he wasn't
the brightest guy and he just kind of,
when he went like, oh, he's like put his
head down like that. And he was, you know,
a little pound puppy fucking
looking dude. And uh, she, uh, she,
she gave him like a lighter sentence and
cause he was good looking. I think so,
yeah. Plays in. It gets why ugly
people are complain so much. Like
they won't take the time to develop
a fucking personality. Right?
Some jokes do it. The rest of us have
to do like I don't get mad at Brad Pitt.
You know I haven't me fucking cause he's
fucking beautiful. I'm a fucking bald,
redheaded mail.
I know where I am in the pecking order
and some of these fucking people who are
complaining right now who are mad that
beautiful people get treated differently.
I understand racially speaking, but you're
not going to do the beautiful thing.
And then, then there's another thing
they tried to say. Well Society tries to,
you know, they're the ones that
fucking did like, you know,
like I love when like there's
a supermodel, like the dude,
this is like an impossible standard
of beauty to try and live up to. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. That's why she's on the
cover of a magazine. She's that level.
Beautiful.
And you're going to try and sit there
and tell me that that was learned. Well,
here's the thing that's only women because
when you see Jason Mamoa playing aqua
man,
you don't hear men say that's
an impossible standard of
beauty that we have to,
no, I just make fun of it. It's fucking
stupid that tries to, hang on sir.
Okay.
I don't care how much you can kick my ass.
That is the dumbest shoes.
Me On a fucking serial box.
It's a trident.
For years they had a problem like with
aqua man. It's like he's in the ocean.
Human beings are on earth like, what do
we like? I have to see that fucking movie.
What are they going to be? Is it going
to be like Japanese people like fitting?
He's busy going to save sharp. He
goes under water. Is that a skin?
Well, the bumps. What is that? Is that a
suit? It doesn't water get in the gloves.
I think that that have to be
all one piece, right? Yeah.
You'd be annoying as shit is any worse
than water and your gloves will look.
It looks like it catches
them like a water catcher,
like not just like water gets in
the gloves. It's like a funnel.
He looks like a stripper at a Bachelorette
party. Does a good why she pays
money. You got a good one.
God dieted down for that. Um,
yes he did and he got all the ABS.
So he's B's better than I am.
Always this button that says this
is the fall look for one. Yep.
This is when he's in the Black Sea.
You know what I mean?
He wants to fucking gets cold. Yeah.
Did you see what's going on in the UK?
The UK is banned advertisements that
a feature, a unobtainable bodies.
There's a racist tweeted recently. The
way they eat fish and chips over there.
This can be most of advertising.
Well they had these ads for summer bodies.
You know, you see a girl in a bikini
and they're now making it illegal.
Why can't you aspire to that?
Like I look at that aqua man guy that
makes me want to go to the gym. I know.
Oh you know he's got a full head of hair
look like you've got to make me feel
better.
It's because the people that complain
who are the people that complain and the
people that complain to the people that
don't want to work to be that lady,
they don't want to work to get that
kind of a body and they want to,
they just want to not see it.
They don't want any it.
They don't want to go to the subway
and see a body that they never,
yeah,
I saw it.
I saw an actress complaining one time
cause the studio total that she needed to
lose 15 pounds and like you
can't drop 15 to star in a movie.
I mean what,
what carrot can they specifically carrots,
some veggies in your diet.
What are they have to dangle in front
of you to go to the fucking gym?
Like the rest of us, like I
literally like, cause I always say,
oh guys not to deal with that.
It's like yeah we do. Of course.
Yes we do like how to deal with that
to gain 20 pounds to forget about him.
If just having five
lines in a fucking movie.
If I am north of 171 72 pounds,
the fucking tweets,
I get a Billy booze bag.
Hey Billy Bitch tits,
hey fat,
freckles,
all of this shit that I get like I know
like they sit there and they like it.
They had like a,
they're acting like like fucking preteens
where everything is just everything's
about them and the whole fucking world
gives us shit celebrities with their
fucking political views as the funniest
thing ever. It's like all you're,
you're not, you're not making anybody
changed their mind politically.
I think I need a FAC and
speak up. It's like, no,
you can't have the
spotlight on you enough.
That's all you're doing because all
you're doing with that bullshit is you.
First of all,
you're alienating half the fucking people
that are going to go see whatever the
fuck you're in.
And then secondly,
you're just getting on the radar of
lunatics in white vans with two seats that
are looking up how to fucking
build pipe bombs like that. That's,
that's the fallout.
It's like the jerk when he goes to the
average run of the mill, son of a bitch.
He had already picked Steve Martin.
The idea that a girl shouldn't
be asked to lose weight,
to look hot for a movie is fucking crazy
because that's what you're playing.
You're playing a hot woman
and there's part of the job and there's
millions to everybody's in shape.
I remember fucking CNI.
He's still a bit about this.
I saw a Ben Stiller in,
in meet the Fockers or something.
There was a scene where he had to
have his shirt off in the pool.
He had fucking abs and a
comedy. Yeah. Cause that's,
cause you was seeing the influence
for the fucking Internet.
You know what I mean? It goes just like,
you know, he, he gets in your head,
people just fucking trash and you like,
I already knew I was unsightly,
but I didn't realize how many things that
people didn't enjoy about until I got
on the Internet. I was like, wow, I never
noticed that about myself. So, um, yeah.
I don't have 'em. Look if somebody really
has like a fucking eating disorder,
you know, I feel like fucking obese.
I have sympathy for those people.
But you 15 pounds, 20 pounds overweight,
I mean fucking and you know it.
Did he drink some fucking smoothies?
These women that are playing these
roles have to understand first of all,
that part of the reason why you got that
role is not just because of your acting
ability, but also because you're
pretty, you have a beautiful face.
You were born with it. You didn't even
work at it. And then on top of that,
you're supposed to be playing a
beautiful person in the movie.
They would like you to not be fat.
Well, it also, discrimination is millions
of dollars at stake. There could be lost.
So I always feel like your job is Amy,
if you look like me,
is to show up on time knowing your lines
in the best possible shape you could
get yourself in that. That's the role
that's I even if I'm just fucking,
what about your Artie Lange?
What if you're already laying in,
you're supposed to play the guy that
smoking cigarettes and you're the brother
in law that's drunk all the time,
then your job is to look that way.
You just slipped away.
Her job is looking at the hot
woman that everybody wants to fuck.
If they're telling you you
have to lose weight and you're,
you're a beautiful woman, it's because
they want to make you more attractive.
It's,
there's not like discrimination.
There's a reason they want
a better product because we
want to make money. Yeah.
They wanted to try and make
them a better product. And uh,
I'll tell you nothing to like really
that those both male and female,
like those beautiful people at that level,
it's like they're fucking aliens.
Like I, I've done a couple of movies. I
did a movie one time and I remember, uh,
it was a scene,
we were in a car and the star of the
movie was holding onto the steering wheel.
And I was like, I never thought
this ever about a woman. I was like,
her forearms are gorgeous.
I was looking at me like, I was
like, those forearms are perfect,
but I didn't make me when I
went to Stockholm, Sweden,
how beautiful the people were there.
I was walking down the street pointing
at guys with my wife, go knit,
look at that guy, look at
that. That fucking guy,
like he's like an accountant
walking down the street.
Like does he know if he
fucking came over here?
He'd be starring in movies and
that's not all a Sweden by the way.
That's like just when you're in Stockholm,
that's like their Manhattan.
So all the beautiful fucking people.
But I mean I went to a couple of,
I went to this magnet,
played in a but like a a magazine or
something like that when I was over there.
And the woman behind the counter
was like a fucking 11 here,
but she was working at a magazine stand.
So that was her energy. Like, hey,
how are you doing?
I'm working in magazines.
Then my dream hasn't come true yet.
And you just looking at him like you,
you could sign with the WHO's
that big a modeling agency. Yeah.
Like that all like Cindy Crawford
and all of them are worth back in the
day, the Vikings, it's viking blood.
They the best looking people.
They,
they went over there and
raped and pillaged and all
that good DNA is left there.
They cut the best.
They kept him alive.
Killed everybody else. Oh,
is that what happened? Yeah.
I don't know what happened.
That's why they're so big. Beautiful.
Oh yeah. No, this super small.
That's one of the funniest things happen
when you go over to the, to like, uh, the,
uh,
what do they call those?
The Nordic and then Scandinavia's
within the Nordic countries.
I always have to remind myself that like,
you go over there,
it was the funniest fucking shit
cause he's so god damn tall.
They would be kids almost my height,
whose voices hadn't changed yet.
And they had the mentality of
like an 11 year old they'd make,
he said they was speaking that
I did hide it. He aged out.
If you're talking voice and change that.
And I was just sitting there laughing my
ass off. Go. These are like fucking, yeah,
they like, everybody was like,
uh, like six, three, six, four,
six, five like rail thin with
their fucking European pants.