The Joe Rogan experience,
they back to your core point.
I mean that's the reason why I also write
science fiction is that the world of
science is changing so fast that we really
need to apply a lot of imagination to
imagine where it's going.
Because if you're just looking
at what's happening now,
it's like this train is
going to speed by you.
We have to kind of imagine
it's like Wayne Gretzky.
We have to imagine where the puck is
going to be, not where it is now. And I,
I mentioned George Church who's
like, he's at Harvard, he's like the,
the Living Charles Darwin.
And I do a lot of speaking alongside
George and it's become our little thing
that he says that he reads,
um, science fiction like mine.
And then imagine says, well, that's
pretty cool. How can we do that?
And what I do is I look at the research
coming out of labs like Georges and I,
sorry,
well that's where we are now.
What's that going to mean in 2050
a hundred years? And so we have to,
that the science fiction plays a more
important role than it ever has and kind
of imagining where we're going and it's
that imagining that allows us to try to
say, well, what if that's one of
the options of where we're going?
What are the decisions that we need to
make now so that we can have a better
outcome rather than a worse
than if you are gambling person.
I don't know if you are,
but if I had to give you 100 bucks
to put on something in 20 years,
it's going to be
profoundly just eh change.
It's going to change us in a way that
is something that we're not really
prepared to understand or deal with.
What do you think that's going to be?
I think it's going to be predictive
genetics that we're going to have.
All right now it's like you go
to your doctor when you're sick.
You could have been,
this could have been some genetic disorder
that you had from the moment you were
conceived and it was ticking and it was
ticking and you showed up 50 years later
when that's been manifest.
So it's going to be very different.
You're taking your kid home
from the hospital, your
newborn, and the doctor says,
Hey, congratulations. This is
really great. Um, but just Fyi,
your kid has a 50% greater than
average chance of getting early onset
Alzheimer's 50 years
from now and your cat,
your kid has a really great chance
of being phenomenal at abstract math.
Like how are we going to think about how
we're gonna think about what it means
to be human when we have
all of that information?
And there are things now that we
call fate and it's, it's, it's, uh,
just a different model. And so I
think that, and once we have that,
that's going to change a
lot of a lot of things.
It's going to fundamentally
transform our healthcare.
What we call healthcare
now is really sick care.
You show up with a symptom and
this is going to be predictive.
And it's going to change the we,
the way we make babies because people are
going to have real choices about which
embryos to implant and we're going
to have a lot of information about,
I read a lot of really intimate stuff.
So you feel like genetic
manipulation and genetic engineering,
genetic understanding, genetic knowledge,
and then applied genetic medicine,
those are going to be the big
changes in the next 20 years,
even more so than technology,
which it's interconnected because these,
there's really, it's like a super
convergence of these technologies. So the,
the genetics revolution is the artificial
intelligence revolution in a sense
that the complexity of
genetics is so great,
it's way beyond what our brains
on their own could process.
And so really with all of these
technologies are touching each other.
And so the biological models
are now influencing the AI.
So for example, we are coming to
the limits of silicon storage,
but DNA has unlimited storage capacity.
So it's the,
as I've said before,
the kind of the boundaries between biology
and AI or genetics and AI is going to
be very blurry. Yeah. That is a,
an interesting concept, right?
The idea of storing information in
DNA and that has been discussed. Yeah.
Which the great DNA is the
greatest information storage
mechanism ever imagined.
But the question is what happens when
you do store things in there and how does
that information interact with all the
rest of the stuff that's in your body
already? Well, I mean, if you can
do it in your body, you could,
doesn't have to be in,
doesn't your body just think of like your,
your DNA has 4 billion years of history
and it's done a great job of recording
it. It's incredible. Like am I
have old eight track tapes? They,
they haven't lasted.
That is a squirrely concept that you have
all that data inside your head. I mean,
that's also when people make,
when they try to understand
instincts yeah. That people have,
these are some sort of genetically
encoded memories or some understanding of
things that are dangerous and that these,
they're in there because this is how
we've learned over the years without
actually having experienced these things
personally. Yeah. Yeah. No. So it's,
it's baked in. Our genetics are
baked into us. And so, you know,
I don't know if you've been to Indonesia,
I was in Indonesia and they went to
this place called Komodo island. Oh Wow.
The dragons Komodo Dragon.
And it was fascinating because it's
like you can tell they don't have
plaintiff's attorney.
So here's walking around there,
all these Komodo dragons and so yeah,
these are like the most deadly creatures
on earth and there's like some little
guy with a little stick and it's like,
well how effective is that stick?
But the way it works,
so you're just walking around walking
around cause they come checks when they're
not killing people or killing animals.
They're just sitting there.
And so it's pretty scary.
Do they ever get Jack,
do people ever go there and
get bitten? Yes. And they say,
oh it's only a few times a year.
It's like, well a few times. Yeah,
that seems like a lot of times.
A year is a lot.
But the way it works for a Komodo Dragon,
a mother lays the egg and then buries the
egg and then forgets where the egg is.
And then let's just say that this egg
hatches and this little Komodo dragon
comes out and the mother sees
her own baby Komodo Dragon.
She'll eat it in a second. Oh Jeez.
And so if you're a Komodo Dragon,
you better have your entire survival
strategy baked into your DNA because
nobody's teaching you anything.
And so for us,
we have this sense that it's like
parenting is really important.
It is environment. It is
really important. It is.
But so much of who and what we
are is baked in to our genetics.
And I think that's,
that's going to be this challenge.
We're going to see ourselves
as increasingly genetic beings.
We can't become genetic determinist
think that we're just genetics,
but we're going to know a lot more.
We're going to demystify a lot of what
it means to be a human. Poof. Yeah,
tiff is right, but are we going
to lose the romance and the,
the just the randomness
of life because of that.
That's what people are
concerned with. Right? Like if,
if we have some sort of genetic uniformity
mean especially in particularly with
like things like intelligence
and athletic performance,
we're not gonna appreciate freaks as
much or maybe we'll all want to be freaks
because the freaks are the ones who push
us into I am not going to want to be a
moron. Yeah. Well your your question,
it's, it's the essential question.
It's like what makes a human a human isn't
to some way of Higher Iq that doesn't
make you a better human that makes
you someone with a higher Iq.
But how are we going to think about
constructing societies when it's up to us?
Like if we are going to say
we value certain people,
certain ideas,
I think we're going to need artists.
Like right now people like artists
are sometimes in the mainstream,
sometime they're on the fringe,
but artists are going to be maybe the
most important people in this new world
then,
right?
Like right now in hospitals we have
kind of a hierarchy and like the most
technical people are the people who are
valued the most and the least technical
people.
Like some of the nurses or nurse's aides
are the people who were often valued
and paid the least.
But when technology can do
these technological feats,
what's going to be left is how can
we be great humans? How can we emote?
How can we connect?
How can we create art?
And if we get swept away by
this tide of science, as in,
you know,
how excited I am about the size a bit,
if we could really undermine our humanity.
But as for humans,
what humans value is many aspects of
that humanity. Art, the curations.
Yeah, yeah. Literature things we, we,
when you read someone's great pros,
you're,
you're reading like an
insight into their mind.
And that's what's interesting
about it, right? You're like, yes,
you're not going to get that
from just ones and Zeros.
Yeah. And that's, and there,
there will always be this
way we call it mystery.
And even if we can do a genetic analysis
of Shakespeare and Mozart and and
whatever, like it's still miraculous and
we need to celebrate that and we can't,
we can't allow us to say that we are just
our genetics or even just our biology.
But we also can't just say
biology has nothing to do with it.
And especially because we're going to
know more about our biology. You know,
about our, our, our differences.
And that's, that's normal.
I mean it used to be in the old days they,
everyone thought,
well God is weather and now we
understand weather pretty much.
And nobody's saying, oh that lightening,
that's God is delivering message.
It could be, but we still like, we still
have that mystery and I think that it's,
in some ways it's about our orientation.
Like how do we make sure that
we keep this view of life,
that we have artists and humanists who
are just at the core of this conversation
about where we're going.
What if that mystery ultimately turns
out to just be ignorance and that as you
develop more and more understanding,
there's less and less mystery?
Would we like to be less smart?
Well, we like to be, yeah,
or overwhelmed by possibility.
I mean that could be,
I think those would be
part of what romance is.
It could be and certainly like the unknown
every we wake up every morning. Sure.
And we just don't know the answer.
And there are some people like to going
back to the issues of of life extension.
There are some people who say,
well that death is essential
for appreciating life.
I talk about this stuff all around and
then there are people who say, you know,
you're talking about eliminating
these terrible diseases,
but I know somebody who had that terrible
disease and their suffering was a gift
to everybody else because we all had
more humanity in response to their
suffering. Like, well
that's kind of screwed up.
I'd prefer them to not have
that suffering, but those
people are thinking wacky.
It's Wacky,
but we need to,
I totally agree with you that if we allow
ourselves to get swept away with this
kind of scientific determinism,
if we don't say we really value
our humanistic traditions,
our artists,
our cultures,
we could get lost and we had to become
obsolete. We could become obsolete,
but we could also just become less human.
And there's something
wonderful and there's magic.
But do you think that monkeys used
to think, man can become a human?
We become less monkey.
You know what I'm saying?
But no being looks in the mirror and
recognizes that they are evolving.
Yeah. We've, well, we've only
been, homo sapiens were about
300,000 years. Right. Um,
so we just, it's hard. We know
where we've come from. Cause you,
you see all those little charts
from high school biology,
but it's really hard for people to imagine
being something else in the future.
It's, it's, it's outside of our, of our
consciousness. And so say she will square.
Yeah. And we are monkeys. It's just
that we've redefined our monkey thing.
You know, we, we do it with
a little different way.