Fight derrick lewis. I'm, I must feel
like shit for Steve Bay. You must be like,
God, don't you feel bad
for Steve Bay? Yeah.
Cause like if Daniel
Cormay wasn't injured,
he would have got that shot click.
He was him was okay.
He would have got that shot in New York.
But now Steve Bay's and everything get
that shot. Dude. How about John? Steve,
I feel tend to spit balling. I
like gems here, but I fee, I feel,
I feel terrible for steep bay to
really do because I mean there's,
how long has it been since he lost
the title? A year here. A year.
How long has it been and,
and he's tried to fight
June two 26 oh my gosh,
he's 26 so it wasn't a year.
DC DC's fought twice more than a year.
February, February. Fuck.
Oh, what are you talking about?
Do you not know how to count? No,
that's wrong with you. I dare you. I
didn't cut, what'd you say to 26 oh, oh,
oh. I thought you were
saying. Okay. I was like,
how dare you?
How dare you make that mistake.
You will see two 26 okay, well that's
July, so that's not quite a year.
He's been relevant. He's fought
twice since that loss loss of Steve.
He hasn't fought. Damn.
It's heartbreaking.
Damn. Jon Jones, Steve Bay
coach, Javier Mendez can Tim wise
tp meal. Chuck is waiting for,
you can use to move on.
It's not happening.
I don't think he necessarily is waiting
for it. No, he is. He even wants it.
He wants it, but I don't think they're
offering him a valid fight him.
In the meantime,
I haven't heard any big fights that are,
that are being mentioned. I
mean, obviously I could be wrong,
you know.
Well, the only, the only thing they
could really offer him as what is funny,
I have all these questions and
I don't ever call Dana. Dude,
come on Bro.
I don't call Sean Shelby and I'll call
them McMahon or I just sit here with you.
We Talk Shit.
We just speculate.
Total stroke total speculation.