From the animal level to the plant level,
to the fungal level.
You find these things
everywhere. Um, you know, um,
and people say,
well,
there's about 150 species
of plants that contain DMT.
That's only because we've only looked
at 150 species of plants. You know,
if you look at these large genera
that are, that are, you know,
famous known for having tryptamines
like Acacias and my most and on these
things, uh, we know of a
few species that have DMT,
but there's hundreds of species,
thousands of species.
It's just that nobody's looked,
nobody's going to fund this work.
I think you can reasonably say that,
you know,
there are about 1400 species
of Acacia in the world.
Probably 75% of them have DMT.
And actually I would go to the next,
I would,
I would even claim without evidence.
That's never stopped me before.
But I think it's reasonable to suppose
that because DMT is so close to
mainstream metabolism,
probably all plants
have DMT to some extent.
Most don't have large,
large levels of it.
They don't have useful amounts of DMT.
But if you took with
sufficient instruments,
if you just started ranting randomly
sampling plants and analyzing for DMT with
the Mass Spec, I'll bet it would
turn up and almost everything.
What is a, which is it? Filovirus grass.
It's toxic to sheep because
that's CMT. Yup. That's the one.
So the DMT in it for whatever reason,
way it interacts with the sheeps digestive
system, it becomes poisoned. The, well,
no,
not entirely.
I mean it's got Phil Harris Grass has DMT.
It has five methoxy DMT.
Other trip to means.
It also has something called Grameen,
which has a,
it's like DMT with only one
carbon on the side chain.
Grameen is more or less toxic. Graming
shows up in a lot of grass species.
That's probably the thing that causes
what's called FileVault staggers.
So if you just fed DMT
a synthesized to sheep,
it wouldn't be toxic.
Hard to say.
Did they produce monoamine
oxidase? Nobody's done it
to shape. Yeah, of course.
So do leopards or jaguars all mammals.
So when you see those jaguars eating
the leaves and then tripping their balls
off, rolling around in their back,
what do you think is happening there?
You've seen those videos. I've seen, I've
seen those videos. Well for one thing,
many rare eating, uh,
banisteriopsis right,
which is the source of the Mao inhibitors.
Right.
And I don't know what to make of that.
It certainly does seem like some kind
of a catnip for them and caused us an
altered state for Mao inhibitors in,
in and of themselves.
They produce some sort of a psychedelic
experience. Uh, they can, um,
not just from the Mao inhibition,
but they often have other effects
that are psychoactive, like harm,
harming Armenia is a good example.
You know,
we used to think that
harming was basically,
it's the Mao inhibitor and Iowaska and
then doesn't do a whole lot beyond that.
Well, it turns out now harming
this, getting a second look.
It's interesting that the
tar mean, uh, you know,
was discovered in began,
I'm Harlow about
maybe 10 years before Iowasca
was ever reported to science.
So harming is one of these hoary
old alkaloids. I like to call it,
you know,
it's been known forever and now we're
just finding out it has all sorts of
interesting pharmacology's it's it,
it's an Mao inhibitor for sure.
More importantly,
it appears that it stimulates neural
genesis and that's relevant to Alzheimer's
and brain development.
And even down syndrome.
It is an inhibitor of this kinase,
this regulatory protein called Dyr k
one which has got its fingers in lots of
different cellular pies.
You could pile it many different
regulatory, uh, functions.
And harming is a very potent,
very selector inhibitor of this kinase.
So that's relates to this.
It actually stimulates nerve
growth in the hippocampus.
So, uh, you know, we're, and,
and we're finding out that there are
a number of other receptors that it
interacts with, including
Serotonin, dopamine transporters,
even one called the imagine
lean receptors that are, uh,
you know,
of undefined functions.
So like most natural molecules,
it's not a one trick pony,
you know, um, harming
has a number of effects,
you know,
and that's why taking Iowasca
is a different, you know,
it,
that's why it's not a pure DMT experience.
Cause you've got a whole
mixture of alkaloids that are,
that are contributing to that effect.
Who were the researchers that
when they discovered harming,
they didn't know what it was and they'd
try to label it telepathy mean to,
they realize that it was
harming. Right, right. Well yeah,
this is part of the,
uh,
what you may call the, the, the,
the sad and sordid history of the,
of Iowasca.
Yeah.
In a certain way because
in the early days,
in the 20s, when people
are looking at it, um,
a number of independent groups, we're
working on it. And they were identified,
they were isolated molecules.
They weren't aware of other people's work.
And so they misnamed these
things. Know, I mean, uh,
I can't tell you exactly,
I think initially it was Louis
Lewin who discovered, um,
uh, are mean and he called it bend
the story. And then that turned out,
well,
another group years before had isolated
the same molecule from began I'm Hormel
and telepathy in was one of
these misnomers that came out.
The problem with with this was that
back in the day people didn't collect
voucher specimens.
So a lot of this chemical work was
done without the benefit of her barium
specimens,
which now every everybody that wants to
do fido chemical work hopefully has the,
the good sands to collect specimens of
the original Platte so that people can go
back and look at that.
A lot of this early work was reported
and there was no voucher specimens to
document the collection.
So a lot of it had to be dismissed,
you know,
uh,
they cut the Beta carbon lean chemistry
of banisteriopsis didn't really get well
defined until, um, some
Chinese scientists, uh,
or at least they had Chinese name worked
on them and discovered harming tetra
hydro harming and the harmer
lien as the main alkaloids.
They could reference that to
botanical voucher specimens.
So they really should get the
credit for discovering it.
And then once that was done,
then it was known. And you know,
other scientists had to acknowledge that.
Why did they describe it as telepathy?
There was supposedly some sort of a story
about some group telepathic experience.
Yeah. This was just romantic. This
was just some story, you know,
out of the literature. Um, yeah.
I mean, I mean it, it was rumored
to be able to cause telepathy,
but this wasn't Iowasca they
were only taking hormone.
It's not clear. It's not
clear. It's not clear. Yeah.
I mean they may have been taken
but they may have been taking it,
but whether they were getting telepathy,
I kind of doubt it when we know
we could get telepathy on Iowasca.
It's not so uncommon.
It happens all the time.
People have group hallucinations,
group visions.
Has anybody ever bothered to
independently like sequester people,
put them into like different rooms,
have them do Iowasca and then have them
describe a very similar experience are
almost identical experience to prove that
these telepath he experiences exist or
at least to as far as I know
that hasn't been done. See, yeah.
Cause everybody wants to talk afterwards.
It's like I do see the dragon. Right.
I don't think that's been done. That
seems like a worthy study. Cause if,
if I've heard from more than one person,
uh,
in fact my friend Kyle
Kingsbury and his wife
had an Iowaska experience with a,
both had a visualization of their child
and then when they got back she was
pregnant and they want to having this
child from their visualization from,
from, from this experience. Um,
obviously they're very close and
they were together and they probably
communicated quite a bit. And, you know,
I would just think it'd be
really interesting experiment.
It would be very interesting. I mean,
and that sort of points out there is,
you know,
a realm of experience,
a realm of knowing that these things give
access to that's normally close to us.
I mean, that's kind of a
trivial statement of course. Um,
but then you get down to questions
of how verifiable is that?
How real is that? How uh, you know, and,
and people get,
um,
I don't know if the term is hung up,
but they can get baffled
when you start talking about,
you know, the reality of say the
entities you encounter on DMT.
I mean this is,
this is uh,
some people I know are obsessed with
trying to verify the reality of the
entities that you find on DMT.
And again,
it comes down to if you experienced
some, they're real. Yeah.
If anything you experienced is
real because you've experienced it,
does it have a corresponding
existence in the external world?
Well, you know, what's external?
Let's internal, you know, we, we,
we throw around these terms,
these,
these epistomological metaphysical
terms quite carelessly,
you know,
without really thinking about it.
What does it mean when you say
I'm in here and you're out there,
you know,
and then you take a psychedelic and you
realize that start official boundary,
you know, we're all one,
there is no separation.
It's separate in normal consciousness
though it's separated in normal conscious.
But then what is normal conscious if
not a reflection of year neurochemical
brain state.
I mean,
everything you experience is an altered
state because it's filtered into this
brain processed by the brain and you know,
the brain is a biochemical engine
that, you know, as I say, often
we're made out of drugs,
but it seems that our normal consciousness
is the best state to propagate
biological life and to keep our,
our whatever we've created in terms
of our community structures and
relationships and friendships and the
ability to build structures and houses and
things like that.
These,
all these things are done best
when you're here and present.
Whereas when you're on a psychedelic
state, I agree with you. Well,
the way I've always described it as,
if you had a meeting with God and you
went and God gave you all the answers to
the world, you, you experienced, uh,
undeniable beauty in the most extreme
form possible where you couldn't have
imagined it and then you came back
whether you hallucinated it or not,
it's the exact same experience.
Exactly. I can't put it on a scale.
You can't weigh it.
You can't,
like we've stretched the tape measure
around and God is 47 inches across like
just because,
you know what I'm saying?
Just because you can't draw and
measure it with what we term our, our,
our, you know, our metrics for reality.
Right? And that is exactly the, the thing.
Don't worry about whether it's real
and the way we would define real.
Is it good information or is it bad
air, is it not? That's the thing.
It doesn't matter where it comes from it,
it's such a fits good information.
Then it has its own internal validity
of whether it came from some part of
yourself that is normally obscurity.
You or it came from the plant teacher
or the aliens transmitting it through.
It doesn't really matter. But
we, we are obsessed with that.
We are in reality because we think
we're being fooled a lot. Right? Like,
and this goes back to
Terrance's Lacera era,
a psychedelic experience
where he had a Ufo encounter.
The easily dismissing amongst us would
go while he's tripping his balls off on
mushrooms. Of course I saw you. Oh, is
there a leprechaun drive in the UFO?
Like all that's nonsense, right, right.
Easy to dismiss. Yeah. And in fact,
that is the nature of these phenomena.
That's what's really interesting,
easy to dismiss.
You know,
that that was another aspect
of the experiment of the
La Truro I left out when I
was talking about my lecture.
But there's almost always an element of
absurdity in these experiences and in
paranormal experiences. In UFO
encounters, it's like little green men.
Yeah. Are you kidding? But right.
The fuck there are little green
man and little blue man. You know,
a guy you should, uh, have on the
show. Maybe you have already, uh,
is uh,
Whitley Strieber.
No, I haven't had them on,
but he's so out to lunch. Um,
I have massive reservations.
There's a video of him
looking at a fly in that flow.
Clearly a fly flies in front of a camera
and he's describing it as this a man in
a suit and it's like,
like there's something wrong with him.
Well, I missed that. I missed that part.
I think what's interesting
about Whitley and I agree, I,
I totally dismissed him, you know,
for a long time I thought, you know,
he is really a nutcase.
He's from the communion books where
people don't know exactly what a series of
books about being abducted and yeah,
but
I sort of have to change my
opinion somewhat because,
and uh, um, uh, Jeffrey cry poll,
who I do know,
is it Jeffrey Cripe bill is a professor
of comparative religion and mythology at
Rice University.
And his focus initially is sort of on the,
the Superhero as, as in contemporary, uh,
you know, mythology as a mythical
figure on that sort of thing. He, and,
uh, I was invited to, uh,
a simple, uh, you know, a workshop
that Whitley was going to be at.
This was a couple of years ago in Hawaii.
While I'm always interested in a free trip
to Hawaii, right? So I said, I, you know,
I like to come to this thing,
but this guy is a nut case.
I'm not sure I want to appear on the same
stage with this guy. I mean, if it's me,
say that, you know, he
said that cancer and,
and um, you know, and, and the, the
guy who was hosting it said, well,
you know, did you know that he and
Jeffrey Cripple wrote a book together?
And I said, oh, I don't, I said
that, I know Jeffrey cry bill.
I know that he's not on that case.
And that's interesting.
And then I found out about
the book and I said, I,
I told the guy,
if you invite Jeffery and Whitley,
then all come and we'll participate.
The name of the book is
a supernatural two word,
supernatural,
a new vision of the unexplained.
And it's really very interesting.
Um,
the book is basically,
you know,
alternating chapters.
Whitley tells us stories
about what happened to it
and what has happened to and
what continues to happen to him. He
lives in some kind of alternate reality.
I I t I get that. I mean, I don't
know if I accept it, but I get it.
And then in alternating chapters,
Jeffrey comes along and
kind of unpacks this and,
and explains where does this fit
into sort of the, the, you know,
phenomenology of mythology and,
you know,
reasonable explanations. And, uh,
and it's a fascinating book.
If you just suspend disbelief
for a minute, think about,
assume that Whitley's is sincere.
I don't think he's lying.
I think that these things really
happened to him or he thinks they do.
And some of the most craziest
things, these are not, you know,
the media has made like everything,
they dumb it down, you know,
and they put it into the box
of alien encounters. Guys,
a nutball, uh, you know, and they dismiss
it. But if you take a culture look,
one thing to Whitley's credit is he
doesn't claim to understand what's
happening. He doesn't call it
an alien encounter. He does,
doesn't play me anything.
He just says this is happening.
I have no frigging idea what is,
what this is. So that's
all honest. You know,
that's an honest scientific stance.
I do not understand this phenomenon.
So I give him credit for
that. And then he, and,
and Jeffrey wrote this book.
There was a very interesting, uh,
you know, later on, so I read
all this later on in the book,
there's a chapter where they get to what
is the possible physical explanation of
what's going on here. If there
is a physical explanation
and one of the headings,
I think the chapter one of the headings
and the chapter was labeled the soul as
a Ufo.
And that kind of blew my mind.
That got my attention. Because,
you know, when I did this,
this workshop with them, I was kind of
bringing the flag of psychedelics, right.
And I was saying,
if you don't aggress psychedelics,
you've only got part of the
picture here. And uh, and they,
and they were talking about how the soul,
how this could be some sort of a
physical plaza moy type of thing.
They were in woking, you know, scientific
terminology. I don't know if it was,
it was legitimate or not,
but just the idea of the soul of a Ufo.
And I was able to respond to
that and say, well, you know,
the experiment at La
Chorrera was essentially the
blueprints of how to build one
of these things that you're talking about,
you know,
which it was really this,
this transformation.
And so that was,
that impressed me.
I don't know what to make of it.
That I think, I think there is,
and they don't really know.
Nobody knows what to make of it,
but I think they're just
odd things going on. Um,
but that some people experience yes.
And uh,
and whether they are actual encounters
or dreams or somewhere in between.
I'm not sure. It would be
cool. It would be good. I mean,
yeah. I don't know. I mean, when you,
when you, when you meet with Lee,
have you ever met him?
No.
He is like the most drab
person you could imagine.
I mean,
he's like an accountant.
It's probably worn out from telling all
these stories worn out. Yeah. It could be.
Could be. But he was, but
he was a fiction writer.
He was a fiction writer.
And then he comes out with this
incredible real world story.
But he reads like fiction and I,
there's obviously something off when
you talk to him or you hear him.
I've never talked to him personally,
but when you see him in
interviews and conversations,
there's something off you now.
What is that something off?
Is it a psychotic break? Is it something
that drifts in and out? Is does he,
is he having problems with normal? I
mean I don't, I don't know what it is,
but I'd thought I'm really needing to
find that video of him talking about the
fly. Did you find it?
Oh thanks. The flies,
a man and a fucking space suit. He's like,
it's not a man in a suit. What is that?
And I'm like,
oh Jesus.
Two with lunch called the bed
with quite a few of those.
There's quite a few really
bizarre videos of him. He like,
he's having a hard time
with normal reality.
So which would make sense during the
dream state cause all of these things are
happening at night. Right,
right, right. This was the,
this is the big thing that I've always,
the big problem I've always had about
these UFO abduction experiences.
First of all,
they all take place when
someone is either, uh,
at night.
It's either they're on a dark road
where there's no one around and they're
sleepy or they're at home and their bed,
like the vast majority of them take place
at night or while someone's lying in
bed,
which is exactly when you're dreaming.
Right now we don't totally understand
the dream state, but we, there's,
there's a connection,
at least an implied connection between
psychedelic chemicals that your brain
produces endogenously that could be
released during the dream state and in
different levels with different humans.
I mean,
obviously some people have problems with
producing serotonin and dopamine and
then other people have
no problems with it.
And this biology of the human
brain varies, right? Right.
So it's not without considerate or it's
not without possibility that there's
someone who has a real issue with
these chemicals just busting through.
Right. Flooding their, there are,
yeah. Oh wait, no, there are people.
I've then does this mental illness,
but then does this contradicts what
we've already said about psychedelic
experiences?
Like why would we diminish his indogenous
psychedelic experience if that's what
he's having?
I mean,
it is entirely possible that
you're dealing with someone
who may be perhaps does
have some sort of psychotic breaks,
but also is experiencing
psychedelic experiences due
to some endogenous DMT dump
or dump of whatever.
And all these things are taking place at
the same time in the dream state during
heavy rem sleep and he's coming back
with his uniform stories of alien
abduction.
Yeah, no, I agree. It's, it's, uh,
I mean it's hard to Parse it out
and I'm not saying I accepted all,
but I, uh, it's easy to dismiss,
but maybe you shouldn't write.
Well there may be,
is something there we should approach
it in the spirit of here's a phenomenon,
right? We don't understand
that. We shouldn't dismiss it.
There's something to be understood here.
Not necessarily his understanding of it,
but something to be looked at there.
And I thought this book was
interesting for its balance. You know,
I would not have Whitley Strieber on your
show without Jeffrey cry. Yeah. Show.
That was the thing. Cause he,
it would be fun and maybe it's,
you know, maybe it's a bridge
too far and I'm not sure. Yeah.
Maybe then maybe we get to the
bottom of this thing. Yeah. Well,
is there something to be got to the bottom
right? That's where a bottom at all,
just one man's delusion or is there
really something at the base of it.