He still has his youtube account and he's
still able to, you know, the, with some,
one of the things that we're seeing
with d platforming is it's sort of a
cascading effect.
So Domino's,
Twitter takes you down and then
Facebook takes you down a guy,
not limbo but some other right wing
or that got like a said some shit.
And then Gavin McInnes, they taught boys,
guy took him off of everything. Yeah,
he's off everything. Yeah.
Yeah. And that's, that's
that. And with him it's even,
what was he, he's like a
hate speech guy, isn't he?
He's like fucking inciting
violence and whatever.
He definitely did incite violence in
that he wanted these proud boys to fight
against Antifa and he felt like the
Antifa people were thugs and that they
showed up at conservative events
and they threatened violence.
And then he wanted the
proud boys to fight them.
I actually had him on my podcast long
before any of this shit went down when I
didn't even know what the fuck the
proud boys was. And I was asking him,
I knew him as the cofounder of vice
and I know knew him as what I would
basically say is he,
he was essentially,
who's a shit talker.
He's a provocateur.
He was a clever provocateur
and it was kind of a funny guy.
Like he came the last
time he came to the show,
he was dressed like Michael
Douglas from falling down.
He had the fucking briefcase and
everything and the crazy tie and yeah,
I mean he's doing,
but he did it on purpose.
He said he's dressing like Michael
Douglas from falling down. Like he's,
he's a guy who would trick people into
coming in and talking with him on his
youtube channel and they thought that he
was liberal or progressive and then he
would,
you know,
he would basically talked him into
a corner and slash or Barry Cohen,
that shit or leg in a way.
Yeah,
he was doing a lot of that and there was
some of those very clever I was doing
on his youtube channel. Then he got
into this whole proud boys thing and we,
there's a video you can watch the
bizarre origins of the proud boys from a
podcast that I did with Anthony Kumina
from opie and Anthony and he explains how
the proud boys initially, we're
just a joke. It's, it's uh,
it was literally a joke and they did it
to make fun of a guy that was one of the,
was he one of their interns? I
think so. It sounds, yeah. Yeah.
It's kind of a crazy story,
Matt.
And then that shit took a real life of
its own and now they're fucking junior
ticket K of, exactly.
That's crazy. They, they be,
they all of a sudden it got away from
him and they became an organization where
you could just join.
So all these people join and then they
act as a proud boy and they were beating
people up and all this other crazy shit.
And he doubles down on set. He got out,
he quit.
He denounced his position and he
realized that his life is falling apart.
He's being labeled as, you know, he,
they falsely claim the FBI labeled
them as a hate crime, but they didn't.
But the southern poverty law center did
label them as a hate crime and suffered
several other organizations it as well.
But the southern poverty law center,
they've had some pretty crazy shit
that they've said as well. Okay.
There are a serious,
a liberal progressive organisation that
occasionally oversteps the boundaries of
logic and reason they,
but he,
what he did was start an organization
and I had a joke about about vegans.
My joke about vegans was the problem
with vegans is a problem with any other
group.
If you get a group of a hundred people,
what are the odds that one of them is
going to be a fucking idiot? Right?
Well that's 100% right.
If we're being like really charitable,
one out of a hundred is a fucking moron.
So if you get a group
like vegans were just,
anyone can join and you have,
there's 300 million
people in this country,
that means there's 3
million fucking idiots.
That's generous. And a lot of
them are Vegan. And this, this,
the joke was that the problem is not
the actual people with good ethics and
morals don't want animals to suffer.
The problem is you let a bunch of people
with no identity join your gang and
then they become a part
of this plant based gang.
This is same thing with the proud boys.
I think some of them probably went into
it thinking it was a goof and they were
going to go there and they
thought these Antifa assholes,
these 90 pound dork swinging bike locks
at people and calling everybody a Nazi
and a fascist and trying to shut down
every single conservative speech there was
at any, any sort of university.
These people were preposterous.
They were called Ben Shapiro and Nazi,
he's a fucking Jewish man.
Where's a Yamaka?
I mean,
it's crazy to call him a
Nazi is completely insane.
But he's the conservative.
They all right. And they'll all
left almost, right? Yes, exactly.
And so their idea was to have something
that would be there to balance out the
alt left and it got out of control and
so he denounced it and he stepped away
from it. Pulled with, but it's too late
because he's now what you said. See,
you don't know him,
but you said he's the hate speech guy.
You said he's that guy that, hey,
that's how everybody's going to see him.
So if you found out your sister was
dating him, you'd be like, what?
You're dating hate speech guy? Like that's
who he is. And he's like, no, no, no, no.
He's not that. It's like it got away
from him. It just, it became this,
it wasn't him anymore. With
all these people that joined
that were actual racist,
too late. It doesn't matter too late.
There's no room for that in this world.
I'm out the game. Yeah. Yeah. So any,
all these other groups hat,
once he started getting deep platformed,
these other groups got pressure to deep
platform him because they said, hey,
you keep the hate speech
guy. You're telling me the
hate speech guys on Youtube.
And they're like, fuck, okay,
we got to take them off.
And so that this domino effect
does seem to take place.
So with this Sargon of a cod thing though,
it doesn't seem to be taking place with
him because people are examining what he
said and they're saying,
well this is a sloppy use of these words.
It's not wise what he did,
but I do not think he's a racist.
And I don't think he was promoting racism.
What he was doing was he was
using words poorly off a week.
But yeah, I mean that's what he's guilty
of. But that's the, I mean that's a,
that's a good sign. He's not
being deep platform. Then if like,
like if people are taking a
beat to realize like, like, oh,
I don't hate gays and blacks. Like
that's, that's the point that the whole,
this whole thing has been a lesson in
patience and that's good to hear that like
this guy is being afforded
some patients about,
but in their defense,
he's already been kicked off Twitter.
[inaudible] he'd been kicked
off of Twitter before. I
don't know what for though.
Do you know what he got
kicked off of Twitter for?
He got kicked off Twitter previously,
so he already had that scarlet mark.
You know, there was already, people
are already looking at him. I mean,
he's been in articulate on Twitter before.
No Way.
I don't know what he had done.
He had,
they had determined that he had
harassed somebody. What's that?
This could be a new account, I guess to,
he's on it right now. Is it a new account?
Might be how many followers does he have?
13,000 yeah.
That's probably knew you had a lot
more than that. He must've, uh,
I'm wonder if you started a new account
permanently banned account. Let's see.
Yeah, he's permanently banned.
April of 27. Oh, so it's pretty old.
That funny. April of 2017 is millions of
years ago now. The news cycle is so fast.
It's too fast. It's weird, right?
It's, it's, dude, I'm telling you,
when I was at the shows,
like a story would be hot Monday morning
and then Tuesday morning I was like,
what happened?
No one gives a shit.