The Joe Rogan experience. Interesting.
Um, what else should we be concerned with?
We should be concerned with anything
that North Korea's doing. Oh, absolutely.
I have, um, spent a lot of time in North
Korea. That's why I brought it up. Yeah.
So I've, um, I advised the North Korea,
actually North Korean governor on the
establishment of a special economic zones,
which I certainly believe if North
Korea could have economic growth and
integrate into the rest of the world, that
would be great. And so I, I, um, when,
so you want all this was in 2015
but I've been there twice. Um,
cross the border from China
and zigzag the country by land,
visited 10 or 12 different sites.
So spent almost two weeks by Lance.
I've really incredible.
I mean, North Korea, um,
one, it's the most organized
place I've ever seen. I mean,
there's not a anywhere there's
like on the side of the road, the,
the stones are all raked. There's not
a stick. Every little line is drawn.
It's like total control.
There were very, in the,
in the agricultural areas there were
very few machines and very few farm
animals. So I saw people
pulling plows, like you know,
usually have the animal in front of
the plow and the person behind here,
there were like two people in front of
the plow and one person behind the people
where the, the uh, the animals
and we would go and visit these,
the just, cause they didn't, they,
a lot of the animals got eaten
when they had their famine.
And so we visited these different sites
for these special economic zones and
they would say like what they had done
and what they were thinking about doing.
And I would say like, how do you, do you
know anything about the market? Like do,
what are you going to sell here?
And they said,
well we know about clearing land and
building a fence. And then we left,
we went to,
to Pyongyang and I spoke to about 400
economic planners and I said, look,
I know you have these plans that
do these special economic zones.
It's totally going to fail
the way it's going to work.
You have to connect to the market economy,
you have to empower your workers,
you need information flow.
How else are you going to learn and adapt?
So North Korea,
it's a really dangerous place and
now it's even more dangerous because,
um,
president Trump threw it was this kind
of nonsensical hail Mary in these,
these meetings with Kim Jong Un,
there was no,
never any indication that the North
Koreans were planning on giving up their
nuclear weapons.
They never said they would.
It's the last thing they would do
because their goal is survival.
And so there was this kind of head fake,
which was like a PR stunt to be able
to say, all right, we're having these,
these meetings.
And of course the North Koreans weren't
ever going to give up their nuclear
weapons there. They're still not.
So now things are ramping up.
So North Korea in the last couple of
days has started firing missiles again at
the United States today and see us
military seized a North Korean ship.
So we're going back to
this very dangerous place.
And so I think we really
need to do a much better job.
We need much more considered.
North Korea has, it's really,
and these guys are really
smart. I mean, I, the, I, they
are various people say, well,
these guys are poor.
They must not be, I mean,
like imagine like we're playing cards
with them. We've got the whole deck.
They don't have anything, have
one card. And yet they're there.
They're in the game. They're
holding us to a, to a stalemate.
And it's really worrying. And why did
you go over there and like, w what,
what were you thinking?
So I thought a lot about it because I
have a background in human rights. Um,
I was a human rights officer for
the United Nations in Cambodia.
I'm the child of a refugee.
I have this very strong belief in human
rights and that in supporting people in
North Korea,
they have about 120,000
people in the most brutal,
brutal,
horrific prison camps.
And so when I was asked to be part
of this six person delegation,
advising them on the special, on the
establishment of special economic zones,
one instinct was screw them.
I don't want to be part of this at all,
but I also felt that if North Korea could
have some kind of integrated economic
development that would at least
connect them to the world,
that would create some kind of leverage
and that would, uh, that would help, uh,
help people. So I decided to
go, um, and I'm glad that I,
that I did, but this is, these
are really hard issue people and,
and it's very unfortunate that in,
in president Trump's negotiations
with the North Koreans,
human rights was never once mentioned.
And I think that that's
coming back to values.
Like we have to be clear about who
we are and what we stand for and be
consistent in fighting for it.
Do you think that Trump didn't bring
that up because he wanted to be able to
effectively communicate with them
and not put them on their heels?
Maybe. Um, but I feel like
has had they done, I mean,
I think that if he thought that
there was a real chance of progress,
but the hard thing was he didn't
know much about the North Koreans.
He has people and we have brilliant
people working in the United States
government and all of those people,
all of the US intelligence agencies were
telling president Trump that the North
Koreans have absolutely no intention of
giving up their nuclear weapons. Right.
And so maybe he did think that he would
charm Kim Jong gone, or he would say, hey,
we're going to give you economic
development or, or whatever.
But I think for most people who were
observers of north who had watched it for,
I thought that was not,
uh, so we gave away a lot.
So we didn't mention human rights.
We suspended our military exercises.
We gave them the legitimacy
of a presidential meeting,
which they'd been wanting for 30 years,
and we didn't get anything back.
So it had we gotten something
back then you could say, well,
that was a risk for taking maybe. Mm.
Yeah. I haven't heard described that way,
but I'm agreeing with what you're saying.
What do you think he could
have done differently though?
I don't think the meeting should
have happened with no is no, no,
no conditions. There were no
police. So if he had said,
I'm open to meet with the North Koreans,
which is something the North
Koreans have always wanted,
we could have met with the North Koreans
anytime I immediately for the last 30
years, but in order to do it, they
need to do this, this and this.
And if they do it, we'll meet like that
would have been a legitimate thing.
But what he said is somebody, the
the, the North Korean, I'm inside the,
the South Korean national security
advisors peeked into his office and he,
and he goes, hey, they wanted me
to go. And it was like sure that,
that seems like an
interesting thing to do.
And I think that with this diplomacy
you kind of have to get something.
And so we gave away so much upfront
and the North Koreans weren't,
didn't have an incentive to do anything
in return was his perspective that it
would be better to be in communication
and be friends with this guy who's that
was that what he was thinking would be,
but we have real interests
in the sense that we,
we have large military forces in Seoul.
We have a lot at stake.
We have our closest ally,
Japan who has had citizens abducted.
And so I think that was what he
thought is like, let's be friendly.
And then with the force of personal
chemistry, um, everything will,
will unlock. But I think that
was always extremely unlikely.
What do you think is going to happen
to that country? I think eventually,
and I've written this,
I think eventually this regime will,
will collapse under its own weight,
but it's really held out a long time
because you think of the collapse of the
Soviet Union, they had enough, Soviet
Union had enough bullets to survive.
If they had said,
you know,
we're just going to shoot everybody at
the Berlin Wall and every dissenter,
they would still be, the North Korea has
essentially murdered millions of people.
So with famine and execution
and, and, and, and prison camps.
So I think they're going to stay
for a while, but eventually, um,
there will be leaders in North Korea who
will come to the conclusion that it's
safer to oppose the Kim family than to
wait for the Kim family to come and get
you.
And that tends to happen in these kinds
of totalitarian systems where there's so
little trust. There's so little
loyalty. Jesus. Yeah. What is there,
what other conditions like
technologically, like what,
what is their infrastructural on?
So the general infrastructure
is absolutely terrible. I mean,
they have roads in the big cities that
are actually quite nice roads because
there's no cars. And so, um, but their
infrastructure is, is terrible. I mean,
all of their, their, um, power supply,
they have brownouts blackouts all the
time at their manufacturing is all being
decimated.
So it's terrible.
But they have really focused their
energy on building these nuclear weapons.
Because they think that these nuclear
weapons give them leverage to do things
and to extract concessions
and to get, uh, to get a bits.
It's terrible infrastructure.
So do they don't have an internet,
right,
but they have something similar but it
only allows them access to a few state
run websites. Well average person
doesn't have access to the Internet.
So the way it works is
it's all about loyalty.
So you need three or so generations of
loyalty to the Kim family to even set
foot in Pyongyang, the
capitol. So really? Yes.
So it's not like you can kind
of move around or whatever.
It's like just to be in the capitol,
like you have to have your loyalty
proven and so average person out in the
country, they don't have
access to much of anything.
They have a little bit more
now than they did in the past.
And then for this relatively small
number of elites who are in largely in
Pyongyang and in the other cities,
which are like,
there's a ring of defense around
these cities and just to, to enter,
you have to have all of these checks.
Some of them have access to limited
internet. Um, but it's, it's,
it's tightly controlled and it's not
like you're kind of going on Google and
look going wherever you want.
Right.
And they probably would get in trouble
if they googled the wrong thing. Yes.
And trouble. It's not just you
trouble, like if you try, if,
if my brother or my uncle does something
that gets me in trouble with the
regime,
the whole extended family is out.
And that means you either you go to
prison camps or you're kicked out of
Pyongyang.
I mean,
at this it's all about collective
punish and people are terrified.
And by that ruthless punishment
structure that they've set up,
that's how they've kept
control of the country.
And everybody's forced to rat on each
other, right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. They're,
they're,
they're actually the compelled to tell
on each other for one thing that you did.
If you don't, then what if you don't,
then you are complicit because they, yes.
So that's, and that's, they're
these horrible stories.
I've met a lot of these, um,
uh, of these people who are in the prison
camps. Like, I have a, a friend of mine,
I mean she was this 13 year old
girl and her father, um, was a,
like a low level North Korean official
and then he was accused of something.
And so this family that was
privileged all of a sudden was,
was out and just,
just these horrible things in prison
and rape and this little, I mean,
now she's in the United States and
incredibly positive and it's amazing how
resilient she is. But this is like a
real hell. It's a real, it's an issue.
And I think that for us as Americans,
as humans,
we're less human when there are people who
are suffering like this. Yeah, I agree.
Now, um, you were traveling
all over North Korea,
but what were they having you do while
you were so we would do is we would go
from one of these special
economic zones to the other.
And in each one it was kind of
the same story. You'd get there,
there'd be like a big field.
The farmers had been kicked off,
there was a fence around it.
And then the group of,
of the local officials would come and
they'd have like a big chart and they have
a plan. Like here's where we're going
to build this building and here's,
and I would always ask the same question
like what are you going to do here?
Why do you think you're
going to be competitive?
How do you know what
the market prices are?
How are your workers going to be
empowered so they can change things?
And many in the old days it used to be
you just kind of have these automaton
workers.
Now workers are actually
making big decisions and
fixing things and they didn't
have an answer to any of those questions.
And that's what happens when you have
these totalitarian top down systems is
that like if, if you, being creative
is actually really dangerous.
So if somebody says do x, you
just do X. Wow. Yeah, no, it's,
it's really incredible and it's,
it's so sad because I spent a lot of
time in South Korea and this is the most
dynamic place.
There's like I often I go to soul just
to see what technology is going to show
up here a few years in the future.
I mean it's Seoul is like the future
and then just 35 miles from soul is the
demilitarized zone. Then the
other side it's, it's incredible.
And the real problem would be once they
finally did get free of that community
or the of that,
uh,
that mean you can call them whenever you
want them dictator and that he and his
family, what would they,
what tools would they have?
Like how prepared would they be to be
a Tom? Well it's really the good thing,
the benefit that they have if there is,
so here's my thought of what a
scenario a scenario might look like.
And I think eventually probably there'll
be some kind of coup attempt against
the campaign.
Let's just say it succeeds.
But that would probably result in another
military dictatorship with another
group.
Well we don't know cause then I think
immediately I think the Chinese would
invade. Really? Yeah.
Cause people think of the curve when
people think of the Korean War from the
early 1950s,
they didn't go to the Korean War.
It must've been the Americans
fighting against the Koreans.
But the Korean War,
the two sides,
where is America and the South Koreans
fighting against the North Koreans and
the Chinese, the Chinese did the most
of the, uh, of the, uh, of the fighting.
And so China and North Korea is the only
country in the world that has a treaty
alliance now with China,
kind of like we have with Japan and with,
and with South Korea.
And so China,
their biggest fear is having
a reunified Korean peninsula,
al allied to the United States.
So I think if there was a coup,
the Chinese would immediately
move in militarily.
Then immediately there would be this
call to have some kind of UN body.
Um, and there would be a
call for a UN authority.
And then I think it would be agreed that
the Chinese would stay and they just
would put on blue helmets,
um, like as a, as a UN force.
And then we'd have to
negotiate what happens next.
And I think what the Chinese
would do would be say, well,
we'll leave when the Americans leave,
is that,
I think that would be
what will likely happen.
But eventually I think we're going
to see a Korean reunification.
And the good news of these reunified
countries like eastern West Germany,
is there's a whole system
of law that is just,
you just North Korea will be swallowed
into South Korea. And then you have law,
you have an infrastructure, and it'll
take, you know, one or two generations.
But I think that will eventually happen,
and I'm hoping it can happen
without nuclear war. Terrible,
terrible bloodshed. But it's
that it's going to be a big
challenge. God Damn. Yeah.
That sounds insurmountable.
Yeah.
Just hearing you talk about that all about
North Korea getting absorbed by South
Korea, I'm like, oh my God. Yeah. Luck.