I know what you're saying,
but the idea is that if you have a minimum
amount that you allow people to pay,
then at least the people that are
working for that company will have a real
income where they can pay their bills and
feed themselves. And that this company,
because they have all the power,
they have all the money in a poor worker
who's stepping into the market for the
first time or you know,
just hasn't been able to acquire job
skills that would allow them to make much
more money per hour that they would
be taken advantage of by this large
corporation.
You know,
the corporation is,
don't have all the power because
they're not the only employer. I mean,
all employers compete with one
another for labor and um, and the,
and they bid up wages. I
mean, you can't, you know,
pay people less than the market value of
their labor because somebody else will
hire them, you know? So if
you could talk about, oh,
wouldn't it be great if
everybody can earn more money?
Has there ever been a proven example of
this where they've had no minimum wage?
And it's been oh,
financial boom.
Oh absolutely. Well, first of all,
we didn't always have a minimum
wage in the United States.
I mean it happened really in the 1930s
but you can look at situations of
countries that have no minimum wage
and they have very low levels of
unemployment. And you can look at areas
where the government uses, well, I mean,
you know, they don't have a minimum wage
in, in, in Singapore. Um, and you know,
and there, there are countries that
since Singapore, one example though,
it's an extremely wealthy country,
right?
Well that's one of the reasons and
they have, well they don't, they,
it's very easy to do business,
but you can look at examples where the
United States has imposed a minimum wage
on other countries. I mean, the minimum
wage did a lot of damage in Puerto Rico,
but, you know, look at another American
territory. American Samoa, right?
American Samoa, we basically destroyed
American Samoa with our minimum wage.
I mean, there's, Samoans are, you
know, are, are furious about it.
This happened years ago actually. And
I, the reason I even found out about it,
I was watching 60 minutes and they were
doing a report about I think football
players in Samoa.
And um,
and during their report they mentioned
that there was like a depression going on
in Samoa and it was like there was 30%
unemployment and really high inflation.
And I was like,
what the hell is going on in Samoa?
So I wanted to research that on my own.
And I found out that we impose the
minimum wage on Samoa and we destroyed all
their jobs.
They're,
the two biggest employers were to
a chicken of the sea and starkist,
they were canning tuna and then they were
shipping the tuna back to the mainland.
But the minute they raised the minimum
wage, they made the production, uh,
uncompetitive because now you had to
pay the higher wages plus the shipping
costs to get the tuna back to
the mainland. So they, they all,
the canneries shut down and then
it created massive unemployment.
And then prices went way up on the
island because they no longer had boats
coming back and forth to pick up the tuna.
So now all of a sudden the shipping
cost of imports went way up.
So they had massive inflation,
sky high unemployment,
all because of the minimum wage.
So you could look at examples of
how minimum wage destroys jobs.
Uh, you know, right there,
yet they continued to advocate
for these higher wages.
It sounds good. Oh, everybody should earn
a decent living. Well, you know, not,
if you don't have any skills, you
can't. And a lot of course, you know,
a lot of kids, you know, they're
16, 17, 18, 19, 20. I mean,
people live with their parents still.
Uh,
the most important thing is getting a job
so you can acquire the skills to get a
better job to, you know, to move up the
ladder in an organization to enhance your,
you know, your value. Do
Employers in general,
what's the argument against this,
against what you're saying
about minimum wage against,
to all of these ideas that you're,
you're just proposing. Do you,
do you get a lot of pushback? I
mean, I'm sure what you're saying,
this free market capitalism approach is,
you know,
there's a lot of people that oppose it.
Of course. I mean he knows a lot
of people that don't think it out.
They think with their mind or their,
or their,
they're harsh and they
don't even get there.
The re the origin of the
minimum wage was racism. I mean,
the first minimum wage is here. It was
designed to keep employers from hiring.
Uh, the Chinese are from hiring blacks
because they know that that's where the
minimum wage came from.
You know,
to try to prevent employers from hiring
certain people. So they said, well,
let's have a minimum wage and that will
reduce a hiring of people who have less
skills. And, and so, and the labor unions,
the biggest supporters of the
minimum wage are the labor unions.
And none of the labor unions workers earn
the minimum wage. So you might think,
why are they, did they still care about
the minimum wage? If they don't eat that,
they'll get paid a lot
higher than in wage.
And it's because you always have a
competition between skilled labor and
unskilled labor, right?
So let's say a business,
a business man has the option of hiring
a skilled person to do something and
let's say the skilled person is going
to charge $20 an hour or an unskilled
person,
and let's say I can hire three unskilled
people for $5 an hour and that equals
15 well, hey, I'd rather
hire the unskilled worker.
I can pay three $5 an hour to do
the same job of one skilled worker.
But now if the skilled worker can
could lobby for $7 minimum wage,
now if I have to hire three
unskilled people, it costs $21 Aha.
Now all of a sudden I
hire the guy with skills.
So the labor unions benefit by keeping
unskilled people unemployed because they
have more skills and therefore they
can, you know, they can get more work.
That sounds like a complicated mess
to me. It is a mess for the, for the,
for the people that get get
priced out of a job. Yeah. Now,
democratic socialism is the
thing right now. This is the,
you're hearing it all the time,
you're hearing it constantly in the news.
What do you attribute that?
Do you think it's a frustration with the,
this lifelong politicians?
Like what do you think it is that's
causing this up for eyes and upswing?
The woman, what is her name? That
one in New York? Yeah. You know,
she's actually half Puerto Rican.
Might mind my countrymen, but yeah,
I forget her name and country.
Puerto Rico, United States. So
you know, I found this out as
I'm traveling now, you know,
I still have an American passport,
but when I,
when I mentioned what country I'm
from and I look where you live,
I always have to select
Puerto Rico as a country.
Even though it's part of America,
it's,
it's still considered its own country
even though you still are American
citizens when you live there and
you travel on a, on a US passport,
it's listed as a separate country from,
uh, from the battle to the reader name.
From a tweet that shocks Andrea. Yeah.
And you know Cortez 28 years old.
Yeah. Well, she beat, she beat
a 10 term incumbent combination.
Of course he was a white guy.
That's a, that's a negative for him.
She's but a woman of
color. Yeah. You know,
Latino Nice look at woman to
actually so, but, but, but,
but the thing is people I think in
that community are just voting out of
frustration. In fact, I looked
at her commercial, you know,
and it's a very powerful
commercial, you know, Kinda
like, you know about, you know,
I'm women like me are not
supposed to run for office.
We're not supposed to have court when,
I mean that's all bunch of nonsense.
But it's a story that, that,
you know, I think resonated
with a lot of people. Like,
Hey, let's stick it to the man. Right. You
know, and uh, and that's what they did.
But I think that this,
this a wave is going to be
bigger than people think.
I think people are underestimating
their like, oh, this is unique because,
you know, she, um, she's in a, you know,
a heavily minority community and so
that message work better. But look,
Bernie Sanders read this here.
The change just pulled up.
She won in a district
where she didn't even run.
Progressive candidate also won a primary
and our neighboring district in the
Bronx as a write in for the reform party.
Oh well that's alright. But she won.
She won. Well, I, you know,
I don't think you could have two
house seats simultaneously. Easy,
but the eyesight.
But if you look at Bernie Sanders appeal,
it wasn't just, you know, you know,
poor people and minorities that were,
that were attracted to
the Sanders message.
And what was that message
that was attractive socially?
It was, you know, it was,
it was, you know, giving things ratios
when we got, we got to tax the rich,
we've got a tax corporations,
you should of wealth and it's all
about getting stuff for free. Right?
It's all about, uh, you know,
free healthcare, free education,
guaranteed jobs. I mean, they want,
they want the government to
guarantee everybody a job.
Well then was one of the
things that Bernie said that
he could guarantee people,
Joe, you can't be one in the country. How,
how's the governor getting Karen teach?
First of all, where's the
government saying, where's The gun?
We're going to get the money. They
did that in the Soviet Union. Yeah,
everybody has a job, but
nobody makes anything. And
so everybody is poor. I mean,
you can't, they want,
they want a guarantee,
a $15 an hour job plus benefits plus
vacation plus health care to do what?
And of course,
what's the governor?
The governor is going to assign jobs to
everybody. What are they all going to do?
I mean,
people forget that we don't want jobs.
We want the productivity
that result from the job.
So it's about productive
employment, not make work, right?
We don't want it to government digging
holes and filling them. We want real.
And how do, how does a private
sector know what jobs are needed?
It's demand. It's there. It's
individuals that want something.
They're guided by a profit motive.
You know,
the government does that have
governor doesn't make a profit.
There's nothing to guide them to
efficiently allocate resources.
And how's the government going to just
figure out what people should do and just
assign them?
Yeah.