Do you guys want to go to Phoenix
to see Cain fight in Ghana?
You want to just fucking get on with
it. Is that it's like, it's Sunday.
It's a Sunday. I could do it. I'm thinking
about just fucking flying to Phoenix.
I never go to a live USC as a fan,
but I want to see Cain versus in Ghana.
In the arena though. 100%.
I was going to snipe me out.
It was going to stop you. Oh, I don't
know. Days with me. Well, the four of us,
the of us go live.
We'll put fucking snapchat
cameras on our eyeglasses. What?
What is the date? It's crazy. It's
a Sunday night. It's the 17th.
We check every free coun.
Yup.
You got me down for that. Would
you want to do, do it? I'd do it.
Take a private jet as long as it's not
this weekend talking to Eddie indicting
murdered fun man. That seems stressed
about it. Oh, look at this boy.
Your boy's got good. Uh, you're, you're a
DM buddy has got good takedown beef. Yes,
that does. Cause he knew he's fighting a
wrestler, Bro. Oh, blocked second round.
Two rounds for the, for Ben,
they had two friends. Canes.
An epic fight is an epic fight.
I really, how about this?
Not even, not even a little
bit epic. Here's why. Why?
Because Mr and Ghana all due
respect. Great Athlete. Two years.
Okay. Once again, Keynes had 150
surgeries. How it goes. He's 37 years old.
A fake skull. How it goes. Ready? Okay.
Is it lower down and then punches
in the face until it's over?
I don't think so.
It might not to be like Jds,
I think can get to a hundred I
hate to agree with Brian, but yeah,
never agreed on anything.
It's true.
Wrestling, you went to knock
them out like jds did. Cain wins,
but I don't think he gets a single.
I can just take some technologies
and shows him getting
his head in his chest and his bank.
JDS in Ghana is fucking
dangerous unless you have cardio.
He shown something to fight.
He didn't know what the fuck he was doing.
He thought, well, the Steve Bay fight,
he thought he was gonna
win that fight by chaos.
He thought he was just going
to go out there and Kale.
He did land good shots on top Curtis
blades and that second fight and Curtis
blades is a good wrestler in,
Jeez.
What would be Mark Curtis
plates in that second fight?
You got to remember he just
fucked up Curtis bleeds.
I totally forgot about that and forgot
about it. That's why I went for the FCA.
And you're gonna have a hard
time getting in the arena
companion. Hey guys, there's
a fight. Let's get more.
Be Funny to do a fight companion,
but travel, I always travel so,
but I was thinking we're going to
be taking it to the bottom on page
a party.
Have a good time.