The Joe Rogan experience.
I was so impressed with
the your performance from
that past UFC that I had to
had to talk to you. I was like,
that was what I've seen guys make.
Like you are always a very
dangerous striker from
obviously from the [inaudible]
hockey fight.
Every got everybody got to see that.
But to see how fluid you were
against a beast like Eric Andrews,
I mean Eric Andrews a scary cat. Yeah,
he's, he's coming from blood. Right.
And you were so fast, man. It was crazy
to watch. It was really interesting.
Thank you.
What if you had to give
yourself a percentage leap
that you've gone up over the
last year,
what do you think it would be compared
to like who you were before that?
Not The hive leap. I mean, not that I
like, that performance for me was like,
I feel good about it, but that
was only four months. So I'm like,
I know that there's so much more for
me to gain. That's what I'm like, yeah,
I gotta go back. So the leap, not,
not too much because I know there's still
a lot more to go a lot more. Yeah. Wow.
So you've decided, so for people who
don't understand what we're talking about,
you went to Thailand, he spent four
months down in Thailand and um,
you were fighting like a Thai boxer.
It was crazy. Like Martell, grotty,
who works in the production truck and
he's the guy who picks out the instant
replays.
He and I talked back and forth sometimes
while the fights going on and mark mark
market with his heavy Boston accent,
like dude classic,
he's classic Chi stance and he would
just sell a light on that front leg
inside leg kick was so ferocious.
It was fun to watch men.
So it's just usually wherever I go.
Um,
I've always been good at just like kind
of absorbing the culture. I'm a guy,
like I can go into a room full of people
and I can just kind of pick up what the
energy is like. And that's another
reason why I wanted to go to Thailand.
So just the way that they
train and the discipline,
the power. But the relaxation,
like everything I was learning,
just like then there's so much
more to Moitai. So I would just,
even the days that I didn't train,
I just sit around and just watch these
guys because moy ties with more than just
punching, kicking elbows, minters
balance. You know what I mean? There's,
there's repetition. Like how many
kicks are you throwing? You know,
the guys at the stadiums, they're
like their Kik, Kik, Kik, Kik.
So I was able to learn a lot, man.
And they're still a lot to go.
It's beautiful to see someone on
that pursuit. And I think it's, um,
it's much like Roger
Mayweather said about boxing.
Like most people don't know shit about
boxing. The lady said that, it's like,
if anybody say that he's going to say
that because there are levels and layers
and there's,
there's paths to go down.
And it's interesting when you see
someone like committed with a very,
like a very specific style,
like your,
like your adoption of
that Moyie Thai style.
So if it's so effective
as a striking style,
it's really interesting when you think
of all the different ways to attack with
striking that one way became
very particularly successful.
You know what,
before I even started
training MMA as a whole,
um, my first mixed martial, my first
martial arts class with Moitai class,
I knew that I wanted to train
Moitai or to learn when we tie. Um,
and so since I've started,
I always thought like, yeah,
I wanna go there. You know,
just, maybe it's cool, but, um,
[inaudible] has always been my thing,
but I had never really learned it like
the actual way, you know, like from,
from the root of, uh,
of where it comes from.
I always just kind of like passed down or
like Brazilian style, Moy, Tai, you know,
like shoot the box type stuff. So, um,
that's completely different from stadium
we tie and most people don't know shit
about stadium Moitai. Like unless
you go to, unless you go to Bangkok,
let's characterize it for people.
You do say that that core was style,
just way more aggressive,
different,
a different way they utilize techniques.
Yeah, it's light on the front leg.
So sometimes they are like more shogun
would be light on his front leg a little
bit. One thing that they were doing
a lot that it's pretty similar.
It's just like they go at it,
shoot the box, they'll go at it,
you just go until the other
guy stops. Pretty much. Um,
but from the shoot the box,
I was like very combo based,
like punches and kicks are like one,
two like you have to memorize these
crazy combos. Codero is he like,
I think he's one of the guys that just
like passed it down a lot in San Diego,
Lima that guys like that.
But they have this system and
it's very like combination based,
um, memory slipping Punchkick all this
stuff. But the ties are just like,
it's just straight kick,
you know, like punch view.
You fall down on that front
foot, elbow, knee. It's just,
it's broken down completely
differently. Um, it's just a whole,
whole different style.
Yeah, it is like, so the,
the shoot the box stuff has punches,
kicks, knees, elbows, combination,
same tools that you're gonna use
him Moitai button. [inaudible]
has got a whole different game
plan, you know, clinching,
like I've never trained as much clinching
in America as I have in Thailand in
just four months and I've been fighting
our training now for like nine years.
So just in four months I've gotten more
clinch time in Thailand that I have,
you know, in my whole career. And that's
because it's a whole different game.
You got to master the clinch and t in
Noida you have to for effective like real
true. Moitai are you getting a
lot of wrestling over there? Yeah,
so that's one thing too. I heard, um,
I heard shop talking about it. Um,
tiger has amazing,
like it's an amazing gym,
40 to 60 guys on the mat from
everywhere. Chechnya. Wow. You know,
in everywhere, in everywhere. Man. Those
guys, they come there maybe for a week,
maybe two weeks, um, maybe for a
month. But you're getting constant,
um, good training, grappling,
everything, MMA, boxing, crossfit,
everything you need is in one place. It's
a, blew my mind being there, honestly.
That's fascinating.
And your,
are you the coaches that you
were working with before?
Are you still working
with them and Thailand?
Are you just gonna I know you had talked
about actually moving to Thailand. Yeah.
Yeah. The plan is to move there like
as soon as possible. Really? Yeah.
So I was like hitting you up like
y'all want to get on your show.
I want to talk a little bit.
Um, but yeah, I want to, um,
the plan is to move to Thailand like with
the next couple of weeks for at least
a year.
And I want to go there just because
I can just train. The lifestyle
is completely different.
I can walk to the gym,
hop on a motorbike. It's
just, it's so simple. Um,
but to answer the question
about my coaches, um,
I always have my brother in my corner.
He's just kind of like moral support.
We started this together.
Um,
I had a conditioning coach slash friends
slash mental type of like support,
um,
Lorenzo Paprika.
And then my head coaches have switched
probably two or three times in the last
couple of fights I had Kenny
Johnson from black house, um,
John Wood from syndicate. And now I have
George Hickman from Tiger Moy. Tai. Yeah.
And so this change that
you decided to make a,
did it come after the Johnnie Walker
fight? Yeah. So the Johnnie Walker fly,
like that camp was tough man.
Like I was doing so much to try to improve
in my wrestling and grappling because
that was always like a
big hole that my game. Um,
so I spent so much time wrestling over
at Black House with Kevin Casey and this
guy that I fought Blake troop.
They're huge and these guys are great
grapplers so in cases of powerhouse, yeah,
he'll put you into the ground and he
feels like cement block on top of you.
So it's old school Hixon Jujitsu.
Exactly. How pressure man. So, um,
yeah, I would, I was just grinding myself
into the mat every day for that camp,
expecting like, okay, I'm comfortable
in the feed. If it goes to the ground,
I'm ready. And um, I,
I think I just completely lost sight of
like my striking my Moitai in that fight,
his size, everything. I just kind of
froze up, man. I was just like, ah,
I didn't know what to do, how to get
there. So let's all part of the education,
right. I mean this is what this,
this career of fighting that you're,
you're on this path is
what it's all about. Yeah.
And fighting for me is like big
self-awareness too. You know?
I think it's always important though,
when a guy has a setback to see how he
responds. Some people get discouraged,
some people get encouraged,
some people just decide like they're
going to be much more committed.
And that's what you did.
You just mean making that move to do
your camp in Thailand and seeing how it
paid off.
I mean,
Eric Anders is a very tough customer
and you essentially shut him out. Yeah.
It was very, very impressive man. That
was the, that was the plan though,
because I knew he was telling
me he's talking to them before.
I sparred with him before
that everything in like he's,
I've watched all of his fights.
The guy's hard to put away and making a
case for the fight being stopped. Yeah.
We were making a case. I mean, DC was
saying like the, we can stop this fight.
I was saying it, I was like,
you are fucking his legs up.
I feel like this is about it.
During the fight, I wasn't lying.
I'm sure you weren't, but
that guy is so damn tough. He
kept coming, man. I mean, he,
he never stopped trying to win that fight.
Yeah. There's no quit in him. No. I mean,
even in the, in the Santos
fight, remember? Yeah. It was
just they were due or die.
Yeah. And then he tweets, he is like,
I haven't been that tired since like my
wedding night or something like that.
He's always got good good tweets after
the fight. Shout out to air handlers.
Okay.