The joe rogan experience.
I guess the other reason that people are
on my case to some degree is because I
have made a strong case,
which I think is fully documented
by the scientific literature,
that there are intrinsic differences say
between men and women and I think the
evidence in that,
this is the thing that staggered me is
that no serious scientists have debated
that for like four decades.
It's that argument was done by the
time I went to graduate school.
Everyone knew that human beings,
we're not a blank slate.
That biological forces not parameterize
the way that we thought and felt and
acted in and and valued.
Everyone knew that the fact that this has
become somehow debatable again is just,
especially because it's being
done by legislative Fiat,
they're forcing it to me as a scientist
is it's just well in the states too with
tight with title nine for example,
because title nine is sort of predicated
on that viewpoint. What is title nine?
Oh,
title nine was originally just a piece
of legislation that mandated that female
sports teams were funded to the same
degree that male sports teams were funded
in American universities,
but it's been expanded out so that if
there's any differences in any areas
whatsoever between the genders,
then the universities are being taken
to court and like 200 of last I looked
about,
200 of them were up and they can have
their funding revoked if they violate
title land provisions. So it's become
like a vicious weapon for social justice,
Warrior equality of outcome types.
And so it's not just about
sports. No, it's got way,
way beyond that. Yeah. It's, it's, it's
become an equality of outcome issue.
Fundamentally.
There was an article that I sent you,
one of them was, uh,
from, uh, think I, I got,
I got it off of digg.com but it was,
um,
Jordan Peterson is having his
moment and we should ignore them.
I send this to you and
there was one part of it.
Hey Bro, the last part of
that might be true. Um,
one of the things in the article was
citing this study that showed very little
difference. Oh yeah, true. Amen.
And Amen. God pathetic study. Yeah.
Well I sent it to you cause I
was like this, this is not right.
Well the thing is like most
things, it's complicated, you know,
so our men and women more
similar or more different?
Well it depends on how you define the
terms first, but they're more similar.
Well why? Well they're the same species.
So we could start with that like,
but the question is what
are the differences and how
do they manifest themselves
and are those manifestations important?
So here's an example.
If you took a random woman out of the
population and a random man and you had to
bet on who was more
temperamentally aggressive,
if you bet on the man you'd
be right 60% of the time,
but you'd be wrong 40% of the time. And
that, that's not a walloping difference,
right? 60 40, it's not 90
10 like, so there's quite,
there's a lot of overlap between men
and women in terms of their levels of
aggression. And you think, well,
they're more of the same. Yeah.
Except so then let's say no, no,
let's play a slightly different game.
Let's pick the one in 100 most aggressive
person from the random population
while they're all men. And that's
why all the people in prison are men.
So even though on average
managed them well, yeah,
it's 90 90 90 to 95% right? So, and
often if the women are in prison,
it's cause they got tangled up with
a really bad guy. You know, so,
so one of the problems is,
is that differences at the extreme are
where the differences really start to
manifest themselves.
And so you can have a small difference
at the level of the average.
But out at the extremes it starts
to make a massive difference.
So let's say to be a Google
engineer, which is hard,
right? Because you'd not only,
you have to be an engineer, but you
have to be very good engineer. Say,
well you have to be interested in
things rather than people. That's,
that's a huge difference in interests.
Like men are more interested in things,
generally speaking. And women are more
interested in people generally speaking.
Now, there's still a lot
of overlap between them,
but that's one of the biggest
differences between men and women.
It's been demonstrated cross culturally.
It's also very big difference in
the Scandinavian countries. Well,
on average the difference isn't that
great even though it's a relatively large
difference.
But at the extremes it's the same thing.
Almost all the people that are hyper,
um,
what would you call
hyperfocused on things?
They're almost all men and all the people
who are hyper focused on people are
almost all women. And so how does
that play out in the world? Well,
in the Scandinavian countries,
it plays out this way,
but 85% of nurses in Scandinavia
are female and about 85
to 90% of engineers are
male.
It doesn't mean women can't be engineers.
It doesn't mean men can't be nurses.
It also doesn't have anything
to do with intelligence,
but it does have to do with interest.
And the differences in interest are
big now at the extremes in particular.
So when you read a review like that,
the one that was pointed out,
the first question is, well, what
do you mean by big and little?
There's more overlap. There's more
overlap between men and women.
Then there is difference on virtually
every parameter. Okay, fine.
Are the remaining differences significant
in how they play out in the world?
And the answer to that is
overwhelmingly significant because you,
you select for extremes.
So here's another example.
Ashkenazi Jews have an average Iq of
115 so in the typical population overall
has an average Iq of 115 points is
about the difference between the typical
college student and the typical
high school student. Okay?
So it's not a massive difference. But
if you go up to the extreme, say, well,
let's go look at people who only have
an Iq of 145 which is kind of where you
hit the beginnings of genius level.
It's like the Jews are
overwhelmingly overrepresented.
So relatively small differences in
the can produce walloping differences.
At the extremes,
people don't understand that.
It's not surprising because it actually
requires a fairly sophisticated grasp of
statistics.
But when we're talking about things like
differential outcome in the workplace,
um, then you have to take a sophisticated
statistical approach to it or you don't
know what the hell you're talking about.
And unfortunately many of the people
who are talking about things like gender
differences, they have no idea
what they're talking about.
They don't know the literature,
they don't know there is a literature,
they don't understand biology, like
the, the social constructionist types,
the women's studies types,
the Neo Marxists, they don't
give a damn about biology.
It's like they inhabit
some disembodied universe.
So the review was poorly
written at best and did not,
was showed it a very poor grasp of the
relationship between group differences
and economic and practical outcomes.
It's not just that it's
deceptive and there's,
there's a need in some way on that side,
this side of the debate,
the Anti Jordan Peterson side to
label men and women as being virtually
identical when there's so much
evidence that that's not the case.
And what your saying? Well, you've,
you've never said one is superior,
one is inferior.
What you are is a guy who's pointing out
the reality of the difference between
the various types of human beings and
you've been very open about the extremes
about, look, I'm, I'm well aware of
the extremes. I deal with MMA fighters.
I know a lot of female MMA fighters are
as aggressive and as tough as any man
you're ever gonna meet in your life.
And I know a lot of men from comedy
that are meek little guys who,
they're not nearly as aggressive as some
of these female fighters. Like there's,
I think one of the beautiful things
about freedom is that people get an
opportunity to express themselves
in a way that genuinely them.
And whether that is like a,
our friend Alex Honnold who's a,
a free climber who was like climbing up
these fantastic mountains with no ropes
or whether it's a female and then
they fight, or like Raquel Pennington,
it was just a tank and beating
the shit out of people.
And that's what she loves to do.
All of these extremes are available
to people because of freedom.
This is not a suppressive thing and the
ones and what's stopping people from
choosing these paths?
I don't know if you saw the most
recent slip up by the CEO of Youtube.
Um, I retweeted it today. Um,
they were talking about why
there's not as many women in tech.
And she basically said they,
both her and the CEO of
Google said exactly what
James Damore was saying in his
memo.
They completely fucked up.
They tried to find this, look at
this. This is God damn hilarious.
And James Demora had this on his page.
They respond to women.
A lack of tech goes could, you know, go
to jail, go to James Demaurice tweet.
Just go to the, the, the what
I retweeted and what he said.
So there was a study published
a while ago, uh, about,
no, Jamie's scroll back up,
right? It was right there.
It's right there. It just
doesn't make his tweet larger.
There you go. Let's see. It said he
sang, did I read this right? See,
I don't know how to say her name
is Susan. What? Jic Six, sorry,
I don't know how to say her
name. W A w. O. J. I. C. I. C. K.
I said that women find Geeky
male industries as opposed
to social industry's not
very interesting.
And Sundar cites research on gender.
That's exactly the difference in
interest that I just pointed out. Yes.
This is what James Damore wrote
in his memo that got him fired.
And this in my mind, if I was the
lawyer for James Damore, I'd be like,
oh well look what we have here. This
is, this is checkmate. You dummies.
The divorce story is really interesting.
You know,
because I think it's
such a classic story of,
of an engineer getting
tangled up in politics.
So Maura went to this diversity seminar
and he wasn't very happy about it
because he knew the literature.
And so at the end of the
seminar they asked for feedback.
Well James Demora is an engineer.
So when you tell an engineer that you
want feedback, the engineer thinks,
oh you on feedback and the and you
want like facts and stuff, right?
Cause that's what feedback would be like.
So do more.
Went and wrote this like Thoreau memo and
gave it to them. He said, well, you know,
this is what I think,
here's some feedback,
and then it traveled around the,
he got no real response from the diversity
people and then he posted it on one
of these internal boards at Google
where people can discuss things,
which people at Google do all the time.
So it was perfectly reasonable for
him to post it because he didn't get a
response from the diversity
people. He thought, well,
let's see what other people think.
And then it was there for a
long time until it was leaked
into the outside world.
It wasn't like Demora was trying to
expose Google for for what it is.
He was just doing what an engineered
type would do with someone asked him to
provide feedback because he's not thinking
politically. He's not thinking, oh,
they just want to hear
what they already said.
He thought they actually
wanted some facts anyways,
I think they picked on the wrong guy
because turns out to be pretty damn tough.
But he's very smart and a very kind guy.
When you sit down and talk to him,
he's not a sexist. He said he's a guy
that's talking about facts. In fact,
he wrote more than a page and a half I
believe on strategies for getting more
women interested in tech.
He's not a sexist,
this is just a guy that was talking
about the differences in the choices that
people make that it's based on just the
variations that you were just discussing.
Well there's a good study done a while
ago and unfortunately I remember the
author, but they were looking at
junior high math prodigies and they're,
they're pretty equally distributed
between boys and girls.
But by the time university came along,
they math prodigy boys,
they tend to go into the stem fields,
but the girls wouldn't.
And it doesn't because they lacked the
ability cause they had stellar ability.
It's because they weren't interested.
And it turns out like the interesting
turns out to be a big one.
So with personality alone,
if you measure men and women's
personalities and then you add up all the
differences in personalities,
you could tell with about 75
to 80% certainty by looking
at her full personality
readout, whether a person is male or
female. So you'd be wrong 25% of the time,
something like that.
But if you add interest to that,
you can get it up to about 90%
and so, you know, you say, well,
are these differences large? Well,
individually they're not that big.
They make more difference at the extremes,
but if you add the mop,
then you can almost completely
differentiate men from
women. So by that token,
they're,
they're very large.
And the interesting actually
it turns out to matter a lot.
Like it's probably the most important
individual difference that has been
discovered between men and women at the
psychological level and has real decent
explanatory power because you might say,
well,
men have a slight edge in spatial
intelligence and that's why they're
overrepresented in stem fields.
And women have a slight edge and
verbal intelligence, this is debatable,
but literature kind of indicates that.
And that's why they're overwhelmingly
the majority of fiction readers for
example.
Um,
is that the reason that there's
differential representation
in the stem fields?
It's like, no, it doesn't seem to be.
It doesn't look like it's
an intellectual issue,
which is also what the more pointed out,
by the way, he never said once that it,
this was a cognitive issue,
but it's a matter of choice.
Matter of interest and women tend
to be more, more people oriented.
Now the thing is,
this is also being discovered in
chimpanzees and other primates,
like if you offer baby
or child chimpanzees,
juvenile chimpanzees,
the toys choice between thing like toys,
like cars or people like toys,
like dolls.
The males will go for the thing like
toys and the females would go for the
people like toys. Do you see that
in primates and you think, well,
it's not surprising. It's like, well, no
it's not. It's not that surprising really.
I mean women have to take care of infants,
tiny infants and you have to be really
people oriented to do that because a tiny
infant isn't unbelievably demanding
social relationship and it's a primary
relationship for about two years,
you know,
and so women are tilted towards the
kind of temperament that makes that
possible. It's like, well, it's not such
a shock, really. That's such a surprise.
Okay.