Hello Freak bitches because I've hung
out with you a lot since it's been three
years. We've lost, I've been
hot though. It was weird.
We're trying to figure it out.
We're like,
why does it not feel like three wheels
three years now since were since I
couldn't come in for awhile
and I explained this to you
on the phone and when we
hung out a couple of times my mother was
passing from Alzheimer's and then when
she did pass it was like I was
emotionally incapable. If I would have,
cal couldn't even have said those words,
I would have been a blubbering idiot
on your show. Sure, sure. And you know,
you know, whatever. Some
people might've been like,
hey that would have been great radio.
I mean you were the one that said, hey,
get your shit together. You know what I
mean? Cause I wanted to come here and be,
hey,
be able to tell if I said it like that.
That would be like Joe k shit together.
So your mom's dead Bro.
It's us talking. You know
what I mean? That's how I
said it. I know what you mean.
But it would be more like,
you know, I went to, it was a,
the last four years probably started
probably last right before I stopped.
The last time I came on the show there
was like a big law suit over jump around
that I actually wound up winning, but like
if froze money that I depend on Brian,
like mailbox money,
we call that those checks.
It just kind of come in and
then you're jumping around.
It's been really good to me to jump around
is one of my favorite hip hop's 25th
anniversary this year, the whole
first album. So, but point being out,
when I first started hanging out with you,
because I was such a fan of that song,
I was like,
I can't believe I know this dude.
I remember you were weirded out
when I lit a joint in the club and,
and you were like, what are you
doing? I was like, what do you mean?
What am I doing?
I'm lying to join.
Everlast goes, he goes, you want
to get high? I go, fuck and,
and I go where you want to
go? He goes, go. He goes, Yo,
we ain't going nowhere,
but it looks to me like sideways,
like go splurge Shit right in
the club. And I was like, oh,
this is hilarious.
Wasn't that that same night
that you performed on stage
and there was a bunch of
musicians and it never worked together
on stage. Dave Navarro dated Camp Freddy.
They had like a man or they just did a
bunch of covers and I remember being a
fucked up and they weren't
calling me a bunch of times.
Nobody ever leaves his nails right there
like three or four times before I'm on.
What was it like to what is like,
yeah, that's true. This is a fucking,
that's us all. We're barbecue.
There we go. Like, God,
I can't see my eyes.
That's exactly the spot we were
smoking a joint in too, right?
It's exactly where it was bad.
I just never remember you looking at
me sideways and go and go, oh fuck up.
Go what? The hide in the bathroom
and smoke a joint. Fuck on here.
I took way too good for that bullshit.
Especially in Vegas.
If any place in the world you're
going to be over outlandish tipper,
be there because you'll get away
with murder. Almost literally
the valets, we'll say like, all right Yo,
the cops are on their way. You put it,
get the fuck out. I'm sure they
want to keep them checks coming.
Cops are coming with you like it or not.
Imagine being a Carbon Vegas,
Jesus Christ. How regardless how
many people they have down there,
Robin casinos and shit.
Crazy movie style heist heads with masks
on and machine guns and shit taking
over casinos. But um, oh,
I was talking about so that I
was like so much money got froze.
So I was having plus my ass crazy heart
like on the road trying to make up the
difference for awhile.
And then my mother started going way
downhill Kinda fast over two years,
you know, it was like dealing with that
is anybody going through that is is,
you know, gets, I mean there's a
lot of things that go on in my life.
They're getting my heart
sent out to those people.
Watching somebody you love just
disappear. It was tough, man.
That was effective. Right. It changes your
perspective. You realize that this is,
this is how it ends. I had a lot of guilt
involved because with a kid with CF,
I couldn't have my mom and home with a
nurse and any infections that she could,
she was getting lung infections all
the time. So I had her in a home,
a really beautiful home.
They took a magnificent care of my mother.
But there was a lot of guilt. I
was, I was fricking for a while,
like with a lot of darkness that I
was swimming through. And as that guy,
he's just wasn't good for me to
come through. And then, you know,
and then after cheap has, and Layla is
just been like a learning, you know,
I'm only just me and my wife now,
it's,
she's seven years old and I think,
I'm not saying we got anything licked or
co, but like the life we have to live,
we've been able to figure out
with her cystic fibrosis. Yes.
With the cystic fibrosis. Oh
cause it's all, I mean it's heavy.
There's a lot of shit you got to worry
about infections and any common cold
because senator the hot, it's like so
much pressure on a person to to do that.
It's, it's, it's my wife and I like, you
know, I won't fucking make it funny. We,
we've been very close to
the brink a few times,
but we've finally gotten to a
stage where it was like, Nah,
none of that's gonna break us.
You know what I mean?
We're good and we're good and we're good
in this life and theirs and we accept
where we are and we're going to
make sure this, this young lady is,
is going to make it does beautiful as
deep and as far into this life as she can.
You know? And it's been some medical
innovations to right. Having,
they're working on some
stuff, man. There's a,
there's a couple of drugs that aren't
quite for her yet because this drug has,
in the, on the DNA level of the
chain, there's, there's mutations.
Layla has two different mutations.
One's called the Dell Delta f five
five Oh eight I believe it isn't.
You've got me high in a little drunk
care, but no, no, no. People know.
People who know know it's easy to
find out. She has the most calm.
That's the most common one,
like the Delta five Oh eight,
and then she has this other weird
kind of offshoot one. There's one.
Some people have a dub dealt
what they call a double delta.
There's a drug right now that's really
working well for the people with the
Double Delta.
They're starting to experiment it on,
on it for people with the single.
Now does she have to be on a special
diet like uh oh the only diet we did,
we just need her to, she needs to do,
they have a problem gaining weight.
Cystic fibrosis, they um, uh,
they don't process fats properly.
They have to take enzymes with
everything they eat. So gaining weights,
a real serious issue. Um,
Laila actually has a g tube,
a feeding tube that she gets sick,
shake the protein shakes a day,
pumped into her stomach. Oh
Wow. Um, she again, if you're,
my daughter very rarely is down
about this. She'll have her moments,
don't get me wrong, where it's like
frustration and anger overheard, but it's,
this is life. She's never known anything
else. So it's like at the same time,
like we post a lot about it. We've, we
made a decision. Layla has her own page.
People are free to try and follow it.
If my wife will approve you,
if you can get by the security clearance.
Her thing is Layla l a I.
L a beauty oh nine.
She wanted her own page because we start,
I've never posted anything
without asking her. Right.
Even when she was like barely able
to understand, I tried to be like,
can I post this picture? A lot of people
will see it and she'll say, okay daddy.
And now she might, you
know, she's sharp. And uh,
about a year or so ago she was like,
I want my own Instagram page.
I want to share my life,
like cystic fibrosis with people.
And so she's doing that and we,
this is may actually a cystic
fibrosis awareness month.
So we've been posting and she happened
to be in the hospital the last 10 days.
She's home right now.
Recovering. Um, cello pneumonia.
Do an article on a cystic fibrosis
treatment. And what was that? Oh,
that was a while ago. I don't
know. But my wife and I are RF.
I did it involve CBDS.
I don't remember because I read a semi
things and we're investigating some stuff
on that level right now because there
are a lot of good things going along with
this because it's one of them.
It's one of the best anti inflammatories
there are when no side effects and all
kinds of stuff.
We're not using it on my daughter yet,
but we're investigating like
what kind of uses there are you,
I forget I'm going to have
to go back through my emails
or whatnot. And so she's,
I remember you did send me something,
I don't remember if it was cbds
or stem cells or some shit,
but I just saw level now there are
a lot of levels they're working on,
on the stem cell level there.
There's a lot of things going on where
it's like if they can create correct
things on a cellular level, at
some point it's going to be, yeah,
there's never going to be a cure.
It's a genetic disease.
So you can't say cure in that sense.
You know what I mean?
Like the way it works is my w two p,
the two people that are,
that fathered a child have to
each have the gene. All right.
So me and my wife are known as what,
what are known as carriers,
which we never knew cause we searched
our whole history after we found out.
Nobody in my family's ever, ever
had this. Nobody in her family ever,
ever had this.
But we're known as what's carriers.
So when we got together
and we had a child,
there's a one in four chance that
child's going to have cystic fibrosis.
There's a two and four chance they're
going to be a carrier. Oh Wow.
There's a one in four chance.
They have no nothing at all,
which is our other daughter Sadie. So
we kind of represent the whole spectrum.
Yeah. Like our family, you know,
Layla, her mom and me and Sadie. Um,
which is another reason I go, I'm not
having six kids cause I love being a dad,
but it's like two cystic fibrosis
children in the same household.
Even in a lot of people do it.
It's hard because they pass
infections and it's very, as you be,
I can't even imagine how
the people with multiple,
two or three kids with
cystic fibrosis pull it off.
I hats off because I know what it's like.
We're just one that's kind of the, um,
of not just t must be
changing you as a person.
Like think about like how
much more compassionate this
is made you and how much
more appreciative of how I've had to
also accept and learn how to deal with a
lot of anger. Yeah. A lot
of anger. Like, um, uh, I,
I consider myself a pretty
spiritual person. Like I said,
I've explored a lot of religions.
Um,
I find religions confining, you know,
I mean, I believe in a greater power,
greater high, whatever, something bigger
than us. I kind of believe in that,
you know,
whether you want to call it God or
just are connected collective energy,
you what I mean, whatever it might
be, somewhere in between their lives,
something greater than us.
Um,
I felt for another reason the
last three years is, is um,
what's the captain's name
in, uh, in Forrest Gump?
Captain Ed or no, Captain. Whoa. The
captain, Captain Dan, Lieutenant Dan.
I,
for the last couple of years,
I'm Lieutenant Dan on the top of that
fucking sailboat. Like, fuck you,
that this is what you're going to do to
this little kid. You know what I mean?
Watching my child suffer. You
know what I mean? There's greater,
there's huge injustices in the world.
And, and let me tell you another thing,
having to take my daughter to
children's hospitals all the time,
I see people that have it worse.
Do you know what I mean? Angela,
do you not know? I'm a huge fan. I don't
know him personally, but I'm a huge fan.
He's a great dude. But one of the things
he said to me that I'll never forget,
he was uh,
talking about the secret.
Do you remember when the
secret was this big movie,
the book traction and people are going
to manifest their own destiny and they
were going to make it happen.
And everything in your life you created
in your mind. And he was like, fuck you.
You're telling a young sick
kid that she made that herself.
She made that he, she made herself have
leukemia. She made herself have cancer.
You're telling me that fuck you. Fuck you.
And when he said that, I was like, wow,
I never thought about it that way.
But he's totally right.
That's exactly what it is. Like
you can't, that's ridiculous.
You're dealing with a bunch of people
that have become successful and told you
why.
Cause I saw it happening.
What about the people that saw
it happen and it didn't happen?
This is bullshit or a far greater
number by the law. It's a part of life.
It's not the whole key
to manufacturing a life.
It's an excellent like ha being
a positive person, being healthy,
having a good vision and focus.
All those things are contributing factors.
But kids that are sick or the monkey
wrench in any idea that we've created our
own reality, I don't, but you can't
make a baby responsible for cancer.
That's crazy. You also can't make
a god responsible for like, uh,
God has a plan, you know? No one,
sometimes there's a fucking plan.
Sometimes there's a glitch in the goddamn
matrix and you just got to deal with
it. You know, you got to handle it. And,
and the more important thing for me,
that second most important
thing in my life,
other than keeping Layla
as healthy as possible,
as making sure she knows that,
you know,
she can still achieve
and all that she can.
She's at an age now where like,
she kinda, and I, you know,
I'm not trying to have her hate me
in 10 years if she ever hears this,
like we're giving up her business,
but she's in a stage right now where
she's very resentful of, she is,
she expresses it well. She'll say, she'll
say, I hate this. I hate that I have this.
I just want to be normal.
I just want to have a normal life.
And it fucking rips your heart out man.
But you can't. You have to say, hey, hey,
you are normal. This is your life.
Your life is normal. It's like Carla,
I'm a big Car Lyn guy, you know, mean.
I know you're studied student of it,
but it's like he had his routine where
it's like about being homemade or all
natural. He's like, everything's
fucking all natural, right.
No matter what you do with it,
it's all fucking Nashville.
And that's kind of how I tried to approach
it. Whether it's like you are normal,
this is your normal life. You're not
any better or worse or you know, I mean,
you have to, there's, there's
fights. People fight that
you don't even see Layla.
You know what I mean? That you don't
understand. Yours is obvious years.
Is he right here in front of you to fight?
Some people are going to fight demons.
They'll never meet. Yeah. This is
a phrase on that, uh, what is it?
Comparison is the enemy of happiness.
Thank you.
I'm fucking going to use that,
Joe. Thank you. That's uh,
I'm gonna look it up and I'm going to
find out. Find out whose quote that was.
Comparison is the enemy of happiness.
I really liked that. That's it.
That's a very useful,
the inspiration sentence.
You should get inspiration
from other people,
but comparison is not really healthy.
Who Was it?
A State or Roosevelt said comparison
is the thief of joy. Oh, there you go.
Perfect. That's so eloquis
probably me. I probably fucked up,
but that's even better. God Damn
Theodore Roosevelt. You bad motherfucker.
He was a bad ass mother fucker.
Right?
And without charging up the hill
and San Juan and all that shit, man,
comparisons about the first is
Theodore. The other one was, well,
this is the guy that made the, he, he
set aside, um, the national parks system.
He set aside like Theodore Roosevelt is
the reason why we have the grandkids,
which our current guy is trying to rank
fucking mantle, not the Grand Canyon.
I know camp. Yeah. I was
happy about that shit. No,
everybody's upset about it. It's,
um, well, shout out to Sam Duke.
He's in Alberta Right now. I know. I see
him giving you a hard time cam and you,
he's so nice. He's a nice guy. As a nice,
and people threaten him. He just put, Hey,
look at this guy straight
at me. What? I threaten you.
I wouldn't threaten you and I can
probably kill you. Well, the whole,
but I wouldn't eat you.
That's why I won't kill you.
It's a lot of people in other countries,
man.
A lot of people that get mad
about his hunting pictures,
they're from some other country.
They're all,
a lot of them are from South America.
Like a Yam. You're going to be, oh God.
When the electricity all goes out,
they're going to become a man.
They're going to be coming to you.
He'll be happy as fuck.
And I need a recommendation on the
beginner bow. I'll, I can hook you up. Oh,
there we go. Yeah. Got Joe's a bone man.
Now Dude, I'll get a Hoyt to send you one.
You really want to learn. Yes,
that'd be the Shit I do. All right,
well next time I'm hanging
out with John Dudley,
I'll have him come and coach you and
we'll make a little video. Let me know.
Maybe I can attend. Maybe I
can jump in. Well that will,
I want him to coach you and teach
you how to shoot. That's amazing.
That would be perfect. We'll do it. We'll
make that happen. We'll make that happen.
Yeah. So that's three
years. Kind of a lot.
Condensed Reader's digest version is,
I,
I emotionally was in prepared to
be here and hang out and have fun.
I would have been like the,
I would have been the like
episode that everybody's like, oh,
you gotta hear this heart
wrenching fucking, oh my God. Well,
it's heart wrenching now, man. But
I'm glad she's doing better now,
but it's heart wrenching. But, but um, I,
I can stay in here like a man and be like,
look, here's, I've been through it. Right.
You know, you didn't want to see me.
And it's like you didn't,
it's like you didn't want to
see me cowering in the Fox hole.
You know what I know now the
battle is over. It's like, yeah,
I cowered in the Fox
hole for a little while,
but then we got out and we won the battle,
or we, you know what I mean? That's,
that's where I want it
to be before I came.
Okay.