Okay. What does that, how
does that James, I don't know.
It was in that period with the rabbits.
It said stoats stoked.
I've never heard of it. It's Keating.
It's eating a nested bird. Yeah.
Probably another cute,
but that also I learned about
from the mediator podcast is a,
how many squirrels kill birds?
Oh yeah.
They kill and eat birds eye.
That's a big part of the decimation of
the population of certain bird species is
interested in the squirrels. I'm
interested in this. What did he eats?
Fucking mice. He's a murderer. It's a
little fucking bad ass. That's crazy.
That little thing. Eat a mouse. That's
about what's a rat? It's eating a rat.
That's like his size. Is this something
that's uh, own New Zealand? I think.
I believe so.
Some Little Zealand murderer,
I don't think I've run into that
was native to New Zealand was a Kia.
It was like a parrot that flies around.
Was the thylacine native to New Zealand
or just Australia? That's Australia,
right? That's the Tasmanian Tiger
was also known as your total weasel.
Simply look at how he's nine
ounces just America, North America.
He's just had a little fuckers out here
at Merck and ugliness and stuff. Oh, okay.
Got over here. Distinguished by. Oh,
he's a weasel.
It looks like a larger size and longer
tail with a prominent black tip to kind
of weasel, which was terrific.
Level of carnivorous.
Isn't it funny that weasels are
thought to be like a little bitches?
You little weasel, bad ass. This weasel.
There he goes, look at him. Yeah.
And weasels will fuck up a cobra.
How about that? Look at him.
What is he doing that a rabbit.
That's how he's killing. Look at it.
Stoat kills rabbit 10 times its
size. It's Christ. 2 million views.
There it is. All there it is. Look how
small he is and he's chasing a rabbit.
That's insane. What a little
ruthless motherfucker don't show it,
but it seems very cute. So should we
do the play by play on lights? Doubt.
Oh, life. Stout kills rabbit 10
times the stoat or stout. See One,
I don't know. This is stowed
her style. I don't know.
I'd rather than in this credit or my
time outside fucker, look at him. Go.
He really is 10 times the size
that he's sharing his door.
I use kind of adorable though. The
way that he's doing it. Ruthless.
What's he gonna do? He's going to go
for the hind quarters, like a wolf.
The other rabbit tried to stop him. That's
like captain, save a hoe over there.
Maybe this one just, Oh, oh, that's
him pass by. I was going low.
How about the other rabbit? Just
sits there was friends. Gets Jess,
dozens of rabbits that aren't like,
let's gang up and get this stoat man.
How crazy is he? Doesn't try the wraps
it around really close to him on now.
He goes, where's he going? Is he going
like, so he's probably going to hit those.
We're going to hit those hind quarters.
He can get some shock and some blood loss.
This, yeah, no, he's gone. He's gone.
He's going to pull them down with the
leakage of blood loss and you get,
you know, he's going, aw, Joe
Rogan. He's going up. Oh my God.
This guy, deep back, look at the other
rabbit as what's going on. It's like,
this doesn't seem right. The other. I
was just going to look away you pussy.
We're not friends and even help your
friend. What a little monster. Oh,
dad is so crazy. He's deep on it. That
is soap. So he's got his teeth for those.
I don't know.
I was watching,
but he's got his teeth like
behind the ears of this rabbit.
He's killing it by biting the back of
his neck and he literally is 10 times
smaller than it does. Is it dead
right there? The other rappers like,
thank you BBC.
Fucking dorks help your friend.
That's why you're going to go extinct.
You cunts
fucking Nate. How about you turn a bitch,
turning them a bite him in the neck.
Is it closer? I'm really stoat.
They're stout. You think s?
T. O. A. T. It seems
like it would be stout.
Yeah. No, but you would be
stout. Stow Stout. Stop.
Stalled. I think that back wounds stout
and never seen one of those before.
My time outside. Never. You never met her?
No, I didn't even know it was a thing.
They're savage.
Next thing you know they're going to be,
they're going to be like nipping at
your calves, trying to take you down.
That should be the American animal,
not an eagle weasels in Ireland
and here or everywhere else.
They're called short tailed weasels.
Oh,
so it's some kind of weasel weasels
are vicious little motherfuckers.
That's what I'm saying.
Like why are weasels like the wheat?
So think about like Pauly shore
and he would do the weasel.
You thought of him.
We sell in.
You didn't think of him as being a
ruthless killer of something 10 times and
size. Those are cute. Like if Pauly shore
was taken down, giant bitches, huge,
25 feet tall women and just smashing them.