The joe rogan experience. So, okay.
I know a bunch of my u s team members
are going to shoot me in the face for
tough talking about this
because in the face, yeah,
literally in the face because one thing
that was an ongoing thing for when I was
on the u s team,
we,
there was this thing that went on about
how long we could go at a tournament
before we talked about
this particular person.
So during my time on the teams,
we actually had a person that was,
um,
she claimed to have a medical disorder
or she didn't actually claim to have it,
but supposedly it happens.
But she claimed to have a disorder
where she had attachment to items.
This girl that was on my team actually
ended up marrying the Eiffel Tower.
Are you serious? I'm not kidding. She
went and she had an attachment to,
yes.
She actually filed some claims against,
supposedly filed some claims against
a bow company that this boat company
actually had a rubber laminate
on the limbs of the bow and
Mary's, I feel cow. Is that her?
Wow.
Oh, she mad. Harris is famous
monument. I wrote a mini buses with,
you've worked with her. I uh, oh my God.
She's a former soldier who
lives in San Francisco.
She has been in love
with the objects before.
Their first infatuation was with lance,
a bow that helped her become
a world class. Our chair,
she is fond of the Berlin Wall and she
claims to have a physical relationship
with a piece of fence.
She keeps in her bedroom and the
fuck. Why? What are we doing?
People we can't.
We can't do this.
We've gotten too crazy.
We got to pull back.
We got to pull back. Here's the
thing, Mary. A fucking bridge.
Just pitch. Married a bridge. She married
a Brooklyn. She married the Eiffel Tower.
This bitch is marrying a bridge
though. Just kissing. Kissing bridges.
Parts of being in love
with a public object. Yeah.
What the fuck does she just say?
[inaudible] love of the public object.
Crank that up.
I want to hear this crazy lady.
I feel very, very blessed to have a
piece of my sweet Golden Gate Bridge.
Oh, Jesus stopped. I
give up. I'm out my home.
You there as long as I could
love with the bridge. Hey,
now, meanwhile your dad, wait, wait.
In the middle of all this,
there's a lot of people like me that
I've shot tens and tens and tens of
thousands of arrows trying to
win a metal for the country.
But that's different. You're chasing
an accomplishment. The bridge. Yeah,
they just trying to fuck.
Meanwhile, she's on our team bus.
She literally,
she slept with her bow one night edit at
an event and then got an infection from
the silicone on the limbs and the
rest of the team had to deal with this
problem. Um, when you say infection,
I don't know where the infection
was, but I have met Elle. Oh No.
I had on a step away from it,
but hey, how good was she as an RJ? Me,
this is pretty rare.
He's actually like gloves.
This son of a bitch. Um, how
good was, she has an archer.
She must have been very good.
She's on a team, right? Oh,
putting the hat on the bow. Not a good
sign actually look like potholder.
But she must have been like a
worldclass archer. Right? Don't do it.
Don't do it to me. John
does. I would say decent.
Good Archer. Danger decent.
Here's, here's the thing.
Okay, so she married the Eiffel
Tower. How'd that work out?
I think she's still married to it.
Friends. People were pissed. This is true.
This is 100% true.
French people are pissed because
American just goes over there,
gets his fiance visa,
marries a tower. Right?
So now we've got a dual citizenship.
Meanwhile,
she's got this thing for
the Berlin Wall. Yeah. Okay.
Well, the Berlin Wall is
a flirt, first of all.
So what Berlin Wall is always like being
real sween giving you this extra long
hugs.
The Berlin Wall in asked for it.
Jamie can not, of course, she's,
she's in love with the Berlin Wall.
Who's got how you got married?
She's married to Eiffel
though. So here's the deal.