I'm just terrified. Terrified. I'll be
one of you guys out there every day. Yeah.
All right. Now I know five friends would
go out every day. You, you're one of them.
Other guys. I do too. Every
time they get a chance.
The guys I play with Google every
day. Yeah. If you could pull it off.
It's like a gentleman's leisure
way of life. Yeah. You know,
it's always back when I was a club comic,
that's how I killed today.
Guys started playing with was like 13
and so I would just go to a golf course
and you know, schmooze out a deal where
I could play golf there every day.
And you ain't Jack Shit to do during the
day and clubs for 15 years. You know,
I'm doing 48 weeks and making 500 a week
or whatever it was when I started and
it was a middle act out there. You had
to work them all. You're, you know,
cause you do the $500 real bad. Yeah.
Do you ever look back on those days?
Look like to reminisce?
I, you know what, I, it,
it's a good thing for me that this
was the path of least resistance,
right? Because, uh, it
goes, everyone for stand up,
I'd be a regional marijuana distributor
in the state of Texas, in a, in a,
in an industry that has some
questions coming up. So, uh, you know,
I did it because I loved it,
but it was also fun, fun,
fun, you know. Uh, and, uh,
and it was easy for me.
I didn't mind the travel because
I like drinking free and bars and,
and, uh, and, and, you know, did, you
know, practicing this art form and,
you know, and I, but I never ever thought
it would, you know, go where it went,
you know, if, you know, people ask me,
well, how do I do that? I'm like, wow,
I did it. And I was right there
when it happened. I have no idea.
I barely remember it. Did you live in
Mexico for a little bit? [inaudible]
and factors that really,
really,
really good PGA player from
the same town I lived in, uh,
that played golf every
day where I played golf.
I didn't know him young,
he would have been,
let's figure it out. It
would've, he would've been,
he's like 21 or two now. And,
uh, he was in, he was on the, in the heat
for this tournament name. Uh, Abraham,
my answer is his name and, uh,
born in Reynosa Mexico ways.
They actually born across the border
because there's no wall. Right.
They can just come over there
and have the baby so that, and,
but his parents must've been fairly
well off for that part of the world,
you know, to do that. But he's great.
He's great and not dig it because,
uh, I, you know, and I see where
he came from exactly. You know,
it's where my son made a hole in one,
it was eight years old,
was on the capacity golf course and
rhinos and microcode holds in one as a guy
getting his career.
Uh,
I've had one of my sons had one,
you know,
[inaudible] like I like the
big guys, maybe 16, 17, 18.
The whole lot in a whole lifetime
does no equivalent in other sports.
Yeah. Yeah. We're all in one. There's no
equivalent in any other game right there.
There was a double eagle.
The uh, what's that mean?
That's where you make a two on a par five.
So that means you sunk a whole
firm to 60 to 262 yards out.
You made it on the second shot.
There's very rare,
very rare,
but dumb legal,
slightly less rare than Hohenwarter.
Way less rare.
Way less rare because a whole,
because that par three could be
as much as 125 yards, you know?
And then most of them aren't made on
the longer one 85. But know you're not,
you guys like me aren't hitting
the par threes from two 35.
And if you think about it,
I kissed this.
Nothing like that in any other game or
sport whole in one where it just works
out perfect.
Maybe your walk off Grand Slam or yeah.
Maybe this happened way more often
than, yeah, way more. Well, yeah,
way more often than the hole in one for
how many people try it every, you know,
you don't get many chances
at that Grand Slam.
But how many people tried to
have anything may pitch at you.
You're definitely going to hit the ball.
It's right there like that
golf ball's just right there.
I mean you might not have a good lay,
but you're definitely going to hit it.
Am I saying all the right? Yeah. Well if
you hit a foul ball, you got to play it.
You got to go find it and yeah,
it's just,
it seems like the odds of you getting
a hole in one must be off the charts.
It must be like 1,001 or
100,001 or something crazy
like that. Yeah, maybe. I mean,
but most people may maybe never,
you know,
what do you think the numbers
numbers would be? What are the odds?
Oh Fuck Jalil in one [inaudible] let's
throw the math to those carb guys.
Those signs. Two days they were
killing me buddy. But my, yes,
my son made one the 11th day ever played
golf in front of me and his coach and
his best friend and know,
and it was a 95 yard,
part three from the regular women's
cheese where the US kids club,
a driver that I still have. Wow. And uh,
and it just straight at the hall.
He had a great golf swing.
Kids if you treat them or you know,
he's,
his golf coach was good even though they
spoke a different language. Uh, they,
they understood golf and how
to teach him that showing.
And so he was good at it and he
didn't really play much anymore.
He decided staying but,
uh,
bad at 10 yards in front of the pen,
bounced twice roller right in the middle
of the cup. And I know at this point,
I've been playing golf for 30 years
and I'd never done it. Wow. And, uh,
so it was a big deal.
And he got his name and a couple of
newspapers and they mentioned him on the
golf channel.
He was the youngest kid that had
made a hole in one that year that was
registered and then like two weeks later,
a six year old tits.
And my son was like, uh, you know, they
took all the joy out of it for him. Yeah.
That was one kid. He was lucky hit
his, went on an off a mailbox. You're,
you're just going off a perfect golf shot,
golf shot. It's a hard thing to learn,
right. That swing, Eh, you know, it is
a really difficult thing to do and it's,
it's just a,
it's a thing that you learn how to aim.
It's like a bow and Arrow, you know, uh,
even though that's a little easier
to teach somebody how to do,
but to do it exceptionally
well, you know, it's, it's,
it's not easy to do and a and,
or a sling shot,
how to get the power at the right spot or,
or even flat casting.
It's not power everywhere.
It's power in the right spot that does it.
And whip of the risks.
Yeah. And, uh, so it's,
it's, it's hard to do, but it's
fun to do once you, once you,
once you learn how to hit a good solid
golf shot and the ball comes off the way,
as opposed to it's, you know, it's
bliss. I'll tell you something. Here's,
here's the story about golf.
My best friend who passed
away died of brain cancer.
So they had done a surgery on him that
it had just Dan scars down his neck,
down his back where they were trying
to Harvard. They were, you know,
they were shooting it, you know,
he was already, you know, he had,
he should have had a death sentence.
We just weren't saying it out loud.
And we were, uh, at by plays
and Montecito, and, uh,
we had thrown everything at this cancer,
but the kitchen sink and we were looking
for the fucking thing, you know, and, uh,
and Steve Goes, let's go golf course, man.
Uh, he goes, I'll help you read some pots.
He was always good at reading.
Puds we'd been playing golf
since we were little kids.
We'd known each other since
we were six. And, uh, and, uh,
so when I got my clubs at
his clubs were in there too,
so he reached into his pill bag and
takes another pill of pain pill and said,
after all mine on there, you
know, I'm not taking a swing. So,
and he did off the first tee box and
it hurt and it wasn't very good. And,
uh, and, and he just went and, uh,
but every once in a while he'd put a ball
down and he's hit it and we get to the
17th hole is a par 367 yards as long.
Oh.
And he hits his drive with his,
with his driver and, and uh,
and it fades off a little bit to
the rapid he caught it. And, uh,
so it was up kind of by
the world up by the green,
but the was kind of on the other side. And
I was like, great, you know, didn't, uh,
and so he hits a chip shot, which is
easier to do. And he's always really,
really been good at that. And he hits
it to about seven feet. And I'm like,
oh my God,
he's got a seven foot putt for par.
And he makes it,
and this Diane man gets the biggest
grant I've ever seen in my life.
And it was crooked because
his muscles had been cut,
but it just brought him pure fucking joy.
And then I got to see the last par he ever
made. So, and uh, I got to witness that,
you know, joy. That's pretty cool.
Awesome. That's pretty cool. That's
golf, you know, it can, you know,
if it means that much to you,
you know,
it can make you feel better if you
do it right. One time. I get it.
I think it's like in any
difficult game like that,
I guess it'd be like
that with a lot of games,
but there's something about golf to there.
It's very physical and
you're doing it outside.
It's one of the only things you have
to do outside, you know, other than,
I guess you could do Tennyson's
I'd like really, right.
But golf is a fucking giant ass course.
You're going to be walking.
You gotta go outside.