Hello Freak bitches. Have they
heard at Starbucks? You know what,
how many times I go to an audition,
I hear this like my, this is my,
a lot of people don't like to audition.
I like to audition and I tell you why.
Cause I fuck with them cause you funny.
You know I've ripped my pants.
You know if you watch, uh, uh,
what's that show on CBS
that's been on forever.
I don't fuck you on a Monday nights.
Big Bang theory. The one before that.
How I met your mother. I did. How, you
know how I got, how I met your mother.
I didn't even know he did it. Yeah. If
you watch the episode, you're like, Joey,
you're an extra, I'm an extra. You know
why? Because I want him to the audition.
I had no underwear on and there was this,
you see these things that pop
out of chairs. Yeah. Side things.
Armrests and she goes,
get up to read. When I,
when I got up to read the fucking thing,
you got caught in the hole in
my pants and my dick came out.
All three women sat there and I go to
[inaudible] grow and then I lost them for
sure. They even told me
they go, you got the job.
As I was walking down the street on Fox,
my phone rang my age. She goes, go back.
You didn't even read, I didn't even
read it. They had called. My agent said,
we love this guy.
I went back and
they saw the Cuban, they grow, you know,
probably not used to someone
with confidence. It didn't
give a fuck. You know,
I went to an audition one time bro, where
the guy had done, never forget this,
the guy was a white trash guy.
Like this family moved in.
It was a pilot for ABC and this
guy is one of those guys that uh,
he had a little circular pool in
front of his house and he was,
he was watering shit,
but at the same time he had
like a [inaudible] and he's
fat and he's got jewelry
on like one of those guys are like
long island. You know what I'm saying?
I'll never forget, I get to the audition.
All these guys are that Tony Line go,
God rest his soul.
He's Big Italian dudes and
I knew that we're going to
get the park, bro. I'm like,
they're going to get the part. I'm not
going to get it, but I had warm ups on.
All right.
I had a warmup sign with the string and
I had white tidy whities and that the
zip up jacket and I had a way
three 80 so I walked in. I go,
I know what I'm going to do. I'm going to
take my pants off, right. I'm taking my
walk in and what do you think these two
ladies say to me? I hold on one second,
we'll be bit with you in a minute. So
they turn around. That's my cube bitch.
I took those sweat pants off.
I took the shoes off and my socks and I
walked closer and I took my shirt off.
When they turned back around,
all I had was boxer shorts on
like the tidy whities. That's it.
Ted's hanging out stomach,
hanging over the and the way they did as
soon as they turned around and they're
like, oh my God, they're like, that
is terrible. What you sure? I'm like,
I'm not putting on shit. All right,
I'm reading this motherfucker. However.
So you were supposed to like wave and
say good morning and they're like action
and I'm, and they like can't even look
me cause I'm going to do, we make it,
you know,
and they'll can't even look at me and I'm
making believe on flipping burgers and
like look over at them. I go
live in like a doctor. That's it.
They booked me when I
got through the audition.
That was the read live in like a doctor.
They even gave my own line of
clothes or dishes I wanted to,
they gave me whatever line
I said in the audition,
like whatever they said wasn't good
enough, go nail my own fucking line.
Yeah, that's, that's probably why you got
it. What does this look, look and Joey,
he's just sitting in the back. That's
when you were in those big daddy shirts.
Yeah. Look how big I was.
Jesus Christ. You are enormous.
Back then [inaudible] it must've been
like, what, 2000 then? Right? Right. Yeah.
This is 2000 2002 when I met you,
like right after my chair brought you
onto the set of news radio. Oh by name,
and they were all like,
um,
W who is this guy we can leather jacket
on because this guy, your friend,
like I go,
that's Charlie.
Okay.