So as much as possible,
it's usually four fights a year and
then as you get better it drops to three
fights. And then when you're the champion
that drops the two fights. So, um, that's,
that's the progression of fault of
fighting. You can't, like for instance,
how many fights did the anti
have this year? Maybe two.
It before, when you start it now he
would have like three to four. Yeah.
He's very angry that this rematch is
not happening. And I side with him,
it was a Tyson and pulled out Tyson
got a deal with ESPN. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
and it's, it's a, it's a big deal because
I, you know, talking about chess match,
I think that's, he's pulled off the
greatest chess match move there is
first he comes over from England.
He wouldn't,
he takes the challenge if we Deontae uh,
Joshua didn't,
he boxed had a great fight.
Now he's put himself right up with all,
all three of them are on the same line
to me. And then now for the rematch,
they want to,
people want to see Deontae and they
want to see Tyson fury again because the
first fight was exciting. Uh, Joshua,
who's he fighting?
You know he's going to fight the big baby,
but nobody knows him.
Everybody knows Deontae boxing fans.
Now that's about everybody knows Tyson.
Everybody in,
especially after that fight because
it was such a spectacular fight.
Oh my God.
The first knocked down was great.
The second knock down was preposterous.
So the fact that he rose like Lazarus.
Yeah. I mean it was crazy. And then one,
the rest of the round he gets tagged a
few times and it starts boxing and then
even tagged Deontae I still had them
winning that fight. It was close. Oh,
Tyson. I think by around thing
boxing one that night. Every, yeah.
Both guys looked great and uh, boxed
well and made it exciting. Fight that,
the rematch. Obviously everybody
wants to see the rematch again.
So when the rematch happened
that that put, um, Anthony
Joshua on the shelf. Yeah.
In my eyes now is put them on the
shelf a bit longer with this ESPN deal.
And you know, Tyson fury
is boxing in front of, uh,
the public, uh, Anthony,
Joshua and Deontae there pay per
view right now. Who are they?
Gonna fight paper view.
Nobody wants to see no silly flight.
They want to see what the
flights. Yeah. You know, it's,
it's a great move by Tyson fury. It's
a great mood. But the first fight,
the fight ended in a draw, right?
Yeah. Yeah. So in the draw,
Deontae keeps the title,
but it least Tyson walks away like saying,
look, look, I won the decision. I feel
like I should have won the decision.
There's a dispute,
there's a debate about it,
but everybody wants to see that fight.
I'm going to draw is not unreasonable,
but kaizen could lose to,
somebody
can lose to some fucking awesome. Yeah.
I want them mucking around saying, oh,
I'll fight. This all won't find it
till next year somebody might lose.
This is what happens.
And now none of them can fight other
because if Joshua fights fury and loses to
fury,
Joshua was a star goes down.
If Josh will fights Deontae and beats
Deontae the Tyson Deontae fights.
Not that exciting. But if Joshua
wants real respect, he's got a fight,
either fury or Deontay fights.
Those are the big fight
obviously gets respect.
He's the heavyweight champion of
the world, but split. You know,
that's a weird thing too. I'd like to see
Joshua Ortiz. I been interesting fight.
It would be an interesting cause.
Our teas can box and hit. Yeah.
Well that was what showed how God damn
powerful Deontae is that Ortiz was
winning that fight. Yeah. And then I
was, I think it was the 10th round,
so the seventh or 10th I don't remember.
But I remember when he called them,
I was like, God, that guy, he me late
in the fight. That guy carries that pal.