The Joe Rogan experience. Oh, that's why
I made a tweet. Somebody posted before,
like I'm just saying how Cory steady
dropping down the rankings when you got
guys like diamond race,
he beat Volkow who is four and everybody
say he lost that fight but he's Volcom
was six actually sound like that.
He lost that fight.
But he jumped up there for like,
how does he want off decision?
Like oh it's cause you
lose or win on decision.
They don't move rankings up for decision.
Then he won off decision.
He went up to number four and somebody
said, how did that even possible? I said,
it's to the point now I can't worry
about fighting hoopers and charge the
rankings and my opponent.
Cause if I worry about both of them,
I'm not focused on something.
I was worried about the opponent.
I'm going to keep beating whoever they
put in front of me and eventually had to
keep trying to put these guys at
the fight. John like off knockout.
So you said Andrea Smith.
He knocked out Rashad, uh,
shogun and then choked out Vulcan.
He went up there to UFC John
and he had an underground.
All the extra stuff is good
when you're knocking guys out.
And I think it's gonna be, same thing with
Santo. He known for knocking guys out,
but his losses, um, an 85 other than
branch, he also Eric Spicy on the ground.
John is good on the ground.
John's going to take them down
as soon as you can run to me,
you hit him one shot, I'm gonna take you
down and you ain't gonna have no answer.
Right.
You know what I mean?
If you don't have everything tested by
the time when it's time to go to the
championship fight, if you gained, do on
striking is over. Tiago to me seems like,
I mean,
he's a very dangerous guy,
but almost like so aggressive that
he's almost like a kamikaze guy.
Like he's do or die,
like kill or be killed.
He comes in just swinging and
throwing hammers and if he connects,
it's dangerous. If you can act is bad
for everybody, but it might not connect,
you know? I mean, that's kind
of how he is. He's, he's a,
he's a a wild card.
That's the best way to put it.
Like he could connect on John if John
fucks around and I don't think he will.
I think, I mean he hasn't ever before
except for the Gustafson fight.
I don't think he was prepared
as much as he should have.
And we saw that in the second
fight where he just dominated him.
But I think that if he makes a mistake,
Tiago could shut the lights out
on anybody. That guy of swings,
he throws like it's less sledgehammer.
Even rose is not trying to make it to
the final round. He's not pacing himself,
does none of that. That
dude, he comes out hard.
But it's like I think
about him as my fight.
We are literally Chiefy going into
that fight. We, I knew 100% now there.
He's going to try the rest of me.
If he can't take me now,
everything is going to be haymakers cause
he seen me get touched in the chin and
go down a robble. So as long as I
keep moving, if I make him miss,
he's going to get tired.
And he's going to stop throwing those
big haymakers and sometimes when he's
swinging,
he missed.
He almost falls over and it gives you
like the counter or to take down. Yeah,
that's thing in our division.
There's so many people not right.
More like rock 'em sock 'em robots I
think cause they got their hands up and
they blocking and it's like, oh he's not
hitting the but with four ounce gloves.
I guess I'll put like I was caged Safa
Ryan Bader in John Anthony Johnson Bader
had his hands up but Rumba
was hit his hand so hard.
Also you see his hands just drop,
he was out.
It doesn't matter if you let them hit,
you get a chance to still getting wobbled.
And I think with John,
John's good at evading punches.
Most guys stand our block and counter
back or try to take a punch and hit you
back. Like take a punch to give a
punch. Yeah. It's not that kind of,
he's going to move,
move, move and you swing.
He so long he can put his hands out
and keep your distance and hit you with
those quick, fast, long kicks and
stuff and I just, like you said,
I don't see John Messing around.
He knows is dangerous. He's smart.
I will say John's not only
the best fighter if he's
pot and mentally as a mixed
martial artist, he sees what's going
on really well. He knows how to adapt.
He can go out there and try tricky stuff
at times when he know I can try some
stuff right here and get away
with it cause I'm home. Yeah.
I could show gun fight. He went out
there and showed up jumping knees,
jumped with the kicks because Shogun
was so short. Yeah, he knew. He said,
I'm a different breed. I'm longer on
fast and tricky, but I think we'll come.
A guy like Gus,
he didn't do all that stuff,
but he knew he had to stay long in the
vape punches and kit to take down and hit
him when you can. Yeah. The Gospel
fight. He showed his metal, right.
It showed that he could take it and
then winning the championship rounds,
even in a fight that he wasn't
really properly prepared for.
He showed that in the
Vito Belfort fight too,
when he got caught up with that arm bar,
he overcomes adversity.
He's not just a hammer. He knows how
to be the nail. He knows how to do it.