Those are the operation paperclip.
You can call it paper clip. He Shit,
our government brought those. He, you
think he would always say to us? Yeah,
but that's the, I think there was several
waves. There was like 34,000 of them.
Yeah. There was a lot of fucking Nazi
scientists brought over on Youtube.
It says a operation paperclip was,
uh,
anywhere from like 1200 to 1500 psi.
The total number of admitted congressional
hearings in the 1970s operation
paperclip, Frank Church Committee in the
70s released it and leave the numbers.
34,000, 207 look it up. There's a lot.
I told you they give people simple as
you pulled it up, but it is fascinating.
They brought those people over
here and that's where the,
the space program came from. Came
from the shirt. Not as a sick joke.
They already had the
CIA. That was LSS. Okay.
The CIA's Oss. That's all on record. Okay.
I'm glad you question me. No, but I don't
know what that means. What is oss again?
Uh, office of special plans are
off. That was before the CIA.
And then the closet for
teaching, so to like, um,
the office of strategic services.
Like what was before the seals,
what Jesse Ventura was the frogs even
terocin in that he was an auxiliary of the
navy. He was never in combat.
Anyways, let me expand on that.
The LSST,
the office of what is the
sheet wandering refills?
The Oh, ash ash was British intelligence
are the most powerful British,
the most powerful
intelligence agency ever.
They set up proud house at 22 after
World War II to anglicised that U s we'd
British intelligence, not a British
geologist takeover a marriage.
It was just all this, just like on
PBS. Okay. This just stuff that's true.
They'd met say they only academics are
watching it, so they'll tell the truth.
The general pop culture is all crap meant
to be dumbed down into turn you off.
But when you go to the
real academic stuff,
I mean the old days of
frontline and stuff,
like I watched that to know if it's
true. Later got the documents, it's all,
it's all real. That's like, those
shows were like really accurate.
Like Bobby Kennedy plan to blow
up the embassy and on nurture.
So like what was I getting
too? I don't Nazis Nazis. Well,
Wernher von Braun.
Really Weird.
Isn't it weird that the one man who
directed all six moon missions was a Nazi
and he was brought in that
one? Isn't that crazy? One guy,
he didn't smoke weed and one guy is having
a problem with memory. Two guys did.
And why you want to Defend Warner?
That's fine.
35 Nazis and I've seen
doctors rant about it.
He sketched for Hitler.
This plan to drop atomic bombs
that they hadn't developed yet.
So when you see red skull marvel comic,
they've got a big bomber to love New York.
It wasn't a bomber,
it was a space plane and it was about half
the size, but it looks just like this.
And the Germans actually
some of their scientists,
what's the Russians or the Russians
tried to build their special,
it was half the size. That was
actually the German plan show show.
You look it up.
I'm not kidding.
Because the Russians took a lot
of Germans as well. Correct.
About a third of them. Yeah, so look,
the reason I'm wearing this just
explained this is a gateway to all of it.
So you have British intelligence
did one world war one,
Germany had way more advanced technology.
They then take over British intelligence
basically merges with the u s and then
the Germans and others say,
we've got to go way ahead in technology.
There was all theoretical and labs,
but they could mass deploy it that you
didn't have enough machine shops and
systems to build it.
And US special forces went on suicide
missions and blew up the underground
mountain. How about the Nazis were
the first to build flying saucer,
all of it. But let me
tell you, that's crazy.
British cars,
British intelligence flying saucers,
the CIA,
the CIA and 47
so now the Nazis are over
here and they go, listen,
you don't want them running everything.
And they go to Eisenhower and they say,
we want to launch a off based breakaway
civilization where you compartmentalize
things, forget empires, and you'd have a
new ruling class of technological elites.
And then the elites are all in charge of
the public's watching TV and we'll give
him widgets and foundation
series type things at the verb.
This is all in the documents and
let them try to run an empire.
We'll build a whole new empire. And so
Eisenhower gives a speech, worry about,
he doesn't just say military
initial accomplished,
he says the technological elite lots,
the full 21 minute speech,
his farewell address and 62 he says,
or six 61 he says,
you need to watch out about
the scientist because,
because he said no to the NASA
plan when he found out what it was.
But is it's a breakaway civilization where
you don't try to run the whole planet,
you siphon off resources and
build a whole new advanced system,
and then you play her body off against
each other and collapse it. So when I say,
what is an Assa if we could take NASA
back over, it's bigger than the CIA.
It's the real government, the space
ships and the stuff that's all PR.