Edwards, what's going on? My friend?
Not much. My man. What's that shirt?
What does it, a moon, smiley face.
Graffiti and the moon, you know,
me and my smiley faces, people would
graffiti the moon. They get up.
That's probably the first thing we're
going to have to worry about these virgin
flights. People leaving some shit
that you could see from Earth,
you know, pissing everywhere. Dude, so
much to talk about. So much going on.
There's a lot going on in the world of
MMA in the world of Doug Jitsu. Yeah.
Your world, MMA, even boxing. It's a lot
of, a lot of shit going on. A boxing,
which just like, we're going to get
beyond Deontay wilder on Monday.
He's going to be in here. Oh yeah.
Yeah. He's uh, he's saying that.
Did you see the video
on his, uh, Instagram?
He shows that it's more than 10
seconds. Yeah, it is. It's fact.
And he plays the clock.
As soon as Tyson fury goes down and
then it's more than 10 seconds before he
gets back up. The only problem with that
is, I mean, it's human error, right?
You can't, you can't start
immediately. Right. You know, there's,
there's always that little,
that little space and ties and they're
supposed to be a guy on the sideline
though that starts the right. Yeah. Yep.
And then he picks it up with five, four,
right? Yeah. But the rep problems,
referees know when they're in the heat
of the battle, the fucking adrenaline,
there's seconds. It's not like they have
a stopwatch in their hand to hit it.
Every time a guy goes down,
which, why don't they have Paula?
It's too much to remember. We were just
talking about the heat of the moment.
Boom. Click too much to remember. I mean,
think about all the Shit Tyson fury
as to America. That's all in stake,
right? If you're, I mean,
that fight I wanted, of course I'm
rooting for a while there cause I like,
I like big knockouts, you
know what I mean? And um,
he looked good in the first two rounds
and then he just looked like he abandoned
the, the game plan and he was just looking
for the knockout after that. Well, he,
he's got a problem. The problem is
he can knock anybody the fuck out.
That's a problem.
Anybody except that Guy Tyson theory.
It seems like you almost knocked him
out like he knocked him out. Yeah,
if it wasn't,
I mean he definitely made,
did 10 he was definitely down for 10
but here's the thing, if the referee,
instead of saying eight said seven
instead of saying six at five,
we've gotten up quicker.
I think you probably would have
because he's waiting for eight,
nine and then he's standing up
cause he's trying to give himself,
he's an old vet. He's trying to give
himself as much recovery time as he can.
I don't know. When I watch,
when I watch him getting up,
I look at that replay and you see his
head like his head comes up like he's
trying to get up and he can't and then
he just like stands up like a Zombie.
I think that's an gypsy shit.
It's scary.
Well I did not expect
him to get up, um, fight
that. So it was while
they were celebrating too.
The thing was like when he
went down, I went, oh shit,
I can't believe he knocked
him out in the 12th like that.
And it was the left hook going down.
That was the craziest. He was boom,
the right hand, that bang, the left
hook going down. It was so insane.
And he walked off. It was a walk
off. It was a walk off, knock out.
He was dancing and he was pointing to
his woman in the audience and she was
saying, I love you. And he was like, the
whole thing was to celebrate Tory moment.
And then the look on his face when he
realized that Tyson fury had gotten up.
Like what? Yeah. You know,
you know what that is?
Remember I remember the eighties
and nineties, um, the Friday,
the 13th movie when you killed Jason and
then you turn around, it's like, oh shit.
That thrives when a full set up.
That's what that was. How does wild,
they're punched so hard as a man who
studied martial arts his whole life.
Like there's some dudes, right?
Don't you think? Yeah. Just,
they have some free explosive power,
but it's crazy how much he's gay.
He's only 212 pounds.
That's the crazy thing.
It's like he's very
small for a heavyweight,
like a lot of these guys to 50 remember
I remember a guy named Mike Tyson.
Oh yeah. He was still like in the two
fifteens right? He was like two 15 yeah.
Yeah. Not much like a truck.
I don't, I don't know how you,
I mean I didn't have that kind of power.
My knock outs were from like,
stuff you didn't see and quickness,
but like a guy like Jeremy Stevens,
it's like that, you know, Melvin Guillard
had that kind of pillar. I don't,
how do you develop,
I don't know if you could develop that.
I think that's a natural thing. Yeah.
Rumble Johnson type pounds. Yes. Yes.
I think you can develop that. I don't
think so. I think you can accentuate it.
I think we got to hits hard with
better techniques and get hit harder.
I think it's a bone structure thing.
I mean it's like if you look at uh,
Deontae he's kind of built like a
gigantic Tommy Hearns. Yeah. You know,
just widen the shoulders and his back
is just a fucking bundle of like small
soaps.
It's just like those little,
those thick ass ropes that they use
for, for boats, you know what I mean?
When they more ships, that's like the
muscles in his back, just, just jack back.
That's where all the power comes from.
I guess you should let him body shot.
You fuck all that.
Fuck all that dude.
That dude's a scary dude man.
Yeah,
he hits harder than anybody I think in
reaching memory. Like his one shot power.
It's ridiculous. What
do you think? I mean I,
Tyson was a better boxer.
Pure boxer too. So,
but like I would love to see like
big power punches. Like I, they,
they need to make a boxing game
where they, where they have all the,
and I'm to guess they might have,
I don't know,
but they need to have one where they
have like all the power punchers power
punch it. I won't have it. Right. Well,
you know what, I feel like that's a,
there was a perfect boxing match because
you haven't Tyson fury, first of all,
you have this guy that overcame depression
and suicidal thoughts and you know,
drug addiction and alcoholism
and he was just obesity. Yeah.
He was living in a world of depression.
He was just drinking constantly and doing
coke and fucking his life up and then
loses more than a hundred pounds.
Cleans himself up,
gets in there against the scariest
guy in the heavyweight division.
It puts on a boxing clinic.
However, he still gets clipped.
He still gets clipped not once,
but twice hard and dropped hard,
especially in the 12th round.
So it's like for a person
who loves watching fights,
it's such a perfect fight because
you've got so first of all,
they're both great guys.
Like, like both guys.
Like if you're a fan of like
exceptional human beings,
both guys are great guys.
Yeah.
Like the more I see Deontay
wilder interact with his
family, talk about things,
talk about the way he approaches fighting,
the more I appreciate what he's doing,
you know?
And then Tyson fury.
How do you not love the guy and the way
they exchanged like pleasantries after
the fight was over and Tyson was telling
him he loved him and he kissed his
fucking fist. I mean, it's like you is a
great all around a great feeling after,
even though it was a draw, I was like, I
felt good about it. That was rocky one.
It was rocky one. That's what that
was. It was rocky wine, right?
It was rocky one sort of. Right. But it
wasn't a slugger. That one, you know?
I mean, what it was was just a great,
nobody won. Nobody won in rough.
Yeah. Yeah. It was a great,
great boxing match. That's what it was. It
just like, it had all the good elements.
It was the best heavyweight fight
I've seen in a long time. I mean,
that might have been better than,
than Holyfield Tyson.
That's hard to say because I know
Holyfield was like the good guy coming in
against the bad guy. Like there was so
much to that fight and then with Tyson,
like you thought he was invincible and
then Holyfield just eaten his shots and
slowly beaten them down and
then eventually stops them.