But you don't ever work out boxing wise
anymore. Yeah, but do you don't hit it.
Hit a bag.
My son's 15 and I know he wants to
buck so anytime we get a chance,
you know I'm always training him.
How big is he now? Six feet.
Jesus has told them the news.
Tyson's son, Tyson son
is 16 oh Miguel. Yeah.
Tyson son was saying that he wants
a box to Tyson's. Like listen, no,
Miguel was not built like that. But
he's also saying, listen you, you,
you grew up soft and you
know he's saying like,
you don't want to meet someone like
me. You know like the way he was. Yeah,
I know Mike. I know you want
to meet some animal like me.
You know like when he was fighting like
he like he thinks of what he would've
done to his own son's like,
oh don't do that.
Like he was talking about it on the
podcast and his son Miguel's Oh really
talented kid. Like musician wise can play
like seven different instruments. Wow.
Spanish. Wow. The kid's really,
and he's a really smart, nice kid.
Well, Tyson is a smart guy. He's not
like he, I think people mistake tied.
Some are big a dummy. He's very,
very intelligent. Well read.
Boxing is in at least some levels of very,
very intellectual pursuit.
There's,
you have to have a strong mind to
be able to dodge those punches,
get in and get yours in that you have to,
you have to be able to sort out that
problem is a problem in front of you.
The problem is another man who was the
same way as you, the same size as you.
He's got gloves on just like you do and
he's trying to do what you're trying to
do to him. And you have to do
that within seconds. Boom. Yeah.
Punches thrown at you. What do you
do? What's, what's the rebuttal? Yeah.
People don't understand.
They think just because someone doesn't
have the best vocabulary or because they
don't have a,
a comprehensive education that they're
not intelligent and that's a big mistake.
No, twice Tyson's intelligence. Uh,
I remember going to the
Catskills when I was, uh,
I won the world junior championships
in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.
And I remember the American
team was saying, oh, well
you never fought the best.
I'm like, I didn't fight
the best. I thought American
sent them best team. Yeah.
But one guy,
he doesn't like taking plans and this
manager don't like taking plans either.
So I'm like, who's that? And they told
me it was Mike Tyson custom model.
So me and my trainer,
we left Canada and we drove all the
way up there and while we were up there
raise the Roderick was up
there and they said, oh,
raising really came to inspire with
us. So okay, I'll start with the,
I'm here for four days.
So first time Tyson actually met me,
you know, he was Nice Guy, really
nice guy, took me in his room,
showed me some old flicks that I've never
seen before of old time fighters would
tell me about each fighter, like he
studied them. And then, um, you know,
this is where he got his old star is
his style of fighting from. And uh,
first day in the first day in the gym
bell when he came across and he was trying
to kill me.
Like,
you know I did my Muhammad Ali thing
obviously stayed away from his power,
but the first day was really hectic and
then the second day was a little hectic
and it got better as it went along.
And the last day is I got actually the
better of him the last day and I remember
custom models saying, Mike, you're going
to meet him some day. Don't you do that?
And not always echoed in my
mind that will we ever fight?
Will we have a fight? Cause cause the
model said that we're going to fight.
Why did it happen? And there's
footage of it. Yeah. Wow.
Lennox has the footage of it.
Footage of the training centers.
Barring how old was Tyson at
the time? Tyson was like, uh,
he was about 52. No, no. How old
was he at the time? Oh, at the time.
15. Um, he was, he was younger
than me. I was on Sunday.
He's about 17. Wow. I was
18. He was younger than that.
There must've been
fours before the, uh, empire state
games and everything. Can you,
would you want up there before you went
to the 84 Olympics? Yeah. Yeah. Well,
it must have been crazy though,
knowing that, you know, you,
you guys were going to be a part of boxing
history and knowing that all the way
back then and being a teenager and
standing in front and here in custom model
scream that out.
That must have been intense.
It was intense because custom
motto wasn't that loud when he was,
when they, all of a sudden he became
loud. It was like everybody listened,
you know, and then, you know,
there's certain ways that you would
get across to people and some,
some people take you
have to shout at them.
Did you ever wish that you
fought him in his prime? Um,
in essence I did fight him in his
prime and you know, when you say prime,
I was in my prime too. You know, you will
fleeing your prime. You were, you were,
but I feel like his enthusiasm
had waned before then. You know,
um, I, you know, this is my perception,
how I look at that whole thing is
Mike Tyson was an early bloomer.
I was a late bloomer. So, you know,
when, when both of us meet, you know,
there's never a perfect time. Perfect
time for us is when we meet in the middle.
Right, right, right. And, you know,
right. And if he won, maybe people would
look at it differently. Right. This,
because you beat him and beat him so
soundly that people look at it like maybe
his, his time had already been gone. Yeah.
Lenox turned pro after Mike
had already had a defeat. Wow.
No claims turn pro and 89. Wow.
I never even thought of that.
And Mike lost in January.
Right?
Yeah. This is us open up. Look at
you. Look at Kevin Rooney.
Wow. That is crazy, man. God,
that's crazy built back then too.
We had a big neck. Yeah. He, well,
he was always doing those neck bridges.
He, but he also just had freak genetics.
I mean, just phenomenal genetic
specimen, you know. Uh, I had um, uh,
Teddy Atlas in here and Teddy House used
to take Mike to the smokers when he was
13.
And Teddy was joking around about it,
said everybody always lied
about how old people were.
They would tell you the kid was 16,
when really it was 20.
They always did that and he said, uh, he
goes, uh, so, uh, how old is this kid?
He was 13. He goes, what does he
weigh? He goes, 190 pounds. It's like,
what the fuck teddy, come on. He's
like, I'm telling Ya, he's sick.
He's fucking 13. What do you want? So,
you know, nobody would believe it
because he was such a specimen.
I watched that one.
Teddy was great man.
Do you think he should
have stayed with teddy?
Should have stayed with Kevin and
Teddy? Well he definitely, you know,
he was so wild. Like how, how could
you tell him what to do back then?
That was part of the problem. I mean,
he was never, no one ever prepared him.
And this is one of the things that we
discussed on the podcast was that he was a
12 year old, 13 year old boy
and he was getting hypnotized.
He had came from a terrible
background. It was, there was no love,
he was abandoned and all of a sudden
he's getting love and attention for
something. And this one thing
was this man who was telling him,
you're going to be a great fight or
you're going to be a world champion.
And he would hypnotize me saying,
you don't exist. The task exists.
You know you're going to work
the body and destroy this man.
And he would tell he would
put these thoughts in his
head and Mike couldn't wait
to just get out there and fuck people up.
Cause that's where he got the love.
That's where he got the attention from.
But he never turned,
never told them how to shut it off.
He never,
I mean he didn't have time to
work with him cause he was,
he was on his way out and he
was dying when he met Mike.
And so he only taught them how to destroy.
He never taught them how to cope.
He never taught them how to understand
that there's going to be a lot of shit
coming your way and you've got to know
what that is and don't get caught up in
that hype train. Don't just don't get
wrapped up in Hollywood. And you know,
he wound up marrying robbin
Gibbons and you know, all,
I don't think cus foresaw
all that other bullshit. No.
How could he of course was around
Mike would be totally different.
He would have been a different man if
costs lasted another 15 years given if
Jimmy Jacobs had lasted another
five years, maybe. Yeah,
maybe it would have helped.
But I mean it's like once
you're once removed from cus,
it's like Kevin Rooney was
once removed from costs. Right.
And then Teddy Atlas was way more of
a hard liner. You know, Teddy Atlas,
you couldn't put any bullshit with,
you know,
and like those other guys who
just got to go, ah, you know,
when he got to Aaron's snowball
and all those guys was with them,
bums reaching Ghia Ketty they
just didn't, they, they didn't.
They could have never brought
Mike to the dance. Right.
They got there when he was already at
the dance and they just trying to like
maintain things and he's
not listening to anybody.
They also weren't boxing people
as far as I was concerned
when he was up with costs use.
It was in a good situation.
You know, there was a lady in
the house cooking meals. Uh,
they had custody of being a father figure,
talk to him every day.
And that's what young kids
need. They need that, you know,
to be spoken with by older
people. Yeah. And you know,
a lot of young people nowadays are
not even respecting the older people,
but they can get in a lot of information
from an older person. You know,
how do you deal with this
situation? Well, you know,
you hear it from an older person that
kind of makes your mind thinking, said,
you know, you're right. It works for them.
So anytime I get a chance to
talk to kids about, you know,
their life and where they're going
or it's take that opportunity.