During the Pan s period or some shit.
Pangea. Do you know what that is?
It's the era. No, it's,
well when they think that all of the
continents were connected together.
We are one,
we are one flat earth as one flat table.
Just flat. No, no, no.
Just obviously not like giant chunk
and then the rest was water and then it
spread out, which is fucking
weird. Like what is happening?
How did that and like also is that
happening on our insides on like it's
obviously on a cellular level of the
things. Just splitting and being torn.
The fuck apart is, here's the, the
modern pangea map. This is modern.
It's a modern country
separations and all that because,
oh this is what it looked like if
he brought up, I thought this was,
there's more to pitch is still
real America. What is that?
I thought there was some
knuckleheads that thought that.
Is that really all of the
continents together? Whoa.
It shows you how much God damn water
there is like that's a mind fuck. Yeah.
Cause you'd really like to think that
we're all dirt and not as much water.
It's so much water. It's all water. It's
like a little speck in a huge ass ocean.
This was really crazy so
it was ground dwelling.
Motherfuckers have figured out how
sock all the fish out of that water
just to be able to get those suckers out
your bare hands and then they were like,
Yo, we need something. We need a
smaller situation. I think until they,
they came up with the
nets and stuff like that.
I don't think they were real effective.
I think they just got what they got and
they ate that but the populations were
fine but in the last whatever hundred
and 50 years they've been using nets,
they just jacked that whole ocean.
What do you think happened to the
dude who figured out like the hook?
He probably got all the pussy in town.
That dude or like hook the fish.
He was getting all those fishies.
He was getting the ones that were way
deep to what the kind of pussy that you
would get back when you invented a book.
You don't want it
in your modern mind you don't,
but back then you're like,
Yo, this is fresh, fresh.
It only smells like musty.
How'd you become a African American?
Something's happening to you.
Wake and bake in this,
taking you to another level.
Another level for
sure. Yeah. Let's guess how long ago do
you think they invented the fish work?
Did they even know? I'm going to
say it's a really old invention.
Rolled Arrowhead time
period close to like native,
native before pre need
pitches would just break.
If you think about a big fish
hooking like a little thin,
what would they make it?
A bone probably must be [inaudible] hard,
but you would think don't
want to be too heavy.
You should just sinking wold also break.
Yeah. I want to be able to go get well.
Yeah. It must've been bone. I bet it
was bone and the bones get brittle,
especially after like you know they're
off the body and they start to calcify
and all that. How old do
you think it is? This guy,
really old juniper. What it says?
Juniper wood was the first one,
21 to 23,000 years ago.
Jesus Christ.
There is Norwegians.
Yeah,
they're made from sea snail shells.
There's a bunch of information
I'll put together in this thing.
Okinawa island data between 20 2003
80 and 20 2007 70 in that crazy.
They'd get it that close. They're
basically in an inter, you know,
give or take 80 90 years,
hundred years it carbon dating.
I mean that's the only thing I remember
from high school. How do you even,
how do you date it back?
Do they find,
is it like a forensic thing where they
grab a fly and they're like, yeah,
this was six years ago because of the
juices on the wings. I think it's,
there's like a bunch of factors.
Like one of them is the dirt
that's around where they find it.
Like if they find it on the ground,
then it's covered with dirt over
hundreds and hundreds of years.
He could take some of that dirt and test
it. Yeah, they can see what's in it.
They they're trying to test,
I think. Whoa. That was
crazy. I want those earrings.
Is that a fish hook? I clicked the
other shelves. Those are fresh.
Those are really nice. I would rock
those. What'd you the comedy store?
Oldest fish hook found at Okinawa.
Wow. 23,000 years ago. That's crazy.
So they're saying that the oldest
fish hook is linked to the Norwegians?
I would say Japanese.
This is Okinawa.
Norwegian thing was saying that
and up until the 1950s there were,
they were still using wood and just
like a added fact and one of these make
sense if they all figured it out the
same time, different spots in the world,
you know, wonder if it's one of those
things like, you know, like the,
there's just some weird thing.
Who's that?
Is that Rupert Sheldrake is
the morphic residence theory.
He's got this weird theory that I think
the idea is that if some a rat learns
amaze on the east coast rats on the west
coast, we'll learn that maze quicker.
What, what, how like uh, like, uh,
they don't know the no consciousness
amongst the rats. As weird as it sounds.
There might be some sort
of strange connection that
all rats share and not just
all rats,
but all living beings.
His argument was that if this is
demonstrate a bubble with a rat in a maze,
that if they did something
like a with human beings,
if they could figure out a
way to, uh, to prove this,
that's likely what's happening.
Is it like he,
he brought up a bunch
of different factors,
like inventions that are simultaneously
taking place like all over the world,
like one and strain. Yeah. You shouldn't
attribute some of that to education,
right? Like, yeah, definitely a
challenge that's going on, like the,
the trends that are
happening in education,
but they also think there might be
something else going on underneath the
surface, like on a different
realm. Like if you learn,
if we're all a species and
you're on one side of the world,
you learn something that people on the
other side of the world have greater
access to it in some weird way.
That's really bizarre.