[inaudible].
Boom. Good. Okay. We had
some tough technical problem.
Let's try it again. Okay.
So anyway, brother, welcome. Thanks
for coming here. Thanks. Thanks.
So what we were saying before,
we actually said this already,
but let's say it again because
the people didn't hear it.
You were one of the pioneers of standup
comedy in Brazil. Yeah, yeah. He was a,
I started with like four or five guys.
We started doing it like 16,
17 years ago and uh,
nobody knew about standup.
It was something that I found out when
I came here to live and play basketball.
I had a scholarship to play
basketball and I watched Jim Gaffigan.
Oh Wow. And Brian Regan.
Ah, I know those guys.
And I thought it was so weird
because those guys were like, that's,
I was questioning his, his,
his, does he call his name?
Brian Regan does.
He is actually him because we used
to have characters and impersonators,
so we was kind of weird.
But at the same time,
it was interesting because I'm not
a guy who does characters and I do
observations and I ride,
I was a journalist, I'm a
heavy degree in journalism.
So he was interesting for me to see
those guys doing comedy and I thought we
could do the same in my country.
It's so crazy that it took that
long for it to get to Brazil. Yeah.
You would think that because
everything else, I mean,
you guys have movies and you know, uh, I
mean city of God, you have action movies,
you have all these,
you have so much that's so similar.
The fact that standup comedy made
it there is so unusual to see a,
I took a long time a, it
was, I don't know why,
but the image off a comedian speaking
like with a blazer or a suit or something
was Jerry Seinfeld, very American.
You know, and those jokes,
do they actually connect them much with
us? Like, Oh, I have those buckets.
And it was something that we
have bigger problems than, oh,
I just have a pocket. Or when am I
gonna put my pan? I was like, he was,
he was something that I could, we
couldn't connect them much, but when we,
when we saw there was a lot of people
doing other stuff and there was like this
huge role that we could actually explore
that was when it become interesting for
us. So comedy in Brazil, there
would basically be like a,
like say if I was a Brazilian community
and I would come up with a fake name,
if you will, and I would do a character,
a wig, a wig. I'll wear a certain outfit,
outfit like a very over
the top screaming and uh,
and that's teal still exists in Brazil.
This is like a popular part
of the people stand up.
I'm not saying that it's for everyone.
Now I have my Netflix bash show.
We B is becoming huge because,
uh,
we have some other options right now
with the Internet. Everything changed.
The game changed
completely. So we have, uh,
what is good has his own space right now.
It's not only was the TV
ones shoot to watch it.
So the game changed a little for,
for all of, so how did you start out?
Did you start out by going
to music clubs or, he was,
I actually studying the a BDSM
club sadomasochists clubs.
I remember that there was like pictures
Cox in the band and in like a giant as a
huge vaginas and their habit,
and we had that show any you was,
it wasn't good,
but it was an experience for all
of us to go on stage and try to,
to,
to show them a,
our opinions and our jokes and
some irony and sarcasm and we wish,
which was something that people wasn't
watching, eh. But then he becomes,
he becomes something huge and we got
chances to go to TV and everything else.
But at first it was difficult because
people could not understand is he a
character?
Is he playing a part?
So that's why I had an ice tea.
We'll have a lot of problems with the
law because like I did a rape joke,
which I'm not proud of. I'm saying
it's not something like, oh,
I'm so over the top, I love it in the
line. And, but uh, he was like, does,
does this guy wants people to be raped
at what is, what is he thinking? What is,
because with all those jokes was taken
out of context and put it on newspapers
kind of killed, uh, you kind of killed my
desire to the comedy over that as well.
Really? Yeah, it was, it was difficult
man, because he was like journalists,
journalists in the audience waiting
for me to say some shit booed out of
context.
And then the guy at like fucking like
billions of clicks on their websites
because of core joke. I
did. Yeah. That's how we,
the controversy was starting over that.
And I don't know if it's
the same thing here.
So they knew that this was a new thing.
They,
and so they would come to see it.
And then what were they criticizing
it before this? He was, he was huge.
Everybody loved today first.
But when, when, when, when,
when we started to have money
and a TV shows and we kind of,
uh, ran away out of the underground,
I was doing shows at midnight,
like packing at three, 300 CT
at there, at midnight in Brazil.
That was my thing. I underground in
some fall in the middle of nowhere.
But then people have this guy's talented.
Let me give him a chance.
So they put me on TV and out of nowhere
I was on TV doing the same thing.
Wow. So the, the,
the country was not that prepared
for what I was doing at the time.
What kind of laws do you have in Brazil
in terms of like the language that
you're allowed to use on
television? Uh, you know, the,
I'm not saying there's like a government
censorship about what you can say,
what you cannot say, but uh, sponsors and,
and even TV stations and the media is
very sensitive about everything because
it's to a poor country. It's still a
Brazil, still a third world country.
So we are, we are like, we have a lot of
people that don't understand the though,
oh this is comedy. What, what's comedy?
So it was my duty to
explain a little bit why.
Well we're stand up and kind of
for open a road for all of us.
That's how I felt.
So you and you said three other new ways,
like three or four guys.
So who are these other guys?
They're still doing comedy in Brazil.
Yeah. They still doing this to heal.
What are their names? Uh,
Marcello Mansfield than illusion.
Chili or kind of feel you.
There was a small group of guys that
we started doing Brazilian Portuguese.
It's such a beautiful language. I
love it. I love it. It's like a song.
It's like it's [inaudible] I'm
doing Jujitsu for 23 years.
So it's like, to me that sound is like,
it's such a cool sound. What does,
what does Brazilians say in,
in Jersey says those that awards are
something that they are still repeating
that you know? Well, I mean,
you know Paul Hall, Paul,
which is com. Yeah. Is that
fucker com which went to come.
But sometimes we'll come ah, pull
though. Sometimes you say it like damn,
but it's come, it's called
Com. But so that's funny.
Cause like that's like the word Shit.
Like shit could be like,
you could look at something,
go chef medic. That's good
input to this. Mad At. Okay.
But shit can also be bad.
Yeah. You know, like fuck too.
Like fuck could be good or fuck could
be bad. Like you could stub your tongue,
go fuck. Or You could, you could see
a girl with a beautiful body and go,
fuck yeah. But Paul is the
same thing. It's so crazy.
But it's called boom.
Got Big ba Ba.
But anyway, you're getting a
choke for her. Yeah, I got it.
I got is the same.
Exactly.