Hello Freak bitches because you're,
we're going way, way, way back. The,
the real issue.
This is like a year before,
more than a year before
everything went sideways. Oh yeah.
What went sideways and why? So you're
this Super Progressive Vegan guy,
but what went sideways?
So I'm an ex of mine.
I'm an ex of mine.
Uh,
I'm trying to think about like
how much I can say, um, started.
Um, it was weird, like girls I was dating,
like she would kind of
like pop up and be like,
following them on like social media.
And I kind of was like, all right,
it's a little weird. Um, girls, you were
dating, but you were married at the time.
So what was also not talked about in these
articles is that for the last however
many years before, um, Alison,
I got separated. We were
in an open relationship.
We just didn't,
we talked about it on the show eventually,
but for a while we didn't talk about it.
Um,
and which to anyone in a
fucking open relationship,
like it's a nightmare when you're not
talking about it because you feel like a,
a lecherous cheating creep,
uh,
cause you're in an open relationship
and you don't talk about it.
So then when girls meet you and you tell
them like, yeah, right, yeah, totally.
When you go, I'm in a secret
open relationship, like
you're full of shit. Um,
and so, you know, I like kind
of did the road of thing,
but like felt like a fucking creep and
three meaning hookup with girls. Yeah.
And, uh, and then, uh, uh, you
know, I was finally just like,
we have to talk about it and
at this point, and I don't
want to shit on anybody,
uh, you know, at this point,
um, you know, my cohost and I,
we were like, we were pretty much
just like really good friends, right.
Who lived together and did
a show together. And, um,
so years later, years after, um,
me and this girl broke up years after
all this shit, I'm living in La.
Um, I have, uh, I've had
a girlfriend for a year.
It's like a very healthy, wonderful
relationship. Um, years after all this,
I guess what happened was
one of these girls, um,
essentially started to try to find any
girl who has been pissed off by me before
and they found enough for an article that,
um,
I think like two articles came out.
I left to do some radio because the show
was getting a ton of complaints. Um,
because our inner circle started to
find out that there were quote unquote
accusations, which the word accusation
makes it sound Weinstein. Um,
accusations of, so that's what
they were saying. But there was,
it was very unspecific.
What I've read,
they said predatory behavior and I was
like, oh, meaning he's trying to get laid.
That's what a man does.
Not Predatory in the sense of you're
victimizing someone to raping someone or
doing something horrible
to someone or even,
and this is when my own words kind
of bit me in the ass because you,
I spent an entire year a or
years being like, you know,
a Hashtag believe women. And then you
read that and you go to that Hashtag.
Don't believe when it like you
don't know what to do. And like I,
I was always like, if you call girl who
accuses you, uh, uh, you know crazy.
You're just projecting
and like you're trying to,
and then suddenly I'm reading this
article, I'm like, this is fucking crazy.
And I didn't, uh, all of my style on
one article you talking about the,
there's a decibel.
Yeah,
there was a decibel article and Hell
hath no fury like a woman scorned man. I,
uh,
it was really bad and I read it for the
first time and I don't want to go into
details because I don't want to shit on
people who like, feel like they were, um,
you know, hurt or whatever.
Um, but a good majority,
the article isn't even fucking true.
Um,
there was one part where Jazz Abella even
wrote it. Like if we can make it better
journalism because it's
one woman who wrote it.
Oh, Yay. Oh yeah, totally. So this, so
the author, there's one moment in it,
and I'll try and make this a about
journalism and not about the, the woman,
but one of the complaints about
me was I had a consensual night,
um, with a lady in Nashville, um,
who I guess because she like listened
to the show. Maybe they're like,
that's predatory because you're
like famous. And I was like, mom,
no one else thinks I'm fucking famous.
Uh,
well, wait a minute, wait
a minute. Wait a minute.
There were defining as predatory because
you're famous. That's part of it.
Every time Mick Jagger gets laid,
it's predatory.
That's part of it. That's what
I don't, that's the thing.
And it was the way I don't fucking
call me. If I'm Mick Jagger famous,
you can call me a fucking predator.
If I'm,
I can barely get a plus one to a Vegan
festival. Famous like, don't please
do not call me a predator. I mean, look,
it's, there's levels to fame, right?
And I know you're being self
deprecating and everything like that,
but you did have a nice
following and you did,
I saw some of your videos online where
you did big crowds. So it's not, no,
it's not like you didn't have
fans give that fence but,
but the idea that you liking some woman
who is a fan and her liking you like
that somehow under the Europe Predator
because she enjoys your work is crazy.
What is that how they were defining
it? Because I don't know. And then,
but then it seems like they're being
very convenient, their definition
and, and, and that was part of
it. There was like, uh, uh, um,
there was another one where it was like,
yeah,
the predatory stuff's
specifically was that,
and then what was even more fucked
up about the article was it said,
um,
and I'm not going to quote exactly.
She also wrote into another
podcast and I heard this,
but essentially what the woman said,
we did not sleep together.
It alluded that we slept together.
It didn't say that I was in
an open relationship, but
we didn't sleep together.
Um, she told me she didn't want to, uh,
uh, sleep together and I was like, great,
no problem. She's like, I don't want to,
I don't want it to go further than that,
you know? Okay. So I was like,
cool, even if you change your mind,
we're not going to do it. Got
It. And then in the article,
in the article about me being a Predator,
it's like I felt so safe and,
and it was a great night and I was like,
this sounds like an article about
BP in a good dude. And then it said,
but then weeks later she
heard on the podcast that uh,
she was just a quote road fuck.
And then Jessebelle in parentheses is
one Arthur from Jess about and fantasy
said, Jessebelle could
not find the clip. Right.
Cause it doesn't fucking exist because
I'm not going to call someone a road fuck
next to my wife on my feminist podcast.
Not only that,
you're not going to say it if you
didn't even have sex with them.
We didn't have sex.
Right. So this is just,
they just decided to take
this characterization by
this one woman that's it and
flavor the article.
Yes and very unfair.
No and dude like is this punishment you
think for you because you somehow or
another. So that's why it becomes easy
and and just to be like incredibly clear.
Like if this woman was like hurt by that,
like that sucks man.
I've been burned by girls do anything.
If she didn't,
if she was hurt because you didn't
eventually become her girlfriend,
her boyfriend rather.
That's just on her. Sure.
Unless you're ms
character. No, no, no, no.
It's Catherine just trying to be, you're
trying to be nice to be nice. Yeah.
I assume she is probably,
you know,
I mean she's probably taken
out of context as well.
There's a real problem with writing
things about people and one of the real
problems with writing things about people
is they don't get a chance to respond
in real time to things you're saying.
So you establish a narrative
and then you keep going with it.
You write paragraph after paragraph
with no s no one responding to them.
A month later, I, I saw like the,
the, the woman who wrote the article,
like there was a request in my like,
other inbox and Facebook that like,
you don't even see and like for a comment.
So like, I mean, she did reach out. Um,
but at that point I was,
uh,
at that point I was literally googling
ways to kill myself. So I'm like, I did,
I could not get back to googling ways to
kill yourself for real. Yeah. For Real.
So, well just to like why put
against this on the article.
So here's what happened, and this
goes to your, your question before,
because I had called so many people sexist
because I had sort of made my almost
career by that.
Um,
it was a fucking fun man
when people heard about this,
like,
and you see the headlines and this is
another like problem with like clickbait
journalism. The headlines look
like I was fucking accused of rape.
There was a one article that
used the word sexual harassment.
Sexual misconduct was in all the
headlines that I have no fucking idea.
So seen that one about people
connected to Harvey Weinstein,
like about Ben Affleck, they call it
sexual misconduct. What does that mean?
Like in something that you don't think
they should do? What's really creepy?
Eagle and I almost lost a job.
I did just lose a gig because
when you Google and B,
it's like sexual misconduct stuff. And
like that's really scary. And again,
I don't want to be like, you know who
the real victim of Harvey Weinstein is?
Jamie Kilstein. Right. But like,
uh, let me just stop you right here.
If you say like one more time,
I fucking head's gonna explode too.
And I get comments like
that. It's brutal. It's a
brutal, is it as bad as I
just want you to slow it down.
I'm gonna use it every now and then. This
coffee over here, breaking the light.
The light meter. I'm gonna do it
too, man. A lot of people do it.
It's an easy one to do, switch
to water, but that word is a,
it's an, um, it's, uh, people use it
as, um, I know, I know. It's okay.
I do it too. We all do it, but it's
just, it's nice to know. Yeah, no, I,
it's also a very progressive thing.
Like there's a way like that people talk,
like when they're really progressive
that like you don't hear like leftwing
people talk. I keep getting
fucked over by the progressive's.
It's a way of a peering.
Um, what's the word?
Submissive or
passive?
Yeah. It's not a, it's not an aggressive
way of communicating. All right.
What if I said like,
but like I kept like punching the table,
like as I did it on a
fucking, like much, you know,
like go to like step to me
just smash a paps. Uh, can.
Um,
so,
so you got a bunch of people that were
upset at you because you had embodied
the quintessential allies.
So it was there.
Nobody had a reason to
like me or to defend me.
On one half of the Twitter sphere you
had progressive's who thought I was a
sexual creep.
And then on the other half you
have comedy fans who are like,
fuck this dude.
He's the one who called everyone a sexist.
You don't need to read the article.
If you see a headline, I mean, God,
I attacked so many people without
fucking reading the articles.
Of course there are people to this day
that will come up on citizen radio that I
don't know why I was mad at,
I would just figure out the story as
we were covering it and be like, Yup,
fuck that guy. I guess. Yeah,
of course. And so nobody,
there was no reason to root for me.
There wasn't a strong enough fan base.
It wasn't like if, you know, a, a
bigger comic gets accused of something.
Well he has thousands or millions of fans
and then this small community who are
accused him of something
I had sort of nobody,
and when I burnt all the bridges
and in comedy and you know,
I never just showed up at clubs
to do sets and stuff like that.
I just had this audience and sort of
thought I could never get fired, you know?
Um,
like when,
when Allie and I sort of became more
platonic before the open relationship.
I mean, there were days it
was, it was so, uh, you know,
I mean I would sleep on the couch but
there were days I would go on the road and
I would not cheat and I would go back
to the hotel and sure cough and like my
orgasm was better cause I'm like,
I saved citizen radio.
Like I was trying so hard not to,
not to do anything like that.
And so anyway, I lost. Yeah,
there was no one to root for me.
I just had the small audience.
It's a small audience.
Either thinks I'm a Predator or they're
too nervous to say anything. Well
you fit the Quintess you,
you,
there's a classic view of what a male
feminist is and that classic view is a
sneaky guy
that is like getting in tight with women
and saying all the things they really
want to hear.
And the classic story is that those women
are never attracted to that guy anyway.
And one up and go and fuck some jocks,
some Alpha Guy.
I mean that's literally what happens.
Yeah. You don't say like do you,
but it's just this thing that
people, there's, it's just,
well,
it's a cliche and I totally,
and I also think it was the homophobic
politician who sucks the deck right
there. Like the Super
Religious Guy who, uh,
turns out to actually be gay.
Like Ted,
what does that kind of thing
to the guy from Colorado?
Can we just say careers and start a bar?
You probably could take rice.
Uh, yeah. And so it
haggard Ted Haggard. Yes.
And to try to have a bit about
them and who didn't we have, right.
And so this is what happens.
Yeah. This is sort of the,
the problem with acting like you
don't have flaws. And I always did.
I thought on the show,
my favorite parts of my show were when
I talked about depression or alcoholism
and, and we were getting emails in
from people who, you know, it's edited,
really helped them. And I wanted to talk
so much more about that stuff because I,
I do think it's important to examine
your flaws, but on a political level,
I held myself up. It's
like an untouchable, well,
I think you were doing essentially the
same thing that you were talking about
doing on Twitter where you're addicted
to this positive response and you're
addicted to saying these things
about people attacking people there.
There's, this is a, it's a
real problem on the left.