And we're live. You've fucking handsome
bastard. Look at you. Oh yeah. This shit.
What's going on man?
What's going on?
Um,
every time I've done this
once before and I've watched,
you know,
throughout the years
and when I come in here,
I get a little, um, nervous. Why?
You're a guy who knows a lot about
everything and I don't know a lot of,
I don't know a lot about everything.
I know enough to make it seem like
I know a lot about everything.
Whatever you're doing, it's, you
know more than I do. Right? Like,
like we were on your treadmill
out there and you go,
it's 13%. What did you say? 10%
more difficult than regular running.
Okay.
I forgot the fact.
What you just said from
the time we walk in,
I lost it so I don't,
I don't have the repension
that I wish I had some Alpha brain. I
need something. Do we have any here?
Is that what I'm missing
in my diet? Alpha? It's a,
what's interesting though is that
people will come up to me with shit that
happened just a few years ago and I'm
like, I don't remember that at all.
Like I think you have a certain amount
of room in your brain and my brain is
always deleting stuff that it
doesn't think it needs anymore.
And then shoving in new things.
Like sometimes someone will tell
me about something, I'm like,
what are you talking about?
And they're like,
you don't remember there was the guy
with no arms who drove us around. I went,
what? And then I have to go. Oh yeah.
It's like I find the folder in my head and
like, oh, there it is. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And then we went to the pool
hall and Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah.
And then I'll remember. Gotcha.
But if, yeah, it's just a,
for whatever reason, this, uh, I can only,
I only keep things that I'm
interested in. Gotcha. Yeah.
I just wish I could retain a lot of
the things I either see or hear to then
recall it in a conversation.
You can, but you got to write things down.
You got to like want to recall things.
Yeah,
it's a problem.
I don't do a lot of writing as far as
like a notepad or anything to just take
notes.
When you write your act,
do you write it in your head
or do you write it on paper or
it's all audio? Just audio.
I'll go to the comedy store.
I record it and I listened to it on
the way home and then I'll go, oh,
maybe I'll do this next time. Maybe I'll
do that. I'll take that out and this out.
And then, uh, so there's no writing.
My Act is more recalling stories
then sitting in a room going, oh,
I think this is funny. So that's
kind of how I work. But, uh, yeah,
the reason I say that to
start off is just like,
I see you go down a lot of different
paths on the podcast and I often the gold
man, if I was sitting in that
chair, could I add to conversation?
And a lot of times it's,
no,
I can't kid just because
for whatever the reason,
I, uh, I just feel like I need to
be a little bit more, um, well-read.
How often you read? Uh, like
I read the Goggins Book. Yeah.
And that fucking book, yeah. And Life
Dot Dude had, huh? It's sad life.
But then on the flip side,
inspiring to, you know,
a guy like myself were, you know,
I'm running, I'm running say,
or I'm working out and I thought of
this guy, go, you know what, let's,
let's put another mile into
this. So, uh, yeah. I mean,
I'm just now starting to get into a
little bit more books than I have in the
past because in the past, to be
honest with you, I haven't really,
I haven't really read much.
I try to read a one new thing a week.
And the way I try to do it is, uh,
I have, uh, uh, I use a lot of
audio books, but I also read books.
So I go back and forth in between them
in between reading and audio books.
But I find for whatever reason,
I retained more with audio
books than I do with reading. I,
maybe it's my add or something like that,
because when I'm reading,
I kind of have to back up sometimes. Like
I'll go through a whole paragraph for,
I'm thinking about some other shit while
I'm reading, and then I got to go, okay,
asshole backup, reread that,
go over it again. You know?
That's what I find. I, I,
my mind wanders like, yeah.