The joe rogan experience. Well, if
you're going to do Sam Tripoli's podcast,
tin foil hat,
just understand that it's a different
kind of conspiracy theory podcasts.
It's like his big foot psychic,
like those kinds of questions
and expect to get a
contact high from the room.
I just wanted to ask you about that George
Saint Pierre stuff with you or foes?
I think it's head trauma.
Yeah. Yeah. Or did he,
did he have sex with those hot green
check? Maybe did, but if I had a gas,
the way he was describing things is
very similar to the way people describe
things when they've experienced
success of head trauma. Really? Yeah,
because he missed his time.
He's memory's not, not good.
Like he'll get home and then he'll have
groceries that he bought and left in his
trunk and not even realize it.
And it'll go out to his trunk
and the rotten and he's like,
I don't even remember going to
this door. Wow. The alien he's got,
I think he's got this idea that this,
these glitches in his mind,
it's not a fucking coincidence that
the guy got punched in the head.
I think they did a stat
before the Bisping fight.
I think it was more than 800 times.
Wow.
You got hit in the head and his UFC
career, forget about all the gym training.
Forget about all the other stuff.
Right.
And forget about the fights outside of
the UFC that he had before he got into
the UFC when he was in Tko remember?
Yeah.
So he's experienced a lot of head trauma.
One of the symptoms of head trauma
is memory loss issues and mean. Um,
and Hendricks hit him hard
a lot. Yes, he did. Yeah.
And he's only one guy that hit him hard.
I mean,
a lot of guys hit him hard that Sarah
scrambled is fucking brain and a lot of
guys hit him hard. And that's
just outside of sparring. I mean,
that's us outside of everything else that
he's done sparring with Rory Mcdonald
and Wonderboy and all the other
guys that he had to spar with. Yeah.
I think that's most likely what it is.
People who have been,
who've experienced a lot of head trauma.
That's one of the real
problems with it is. Um, um,
what does, what does the dude from
the Chicago bears, the famous guy,
the fucking quarterback from the bears?
Yes.
Mcmahon was on the cover of sports
illustrated talking about it,
but he'll be in the middle of his, um,
his living room holding these keys.
He had no idea how it's keys got in his
hand, doesn't know where he's going. Wow.
Where am I going? Like, why am I standing
there holding my keys? You just forget.
Stop. Scary. Yeah, there's
really scared actions. Well,
that's why it's been so impressive
that you, with your long fight career,
you kickbox do box.
Do you know you had a lot of MMA fights?
I think I learned early on with the
kickboxing and boxing and I looked at the
older guys and listen to them talk
and went, I don't want to be that guy.
So I started paying
attention to the defense.
I started watching films on great
boxers with great defense, footwork,
head movement, you know, all that
sort of stuff. And just, and I,
and it was the key. I never got
hit with anything I didn't see.
I think you have sturdy jeans too.
You've got them. Croatian gene helps.
I'm sure it helps. So I'm, I, I'm the
smallest correlation on the planet.
When you run into the Croatians are all
huge, like Steve Cro, cop type characters,
steep
Emile [inaudible] choose a bear of a
human being. Yeah. Right. Yeah. Super.
But that's just, have you ever seen the
Olympic water polo team from Croatia? No.
Can scariest dudes on the planet.
Third of all, massive six,
eight guys that just will drown you.
Okay.