Conversion therapies, the weirdest
shit of all time. There was a,
an article that I've read,
uh, about, uh, they were,
they were manipulating pleasure.
It turned out it's, I started,
I started reading it from a,
a study on rats and they did this
thing with rats where they, um,
provided they've, they figured
out a way to give rats orgasms.
They figured out a way to jazz up
the pleasure center of the brain
and they would do anything to do
it. They would, they would shock,
they would run up, pass an
area that shocked them. Like
they, they, they did do it,
do anything to get to this area where
they can have these orgasms and they
wouldn't have him up to 2000 times a day.
They would just not just all day long.
And in reading male and female rats.
Yeah,
just rats just right there.
Just, just rats trying to come.
And so when I was that
we're in hour three.
Oh, it's amazing. She studies amazing.
Well this is what's amazing about it.
Sorry folks.
Mr Mrs [inaudible] time to turn away.
They did it with a, a gay man. While they
were doing this, this is in the 1970s.
There's a couple different
studies that they did,
but one of them they did with this gay
guy where they tried to stimulate certain
parts of his brain while they were showing
him heterosexual porn and they were
trying to convert him
into being heterosexual.
And apparently they had some meager amount
of success with this where he engaged
in sexual relationships with women and uh,
and apparently even enjoyed it.
And they did something to the,
literally stimulate a part of his brain
that would excite arousal and tried to
connect that with, um,
with heterosexual porn and,
and made him orgasm,
uh,
made him masturbate to orgasm while
they were doing this and showing him
straight porn. And the idea was that
they were going to reprogram his mind.
How'd that work out? It didn't, but
it did. It did in terms of short term.
But it didn't mean it must have been just
massively confused, easily sexuality.
It's not just about what makes
you have an orgasm. No, it's not.
It's also incredibly,
it's incredibly complex.
And one of the things that
happens is, uh, you, you get,
you can have gay experiences
when you're young,
if someone does something to you in
imprints upon you arousal at a young age
with,
with gay experiences,
sometimes even heterosexual men will get
aroused by certain gay images and gay
things because of their past.
Because of that.
Like Chris is talking about that we're
all on a spectrum and speculative.
Yes, I think so for sure. We all
certainly are. But it's also speculative.
How much of that spectrum is influenced
by your environment versus your jeans
and you know, and this is very
taboo for some people discuss,
even though it's really the human
sexuality is incredibly fascinating and
there's,
there's some major taboo
areas of exploration and when
you start looking at like
what makes a person gay or straight,
whether it's nature or nurture,
whether it's a combination of those
things where it's someone's just radically
gay from the room or whether someone's
radically straight from the womb. These,
these studies where they were trying to,
they were trying to turn someone with
science and they were trying to turn
someone straight. It's cray. It's, uh,
it's very, you couldn't do it today.
You'd never be able to do
it today in America. Yeah.
I believe it was [inaudible] 71 they did
it. Yeah. I'll send it to you. It's crazy.
It's crazy. Um, widely criticized,
but heavily studied. You know,
the woman, they did it to a woman
to, uh, they, they stuck these,
this woman had a problem
with pain killers and so, um,
they figured out a way to wire her brain.
Is this like electric shock therapy?
These fucking dental drills,
they put holes in their brain.
They fucking can do whatever they wanted.
Do this.
Now's the time we break
out the Ilan Musk weed.