Search net gear for Tyron Woodley had
some choice words about Colby coven too.
Yeah, he was, uh, you know, talking
about Colby, like campaigning,
hard to get the fight and talking
all kinds of crazy shit about him.
But Tyron was saying like this,
first of all,
everything he's saying about our
training sessions is 100% bullshit.
And he's like, when I get that dude in the
octagon, if he ever does get that shot,
he goes, I'm going to fuck him up. I said,
he was Colby Covington is never going
to fight again after he fazes me.
That's what he said. Yeah, he was,
we were talking before the weigh ins.
We were standing around the octagon
before the weigh this past UFC in Detroit
and he was, he was like
shaking his head and he's like,
I'm gonna fuck that dude up. He's
like, he does not understand.
He's not on my level. He's talking
to all kinds of shit. He's, you know,
writing all these checks that there's
no way he's fucking talent can cache.
And when I get them in there,
I'm going to smash him and he goes,
I'm going to take my time on him.
I'm gonna try to hurt him. He,
this is what he said to me.
That was crazy. He goes,
I have never tried to hit anyone with all
my power in the octagon. And I'm like,
wait, what? That's not possible.
He sends people flying across the aisle
and watch his fight with Jay Huron.
Oh yeah you can, you can hit
somebody harder than that.
Are you sure? Cause that's,
that doesn't seem normal. That doesn't
seem right. Talking about his leg kicks.
I was just going to ask you,
what'd you think of being
there for the Gates Alvarez?
That was great. Gosh it was amazing.
There was two fights that night that made,
there was, there were humbling.
Um, that was one of them.
That fight was humbling like
the fucking guts and glory.
Watching those guys go at it.
But Yancey Madeiros and cal by
Oliveira might've been even crazier.
I think that was the
craziest fight of the night.
I believe that one performance of
the night. Thank the baby Jesus.
Cause if it didn't,
there was some criminal shenanigans afoot.
It was the craziest fight ever.
They one would get rocked and the other
would get rocked and you'd think the
fight was over. And then the other
one come back, a rock, the other one.
And then finally Yancey
one and the third round.
I mean it was just a fucking k odic war.
It was such a good fight.
Just such a good fight to bonuses to
fight of the night awards. That's nice.
See,
that's what I love about the UFC when,
when people really perform and
lay it on the line like that.
But did Allah did Haldo uh,
although in Holloway,
when any sort of a fight of the night,
I know Francis didn't,
but they said they were,
yeah,
they were going to hook him
up with some sort of a bonus.
How do you not give that Guy Kao the
night? What? What are we doing here?
What is it?
What's that say?
It just says that those
two guys fight at night.
Didn't say anything about
anything else. Oh, okay. Well.
So does it says that fight,
that fight of the night? No,
no, no, no, no. The Gate,
she g and Cowboy Oliveira Yancey
Madeiros got fight of the night.
Well Max Holloway's performance
was nothing short of masterful,
nothing short of Masto. The way
he handled Aldo, the way he, he,
he yelled at me after the first round,
he gets done with the f,
the round that he runs, he's going
back to his and he looks at me, goes,
the man is tired,
the man is tired.
He's a motherfucker,
dude.
Max Holloway is a real fucking warrior.
I mean to the core,
that guy relishes it. He
loves it. When he was like,
like chicken neck in it all
though he's got his hands down.
He's talking shit to them and stalking
him. You could see it in all those face.
Like he was drowning.
He would see the waves were coming and
he knew he wasn't going to be able to dog
paddle for too long.
Like he's like Jesus Christ.
Like how am I going to
keep up with this guy?
And the thing about Max Holloway that's
so interesting is he's in a lot of ways,
he has that sort of Nick Diaz approach
where he's not hitting you with all of
his mind. He's not throwing
these haymakers and less,
he's got you hurt until he's got you hurt.
Once he's got you hurt,
then he's just fucking
whip and bombs your way.
But until then he's just constantly
on you just constantly peppering you,
constantly, your kick knee punch,
move forward, move forward,
and you're just dealing with
him and trying to breathe.
You don't get any breath.
And he just keeps that pressure on you.
And he knew all those fading, right?
And I'll tell you all to look good.
And at first I thought he's
going to start picking it up.
Like almost the old with the leg kicks,
he should get clay kick, clay should have,
he should have gone.
His strategy should have been almost
entirely leg kicks centered. Right?
And he was trying to catch him and he
caught him with a couple of good punches.
But all of his punches are sprints,
right?
And if he doesn't knock
you out with those sprints,
like he only has so many
of those in the gas tank,
you're fighting the guy that can do it
for a marathon and he and he can and Max
Holloway,
Ken,
he is so well conditioned and so aware
of visibility and not stretching himself.
So when they got to the third he started
slugging it out with all though at the
very beginning of the third he's like,
I know this guy's tired. He goes,
I'm going to make them sprint with me.
And you could see like as the,
the beginning of the
third round played out,
all was swinging wild at and
I was watching it. So I was a,
I was going like this is not conservative.
Like he's not conserving
his energy at all.
What he's doing is trying to take Max
Holloway out with one shot and he's
blowing out his entire wad doing this.
And then you saw Holloway
just calming out,
common on common on just bang,
Bang, Bang, pop, pop, pop, pop,
pop and all of those trying to move
his head and he's using all his head
movement. But he never gets a break. Yeah.
It's an incredible pace that Holloway.
That's incredible. It doesn't give
you any space. You don't get any rest.
You don't get it. He does. There's
no laying back with Holloway.
Max Holloway's on you, on you, on you.
I love what he said about fighting Aldo
in Rio too. He goes, that's what kings do.
He goes, they go to the other person's
village and they'd take the crown.
It's like, Ooh, it's right. It's
what they do. That's what he did.
He's the baddest motherfucker. I think
he's the best one 45 forever. I mean,
he might not agree with it yet
because of the record, which I see.
I see his point,
but the way he fights the,
the octagon Iq that he shows his,
his fight Iq is ability to find a weakness
and to see it as predatory behavior
inside the octagon. I think he's the
best. I really do. I just think I, I,
it's so impressive to me that he's not
like all doe in his prime was spectacular
and amazingly impressive.
Like his flying knee,
first round knockout of Cub Swanson. The
knockout of Chad Mendez, you know, I mean,
he's, he's the, the Uriah Faber fight.
We brutalize your rise leg. I mean,
he's unquestionably one of the greats
of all time, but in my opinion,
skill wise,
Max Hallway has now surpassed him.