Now,
what do you think about these guys that
are talking about bringing animals back?
Um, like as a scientist?
Sure. De Extinction is,
it's a weird word. It is. It is. It's a
reintroduction. Is that a better word?
They call it the extinctions I would
call. That's what they call it. Yeah.
De Extinction is,
to me it's fascinating,
especially if it's something like
say the passenger pigeon, right?
We used to have billions of them in
the United States, wiped him out. Um,
and now they're saying, you know, Dick, we
can take the closest living relative, uh,
isolate some jeans and make a new
passenger pigeon. Is that worth it?
Cause it's something we wiped out
in the last hundred years. Yes.
I feel like that's, we should heal the
ecosystem by putting that back. Right.
That being said,
we still need to learn from our mistakes.
Like we need to take into account
what we did and why we did it.
And like do I think there should be a
Jurassic park and a bunch of mammoths and
TRX is absolutely not. That's a
waste. Whether we can or cannot do it.
To me that's a waste of scientific
resources that could go towards conserving
things that are on the brink.
Now,
when you say like he'll or men,
the environment or the ecosystem,
when you would bring back something like
a passenger pigeon isn't like 90% of
everything that ever existed
extinct. Sure, absolutely.
So does the ecosystem adjust and evolve
and would reintroducing something like a
passenger pigeon would it kind of fucked
things up that exists now where new
animals have taken a different
position on the hierarchy?
It's too short and evolutionary time.
So we are in what's called the
sixth mass extinction event, right?
There's been five others before us.
The one we're in now,
it's happening at 80% greater rate
than it's ever happened before.
So we are wiping out things more
quickly than the world can adapt.
So you know, you go into an environment
and you take out all the apex predators,
the prey explodes, the prey
explodes, the grass gets eaten down,
everything collapses. Now if you
left that environment over time,
over evolutionary time, it
would adapt, right? Maybe say,
say all of the predators got a
disease and they died dad out over 300
generations during that time,
something would evolve within the
environment to adapt the prey so that it
didn't wipe out the environment. That's
just kind of the nature. It's balance.
But when you go in there and do
it in 10 years or five years,
it throws off the equilibrium.
So when you, in theory,
when you reintroduce something that's
been, and it's not theory, it's,
it's science,
they've shown this even right here
in the California Channel Islands.
When you put something back
that's missing from the ecosystem,
it's like you're putting a
piece of the puzzle back, right?
And then you can allow it to do
its thing over evolutionary time.
What did they do in the channel islands?
So I was actually a big part of
that and I loved, loved the project.
So the California channel islands were
settled by agriculture. There were sheeps,
goats, pigs, blah, blah, blah. There was
everything brought over there. Right?
And so not Catalina, but think about
the northern channel islands. Um,
what happened was when all
these animals were brought in,
all the farmers were there.
Then Golden Eagle started coming over.
Golden Eagles came over to eat
the pigs and everything else.
They flew across the ocean,
flew across the channel,
started praying on pigs
and everything else.
There was an animal on the channel
islands called the Channel Island Fox.
Very gorgeous, cute,
cuddly little Fox. Um,
you can see them if you've got a Santa
Cruz island, there's loads of them now,
thanks to the work that scientists have
done. Anyway, they were like, okay,
the Fox is being there. It
is, isn't it gorgeous? Thanks.
So the Fox is being wiped out through
habitat destruction through all these
undulates that have been brought in.
So scientists got together and said,
what undulates cows. Yeah, domestic
animals, cows, sheep, goats, et cetera.
So scientists came in and said, you know,
the habitats getting destroyed, the,
and that,
that's just the keystone.
There were several species that were
on the decline. The cows are getting,
the livestock is wiping out the habitat.
The foxes are declining.
What did we do? Well, obvious answer.
Let's remove all the livestock.
So we removed all the livestock,
right through helicopters.
It was a lot of pigs that were causing
damage, all that kind of stuff.
We were moved at all.
Then the Golden Eagle started praying
on the foxes because their main habitat
was gone. So now the foxes
are under even more pressure.
So then we were moved the Golden Eagles.
This is a very abridged
version of what happened,
but now we've got the Golden Eagles
also pushed out the Bald Eagle,
which are fish eaters,
which lived on the island.
So now after loads of years of removing
golden eagles, like relocating them,
removing all of the livestock,
now you have a healthy population
of channel island foxes.
The Bald Eagles are
back there eating fish.
The whole ecosystem is back in balance.
Had it been left the way it was,
what you would have found
at the California Channel
Islands over say 20 or 30
more years, 40 or 50 more years?
No foxes, no, no bald eagles,
a ton of Golden Eagles and a ton of pigs.
And likely over time pigs would have
exploded to the point that they Easter
island to themselves. Right? They
ate up all the resources, destroyed,
all the habitat. Population
collapsed. Golden Eagles collapse,
nothing left on the APP. What do you
mean by Easter island themselves?
So you're familiar with Easter
Island and South America?
I know what those statues are
and all that stuff, but I,
I'm not familiar with what happened
to Sean. So that island is,
was an ancient civilization. That was
the Mech. It had everything offline.
It had big trees, tons of food,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
People settled there and they said,
this place is incredible. It's,
it's paradoxical. Um, and then they
started cutting down the trees to fish.
They started eating all the mammals.
And what actually happened is
because there were so remote,
the middle of the ocean, nowhere near
South America, nowhere near anywhere else,
they cut down the last tree.
There were no more canoes,
there was no more food on the island.
And the population collapsed.
The island was barren. It was void of
trees, void of life, void of anything.
And they didn't have the canoes or
anything to leave anymore because they cut
down the last tree to build,
build a boat or make firewood and
everybody there died. Oh Shit. So that,
that's what happens when you
use up every last resource. God.
So wow, when did this
happen? Uh, I couldn't,
couldn't tell you cause I thought it
was like a mystery what happened to the
population of Easter island. So
they, they're pretty, that's yours.
That's the accepted, that's the
scientifically accepted understanding.
Did they get this from fossils?
They get this from bones. So they,
they've sort of pieced it together.
Yup. They took, they take, you know,
isotope samples and measure
carbon dating and Yadda Yadda.
I think that the heads are
still a pretty big mystery.
Why I think a certain people believe
that the heads were like, uh, an Ale,
you know, calling to the gods to help save
things cause they were going so badly,
Yada Yada. But I believe the heads
are still a pretty big mystery.
But the actual anthropology,
that population, the collapse is,
is known to be due to a running out
of resource. How long did it go for?
Couldn't tell you. Did they have an
idea of how long the population lasted?
I think it's all, I think
it's all published. Yeah.
I don't know off the top of my head,
but it was,
it was a thriving population that
flew too close to the sun as they say,
because of Easter Island, small
size. When he's 63 square miles,
it quickly became overpopulating its
resources. We're rapidly depleted.
When Europeans arrived in Easter island
between the late 17 hundreds in the
early 18 hundreds it was reported that
the more I were knocked down and the
islands seem to,
did I say that right?
My why being knocked down and the island
seem to have been a recent war site.
Hmm. Last supplies. Yeah.
Let's see. The next one there.
Constant warfare between the tribes,
lack of surprise, plies and resources,
disease,
invasive species and the opening of the
island to foreign slave trade eventually
led to Easter island's
collapsed by the 1860s wow.
So it didn't take long. 1700
the 1860s that was a wrap. Wow.
It was annexed by Chile,
and so they've never tried to repopulate
the island with trees or anything else,
and they're just kind of leave it alone.
I believe so.
I know you can go there and visit it
and see the heads and I think there are
some things there now, but it's, it's
barren. There are no trees. There's no,
you know,
it's all been depleted.