I forgot.
That's the Joe Rogan experience.
It's funny because like
there are these chapters,
it's like this is all coming full circle
to what we're talking about with like
Richard Branson on a boat,
getting his dick sucked doing coke,
but,
but here's the thing,
there's a cycle and if you hang in
there long enough becomes cool again,
like if you're hammered and
you're 20 and you're out there,
how it a party is kind
of silly and it's fun,
but if you're hammered and
you're 60 it's kind of sad. Yeah.
But if you're hammered and your 90
it's funny again. Yeah, absolutely.
It's going to hang in there. If you're
a 90 year old drunk, I got a job out.
You all just shocked my Gig,
which by the way,
apparently the latest in the
sexual harassment Olympics,
the latest a entry is Stan Lee
from marvel comics. Really?
Yeah. He's 95 years old. Yeah.
He lives in some giant mansion
and he has a bunch of nurses.
He's trying to get them all the bloom.
Of course now he says it's the shakedown.
He says they're all, they're all
just trying to get money from them.
May very well be the case.
She or it may well very well be the case
that he is like a lot of 95 year old
dudes with 20 million bucks in the
bank and about six months to live.
Just getting it on. What do you
do? You try, you'd go for it.
He swing those fucking
dice. Come on. Seven
Stanley, if he really can. If
the enemy, if you're worth,
well, hold on. Go back to that. What does
it say now? He, okay. He bought someone.
Then it was revealed that someone had
bought an $850,000 condo in his name
without his knowledge. Yeah, that was last
week. I don't know if you're at oh no.
What happened?
Follow police report after discovering
that someone had stolen $300,000 from him.
Wow.
Using a forged check and then it was a
reveal that someone bought an $850,000
condo in his name without
his knowledge of fact.
It came to light when his team
did a full audit of his accounts.
Following the forged check, whether this
is any way related. Okay. This guy be,
he might be being honest.
This might be in reaction to
the shakedown, the shakedown,
but this guy has so much money that
someone bought an $850,000 condo in his
name, and he didn't learn about it until
they were going over the books. Well,
he didn't.
Yeah,
he didn't mind me about it until
they found a $300,000 stolen cheque.
That's a baller. Yeah. Stanley,
y'all and out of control hero.
ALTEC kicking kicked
fucking ass superhero. Yeah.
I'd like to think that he's not the guy
who's trying to tell these maids to suck
his deck. Naw, I doubt it. I
like to think that. Me Too.
I want some heroes left a
couple of those guys. Phew.
But hang in there guys.
Okay.