Seattle, you must be, I mean,
cause you're here, right?
You feel tremor because they must
say they happen all the time. Right.
I've only been a few times. One
time I felt them before. The,
the biggest ones I ever felt
was when I first moved here.
I first moved here in 94 and it was right
after the Northridge earthquake and uh,
I was in my house and I felt,
uh,
I guess it was like a 5.5
where the whole thing just,
it was weird,
but it gave me the impression that
the house that I was living in or the
apartment that I was in was
made out of the same stuff,
like a box that a
refrigerator would come in.
You know how like you can
move it around inside.
The whole thing was just
moving like easily left and
right. I was like, Holy Shit.
That was my, I've only had a few times
that I've, you know, felt on, I'm like,
it's like it's, you know, at
first I thought it was a truck.
I thought a truck was rolling,
you know? And I'm like, no man,
that was an earthquake. And the
one that I experienced was nothing.
I mean baby one,
the ones that they're getting right now
somewhere in the world, I mean there's,
there's always something that's
like a five or six. Yeah.
So this goes back to your point about the,
uh, you know, a lot of planets, right?
We'll be like way more plate
tectonically active, volatile than ours.
So,
you know,
I mean a lot to me and I
think good planets are going
to be like really hard to
find. Yeah. So, you know,
it may be, that may be the
solution. The other solution is,
you know, I mean, the way
you guys found out about me,
so I did that article about the previous
civilization, you know, like what is it,
how do you know whether or not there was
a previous civilization? And you know,
one solution could be that,
look, they were here, you know,
that somebody did arrive and
spent some time on earth.
But if it was like half a billion
years ago and they only last, right,
every civilization has a finite
lifetime. They only lasted for, you know,
even a few hundred thousand years,
they wouldn't leave.
There'd be no record left to, it'd
be nothing. There'd be nothing.
What do you think that's possible that
something's ever visited here and because
that is the big question and that's the,
the thing that gets the UFO dorks
more jazzed up than anything is the
possibility that we'd been visited. Yeah.
Not In the, I'm, I'm definitely not you.
Ufos. There's, there's two
arguments against you. Fo's
uh, one is as, as you know,
a friend of mine, Jason Wright says, he's
like, look as astronomers, man, you know,
we're finding all those aspects. We're
finding a little chunks of rock moving.
You know, nobody looks at the sky harder
than we do. Right, right. And you know,
if anything, unless you want to
go to the conspiracy theories,
we would have found something.
My other argument is like,
what's with the headlights? You know what
I mean? People are just like, Oh man,
I saw lights in the sky and then they
moved around and then they disappeared.
You know, but they don't really
want to be seen. I'm like,
why did they have headlights on? Like
why just turn off the fricking roommates?
It just, why would they have
lights in the first place?
You came from another civilization and
you can't get around without your high
beams.
You know what the fuck are you seeing
what those lights and you're not seeing
shit.
When was the last time you saw planes
have lights or their planes don't run into
them. They don't have lights so they could
see where they're going. Yeah. So what,
so why do they have, right, exactly.
The planes have lights so
other people can see them.
So they're here but they're mysterious.
They don't want to be found in turn
off the fricking light. So they, yeah,
they wouldn't have any lines.
Yeah, they always have lights.
People are always saying like a hub and
I saw license guy and then they moved
back and forth. And the problem
with human memory memories, right?
Horrible and memory of events that are
stunning or shocking or a nerving or you
think you saw something, right. They've
done all that research. Even in trials,
right. Where people see things currently
Ufo is, you know, I'm just kinda like,
do you think it's possible that there
could be life on other planets and it's
possible there could be intelligent life
on other planets and we send probes to
Mars? Why wouldn't I think that
if they do send something here,
they're going to send something without
biological life inside of it. Yeah. Yeah.
Well this is,
you know,
it's a really interesting question is
like you were talking about like what will
we evolve into in, you know,
a million years, uh, you know,
it may be possible that biology
is a short period of intelligence.
You build machines and the
machines become, you know,
download yourself into them.
I mean, that's a real
possibility that like, you know,
silicon makes a lot
more sense than wetware.
While the problem is we think
of artificial intelligence
as artificial, right?
It's definitely real, right? Yeah, no,
that's exactly, it's not, it's not fake.
It's right there. Right. You know,
it's like there's artificial milk,
you know what I mean? But it's, it's
a liquid. It's an actual liquid.
There's not an artificial life,
silicon created life.
That's again,
the idea that the biosphere,
this may be that what the biosphere
solution to spreading itself to getting it
maybe that like, yeah, silicon that
that's kind of a normal, I mean I'm,
I am super skeptical about like the whole
trans human thing about we're going to
download ourselves into intelligent,
you know, it took, are you,
have you ever gone to one of those
conventions dorks now there's some pretty
serious dork in, well, there's
geniuses in those dorks too.
It's really interesting.
It's like they're fully,
wholly committed to this prospect
of downloading themselves.
You've talked to Kurt's well before.
Uh, no, but I've read his stuff.
I got a chance to interview him a few
years back for [inaudible] smart beyond
smart. But God damn is he committed
to it. And then when you get to it,
you realize that what he actually
wants to do is recreate his father.
Yeah. He's, his father died when he
was young and he wants to be able to,
through memories and photographs
and what he knows about his father,
literally recreate his father and be
able to have a conversation with them.
He was talking about this,
but what he's doing is he's going way,
way into the future into the possibilities
of, he's not seeing like, well,
five years from now we're going
to be able to send, you know,
gigabyte pictures through the mail.
Now he's saying,
let's think of if you
keep going exponentially
electronics and technology and
innovation keeps continually accelerating.
We could potentially get to the
point where it's the impossible.
Well,
you'd be able to recreate human beings
based on your knowledge of them and in
the end there'll be able to come
up with some sort of a program.
Will he'll be able to have a
conversation with his father. Yeah. See,
I think that misunder I
mean, I think it's, you know,
it's true about like the possibility
of a singularity in technological
development, but you know, it's not going
to be his father. That's the sad thing,
you know, I think we seriously, you know,
I've done some work on this as an
interest of mine about mind. What is mind,
you know, what's the relationship
between mind and matter? And, um,
I think we have like a
serious misunderstood,
we don't understand consciousness very
well at all. So the idea that like,
oh yeah, it's just got to be
trivial to download your, you know,
your consciousness into a computer.
I think it's pretty, you know,
there's like a shit load of assumptions
in there about like what mind is and the
relationship between like your
neurons and, you know, awareness.
So that's why I think those guys,
it's a little bit of a religion,
you know what I mean? There's a little
bit of religion and, and you know,
so it's like 2045 is the new benchmark.
For whatever reason.
That's the new number.
They get to keep going back.
It's gonna be like every
other, every other rapture. Ah,
we thought it was 2045 we really got 2065,
you know,
we went to this 2045 conference.
Me and my friend Ran Dunkin and we got
to talk to some of these guys and it's
really fascinating.
And one of them had created some
robot that was supposed to be him,
but it didn't work well. So they
never revealed that at the conference.
Too many bugs in it.
It's intriguing.
It's like I want them to
keep going cause I mean when,
when do we get going to get to x?
Mokena when are we going to talk about
good movies? So did you like that?
One of my favorite movies ever.
So smart.
So like just like simple stop beating me
over the head with it and cut the shit
most moving moments in that
movie. Yeah, the entire,
I think that's one of my
all time top 20 movies,
which she stabs him just emotionless.
It was amazing.
Amazing alert. Did you
like a annihilation? Yes.
I didn't like it as much,
but I liked it.
It was very weird and the ending seemed
like some producers put their urges in
the soup and just like back to Pittsburgh,
what's happening here?
Who made this part? But I enjoyed
it. Yeah. So I think like, you know,
I mean the danger with anything when
it comes to AI and said, so what are,
you know, here's an interesting thing
about Ai. Like we're, we are getting,
making amazing strides with AI now.
Now artificial intelligence is
different from artificial consciousness,
you know what I mean? So like,
but um, but the AI that, you know,
what we're getting out of it is nothing
like us, right? So the, you know,
back in the day where people were like,
oh,
we're going to like model the human
brain and that's how we'll do it. Well,
like make programs that are, and
what they've learned, it's like,
oh that doesn't really work that well.
So now this is the whole big data thing.
Like, you know, network
theory and big data and deep
learning. We're like, you know,
they're using statistical,
you know, the power of,
of having huge amounts of computing
and statistical reasoning so that like,
you know, get the computer. Like, you
know, it'll find the picture of the cat,
but you have no idea why it found
the pit didn't reason. Like, Oh yeah,
that was where it looks like
cat and I liked cuts, you
know, it was just like, oh,
these kinds of lines go with that kind
of thing and it has no idea what it's
doing, but it'll act intelligently.
And so that's, you know,
I mean that's kind of freaky deaky in
a lot of ways too. I think people are,
I think it's smart to think
about the dangers of AI,
not necessarily what additional
features to us. Yeah.
Not necessarily the dangerous.
Just the dangers to this thing that we
are this weird monkey thing that wants to
keep being a monkey thing.
Well you mean in the sense of like,
right that it's going to replace us?
Yes. Yeah. Yeah. I think it's inevitable.
I mean,
do you,
don't you think that if you go back and
interview the single celled organism
before branched off into multicell,
that'd be kind of a boring fuck
this multi-celled bullshit.
I don't want to stay a single cell
at the bottom of the assholes,
man with their rock and roll
music metal cars. Fuck that.
I don't want a car, man. I liked staying
down here. There's a real thought to that,
that we are the wetware that
is the problem. No, no, listen,
I think it's fully conceivable. Like I'm
not going to like, it would never happen,
but as a, a guy knows, a
philosopher says, you know,
there's a certain way in which everything
we do with AI right now, it's not like,
you know, Watson is playing chess. It's
like we're using Watson to play chess.
It's our tool. You know, and I think the
PR, the fear is the tool gets out of hand.
Not that it like develops a thing
where like I hid humans. You know, dad,
I hate you, but more
that it's like, you know,
these things which are
not actually thinking.
They act intelligent but they're
not thinking it can have a huge,
like it'll have a really negative
impact. You know, it'll, it'll, you know,
what does it,
there's that example of like,
if you design something that is
an AI system to make paper clips,
it ends up consuming the entire planet
making paperclips because that's what you
told it to do. Right. You never told it
to make a sustainable amount of. Right,
exactly. So I'm, I'm more worried about
that than I am of like Skynet, you know,
coming over and like,
you know,
deciding that it's going to take a drop
all the bombs on us cause you need to
get rid of it.