I see, I see. Jeff is like beyond
unique. Like there's nobody like him.
And what he does and what he is
able to do is really, it's really,
it's not only fun to watch,
but it's really like, you
know, you're a self starter.
He's a self starter.
Like it's great to see self starters
who find success because it really is
difficult to like take something and
like make it not only financially
successful but also like something that,
that we all respect and love. You know?
And that's,
you know,
I'd say the roasting thing
that Jeff really pretty much
has rebranded into like,
you know, every, every,
every possible way you can do it is always
good because he's behind it, you know,
when it's not, when it's not really
with him then and you're like,
I'm not so sure. There's other
people who are really good at it too.
But I'm just saying that like,
you know, that is when, you know,
we're on the road and people will scream
out the car door. It's the roast master.
I mean like,
you know,
I had my insomniac time but he like
2030 times that in terms of like
recognition,
I mean it's just amazing.
It is. Where the year you're
synonymous with roasts. Yeah. You know,
I mean like people say roasts,
they think Jeff Ross,
I earned it because wouldn't
people laughed at me and thought,
oh that's a dead art. It's
a lost art. It's antiquated.
It's Corny. It's old guys.
I stuck by it and said, no,
it's alternative comedy. No
one's doing it. I get to,
I get to hang with legends like Buddy
Hackett and Milton Berle, you know,
and I stuck to it because, and
there was a watch, there was a,
there was a time where I was
like embarrassed. Like, Oh,
I'm going to be pigeonholed as the roast
guy. Were you embarrassed? Not Him.
I don't know if embarrassed is the
right word, but comfortable. Yeah.
Cause you're like, well I want
to be more than that. You know,
when was this around? This is probably
10 years ago and I was in Vegas,
Chappelle. Again, words of wisdom.
He's like, dude, that's your lane.
Make that a five lane highway and ride it.
And that's kind of what we started,
what I started doing,
sort of really owning it and loving it
and to the credit of the world as we
became more pussies in the world,
like roasting became more and
more potent and important. Yeah.
And the world needs to develop thick skin,
and I think roasting honors people,
and it's done with love, but it also
kind of toughens us up a little bit.