You know, um, yeah.
Well there's a,
there's a movement going on in this
country right now that the social justice
movement and a,
it leans in that direction that people
don't want to look at things for how they
are. They want to look at
things for how they want them
to be. Yeah. That just,
I just don't understand.
You cannot
legislate that everything is going to be
equal for everybody because everybody's
not equal. I'm sorry. They're not equal.
They may be equal in terms of
their value as a human being. Yes.
But they're not equal in math skills.
They're not equal in how fast they run.
They're not equal in creativity. They're
not equal. Everybody has their own value,
but that doesn't mean they're marketable.
Skills in an open society and an
open market are going to be the same
now. It's ridiculous. I used to,
I had a joke on one of my special
sauce two specials ago about, uh,
there was a story about a woman
who was guarding the White House.
She was the lone guard at one of the doors
of the White House and some crazy man
broke in and knocked her to the ground
and just ran through the White House and
he was running around inside the White
House for like three minutes before they
finally some off duty.
Uh,
a secret service agent tackled this guy.
He saw like, what the fuck is going on?
This guy's running through the
White House, tackle this guy.
And that the joke was that people think
that a woman can do everything a man can
do. I go, a woman could do
everything a man could do.
Is that true? And some woman,
it was in the crowd of the comedy
store is like, yes. I go, well,
that doesn't make any fucking sense.
Here's why it doesn't make
any sense because a man
can't do everything a man can
do. I go, look,
I've met Shaquille O'Neal and his Dick
is where my face is and if the White
House's is experiencing a Shaq attack,
I'm the wrong person saved the world
because he's just going to run right over
me. I go, but if my wife and kid
where garden, the White House,
guess what I'm getting in?
Okay. I love my family,
but if it's between me and get it,
there's no way they're going to be
able to stop me. I loved them to death,
but I'm a man and they're women and if
there's a woman garden, the White House,
I don't care who she is, I'll fuck her up.
It's not going to happen. This is crazy.
But this,
someone had this idea that they would
put a woman in charge of a very physical
job.
You should have a giant man with a
violent temper and he should be armed.
Okay. Cause this is the guy that's keeping
bad people from the fucking president.
Yeah. I don't know. I don't understand.
It just seems like you got to
find your own lane. I mean, yeah.
You don't want to put me in the NBA.
Yeah. Physical things in particular. And
then there's also mental things. Look,
I suck at math. Okay. If, if, if
everyone has a chance to work at CERN,
right? Everyone has a chance
to work at the large Hadron,
including people that have
no idea about physics.
We're gonna have a real time
making these equations work.
Yeah, that's what I mean about
finding your own lane. Yeah. Cue.
I can't add two and two and get five
every time. I'm just not good at math,
but I'm good with words. I can talk, I
can read fast and I can comprehend well,
but I am not good with math,
so I got myself into a lane where I
talk for a living. I read, I talk,
I, it's qualitative, not quantitative.
I can accept that I'm not suited for that.
I mean w w I don't feel bad
about myself because of that.
Well, once you do something
and you're good at it,
you can accept not being
good at other things.
It's much easier if you find
the thing that you're good at,
whether it's gymnastics or singing
or painting, whatever the fuck it is.
If you could find a thing that
you're good at, it will make you,
it'll give you a s a feeling of self
worth and you won't need to be good at
everything you can accept and you can
enjoy other people being good at things as
well.
Yeah.
I shared earlier,
my dad was an alcoholic and I would
compare myself to that kid across cause I
had a damaged personal truth.
But I found a currency because at that
time in my life I was a pretty decent
athlete for this small school I was
going to. So that was my currency. Yeah.
So now it didn't matter what was happening
at home because I got strokes for
being able to jump high and run fast
at school. So that became my currency.
So now well I compared myself to him.
Okay,
maybe my home life wasn't as good as his,
but I could run faster and jump higher.
So that became my currency.
So now I, okay. That level,
the playing field for me and
you all would like you said,
fine what you're good at at a given
time and do what you're good at.
Find something you love,
find something you're passionate
about and they can also excel at.
And if you can work it out where it's
your vocation and your avocation,
you love doing it and you get paid for it,
then you're just double blessed and
then you got it right because you enjoy
doing this and it works
out and that's good. Yeah.
You catch lucky breaks if the
image, but that's, boy that's lucky.
Yeah it is.
And if I just think if you're
in your life and theirs,
you don't have something that
you're passionate about. I mean,
and I don't mean that in a cliche way.
If there's not something where you wake
up every day and there's nothing in your
life that you're excited to do,
man,
you need to go back to the
drawing board. Yeah. Cause if,
if all you're doing is just grinding
it out, you get up everyday,
go to a job you don't like do task you
don't care to do and come home to a home
you don't want to come home to and wait
to get them to do it again the next day
you're burning daylight.
What the hell existence is that I just,
I don't, I don't understand
that, that find something.
I don't care if it's gardening or
music or art or athletics or something.
Find something you're excited to do.
Yeah.
Expose yourself to different things with
that very purpose of finding something
that you love because their assumption
out there, there's something out there.
I guarantee you something. Yeah. There's
something healthy. It's not illegal.
It's not going to be high risk.
There's something you can do that's not
going to kill you or put you in jail
that you can be excited about.
Yeah. And I think it's, uh,
one of the most important things to do
when you're a parent is to try to expose
your kid to as many different things as
possible to find those things for them.
Yeah. I got two boys, as you know,
and you know, one of them really well,
and I did that growing up because my dad
never took me hunting a single day in
his life. He never took me
fishing a single day in his life.
He never took me camping a single day in
his life. He never took me to the lake.
He never took me skiing,
boating, anything.
So I took them to all of
those things I had no,
I had no clue what I was doing,
but I took him Turkey hunting,
duck hunting, deer hunting, she's
skiing, snow skiing, camping.
I did it all.
And to see what they like,
let them pick.
And boy,
when you don't know what you're
doing as a dad, that's a bitch.
Yeah. I mean, just little things like you,
you go camping and you don't realize that
sitting in your tent up on the side of
a hill,
even if it's like eight or 10 degrees,
is a bad idea. You've got to get on flat
ground. I mean, it looks flat to me,
but I spent the night try
not to roll down a damn hill.
It didn't look like it was on a slant,
but it was,
but you figure these
things out as you go along.
But I was glad I gave him those
experiences so they could choose.
And they did. And they, and there's some
of it they liked, some of it they didn't.