It's calling someone outright today.
It's so strange how, you know,
I don't know if you know,
but all in the world to stand up
comedy used to be progressive liberal,
like, like weird coffee shop
type rooms. It was all comedy.
They don't even use that term
anymore, right? Because it's so toxic.
And I try to avoid saying, I'll try. When
you say alternative media all the time,
and this has happened over the course of
just a couple of years. I mean, the, the,
the thing is shifted and it's moving
and evolving and morphing so quickly.
You want to know what's
really crazy. For years, I,
my Wikipedia page at claimed
that I invented a Zeppelin,
Zeppelin like a blimp. Yes.
Yeah. It's funny, right? Well,
Wikipedia said I was Brian
Callan's brother for a decade
here. Here's the thing.
When I went to Sweden, I specifically
stated, uh, let me, let me, let me,
let me back up. Paul Joseph Watson
of infowars put out a call saying,
I challenge any journalists to spend
a weekend in Malmo and I'll cover your
costs. Everybody's bombarding
him saying, Oh, pay me, pay me.
And he's kind of just ignoring it.
People are threatening to sue him.
You better pay.
You promised.
I had already set up a go fund
me for the project before,
I believe it was before he announced.
I made a video about it saying
Donald Trump said x, Y, and Z.
We're going to go to the story.
When I saw he made this call,
I think it was actually Emily who
noticed it, I said, hey, I'll do it.
And he was like to be on,
I think it had something like,
I was just taking the Piss, but
yeah, sure, I'll send you a donation.
And I laughed and I was like,
hey man, I'll take, you know,
if he wants to throw money at
my go fund me. Here's what,
what ends up happening is
people then claim I was uh,
I went to there because Paul Joseph Watson
Challenge challenged me. Not True. Um,
he donated about 9% of our total fund
that we raised and I was already planning
on going there. Wikipedia. Uh,
there was a challenge on the,
on my Wikipedia page where they,
someone said,
you wrote Tim Pool went there because
it Paul just Watson challenged him to,
that's not true.
What's your proof?
This youtube video from Tim Pool where
he says, we've already arranged this.
We're not going here because of
politics of Watson. That response,
that's not a reliable source.
Someone came back with a reliable source.
You know it, it was a Huffington post
article that quoted my youtube video.
How's that? I don't understand. Why
couldn't you just take my word for it?
Why did you have to get
Huffington post to just quote me?
That was apparently so that's enough.
I guess.
So the reason I bring this up is
because what happens then if you're a
conservative and a bunch of friends who
work for various news organizations all
at the same time write 10 articles
saying Joe Rogan is all right now on
Wikipedia at 10 articles pop up
immediately saying this is a fact.
10 different organizations have written
it and there it is in your, in your page.
And the crazy thing is the UK
does this all the time, you know,
they call various personalities.
All right? They call
Sargon, they call Dank Ula.
Yeah. Just go to Wikipedia and look up
the phrase, it means white nationalists,
neo confederate. It's like
literally about a white ethno state.
These people have denounced this and
that. And you know, it's like with,
with Sargon,
avocado was a really
fascinating phenomenon on
patrion where all of a sudden
these left wing outlets, sad Sargon was
banned for, uh, going after the alt right.
And I'm like, well, hold on.
You've written in the past
that he was all right. Well,
you, when you say you like the media is
not these, these various organizations,
same organizations, but different authors.
Well, I don't want to, I don't want to.
Okay. But not the same journalists.
Um, I, I will lean towards, I believe.
Yes. Because it's, it's,
it's so, so whenever it's
convenient, they just throw it,
throw that there are some people
who write. The problem is if I May,
if I named these people,
they're going to,
they're going to point their pens in my
direction and then all of these things
are going to swing at me. And the
other thing too is I don't want to,
I don't want to brigade them.
It's not important anyway.
What's really important is the actual
reality of how it was done. There are,
I really want to name this organization,
it's, it's one of the prominent,
well known, but they repeatedly write
stories that are just so over the top.
I roll my eyes and I'm like.