Everything good with you right now
while I'm smoking like a bitch.
You smoke every day. Was it? What
you smoking before all this? Hell No.
Just currently. Secretly Stan
hope got me back on the bastard.
You son of a bitch.
I quit for like 15 years in Doug.
Stan hope snuck Everytime I see Doug.
I'd smoke one.
He's got an evil spell on me. Oh, he's
eve. A little man. He's sober right now.
No cigarettes for him either.
That he always says that. No,
he's doing sober October. Are
Y'all doing sober? October. Wow.
Why did you ask me? I would've sobered up
for it. No. No, you wouldn't have done it.
No. I want to do, uh, get fucked up.
I want to go to retox retired.
That's when my boyfriend, Johnny
calls it. It's time to retox.
How many cigarettes are you smoking
a day? No. Well No. Who's counting?
You just keep walking. I'm not smoking
less than 10 less than 10 it's not bad,
but I was smoking a lot.
See,
I'm cutting it by 10
every week. Oh, okay. So,
so next week it'll be down to one a day.
All Week. What days? Not Bad.
And I'll see how I deal with it.
If anyone dies.
Okay.
This whole thing has been
completely fucking insane. And you,
yeah,
and I don't have to tell you,
but you caught this madness is
outrage culture right at the peak.
I think you, you hit peak
outreach culture. Thank you. Well,
people didn't give a fuck if
you were making a joke, get,
didn't give a fuck. Have you had
no idea that that lady was black?
Didn't give a fuck what
your mental state was.
Didn't give a fuck if you were on Ambien,
didn't give a fuck if you were drinking.
Didn't give a fuck if you
sincerely apologized. Oh,
go ahead. I do want to talk.
Don't pick that. Did, but
they didn't care that you,
you sincerely apologized and did not,
didn't mean to offend.
You were cracking a joke about it.
Woman
it,
it was funny how they've missed,
characterize it and lied about
it and added words to it.
But, um, yeah, I like talk
about the tweet, but uh, yeah,
I seriously apologize to all who might
inadvertently offended and because they
were offended for like it,
it wasn't even what they say they were
offended cause it didn't say that,
but they think that I tweeted
a said she looked like, uh,
you know, somebody and I never
said anything about her looks,
it was a political tweet and
it's just proof of how um,
everybody's under mass mind
control because they took a, um,
and of course I'm always
interested in that. You know,
you know that I've talked to,
yeah,
that's what I think people are under
the wave of self imposed mind control.
I don't think it's like there's anybody
pulling the strings you can get out of
it. No, I don't think anyone's pulling
the strings. I don't think this is a dead,
no, I don't, I don't think it's by design.
I think people were caught up in a
wave of fear and paranoia and political
correctness.
And I think one of the reasons why attack
they attack someone like you is first
of all,
you're wealthy and successful and famous.
You are beautiful and one of
the best comics of all time.
And you're also, uh, you're,
you're an easy target.
You're a white woman.
As a white woman,
what do you identify as?
I identify as a Jew. Well, there you go.
And this is what you thought this woman
was as well. What is my cousin Sharon?
She looks just like my cousin,
but it wasn't nothing to do with how
she looks that came after my tweet,
but the next blessing it about the
planet of the apes of her hands.
What she engineered in Iran.
And I had been on there talking about the,
the,
I call it a woman's revolution in Iran
for years and speaking to people in Iran
and bout it and what it means to,
uh,
the women who are second
class citizens there.
And uh,
so if you take that one tweet out of
like probably I tweet a lot. Yeah, I was,
I was traveling 400,000.
No, I don't go crazy.
I stay crazy. I admit it. I mean,
what the fuck? They're like,
you know what you've said you're crazy
for years and you know what? You're crazy.
Well, yeah, I said it
for fucking years. Well,
it's also one of the reasons was our
crazy, all comics are fucking nutso.
At least I don't wash my keys like some,
I know some guys they had,
they got to wash their keys five, six,
seven times where they can go on stage.
What's his name? Oh, I'm so
bad on names. Chris Farley.
I always ask comics, you know, I ask
him what's, what's your secret number?
Which years Joe number.
You don't have a number.
You don't have to do something a number
of times. You don't have a number.
What's your birthday?
Eight 1167 eight what's that?
August eight 1167.
You were born in 1967. Yes. Jesus.
F Christ. Um, I was in the, my,
I was in the Utah State Hospital.
When you were born,
what were you doing given birth?
No, I was in a mental institution.
That was my first hospitalization.
It lasted for nine months and it was the
Utah State Hospital in Provo where the
Osmonds are from.
So it was always a big Marie Osmond Fan.
The,
the mental
health aspect of this conversation is an
important one because here's my take on
this. Extremely important.
It is important.
And yesterday was mental health
awareness day. Yes, I know.
And I was quite aware
of being mentally help.
The yesterday as I was smoking,
if someone has, all I eat
is cheese. If someone has a,
an injured leg, you don't expect them
to run marathons. If someone has a,
you know,
something wrong with their liver,
you don't expect an a processed food
correctly. You don't blame it on them.
But if someone has a mental health issue
and they do something erratic, yeah.
Or they say something that's inappropriate
and then they apologize for it.
Or if they're a comedian or
if they're comedian and you,
you've had the jit imit Breal diagnosed,
treated mental health issues,
trauma related issues.
There you go. How'd do you like
that? It's a little, I can do that.
Help you do better Kenya.
Yeah. But for whatever reason,
people want to pretend that this is a
deliberate act by a calculating person who
is just being an asshole. And that's
not the case. You're not an asshole.
Not at this time. I have been an asshole
when you weren't here, but you weren't,
that's not what you were
doing. No, I was talking about
about Iran and the woman's
revolution there and how, uh, how,
and it's always been
because you know what?
I had my DNA done cause I wanted to
know and I am of North African ancestry.
How much, um, it's like
a very small percentage,
but it was something like 25,000 years
ago, they left, um, north Africa,
which is kind of Syria.
And um,
they went to Lithuania and um,
Russia and uh,
some Europe,
July 23 and me or something
like that. Yeah. Yeah.
And it just answered so many
questions for, you know,
why I feel this yearning towards that
part of the world. But I do, you know,
and especially the geopolitics,
there are some,
it always intrigued me and I have
always attempted to use my voice to um,
you know,
support all,
all the people there.
Well it's a fascinating,
so it was, you know, this one
tweet was about, it was about,
I mean it's actually a genius tweet if
you really fucking know. What did you say?
What exactly did you say to
let's find the tweet, Jamie,
I'll tell you if it's, the artificially
rendered is an artificially rendered one.
Yeah, there's a lot of them. Were
people distorted what you actually yeah,
at first it was racist Roseanne and
then about a couple weeks later it was
disgraced comic Roseanne
and her racist tweet.
And then after that it was disgraced
comic and her offensive racist tweet.
Cause there's all these hoops
you gotta jump through, you know,
they're never done punishing.
You were saying before that all my
friends said don't apologize to social
justice warriors because
that's the kiss of death.
That's fucking chum in the water.
Blood in the water, you know,
is definitely a little bit of that.
But what I was saying before the podcast
to you is I don't, I don't really,
what I really think happens is they find
a target and they don't care if it's a
viable target,
but once the target gets greenlit,
they go after you until
some new target comes along.
Until someone distraction the
target and its recreational outrage,
they find me,
they attack you and they go after
you and try to distort your position,
the fuck you said. And obviously they
don't. That's what kind of cracks me up.
It's like,
look at this,
look what they're saying it meant and
you know I'm not going to bow down before
them and say you were right and they
want me to, but they weren't right.
I'm right. I wrote it bitch,
so I know what I meant.
So you don't get to tell me what I
meant, but they don't care. It's just,
the thing is they don't want to
look at it rationally and say,
well here's a woman that has a
history of mental health problems.
She was on Ambien and drinking.
And she says something that
is slightly irrational,
but given your explanation of it,
Doug both always think all
my tweets make no sense.
You've been saying that for a fucking
year since I went on Twitter. You're like,
her tweets are just buttons, straight
up crazy, crazy tweets for sure.
I don't think they're crazy.
You just don't get them.
Well maybe if I was in the same
mindset as you, I would get them. Yeah.
But obviously no one had,
when I say crazy,
I don't think like other people.
I know that I've always known that my
whole life I had always test other people
to see what they were thinking. Like
as even as a kid, I'd be like in bed,
I tried to fit in, they go, let's play
barbies. You know? And I'm like, fucking,
I don't want to, I'm like, okay, well,
but let's have Barbie be a resistance
fighter that paratroops into, um,
you know, into the hidden lines of the
German thing and save all the Jews.
And they'd go,
you have to be her cousins skipper.
And then they'd hand me the skipper doll.
I always had to personify skipper
and they got to be Barbie.
I didn't even know a bar. We
had a cousin. Yes, skipper.
She has a little tiny tits and I resented
that because I always had very large
pendulous breasts since
I was four or five.
I did. I don't, I don't think or look
like other people. I am an alien.
Really? What planet you
think you'd be from? Well,
somebody told mass from [inaudible].
Do you know anything about that?
That's the people that call the art bell
show. They would always say that. Yeah.
That's what they say. Round faces are
fun. Play. Do you see you got around face.
That's what I told you.
I don't even go by what people look like
except for I do look at the shape of
their head. I have to admit
that's how I classify people.
I classified people my own way cause I
don't think like everybody else thinks I
take a person shape of their head and
that's the group they represent to me.
And I have noticed that the
Dutch have the largest heads.
The Dutch have pure score.
Not all of them of course,
but some of them you're the
average height for a Dutch person,
like six feet tall. I know the
women folks. Yeah. Vikings,
Vikings,
yeah.
I love all the different peoples of the
earth because they all have a variety of
foods that I enjoy. So
I like to, you know,
I don't just mix with one kind of person.
In my real life I mixed with all
kinds of people and you know,
cause I'll go anywhere for a
free meal. But I, but I love,
I love cultures and I love all people.
That's all I want to say. You know,
I would never,
I'm not that person.
You're not a racist by any stretch of
the imagination, but you are a person.
My sense that I'm a Misanthrope,
I'm a misanthrope misanthrope but I
am a respect truss of no man or woman.
But most comedians, yeah,
we're all like that, right?
Thropic intentions or you have
to hate all people the same,
but you definitely have
to mock and make them.
It's a part of the job description.
Yeah,
you're done the mock
and make fun of and you,
you look for things that are irritating
about everything. No Shit right there.
That's sort of the job.
None of that.
That was part of your
character on your show. Yeah.
It was part of the reason
why ABC wanted you bag.
It's part of the reason why the show
became such a giant hit and its return.
I mean it was a fucking huge hit
coming right out of the gate. Yep.
28 million people. That's a lot of fucking
panties is number one. Every episode.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people and a lot of that
was because people love this aspect of
you,
but as soon as you get labeled a racist,
everybody throws their hands up and
goes, Whoa, I didn't know she was racist.
She's racist. And they don't care about
nuance. They don't care about the details.
They don't care about ambien.
They don't care about alcohol.
When I called you on the phone
was the first thing that I,
one thing I've learned Gel. Well, if
you're going to take an ambien down,
not do not drink a beer.
Always only drink a wine with ambien.
I have a good friend of mine
who is one of the nicest,
most respectful guys
you ever want to meet.
He woke up in Germany on a plane,
covered in his own vomit with the police,
standing over him,
asking him if he knew what happened.
He wound up getting arrested.
They brought him to the jail
in Germany and they add in the,
he's a CEO of a large company and they
went over things with him and they said,
what happened?
What
do you remember? He goes, well,
I remember taking an Ambien and then
that I went to sleep and then I had,
I guess I had a beer at some point
in time and they go, okay, stop.
This is what happened.
And so they described how he was hitting
on the stewardesses and trying to start
fights with men.
That cabin and
wasn't as being as real selfie was on
Ambien. Yeah, I know. It starts thing.
He's the nicest guy.
If you knew this guy,
you would never in a million years
believe that he was capable of anything
remotely like this. And the German people
actually let him stay in the country.
They let them continue his
vacation. They're like, okay.
For gave him promise not to do that again.
He goes,
I'm never fucking taking that
shit again in my life. Yeah.
And one of the things that I said
to you when I called you up, I said,
what were you doing well and you told
me you are on Ambien. And I said, okay,
we'll stop right there because I know
quite a bit about that because I've had
personal experiences with friends
that have had real issues with ambien.
I had a bid I did in my act about a
friend of mine who literally made a meal
while he was on Mbn. Yeah. Cooked at
the supermarket. What? God food. Yeah.
Cool.
Look at tiger woods that he was on that
and then you'd go driving off in the
golf cart and to meet some check,
you know?
And that I don't understand where
people said they have sex on Ambien.
People say that's a big thing that
people take ambien to have sex.
I don't even know how they can stay on.
I guess they don't stay awake,
but another part of them wakes
up and their sex part comes out.
That's all I can figure. I've never
taken it. I'm terrified of this.
Don't ever take it. Yeah, I get, nope.
I have no problem going to sleep.
I've never had a plan to do,
but you know what I found is THC,
they sell it down at the dispensary
and there's one for sleep at night.
And um, I've been doing that and I, I've
been sleeping through the night, uh,
when I was taking the sleeping
thing to sleep and drug ambien,
while I don't want to say it because
we don't want to get sweet candy, man.
You don't want to say it three times. You
don't get sued. Not me. I say an Ambien.
I bet you they give a
fuck. They said, yeah. Did,
do you see that? Yeah. Well, you know,
I had Hamilton Morris on the
podcast who was a drug expert. Yeah.
And he w he writes for vice and it does
a pieces for vice and he went and did a
piece for vice
incident. He came on and went
in great detail about how that,
that is something that
happens to people that, well,
they have no idea what the fuck they're
saying. It's called the hypnotic.
That is the classification
of drugs that it falls under.
And people do all sorts of involuntary
things when they're on there. No,
it doesn't just make
you say racist things,
but you didn't say anything intentionally
racist. No. It's the way people decide.
Well,
about the work of Valerie Jarrett's hands.
And I also was referencing
my very favorite movie.
So if we could talk about how fucking
awesome that movie planet of the Apes,
great fucking movie. Also.
It's the definitive people, uh,
get your, come on people now
smile on your bird. It's like,
come on. It's like the hundredth monkey.
Is that the thing? Is that the name of it?
That's what it is. The hundredth monkey
on the typewriter. They write a curls.
Mckees what is it? How that work, that
if you have a certain amount of months,
that hundredth monkey,
that changes everything.
If p f a f a species does
something 99 times in a row,
the hundredth time it's
gone into their DNA. Yeah.
And then they evolve to the next level.
Hundredth monkey effect.
I'm just effect is a
hypothetical phenomenon in
which new behavior ideas claimed
to spread rapidly by unexplained means
from one group to all related groups.
Once a critical number of members of
one group exhibit a new behavior or
acknowledged the new idea.
Yeah.
Well the thing is a lot of people put
pictures of that woman right next to the
lady. I understand the picture was
put up after my tweet. I understand,
but I am nothing to do with that picture.
I didn't say she looked like
anything I wrote. Seriously.
I'm not that fucking shallow.
Okay.
I never talked about nobody's lugs unless
they're like thin and blonde and I'm
jealous but you know and
youthful now but or whatever.
But wasn't there another tweet that you
made a long time ago about who was that
other woman? Susan Rice. Yes. Yeah.
Well you said she has giant swinging
eight balls that she's a man.
Let me explain that now.
Cause this is the regional
listic regionalism.
I'm from Utah and all the girls in Utah,
when we got married and are, we heard
our moms do it too. It's always,
where's your ape? They go, what's
your age doing this Sunday?
And he's like, oh, he's watching football.
All good. Let's go out to lunch. You know,
it's all,
all of the men were all apes.
That's how it is in a breeder culture.
Like Salt Lake City, breeder culture.
Yeah. Culture. So it's
like, where's your ape?
And there's like, man, you're a peasant.
Big fucking swing and eight balls.
I give him that.
You know,
it's a regional lipstick thing and uh,
you know,
so I used it and apologize,
but yeah.