I'm a lesbian man.
I'm just looking for gas to peg me.
I bet there's a lot of them that would
want to fuck you just for revenge.
How much of that is a women that,
why is it that the pretty women don't
seem to have any problem with men?
Like a lot of them are like
pretty easy going about men,
but if you have bad genetics,
like if you got dealt
a wrong in the stick,
that's that is if there's like people
talk about income inequality in this
country and that's definitely a real
thing. But if there's a real thing,
it's like who do people want to
fuck inequality in this country?
And that's off the Goddamn charts,
right?
I mean there's just, as men
and as women, we just have to,
we have to understand that some people,
they have a unearned
tyranny on sexual affection.
It's unearned. They didn't have to
do anything like these Russian women.
The people aligned to you about, right?
Yeah. You, you meet them and you go,
Jesus is just Russian gladiator
genetics and perfect like model form.
And you're like, Holy Shit, let me
get the fuck out of this room quick.
I was on a cruise one time,
I was married and um,
and I had rented the, like the back
quarter I've ever gone to the same spot.
Oprah stays in and it cost a fortune.
And I were out on the deck and,
and there's two big suites in the middle
and another one just like mine at the
end, but the one that was in this one,
which was also a real expensive room,
was this Russian dude. And he
was short, got a chunky and bald,
but the girl who was with him was
just a 12 and I knew his second,
I saw her,
I was fucked because there's no way
my wife was not going to catch me,
just at least take it away. One little
glimpse at the corner of my eye.
And then she would go, oh
yeah, that's what you want.
You'd rather fuck her
than me. And I'm like, no,
absolutely not. Absolutely
not. Why would I, why would I,
that's outrageous.
What did that Regis assertion?
What an accusation.
Yeah.
If they only knew how vulnerable
we are to a woman like that,
it's like that woman can,
there's a lot of people that that woman
can like run their life and they'll meet
a guy who's an accountant who's never
fucked a 12 and they'll start talking to
him and basically,
and you can do anything they want to do
as long as they're willing to actually
touch him. As long as they're willing
to stick their fucking beautiful times.
Guy's mouth,
he's helpless to suck on his list and
the grind that pussy against Dick,
he's God has asked.
She later put your finger on the base
of his taints and rub it while you stick
your tongue down his throat,
his dick, as hard as a rock.
These things,
they've never happened to this man.
There goes the neighborhood time
down to jack the car up to the house,
throw the in the fucking dream yard.
Tell the kids, yeah, that's an ice tea.
So I really hoped it would
turn out this way. A hood,
ice tea and body count.
Fuck yeah.
There's certain women that they
could just run you. Oh, oh, oh.
I know. I know. I know.
I know. I know. I get it.
Yeah, man, I get it. I married one of
them. Got To be careful. Just get you,
uh, if you, if you're not, if
you're not, here's the thing.
Yup. How much of that,
like for dudes who you,
there's certain cases where you know,
it's not gonna work. Like God dammit,
this dude, he's like, uh, uh,
a small sheep and he married a wolf or
it's just a matter of time before she
fleeces them and gets the fuck out of
dodge and hopefully he'll still be alive,
but this is not going to work out well.
We've all seen that before.
Oh, I wish I could tell you this
story. I wish you could too.
Let's shut this fucking podcast
off and resume 10 minutes.
Okay. All right. Let me,
let me tell you this story because
I just don't want to say, man,
it's intertwined with something.
Right, right, right. But it's very,
very pertinent Joanna.
Do with that on the legal ramifications.
Can anybody go to jail? No.
Can Anybody get sued? No.
No. I don't think so.
And it's the truth. Okay.
So I've just created a fictional scenario.
Let's call the gentlemen,
what do you want to call
them? Let's let, let,
let's call him Todd Blaker tie.
Bleeker okay, now I can't even do it
this way because I'll get chastised.
I'll get die. I think people would
find out slow down there. Right.
I and also I've drunk and I know you
getting drunk on your show and Oh,
it's my fault.
You give me a fucking people on reddit.
They had their fingers above the keys.
They were hovering right.
Ready to start searching, right? No, there
is no such thing as a guy named Matt.
And I will not tell you the
story on the same. But anyway,
what was amazing was I saw it
happening in front of me. Yeah.
You know,
his,
his wife was there and they'd been
married for a long time and he didn't look
like much. And, and uh, and at all.
And uh,
and,
and there was a kind
of an assistant and uh,
that was ridiculously gorgeous.
And so I just looked at
that and I was like, uh,
you know where this is going.
[inaudible] exactly.
I've seen where I thought
it was going in and uh,
and there was nothing he can do
it. I mean, it was absolutely,
he was completely right.
Just perfect. You know, there was nothing
he could do. He wouldn't give everything.
Oh yeah. Like Gary Oldman and Dracula.
Remember that time we would have,
like we'd known the Reiner
was just hypnotized by him.
Ah, she's going to put a shirt
in the middle of the night
and Gary Old Oldman be slithering
into the fucking windows as missed
body heat with the, it's like, oh yeah.
With Kathleen Turner towards the
fucking chair through the window,
drove throw it right in the fucking bat.
He didn't even want to abuse
the door to fuck her. And uh,
that was great.
Katherine Turner Back in the Disney
Ah, Woo. People hot as it gets,
as high as she was so sexy.
I mean,
she developed some health problems as
she got older, but when she was young,
Holy Shit. Yeah, it was
amazing. It was champagne.
Yeah,
it was a lot of error.
Feel like rubbing,
went off thinking about me owe
you a few said go ahead and do it.
Nice. Nice reciprocation. Yeah.
It's hard when you watch the guy get
preyed upon when you're watching like a
man's struggle with the fucking spiders
web and you're like, well, hey man,
you know, it'll be fun when she does
fuck you. Right? Yeah. Yeah. Right.
So as long as he could stay
active and get close to her,
don't let it get too much money.
It was careful.
Yeah. It, uh, I know
because, uh, you know the,
the, the, I had been around
for a long time and it was
a contract, so, right. Yeah.
So there goes that part of it,
but I think the paperwork was fairly solid
in towards the end of like a limit or
whatever. Okay. Now
everybody's going to go,
this is get moving.
Alright.
I knew a guy who was about to marry Gowan
shooting him and he was trying to, uh,
do,
uh,
no prenuptial and my friends
were screaming at him like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
And he's like, look man, I don't if it,
if it doesn't work out, I'd like
her to have half and then went. But
it's almost like,
you know,
like you wish you had garlic to put
around you right now you're telling Noah
about the flood.
So really two animals and they
both very much and they are ugly.
She's not okay. Understand
this. The world is not fair.
The reality of not fair as you made enough
money to attract her, but she's got a,
she's got a web,
you might get hooked you Mike and inject
it or you might be able to figure out a
way to keep her nervous.
Right? How you do that, Joe?
Mysterious, Bro. I'm serious.
And I have like a book.
Is that how you did a special books
that you read? You gotta be Moody,
got to go on early morning runs.
Well, they're still asleep.
You gotta get show powers that they do
of these things. You got to show powers.
They don't have a ton. What are these
things? You have to be different.
You have to be able to quote Shakespeare.
Yeah. You gotta be, um, yeah.
You've gotta be willing to give up a lot
of money if you're not going to be dude,
and you got a hot wife,
you got a certain amount of time before
she gets bored with you fucker trainer,
right?
Her trainer here at what I think is
going to happen is within the next thing.
That exact same thing.
Oh, I've seen that happen.