Yeah. What's the benefit of
grass fed beef over regular beef?
I know there is a benefit but I don't,
I don't, I never can recall correctly.
It's something to do with the small
central fatty acid ratios. Yeah,
cause grain you're gonna,
you're gonna have more of the omega six
fatty acids which have been unfairly
vilified meaning that a lot of people
are just like don't eat any Omega sixes.
Don't have any arachidonic acid. Like
don't, don't overdo your seeds or nuts.
Your nut butter. Kind of like the the
orthorexic health world as a whole.
You know like when you read
nutrition magazines and stuff,
they're like do your Omega
threes but be careful.
Americans have a 20 to one
omega six to Omega three ratio,
but the problem is that Omega six is,
that's a lot of those are derived from
what are called parent essential oils.
And your cell membranes need a certain
amount of omega six fatty acids from
seeds and nuts and plants and
even to a certain extent grains.
And when you have an excess of
Omega threes and not enough,
we'll mega six is because you're going
so far into the fish oil category than it
actually damages is a component of your,
your mitochondrial membrane
called Cardio Liben.
You actually make less of that
interfere with normal cellular activity.
What seeds are most beneficial? Uh, uh,
I would imagine the most
nutrient dense ones,
so specific Wiseman's Macadamia.
I mean what I is like almonds,
macadamia nuts,
Brazil nuts.
I just don't eat the quasi nuts
like peanuts, which are, you know,
they're not as high in nutrient density.
They're more of a legume than a nut. Um,
I, a lot of my nuts either
raw or lightly roasted,
you always look at the label to make sure
they didn't put a lot of vegetable oil.
And Canola oil in them a little,
you know,
I'm a fan of nuts in in moderate my nuts.
Like you're nuts if you are going
to have to shell them. Right?
Like if you've ever had to shell a walnut,
you're not going to eat 30 walnuts
cause that'd be exhausting, right?
[inaudible] like yeah.
[inaudible] shell.
It's annoying as hell but keeps
you from eating too many of them.
I buy them shelled and I
eat fistfuls of them. Yeah.
Like last night I like a half a bag of
pistachios are great for your microbiome
to,
yeah.
I actually had a couple of research
studies on that last year that showed an
improvement in the diversity of the
bacteria in your gut with pistachios.
That's one of the nuts as good for your
by probably because of the fiber content
in pistachios,
but grass fed versus grain
fed is primarily the omega
three fatty acids may have
less of the arachidonic acid,
less of the potentially
inflammatory omega six fatty acids.
There's probably part of it being
that grass fed grass finished beef is
generally raised on a farm that's
using less herbicides, less pesticides,
raising their meat and more
sustainable fashion. You know,
giving it less hormones,
giving less antibiotics.
That's painting with a broad brush.
But generally grass fed,
there's more to it than just
the fatty acid composition.
It's just a better meat overall.
In my,
well better health wise grain fed beef,
I will not lie like you can,
you can have a pretty damn tasty fatty
cut of grain fed beef. Certainly can.
But I honestly prefer the taste of
grass fed. I liked the denser meet,
the darker meat, I liked it
better. It's just, to me it just,
it just tastes healthier. I just,
my, I crave it more, you know?
And when I go back and forth between
the two of them, when I eat grain fed,
it feels like, like a lazy cow. Like
it's mushy and it's got like, it's good,
it's delicious. Don't get me
wrong, but there's a difference.
It's kind of funny cause I,
I've gone over to Dubai a few times and
tall like fitness conferences over there
and they advertise grain fed
like they want everybody to,
like when you go to
the restaurant is like,
this beef is the finest grain fed beef,
fat Peter Luger's,
which a lot of grain pretty
widely recognized as the
greatest steakhouse in the
world that places all graces that trip.
I actually,
I didn't like my steak is how fucking
dare you. I know you're going to get,
I'm going to get killed.
Some rude Brooklyn waiter's
going to take me out. But uh,
I didn't like it. What would you
like it just something about like,
the meat just tasted, it tasted like
it was drenched in vegetable oil.
Like something about it just didn't
taste right and maybe I had a poor Peter
Luger's experience that doesn't even
make sense. I did not enjoy it that much.
Food. I ate there and afterwards I'm
like, I don't think it gets better,
I don't think.
Yeah.