The joe rogan experience. Oh, how
about this one? A guy got fucking, uh,
sentenced or he got convicted
and will be sent in soon.
I think he gets sentenced in April for,
uh,
getting his dog to make a Hitler salute.
Make you a video. Yes, it's on my, uh,
on my Twitter page. I retweeted it.
The guy is in Scotland and
he's a proud shit poster.
He's one of those guys, Jamie loves ship
posters. It's one of his favorite things,
you know. Um, but he's one
of those guys that just,
he posts stupid shit to
get a reaction from people.
And so just to piss his girlfriend off,
he decided he tried to get his dog to
do the Hitler salute, the Nazi salute.
And uh, you know, he gets his dog to
do it on this video and he says gas.
The Jews apparently,
you know,
like he's trying to like get his
dog to, to do this. Like when he,
I guess he thought it was funny,
right? And then he puts it on youtube.
Not only does it get him in trouble,
which I get people being mad like, hey,
that's insensitive. Okay, whatever.
It's what he's trying to be insensitive.
They fucking arrested him. They tried him
and they convicted him. Which country?
Scotland.
The UK.
I mean this guy's convicted and
now he'll be sentenced. Wow.
It's fucking crazy. If you've
seen the video [inaudible] Jamie,
pull up that video because it's
crazy to watch. It's not that big.
A deal has been pushed off up until
April time. Yet next month. Yeah,
that's what I said.
What is the pull up the video.
Yeah. He's um, that's one
thing about United States, man.
You forget about free speech.
Like I was talking to somebody from a
different country recently. He goes,
you have no idea how big that is. And
we kind of take it for granted. Giant.
Giant. Yeah. It's giant
and it's, it's everything.
Okay.
It has been identified
by Youtube community is
inappropriate and offensive to
some audiences. I understand. Please
proceed. Give you some volume.
Uh,
uh, and so I thought I would call them
and he the least cute thing that I could
think of.
You can't even understand a word he says,
why don't they just speak English? Oh
God. That's the juice gas. The Jews,
the Jews were more gassy juice.
The juice,
guess juice. [inaudible]
juice. More gas. The juice.
The juice. So He's, it's tick.
It took them forever to teach this dog.
This is this the idea.
That's where we're watching
this over and over again.
Oh God.
See?
Oh Wow. Boy. It's
adorable. It is very cute.
He taught the dog to do that.
It's crazy.
That's, it sucks that he's getting, well,
it's a classic shit post video.
Yeah. It's like these guys,
this is the whole pepe, the frog thing.
You can take it down. This is the whole,
it's all the same shit.
It's a bunch of people that are
having fun sang shit that's totally
inappropriate. This is what it is.
That's what that is. It's the same thing.
And the people that think that,
like anybody who would do that is a Nazi.
You're not correct.
That's not true.
I guarantee you that guys not
a Nazi I think. I don't know.
I'm assuming he's not a Nazi.
I'm assuming he's a shit poster.
He's a guy who's trying to
be funny. Hundred percent.
That's just ignorance. Yeah,
and that funniness is funny to them. See,
here's the thing. You might not like it.
You might think it's, it's horribly
and offensive, but here's the thing.
No Jews got ma got gassed
during the making of that
video and the worst thing it
did is get racist to laugh.
The best thing it did is get people
to talk about what's appropriate.
There's nothing wrong with that. I mean
it's not good. I mean I don't like it.
I wouldn't do it. I wouldn't tell people,
hey, this is the most awesome video ever.
Come watch it.
But to put that guy,
not only to put them on trial but the
fucking convict, him and Scotland,
how dare you, you people are
supposed to be ahead of the curve.
Skyland supposed to be a pretty fucking
bad ass place. That's ridiculous.
Isn't Scotland though? Like the, like the,
like a place that you have to think at
Scotland where you can't even talk about
sex on stage. You can cuss, you
can like show you pull a tit out.
But like if you're done, it's to talk
about sex. I think it's Scotland.
There's a noble Billy Connolly's
from Scotland and Billy Connolly's,
a pretty famous worldwide comedian. I
think a suite. It pretty outrageous guy.
I might be thinking of Sweden. Yeah
Cause Cause Connolly's pretty, he's,
he's like in the line of like popular
American standup comics of his era.
He was a very respected guy and
he's from Scotland. Must be sweet.
I think I'm thinking of
Sweden. Maybe. I don't know.
I don't know Jack Shit about those
other countries that I only visit
occasionally. Right.
But, but when you go to,
when you go to these countries to do
comedy, do you ever have to be like, Hey,
don't talk about,
no,
I wouldn't go if I went to a place they
told me I couldn't talk about something.
I'd be like, well why would I go there?
All right, well, I'll just go somewhere,
work and talk about anything.
I don't want to go somewhere where only
talk about certain things. It's like I,
I've done a few,
uh,
air quote clean shows in
my day where I got a Gig,
especially when I was first
starting out. They're like, Hey,
can you do a half an hour clean? And I
go, okay. Yeah. And I would just edit.
I'll just edit the shit out of
something. Use words that, you know,
there's like Innuendo that you could get
away with and I could sort of squeaked
by with a bullshit half hour
set, you know? But I would
never do that today. Right.
I got on one too. Yeah. I don't
want to, it's just like I,
what I want to be able to do is find
out what's the best way to express the
thoughts that are in
my mind that are funny.
That the best way is never
by censoring yourself.
The best way is by figuring out what's
the best way to express yourself.
Okay.