We're absolutely not meant to live,
piled on top of each other within,
you know,
10 million of us in a square mile and
the island of Manhattan, you know? Yes,
absolutely. Do you remember when there
was the floods in Manhattan? Yes.
All the money in the world
couldn't get you out. Right.
You have to walk across the Brooklyn
Bridge to leave Manhattan with everybody
else,
you know?
Yeah.
And there was a word real worry because
of climate change that was going to be
happening every year. Now people
are like, is this the new normal?
I remember Shane Smith at some piece
on the walkout. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Shane had to walk out and,
but he had some piece on vice where
they're detailing the inside of his, uh,
apartment building. Like the fucking
thing was completely flooded,
like six feet high and water,
you know, and people were,
weren't worried like this is going to be
what's happening on a regular basis now.
Like this climate change
thing has changed.
I've a heightened sense of, oh,
you know, since have three kids. I,
it's something that I think about. It's
something that I have ready. You know,
I bought a generator. I have,
yeah, I checked the batteries,
the rechargeable batteries for
all of the equipment that I have.
I own solar panels,
I own other Duffel bag full of everything
that I need to throw in the back of my
pickup truck,
grabbed my kids and I know which way to
drive away from the city to go to the
cabin.
It's something I've plaid just because
I'm the ward of these small humans whom I
love.
You know,
it's funny you talked about like
restriction again and the thing just,
I'm thinking of preparing,
you know,
and the most common thing that people
prepare his food in and they prepare cans
and cans and cans of food,
but still they eat so much of that
food that the best way to prepare,
the best way to prepare would
be to start to eat less and,
and learn how to live at 1700 calories.
You know,
and learn how to live with
the people around you.
Because if you're going to spend like
two months in the bunker or an a bug out
location or whatever,
you're nuts,
some like asshole to your kids and your
friends and family and people with you.
One of the things that happens to people,
this is really fascinating when,
when disasters do strike, cause everyone
gets a lot friendlier. You know,
and this is one thing that I've
experienced myself this week because, uh,
when we got evacuated,
it was two 30 in the morning on Thursday
and there was fire a rock's throw from
my house and I'm not talking
a little bit of fire,
I'm talking to this hundreds of acres of
fire. I mean it was just roaring over.
We started see houses,
started seeing the gas lines explode,
houses burst into flames and
it was right down the street.
So we're seeing this and uh, you know,
we're, we're, we're, we got outside,
we're in the driveway, the neighbors
come over, everyone's talking,
what are you going to do? I
go, we're getting the fuck
outta here. And he's like,
have they given the evacuation orders?
I said, no we haven't, but I go,
it's right there man. I go,
we got to go. I go, if it,
if we're wrong and we come back in,
the house is still here. That's okay,
but you want to get out of these things
quickly because they can turn south
quickly,
but there was a sense of camaraderie
and community that that happens and then
quite a few of us all
went to the same hotel,
including my friend Tom Segura and his
wife and his family went to this hotel
too with some of my friends
from this neighborhood.
We're all there huddled in
together and but there was,
there was an people were little extra
friendly. There was a, and this is like a,
there was the same kind of feeling after
nine 11 when I was in New York City.
There was,
people are a little more friendly.
We felt that during the ice storm back
in the day, people were, like I say,
I saying the street that we
live on, and then they go, well,
who's got a wood burning stove? And
they go, oh, Roger does come over.
Then people would go to Roger's house
and all of a sudden all these neighbors
that just wave at each other,
we're all at Roger's house
by the wood burning stove,
going back to the houses to get blankets,
planning, sleeping arrangements,
planning food arrangements,
and assessing each other,
giving each other their personal space
and learning to how to speak to each
other in a respective manner that we
might have to do this for several days.
Yeah. Through the bed, through tragedy,
a sense of community was built somewhat
or reinforced for a brief moment in
time, which made going back to our
regular lives on that street better.
Yeah. You know? Yeah, yeah.
If you ever read, uh, Sebastian younger's
tribe, nope. Nope. It's a great book.
And he kind of talks about that,
about how in part situations of extreme
stress and when people are really
pushed,
um,
those people bond together and they find
that these are the happiest times of
their life.
People that even go to war,
they find that they missed the comradery
of the bunker. They miss the miss,
the camaraderie of being in the trenches.
They missed the camaraderie
of being together, huddled up,
not knowing what's going
to happen in the future,
but co counting and depending upon
each other for their very lives.
So that's a thing that happens
in very, very, very busy
kitchens. Yeah. Uh, you know,
a bunch of no education guys
out of cooking school, working,
uh,
difficult restaurant line. You
know, we're working six guys,
six,
four burners every night.
A difficult menu with a difficult chef
and a very busy restaurant tho those,
those hours,
you know,
from 6:00 PM till 10:00 PM at night,
like it's intimate.
It's intimate. Like,
you know, like my nose,
you're bending over to get into
the stove. They get a chicken. No,
I'm grabbing something out of the fridge.
My nose is in your,
but your nose is in my, but
uh, you know, I, I need your
knife. You need my knife. Uh,
it's very, very, very close.
Quarter is often like some of
my strongest relationships.
Some of his strongest relationships
are, you know, the bond that I've built
with guys that I've cooked on in lines,
whether in Europe or here are unbreakable.
You know, these guys got your back.
Tony talked a lot about
that, you know? Yeah.
I think people are better off when they're
struggling. Yeah, I really do. I mean,
I think they're better off when
they're there. They're, you know,
when life creates challenges and there's,
there's things to overcome and there's
difficulties to get through and there's
real pressure involved in these,
and there's physical activity
involved in these pressures as well.
It's growing on the Galley,
the century,
and the cat of nine
tails looming over you.