The majority of fire, the majority
of fighters they have fought me.
They've always been me like
almost all my career, you know?
So I always say I'd rather be the park
then looked apart because I've been in
many situations where I've seen guys
looking apart, but then when it's,
when they get to the nitty
gritty, they are not depart. Well,
you look the part too,
don't get it twisted right.
Giant Tommy Hearns. Yeah. You know when
Tommy was in his prime, it's just uh,
it's what,
what makes sense though is that you
keep that power and the 12th round,
where's those bigger,
heavier guys?
Maybe because the blood's got to push
through all that extra muscle and all that
extra body tissue.
Maybe they can't keep that power that way.
You can because in the 12th round,
first of all,
I don't know how the fuck he got up.
I do not understand.
I remember watching it on TV. I'm like,
wow, he knocked him out in the 12th round.
That is crazy. Right? It's crazy.
And then of course you played
that thing on your Instagram,
which basically shows that
you did knock him out.
Oh, definitely knocked him out. He
definitely didn't get up in time. Right.
He definitely didn't,
you know,
but it was his job to just get up at 10
it's not his job to know exactly when 10
seconds is correct. Correct.
No, jet Reese, Stephanie
had delays on the account,
on the scene, the fight like six times.
And then definitely when he got to eight,
you know,
eight was a very long delay.
Eight then you said no,
you know,
um, yeah, like I said, 99 out of 10 judges
would have waved at all, you know, easily.
Especially when you've seen the guy,
our role in the back of his head and he
and him hitting the canvas and his, his,
his, his whole head meat penetrated
like it started getting tight.
The muscles in the head is
getting tight in the back and
you know, but it's,
it's so much with that.
I know how he got, I didn't understand
how he got up either. God is a good God.
Well, he believed that that's
what he believed. He believed it.
Yeah. I mean, look, he got
up man, and he got up and he
boxed. Well, he recovered you.
You mean you came after him and you hit
them with some more big shots and he
kept moving, but then he started
getting his legs back under them.
You started Landen.
There's also other things as well too.
You know he's still a gypsy
though. Yeah. You know,
you know they believe in a lot of things.
You know that, right. So you never know.
You know, phenomenal
fight though. It was epic.
It was absolutely amazing to watch.
Most definitely watched it by myself,
but my family was gone. They went out
for the day. I was like, this is great.
Just meet. Did you watch it on
mute now? See what I'm saying?
The commentators, man, they
was horrible. It was horrible.
I felt that was very biased.
It was a lot of things.
They was pulling out what we're doing,
but a lot,
a lot of things what I was doing,
it just,
even when I knocked down in the knife
round, they had all this to say,
but when I'm not done the ninth round,
it was so quiet and it wasn't
even a devastating knockout.
I was getting hit behind the head,
but they wanted to call out
me hitting him behind the ear.
But how many times I got hit
behind the head never was revealed.
It was like even just this, just a
whole, you know, bill up to it. You know,
he sold his story, he sold his
store over to America and you know,
any combat sport it did with
emotional emotions, you know,
people got emotionally tied to it.
People,
a lot of people could relate to his story,
you know,
certain things I could relate to. And
then, you know, when, when you, you,
when you capture, you know, the
world and you capture people that,
that um, they get emotional involved.
They want you to win. Right. You know,
just because of the stuff I have worn
them and wearing and stuff like that.
And um, um, the commentators, you know,
especially Paulie's specialty, uh, and uh,
it got very emotional with it, a lot of
other other, other casts as well too.
Just going back, listening to them,
I saw the fight six times, you know,
um, I definitely had, you can see
a very, a better look on the fight,
muting the TV,
you know,
well, I listened to the
commentary, but you know,
I do commentary myself or UFC.
So a lot of times,
even if I'm listening and I'm not
really listening to that much,
I'm just watching you
watching what's happening.
It's like I'm having a conversation in
a room with a bunch of people, right?
I was watching what was happening,
but it was interesting to me was a,
you made adjustments, you know, and one
thing that you made a big adjustment is,
um, when you landed in the 12th
round, you shorten everything up.
You shorten that right hand up.
It wasn't a winging punch at all.
It came straight down the pipe.
And then that left hand behind him in
the fucking timing cause he was already
going down. You already hit
him clean. He's going down.
Then that fucking left
hook man. Whoa. What was,
what was really crazy
that he got up from the,
snapped him around like the extra cyst.
It was when he went flying and
then flat line in and laid back.
I was like it's over.
I can't believe he knocked him out in
the 12 fucking round cause all fight.
I was saying all this
guy needs is one punch.
Like you got that scary
creepy power and then boom.
Well you could say that all day long
but if it never lands it doesn't mean
anything. Right, right. And it landed and
the way it lands, it was like Holy Shit.
I told her, I said you're going to
have to be perfect for all 12 wells.
I only have to be perfect
for a couple of seconds.
That's one thing that I did
hear the commentators say.
They said that he's proven that he doesn't
have to be perfect cause he got hit,
but it was like he, but he didn't
get hit clean. You got hit one time,
like pretty solid behind the year,
but the big one was in the 12th.
I'm so impressed with both things with
you being able to land like that with him,
but able to get up.
That was probably one of
the best heavyweight fights
by fucking ever seen it was
show me that night. You don't.
Sure. The heavyweight division has,
has been there for for a long time.
And then we started with last year or
something to just started religious
progressing in and people
started talking about it. Um,
especially been dead in
America. I remember one time
when no one knew who was,
who was the heavyweight champion
of the World War, you know,
it was a European guys
and stuff like that.
So I always made it my business like I
want to bring it back, I want to do it.
Like I led it. And a lot of the other
former champions did it where people knew,
well,
understand the sport of boxing then who
was the champion and stuff like that.
I always felt I had that, that duty to
fulfill even when I was in the Olympics,
because a lot of people don't even know
I was in the Olympics, you know? Um,
I was the only American tomato
in 2008 Olympics as well.
And just from that point, it felt like
I had to be the one to bring it back.