Right? And then what we have is just
like, uh, I kind of like, uh, um, uh,
I guess you could say what a capitalist
commune or I don't know what you'd call
it.
It's like a group of people communing
together is seeking to like extract money
from the universe, but also like,
you know what comes to mind? Sorry.
Anyone from blizzard is listening. You're
like, it doesn't like your job there.
But I got to, I went to on this
tour of blizzard and they fucking,
every company that makes video games,
they make the best video games outside
of like the only gay by notch up with it.
Right now I'm in the God of war.
It's so fucking good,
but it looks pretty bad ass.
It is amazing. It is amazing,
dude. It's the first triple a game I've
liked and so long. What's a AAA games?
It's called AAA. Aaa. It's a really
expensive game to make. It's like,
it's like a hardcore big time. Pull
up a video. So he got a war. God,
it's so graphics are pretty fucking
incredible, dude. Dude. It's beautiful.
Don't get me gift. Fuck that alien
damn bullshit. God. A war is like,
it's so good man.
And like I'm stuck in here.
Right, so you put on the HTC vive
today, the new one that we have. Yeah.
You didn't get into a game yet.
There's,
there's some games in it where you're just
like, Whoa, I see where this is going.
And I saw that from yours, but yours
was when I was over at your place.
What was that? Two or three years
ago? Probably two years ago.
Look how good the Freightos.
Oh good. That is you.
You see like the dirt on his hands.
It's like you're watching an episode
of Vikings. It's really good. And it's,
and it's like bitch ass fucking thing
freezing up again. Here it goes.
So this is actual gameplay. Yeah. See why
is this dude, that's fucking Gameplay,
dude. That's gameplay. That's game plan.
That's amazing. Yeah, it's incredible.
It's amazing. She's so
hot. It's very hot. I know.
You think you could hang out with a trick.
It was like cut people's
heads off of sorts.
Absolutely. Look at her.
Look at him, brother.
Her fucking bad dude.
What's great about this game is not just
the graphics which are incredible or
the fight mechanics,
which are also incredible,
but the fucking story is really good and
the acting is really good and like the
relationships between
characters are really intense.
This game will make you like tear up man.
Like it's like fucking shit.
You see what he just did chop that
dude and half with an ax. Holy Fuck Up.
He's just got smashed by Chad smashed. He
gets smashed a lot, but he's created us.
The God of war. He doesn't give
a fuck. Does not give a fuck man.
That's incredible. I wouldn't even
show much more of this. It's spoilers.
I don't want anybody to see any of the
characters and to know what's happening
because it's that good. Like it's
such a good game. Most Games,
the way I've played video games is I
try to rush through it for some reason,
which is really dumb to be like,
oh, I got to win this thing.
This one you want to hang out,
look around,
like see the landscape.
Like you get really into it.
It's a glorious game.
But you know that to get back to where
we're talking about it, blizzard,
uh,
one of the people working there told me,
we like building world of Warcraft
because we like playing world of Warcraft.
We've created a dimension we want
to be inside of like we enjoy it,
they love it. Like, and,
and that's why the game is so good because
it's being made by people who enjoy
playing the game. So I don't know
how many hours they work at blizzard.
I imagine it's, it can be a
pretty brutal schedule, but,
and in anything you do, even things
that you love, I know become grueling.
But I think that example of a company
versus a company where you're like either
doing something that you don't even need
to be there to do or oh, no comparison.
No comparison.
Medium might be massive hours a day,
but I bet you're having a great
time a lot of the time and the,
the actual results and saying,
you know,
I was friends with a lot of those guys
from id software back in the quick two
days. Yeah. And played quake three.
I got to play quake three before
it ever came out with you.
That's what's his name was cliff.
Nope, that's, that's cliffy be, he's,
it's soft. It's softwares doom
and quake. Cliffy B is unreal.
And uh,
no, I was with you and cliffy be gave it
to her. I didn't see the quake tourists.
They're both amazing. But we, yeah,
we got to see unreal tournament when
they were putting that together and they
were putting together this new engine
that will end up being used in a bunch of
different games afterward.
But it was fucking crazy.
We get to see the graphics like
as they're designing things.
And same thing with a, the quake studios,
but those guys all were crazy gamers.
They would get land parties and sync
all this. We played at the ID software.
We've got to play death matches
between everybody in the studio.
It was awesome to play quake with the
guys who made quake. Fucking cool.
The Fun of Shit ever. Fucking
cool man. And you know, I mean,
what they did was,
if you've never played one of those games
before, the three dimensional games,
when you're running down, you hear things
over here behind you and you like you,
you,
you know,
you could turn around and sneak around
corners and people are chasing around the
map and sometimes you could walk and it
doesn't make any noise or you can run
and you can hear the footsteps.
Fucking cool. Fuck. It's the crazy.
There's so adrenaline packed when you're
playing those games like these guys,
I'm so terrified we're putting a lan
in here in the next couple of weeks.
Now you are. Oh, we're going to you
and I, we're going to have some fun.
Well, no or not because you're
going to be me at fucking quake.
I suck at shooter's. Dude. Played in
forever please and played it for forever.
I'll probably be terrible
for dues the first 16 hours.
If I like had a shrink ray and shrunk.
You like India,
like a eight year old,
you would still beat me at shooters.
I suck at fucking shooters, man. I'm
not your thing. What do you like?
You like those, uh, role playing.
You don't want to say it dude,
cause you're going to make fun
of me. I won't do it. Come on.
I like Hearthstone man.
Was that what it is?
I can fell for it.
He didn't fall for it and being sincere.
I don't know what it is.
Online fantasy card game.
It's like a furry thing like furries.
I love comedians seminar cause it's
like I knew you're going to insult me.
I just didn't know how and
like it's way the way you did.
It was way worse than I expected.
Thank you. Pretend to be a Fox, right?
You're like Fox skin.
Are you other than you other kids,
is that what it is to
just get a kick out of it?
Do you ever do in your footie pajamas?
I'm like a little bunny rabbit tail and
I in the woods and I'm a rabbit.
Ah Fuck Man.
I've gotta be clever to get
away from the farm. Right.
Let me tell you something.
It's a wonderful fucking game with,
and it's deep and it's got
a lot of strategy and I, and
I, and I love playing it,
man. I really do. I'm
not good at it anymore.
I went through a period of being good.
I haven't played it in awhile
because I've been playing God a war,
but oh yeah,
this looks like death.
What is happening? What is happening
here? Let's see your cards. Yeah,
they're cards.
You basically like,
I'm not going to explain the rules of
Hearthstone on your show, dude, but
great games is killing me. It's
a great, it's a great, very fun,
very enjoyable game.
Good game for nine year old girls too.
It looks like I get it for my kids.
I'm just thinking like odd to do is
safe star craft or I could alive,
but I knew I didn't tell you the truth,
but I knew you were addicted to that.
You had a real problem with that.