Speaking of delicious. Are
you hunting at all? Yes. Yes.
Yes. What's your hunt? Well,
I mean I'm going through the two elk
that I've given away a lot of it too and
got shot last year. Every year
I scheduled to elk hunts and uh,
assume I'm going to strike out.
And uh,
the last two years I've been very
lucky and I got to elk each year.
So it's breaking the rules of the
secret in think and grow rich, you know,
to assume you're going to strike out.
I supposed to sit cross legged in your
son and manifest that shows. Yeah,
I work hard,
but I assume it's a hard thing to do to
fucking it is and people don't realize
they don't.
And he'll,
he'll look at a clip like there's clips
of me online and the clip is like a
minute long and it seems like,
oh look,
look how easy you don't
see stalking in for hours.
You don't see the hundreds
of hours of shooting arrows.
The coaching from John Dudley,
all the reading,
archery articles and understanding what,
keeping your mindset clear in the moment.
It's a lot of difficult to long haul.
My boys have their first hunt in
three months when we'll kind of,
we've been prepping for seven months.
They're doing bow hunt and Kona real pig.
Oh yeah. My, my wife, she's
going to have to sheep.
How old boy is it going to have to pay
the 10. So you're getting them a crossbow?
No, no, they're right now they're
shooting at Hoyt ignite. Um,
they're shooting at about 25 yards.
Justice shooting at about 40 yards
and how much they've been prepping.
They're about 45 now, which is
going to be enough. That's enough.
But I mean there's still contact
Brian. I mean there's still, when they,
when they draw their, you
know, pointing up and pull in,
so they've still got a couple
more months of training to,
to really get dialed in. Um,
but yeah, it's, it's difficult.
I still haven't even gotten my elk bow
hunting. You know, I spent my last time,
I spent six days up in the Colorado
mountain range in the, uh, the um,
what they called the Santa De
Cristo Range, you know, and,
and on the last day I finally came in
on elk and it was dark and I shot and I
missed.
And that was after seven fricking days
of trying and you walk out or how far was
a shot your horse out? Completely empty
handed. It's about 45 yards in dusk.
But you know, I mean, you
know how it goes. You're
shaking. It's so dark and yeah.
Um, anyways though, so I'm going
to do a, I'm going to do Kona.
Actually I'll get you in touch with
Dudley cause I know been touching him,
we've talked before,
I know how you shoot,
you shoot with a finger
trigger that shooter. Yeah,
I need to, it's, it's on my list. But
as those moments like that when you,
you're hunting for six days and you just
trekking through the woods 20 miles a
day and you're exhausted and
you finally get that one moment.
There's so much weight on that moment
that it's so difficult to stay focused
entirely on the task of
executing the shot perfectly.
And there's methods. There's a guy named
Joel Turner who has, um, I don't know,
he's got a website called
iron mine hunting. He's a, uh,
he's a, he's an instructor for um, uh,
first responders and snipers and things
along those lines and iron mind iron
mine where she lived,
I think he's a Pacific northwest guy
and he's helped me tremendously. His,
his methods. It's all about keeping a, uh,
the difference between an open loop
system in a closed loop system.
Be Able to control it and stop it and
stop the process anytime you want and
keeping yourself in that versus
like a baseball bat swing,
which is once you start swinging,
just swinging. And the idea is to,
to maintain the present NT,
to have a mantra and he gives you a
mantra to chant and to think about it in
terms of controlling all
of those movements. So you
are in control constantly.
Well you, you develop your own, but the
idea is to talk yourself through it.
Don't let your excitable mind take
over Oge it's coupled with the dope.
Did you freak out and you pull the trigger
and you shoot fucking over the things
back and you don't even know what
happened. What's your mantra? Lost? Um, I,
I pull back and I say draw.
I go through all the steps in
my head that I'm supposed to do.
I actually modified his
and went to John Dudley's.
So his,
he has his own one,
which is a drawback and aim. Get
it done, watch it to keep it.
And the whole idea is just
keeping those things in your head.
So you have one thing,
but what would Dudley,
I go through all the
different things that he says,
like a drawback.
Tip of the nose center,
the peep center, the bubble pulled
through the shot, pull, pull, pull,
let the shop break. And so I go through
all those things in my mind, but the,
the whole idea is did
not allow the freak out.
Cause the freakout is what
causes the target panic.
And when you have that itchy trigger
finger with the finger trigger,
you look good. And that's,
that's, I've done it. I mean,
I've seen it. I've done it.
I've seen it, I've heard it. Everybody
does it. The, the Arrow goes in the spot,
you know where you're yanking
it and you're pulling it.
He's not very precise and you want to
get it to where it's a surprise shot.
And when it's a surprise shot,
you're just concentrating entirely on
the area that you want to hit on the ALC.
Your form is perfect, everything's aligned
in order and if it's not, you let down.
If it's not, you let down and try
to get your shit together. Yeah,
she was trained to hunt competitions.
Helped me out quite a bit, I'm sure.
But those are like,
it's like a three day shoot,
but they put shooting around and
getting exhausted. No, no, not really.
Like they're, uh, they do
have part of it as like that,
like an obstacle course
race with your bowl.
But then part of it too is just
a three day shoot. But like, uh,
like a a 40 target three day shoot where
one shot might be I'm facing you but
the targets behind me and you've
got a ten second time spend a draw,
turn and shoot or you got to take a shot
seeded through the trees at 40 yards
and then within 20 seconds
do a shot at 60 yards.
So a lot of hunting scenario,
we would tell you that that is
going to cause target panic.
Did that whole thing of shoot now
that you should never just do that,
that you should always
execute the shot correctly.
Even he doesn't even like
this fucking game, this thing,
this a techno hunt that we,
we've done, he doesn't like that.
He thinks that that thing causes target
panic because you only have a brief
window and you're like go,
it's like you,
he believes that you should concentrate
entirely on the correct fundamentals and
execution of archery and then with time
and understanding of the situation,
the experience of hunting itself, then
when those moments present themselves,
you're going to execute correctly.
Whereas when you have this like ten
second you've got to turn and behind your
back ready go. He like Blah. You're
just, you're just going to hit that.
You're going to hammer that trigger.
You going to put that pin on the target
and hammer that trigger, and that's just,
you are emphasizing all the wrong things
that you could do when you're hunting.
Yeah.