Hello Freak bitches. You
pulled me in buddy. Uh,
I was uh,
I was in Los Angeles and I got a call
from my manager and it was essentially
saying, all right, there's this
thing that we got an offer for.
I'm sure you're not going to want to do
this, but next friend Jeff says, scam.
What a pitch. Mine as well. And now
here we are many, many years later. Um,
that was UFC 12 in 1997.
Uh,
and uh, Bob Myerwitz was the
president and owner of needs.
Just give him the finger. How dare
you? Is that what that was? No,
it was picking my Bob Myerwitz was the,
uh,
the owner and a Campbell Mclaren.
What was your official title?
Producer, you know cocreators what
they call me now? Aye. Aye. Aye.
E p. Dot. Shows and was the head
of programming for the company.
So you were there for you
fc 1.01 young guy was,
oh my boy. I was like a little
hill. See my up there on the screen.
I was a scrappy little youngster when I
was working for you guys. What happened?
Yeah.
I became an old man,
you know,
can gain years and uh, you
know, you still can look oh gay.
Cause you look like a fighter to me.
You look more like a fight
or now than when you started.
Well I didn't lift weights done.
That's why I started doing Jujitsu.
Like right before I did that show. But
back then I was just doing kickboxing. No,
no weightlifting ever.
But once I started June doing
Jujitsu and getting manhandled,
I said to put some meat on, this is
ridiculous. I'm tired of getting raped.
Well the Gracies, here's the pledge
they made to me and he'd go, you know,
gamble gums, study Brazilian, Jujitsu,
Gracie Jiu Jitsu with the family.
We promise not to break your ribs the
first couple times. That was the precise,
that's it. That's the, that's what I
get for. Nobody writes on free. Yeah.
You don't get good at Jujitsu
by not getting your ass kicked.
Everybody gets their ass kicked.
It's impossible to not get your ass
kicked and get good at Hugh Jitsu.
You have to do it. You have to experience
it. Do you think you're good at Jujitsu?
I got a couple of black belts. As far
as like regular people. Yeah, I'm good.
As far as like really good Jujitsu people,
I'm not that good.
[inaudible].