The Joe Rogan experience about here's
an interesting cat man. Yes, yes.
A bunch of things rolled
up into one because he's a,
he's a legitimate Catholic, like
he was really Catholic. Yeah.
Despite all the scandals and kid
fucking and all the craziness.
And then on top of that
he's this character,
but now he's not the character anymore.
No.
Now he's like a guy who's not
totally playing the character,
but the character comes in and out
like little shadows. Yes, it does.
It's like what are you,
what's your real thoughts on things?
Cause I know you as Cole Bear. Yeah.
Know you from the Colbert report,
this hilarious fake Republican guy
and now I'm seeing you. I'm, I'm not,
I'm not sure what's going on here, man.
Yeah. I mean he's, well, and when you're,
when you're in late night, you know,
I play a character on my show too.
That's like a heightened version of myself
that's developed as like a very extra
nerdy, it's almost like me as peewee
Herman, a little bit like it's, it's uh,
towards me as my younger self. It's like
very socially awkward. I'm a love, oh,
sorry. Like, it's a lot
of up there, you know,
and it's different than what I do
on stage. Uh, and uh, you know,
I can only imagine, even
though he is still, he's like,
his big thing for late night was like,
I'm going to be myself.
I'm not the character anymore.
You still build a little bit of a
character for yourself, you know? Yeah.
Well also with him it's like that's
what brought him to the dance. Yeah.
The reason why you, there is like what
kind of meetings that they have with him.
Like what are we going to do here?
We can tie this trait. Pico bear,
I heard him say once, he only said
this in one interview, but he was like,
we're basically creating a
new character for late night.
And so he had the same writers from,
from the cold bear rapport. And so, uh,
he was like, we're sort of
like creating a new character.
How does this character work? But I
got to say the old show, I mean he's,
he's great.
The old show was probably
the best performance ever
made by a single late night
comic because the way that
he, when I watch it now, if
I go back and watch clips,
I'm like the way he would do like three
or four fast little turns, you know,
you know,
single line where it would like mean one
thing but there'd be some sub tax than
he would flip around and he would do it
like it was like watching, um, like a,
a figure skater do triple axles, you
know, like watching him do that. It was,
it was really impressive. I liked
the guy, don't get me wrong, but I,
I like him more on the Colbert report and
I'm like him as a late night talk show
host.
But I do have to agree.
I think that's also my prejudice
against that format. I'm like,
you guys just saw what Jack Parr
did and kept going. Totally.
It's the same goddamn thing. But I
understand why he couldn't do the cold,
but he did that show for like 10 years,
you know, like you can't, you can't do,
that was a limited thing for him.
You know,
like he had that character and so he
could only do what was in the box,
that character. And so he's looking
to do more and, and I get it.
I also feel like man,
that Colbert report is more interesting
than the late night show to me is that
comic and as a comedy
writing fan for sure,
because the late night shows her just
promotion shows, that's all they are.
All they are is, Hey Adam, I hear
you. Have a book out. Hey Mike,
tell us about your new show. Here's
our 10 minutes of comedy before that.
And then we do that. Yeah. It's,
it's basically like a version
of a commercial and the,
and the nightly thing is a prison,
you know,
because you can only talk
about what happened that day.
So the smartest thing that
you know, John Oliver, right?
He was up for the daily show.
He wanted to do the daily show.
He was John Stewart's pick for the
daily show. They said this in the,
in the oral history book
of the daily show. Um,
and then comedy central didn't close the
deal with Oliver and HBO came and said,
you want to do a show instead? You know,
and John Stewart was like, all right,
go with God.
That's what John Oliver did instead.
So we're living in that alternate reality
from John Oliver Hosting the daily
show. Right. And so the smartest
thing I ever did was do weekly,
not daily because it lets him go
wider. Right? If he was doing daily,
he would have to just talk
about what happened that day.
You don't have that much.
You don't guess what,
you can't have as much of
a complete thought in 24
hours or in realistically the
six hours you have between when you show
up. But when you take the show, right,
you can't say as much you it's,
it's harder. And so being on that,
you know, weekly schedule and he's only
doing 30 something shows a year, right.
Cause they have hiatuses
that's what allows them to
have those big long complete
thoughts that everyone likes so much.
You know,
these ramps and intelligent takes on
news issues and pointing out hypocrisy.
That's great. Our show, it takes us, we,
it takes us like three or four
months to write an episode.
Like we're writing 16 at
once, but like, you know,
that's how long we have to think about it.
And so we're able to take
twists and turns, you know,
we go into it thinking this is going
to be our angle and then we're,
we're diving into the research. We have
a wonderful research staff and they say,
actually this is the more interesting
part of the story and then we are,
have the time to go chase
it that way instead. Right.
Whereas if we were on a daily schedule,
oh shit.
Well we don't have time to pivot
because we got a show to make. Right.
Do you ever feel time constraints?
Like in terms of like the subject matter,
the subject matters, like
very, very involved? Yeah,
I mean we try to do the most
difficult topics. We can't, you know,
we don't hold back from anything.
Um,
but the only constraint that
we have is that the show,
we've got 21 minutes and then in,
but we've got commercials.
So we only talk about some for six
minutes before we have to move on. Right.
And so that's the,
that's the only limitation that we have.