I don't think it was science is saying,
hey,
nobody comes back from the
dead after three days. Hey,
people can't really walk on water. Hey,
uh, why did he turn water into wine?
Why didn't he just make wine?
He's fucking magic.
I never thought of that. Stop
with the magic trick, Bro.
We're trying to get fucked up.
Just make us why camp tied a wind gunny
whiskey in that and those magic robes
get the miracles were sort of
like stupid fucking parlor tricks.
His miracles are horrible.
He knows the best.
There was a thing back in the 80s called
the power team for Jesus and what they
were with these dudes that would do
like feats of strength for Jesus.
Like they would, uh, they would
fucking break bricks with their head.
They would rip phonebooks and half,
they would lift up heavy weights,
do it for Jesus. Wow. But Jesus gave him
the power. Yeah. But it was also like,
hey dude, Jesus's, he's
magic. He's got magic.
Like he's not going to be impressed by
you breaking a board with your extra
thick skull. You fucking, yeah. Well
look at one of my children down there.
If you never heard of them. No, I dude,
I used to watch them all the time.
They were all like this religious channel
and I used to watch the power team for
Jesus going, what in the fuck is
this? That's amazing. It was. So,
have you found anything on it? I found
a lot. There's got to find that good.
A good one. Those guys are the
third street promenade. Oh,
Deep Virginia. Jesus. Yeah.
See? Oh, a break bricks.
Yes. What chooses a frog?
This brick for the load
star roads for sure. Devil. Ah,
yeah, I do use my head. Oh yeah.
Oh, Max kicked it. Whoa. Whoa.
It seems a little too
easy to break though.
We're really making the best for
Jesus. Ooh, drops it elbow low.
I'm gonna blow up this balloon for Jews
or they blow it up until it explodes.
That's why they have to wear goggles
on. It's like a whole lot. But yeah,
it's a bladder. That's not,
this trick is not great wax.
You're right in the face. It's just
so stupid song. Boom. Here comes, go.
Boom. I ripped a phone book. What's
that? What's that thought it was pot.
That's saliva pod as a Christian pod.
Pod payable on death.
What was the goal of the Christian
rock? Yeah, that's like, um,
they have some great fucking
songs. Yeah, here comes the boom.
Yeah, it's Brooke's ripping and phone
books and half for Jesus. Look at this.
He's bending a bar for Jesus is going
to love us. And by the way, this is a,
this is a newer power team.
This is not the original power team.
Power came 2.0 is it? Well, the
older guys are dead from steroids.
1990 Jesus now is, this is a 1991. Yeah.
Those huddle look at is,
look at the fucking mullet Bro,
and shaved armpits, by the way.
Notice that right? That use it.
Shaved armpits. Look at the
pants. Those puffy pants,
those gym pants. Hold on. What
is he saying? I was walking in.
All my friends were inside the door
shut behind me. Like the door shut.
Jesus took the blinders,
enrolled them right off
my eyes and inside them.
That bar for the first time in
my life I saw the world would,
it really had to offer me, he
would. It was a big fat zero.
I got in my car, I drove home with
my wife. We got inside our apartment.
My wife went and sat on the couch,
high paced back and forth in the living
room because he's like a lion who would
chain down everything. The world
pass by him and I was chained down.
I said, well, I've looked all my life.
This is for people where they put
pro wrestling's little too game.
It's pro wrestling without the other guy.
It's for people to think
progressive is too complicated.
Like I don't get what they're saying and
pro wrestling. There's too many people,
too many moving pieces. It hurts
my brain. I like this. Yeah.
That was a huge crowd, dude. That's
like 25 plus thousand people.
That plays a giant. Oh, I'm in
the wrong business. Yeah. Look,
they lift things up for, for the Lord.
Oh, what happened? The mullet, Bro.
Gorilla Mullen. The fuck is, he
didn't jump rope. It looks bigger too.
He did more roids and got rid of them
on his head. Grew his foreheads larger,
multiple people. Are they going to
throw him into a, a pet or something?
This is crazy.
Oh,
I wonder if it has the same speech or if
he gives a different one every time. Oh,
well that's the same guy, bro.
Molokais right behind him now. Yeah.
He's got the chains on
there. The same human. Yeah.
They're the same guy that it's a clone
tech team partner. Maybe they're twins.
They're tag team partners. Oh,
Christ. Ladies and gentlemen.
The more you committed to God, the
more you'll be committed to each other.
You'll never understand commitment.
The first time I ever saw them was
like on Jerry Springer or something.
Maybe they had a smash peep. Jesus
on Jerry Springer. Sometimes.
You know, they had to find out who's
the baby Mama. That's Maury. Maury was,
who's the baby daddy?
Yeah.