I mean, and I, I look at this say cause
I've worked with uh, with mark the Khasi.
Casey. Yeah. Physically. I
mean just God given abilities,
but he just doesn't have the
intelligence to make all that shit work.
He's screaming at the TV
right now, you know. I know.
And I say that I say that I,
and I say that with all due
respect because he's my main guy,
isn't he a young guy? Mark? Yeah. He's,
I mean early to mid twenties. Yeah.
Maybe just trying to figure it
out. Yeah. And that's what it is.
He's trying to figure it out and it
kind of pushed him a little fast.
So he didn't have a, you
know, a lot, a ton of shit.
Ones have some Edsons
had some ups and downs.
Cowboy fire was a big down, I
mean he's had, could be pipe,
it was a big down, oh
yeah, that was terrifying.
Fight doesn't even realize how God
could, could be Biz. Oh, I know. Yeah.
That was like,
that's the fight that like put Khabib
on the map really for everybody to say,
Matt, who's going to beat this
guy? And what he did to him.
Who's going to beat this guy.
Yeah.
But that's what I've always said is that
like if you had to pick like one thing
that you're good at,
like what's the most important thing?
It seems to me to be wrestling
because the wrestlers can just,
if you get a like a real high level
wrestler, they just dictate what happens.
They dictate where the fight takes place.
I don't think there is,
I mean you have to know how to strike.
You have to know the other things as well,
but it feels like if you have a
pyramid of shit that's important,
it feels like at the bottom is wrestling
and that motherfucker wrestles better
than anybody in that division. Yeah. I
mean, but see, I disagree kind of. Okay.
And here's why. Um, I don't necessarily,
because when we talk about wrestling,
I don't think it's necessarily
the techniques of restaurant.
I think it's just a waiter brought up,
they're brought up different in Pakistan,
not, not only daggers, they're
definitely brought up differently,
but like any wrestlers just brought
up different, oh, toughness.
A different level of
toughness, a different level,
a level of competitiveness.
So like when you go to Jujitsu school
was first thing you learn how to do his
bowel to Matt and kissed the
instructors ass. That's it.
You know you bout to Matt and and you're
learning self defense and you learn to
respect and wrestling. It's not
about that, it's about dominate.
It's about winning and dominating.
So they have years of experience of
doing that. Like just that mindset.
It's also about being uncomfortable all
the time and it's like it or just the
room is always rough. It's always
tough. Like you go to a Jujitsu school,
it's a bunch of dudes smoking pot,
land back.
They roll five minutes, sit
back, smoke for 30 role,
another five minutes you go to
a wrestling room is hot, sweaty,
they're all uncomfortable or all grinding.
So you take that guy and you
teach them some basic Jujitsu.
You got a champ. Yeah. Hey that this is
the mindset for me. Physical Strength,
physical strength, the grip strength.
I guess so important. Like for me,
like grips is everything and in
wrestling you learn a lot of that early.
So I feel like, um, that's kind of the
different searches brought up different,
yeah, I definitely think
there's something to that.
And then also being able to cut weight
and still compete. Yeah, I mean,
so I'm always my fighters now.
Like when you have that restaurant,
his parents basically,
if you wrestled in college,
like you go all your high school years,
you got 50 matches a year,
so you competing 200 times before you
even graduate high school and then you go
to college.
If you wrestle in college,
you compete against the best of the best
in the best room and then you fight MMA
is nothing,
there's nothing to you and now you,
and then you take a kid off the
street who's never competed before,
they're nervous, they don't perform
well there always at a disadvantage.
And as somebody who wrestled,
right, because of the
experiencing competition. Yeah.
Yeah. That makes sense. The only thing
about some wrestlers because of the,
like,
there's like a tightness to wrestling
and some wrestlers just never learned how
to be loose with Ca. And
some, some pick it up quick.
It's weird what s the difference.
And that's what makes some of them better
than the other ones. When I look at,
you know, obviously Tyron Woodley, he's
got it. He's loose. He's got it. Yeah.
Michael Chandler, when he throw his
right hand, it's loose. Yeah. Yeah. Uh,
but you're right. Some of them just can't
get it. And that's why they struggle.
And they struggle if they fight a wrestler
who can strike. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's terrifying for a wrestler who
can't strike to fight a wrestler who can
strike is terrifying. Oh
yeah, yeah. Absolutely.
Some dude who can keep it standing
and can fuck you up special.
They can kick too. I
know. I know. But that,
but I think that's another
problem with wrestlers.
They fall in love with the striking
earliest Jujitsu guys too. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's, and that's, and, and
that's what messes him up, man.
He Fall in love with it and think,
oh, I have to be well rounded,
so I have to dedicate all my time
to doing this. And I'm like, man,
but you getting worse
at what you're good at.
Why used to watch the George
group Shell fight? I'm like,
if you watch that guy fight,
you never know that he was a Brazilian
jujitsu black belt. Come man.
I used to get so mad at him.
I'm like, dude, what are you
doing? What are you doing?
Like he,
yeah.
I don't know if it was like
fan expectation or just
like in his mind he wanted
to be a striker,
but.