When you put together these drills and
you put together these programs, do you,
do you just sit down and map it all out
in your head? Do you think like, okay,
how am I going to emulate the kind of
stress in a like a life or death gunfight?
Your,
your heart rate jacked.
You might have to physically do something
meant to run from someone or climb
over something. Is that how
you do? How do you create yeah,
you're talking about like the
youtube stuff where I do the yeah,
like physical thing with the shoe.
Yeah. The first thing I do is I,
I put it on my calendar just so I know
that I'm going to make one and then I'll
start thinking about or what haven't
I done? Cause I have to think also,
uh,
I have to think about the audience,
the audience that follows me on youtube.
A lot of more gun guys. So they want,
they want to know about the gun that
I'm using to have to think about that.
And then I have to think,
all right,
what challenge can cause I
want guys to replicate it.
I want them to like put those
little notes on the Uta.
I did this and my time was a
minute and 30, or whatever it was.
So I want him to be able to
replicate them as well. And um,
Juan make them,
uh,
rear with some real world
application in mind, you know,
so front loading a sandbag or uh,
getting in,
pulling something in and out of a call
and doing that with the [inaudible].
Have you punched your reputations?
You know,
when you're doing dead weight
in and out of a car, you know,
150 pounds pulling it in, pushing it out,
pulling it back in and pushing it out.
That'll smoke every freaking ounce of
your being and it'll crush your spirits.
I know. It's crazy,
right? A full grown woman,
you will be able to pick her
up and put it in a car. Easy.
No hard tried getting her out. Right.
Especially if there's no, you know,
you gotta think deadweight yeah,
what did this person is incapacitated.
They ain't helping you.
Those arms just, you know,
those limbs are moving everywhere
and it is a pain in the Dick.
Yeah, you're way better off with 150
pound barbell. Oh yeah. That way.
Yeah. It's like, all right. That's just
that, just your shoulder pull it out and,
yeah. So, but I kept to keep
those things. Yeah. Mine.
Uh, the other thing I want to do is I want
to make them kind of wanting to make a
pardon of. So not
everybody could do it, uh,
because I want to do something that mind,
like industry competitors are not
doing. And I've, I've turned this,
I've, I've, uh,
started a kind of a fad I bought 10 years
ago were more guys are doing this now
they're putting like shoots
up on inner webs, you know,
with some physical activity
prior to or during a witch. Yeah.
Good. But, uh, and I'm
pretty sure I, uh, you know,
I, uh, I made it cool. Well, the more
people doing it, the better. Right?
The more competition, the
better. Yup. Yeah. It's,
it's just such a smart
thing to think of if you're,
if you really want to train the way you
train and really want to think about,
you know, like tactical situations
and real world application. I mean,
such a great way to go about doing it.
And if it looks exciting and fun. I me,
I haven't done it, but I'm
sure it's fun. It's good.
I talk a lot during my court now during
my courses. I don't do this stuff,
you know, I'm not cause I have,
I'll have 60 year old women in it.
I'll have guys with Parkinson's,
even man come to my course.
I have guys in real chairs.
Yeah, I have a guys. How do you,
how do you stabilize a guy when
they have Parkinson's? That's good.
That's what I showed this guy a trick.
What was his name?
See if I could remember his name.
It doesn't matter,
but he was 77 years old
and uh, he said, well,
I could either come to your course
and train or lay on my couch and die.
I was like something, you know, it was
to that effect because he likes to shoot.
I cipro anytime,
but I have to modify the course to him
now because he can't even be prone to
zero. So I would sit
him on um, on a cooler.
And then I used a, you know, furring
strips are, they hold up a target.
They're just two, one by twos, you
know, about five foot long. I had him,
Kris Cross those and hold them and then
V to v Notch and it put his rifle and
that Vena watch cause he
could sit up pretty good with,
he couldn't get into prone,
you can't stand shoot
but sitting pretty good.
And you know when, uh,
when guys like that are concentrating
more, you see that shake go away too. Hey,
that's something we do at my gym too.
We train Parkinson's a tata box
Parkinson patients. Really? It's a,
it's a, it's a national program
called rock steady boxing. Huh?
They come in twice, three
times a week. Where's your gym?
North Carolina. What's it
called? So people could go there?
Spar tech spar a s p a r like smaller.
And then TC,
is it open to yeah, it's all,
yeah, it's open. Um, it, uh,
it's, it's very fight
centric. It's an MMA gym.
So everything we do is very
like fight centric with the,
with the physical work and
lifting and all of that.
Uh, and then we have, uh,
programs like there's, we've got,
we've got some really good fighters,
man, dude, coach there. I mean,
they're like legit.
Um,
so we got really good fighters,
uh,
who do a one on one coaching,
um,
everything from Greco to Bjj to,
uh,
tie bogs to kickboxing to
stand boxing. Uh, it's,
it's an, it's a neat place. It's, it's
small. It's warehouse. It's very spartan,
you know, it's not sexy at all. Perfect.
Yeah, it's my favorite kind of jam.
Freaking. It's Badass. And so what do
you do with these Parkinson's people?
So the rock steady boxing, uh,
folks, they have a program,
they come in a couple of times a week
and they put them through a series of
exercises. You know, a lot of
it's just walking a straight line,
uh, holding this in Wa,
you know, loading one side.
And then once they're all warmed
up, um, they all kit up, man,
you see these guys are wrapping
and everything. You know,
they're so excited to get there
and they put the wraps on and uh,
and then they have, they work
a series of a bag, drills,
you know, uh, one, two lateral
move to next bag is, uh,
hooks, you know, left and right hooks and
there's an upper cut bag and there's a,
you know, the double end bag. And
granted, they're not moving you,
they're not moving much,
but they're moving and they get
there and they love coming there. Uh,
and uh, some of them work up a
sweat. You know, it's, it's pretty,
it's pretty amazing seeing them get
off their asses and get to the gym.
And I look,
I remember you put something out
and I pinged you like a year ago,
it was a on a podcast and you were,
uh,
you were getting pretty emotional
about somebody not loaning to a out.
And I pinged you and I said,
I think I've mentioned that we got fucking
Parkinson's people coming to my gym.
You know,
it's just when people make those excuses,
that just drives me crazy because I've
seen examples where I've been very
fortunate that I have good health,
but I've seen many examples and I've
also been very fortunate that I never got
out of shape.
I just kept working on my whole life.
But I've seen people that are fat as fuck,
350 pounds just barely can get,
get a w all round and then they decide
I'm going to take control my fucking
health. And then they just
just do it. They just do it.
And even if you just got
to walk around the block,
he didn't for walk up flights of
stairs. Even if you just do up, push up,
even if you do us it up, just do
something man. Do some body weight squats,
do something. It can be
done. Yup. It, you know,
the journey of a thousand miles
starts with that single step. And,
and I'll have guys
in my community who are saying, who will
say, yeah, man, I thought your stuff,
I'm sure out of shape and I
don't have the time to snatch,
which is another excuse. Those types
of things. I don't have the time.
Get up an hour early. Right. You
have all the time in the world.
You got an hour of workout.
I'll fuck you up in an hour.
You come work out with me for one hour.
I will have you crying
by the end of an hour.
That's plenty of time from warm up
to cool down one hour done. Yep.
That's 100% yeah. If you're,
if you're a man and man,
this is my friend and my
own need more than that.