The Joe Rogan experience. See
that is just not wise, right?
That's just too much. It's too
much to do. When people do that,
when they just take on too
many different, like I've, uh,
I've thought about other
stuff like doing other stuff.
I've had offers to do other stuff
and I start thinking about it.
Maybe I could find time for that. And
then I, then I give myself coaching.
Like I'm like, what would
you tell yourself? I'm like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
You're not doing anything else.
I can go barely do all this stuff
you're doing now. I think for me too,
as I get older, especially
like right now in my life,
my leisure time is very important to me.
Like it means something
and I don't mean leisure,
like sit around doing nothing but
like hobbies, like stuff that I do.
Like lately I've been shooting
guns. You have a jealous man, dude,
you should come with us thinking about
buying a gun. You should get a gun.
Do you want to come with us tomorrow?
Um, wait a minute. What's today?
Wednesday I might go in tomorrow.
We'll talk afterwards. Okay. But, um,
I'm going soon. But you should
come. It's fun. It's fun.
You learn how to shoot your gun and
tactical stuff. That looks fun. It is fun.
You know, it's like video
game, but some people get mad.
A lot of mad comments lie. Just get
mad. They don't want you shooting guns.
Stop it. Stop it. Think of
the children stop at blanks.
Well, you're not shooting blanks,
shooting real bullets, but it's um,
there's also a game that you can get,
we're going to get for this a
studio that's a, it's a real pistol.
Like it looks like a real
pistol and has a six pound pole.
So it feels like a real pistol
when you pull the trigger. And uh,
it's like that techno hunt thing where
you've got a laser beam that shoots out
and uh, it even makes a noise like had
gone like pow and you shooting zombies.
Yeah. And it's heavy like a pistol. So
you have to hold it like a PESTEL dope.
Yeah. Dude, that's bad. That's
next score and whatnot. Oh yeah.
It tells you how many civilians you
shoot, how many zombies you got.
Cause sometimes people come running around
the corner and it says it's a zombie
and then there's a civilian behind them.
You got to make sure not to start you
guys rolling around and shit out there or
you're just standing still and that
we're not in a movie, bro. What's funny,
you guys are having no obstacles.
I don't think it's a good idea to have
dummies like me roll around with a gun in
my hand. Somebody told me to buy a
Glock 19 that was the gun, that box.
Great gun. All right, cool. Yeah,
you should. Before you do anything,
you should learn how to
shoot. I've I've shot before.
I've gone a few times with you. Yeah,
yeah. For rifles, right? Yeah. Oh yeah.
I've shot in Burbank at the shooting
place where they have a place near ya. Oh,
that's right down the street. Yeah.
Yeah. It's fun, man. It's fun.
We should have a JRE, a shooting
range somewhere. Hell yeah. Have a,
just to that thing that we shot all the
hard drives. Yes. That was fun, man.
That was fun, wasn't it? That was rifle
shooting is fun, but pistol shooting,
um, when you're holding in your
hand it's way more difficult.
It seems to it more different.
You think it's more difficult?
More difficult to aim? Yeah, because
he gave me a rifle and uh, you know,
I shoot rifle so much or I have
shot him so much. It's easy.
You just have trigger discipline. You
just don't yank the trigger. Just pull,
pull, pull, pull paying and let it go
off like a surprise shot. And I was,
I hit everything I aimed at and he was
like, okay, you've shot that before.
But like pistols, I've only shot
pistols at a range with no instruction.
I don't really, I didn't
know what I'm doing at all.
And once you learn like how to grip
it, how to hold it, how to aim,
like you don't really hold
that hard with your right hand.
Most of the pressures with your
left. So, and the, the grip is very,
it's not intuitive. You have to learn it.
It's something that you
have to be taught correctly.
And there's so many people
there that are like, they,
they shoot in competitions and so when
you watch them do it, you're like,
Oh wow, Jesus Christ. Like
there's levels to this.
I just guys that can pull their gun out
and shoot four shots inside of a second
in a second, pull, draw, pull,
shoot four shots inside of a second.
That's crazy. Yeah, that's ridiculous.
But they're just begging for someone
to break in their house. You know,
there's people like that out there.
There's people like that where you,
you know, you break into the house,
you fucked with the wrong person. Well,
tent city's growing, so I
think I need to get one.
LA is going to be a giant
homeless encampment.
It's like if you looked at the
spread, right? If it was a disease,
a deadly disease that was
killing everybody and you
saw like patient zero and
then it spread like two people,
four people, six people, 10 people.
Now LA has more than 60,000 homeless
people and every single underpass that you
go to, you see camps. Now.
It's not like it used to be.
It's a totally different animal now. It's
like the walking dead man where it's,
it seems like it's growing.
Like Laurel cannon when you're going
to Laurel cannon off the one-on-one.
It used to be pretty normal last night
or two nights ago when I went through it,
it was like there was no sidewalk anymore.
It was like if somebody wanted had
to walk on that sidewalk. Yeah,
good luck with that. You're going
through your walk village, you know? Yup.
And needles and all kinds
of fucked up and human shit.
I mean human shits all over downtown LA.
I seen a lot of people shit and that's
nothing compared to San Francisco.
That guy's Zubie who's on our podcast.
He did a bunch of posts about his
trip to San Francisco is like,
it is so much worse. He was saying it
was so much worse than he thought it was.
It's so, it's so beyond comprehension.
How many people were just openly shooting
up drugs, shitting in the streets,
homeless people everywhere.
How do you fix that?
And like if you would think that if
there's something that LA needed to fix,
how to all the things that Ellie
complains about the homeless problem,
it's like one of the most
insurmountable problems.
Like what do you do to curb that?
How do you get these people homes?
How do you clean these people up?
How do you get them off drugs?
How do you get them off the streets? How
do you make it not a public nuisance?
How do you make it so people
aren't scared to go down streets?
Cause there's certain streets in
downtown LA where you see the street,
like you're at the beginning of the mouth,
the street and you look
in those three lights.
I'm not walking down there
like this is terrible.
They need to open up the mental hospitals
again whenever they closed them down.
Wait in the seventies or the
80s that's what caused all this.
They don't have those anymore.
It definitely was a problem.
But it seems like it's
gotten way worse. Right?
Like think about what it
used to be 10 years ago.
Now think about what it is
now. I mean this 10 years ago,
it was still decades after they
closed down the mental institutions,
they changed the standards.
So what it was was they had certain
standards where you would be
institutionalized and they changed
those standards under the Reagan
administration and just sent these
people out into the streets and everybody
thought it was like really cruel because
here you just releasing these people
with all these like severe mental health
problems and just releasing them out
into the street. But
that was a long time ago.
Something has happened recently
I guess is the economy.
I mean I don't know what it is,
but another thing you think seeing
around this area is mobile homes.
Like those, the dry, those campers
like Winnebagos fucking everywhere.
People just get enough money to
get one of them. Mobile homes,
they just park it on the street
and they live in those things,
which is just like a
mobile camp, you know?
And you get these gypsies that hang out
and they cook on the sidewalk and shit.
Like we used to have them here.
They would, they would like,
they were hanging out in sunbathing on
the lawn out here and the owner of the
building's like, get the fuck outta
here. Like, what are you guys doing?
This isn't the park, like go to the park
in what's worse? Sovereign
citizens, what does that,
there's people that don't drive,
they travel and they don't
follow the rules and they like,
if you watch it live PD, they have
one every episode to every episode.
They'll get pulled over and it's like
they won't even roll down the window and
they're like, I don't have
to follow your rules, sir. I,
they never have driver's
license or insurance. They,
it's like people that don't
think taxes apply to them,
but they don't think
the law applies to that.
But that's grown so big recently that
it's so many people now that do this shit
and it's the most grossest like,
uh, if you watch on an IPD, you'll,
you'll witness live P D by PDs
cops nowadays it's, but it's,
I think it's way better cause it's live,
it's like four hours long and the
host alive live in the moment,
like in seven different cities. They
have a whole control center. Like,
all right, we've got a speeding
going on here. We've got an,
Oh there's a chase going on here.
Let's go live over here. Yeah.
It's my favorite. And they have
it. They also have in Columbus,
Ohio where they used to and
they just got rid of it. Yeah.
I didn't even know this was a thing.
And so the sovereign citizens,
like what are they saying? They
get pulled over and they say,
I don't have to listen.
Yeah. They pretty much say like, your
rules don't apply. And they'll be like,
uh, get, you know, give me
your driver's side. I need you,
I'm ready to quick take you to the
jail for just a seatbelt, you know,
violation. Give me your
license. They won't like,
I don't need to give you
a license, sir, please.
They have this shit to keep on repeating.
And they all go to these websites and
they're like reading on their phone, sir,
I don't have to, you know,
do this and that and this.
And then they finally have to like break
their window and just drag them out and
arrest them. Just wear a seatbelt.
Finally, people are smart and you know,
they're talking about though. But other
people, I've just watched another video,
I'm like, Oh, I don't have to listen
to this guy. I'm a YouTube bourbon.
There's something unique, uniquely
satisfying about watching that.
I get pulled over by the cops and he
knows exactly what his rights are and the
cops are fucking up and he calls the cops
on different co codes and laws and the
constitution and then he winds up
driving off. I've seen that before. Yeah,
pull over the da on accident.
They're like, Oh geez. Oops. Yeah.
Or that woman who was a New York, uh,
she was like some kind of high up person
that got pulled over and she starts
yelling at the cops and shit. Like she
lost her job the next day. I saw that.
Yeah. Yeah. That was ridiculous. She
was trying to throw her weight around.
She didn't realize she was on camera
being a corruption man. That's corruption.
You're a citizen bitch. You know.
Everybody needs to realize I,
there was one where a judge got pulled
over and they let him slide but he got in
trouble afterwards as well
cause it's on camera, you know,
and then someone finds that video and
it's like, Hey man, you are a citizen.
You're like us.
Like if you're speeding or something
like that and they pull you over,
you can't get out and act
like you own these cops. It's,
I mean, you got to give your fucking
[inaudible] driver's license though.
You gotta you gotta show
them your identification.
If you're doing something that's
an infraction or violation.
That's the whole reason why we have cops.
Do you want everybody to just driving 150
miles an hour, no ID and masks on? No.
So you have to have rules.
So these are the rules.
If you do something that breaks the law,
they gotta be able to pull you over
and give you a fucking ticket and
incentivize you to drive correctly and
also find out if maybe you're running
from the cops and also they pull you
over, they get your ID, they go, Hey man,
you got a murder warrant
out for you. So, uh,
please step out of the car
with your hands up. I mean,
this is the whole reason when
we have cops in the first place,
then these people that think they don't
have to pay taxes and then the laws
don't apply to them. It's
all on unconstitutional.
Good luck with that case.
Good luck with the ass Wesley Snipes.
How that worked out. Yeah, it shit,
they put Wesley in fucking jail
for a long time. Lauren Hill too.
From the goddamn Fujis. They put her
in a cage for like a year. Right?
How long did she go to jail for
it? It was a taxes thing to men.
They get these wacky,
whether it's an attorney or
a tax professional or some
wacky advisor tells them
they don't have to pay taxes and
they read some internet thing.
It says actually it's unconstitutional.
It's only supposed to apply
during war time. I'm like, listen,
pay your fucking taxes. Okay.
You can protest all you want.
You think it's unjust, that's good.
They will put you in a fucking jail.
And if you're a famous person's
trying to pull that off,
especially a famous rich person, look,
it's not good, but it is what it is.
They're going to make an example of you.
Yeah. How long did she go to jail for?
Three months. That's it. Showing
what? The jail for three months.
Hmm. So she was released from a
federal prison, women's low security,
all facility. All females facility.
Just the fact that they put
her in a fucking cage is crazy.
Like she a danger to the public. Like
what is going on here? She owes you money.
How come that's the one money that
you can't just pay back. You know,
you can't just pay it back. How
come I can't just pay it back? Nope.
Not good enough. That you still
have to pay back and go. Yeah.
And yet they take away your ability
to earn a living for a long time.
Like Wesley Snipes. How
long was he in jail for?
He was in jail for like a solid
year. A whole year behind bars.
Put a halt to his career and all because
he owed some taxes cause he had some
wacky dude that was telling him he
didn't have to pay taxes. How long?
He had a three year sentence. Three years.
Imagine that man cause of money.
They lock you in a goddamn cage.
It's not like he stole money.
It's not like he held up a bank.
It's not like he was a violent person
that was a danger to society. No,
we owed some taxes. He made money and
they had, they're taking his money.
He made money, but he didn't give
his share up to the government.
So the government decided to lock him
in a cage to punish him and to make a a
statement to everybody else.
It's also like you pay taxes,
you get taxed on your paycheck
and then you'd get sales tax.
They're getting tax. How many times,
you know, getting taxed a lot. 10 times.
Well then that's why places like Nevada
people like because in Nevada you don't
have to pay state taxes, so you make a,
you can save a lot of money. Florida,
same thing.
Like I know a dude who moved to Florida
because he was going to sell his
business. So he's like, look,
I'm going to move to Florida and establish
residence in Florida for a few years
and then sell my business so I'm a
Florida resident and then I'll have to pay
nearly as much money can say,
if you want a big business,
it can save you a ton of money.
It's just weird that it's different
everywhere you go. You know,
like some places just don't have state
tax. You don't have to pay. Yeah.
Montana has different taxes. Colorado
is different. Taxes, they all have,
everybody's going to
like a different setup,
different amount that you have to
pay for this and that and over.
There's a weird thing that like a lot
of the big corporations have their
headquarters in Delaware for some reason.
It's like to somewhere tax law for
that. Yeah. A nice little tax Haven.
Well, isn't that why the
juice moved to Florida?
Didn't OJ moved to Florida because they
couldn't take his pension that way,
or he owes money based off the
lawsuit for the civil suit. Yeah,
but he has a pension right
from the NFL. Yeah. So right.
They can't fuck with that pension.
[inaudible].