How would they stop congressmen
from becoming lobbyists? Well,
one thing they do a,
and then I build loopholes into it,
but one thing they can do is
they can basically say, um,
once your congressman you can't be alive
is for five years and five years or
whatever the time is. But the more
fundamental factors, you know,
if you change the way you fund campaigns,
if it was no longer the lobbyists who
are kind of channeling the money in or
that we're getting their
clients to channel the money in,
then it's not like there
wouldn't be lobbyists anymore.
They just wouldn't be so well paid.
They wouldn't be as valuable.
And if they're not as valuable,
it's not as valuable for them to pay
the congressmen and incredible amount of
money to become con, uh, lobbyists. You
know, they would become almost like,
you know, lawyers policy wonks that
kind of go to Capitol Hill and say,
here's what will happen if you
adopt this legislation. You know,
that's an important part of the process.
But they wouldn't be the
mockers in the system.
They wouldn't be the people
who called the shots.
And so the value of their services would
fall and if the value of their services
fell, then, um, it wouldn't make so
much sense to go and become a lobbyist.
Maybe you'd come home and be a doctor
again or come home and like be a business
person again or do whatever you
want, uh, back in your district.
So I think if you change
the way you fund campaigns,
you would change 70% of the problem.
You would just fix it right then.
And these other things that good
additions, but not as critical.
But without changing the
way you fund campaigns,
I think all of these other
changes that are irrelevant,
they just can't get over the money.
You will always hear the phrase,
take money out of politics.
It's a constant phrase,
but that's not really possible now.
And underneath it gets really good.
The point isn't,
the point isn't to get money out.
The point is to get money that doesn't
represent a tiny fraction of the special
interests controlling how
congress people think. So, um,
I think today a congressman
from California Rogue Kahana
is going to introduce a
bill that he hopes will be eventually
part of whatever this big reform packages
that would create,
um,
a way of funding campaigns where everybody
gets a voucher or a set of vouchers.
You know,
Seattle has done this for city elections
where everybody gets for $25 vouchers.
They're only usable to fund campaigns.
So a candidate comes around and tries
to persuade you to give him or her the
voucher and then they take that voucher
and they use it to fund campaigns. Okay.
If Roca Han is bill passed and
everybody had vouchers to use to fund
congressional campaigns,
and you know,
the idea is basically you take the
rebate of the first $50 of your taxes,
which every American pays at least
$50 to the federal government.
You take that first $50,
you'd give it back and you give it
in the form of a voucher and you say,
take this voucher and help
fund campaigns with it.
Congressman would still be raising money.
They'd still be spending a
large time raising money,
but they wouldn't be raising money from
the tiny fraction of the 1% they'd be
raising money from everybody.
And so the point is that you would be
using that money to spread the influence
in the way that democracy is supposed to
spread the influence to every American
as opposed to the influence in a tiny,
tiny fraction of the 1% so
that wouldn't get less money.
I think that could be
more money in the system,
but it wouldn't be corrupting money
because it would be money that is
democratically accountable.