Right. This time just flew by. That'd
be because it's a love fest of truth,
logic and common sense. Well, listen,
man has been a pleasure to meet you back.
It had to be able to sit down with you
again and have a good conversation here.
My friends were right.
You do to deserve me and I think it's,
I think it's a good opportunity for people
to get a chance to see you in a long
form conversation rather than these sound
that they could just choose to hate.
Especially when the sound bites are
edited and a manufacturer. Yes. It,
let's make it perfectly clear. I did
not avoid the draft. I did nothing. Oh,
let's go you that.
I am not raising real quick.
That was an old school story
of an interview supposedly
that you shit all over
yourself in high times. Matt,
by the way, Joe, you've,
you know me pretty well
in the last three hours.
If I had shit on myself
to get out of the draft,
do you think for a minute I would
deny it? No, I would have. No,
that would be a great story.
It was a story. Is that about,
I went in and got my draft
as they're going. By the way,
when I went in 1969 I was superman.
I literally would hurdle Volkswagen bugs.
I was all muscle and sinew.
I could, I was superman.
I was the most athletic running,
jumping gazelle known to man
and I went in for my daughter.
I didn't know anything about Vietnam.
I didn't know anything about war.
My Dad was a war hero,
but nobody talked about it.
I'd never heard of the Bataan death march.
I graduated from the American education
system so I knew nothing and there was
all protest around me,
but I wasn't really tuned into the protest
because I was making music every day.
I mean just obsessed with the Amboy
dukes and playing gigs every night and I
didn't pay attention.
I never watched a newscast in my life,
but I was given a draft
notice and I went down,
I went down and I had my draft physical
and I passed with flying cover colors
and I got a draft card in the mail a
couple of months later through my mom and
dad's house. And One why not a
deferment? It's uh, uh, uh, uh,
designation. I was in, uh, Oakland
Community College at the time,
so I was why was a student,
uh, designation I believe,
but I was ready to rock.
Um, I didn't want to go.
I didn't understand any of my buddies
were going, uh, uh, uh, John Break,
my singer had to go, uh, uh,
Rob Leonard from, uh, uh,
Amboy. Dukes had to go. Uh,
so the only way you could have gone
is if you dropped out of school.
Is that what it is? No, it wasn't
a deferment. No. I would, I could,
I would have been called anytime.
So you could have been
called or just weren't sure.
And then the Wikipedia claims,
I got a four f four f what does a four
f fourF and means you're physically
incapable. I'm never been
physically incapable of anything.
So they make this shit up. So, so I
did an interview with the high times,
which by the way, let's make it
clear. I've done this so many times,
but people ignore my actual statements.
So I had been doing interviews all cause
the employee dukes were on fire and I
was just an outrage on stage with a loin
cloth and the bone Arrow and feedback
and he's killed her songs.
And the band was so good,
greatest musicians in the world.
So I did interviews all the time
talking about the music I loved,
and they never got anything right.
These stone dirt bag hippie writers get
the gas guys in the band's names wrong.
They got the facility wrong. They,
they've mentioned songs we didn't perform,
they got nothing, right? And every
time I'd read the inner voice of God,
we are talking about my music.
You didn't even get the song titles right.
So I started having fun
with these interviewers,
much to the entertainment of my band mates
who would break out in hysterics when
I'd make up stories because I'm not
gonna even try to be accurate anymore.
It was an ongoing maneuver of mine.
We'd have these hippie writers come
in to take notes and I'd say, yeah,
I played this fender stratocaster
as I hold up my Gibson bird land,
which has known for, and
they'd write down, he played
in a Gibson a stratocaster.
There's no such thing as the gifts,
Reddick gas.
So I was having fun with
dirt bag anti journalists.
So now I'm invited to high times
magazine and I was hardcore anti-drug.
So I go, we had, and this guy
is, and his inner is typically,
so, uh, uh, so, uh, tell me about, uh,
this I Amboy dukes. What is
it like a band? I went, yeah,
it's like a band.
So it's almost exactly like a band
fuck kind of question. Is this,
how did this draft Sony,
how he started talking about when I'm
with the MC five and the stooges and we
would party and I go, yeah
man, I was snorting something.
I don't know what it was,
man. I just got higher than
a kite. And he goes, wow,
you think I might've been a
crystal meth? And I mean, yeah,
that's what they called it. I never
snorted. Crystal Meth is made up. Shit.
Just when nuts and I,
we went into the war thing and I go,
I don't know anything about
war. I'm a, I'm a guitar player,
but I went down for my draft physical
and when I went into the booth to give my
urine sample,
I made sure I ate Mexican food all week.
So instead of pissing in the Urine Cup,
I took a big dump in it was green and
went all over the place and the guy went,
wow. He really, yeah. Really?
And so I made up the story for
High Times magazine, you know,
the great magazine of in
good information and uh,
embedded turned out that
my drummer Kj night,
God blessing me to actually admitted this
and testified that that's what he did.
It is. We thought it was the
funniest thing in the world.
We're teenagers and this guy
went into the draft physical,
just an absolute near death lumpy
shit to get out of the draft.
And we thought it was funnier and hell.
We weren't paying attention to
important things in life. And so the,
the Ted Hating liberal press
started quoting the high
times magazine and quoting
an ex girlfriend who claimed
that I adopted her, that her,
I adopted my girlfriend to be read
that one. I did read that one,
I forgot about it. So this
kind of stuff, I was like,
you adopted her so you could
take her on tour with Ya know,
so I could fucker that's the story was,
but that's Ab.
Absolutely.
I don't think that's how it works.
That's not how I think it makes it easy
to talk to him once you adopt them.
I didn't adopt anybody cry.
I never shit my pants since I was,
I think eight months old.
Um, I've never been with an
underage girl since I was under age.
I'm not a racist. And what
else did they say? Oh,
and they seem that they cleaned that I
made Courtney love blow me when she was
12. I think she claimed that I,
yeah, I never met Courtney love.
You can tell I don't have a rash of,
you've just got to be kidding me.
They just make this shit up because they
know I'm so good at bringing my basic
conservative agenda forward
that they have to go full,
solid Lynskey and lie and lie and lie.
And if you go to Wikipedia
to find out about Ted Nugent,
they will repeat these lies. They're
lies. And every one of those things,
every one of those things, if I had
done it and I go, yeah, it was awesome,
but I didn't do any of those things.
Anyone can edit Wikipedia. You know,
that very strange that she
might have edited it yet. So,
so I'm glad we got that. Oh, this
thing is just persisted forever.
Obviously it stuck in your crop because
you wanted to bring it up at the very
young, just sticking my crotch. Just,
it's a fascinating example of the
dishonesty and the anti journalism agenda
driven, um, anti-American,
anti Ted anti second amendment,
anti freedom.
Buffoonery the exists. And I think it
makes for an interesting podcast exchange.
I think so. Not In my craw. It's not
even in my universe, but I notice it.
It's hysterical. Ted Nugent, ladies,
gentlemen. There you have it.