How did you guys feel when I
was going through all of that?
Like what was the effect on you
guys? I was very nervous. Yeah.
I was very nervous about
you. Um, cause I don't, um,
I didn't know what to do
and I knew I could do,
I knew I could help you financially.
I knew I could do that.
So I did that immediately, but I didn't
know what to do. I don't, I didn't,
didn't know what it feels like and I
didn't know what would it be the path to
take.
But when you offered that you were having
problems with your psychiatrist and
the medication and I said, okay, well
let me, let me get ahold of Matt,
who I know will know the right people.
I see people don't tell me anything.
Yeah. You were like, oh,
I was like, you were,
you're such a non complainer that I knew
when I always tell people this story,
but we're playing pool and Ari's
limping around the table. I'm like,
what the fuck happened to your leg man?
Fucking spider bite or something. I go,
what? Let me see your fucking leg.
And he pulls his pants up like a dude,
you got to go to the hospital right now.
You have a very bad staph infection
in this could fucking kill you.
And you're like, come on, you're joking.
I'm like, I start unscrewing my cue.
I'm like, we're going to the
hospital now. It was so bad.
But the fact that you're so stoic,
you will,
you never complained once while you have
this gigantic plus fields on your knee
killed. It was horrible, man. One posted
the juke clay and video and they were,
he was like, do you know that there? And
he's like, ah, it's bogging you. Not me.
What?
So when you were,
when you were telling me that
you were doing bad and it wasn't,
you weren't feeling good and you were,
you were telling me you were suicidal.
I was like, okay, stop. We got to now
this is, we're going to figure this out.
You know, I don't know what to do. We're
going to figure this out. Maybe nervous.
Cause I was nervous that I wasn't going
to be there when you needed me to be
there. And you know, and I would just,
I would just get the call.
It's just get the call. Yeah.
I mean as a friend that's the last thing
you want to do is have some situation
when you feel like maybe you could have
called them and you could have made them
feel better and you,
they would've just gotten over that
hump and then they would have been okay.
Like you became okay man.
I mean,
you were my most depressed friend and
now you probably one of my happiest
friends,
even after I started seeing that guy,
it's still took months before finding
the right pill and the right dosage and
then he would talk to me every like
30 days or whatever it was you,
I remember you describing the process
and one of the things that was
disconcerting to me was how random
it seemed to be. What do you mean?
Which pills they chose?
It's like they're guessing.
That's what seemed insane to me.
I felt like if you like,
say you know you got an infection,
they know which antibiotic works
best on that infection, boom,
they give it to you. But this one
wasn't that cut and dry. It was,
they were just trying stuff out on you.
Yeah. It's like, oh, you need Ibuprofen.
You have an inflamed thing. It'll took
it down. But they know generally. Yeah.
This is like there's,
from what I get gather,
those two things could be wrong with you.
You either have too much dopamine,
too little dopamine, too much something
else, or too little something else. Huh.
And so each of these pills,
I think they're into two categories
or four categories, and they either,
they either affect the dopamine
or they effect the other thing,
either limited or push
more in and then the other,
so they don't know which
one's doing it to first. Uh,
and then once they narrow that down,
they've got to decide if it's like
getting too much of it or too little.
I don't know if you're bipolar is a
separate thing. They're just guessing.
And then while you take this shit,
you've added the horrible feelings
and then added some awful side effect.
You're just like,
ah.
This is one of the things that I really
wanted to point out when when Bruce
Roseanne was going to come on,
I wanted to really talk about
medication and how we're,
we're asking this really,
you know,
she's an elderly woman who's taking
an incredible amount of medication.
She takes.