But again, you know, this
isn't because the drug is bad,
it's because people use it irresponsibly.
And this is something that people
have so much difficulty understanding.
We're so eager to blame drugs
for all of our problems.
Drugs have never heard anyone.
They're just inanimate constellations
of carbon and hydrogen,
nitrogen and oxygen.
They don't jump out of their bags and
vials and attack your serotonin receptors
are dopamine transport
or anything like that.
So this is just a weird pattern that
we've done repeatedly over time.
And I don't know if you read
the new Michael Pollan Book.
I know he was on the podcast right now.
Yeah, it's great. Yeah, it is great.
But um,
one thing that I thought was interesting
about it is that he put a lot of the
emphasis on the prohibition
of psychedelics on leary
and leary almost certainly
played a role,
but I think it's slightly ironic that
he's a journalist and didn't really go
that deep into the role that
journalists played in all of this,
which was humongous.
You know,
journalists are sculptors of public
opinion and it became the standard way of
reporting on any of these
things to say that they're bad,
to sensationalize it and to not have any
consideration for what that would do.
Because anytime a journalist
writes him scare story,
they can really mess with
drug policy in a serious way.
It might seem like nothing like,
oh,
there's a bunch of people in Brooklyn
and they overdosed on some obscure
synthetic cannabinoid amb food Banika who
cares about and beef Herbenick I know.
Big Deal say that it turns people into
zombies and if it gets thrown into
schedule one, who cares?
Not a big deal. Well,
that's a very short sighted way of
thinking about all of this because that's
exactly what happened with psychedelics.
And then we're not learning from the
mistakes of the past that just because
something,
it's fun to sensationalize and talk
about how dangerous it is at this moment
doesn't mean that 10 years from now we're
going to recognize that it has serious
therapeutic potential and we
made a big mistake outlawing it.
And I think a lot of that also comes from
this sort of us versus them mentality
that people have where it's cannabis is
good, synthetic cannabinoids are bad.
Well, synthetic cannabinoids don't
have to be bad for cannabis to be good.
Cannabis can be good without something
else being bad to counter balance it.
You don't need to hate something
to justify your love of cannabis.
And this whole hatred of
synthetic cannabinoids I
think is totally misdirected
because these are products of prohibition
that most people wouldn't even want to
use in the first place.
And when they do use them,
they don't know what they're taking. They
don't know what dose they're consuming.
And so of course they're having bad
experiences that would happen with almost
any drug.
Caffeine included if people just consumed
enormous unmeasured doses without
having any idea what
they were getting into.
And so they're thrown into schedule one.
What happens if 30 years from now,
once the therapeutic potential of
cannabinoids is being really seriously
explored,
we find out that that amb food Banika
that everyone was saying turned homeless
people in his zombies in Brooklyn in
2017 turns out to activate a certain
subtype of the CB one receptor that's
especially useful for Parkinson's disease
or something like that. Then we're
going to regret having done that.
So I think people have to be very careful.
Anytime you say anything negative
about a drug, you have to be very,
very careful because the
implications can be enormous.
I think that the best stance and all
of this is to not speak ill of drugs,
drug the drugs have
breakthrough drug enthusiasm,
but it's not a problem.
Also with just what journalism is,
it's like asking a comedian to talk
about something but not make fun of it.
That's what their job in a certain sense
is to get people excited about things.
And I don't know whether you'd say the
lazy way out or the common approach is to
say something that scares people.
I mean that's,
that's what clickbait is mostly about.
Either outrage or fear. That's true,
but there's a lot of richness in
truth. I agree, but it's hard to sell.
It's hard to sell that rich and hard
to sell. I think the people are lazy.
You know, there's this idea that a
lot of people have that you know,
journalism is organized by some malevolent
Rupert Murdoch type puppeteer who's
telling everyone to.
You go off and you say that
cannabis causes car accidents
and you go off and you
say this evil thing about this
and say the alcohol is good.
Did you see when a Alex Jones was
on my podcast and got high with me,
I'm drunk and I, and when it came
up in his trial for is a divorce.
He said that George Soros puts a,
He tests marijuana every year to see
how much George Soros is influencing the
levels of THC.
That was his excuse.
But people love these ideas.
They love the ideas of the puppeteer and
malevolent puppeteer because it denies
individual agency.
But the reality,
and I say this as a journalist who's
worked at many different publications,
not just device, and this is a
difficult reality to swallow,
is that people are free to say
whatever they want most of the times.
And the journalists choose to report
on things this way. That is true,
but it's also true that they,
like I've been a part of stories that
I've talked to the author of it and they
said, well, this was
manipulated by the editor,
the editor of manipulated the title
the chain. That's a great excuse.
But to the right,
and it's true,
like the rolling stone did an article
about me and they called me as psychedelic
warrior and I said to the guy who
wrote down, what the fuck is that?
I was laughing and he goes,
dude, I did not write that. Yeah.
And an editor gets a hold of it,
tries to make it more salacious.
It becomes something that's more,
it's more likely for people
to buy or click. Right.
Especially with headlines
that that is true.
And the real problem is that this sort
of outrage culture and comment culture
that has emerged provides
no incentive for truth.
Because suppose someone were to write
an article about this conversation we're
having right now, and it
could say, Hamilton Morris
says Katam should be illegal,
or something like that.
Then that will get so much more engagement
because then you'll have all these
people saying, fuck Hamilton, he's a,
he's a trader. How dare he say that?
It should be illegal
that it didn't watch it,
and then you'll have other people
arguing with those people saying, well,
listen to the interview.
Hey,
he actually never said anything about
that and listen carefully to what he was
saying.
And then you create this whole engagement,
a bigger engagement for
doing the wrong thing.