Ooh, spin Colby. You got Ben
at Ben Asker in there now.
Now during tail has a shot to be
a champion. I'll tell you what,
even though Robbie Lawler lost that
fight, God damn, he looked good.
He looked good physically while I grab
the way and he looked Jack Best I've ever
seen him.
He looked amazing.
Apparently he had a tremendous strength
and conditioning routines. Yeah,
he looked real good and he was
fighting fucking for Roche.
It's like the Robbie Lawler of old.
He didn't look at all diminished and I
think maybe the time off was good for him
because he had to get a ACL surgery.
So it might have been dealing with
something before his last fight.
We don't know.
Do you think maybe it was to where
Ben Adkins very so one dimensional.
He didn't have to worry about
the striking at all. Um,
there's a little bit of that for sure.
But the fucking fight started because
he launched Ben Astroneer to the ants.
Slammed him on his fucking head, which
was crazy. Then as tough as shit.
Yes, Ben, one controversially.
We don't know that there was still what
two minutes left in that fight dude,
I've been watching their dog
choke. Yeah. With that much time.
It could've got pretty dice
for four fucking um, uh,
uh, can we get a dicey, we
can't just chalk go Benz.
Uh, Ben, I think you put it on
his Twitter or an Instagram page.
We see Robbie Lawler's arm go limp to
Dick goes limp. Now here's the question.
Did it go limp because he just let it
go cause he was trying to like let you
know, just let it go cause he's
trying to like that's a weird,
hang on cause the choke,
he was like he's squeezing really hard.
It's going to tire his arms out.
Robbie said it was an under his chin now
but here's the thing and this is people
need to stop saying that you have to
be under the Chin could choke a guy
unconscious.
You can do both.
You can choke a guy on conscious across
his face before she can go across the
face. Right like this. And
if you have a real squeeze,
you have like a Marcello Garcia squeeze.
You could put a guy asleep.
Think I'll strong. Ben is to, Ben has
a real squeeze, phenomenal squeeze.
He's trans and he's in this position.
Would that bulldog,
you can get a lot of leverage
in that position. I mean,
I don't know how he's gripping.
It's so much more torque Torque,
so I don't know if he went out and then
Ben let them go a little bit and then he
popped right back awake.
That's what he's saying.
You're your natural movement though.
If you go, if you're fighting a choke,
your your natural is to hold onto
it is not to go lip. That's true.
That's true. That that's why I'm
like, all right. Maybe he was out.
We thought he was out. Yeah, he thought
he was out, but in all fairness,
I thought Ben was out earlier. Me
Too. We're not. They're going to stop.
I thought there were a stop and Robbie
slammed. I'm like, he's out. He's out.
He was fucking, I thought he was out,
but damn, he can take a fucking shot.
He can take a fucking shot because
Robbie hitting wants some hammers.
I was nervous for that fight. Ooh, it's
crazy. We've hooked him up so much,
so much love, so much, and when he came
to Daddy's do Goober, dad bod, I was like,
damn, his justice terrible,
but let's figure this out.
Let's see. Do you have a video of it?
Check both of his pages. I don't see
he posted it today. I think
it was a Twitter. Yeah,
I think it was Twitter and I think maybe
he might've either repost it or replied
to it or repost it with a comment. Oh,
he says this is what happened to it.
It's in the conscious to comment.
Okay,
well let's say it when he
said this is what happened.
Then go to whatever he was commenting on
and then you'll see the video whenever
he was commenting on
is the video the only,
basically they were saying
that in the video that he see.
Let's check it out here. Jack
Sparrow. There it goes. See carefully.
You will see that Ben Loosen his
chalk chalk choke a little bit,
and then herb dean touch. Click on that.
Click on that goes to a long thread. Yeah,
but if you go to the top of that thread,
you'll see the video.
There it is right there at the top right
there. Watch this. So check this out.
See that right there. Normal
move by Bob. But look,
but Robbie does give them the thumbs up.
That's the other thing that you're not
seeing that it's not a normal movement,
but it is a tight squeeze.
It does look like his arm went limp.
I think it went out for a second
and came to, well, herb said,
what herb is saying is he told Bam
to stop when the arm went limp,
when the arm went.
Lynn Ben said is that he's lightening
up and then he lightened up and then
Robbie came back to life. That's fair.
That is entirely possible, folks.
It's entirely possible.
I do not know,
but I do know that Robby
Lawler is a classy motherfucker
because he complained a
little, said what the fuck does.
All right man, good job. Good fight.
He's been in the game so long and he's
like, he can see him. He goes out,
he's got to, he's got a great
attitude. He really does.
He's got a great attitude and a, I don't
think it stock dropped in that fight.
I really don't know. No, I really don't.
And I would like to see the rematch.
I don't, well, I want to see it again.
I mean he says no, but Ben says no big.
Ben Says he didn't want to
fight him in the first place.
Why would you turn right fucking murderer?
But he was so amped up for that fight too.
So angry and like you could see in his
face he knew what this meant. Dude.
How about Ben versus Uzman
mother fucking fight shit.
Oh Damn tail. Yeah. Ben, your performance.
Your Shit. You barely one. Your ugliest.
Fuck.
Your Chin is too big not to miss.
You have no respect for no one.
Oh did I say your a curly headed fuck.
See in London, muppet well till has a
tough fight in London though too. Yeah.
Mazda dials. No joke, man. Maza
dolls. A very technical guy.
He's got a wrestling to men,
he's getting everything. Yep.
Very good at everything
and very good wrestling.
And I think that's probably where he's
going to try to put Darren till after
that Woodley fight.
He said.