Staph infections.
Exactly.
So to be able to stop it in its
tracks before it gets systemic, right.
Spray this stuff on a cruise
line for, for the virus, a virus.
Um, even if it turns out to be that
safe, we're not just wipe down, uh,
schools.
Oh,
because I was worried about the negative
aspect, like what's gonna Happen?
Like what's, what's gonna
be the blowback, right?
Like antibiotics is what's created
medicine resistant antibiotic or staph
infections. Right, right, right.
Your mind always jumps to the worst
possible scenario. Love it. Um,
we'd make it good. Good team. So I'm
the, I got a buddy cop movie. Yeah,
let's do it. So we've tested, does
it induce antibiotic resistance?
And so far it's negative. Hmm. Okay.
Interesting. Oh, nothing. I'll tell you.
Um, so I work with a company
that detects organisms.
So we wanted to detect if there's
another virus coming across the planet.
So how do you do that quickly?
Um,
and how do you do it if you don't
know what you're looking for?
So we can take a drop of blood or a swab
off the table and we can see all the
organisms that are there. Um,
we can do your microbiome,
but that's easy. We can do,
uh,
so a drop of blood will tell you all the
bacteria and viruses in there and it'll
tell you how to kill it, which is
great for healthcare because right now,
microbiology labs I've worked in one,
I used to swab urine and poop on plates.
It was very glamorous.
That's how it's still done.
That is, that's 19th century,
early 20th century technology growing on
a plate. Wait a few days, see what grows.
But that's useless for diseases like
viruses and Lyme disease, Lyme disease,
you know, the, the one from
ticks in your, in your spine.
My daughter got Lyme disease
and she was really sick.
She was losing her eyesight.
Um, it was serious.
It got into her brain and the hospital
wouldn't give her the antibiotic because
they,
the tests weren't quick enough and they
wouldn't give her the antibiotic until
the test were positive for
insurance reasons. And I said,
just gimme that gimme the DNA of my
daughter, the spinal fluid, I'll test it.
They wouldn't do that.
So I was furious.
So I spun out a company out of my lab
with some very smart bioinformaticians
mathematician software engineers.
Uh,
we built super computers to be able to do
this. Teamed up with a guy in Stanford.
Um, my friend, I mentioned
him, Carlos Bustamante, he's
the guy that, uh, did, uh,
oh, maybe I shouldn't, but he did a
famous person's genome recently. His,
he'd been trained on mummy's,
um, and he did Kennewick man.
And so this technology can be teamed up
with what I've done to be able to get
rid of all the human DNA out of
blood sample, leave the viruses,
lead the bacteria, and then run that
through us, a computer supercomputer,
all the DNA and tell you
within probably seconds,
eventually what it is.
So my daughter would have a diagnosis
within eventually be just 10 minutes
instead of waiting a week.
Wow.
Lyme disease is terrifying there.
There are so many people
that are infected with it.
And I know personally maybe 10 people
that have it and a couple that have had
significant issues with it
that have lasted for years.
I know a guy who was hospitalized
for a full year on it. It's,
it's really bad and it, and it can
hide as well. That's the problem. Yeah.
And it Rick's joints.
Um,
and that thought a lot of countries
actually deny that they have lung disease.
Australia's a good example.
People are getting what seems to be Lyme
disease and no one knows if it is or
not. Give those samples to us. We'll
tell you what's in there. Well,
it seems to be very difficult with
certain doctors for them to tell if they
don't see that bull's eye infection.
Exactly.
So my daughter outdoor at
Natalie and middle daughter,
she didn't have a bullseye.
She had nothing to first
thing we hit the bullseye.
Oh, so it's inflammation
around the bite of the tick.
Right. And um, and there's, uh,
there's the actual bite and then
there's a circle on the outside of it.
And for whatever reason,
this occurs with Lyme disease,
but oftentimes goes away quickly.
So if you bring a person in
and they have the Lyme disease,
but they don't have that bullseye anymore,
which is what happened
to my friend Steve Son,
he tried to tell them that
it was Lyme disease. They,
the doctors were incredulous.
They didn't believe him.
It took until the kid had bell's
palsy at his face. Exactly.
That's what happened. If Emily
it, it's crazy. And so, um,
I was bitten by a tick last year,
right behind the knee and it didn't form
a bullseye. Maybe I didn't give it time,
but it definitely was very painful thing.
Um,
I could tell that there was something
going on. It was really itchy.
And I went to the pharmacy and I said,
can I, the antibiotic, it's, you know,
it's probably costs a few dollars for
the antibiotic. And they said, no,
we won't give it to you till we see a
bullseye and you need to bring the ticket.
While I didn't bring the tick with me.
So again, I'm the doctors and nurses.
Worst nightmare. I wouldn't leave
until they gave me the antibiotic.
And I'm glad because I don't want to
wait the wait until I give it to you.
They did. I wasn't going to
leave until I got it. Uh,
but I don't want to wait a week
and I'm starting to lose my,
did you get signed up with them to say,
listen,
you dumb mother fuckers super
smart. I worked with jeans. Uh,
no, not that occasion. It's tempting. It's
tempting. And now you can always say, Hey,
I'm a professor at Harvard. And then
they probably just really kick you out.
Yeah. What did he say? I mean, how long
did it take before they listened to you?
Uh, so I went through, I basically,
I started spouting biology so that they
knew their, I knew something about it. Oh,
it was about 15 minutes. Oh, that's
not bad. He knew what to say.
I can be there for days.
Bye Bro. Trust me. Right.
Let me draw you a picture
of the tick. Yeah. I mean,
I would just think they'd want to hand
that stuff out quick with so many people
getting it. It's so common. I mean,
we looked at a map recently on the podcast
of Lyme disease infections across the
east coast and the east
coast of the United States.
Obviously that's where you live is just
a hotbed. It's crazy. It's everywhere.
Well it is an, and I've got friends on
Cape Cod where it's really prevalent,
really bad, so bad that, so they keep
the antibiotic in their kitchen drawer,
cheeses.
And if you catch it quick enough,
does it stop it in its tracks?
Yeah.
So the real problem is when it gets into
your blood stream and you don't treat
it long enough or quick
enough. Exactly. And so my,
my daughter needed
what's called a pic line,
which has delivery the antibiotic
to straight into the heart. Oh.
Cause they left it too long.
God, I'd want to kill them.
And she didn't have a ring of bring
of inflammation. But you knew, uh,
I didn't,
I thought it was meningitis.
Bacteria in the brain or something like
leukemia was the other possibility.
Those dirty fucking bugs,
what can be done to,
to somehow or another eradicate
those things. Oh. So, um,
again, one of my friends
got a few friends here. Uh,
she was working at Mit and she's developed
a way using the CRISPR system to kill
these, as you say, demo fuckers. Um,
and so there is possibly going to be
the first test of releasing a modified
organism, the Lyme organism
to kill them off. Wow.
And you know, that's going to cause some
new super bugs going to kill everybody.
It's going to be like that. A Brad
Pitt movie, the Zombie One, World War z
might be, but on the other hand, we
might all be saved from Lyme disease.
I would like that though.
It'd be great. I just, I mean,
where did Lyme disease come from? There
was, uh, some conspiracy theory website.
There was thinking that Lyme
disease was some sort of a,
some sort of a biological weapon.
That's probably bullshit, I'm sure.
But it came out, it was in
Lyme, Connecticut, right?
Wasn't that one of the first cases?
Yeah.
So that's a close enough to
Harvard and she's stayed away,
which I thought he said Russians
who are behind it. Oh No.
I said conspiracy theory. I didn't say it
was Russian, but as a biological weapon,
it's a, it's just an awful thing.
And that, and now there's the,
I'm sure you're aware of the lone star
tick that gives people that I'm a Alpha
Gow d disease, the one that, uh,
makes you allergic to red meat,
which is, I mean, where,
where was that before?
It's crazy to see these
things morphing and morphing.
And there are a lot of bugs.
We don't know,
somebody just published a few days ago
that they took surveys of the microbiome
on the skin, mouth, gut across
the planet, different races,
different foods,
geographic geography,
and they have 100,000 different
organisms living on humanity.
And most of them are unknown.
That's crazy. Right? Right.
And all they have to do is just more,
a little bit one way or the other way
and all of a sudden people are dropping
like flies.
Yeah.
And what's interesting is on the skin
and in the gut of people in India is very
different than what we have and the
different smells you might, yeah,
they probably think we smelled bad.
Um,
but I know this because while they're
wrong. Yeah, right. Cause yeah,
I smelled like old spice.
But these wounds there actually,
if you want to kill the bacteria in a
wound, they're different in the wounds of,
of people in India than they are hearing.
Oh Wow. That's interesting. Yeah.