Yeah, those are the old days,
man. We used to have a guy,
I remember they had a guy who chiseled
some tits into a, um, mine, a pine tree,
maybe a birch or something and people,
we'd go out there.
And do you recall whether that no
joke off at the base of the tree. He,
I think he used like a step stool
or something or sat on a barrel.
That's when you found all the
magazines and the woods. Oh yeah.
We used to have that.
But you go out on the train and somebody
will be using the tree and be like,
Oh fuck, I've got to walk
back home now. It's 100% real.
You're making this up. You have
photographs? This tree? No. Why not?
Do you know where it is? Could you
take us back there with a film crew?
I could take you back there with
a film crew. I bet. I bet it's,
it devolved now though.
How long does it trade live?
Go back there and touch the thing and
all of a sudden you can't find your way
back home. Where the fuck are we?
How does we're going in a circle
like it turns out that the tree got tired
of people jerk off on it so it evolves
some sort of a neuro toxic.
Then when you touched it,
it got into your bloodstream.
It distorted your perception of distance
and time and then they go skiing,
but do what if you would've come,
could divide.
They would've seen and could defy gravity.
What do you think about that? I don't,
but you know what I do think.
Imagine if it wasn't,
if come didn't just get humans pregnant.
Yeah.
Oh No.
That's what I think of a mass.
Calm frogs to chickens I
give everywhere you went,
you found God. Let's do it. Fucked a
turtle. You following some turtle person.
He got a rocking.
You can't think about that man.
You imagine if anything
could get anything pregnant.
Then a new combination was
born turtle people too. That's
what's next. Coy People.
Some do fucked a coy. Yeah, busted into
that. Cory. Mom knocked that point.
We imagine you're out there throwing
bread on your Koi pond. You're like, hey,
it has legs. What the fuck, man?
Somebody fuck one eat
fish up on the shore.
It's got a sign for you.
People see people see you at the pet
store shopping and they're like, Whoa,
this guy's shady is smashing.
If Ari fucked it and it came out and
we knew it because that always knows.
So it's like always knows on a Koi fish
with legs and it comes out and you're
like, oh sorry your business.
I'm going to Bali. You
Imagine? Yeah, I'm going to,
can we go find where we're turtle
babies on the other side of the world,
but if you had to make love to an animal,
what would it be?
If you think he had to go in and they'll
be something I could brag about. Yeah.
I'm not fucking anything sedentary. I'm
not fucking anything that's like a basic,
something ends up in the poultry
section or anything like that. No.
Be have to be a female.
What have you had gay sex with an animal.
Which animal would it be? That's not
gate a fucking animal, Bro. It's not.
I don't think that applies to your
fucking an animal that's more important.
If it's a like a male gorilla.
I think it's both. Aw Dude,
gay beastiality. Nobody's
going to be like, oh, remember
when you yes, they would.
They haven't let you off. The
people are mean. They going to go.
Not only did he fuck a chip, he fucked a
mail chimp and everybody would be like,
Jesus, Theo, bro,
you would never buy a beer again. You
put, you want to break the Internet.
You put a fucking video of me sneaking
up on a Cheetah and fucking it wrap,
wrapping a noose around its
neck and you're banging it
while it's clawing on yet.
Just trying to get away and you'll nut.
Nah,
I'm talking about putting on some Eddie
lavert or some Gerald levert and playing
some sweet music and just working on
their plan on holding it in place.
While that's all happening, I think if
you're good enough and general enough,
it'll stay. Wow. You don't think so?
Think about it to you for
a 10 match in it though.
I love to look at the
world through your eyes.
10 when they take you right to the
hospital. Whatever medication we're on,
we got to change it. We've got to fix this
pro. You should meet yourself then, bro,
you are extra terrestrial man.