I've talked to a friend of mine who's
from Brazil who has a completely different
take on the new leader of Brazil,
like he's more positive about it.
And I've talked to other people that
say he's a monster. Yeah. Um, I mean,
if people in Brazil are living
through the current chaos,
I can understand why they might go to a
detailed type finger to say it's going
to be messy, but he's going
to clean it up. Right.
But he certainly seems like
a monster. Yeah. And they,
they're experiencing some crazy
economic crisis as well, right? Yeah.
And it was the foster excrement growing
economy in Latin America was booming.
Yeah. It was just a few years ago. So
it's like this roller coaster ride.
We did a film that recently,
and uh, I might might get
the numbers slightly wrong,
but the amount of people that
were murdered in Brazil in 2017,
I believe it was,
was double more than double the
amount that were murdered in Syria.
Jesus Christ of 72,000.
Yeah.
And after the World Cup and Olympics,
the trafficking gangs and the,
the police malicious just retook all of
those areas that were pacified to attain
to protect the tourists during
the World Cup and Olympics.
So that violence has just come
right back to the fellows.
Say again. There's just so much shit
to pay attention to. Yeah. And Rehab.
The image of Rio is still, you
know, Sam or on the beach and yeah,
I've been a few times. Right?
Yeah. I've been over UFC events.
It's beautiful people.
Very nice, very friendly.
But then you go two or three miles up
into the hills to another world while we
drove.
When you land at the airport,
you drive through the favelas on the way
to Rio and you're like, Whoa, this is a,
this is a different kind of poverty.
And during the World Cup and Olympics,
they put billboards next to that road
to block the view of the favelas.
Did they rely on those billboards are now
starting to fall apart and you can now
sell, see it again? Yeah. Wow.
And you can hear it if you,
if you stay close to their,
you'll hear it. I mean,
we went into the village favelas
many times. We saw one guy,
he was suspected of being a
police informer. Um, so the,
the trafficking gangs had captured him,
slashed his leg,
so he was laying on the ground, put four
rifle to his head and just unloaded.
And his chin was still kind of where
it should be. But everything else was,
this is when you got there while
I, right afterwards, sorry. No,
we didn't witness it happening and we got
there right afterwards. But yeah, it's,
it's, I mean, hideous violence.
They are on a massive scale.
And also I got into arguments on the
other day about this, um, deeply racist.
Uh, you know, the, the, the rich
people are in Ipanema tend to be white,
European descendants.
The poor kids getting shot in the favelas,
almost all black. And if you walk into
a bar and if an email with a black girl,
everyone will assume she's a prostitute.
If you walk into a bar and if an
email with a black guy, everyone was,
she meets a drug dealer. Um, and
again, the exact opposite of,
of the public image of Brazil. Ipanema is
the more wealthy area because there is,
yeah, that's the very, the
very wealthy, Nice Beach, um,
area with all the Nice
hotels and apartment blocks.
But they still must get robbed all the
time down there. Right. It used to be the,
that the violence was separated
from the radio, which areas,
but there are now a lot of wealthy
Brazilians leaving because it's, it's,
it's affecting everywhere now.
I mean,
one of the experts we interviewed
in the last film said, um,
I believe it was one in
three Rio residents will get
caught in crossfire at some
point over the course of a year. I'm, I
might be wrong. I believe it was one year,
three year. Yeah. But it was a
massive, massive number. Yeah.
Fuck yeah. I mean, if, if
you're anywhere near a favela,
you'll hear it.
Most nights you'll head shots being fired
most nights and not like boom, boom,
boom. You know, you'll hear
a fight gung Jesus Christ.
How much time do you spend over there?
Uh, three weeks, I believe it was. Wow.
And what are you covering? We did a
film about the pacification campaign,
the police and army clearing the
favelas before the World Cup Olympics.
So we went back just to see,
just to sort of illuminated for people
to think that this is what Brazil's
actually lark and see what yeah,
what happened afterwards.
And those areas were abandoned as soon
as the World Cup and Olympics were over.