The Joe Rogan experience,
how do you think there's going to affect
things like competitive athletics?
Hugely. So, um, right now,
um, we have this problem,
someone like Lance Armstrong is, he
was doing, he's manipulating his, uh,
his body and what he's basically doing
is adding more red blood cells so that he
can carry more oxygen and people
feel that that's cheating. It's a,
it's a different topic that probably
everybody in the Tour de France was doing
exactly that when he, when
he went. Um, but what if it,
which will be the case, we're going
to be able to sequence the people,
let's say nobody's doing drugs and
we sequence all these athletes,
some of them will just have
a natural genetic advantage.
Their bodies will naturally be doing
what Lamstar Lance Armstrong had
manipulated his body to. Do
you know, that's happening
with a sprinter right now?
Yeah. Well that female
sprinters, high levels of
testosterone. Yeah. No. And it's,
I feel really sorry for her, but
we have categories. I mean, yeah,
you with your world and
in mixed martial arts,
I mean I think I remember it in the past,
there was some person who has,
who was kind of a
borderline on, on uh, uh,
between genders and we're just kicking
the shit out of all of these women in
cage fighting.
It's like we have these categories of
man and woman and we know that the gender
identities are fluid,
but how do we think about it when these
genetic differences confer advantages?
So if your body is primed to do something,
um,
maybe you could have like a Plato's
republic world where everybody fulfills a
function that you are genetically
optimized to do and that you could imagine
that being a very competitive
kind of a of environment.
But what do you do it for now
in something like the Olympics,
if somebody has this
huge genetic advantage,
should we let somebody else
manipulate their bodies?
There's a thing called gene doping in
order to change the expression of genes.
So your body to act like
you're as Jeanette naturally
genetic enhances somebody
else.
It's complicated.
Are they capable of doing certain
physical enhancements through gene doping
right now? Yeah. Like what can
they do right now known as? So,
so the way it works is so your,
your genes instruct your cells
to make proteins. That's, that's,
that's how the whole system works.
So you can change genes or you can trigger
the expression of proteins so you can
get people's bodies to behave
as if they had the, uh,
these periodic optimization. Yeah.
Yeah. And so that's why now the,
the World Anti Doping Agency,
I mean,
they are now starting to look
at gene doping and this is
the first time, uh, that,
that's, that that's even being
considered as a category.
And then there are other
people that have done that.
Are there people that have done
that successfully? You know,
I don't know the answer to that.
I know that [inaudible] is looking for it,
which makes me assume that it must
have done, but I haven't seen it.
I've looked for it and I haven't
seen any reports on it starts winning
everything. Which line is
so, so my, my rope, my uh,
one of my Psi Phi novels, Genesis Code
was about this. So China as you know,
has their system of their Olympic sports
schools and the way it works is they
test kids all around the country.
So let's just say it's,
it's diving and they identify what
are the core skills of a diver,
what do you need?
And then they go around the country and
they test kids and then they bring a
bunch of them to their Olympic sports
schools and then they, you know,
they get them all involved and then some
kids are the best of those kids and the
best of those kids.
And then you get with these champion,
that's why China advance.
So, uh, so rapidly,
but what happens if they're doing that?
But it's at the genetic level and there
are countries like Kazakhstan that are
already announcing that they are going
to be screening all of their athletes.
So the science isn't there yet.
So it's really,
it's impossible right now to say out,
well,
I'm going to do a genome sequence of
somebody and I know this person has the
potential to be an Olympic sprinter,
but 10 years from now that's
not going to be the case. Wow.
Yeah.
It's sort of going to throw a monkey
wrench in the whole idea of what is fair
when it comes to athletics. Yeah. What is
fair? What is human right? What is human?
Yeah.
I mean look,
it's not like people don't already
alter their bodies by training,
by diet, exercise, all sorts of
different recovery modalities,
cryo therapy, sauna,
all of it. Um, you know,
high elevation training,
all these different things that they
do that manipulates the human body.
But it's not like there would be kind
of crazy if you had sports but you
couldn't practice and
you couldn't work out.
Like we want to find out what a person's
really like. No practice, no working out.
And that's the thing is like we
are moving, it comes back to,
we were saying before about in
nature it's like we have this,
this feeling nature somehow
feels comfortable to us.
That's what we're used to is all this
stuff that you're talking about it,
nobody was doing that 10,000 years ago.
It's like, Hey, I'm, you know, I'm,
I'm running after a buffalo and so and
so as these boundaries change as the
realm of possibility changes,
then we're going to be faced
with all of these questions.
Even now look at a sport like
competitive weightlifting,
they have these like the,
the real competitive bodybuilding
and you see these guys in there,
they're monsters and then they have
these drug free guys and everybody looks
like a Yogi. And so it's still a
pretty big, they look pretty big,
but not compared to these,
these other guys.
The only way to get those freak
levels is to steroids. Yeah.
And so like how are we
going to pull these,
this and I think it's
going to be very difficult.
And so maybe we can have some
kind of natural area of life.
But I think that our, our model of
what's normal is just going to change.
Because like I was
saying in the beginning,
we set our baseline based on how we
grew up and that it seems about right,
like it seems about right to us
that everybody gets immunizations.
Immunizations are a form of superpower.
Imagine if our ancestor,
they couldn't even imagine immunizations.
What an unfair advantage when you
have 100 million people dying of,
of Spanish flu.
So we're this,
all of this stuff is scary
and it's going to normalize.
But how it normalizes is, is
that's what's at play now. Well,
the world has changed so much
just in the last 20 years,
but it feels like this is just scratching
the surface in comparison to what's
coming.
It was a,
people miss understand and they
underestimate the rate of change.
And the reason that they do that is
since the beginning of the digital
revolution,
we have experienced a thing called
exponential changes that you've heard of
Moore's law, which is basically computing
power roughly doubles every two years.
And we've internalized Moore's law.
And that means that every new iPhone,
we expect to be better and stronger and
faster and all these kinds of things.
But now we're entering in a world,
a world where we're going to have
exponential change across technology
platforms.
And so we think about,
well what does exponential change
mean in the context of biology? Well,
at the very, very beginning,
it's genome sequencing is, is,
is going to be basically a basically free,
but we're going to be able to change life.
And because we're on this j curve,
like when you think of what's a 10
year unit of change, looking in the,
in the rear view mirror,
that amount of change is only going
to take five years going forward.
And then two years and then one year.
And so that's the reason why I've written
this book cause I, we have to get to,
this stuff is coming fast and
if we want to be part of it,
we have to understand it and we
have to make our voices heard.
[inaudible].