When you look back at
emerging social media,
like we go all the way back to my space,
right?
My space.
You got Tom,
Tom was sitting there and you're
in your top eight and you know,
people would like post music that they
liked and it was never a political,
it was very often very surface.
And for comics it was a great
way to promote shows and it was,
it was an interesting way
to see things but it was,
it was like the like the seed
that became Twitter or Facebook or
it was one of them. I
think we, at least for us,
like we got more of our roots from
AOL instant messenger and Icq,
ICQ cause it was,
you know,
you remember the status message where
you said like I'm in a meeting or I'm
listening to this music or I'm
watching a movie right now.
That was the inspiration. And what we
took from that was being able to, like,
if you could do that from anywhere,
not bound to a desk,
but you could do that from anywhere and
you could do it from your phone and you
could just be roaming around and say,
you know, I'm at, I'm at Joe Rogan's, um,
studio right now. That is
cool. I don't need my computer.
I'm not bound to this chain, to this
desk. I can, I can do it from anywhere.
And then the other aspect of, of,
into messenger was of course chat.
So one of the things that the
status would do is you might,
you might say like,
you know,
I'm listening to Kendrick Lamar right now
and I might hit you up on chat and say,
what do you,
what do you think of the new album?
But now it's all public so
everyone can see it. That's,
that's the biggest difference. And that's,
that to me is what Twitter is it, Mike?
My space was,
it was profiles and you know,
people organized around
these profiles and uh,
this network that develop between
people. And that is Facebook, Facebook,
Facebook optimized the hell out of that.
And they scaled the world.
We,
we were something very
different. We, you know, we,
we started with that simple status and
then people wanted to talk about it and
we, we decided that it should
be on the same surface.
It shouldn't be subservient
to the, to the, to the status.
It should be part of that flow.
And that's what makes Twitter so fluid.