The joe rogan experience. See like if
you're booing a basketball game, Huh?
Maybe I got it.
I guess like there's something that's
so much more intense about a fight.
Especially like there's smart booze.
Like when someone does something illegal
or someone does something she could
stall week. Yeah. Or something. Someone
does something that's fucked up.
There's smart boots,
but then there's booze where guys were
just like facing each other and they're
canceling each other out.
Like you're watching a Billy high level
thing when these guys are trying to
solve what,
what do I have to do to connect on this
guy's fucking brainstem and knock his
lights out.
But we don't have to do is
marketing toward these casual
fans who are basketball
fans and football fans who aren't
really the people who are hardcore who
appreciate the martial arts side of it.
What these guys are putting into it.
You think so?
I think that just marketing,
I don't think they're marketing
towards any specific fan.
They're not marketing towards,
people don't understand that.
But I think that's the almost the same
thing cause they're just trying to get a
mass audience. And the majority of
people aren't people who really,
people say that though.
What makes you say they're trying?
Like what are they doing specifically?
Um, I feel like when they put together,
you know, fights, it don't necessarily
make sense in terms of rankings.
When they put the interim belts on,
on fights where don't
really need to be there.
You just know it's a marketing move.
Cause I think a, a title on a poster,
we'll probably sell that many
more tickets. Good point.
It definitely juices it up when you have
an interim title it like in marketing
dude, it's going like, oh yeah,
we saw this many more paper vision
and as the title and I don't know the
difference between the interim
title or a regular title.
A lot of the casuals don't know the
difference between Michael Bisping or
fucking doors. Samp yeah,
look, I'm with you set a bar.
I almost feel conflicted because I have
this part of me that's like a purist
that's like,
no,
it should be just like whoever number
one is versus the champion and we should
never fuck around.
That's how it was going for a long time.
If they were just like, oh, you know what,
we just set up Nick Diaz versus
Conor Mcgregor. I'd be like,
that's the greatest thing that's ever
happened and I don't care. I don't care.
I don't care if Khabib's one
72 fights in a row campus,
I'm flying to fight a
hundred out of 100 times.
I don't give a fuck where he's fighting,
who he's fighting.
It's just fun and it's exciting,
but let's get real.
I think there was something really pure
and it's beautiful, but MMA is that.
It's always going to kind
of figure itself out.
It is the greatest sport
because it's the greatest sport.
I didn't think it happened any
given Sunday. It's inherently built.
The marketing has sort of built
in already, right? So you can,
you can create a pecking order,
you can create rankings and I think
you can kind of just say, hey,
the pieces are going to fall where they're
going to fall and it's always going
to be super exciting.
And you see with the way they handle
Connor or certain guys, they definitely,
they threw that to the side. And I think
Conor is a great example of it as well.
Why they don't really care though.
Like I fuck it dude.
Go Do may whether they had it for a little
while, was that part of the promotion?
Yeah, they made millions
of dollars off that thing.
Everybody made a fuck load of money.
I mean,
may whether made hundreds of millions.
Connor made 100 million.
I don't know what the UFC made.
Everybody got fucking crazy paid and
then they started zoo for boxing and now
there are other offering,
uh, uh, Joshua and Joshua,
you're offering 500 million.
I'm crazy contract.
Apparently that might be bullshit. I don't
haven't asked anybody if that's real,
but I'm not surprised. They realize this
is a lot of money and promoting fights,
whether it's promoting MMA. Dana has
a big background in boxing. You know,
his son actually just had a,
a, an amateur boxing fight.
I saw that in his Instagram. Yeah, he
loves boxing. Fuck. Dana loves boxing.
So I always loved it. So it's not
unusual that they decided to go into it.
But with Connor it was like one of
those things where you're like, yeah,
that's what you're supposed to do.
If may with a really wants to fight
Connor and Connor has never had a
professional fight and you make a hundred
million bucks. Let's see, let's see,
let's see who buys it.
But I'm just saying as an MMA purists
were what's best for the sport of MMA,
that's not necessarily the best
move and not, oh it's not bad. Both.
It doesn't hurt it at
all because first of all,
it shows you that in the specialties that
there are people that have skills and
techniques and abilities that just
far exceed the very best MMA fighters.
And you saw that with Conor and
Floyd flood just fucked him up.
He just fucked him up. But Connor caught
them a little bit and he'd tell them,
tag them in the beginning and you could
say that Floyd wasn't going full tilt
and he probably wasn't.
I would say definitely wasn't.
He was definitely trying to wear him out
and get him tired cause he knew that he
relied and kinetic energy
for the first round or two,
but he's still got clip with a shot.
He did want to get clipped with. Sure.
I think Floyd wanted to see what Connor
was doing and he spent the first few
rounds like kind of taking in
data and like seeing like, okay,
what are you doing here? What Weird Shit
are you trying? But still I was like,
I did not think Connor was going
to do that good. Very well.
I thought it would be over within three
or four rounds and may whether it would
knock him out and he would just outclass
him in the fact that it went 10 and
then even landed some shots.
I, I was pretty impressed
with by itself. That's like,
it's not bad for, as a purist I'm
saying it's almost like it's the,
the way they're sort of letting
Connor run the show. Um,
I just kind of feel like the UFC sort
of always built this brand UFC. It's,
you know,
it's a cocacola of MMA and I feel like
Connor has basically become bigger or at
the very least as big as the
UFC. And he does, he did,
he doesn't give a shit tweet.
He tweeted out the other day,
I'm the boss and he was
promoting the video game like a,
they did a pull them up with Dana
white is the one of the characters. Um,
but I just feel like that
wasn't necessarily the best
thing for mixed martial
arts as a sport.
I almost feel like what they were doing
with isn't it hurt it at all? Yeah, maybe.
Maybe. I think it's, I think it made
it bigger. I mean it's like, dude,
what Connor created was
like a thing that's like,
it's just really hard dude.
Even when,
when he fought up Marcus [inaudible]
image as his first fight in the UFC,
and I remember,
I'll raise it,
there was like an energy in the crowd
about Conor fight and even know who this
guy was. And you're like, why
is this like such a big thing?
And then every fight was just a
bigger and bigger and bigger thing.
And then we create this thing where like
Dustin portrays like biggest fight ever
as against Conor McGregor and Dustin
had had way more big fights than him,
but still the big deal was that you're
fighting this guy. Like he just,
he would create these stages just that
it was the results. Like you put markers.
Yeah, he starts dust in the first
round slept Josie Aldo in 13 seconds.
It was all real accomplishments. No, it
wasn't. Why him fighting Floyd Mayweather.
It was interesting because he
was so exceptional as a striker.
But do you think that this,
I,
I give the UFC so much credit with
building con Conor McGregor because he
wouldn't have been able
to do that anywhere else.
Like the UFC is such a big brand that
he couldn't have been a belt warfighter
fighter and become, uh, you
know, a worldwide name the
way he is now. Probably not.
If it's, which is weird, it bell towards
a stupid name. They need to accept that
good for him.
They need to accept the money.