It's just,
it's very easy to just to just say,
you know what, that's enough for
me and find what is like for me.
Yes. Everybody's, everybody's
humor is different. I, I love,
I love, there's a, there's
a, there's a viral video.
It is, uh, this old guy
trying to hover board.
He's like, fuck, he's
gotta be like 69, 70,
and you know, his grandkids there
and he's like, lemme lemme try it.
Lemme lemme try it.
And his man gets on his
hoverboard and taste.
If you saw Mike Tyson
following a hover board,
his fall was worse than Mike Tyson's.
I've never seen somebody hit
their head harder and my life.
And I didn't laugh out of wanting
to see his old man hurt herself.
I laughed because it was stupid to try
to get on his hoverboard in the first
place. And when he got
up, he tells the kids,
why is it moving like that?
I played this video,
everybody,
because that should made me laugh.
Some people will watch and go, oh, no,
no. Some people will watch it
and go, oh, whoa, Whoa, oh.
And other than just DAB by 11 because
everybody's humor is different. Yeah.
Everybody's fucking hammer is different.
My humor is different.
Fall in makes me laugh. I don't care
who you are. Falling makes me laugh.
I don't give a shit who you are. If
you fall in front of me. No Shadow.
I'm holding a laugh. There's no shot.
There's no shot. You don't stand a chance.
If you fall in. Pardon me?
There is no shot that I'm not.
That was something son has
got to come out. Right.
Falling is funny.
I still think it's hacky.
I still think far too funny
when my kids fart. I laugh.
I still until this day is the funniest
shit ever to me. Guy Goes that Vu stick.
Get out of here. Stay gas. My little
son, 17 months when you fart, I laugh.
Something,
something within just the ability
to just be fucking silly and stupid.
Oh yeah. It doesn't always have
to have a meaning behind it.
Some shit is just stupid.
My eight year old farts on cue.
She thinks it's hilarious as well
as Jeanie. She'll tell you, listen,
I got to talk to you about some.
They'd go and she starts laughing.
She thinks it's hilarious.
She'll fall down on the couch.
The best thing in the world,
she can't stop laughing is the best
thing you're talking about as a kid.
That's all you got.
Cause you only bit as a kid,
you got nothing else but farts.
That's all you get.
That's all you got to make people laugh.
You should enjoy it. Yeah. This shit,
I still think it's funny folly,
but falling is number one for me.
Falling is number one.
My wife fell down the steps.
She got so mad because I didn't
rush to help her. I laugh.
She had a wine glass. Wine
was all over the, Oh my God.
One of the wars falls I've ever
seen in my damn life got up.
Her shoe was on one step. The other
shoe was all follows. Funny. I like it.