The Joe Rogan experience. Yeah, it,
the other thing too is that how would you,
let's just say things are going to
shit really quickly, right? Right.
There's a nuclear power plant that's
going to blow up any second 92nd.
How would you, are you like a, I know
you're an outdoorsy guy. You Hunt,
you kill harvest. As I say, sorry.
How long do you think you could survive
if things went to shit really quickly?
If you have to survive, you have
all the money you want, right?
But like how long do you think you
could survive in the wilderness?
It would be very hard.
It's not easy and not only that,
you got to get through the winter,
so you're going to have to build
some sort of a shelter. But he goes,
there's no winter here. There is
there. I mean, um, what's the called?
It gets here in la,
but in big bear,
which was only a couple of
hours north of here. Yeah.
I mean there's plenty of places where
you could drive in a couple hours.
You could go to big bear and then
you can go down to the beach.
You could experience the desert.
Yeah,
you can experience a lot
of different climates.
It would really depend upon where you
were stuck in what, what you would eat.
So the thing is,
if you want to stay in the La area,
you're dead because you're not gonna be
able to eat shit. There's nothing here.
Would you stay in your head?
Look, would you migrate,
give your kids in a way you gotta
get Outta here. So you'd leave,
you drive a Tesla, which
carbon away? What? No Way.
It was a big debate that I had in
the, in a crisis situation. Right.
Would you take the test though,
or would you take, would you take,
I have a Toyota Land Cruiser with
the VA gallon gas tank. Yeah.
I got an apocalypse immobile. But so
now I went through a big debate. I got,
I got shit on so much for this. I sent
the same exact thing, things say, listen,
and an old shit situation.
I would leave the Tusla behind argued
with you about that. Lot of people.
Uh, I leave it behind. I take
my pickup truck like Tacoma.
That's what I deal with.
Gas drive 100%. You know, in an
emergency crisis situation, uh,
you don't have access to the gap.
What if the gasoline didn't work?
You going to the liquor store,
you fill it up with alcohol.
We'll run where we had the hurricane
in Florida a while back now every was
saying like,
yeah,
the gas pumps wouldn't work because
the electricity was shut off and uh,
but the supercharger still working,
you could get to your destination still
and like Tesla's used less energy.
It's like at the end of the day I
happened to pick up truck with like two
shotguns and like five things,
the gasoline and be fine.
I don't understand that.
They also make tanks that you can put
in your gas tank, uh, in your, uh,
the bed of your truck rather.
The survival tanks,
they drive as far as you
want getting hundred miles.
Yeah. And they more and they,
you drop thousands of miles.
There's a guy who actually,
there was a podcast that I listened to,
this guy who is like an extreme prepper
and he actually made a trip with one
tank of gas. Yeah. From
Arizona to Canada. Damn.
He drove all the way up to Canada all
the way across with one tank of gas
because it's massive tank in the
back of his pickup truck. Right.
Feeds directly into his primary gas
tank. Yeah. Yeah. And you can get these,
they're like these survival
tanks and you know,
they'll host like hundreds of gallons
or also a toggle. I probably shoot,
I'd probably shoot at the
guy's car actually, I think
to do that. So I don't know.
All of a sudden you're
lawless. Yeah. Barbera.
I know the lights go off for five minutes.
Want to kill everyone?
You're starting fires shooting cars.
So, so then, all right, so you leave,
you take your family, right? You
have your kids. If your wife,
where are you going to go?
You hop in your Land Cruiser.
Where are you going to go?
You have a real plan. Oh,
what are you going to bring you?
Well,
you would have to bring things to start
a fire and things to kill animals. Right.
Those are the things that it would be
very important. I would bring guns, right?
I'd bring Bose.
I'd bring ammunition and arrows,
but I would realistically realized that,
first of all,
I'm not going to make more bullets
and I'm not going to make more arrows.
What am I gonna do and how long am I gonna
last? Giving marijuana? No. Okay. No,
no. I'll be just trying
to stay alive. Yeah,
but you'd also be trying to stay alive
for a long period of time, right?
You might want to bring it needs
the pain. No, really? What? No,
it's not going to eat that. I mean,
marijuana for pain relief. I mean,
I guess it works,
but that's not what I used to paint
night of the impending doom. Yours. Yeah.
You'd be freaking out even more. I'm
freaking out. Plenty. Yeah, maybe. I mean,
I just, there's no, there's not room.
I would bring water for
water purification tablets,
no food shelters and food
that would bring food.
I'd probably be food in the form of
a heavy duty bars like that take.
Don't take up a lot of space,
but dense and nutrient rich like a,
there's those green belly bars and bars.
Yeah.
Something that has a lot of calories,
high calories in a small package.
A small size. All right.
Where are you heading? Yeah,
exactly. Go ahead and go. Yeah.
You got to go somewhere where there's
animals and even then you're not gonna
make it and your kids are
probably not going to make it.
That's the real thing is it's true.
The idea that you're going to live off
of animals. This isn't the Serengeti man.
It's not,
it's not a lot of animals unless you're
somewhere where you can find a lot of
fucking animals. Right.
Like rabbits and shit.
You got to keep them like you're going
to have to kill them every other day
because they're not going to last with
the heat and your kids aren't going to
get a dead rabbit for short
dead rabbit. Yeah. They'll
eat a rabbit. Yeah. I'm like,
my kids will eat pretty much anything. You
have to start a fire. Yes. Really? Yeah,
but it's not easy. We had no, it's not.
If you have a string and a bow and
two pieces of dried wood and you know,
hardwood and a softer would, you can do
it. You can do it, but it ain't easy.
Like starting a boat with one of those
two months in.
That takes a little while, but it's not
easy. You're better off of the Flint.
If you have a Flint and a piece of metal,
you could start a fire pretty easy.
And also you want to bring with
you some Tinder. You want to, um,
if you have some dry Tinder,
Chapin that with you too,
but you're in for a world of
hate. Yeah. Now world of Shit,
if you want to really survive,
right. Those, whenever I
watch those survival shows,
which I love by the way, that they're
already into that shit, they're exciting,
right? Yeah. I'm in it. That shit I do.