Worse environment. I was on this,
uh, discussion about Kratom.
Are you familiar with [inaudible]?
I'm on it right now. Oh
Wow. Yeah. I just took some,
I fucked my knee up the other day.
I did something and uh,
it's been stiff and painful.
So I used to,
before I came here and then I just took a,
took six of them, see what happens. Wow.
10 once, ten one gram capsules.
I don't know how much,
I don't know. Can you grab that? Tell
you exactly what's in it. But uh,
now I get why people might think
it's a drug. What is the drug? Yeah,
for sure. But when I took
four, I was like, well,
I took two for the first time I took it.
I took two and a couple of
times I took to him like,
this is like a mild stimulant,
but then when you get into the range
of eight to 10 pills, it's like,
oh, this, this will
fuck you up. This stuff.
The stuff I take is urban ice organics.
And um,
see it says,
it says take two.
It doesn't say the amount of material
in the capsule. What's it say there?
750 milligrams. Okay,
so not quite at Graham.
Not quite a grim. Alright. It
seems like a a reasonable amount,
but they always construct these things
in these ridiculous dramatic oppositions.
Like it was me versus a woman whose
son had died of some Katam associated
overdose.
And it turns into a thing like,
what do you have to say to this
woman whose son died? And it's like,
I don't know. You know, there are people
that die from caffeine overdoses as well.
It's tragic that this happened.
How people died from this. Yes.
They have to have to take
an enormous amount. I mean,
I think a lot of people set up these
unrealistic expectations with these drugs
where they,
if they'd like a drug,
they want to say it's impossible for
it to kill anyone. It's impossible.
There's no possible way.
If you set that as your standard,
you'll always fail because people
will die doing absolutely everything.
Running, having sex, defecating,
aspirin, aspirin. Absolutely.
There's nothing in this world that
can't find its way into a human death.
So if people want to say,
and even you know, cannabis,
obviously people say you can't overdose
on cannabis and essentially you can't.
But if you look in the medical literature,
there are a number of these cannabis
associated fatalities. You know,
you can debate them endlessly,
but the point is,
once a drug enters a
large enough population,
there'll be a number of sensitive
individuals and someone will die.
It doesn't mean that
the drug is dangerous.
It means that it's unrealistic to set a
standard where if anything bad happens
to anyone, we have to decide that the
drug is dangerous and should be banned.
Yeah, I agree. I mean,
look, water kills people.
There's a lot of these hazing things
where the fraternity kids will be asked to
drink a shit ton of water and Oh yeah,
people have died from an,
a woman died in San Jose
a few years back from a,
a contest to drink water to get her son
like an x box or something like that.
Yeah, yeah. I mean, there's a lot of
things that are lethal, but the LD
50 for cannabis,
I mean,
you literally have to smoke your
body weight or something. Right.
It's something crazy would
be very difficult. Yeah,
but it doesn't mean that you couldn't
get so high that you did something really
stupid wind up dying. Right? Yeah.
Especially dependent upon the person
and the biological variability.
Right, right, exactly. And it's just,
I think it's also just as
sort of a bad road to go down.
People always want to emphasize the
safety of things. Right. In my opinion,
safety isn't the point.
It doesn't ultimately matter to me
whether or not something is safe.
I think we should have the freedom
to do dangerous things. If we choose,
we're allowed to ride.
Motorcycles were allowed to shoot guns.
You're allowed to go skydiving and bungee
jumping. All those things carry risks,
but it's assumed that any adult that
does them is aware of those risks. Yeah.
I couldn't agree more. I
mean it's, it's also who is,
if the society that we
live in was just you and I,
we were the only two people alive who
are you to tell me what I can do or me to
tell you what you can do.
It's ridiculous.
And so when you have grown adults telling
a grown adult who's informed what they
can and can't do, then it
becomes a question of children.
Well then it becomes a,
an an education issue and it becomes
a parental issue. I mean it's just,
you can't lie to your children about
the effects of certain drugs cause then
they're not going to believe
you about the really actual,
the actual dangerous ones.
Brilliant.
And this is of course reflected in the so
called opioid epidemic. Yes. Right now,
yes.
There's endless finger pointing.
Everyone wants to find a
culprit that's behind all of it.
And the easiest person to blame,
of course our pharmaceutical companies
because everybody hates pharmaceutical
companies. So why not
blame them? But you know,
and I'm not pro pharmaceutical by
any stretch of the imagination,
but I'm also not anti
pharmaceutical either.
And when you look at the way,
for example,
the New York Times is
covering the opioid epidemic.
It's always in this tone of
like documents were uncovered,
the show that executives at Purdue Pharma,
we're aware that morphine was addictive
as early as 1999 and it's like,
well, of course, of
course. They were aware.
People have known that morphine is
addictive for hundreds of years.
This is old news and this whole idea that
doctors were convinced by some letter
in the New England Journal of medicine
that said that Oxi content isn't
addictive, is absurd. These are all
morphine derivatives. Any adult,
especially in medically trained adult
should know that no matter what little
variation you make on that molecule,
if it's structurally and pharmacologically
and qualitatively similar to morphine,
of course it's going to be addictive
and that in of itself isn't even a bad
thing. It should be okay to give
people addictive drugs as well.
As long as everyone's aware of the risks,
as long as they understand the protocol
to get off of it. The you, you know,
there's so many people that get on these
things and then wind up taking them far
longer than they're supposed to because
it's easy to get hooked. I mean,
we need to at least have some sort of
responsible direction that these people
need to go to to get off of them
once they're on them. Because people
that get back operations, any,
anything where they prescribe
you a high doses of opiates,
it's a huge problem. I know many, many
people that have gotten hooked because of,
and in fact I should tell you
that my good friend Justin wren,
his wife found out about Kratom
because of you, because of your show.
He had a problem with his shoulder,
got shoulder shoulder surgery,
they put him on Oxycontin's,
he was fucked up on them and he was
having a really hard time getting off and
having the shakes really bad.
And Kratom is the only thing
that got him off of it.
Right.
And that's not surprising.
I mean this has been known for a very
long time in Thailand and that was
actually the reason that it
was originally prohibited.
I don't know if you're aware of that,
but because the government taxed opium
and people started using Chris Tom,
then they made Creton Elisa. And the right
way to say it, cause people say Kratom,
you're the only one I've heard say
Creton people in, it's a Thai word.
People in Thailand call it [inaudible].
So people in the u called Kratom,
it's Aye. It's also, they have, you know,
it's maybe it's a, something like that.
They're not going to go that far, but Tom
is closer. If you did, it would be weird.
But I feel I was, you know, yeah.
Like American people that say Ecuador,
Argentina. But it is Creton.
Yeah, Chris. Tom. Okay.
So we'll try to call it quits
or something close to that.
It's closer to that than Kratom.
Right.
And so the reason why it was made illegal
was because of the fact that it was
pinching some of the profits off
of the opium trade. Yes. Wow. Yeah.
That's fucked up.
And so this has been known for a long
time that it helps people get off more
addictive opioids. And
how does it do that? Well,
it's an opioid itself and a lot of
people don't want to admit or acknowledge
that,
but I think we need to get beyond this
idea that drugs are inherently bad or
opioids are inherently bad just because
the ones that we're aware of have a lot
of problems.
You know,
in some sense medicinal chemistry and
pharmacology and all of this are still in
a very primitive state and
there's so much to be learned.
So we're mostly giving people these
derivatives of morphine that have been
around for a hundred years
and there are better things.
We're going to continuously discover
less addictive treatments for pain.
And I think that the alkaloids in
Kratom are a step in that direction.
And then,
which is so tragic that they're trying
to now make it illegal because this is
something that as far as I can tell,
has genuinely helped an enormous number
of people reduce their intake of more
addictive and more dangerous opioids.
But one of the things that I've felt,
and again, my dose was not extremely
high, but when I was on it,
I was very coherent.
I was clear,
it was clear to me that was affected by
something. But uh, it felt kind of good.
It didn't feel bad. It felt a little, uh,
a little uneasy, like a little like, whoa,
the world feels a little weird right now,
but it did not feel like a,
I was impaired.
I know a lot of people who take
it an like a, I have a friend,
he'll take 10 pills and exercise,
which is just seems kind of fucking crazy.
Yes.
But he says he has a great workout right.
By taking that stuff before he works out.
Yeah.
I mean it seems to lend itself to a lot
of different applications in Thailand.
It's used almost exclusively for
that sort of purpose. In the south.
It's a drug that Labor is
used so they can, you know,
collected the latex from rubber
trees and just get their job done.
That's what it's about.
I mean,
that's what opioids are about
for a lot of the world. Um,
both in the United States and in
Africa and in Thailand is, you know,
people live hard lives and, and manual
labor is painful and repetitive.
And difficult and anything that makes
that a little bit more manageable.
It's a very important tool for humans.
I always felt like people that did
heroin or opiates or something like that,
we're on a very short road to death.
That that was my perception
when I was a kid.
And then I had a friend
who was a long shoreman.
They worked on the docks bring,
they would bring fish in and a fillet,
the fish for the market.
And um,
he worked with a guy that every
day at lunch the guy would go cop,
he would get his heroin,
he would shoot it up in his car and
then to go back to work. And I was like,
you'd go back to work and you're
like, Yup. He worked every day.
Like every day shut up. And every day he
worked like, yeah, who's never late? Nope.
Just did his work. Right. Wow. I
didn't think you could do that.
I thought you did heroin.
The next thing you know,
you'd just be on the floor in a fetal
position and your own urine and you just
would fall apart and die. Right? Yeah.
There's this idea that people sometimes
refer to is pharmacological determinism
that a certain drug has
to do a certain thing.
So alcohol has to sedate
and disinhibit you.
Heroin has to addict you and make
you a slave to it and kill you.
Cocaine has to be a euphoric
thing that's done at parties.
It's also very addictive. PCP has to
make you strip nude and run around,
uh, fighting constant and fighting
cops and punching holes in wood,
in fences. Um, but when
you look at this, you know,
anthropologists have looked at certain
drugs that are used cross culturally like
alcohol.
And what you find is this whole idea
of pharmacological determinism is
fundamentally flawed.
Drugs behave differently in different
cultures depending on the set and setting
of the user.
And so you find all sorts of instances
that are major exceptions to these rules
that we've set up for these
various drugs. For example, PCP,
which is arguably one of the most
ubiquitously maligned drugs in the world.
I mean, no one can imagine that PCP
is medicinal. But even to this day,
PCPs in schedule to not schedule one
like cannabis and LSD schedule two,
it can still be prescribed actually.
And that's because it had
a history of medicinal use.
There was even PCP psychotherapy in
the UK and in the fifties so this is a
something that most
people wouldn't believe,
but to those patients that were taking it,
then there is none of this cultural
association with PCP being a drug that
causes psychosis or makes you strip
nude who is simply another tool for a
psychiatrist to use and help people
release repressed memories or traumas that
they were afraid to talk about when sober.
Hmm. Well, we're seeing that now with
Mtma, right? I mean, and also ketamine,
ketamine, you being used as an
actual tool for psychotherapy,
particularly for people with depression.
It's having really good results. My, uh,
my friend [inaudible],
excuse me,
Neil Brennan a WHO's a hilarious comedian.
He's had struggles with depression.
Yeah. He got great relief from, uh,
from taking ketamine.
Right. And what I think is
really interesting is, you know,
this is often packaged as a
sort of psychedelic renaissance,
but I think in a larger context,
it's a drug facilitated psychotherapy
renaissance because this was not just
limited to psychedelics.
People did something called narco
analysis where they would give people, um,
sedatives like propafol the drug
that killed Michael Jackson or, um,
various barbiturates
or various other drugs.
And the relaxing effect would allow
people to talk more openly to a therapist
and it was considered very effective.
Now this idea of a psychiatrist injecting
you with a drug in order to help you
talk about your problems is,
it's unheard of.
I don't think anyone does it anymore,
but it used to be very common and I think
a return to that is going to be really
beneficial.