What's crazy is, uh, the whole,
this whole animal kingdom thing.
But one thing that scares me that you
were doing when I walked in his playing
these fucking shooter games.
Dude, that game is a real problem.
Jamie and I have been going
to war for the last what?
Two months and this died like two months
ago. Yeah. Maybe like that sounds.
I'm in full blown addiction owed now.
What is the throat like? Aye. Aye.
What's the thrill? Yes. Do you see us?
We're all sweaty and adrenaline shot.
Great ass time. I walked in, it looks
like a just finished working out.
It was like crazy. Me. Now we're
going to war. We go to war.
We're talking a lot of shit too.
We go to war. I tried, I tried.
We talk. It's fun. It's fun. When he
kills me. Talk Shit to me. It's rough.
You're like, God dammit.
He got me fuckers.
Is that a game where people can go
online and play with you to no, we don't.
We let the people know. We jump
online. This is the game. This is it.
This is the game. Yeah. Dude
is a fun ass fucking game.
It's called quake champions and people
right now listening and going, God damn.
And he's talking about that
way, but me and Jamie had
been, um, and Jeff are there.
Employee had been playing this fucking
see this isn't bad because they're like
characters. Like I was playing one
where it's like human beings like,
and when you shoot somebody,
like I got scared when you get scared
to go into the next room because you're
really that nervous.
Like it's freaks me out.
These shooter games have too realistic. I
grew up with frogger, dude. This is like,
you're always in like some
sort of a castle. Yeah.
And the people that
you're shooting against,
they don't look anything like a person.
They look like a cartoon character.
But the graphics are sensational.
But more importantly like the
game play is very precise. And um,
you, you have to have like real
hand eye coordination and skills.
Like you learn things like tactics,
you learn how to move around maps,
you learn how to control resources.
Controlling resources is giant.
Like that thing that guy just picked up.
That's like a 175 health and you want to
get all the armor that you possibly can.
Then you also want to be like clever
about weapons choices cause you're always
engaging at different distances,
different kinds of fights. He like,
sometimes you're stuck in like a car
door and sometimes you know you're,
you're in an area where
they can't shoot you,
but you can shoot them a few
of the right weapon. Man,
you need to bring back
to old school a tar.
That one red button that ran that one red
button did everything on the joystick.
You never killed a guy would a rail gun.
Once you kill a guy with a rail gun,
you'll understand. Wait, I don't want
to kill a guy with a real person.
I mean I a little, yeah, he's laughing
while you do it. When I shoot a champion,
if he jumps at me and I shoot
him in there with a rail gun,
we both laugh and he shot
me in the face of the day,
would a rocket and I was like, dude,
in the Mug, I was like in the Mug,
like right in my face,
and I exploded like my whole spring just
becomes a big red splatter. I'm like,
fuck, it's fun. I can't handle
it, man. It's too much for me.