Dude, you're running out of space to
tattoo. I'm going to tell you right now,
I'm actually getting tattoos on top
of a tattoos. That's outrageous. Yeah.
I just got this, uh, Lj for xxx.
I'm going to get an a, I'm working on
some new ones. I've decided to go back in.
You kind of like remix in
him at this point, you know,
like getting tattoos on top of tattoos.
Have you ever gotten lasered? Yeah,
once I had it like a new wife and I
divorced my ex wife and she wasn't really
stoked on the ex wife's name on me.
Yeah, that sounds like a problem.
So I lasered it cause it was right on
my neck and she always had to see it.
And um, but that's the only time I've
ever done it. I, there's nothing on me.
I really want to get rid of her. I'm
like, oh that it's all a story to me.
It all tells a story. It's like a moment
in time. And I got it for a reason,
but I was trying to be cool
and you know what I mean?
Trying to be respectful and make her
happy at the time. That makes sense. Yeah.
I mean it was amazing.
She hung in there all the way to being
married with another chick's name on your
neck. Yeah, that's true woman. True.
But in that regard. Yeah. Yeah. But yeah,
I love tattoos, man. They're
addicting you. I love him
too. Once I figured it out,
they didn't hurt at the age of 15 it
was on, I didn't let people tell you,
they're like, oh, it's so
painful. And then you get, when
you're like, wait a minute,
it's not so bad. This is like,
it's Kinda like a, a slight burn.
It's like being kind of
therapeutic to bed. I fell asleep.
I was getting tattooed. Same,
same. When I did my back piece,
I fell asleep and I had two
artists working on me at
the same time just because
I fucking hate wasting time. So they,
yeah, they did my back together.
They did my head together to either heads.
Impressive. Let me see the head. Yeah.
Let me see what that looks like.
When did you get that done?
I did my head like, I don't
know, six years ago. Wow. Yeah,
I started,
I had like a piece on the side of my
head that Mr Cartoon did back back in the
day. Love that guys work. Yeah. Cartoon is
such, he's amazing. He's got great shit.
He's, he is a legend. He's a
legend. Even outside of tattooing,
like low rider culture. He's, he's
one of the illest but um, yeah, he,
he did that and then
that kind of set it off.
I always had like praying hands on the
side of my head and then I shaved my head
and I've never grown my hair out
since cause I'm like fuck it.
It's permanent haircut,
you know.
But what is up there?
It's hard to see what all little shine
I have like Virgin Mary writes. Oh Wow.
Um, I think I have like a rose you
think you had on the, you know,
you get a lot of tattoos on my head.
I have like a transplant,
the gas mask on the back of my head.
I have one life. One chance. Um,
yeah. And then like some writing.
Wow. Now when you got burned,
did it affect your tattoos? Did you
have to tattoo over it? Yeah. So I lost,
I lost all of my tattoos on
my legs. Wow. Yes. I lost,
I lost my first tattoo ever,
was a dag nasty tattoo.
This hardcore band punk band that I
loved forever. And a bones tattoo,
which was my nickname growing up.
Um, but I lost everything on my legs.
So then they do like they do, it's
called that grafting. So they, oh,
and I lost some dead dudes when my back.
So they take,
it's like a cheese grater and they grade
all of your skin off your back and my
thighs and then they staple it to you
with pig cadaver and they will wait for,
uh, for you to start healing. Um, so yeah,
so I lost a lot of tattoos and then
I, I did, uh, like on my thighs.
You can't really see. I did, I did
memorials for, for though Chris Chain,
a Dj am who, uh, who all
passed away in the accident.
So I put them on my legs over the graph.
So you can't really see it. But yeah,
I mean I got out pretty well man. Like I
mean you can kind of see it on my hand,
my hand,
you can see it's discolored and stuff,
but for having almost 70% of my body
burnt, like you can't really tell.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
I can't really tell it all because
you're so tattooed up that up.
The pain of healing burns is
supposed to be excruciating.
It's the fucking worst thing ever.
Well for for me too.
I mean I don't think you guys ever think
about being burnt. I know I didn't,
I would just be like,
I dunno,
I just never think about
fire until you're on fire.
And then you're like, oh shit. And then,
and then the,
you know,
the treatments afterwards to like
do everything, you know, like, uh,
like they would put me in this big pan
that was literally about as big as this
table with different
people all around you.
And they would scrape all my burns with
a metal brush to get rid of all the
infection. Cause I had,
I basically, when I,
when I jumped through the emergency exit,
when I open the emergency
exit before the plane blew up,
I was in such a hurry to get out
of the plane and exit the plane.
I jumped right into the jet,
which is full of fuel.
So my whole body lit up,
you know,
so I had jet fuel just in my whole body.
Like I burped jet fuel for
almost like three months.
So they had it like that was the main
thing to get rid of the infection as they
scrub you with a metal brush to get rid
of all of it and all of the dead skin.
And then,
and then I did about 30
surgeries to repair everything,
like skin graft surgeries.
They saved my foot because at one point
they were going to amputate my right
foot. Yeah, it was wild.
I always have pictures that they're
going to have to amputate my right foot
almost didn't make it.
Was it because the way it was was it was
necrosis or like what was going on that
they were going to amputate it I think
because that was the thing that was most
soaked was,
was my shoes and socks.
I jumped into the jets,
you know, and I had done,
like I had exited the plane,
I'd started running,
I had started like ripping off my clothes,
just,
that's what my instinct told me
is just get rid of everything.
But little did I know I would still
be on fire because the jet fuel was,
you know,
I was soaked in it.
So I'm actually running
towards the highway highways
right on the side of me and
I just hear some guy yell, like stop,
drop and roll. And it just like,
I heard it out of all this chaos of
every sirens and everything and I stopped
dropping,
rolled.
And the only thing that was still on
fire was my feet and am came in, um,
pat and I'm out. So I think they were on
fire the longest too. So still like my,
I think my right foot is probably
like over 50% of it to graft. Wow.
Yeah. Was Wild. But, um, yeah, that
was like, I never, like I said,
I never even thought about it.
It's not something you think
about until it happens to you,
but being burnt is like a.