I was telling you guys before I had an
issue today where my credit card got
robbed and uh, you know,
whatever credit card fraud,
someone got ahold of my number,
which is really,
that's the one thing that people worry
about the most about shopping online.
Right. But I guess that could
kind of happen everywhere,
but you got to think that if there's
anything that has changed malls more than
anything,
it's gotta be the ability to just
shop online on your phone like Amazon.
That the fact that they figured that out.
I remember when Amazon came out and
it was just a bookstore. I was like,
who the fuck is going to buy books online?
You can just go to the bookstore.
This is ridiculous. What a
stupid business. Meanwhile,
that guy has more money than any
human on the planet. That's right.
Yet the poor bastards
getting divorced too.
I heard last night that there's
a rule and we lash Washington.
That everything that you make as a couple,
you have to split.
We've been together for over
25 years. Well, California,
California law is, yes, 50 50 well,
longterm marriages 20
years or 10 years or more.
It's 50 50 and that
includes downstream income.
You know from anything you did
that you're still getting paid for.
Say 10 years ago you wrote a book
or whatever Mrs. Bezos is getting,
he's worth a hundred plus
billion dollars. They said, wow,
so she's going to get half of that,
but probably going to,
because it's a lot of stock.
They said they're going to have to just
be stay friends because oh they better.
She should be super nice to him.
Even if he only gives her a quarter if
she's like, I got Rollin, I got wrong.
The richest people in the world now,
but after all these bookstores,
man in a business,
there's some irony that Amazon now wants
to start opening physical brick and
mortar stores.
That is kind of ironic,
but it does make sense though because
there are some brick and mortar stores and
I think that guy's a conquer. I think he
just wants to take over everything. Well,
why else would he buy whole foods? And I
was like, ah, the supermarket business,
I can fuck this up too. Well
automated. He can, I don't know,
maybe you could order whole foods
delivered to your house. I think the,
I ended up that's available yet,
but I think it is right. Yeah,
I was to say it now.
Most grocery stores,
even like all the Ralphs have home
delivery with it two hours to compete with
Amazon prime. Yeah. Wow. Are,
and if they don't do that,
you can just order it online and
pick it up. And I'll bring out too,
I went to pavilion's the other day and
they had a bunch of delivery trucks
parked in the parking lot. I was
like, well look at this. Like,
think of these cool delivery trucks.
Have to have that one store you can
walk in and there's no cashiers.
They just trust that
everyone's not stealing.
And I think they just are a comfortable
with a certain amount of theft.
Oh Wow. Hmm. That's interesting. Well,
they probably have cameras everywhere too,
you know? But it's, um,
the online purchasing
like that has got to put,
that must be putting the most,
as far as like the most impact on stores,
brick and mortar stores.
It's like the ability to purchase online.
It's got to be devastating for them.
Right. Totally. And up in Santa
Barbara, where I live now,
just a riding up state street this
morning, at the end of the ride, you know,
it's like the third,
maybe a quarter of the stores are closed.
I had a business empty and you
know, state street, Santa Barbara,
this was like the happened in place to be.
And I,
and a real estate friend of mine says, Oh,
well, let's see that store there. That's,
you know, $22,000 a month to lease.
Like, Whoa, okay. So you have to,
you have to have a retail outlet that's
really turning over the customers.
And there's a lot that just can't do that.
I mean,
you can't have an antique store that's
going to do that are a little knickknack
store.