Sleep like a baby. Like last night I
got the ring that I do my sleep squad.
I slept eight and a half hours last night
and I take a hundred milligrams of CBD.
I take a little bit of Melatonin and I'm
just out. But you got to take a lot of,
and you wake up kind
of groggy when you do,
but if you're used to that and you
know, like you get up, shake it off,
10 minutes later you're good to
go. What's the [inaudible]? Well,
probably just overstimulation
of the endocannabinoid system.
Here's like super relaxed, which I want
to be when I sleep. Of course. Yeah. Yeah,
yeah. It works. What about regular
marijuana? Does that affect your sleep?
Do you find it beneficial or no?
So CBD can enhance your deep sleep cycles.
All right.
Which is,
which is when a good majority of your
neuronal repair and recovery occurs,
THC allows you to sleep and it
actually decreases sleep latency,
how long it takes you to fall asleep.
But it does reduce the amount of
time you spend in deep sleep. Right?
So if you're, if you're one of
those people whose mind races,
who's hypercharged up when it, you know,
and you got to get to sleep at night,
use THC, like you know,
hit a vape pen or whatever,
but know that you might miss out on
some of the things you want during deep
sleep, memory consolidation, neuronal
repair and recovery. You know,
nervous system repair,
but it's still pretty decent sleep and
you're not getting as much of a reduction
in deep sleep as you would get if you
were to be taking like ambien or Vallian
or something that's literally just like
a sledgehammer for your frontal cortex
that knocks you out. But you almost
get no deep sleep. So if you do this,
if you were to get like a sleep tracker
and test your deep sleep levels,
you would find that with CBD
you don't fall asleep as fast,
but you get higher deep sleep levels.
And then with THC you
can fall asleep faster,
but your deep sleep isn't quite as high.
When you consider that CBD can
counteract a lot of effects that THC,
then that means that what you could
try is take THC to lie to fall asleep
faster, but then pile a whole
bunch of CBD on top of that.
And I've done that before too,
where just take a hit on a vape pen and
then take a bunch of CBD and shoot for
the best of both worlds. Folks that
are taking ambient, I mean that is,
I mean especially people that are
doing it virtually every night,
that has got to have a profound effect
on your brain's ability to recover.
I think there are a lot of people shorting
themselves on the life who are taking
ambien or Vallian. I mean I,
I think to start with sleep,
you need to rely on your
body's own internal chemistry
and that would be breath
work. Like I think everybody, before
they start taking whatever phosphatidyl,
searing and adaptogenic herbs and all
this shit for cortisol and before they
start taking Valium or Ambien
or anything else for sleep,
you should learn how to control
your physiology with your breath.
I think that's the most
powerful way to do it. I mean,
you Prawna your shock or
whatever you want to call it,
like being able to do things
like breath work, box breathing,
alternate nostril breathing,
uh,
even even holotropic like you can go
some very interesting places in terms of
DMT production by the pineal gland,
by just doing holotropic breathwork.
Like there's,
there's a lot of very interesting
things that you can do with your breath,
but I think that for getting to
sleep or for decreasing stress,
you start with the breath and then you
start to introduce some of these other
molecules.
But ambien Valium like in the era of
like readily available CVD and you know,
all the other sleep compounds that we
have available like Valerian and passion
flower and Camomile and you know,
all of those are what are called gamma
aminobutyric acid or Gaba precursors.
They produce inhibitory neurotransmitters.
Like God,
I don't understand why people are still
taking ambien and Valium because they're
idiots. Yeah, there's this addicted
to it or they just want a pill.
I mean that's essentially what it is.
They want some fat in their box
and they want ambien and Valium.
I don't know if it's the same folks,
but may times it is.
I think it's our president. I think
our president takes that shit. He,
I think he's sleeping with ambien. I
think a lot of politicians do that. Well.
They can't sleep otherwise. They're
fucking ruining the world. I, um, I,
I've found that if my brain is racing,
just completely concentrating on
breathing in and breathing out and
concentrating on just the breath itself,
like really being
cognizant of it and slow,
deliberate breaths in and out and in.
And now by doing that over long periods
of time, I've, I've found that I can,
I can pretty much calmed myself
out. You can, but that takes focus.
A lot of people are not willing to learn
how to do that because they want the
fast track out. They should take a drug
and pass out. That is the thing, right?
They just want a pill.
Yeah.
It's very unfortunate that those
things exist in that, that,
that sort of thinking is,
you know,
it's reinforced. Yeah. Yeah.
It's encouraged. In fact,
you know, all these ads and all
these doctors and different people,
well if you have a hard time sleeping,
I'll just write you a prescription.
And then next thing you know,
and I mean you look at the animal
world like they self medicate,
they'll use clay for
parasites and you know,
dogs leak grass for stomach issues and
you know that I guess birds now are
putting like nicotine and cigarettes and
their nest because there's some kind of
benefit to that.
And you see animals self-medicating,
you see our ancestors using
everything from you know,
cannabis to say loan cinnamon to you know,
all sorts of different derivatives
for thousands of years.
So it's not like supplementation or self
medication or the or the whole creation
of pharmaceuticals is something that's
unnatural or not unacceptable human
activity.
But once you start to use it as a crutch,
I think that's where you
run into issues like once,
once you deny the human body's ability
to be able to heal itself or to be able
to decrease stress on its own, you begin
to rely on these exogenous chemicals.
I think that's where he
started playing with fire.
I just wonder what's happening to people's
minds over longterm use of this stuff
where you're not going into these deep
sleep cycles and you're using it every
night because essentially
once you get hooked on it,
a lot of people have a really
hard time sleeping without
it. Yeah. Yeah. Um, I mean,
uh, they're shorting
themselves. Right, right.
I wonder what studies in the Emory,
it's learning like that.
That's where a lot of that
type of stuff happens. I mean,
it's the same thing with,
with um, uh, what's it called?
Glymphatic drainage like this,
this new drainage system for the brain
that they've just discovered in recent
years.
This idea that you actually detoxify the
brain during the sleep cycles and it's
even enhance when you sleep on your side.
They didn't looked at sleeping positions
in this thing called glymphatic
drainage.
And when you're not going through
proper sleep cycles or you're constantly
waking cause you're on your
back and you have, you know,
a lot of people have sleep apnea where
you'll look at their sleep charts and
they'll frequently wake during the night.
Or though you'll see periods where they
just get ripped out of deep sleep. Yeah.
You wake up and you don't have memory
consolidation or you don't have the type
of neuronal repair and recovery
that you'd want or you know, you,
you can't even short yourself on muscle
repair. You know, and, and there's,
there's probably a lot that we don't know
about just dreaming and its ability to
be able to do things like help form
memories or, or make, you know,
learning or experiences more deeply
rooted. But yeah, I mean it's, it's, it's,
I think sleep architecture is something
that just gets super fucked up in a
modern post industrial era.
We've got access to pharmaceuticals and
just take a sledgehammer to our heads.
Yeah, no question about it. And it's also,
there's been a lot of work done on
actually going to sleep with a problem.
It's whole idea of sleep on it.
Like there's,
there's actually something
real to that that there was,
there's some cognitive balancing
that's going on while you're sleeping,
while your mind is actually going over
whatever issues you might have and trying
to come up with a problem during
sleep time during your subconscious,
you don't want to know how
many times now I, and I'm,
I'm learning this as I get older that you
delay a decision or you delay replying
to an email or delay responding to a text
message or what have you until you've
gotten a full night of sleep on it and
the clarity that you get after that.
I mean he just basically think about it
a little bit before you fall asleep and
then you go to sleep and you wake
up with such a better answer.
The same thing with a lock on it, like
walk on it is another thing. We know you,
you make more nerve growth factor and
more brain derived neurotrophic factor
when you walk while you're learning. I
recently gave a Tedx talk and I just, I,
I have made the whole Tedx talk and
I learned the whole thing while I was
walking up on the farm
road back behind my house.
I just walk them through the forest,
pop out in the sunshine and walk up and
down that road and just listen to my ted
talk on my ear buds and give
my talk. And it's just, it's a,
it's amazing for the
brain. But yeah, I agree.
Dwelling on something before you go
to sleep. It does the trick. I always,
if I do that, I always have a
response the next day. That's kinder,
less emotional, more understanding,
friendlier, um, you know,
a reciprocating,
any,
any sort of good vibes. It's, it's,
it's really interesting. It's really,
it really interesting how there is some
sort of a wisdom that's a part it on you
while you're sleeping. There is, and,
and now what I do is I'll
think about what it is,
but I am a big fan of fiction before you
fall asleep and just let you escape to
a whole different world.
I took my kids on this giant tour
of New York City like we went to.