Her low freak bitches.
I hated dealing with actors.
I'd never been around actors and that
thing that we were talking about before
where people just like say things that
they don't really mean because they think
that you're supposed to say those things.
Cause there's like a pattern of
behavior that you chose to, yeah. Oh,
I thought he was amazing in that film.
I thought it was excellent.
I thought he had a lot to offer.
I mean,
there was a lot of that kind of nonsense
out here where I was used to real
people. I mean, I mean for
sure I was a flawed person.
I mean for sure I was rough
and I, I said I just, I wasn't,
I didn't have good decorum. Like the
way I communicated. I was a rough guy.
You know, I'd come from fighting and
then went right into standing up.
And this was only a few years later,
I'm doing this now.
I had my last fight in 89 so
this is [inaudible] 94 I mean,
this is just a few years after
that I was still very sketchy,
you know, so I used to belong. I
felt like I didn't belong there.
I felt like I couldn't be myself.
Everybody was like reading the
Hollywood reporter and variety on sem,
like the fuck you guys reading this shit
for like, it's like this. It was just,
the whole thing to me was like this weird
play that people were putting on where
everybody was trying to pretend to be
something so that they can get auditions.
And I remember going on some auditions
and dealing with some of those people,
casting agents that had all this power
over you and they exhibited it like they
exerted it when you were
in the room with them.
They didn't communicate with you like
you're a person and I'm a person.
They communicated with you like you want
something from me and I don't know if
I'm going to give it to you.
Hmm, let me see what you do.
It was just the way they did. It was just
so shitty. It was just, it was gross.
It was just, there was those fun,
oh, it's gross. I mean, this is,
this is the thing that people have.
The real problem that people have with
his Harvey Harvey Weinstein situation is
not just that the fact that he was a,
a piece of shit to all these women,
it's his position of power that
he had over them that he exerted.
He got himself into this position and
then use that position to on some, I mean,
according to Whitney Whitney Cummings
was talking to me about that. She's like,
what you're hearing is all the women that
said no to him. He, she's like, that guy.
Fuck, fuck the top out
of all, fuck the column.
And it was part of the deals that he
gave and they even went after one of the
girls.
He was fucking that girl from Donnie
Brasco and she did the movie with the
Gretchen Mol. Yeah, she did
rounders. Oh, I remember her blonde,
cute thing that if you watched Donnie
Brasco, she's with Donnie Brasco.
She ain't got a fucking line to that
movie. Not Aligned railing. She's not,
she's an extra in that movie,
basically Sonny black girlfriend.
But when you see her in fucking whatever,
she's got a bunch of lines now and it
was because she was fucking high. We,
they just went after a couple of weeks
ago. Gretchen Maag who wasn't met,
who went after just, you know,
Angelina Jolie and the truth.
Oh they're all saying that this is the
reason why I had dick suck cause listen,
they all got to suck a dick virtually.
Look,
I had heard that there was a lot of them
that were actually very successful that
fucked him. I mean this was this, this
guy's thing. It's, it's Kinda, it's,
I mean it's fucked up and it's dark.
But once that gets going and
once that's what he does,
how do you stop that train? Other
than what they did and they all knew,
they all knew and nobody opened the
fucking mouth. So you can suck my dick.
A couple of them opened their mouth.
A couple of them get,
they got swept under the carpet
and that's always going to happen.
But I'd rather fuck it.
You know the rest of these,
like Angelina and the rest of these
people, listen, I'm over brother.
I don't want to hear this shit no
more. It's, it's, it's amazing.
Like just the bullshit that these people
creating that world. You're right.
When you go to these casting
things and you see these things,
you see the fucking bullshit.
It boils out of a man. Well,
it's one of the reasons why
people in this town are so crazy.
It's because their insecurity
to begin with, right?
The only reason why
anybody becomes an actor,
like why people want to be famous,
not the only reason,
but one of the main reasons why people
want to be famous is because at some
point in their life, they didn't feel
valuable. At some point in their life,
they felt discarded. They felt
abused, they felt ignored.
And they had this it in
escapable need for attention.
This,
this whole that cannot be filled.
And that was the driving force
that led them into acting.
Where would they could be on that stage
and everyone was looking at them all
eyes on them while the microphone was on.
And the words were coming out of their
mouth and they were in the play or in the
movie or doing standup even.
It's a lot of the same stuff
that propelled you and I
being ignored as a child,
you know,
like feeling like you were nothing and
then realizing that when you're on stage
man then your something like that person
up there with a spotlight on them,
that person's shining.
That's a something person that's not me.
I feel like a zero.
But that thing that leads you to become
an actor want to become famous is also
like it's,
it's so fucked up with acting
because you have to get chosen.
It's not like music or like stand
up where you can look at, stand up.
All you have to do as you do
open mic nights, you get funny,
you build up an act in and
people come to see you. You see,
you build up a career and
the next thing you know you,
you become a successful comedian.
That's what happened to you.
That's what happened to me. But with
acting you have to get chosen. You don't,
you don't have to work.
Like if you do plays,
nobody has ever going
to fucking see you ever.
You're never going to
make it out of place.
Nobody's going to see famous play actors.
Nobody gives a shit about them.
You have to be in movies, you have to be
in television, so you have to get chosen.
So you have this whole chain of like Hume,
maybe I'll pick you,
but I'm not sure.
Are you the one?
And so you have to develop this sort
of personality that fits in with their,
what they're looking for. You have to
mold your sensibilities and your ideas.
Like there's a lot of people that are
in Hollywood that don't have opinions of
their own.
What they have is a series of opinions
that they've adopted and adapted because
they think it's going to
lead them to be successful.
[inaudible]
yeah.