Would do things in the FBI would let
them get away with it because they were
providing information that was the whole
ball. Exactly right, and he fought.
Two guys died in prison wrongly. By the
way, this guy's not a fucking good guy.
I know. He's a marine and decorated marine
in Shit. They make those sacrifices.
They make those decisions where they're
just going to like help a person who's a
criminal because they're
criminals providing information
that can allow them to
get more criminal large,
wide.
He was providing all kinds of shit
about the guineas and he sponsored.
That was a great movie too, by the way.
Nice to train a guy who was one of the,
he's Hitman. Dana White. No, no,
no. Tito. I see like a threatened,
he had to move out of town. It was a ball.
Joe Wasn't balls. Baltar related. Yes.
It was both elated.
When I was teaching taekwondo,
I had one of the guys
that was in my class.
It was whacking people for what he Bolger.
He was asking me,
if you want to kill somebody with your
bare hands, where would you hit him?
I was like the neck. I was like 18. I
was like, oh, he goes, correct Joe? Good.
Yeah, I like that. Who was it, Kevin? Uh,
no, no, no. But you know Kevin, you know,
he went away to this, um, now the top kit.
Yeah. All related. All of them together,
you know. Um, this guy was a
different guy. This guy, this
guy was, he went away too.
But I mean, he went away forever.
He was one of those guys.
Like they caught him with blood under
his fingernails and he was working with
white. Yeah. Yeah. Well there's
a lot of guys that were, I mean,
it was a big organization when,
when we were kids. I mean,
everybody knew it was a big org. I mean,
it wasn't a fucking secret. Oh No. Oh,
I know. How did Hannity's attempt
to link Mower to Whitey Bulger?
Hold up this article in the Boston
Globe. So that's not true. What ever.
It's the FBI. He wasn't, wasn't
there. It wasn't there then. Oh,
he wasn't at the FBI.
Lower serve the US attorney's
office in Boston from 82 to 88,
his chief of the criminal division,
first assistant us attorney and acting
us attorney for more than a year.
During that time,
Bolger ran a sprawling criminal enterprise
and got away with murders because he
was a longtime FBI informant who
corrupted his handlers, the FBI.
He corrupted his handlers.
I love it.
And the FBI and the New Guinea to
know organized crime strike force,
a prosecutor prosecutorial unit that
worked independently in the US Attorney's
office reportedly, uh, reported
directly to the Justice Department,
used Bulger to build cases against the
mafia and give him a pass on its own
crimes.
The FBI is corrupt.
Relationship with Bulger was exposed
after he was indicted on federal
racketeering charges in
1995 became a fugitive.
He was captured 16 years later, I
would hear, you know, so, uh, yeah,
it was captured in Santa Monica. And, uh,
so when did Mueller says did mujer no,
the four minute had been wrongly
convicted and look the other way,
there's nothing linking Mueller to that
case. According to several attorneys for,
for the men volumous court records and
a former federal judge who presided over
their wrongful imprisonment trial in 2007,
the US District Judge Nancy Gertner found
the FBI deliberately withheld evidence
at the foremen were innocent.
The bureau helped cover up
the injustice for deck cheese,
Chrysler fucking hate
reading shit like that.
She ordered the government to pay the
men and their families 101.7 million.
Okay, maybe worth it. How
long did you guys go away for?
Let's be honest,
you're never going to make a hundred
millions chicken scratch too.
All got 100 million. If every one of
them got 100 million. I mean I'm, I'm in.
I mean,
how much time do you have to do?
How many times do you get fucked
where you're in jail? How's it?
How bad money per load?
Fuck man.
So maybe it was just a rumor
that he was a part of that. Well,
like you said though, let's, the
FBI, soon as a story broke shut,
they call the paper and said, listen,
get your facts straight. Well,
how crazy is it?
The FBI covered up the information
and knew those guys were innocent.
That is dark.
Who went to jail for that?
Did the guys who covered it up
and go to jail? I'm not sure,
but a couple of them died. You can't
died in jail. Two of them died in jail.
Oh,
you know they caught him because his
wife was yelling and shit all the time.
Yeah, she was cocoa. He had
fucking cash on the walls and shit.
I used to sell dope,
meet door to door when I,
before I started comedy and I used
to go to fuck, I went the hell,
not one where I was and I would,
I would want the white people look at my,
I'd take out my shit and they go,
that's slapped up.
Break sound like 40 bucks a pop,
get the fuck on.
And then somebody explained to me, you
know what the hell is like, why he bolts?
Wow. So you were selling
meat in his neighborhood.
Fucking same in East Boston.
I knocked at the door a couple of guys
and revere that we'll get like fucking
connected. My buddy l know who
they were and shit later on. Well,
they probably knew
people from meatpacking.
They've probably got it right off
the books of course. And I'm like,
I'm doing my little spiel there
for a boy. Look, you know,
a fucking boiler room operation. Now you
break it down per mail, it comes out,
they're three bucks a week and
they're doing the math in the head.
You could tell they were like bookies,
you know,
I feel like that's like 40 bucks a pump.
Get the fuck up.
My steps wasn't really that much, but it
was, it was ridiculous, you know? But uh,
and I was in Rhode Island, a
banging doors and, and, and uh,
I got the same response and I looked down,
I see in the streets,
the lines of the streets
are red, white, and green.
I was in federal hill and providence
with the mafia stock. Look at that sign.
Look at that article. Look at this
Whitey Bulger, Santa Monica high.
That was full of money.
It's still brims with mystery.
He was living in like a normal
apartment. I know. So weird.
He had $822,000 in cash and valuables.
Wow.
Jesus Christ. I liked that
movie. I thought Johnny Depp
was great. And uh, yeah,
he was, he was great in it.
Yeah. That's a creepy dude. Yeah.
He was as creepy as they get.
It's just amazing how much corruption
was involved in that case. Yes.
And at which the federal government was
a part of it and they let that monster,
they let them thrive. Yeah. Yeah. So it
makes you wonder about the FBI today.
Well, it should make you wonder, shows
what they're capable of it. That way.
Whenever you're doing that,
whenever you're allowing someone to
commit murder and deal drugs to get other
people that are committing murder
and dealing drugs, like what?
Because they would just want it.
They just look what happens with
cops in this is very unfortunate.
But this is just,
is just what happens when you have a
a game and the game is arrest people.
The game is when, right. You have a
certain amount of calls you have to make,
and if you could make more callers
because you're in bed with a bad guy,
especially if maybe you grow up in that
neighborhood has always been kind of an
accepted part of that neighborhood. Yeah.
That Guy Conley grew up with one. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Exactly. It makes a
sneaky little deal. Yeah. It was,
Sam had lawyers. It's all about you
have to have it. It's like sports.
You have to have a winning
record. Yeah. You're not going
to succeed. So they, yeah.
You know, play outside the rules. I mean,
that's one of the reasons why cops and
people have such a weird relationship
because they're always looking to arrest
people and [inaudible] cops talking to
her like, ah, I don't put me
on your record. I'm on. Yeah.