Breakfast with their own spinning
shit. Now, Hamas, Nick Diaz,
EOD said, man, he said, I want to
hurt nobody. I want a party has done.
Really? Yeah. For him, man. He is.
Is done. Yeah, because a Anderson,
someone was talking about Anderson
versus nick and Connor said,
I'll fight Nate on the same card. And then
Nick said, yeah, I'm not fighting any,
but I don't want hurt nobody.
He goes, I just want to
party. That's cool, man. Yeah.
He was for him. Fucking amazing career.
You've got to remember Nick Diaz fought.
He was one of the youngest
guys to ever fight in the UFC.
I believe he beat Robbie Lawler
when he was 20 dude, he's beats you.
Look at his resume. It's
impressive. The guy said he's flat.
He's been doing for a hot second. He's
deserved. Yeah. Turning to survive.
Hopefully financially he's good too.
What do you think of that?