Be careful and walk
this line between just,
just completely bring them in but not
trying to change them into who you are.
Did the six year old already have
things he was really into or sports or
activities or, yeah, he was,
well the funny thing has sun is really
athletic and I'm, I'm really not.
So I know you guys are, but I'm
not. I'm so Nomis and me especially,
he's an acrobat.
You saw what I was doing yesterday
cause an animal. But uh, but no,
he's really athletic and he's just always
been good with, with all of that stuff.
And it's funny for me because
I wasn't that kid at all,
but it's great for me cause I'm like,
he's able to do this stuff that I
wanted it so badly when I was little.
I sucked at sports and I so want him to
be good at sports and he's really good
at it and it makes me, what does he
play? Well, he, I mean whatever he plays,
he's just tends to be pretty good at it.
So he played flag football for a while
and he's playing lacrosse now and he's
played soccer.
Keep him away from Lacrosse and football.
We were just playing it with
Brennan shop the other day.
I had no idea how many people get
knocked the fuck out playing lacrosse.
Really crossing guard island man.
Why Lindt?
We were saying like there's
a difference between this,
even in football in that they're
striking each other. They're allowed to,
they're allowed to hit each other with
the stick but they're also striking each
other with elbows,
the running in and they have the stick
in their hand and they're elbowing each
other in the face as the running.
I mean Whoa Shit.
It's a crazy amount of force if they
generate and these kids are getting
flatline touch.
Cause I had Dale Earnhardt Jr
here today on really Nice Guy,
great guy.
Um,
suffered 12 concussions over a
period of four years racing. Yes.
And has like some significant brain
damage because of it that he had to go
through a therapy for to help them like
to the point where he was walking and he
had a hold on to things because it's
balancing so fucked up. He couldn't,
couldn't just walk, couldn't get off
the couch and walk to the bathroom.
He had a hold on to like a
table and a chair and hit him.
Make his way through all of this from
concussions and you know what they're
getting in Lacrosse so they're going to
get football. It's all the same shit.
Head trauma. It's head trauma.
Yeah, so I'm a terrible parent.
My kids go to a very nice school.
It's a great school and we
went to a football game the
other day where the older
kids are playing football
and I'm just sitting there.
All the other parents are having a
good time and I'm like, brain damage,
brain damage. There's some brain
damage, there's some break. I'm like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
These are kids.
They're kids running at each of the
full clip, smashing and withdrawn.
It fall to the ground.
They see the kid get up slow and
hope put his hands on the ground,
he's all fucked up. I'm like, this is
crazy. Look, you always felt like people,
I always felt like lacrosse because my
high school had lacrosse too and I always
felt like it was way crazier ones
cause I didn't know about it.
And then I'm at this school
and they have it and I'm like,
this shit is nuts because they have
stiffness. Yeah. And they're just,
Oh yeah, of course. Yes. If
you're a football player,
you can become some Herschel Walker type
character and become a baller. Yeah,
that's true. But you got no shot.
If you're a Lacrosse player,
I love when they interview
like all the guys in the NFL, they're
like, uh, the young guys, they're like,
you know,
all this evidence is that your lifespan
is going to be way shorter and it's
going to be probably horrific at some
point because of the impact of what you're
going through playing football. You
know, what are you thinking about that?
They're like, Shit's worth it, man. This
is awesome lifestyle. Nobody is like,
you're getting some guys
that you see retire early,
which was unheard of 10 years ago guys,
one guy came out,
played his rookie year and retired,
you know,
you're getting guys early retirement.
Um,
some guys play finish out a contractor
up for a big contract and they're out.
Yeah, that's happening. But
there's still, you know,
there's no shortage of guys who are like,
I'll take the guarantee whatever my
signing bonuses and take some brain damage
with it.
That's how our brains work.
Our brains are designed to not have
that kind of foresight and you get much
older. Of course you're like satisfying
me now. I don't know what that is,
but you can tell people, hey,
whatever it is you're doing right now,
this is really going to
cause you a reference
when like today. No.
Well fuck it. You know.
Well that's the same way we deal with
climate change. Literally the same thing.
People with driving around with
cars blowing smoke. I like, yeah,
one day we'll have every fucking fix it.
It's going to be a real proud,
like you tell us what can
be a real problem here on
earth and like 300 years and
they were like, that sucks. Whatever,
whatever. I won't be here Bro.
Or even 40 years, sadly. Yeah. It will be
like, all right, there's also the issue,
we get a lot of head trauma. They
get very impulsive and they, um,
they don't make good decisions anyway,
you know? So even if, you know,
even if they could have the foresight,
they would be,
probably wouldn't make good decisions.
They're don't,
they're not thinking rationally. And
they did some study. What was that study?
Jamie? We've referenced
this before where they, um,
they looked at kids that play football
literally from pop Warner all the way
through college. And how many
of them have CTE? Really? Oh,
Jesus Christ. It's
stunning. See, I, I always
felt like my,
my point of view on it was always like,
I played football fourth
grade through high school,
right. And I always just like,
man, that's why you're so fucked up. I
know, I know. That's what I'm fucking,
but I just feel like, you know, the, like
you have definitely some big, uh, in a,
in an amateur career, you have
some, you can think back. Like, man,
I got my bell rung a Bell Rung.
I don't know. I mean probably,
I mean, here's the thing, in fourth
grade and fifth grade you're like,
that doesn't happen really. I
mean, kids are like, you know,
walking up and like wrapping up slowly.
Did you,
you're playing with kids who will
eventually not play football even in sixth
grade. Right. You know,
so it starts to be you,
you might have like a stud on a team in
middle school and still a bunch of guys
who won't play in high school
and then in high school. Yeah,
there's definitely some, uh, athletes
that stand out for sure. I mean,
those are the kids that are eventually
go on, but you play teams are,
there's weeks where you're just like,
no one is really good on this team,
you know? Um, and you'll have a
game where you'll feel like, yeah,
I mean there was a couple,
I've got a couple good hits in,
there was nothing really of impact.
And then something will stand out.
Like you'll play a school that has like
an all state are all American player.
You're like, Holy Shit, that
guy fucking fucked me up bad.
And, and you remember it. I
mean, I remember it to this day,
some of those like really
stand out guys and you're like,
that hit stuck with me. But that's once
a year that you play that guy, right?
Or that you remember a school that good
and then if you don't go on to play in
college really feels like kind of a,
I dunno,
a risk assessment where you're like,
I didn't feel like that was, you know,
do I have damage? I don't know. But
I mean, once you get into college,
football is where I feel like that's
where you're really playing with really
good athletes.
It's a friend of mine,
a guy in his neighborhood.
I'm a kid who was 21 committed suicide
and he was a college player who was about
to go into pull up into the pros.
He was 21 years old really. And um,
the uh, significant CTE,
like just really ravaged.
He every year a player played tackle
football under the age predicted the early
onset of cognitive problems by 2.4 years
in behavioral and mood problems by 2.5
years. Yeah, but there's a
study. Wow, this is okay.
Average study found that 211 players
who diagnosed with CTE after death,
who played tackle football before age 12
suffered from cognitive behavioral and
mood symptoms earlier than those players
that didn't start to play till after
age 12. Wow. They're saying that, okay.
Study included 246 former players,
211 of whom were diagnosed
with CTE after death.
That's insane. Well, in college there's,
there's definitely,
there's no such thing as getting around
real high impact hits. That's it.
Those are all people that know
how to play. They're all athletes.
What they're realizing now is that sub
concussive trauma is what's responsible
for the majority of brain damage.
What's subconcussive you're not
getting a concussion. Oh yeah,
he just getting rattled.
Yeah.
So getting rattled where it's not even
fucking you up, but over time, over time,
that and multiple hits that are just not,
they're not knocking you out that just
Jocelyn, you, you can always happen a lot.
Yeah. Even get it from getting
hit to the body. Right.
You get hit to the body and your,
your head snaps back and you,
you don't even get hit in the head and
you're like throwing up and your head's
all fucked up and you're trying
to figure out what's going on.
It's because your brain's been mushing
around inside of your head. Yeah.
The thing that I remember too,
the thing that stands out is when you,
cause it's such thing as like bracing
for a hit and then feeling it and you're
like, fuck, but when you don't see
someone coming, oh yeah. Oh yeah.
It's like a fight punch
coming. Oh yeah. 100% yeah.
Yeah. It's, it's, it's dangerous.
You guys are saving my child's life.
I'm telling you right now.
He's good because I don't
know that much about Lacrosse.
I had to actually like
Youtube Lacrosse to be like,
how did you hold at the video?
Cause there's some videos of some fucking
hits that we were watching the other
day.
And Brendan Played Lacrosse in college.
He played Lacrosse in college
and football, Jesus. And
then he fought in the UFC.
So his brain looks like a walnut.
It's gotta be man. You talked to him,
you kind of know. Yeah, it's a,
it's a crazy fucking sports.
Oh watch these guys just over and
over again. These guys getting Kol,
boom, boom. See that? I mean
they're smashing each other.
The impact is horrific. Oh
fuck it. That boom, this,
these are strikes. This is like me
kicking somebody in the head. This is,
this is not much different
than a kick in the head.
You're just playing him with an elbow.
But the amount of force,
so these guys are getting kicked in the
head with these helmets on and if you
think the helmets protecting your head,
that shit ain't protecting anything. Boom,
look at that. Boom. All right, look, I
don't know anything about this stuff,
but I've thought for a long time. Hard
helmets. Ooh. Gotta just make it worse,
right?
Well,
it makes you more confident that you got
slam your head into somebody and then
you don't realize how bad you're
getting fucked up from that.
You know it's your head.
When you get hit in the head,
even though you have a helmet on,
it's not going to crack your skull.
Your brain still still subsist.
It's hitting you.
You get serious punishment
smashing around in there.
You're all the connective tissue.
It's like, oh, it's awful. It's awful.
Boom. And this is coming from
a guy who's probably seen,
I probably see more people get fucked up
than 99.9% of the people that have ever
lived in terms of like being there live
when someone got the fuck beat out of
them.
I probably see more people get the fuck
beat out of them than almost anyone
that's ever lived in history.
It's probably a small handful of people
that have seen more. Sure. So yeah.
How many fights have you called?
Hundreds. Thousands, thousands.
It least more than a thousand.
Probably 2000 but then I've seen more,
I mean,
I've seen a bunch of live and when I was
competing I saw a bunch of people get
fucked up. I mean, it's
just, I've seen it a lot.
It's just that when you can
avoid that, avoid it. You know,
especially something like Lacrosse, you
can't, can't make a career out of it.
Like get out of there
because they actually just
started because right now I'm
used to like kids soccer where they're
just running around chasing the ball.
It's cute. It's fun to
watch. And uh, and yeah,
my son just got into Lacrosse and we play
catch with the lacrosse stick and it's
great. We have, we have a good
time playing catch with it. But no,
I haven't seen him get him about
tennis, man, soccer, even soccer,
which you think you know, like
who, who's getting hurt in soccer?
Soccer from heading the ball, just
heading the ball, the ball flying.
You hit it with your head.
Soccer players are suffering from CTE
to the point where they're starting to
minimize the amount of heading
they do in practices. Really? Yes.
This is what we're finding out
about brains like this is, you know,
there's a good friend of mine, Dr.
Mark Gordon, who specializes in CTE.
He deals with a lot of soldiers coming
back and a lot of them that are, um,
like my friend Andrew Marr, where they
would blow open doors, so they'd set up a,
a charge on a door and step
back and the door blow.
These guys mean he didn't
even get hit with anything.
Or maybe I eeds like that are nearby.
Those guys suffer significant brain damage
and it's just from the impact of just
getting shook by an explosion,
not even anything actually
hitting them in the head.
Which high school sport as the most
concussions? Is it soccer girls,
soccer girls soccer,
cheerleading had rates
CD boys football by 2015.
Wow. I know. When you stop
and you look at those, uh,
like when they're going to commercial
on the college game and they throw that
grew up in the air and you're like,
man, to get that right. The documentary,
but it's one of the most dangerous
sports show world is his high school
cheerleading because these girls fall on
a gym floor and just smack their heads
on the floor.
It's crazy.