Do you have apprehension about the
horsepower wars with just modern consumer
cars?
Cause I look at some of these cars that
they're putting out that are amazing.
Like the new corvette Zr one,
right? 700 plus horsepower,
right from the factory. The dodge
demons, like 800 horsepower.
Like they're putting out
these insane race cars. Yeah.
Right from the factory that any dummy
like me, I could just go to a stiff,
I have the cash,
I go to a corvette dealership and pick
one up and all of a sudden I'm on the
highway. Yeah. Yeah. I don't,
I don't have a problem with it now until
it becomes a common occurrence where
people don't know how to control,
you know,
hitting no know how to manage what they're
doing behind the wheel of something
like that. But until, until
that's like a common issue.
I don't know that it'll need regulation.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't necessarily think,
I wouldn't be surprised though
that one day maybe, you know,
regulated because everything
gets, you know, governance. Yeah.
Maybe too much.
Right.
Maybe we should just appreciate the
fact that you can do that. I know.
I mean I want to be able to build
whatever I want to build. Right. You know,
if I want that, then production ought to
be able to produce whatever they want.
I agree. But I feel like I feel
at the same way I feel about guns,
like I'm very pro second
amendment. I feel like, uh,
I am a responsible gun owner.
I didn't have a lot of friends
that are responsible gun owners.
I've used guns for hunting. I think
you should have a gun for protection.
I don't think there's
anything wrong with that,
but I don't think it would be a bad idea
to have some sort of course that you
have to go through.
So you understand all the aspects of
safety and precautions you should take and
how to correctly load a gun and
clean and gun. Absolutely. Yeah.
But this is not really the case right
now, you know, and it's not necessarily,
I'm not talking about gun control as
much as I'm talking about gun safety and
gun responsibility. I feel like
the same way about car. Yeah.
I feel like if you're going to
go out and buy a corvette zr one,
I mean the kind of body
mashing acceleration,
the g forces you can get from something
like that right from the factory,
zero to 60 in under three seconds.
That's an insane automobile.
Like maybe someone she's like take
you around a track a little bit.
That's a great idea.
I guess that would be the case.
If you were going to buy something
like that or getting a car like that,
you would need some kind
of a trainer course.
Then you'd have to pass three
hours on a track. If you're,
if you have to have particular license
to drive 18 wheelers down the interstate,
you know there should be a style or a
type of license that you need to achieve
to have a certain type of,
you know,
you want to go buy a viper
ACR and take it on the road.
Those crazy race car vipers,
you could just drive.
She probably know how to drive lifer.
Yeah. Those things are a little handful.
There's their little tail happy. They're
pretty dealer. They're so crazy too,
that the race car one with all the
events and all the Arrow all around it,
that was just an insane thing that you
could just go buy that and take that on
the road. No giant as v 10 in it.
It's pretty crazy. It's awesome.
Yeah.