The Joe Rogan experience. Do you feel like
that's a part of your motivation? Yes.
It's always been that way,
but you're also,
your motivation is obviously excellent,
so there's no way it could just be to
prove someone wrong is hard as you work.
No, but that's just, that's what,
that's how I got to the
mentality in a work ethic.
I got cause in high school I wasn't
like this. I sucked in high school,
I love away. I didn't win a match.
I was sophomore in high school.
I'm a residence as third grade. Like I
was asked tastic and it's was horrible.
Like why got be on time? And the
coach left me out. They left,
they load the bus and left me sitting
there because you got beat them.
I beat this. He didn't want to bring
you home or when I got beat too, I got,
I'll be lost to a girl, Joe. Oh, you lost.
So girl deadass I've didn't
have the mental, I load that up.
When I got out off the met team was gone.
When outside the bus was going.
Only reason I got home because the
Varsity, he came for it, do it at night,
and it goes like, why are you still
here? Wow. That's fucked up. Yeah,
that's what really ruthless coach. But
that's the thing I wasn't, I was at boy,
lady got the little boy that
cried wolf. You know, ever.
I was always trying to get
out of workouts. I was fat.
I was lazy at the time.
Growing up, I loved the outdoors. I
love video games and I love eating junk.
You know,
I didn't always have this mindset.
So when it came to a point when I
wanted to do good and I was trying,
I took my first injury,
my very first injury sophomore year
in high school before Congress,
I snapped my ankle cleanser and I remember
her bike when I was sitting at her
first time I was actually hurt,
but I had faced so many injuries.
Even a coach came up with
like, Chuck Kip, cool.
Y'All was faking everybody's run sprints.
You get up because they all thought I
was faking, but I was actually hurt.
And my buddy stopped by,
he grabbed me and chicken to the
trainer and the trainer's like,
like I was probably a spring
here, be fine. Once the dog,
my dad came and got him in winter,
he did an x ray.
I'm up there was like this much bone
holding my foot from falling off day.
Your ankle is dyke. Pretty much
shy. Why didn't nobody bring you in?
Like you're saying, there was nothing
wrong and I went back to the X. Right.
It was all like, oh bro, I'm so sorry.
Like you haven't been like for so long.
Stop and residents,
third grade,
you know I did it because my brother
did and I want to do everything he did,
but I didn't, I didn't have the drive
he had, but after that scene away,
everybody kind of like dog me out.
I remember coming back from recover from
that and the first time I ran after an
injury and even in my mind like I
can't run this, I can't you running it.
And I did and I was limping and I was
scared it was going to break again but I
made it to where I was going like rocking
duties. It's just, it's all here now.
That's my real everything cause mentality.
Like I never had any problems.
I was just lazy.
I didn't want to work because
I was finding a way out
now that the next year you
can ask the coaches.
They told my parents I got moved
up to the varsity tournament.
What the first or second match and I kept
took second and third and the varsity
term after wrestling and Jv for the
year before and I lost it had got at one
thing cause like different between
court now is night and day is because I
realized if I put my mind to it and just
work, quit wearing. My Dad said it's too,
that's the thing my dad pushed on.
So you're at such a young age.
My brother got it.
He was a star athlete but he didn't get
the openings in the opportunities I had,
you know, because he was always
working for my father and working here,
working there. He didn't have the
time to do camps and all that.
Me being the youngest,
it was a little easier for me.
I seen him when he did what he told me.
When my brothers,
my sisters and teammates and all the
different people around me had done under
the way I need to go to get somewhere.
But being a star athlete as a professional
athlete was never a goal of mine.
I wanted to be an engineer. I love
building club houses and Shit like that.
That was what I wanted to do.
Wow. But all that opened doors.
I wanted to go to school to uni.
Diversity was constant Platteville for
engineer program, but just like sports,
my grades his ass. I didn't
see, I didn't try on,
so I went there to hang out with my
friends and be cool. You know what I mean?
When I applied, they messaged
me back saying, your GPA
isn't good enough to rest.
My coach wanted me there because
by then I was good at wrestling.
My last few years I killed it.
I never made the state,
but I killed in the
regional and the sections.
I want all of the sections and
lost in the finals. He had to go,
you had to win that or third,
whatever. But um, and I said,
you can't get here but you got to go
to junior college. You get your GPA up,
we can get you in again. I went there.
I didn't plan on wrestling anymore.
I loved wrestling. I cry when it was
over. But then, um, I Guy Dave Clem, Matt,
he uses old coach. That's how I
met Matt Hughes to Lincoln College.
He reached out to me. I was
like, I heard about you.
You got the mentality of a war.
Like you work hard, your workhorse.
I need somebody like you to
come here and work for me.
I can't give you a scholarship
because you didn't do much.
I don't have money left. I gave
you 1800 bucks, those 27,000.
I thought I was in like a full ride. I'm
like, Oh Sean, get money. And I went,
they're excited, determined to get to, and
everybody's like, Oh, you're, you know,
we made a state, you're not going to
do good. This isn't this. So again,
that was motivation for right.
They're going to school like they
don't think I can do this date on.
My grades aren't good enough.
They don't think I can get education.
I'm not good enough for sports.
They don't think I'm all American.
I think I'm gonna go ahead and just be
another member of the team that went
there.
I cut up,
but right before the season snapped my
leg in three I thought it was over again
and that coach, like I saw your
fire, different logins at same,
the same leg with different injury for
like three years later you're back to the
first one. That injuries
would change you. Well,
I got tired of people
thinking I was faking.
So because you were injured for real
in people thought you were faking it,
you realized something was wrong.
I feel that I realized I have been
lazy and my father and my whole life.
You go to my old house right now in
the garage is still carved in there.
I never get, Dale was probably like
eight o'clock nine o'clock school night.
My Dad woke me and my brother to help
him. Do some stuff on a boat. We tired,
you know, we want to go to bed and we
got to complain the whole time. He says,
my dad, if you met my dad is
the most motivating person ever.
Don't have an education another.
But he,
he started his own business from the
ground up. He's living the dream,
hunting properties, whatever
you want, he can do it.
And that's where I got it from.
But it took me forever to realize this
and I'll never forget the day tis it
comes to me all the time.
I think about,
he stood up on the boat and
was up against the garage door,
brand new garage door. He just
put a, you know, one thing I hate,
I cannot stand is lazy.
And he took his drill and he cut l a z y
on the back of his brand new garage and
they steal there to this
day I go home and I visit,
I go back here and you'll see it cut in
and do it lazy and he cannot stand it.
And if you know him the way he works,
he's just turned 59 Tuesday and
I can in his voice and I said,
you had a job I don't you.
Oh He's, they are working.
He got a bunch of 20 year olds and
30 year he out works everybody.
59 years of up and down a ladder.
Brian and crane driving a truck
to the shot and that's it.
He always said when I was a kid
saying can only last so long.
I never understood what he said.
He's coming to me on the football field.
I'd be crying and moping around. It can
only last so long. Sorry. Keep going.
I can only last so long. I said,
I'm like, what do you mean why?
You always say that in a later.
I want to start getting hard.
I started thinking like practice
going and looking at the clock.
It's like 45 minutes but can only
last so long and click like, oh shit.
That's what my dad meant all these years.
It's only the last. I'm just go, just go.
Just put your nose. I get to it. So
you have this injury sophomore year,
your ankle snaps and you realize
you've been lazy. So what,
what's shifted in your mind?
What did, how did you change?
Let me just stop worrying about the
excuses to get out of practice and forgot,
remediate or was it a gradual?
As I was healing, you know,
I was on bedrest for awhile.
He was so bad and people come in and out
and my brother used to come over at a
time he was playing football and
whatever and watching his games.
It's just like sitting there for so long
away from all the sports and all your
friends are just sitting
there, just yourself. And I
just realized, like I said,
I've been doing it since third grade.
I've seen this stuff a million times.
I know the moves, I just don't
apply. I think when I get back,
if I actually start trying and drilling
and actually practicing and getting an
extra workout in, I could
cut up. That's what happened.
So what was the first step? When I
came back, it was when that first run,
that was really,
my dad's shop is probably 200 yards from
my house and it was raining and that's
all I, that's the reason why
I ran, because I didn't want
to get where I was like,
I'm going to run to the house.
I'm thinking like, but his leg,
I don't know if I can make it and then
write down that doubt in my mind. Like,
why are you telling yourself
you can't even make it?
How many months out from the differences?
What broke it in what January or December.
And this was summertime. So it was a lot
like I had the cast on for like five,
six months. So yeah, now I
went to the airport, it was
like, it was five, six months.
It was bad. And then I, right now I've
got the plate and the screws in them,
but I broke some of the screws because
I was like trying to move in a wrestling
stance in my boot. And I slipped
my head, um, to tile, oh to submit.
And he had a little gloss over it and I
was washing the cars one day and I was
like, oh just go and my
shadows to, I don't know what,
I slipped on a wet spot lit.
I felt it and chew,
it appears that go across,
my ankle has snap so I had to wait for
all that to heal again. Jesus Christ.
It was a whole process. So I
was late snapped ones. The two,
I still got the two long screw that they
take out to leave to seven and go up
the femur or the Tibia. But the too
long was it supposed to pull out.
But the middle when I slipped
they've broken half my bone.
So that made the bone heal slower
cause now just a little spot they drill
through. It opened up like
that much that much more.
So you had to wait for all that to
heal before I could actually walk to,
they take the screws out and
putting new ones in there.
So you got broken screws in your,
and if you look at like when I work I,
my barrio ankles fat his head.
That's because the plate,
the plate and the screws,
the screws are so long. The
ankle, the swelling, there's
different, exactly. Yeah.
Here's what I'm saying,
which angle?
That's a fat ankle
and that's the normal one.
Pretty fat too. Oh, oh yeah. Oh yeah.
Oh yeah. It does a big difference. Yeah.
So like when I get done training. Yeah.
This one is like this big cause all the
blood and everything swollen around this
group. Wow. So does it
fuck with you anymore?
Like when it gets cold out or anything?
I feel it like mental,
everything has mentioned to me
now, right. Everything in life,
even though she hates it because I tell
her all the time she had a negative.
It's a negative insight on stuff
like finding the positive in it.
Like it's all in your mind,
but you can make the best of anything.
And I'm just like, oh this,
this and this happened.
Like are you could be dead or are you
good or worse? Are you going to have legs?
Like she got her car smashed that work.
Somebody hit the side of a tour it all up
and had to go on shot. He was like, Hey,
the windows in break does like think
about it drives and you windows ain't Bro.
Like it's the middle of winter. He ain't
gotta be cold. It could attend to her.
Yeah.
Like cause I mean a million different
things you can find to be sad but find the
good thing is to find the positive.
It's going to get fixed eventually.
So this ankle fucks with you still,
but not enough to stop you.
I'm nothing to stop me.
And you,
what does it affect you at all when you
kick things? Depends. Yeah, they dig in.
Like if I can get,
if they go to do the elbow,
like I go to kick the liver and ain't
got to sit on it and like the elbow kind
of cash it, I feel it. But
again, it doesn't stop me
15 minutes.
That's nothing lasts only last so long.
I'm going to bounce this off and keep
going. Yeah. So you get out of the injury,
you have the cast on you
for five or six months,
you realize how blessed you were to be
able to move around and that feeling once
you get your, your leg back
under you and start moving again,
what is the changes you make?
How do you start to move your
life in this positive way? Well,
after I made that first
jog and I realize I'm,
I'm good like at first I doubted myself
but I made it because I told myself I
can do it. I made it here.
There's no injuries, I'm fine.
I was just slow and steady,
just start hand fighting like good the
little they got to take down dummies,
hang on the wall, let's go there and
move, you know, not another fascist work,
hand fighting, just kind of grabbed
her leg, work on my shots in and out,
in and out in the morning before practice
and I used to go watch the guys for
off season practice study and
then when I came back it was just,
Oh I have to heavyweight coach.
I coached him, we drove today.
I'm like you guys to meet
Julie. Yeah, coach could see.
I just wanna work with I to do a
little bit extra stuff. After practice.
He worked with me,
then the other coach or come work with
me and it got to the point where like in
the morning I was in there before
school and I was there after school for
practice. Now stay after her
coaching drills, different stuff.
They must've been so confused and they
didn't like the coach is night and day
like different drink. Cornell is night
and day. The husband so strange. He goes,
this lazy kid and all of a sudden
he becomes a savage. They haven't,
when I go back to the
school and I'm visit,
they always asked me to come talk to these
people. They call me a success story.
Not only was this, but I grew up in
area where there was no black people.
I was the only black family there.
So we had racism my whole life.
You know what I mean?
Dealing with that.
So that's another man that was the mental,
the mental of the mental fucks of it
all. Like every, no matter what I did,
you're going to be wrong.
Like I was another coriander's
in two that was even worse.
And he was actually a troublemaker.
So when he would get in trouble,
they would always come get me out of the
classroom like it was Cory and I will
get put on. I ain't even did, I was
a good kid. Never did nothing wrong.
They not an officer principal walking
in like wrong. Like of course the quiz.
Every time I remember Corey,
Richard Anderson, Corey see
Anderson of course. See,
see Cory Richard. But they always pulled
me in there and it was just, cause I was,
it was only a few of us in my high school
in the fact that w I never did drugs.
She was like, when we was on
the ring, I said, I don't want,
I want to come in and show and shoot
with you. I don't want to smoke weed.
I never did drugs. I don't do none
of that. I've been a good kid.
But to deal with that stuff,
I used to get pulled over for no reason.
I had a nice truck, STN drops at
ground with rams and speakers.
I used to get pulled over and my friends
get put in cuffs and sit on the curb.
Like I searched the car
looking for something when I
went to college is the same
thing. Get pulled over all the
time. And teacher would be like,
every time you late for class, you said
he got pulled off. Like I'll tell them,
well on the way here, like I'm serious.
I have classmates that saw them like no,
he's telling the truth. It starts,
we saw them on the side of the road.
Like he always gets pulled over cause
nice vehicle black and they always think
of something they know and
that's just where I'm from.
So dealing with that and the mentality,
I finally figured out, like I said,
that's why when people doubt me,
I think it's trying to prove wrong.
Because I had coaches in high school,
I won't put names on air,
but I remember even when I was doing good,
I knew I was doing good because I had
led a team of sex. I didn't start.
You know what I mean?
I lay the the starting lineman out or
beat this guy and this and that and this
and that and I never got the
position or something was around it.
And then when I came back after I made
the UFC like, oh, I remember this.
Like I ain't trying to hear that and
I'm only coaching at high school.
I will say that that believed in me.
It was a wrestling coach, Marty Kaiser,
Marty Kaiser made everything possible
to make. Let me meet Dave Clem,
who was my junior college
coach who led me to rush.
David Rem led me to been asked her who?
Tim fader and everything.
And I've been blessed with the people
in my life that bring me to Frankie and
mark and Ricardo and I got
like the ultimate people
around me. Like my mom says,
you've always been blessed to
have a good circle of people.
And the one year I had a bad
coach in college, I was like,
my mom said we didn't have so much good.
Don't let this one coach to feature.
Now I'll never forget him. Jason Valley.
I'll put his name on air. That guy that,
that made me the toughest man I
could because no matter what I did,
he wanted to make sure he could
break them. He had control over me.
I was 16 hours away from home in
South Carolina. No family, no money.
He had me on a full ride. He was
just used it. I got you here.
You here because of me. You do this or
I'm gonna cut. You cut meat in. Fuck.
It goes high.
You know what I'm saying?
I go get recruited and he put me back
on the scene. You still need Nli.
You can't do that.
This is necessarily kind of like,
I think that's where I got the mentality
where I want to prove people wrong
because I beat the starter and I beat
him bad 13 and one toilet and you're
talking to wrestle. I beating
them, but you still not starting.
What the fuck you make him Muslim. Awful.
Like, I didn't beat him every time.
When you lost on the first dude a match
by Ryan time, the first week of school,
not beat him every time, but you're
not gonna let me start. Nope.
Cause he pins people and you only
get points kind of like filing.
He knocks people out and you only win by
decision. That's kind of like, all right,
so I left, went to Whitewater where
I met Ben and everything else again.
Went there.
They coach knew who I was.
Nobody asked me my worse cause I
didn't get the rest of the year before.
I was a bench warmer. That kid on team
but never wrestled. That's so crazy.
Kill never asked.
My parents would drive 16 hours of watch
me duel and he'd make me sit the bench
the whole tournament. It'd be a tournament
here like you're not wrestling today.
My parents would be like,
you're not wrestling. They're
like, my parents drove six.
You're not wrestling. I'm like, you
got me eight hours on the school.
My parents drove all that. But what's
this guy's problem? We don't know.
I got teammates now and got us still
fighting everything and they're like, Bro,
you got out of there and like a lot of
guys, he had them, they're academically,
he like we're going to short term short
credits you business and you're going to
do half credit but you're
gonna be at a restaurant.
So he was just sitting at
the deck to a lot of dis.
He just wanted to win and that was it.
So like guys are finished,
they wrestling career, they didn't have
the credits to graduate like coach,
I need help. Like what can I do? You don't
wrestle for me no more. I was like, Bro,
I'm only here because of you. But I left.
He Lauer. He kept hitting me up like, oh,
you keep coming back and next year I
let you start next year if you beat him
again, fuck can. I was like, exactly.
I said, I want you to Ada office.
Told him what was going on. They gave
me my letters trans let me transfer out,
but I couldn't go division two like you
can leave but you can't go division two,
he can't hold you back anymore.
Like that's fine. I'm out.
I left like among the before school
and he showed up at my house one day.
You're like, where are you? I'm
at your house. Like I'm gone bro.
What do you mean I'm going like I'm
done. I'm transferring. Like you can't,
I show him the papers. So how did you
get that? Like I went behind your back.
I got it done. I'm out of there and
uh, Tim fader to coach a whitewater.
I remember we put up at my house.
I almost didn't go back to school
cause he kinda got in my head like,
I don't want to go nowhere else and waste
my last year of school during the same
shit. I can't trust anybody there. I
took what, six the year for an injury,
but I was beating everybody. You
know, I only lost a d one d two guys.
And so it was like,
I don't want to go anywhere else and
somebody's going to screw me over a full
ride. But in this guy pulled up in my
driveway when I was working one day,
he's like, I'm looking for core
Anderson. I've seen him before,
but I didn't really know much about him
and we went to the lunch or whatever.
He was like,
I know your story.
But the thing is I can't give you full
rock cause the d three we can't give
money but I want you to rest for me.
This isn't this. And like I said,
when I went d three nobody knew who I
was because I didn't get to wrestle,
but he knew like, we're not even
gonna let you wrestle for la.
So I thought right off the get go,
like what are you saying? Shit?
Like what the fuck? Like
no, I think that he said,
I don't want people to know what we got.
We're going to wait till the first home
do and I'm gonna let you loose in the
first home dropped to number three,
dude in the country.
And I never forget that week cause
that you really like what you mean.
Like it's the time you get to come out.
Gave him my statement like you ready to
show up? Like you know I'm ready dog,
the number three guy out by
like 12 points and was like,
who the fuck is this kid? He
was like, yes, I'm finally home.
And then shortly after I met Russ Davey,
the guy who came from Colorado
who coached in Wisconsin.
He was my heavy weight coach,
Olympic guy. And uh, he brought in,
been asking is how I got into a fight in
the bin. It was just like, like I said,
the people around you,
he just Emoji like I'm blessed.
I'm saying think about it and it makes
me feel good cause all the things I've
been through and everything and it all
worked out. Yeah. Dick coach probably,
it helped. It helped me. It wasn't about,
and my coach told me when I signed,
when I signed like clothes to give me a
four as the one that kept saying to give
me a full ride, he kept saying,
Corey, you know about the money.
I guess the most assists any
live is not about the money.
Coach Klimt and Steven Rally and they
both say like it's not about the Money
Corp remembers most decisions,
most important decision of your life.
Don't let the money, few e but that
was, that's what it was for me. I'm a,
you know I went to a school as a walk
on pretty much now I'm getting full ride
offs from everywhere and I'm
going to a number one school,
division two and they gave me a full ride.
Like I thought that was something,
when I got there I figured out what he
meant and I'll never forget calling both
coasts like you guys are right.
I'm back home now to try for your now.
Well you can go in Ai. I know a few
schools I want you to as good coaches,
blah blah blah. And I'm just gonna Chill
and think about it when that goes cane.
And the fact that he came to my house,
reached out to him, he told him,
I can't give you money but I
want you for you and as a leader.
And I first got there even though he told
me he wasn't gonna let me arrest him.
He let me run practice for like the
first month because he couldn't teach it
before season. Got these. I want you to
like run practice this, this and this.
Cause you've got that mentality.
You can help these guys show us.
You did in d two and number one school.
You can show us stuff here.
And I ended up being the first NCAA all
American or incidentally filings the
school had in 22 years.
You know,
I lead a team and take downs all the way
up until like the reason the tournament,
my roommate,
when we had a competition going,
I did a lot of things that most
people didn't see heavyweights do.
The way I shot, the way I wrestled
my mentality, I was always working.
I was going to do a straight
the conditioning before
practice and before did
more at like six o'clock we asked you in
the conditioner and I've got a class at
one and I'd be in the gym lifting.
They're doing circuit training till three
and it went from just me to me and my
teammate or me and my roommate to
other teammates and like you said,
people will see how you're doing it and
they were jumping in and before you know
it was like six or seven of us working
out 35 and we just motivating each other
and the bond.
We had her as a team,
like I remember getting
there and everybody was like,
oh what's our goal on the,
I thought about was nationals.
I be like,
oh we want to win nationals or win
conference look like why the Fuck Y'all
talking about conference? That's like
the first step you got conference,
regionals,
all is national.
What about the big picture like oh well
we would never one conference before.
Like we should still want to get
nationalists and like by Andy Year that
everybody was feeding off each other.
We had,
we had three guys from the same high
school me tonight, 789 or 87 or 84 pounds,
excuse me,
and they called us a high nigga death
row because I was school and like death
row sugar night and all that.
So one got prayed up certain,
it was us three and it was like,
it was so cool to have three
guys that was on the same school.
We grew up right down the street from
each other, but we all went separate ways.
One way here, one went there, we
ended up in junior college together.
We in the one guy at
in our very last year,
we all ended up together as a
team captains, senior years.
I last time to do it together,
who we brought like a whole high school
would come to all the matches and as
long as an hour from home. It was
just cool man. And I was, like I said,
when I met Ben there and he brought me
to this thing and I didn't want to fight
again. I was, I had a doubt in
my mind. I want to go to that,
but I want to go back to your high,
your high school days.
When you made that big shift,
did you slip at all? Like you,
you went from being a guy who was kind
lazy and unmotivated to a guy who is very
disciplined that it
was like night and day,
but was there ever a time where
you fell back to your old ways?
I mean it sounds like it took a lot of
motivation in pep talk to myself to get
out and do something every time.
Like I wanted to instead of go work out,
go play video.
So I was big on a dirt bike in a fall or,
and like when I get off the bus, you can
hear the dirt bikes come to my house.
I had the motocross track,
my bag up, me and a neighbor,
he had a freestyle track I dirt bike tray
and I get off the bus and be thinking
like, God, I'm about to go do
my homework. And here you go,
do a little workout lift or something
and you hear him come in and say, oh,
I want to go ride and stay.
I want to go ride.
But at the same time like you're arrested,
you're arrested,
forgot to which one is first.
You know,
I let the guys go ride in my track
and I do pushups or whatever and do my
homework, whatever it was. I
do just a little something.
Long as I get something and I did a
little bit something that's more than the
next person. Right. You know,
by the time my senior year came around
and it was kind of like I still wasn't
all in,
but I was a little more,
I didn't get all in until
after that second injury in
college and during college
was the same injury, same, less, same
leg, different. What'd you do this time?
I snapped my leg and threw out what
freak accident this til this day I,
I just remember hearing
the wrestling wrestling.
Me and my coach drilling very slow,
very slow June,
but we had brand new mats so they was
super sticky and they had brand new
wrestling shoes,
which were super sticky.
And I remember the drill
coach Morgan really high.
So we're going to work to the chain
wrestling. I shoot a single lea.
You get the single back when I shoot
a doe, but you bumped with the hips,
you snapped to your shot. He grabbed
a single day. I snapped the foot down.
He shot devil when I hit it with my
hips, I fell backwards in here, pop.
But I didn't feel it and he stood over me.
I remember him standing over feet
on both sides like, don't look down.
Don't look down. Now somebody tell you
don't look. You're going. Gonna look,
I looked. Emma was like pointed
like this and it was down. Ah,
I'll turn it over that.
Sorry. Armored called.
We got a pool on the other side of the
door and I'm trying to get the doors with
John,
myself and paint out a Pankey.
I'll try to get in the pool because
he's trying to get up and DP.
I'll try to drive it like it hurt.
Like I was like, I want to die.
I was just going,
I remember him putting me on the,
the city go through your mind when
shock. It was shock. Things that hit you.
You don't think that's a crazy thing. If
you don't want to go drag, it hurts you.
You're on snapchat make
no, no, no. It's one spot.
Three spots. So it's like shooting up your
whole leg to your back. It's like, oh,
we're doing shoulders. The point it's
like I just want just always like,
I'm just going to go jump in the water.
First thing my mind goes,
bear called falling water.
Crazy instinct.
I wasn't the most sane kid,
but that was the first thing on my mind.
Go find the water. Just
just ended, you know?
And they flipped me over and I remember
they threw up on a punching bag.
So it has to do with the old injury.
Nothing to do with, oh, it's completely,
totally different. I like four or
five inches up from no injuries.
He just snapped freak acts and
that's what I kept saying, hospice,
it's a freak accident.
So what did they do then?
Go to the hospital that day and they
snapped him to got us snatches it back,
pulls her and snatches and lines
all the bones up and they put it,
I will put it in a cast now,
but you got to get plates and pins to
set district and that when I was out for,
again I was October 27th and I came
back after a lease back January 13th and
14th and I was like a little bit
before regional and we didn't have a
heavyweight all year because I got hurt
and the other guys got kicked out of
school, whatever. So three months ish?
Yeah, he'll fat. Well I wasn't back,
but I was clear to start drilling. I
remember begging the coach, like coach,
just letting me come back.
I can say it was six points because
every time one got on rest of,
that's automatic six.
Did they have to put plates in your Shin?
I'm on the side of my leg,
I'll play it.
You can feel it if you
ran your hand up download.
It's like all bent up and from now all
the wars and shit kicks and wrestling.
It's like all wobbly hoes,
all kinds of stuff from getting kicked,
getting kicked in it from wrestling.
People do foot sweeps.
You ever get to look at an x ray of it
to see what it looks like and I haven't
asked her in forever. I should see
what it looks pretty bad by now.
I remember my first tournament when
somebody flips sweat. Oh my goodness.
That feeling like God having an under
hook and he kicked that plate and I just
fell like ain't kicking my feet.
I just fail because it's the first
time you feel that pain shoot up.
You've never felt it right.
Your nerves run up and down there.
So when it hit and everything just shut
and I fell and he pinned me. I was like,
what's wrong? I'm like, Yo, my leg
gave, I'm still on the mat. Like,
I don't know what the fuck happened there.
Like your nerves and transform.
Like you got nerves on the side of
the leg, you're running the plate.
When he did probably kicked it right and
hit the plate and another thing you had
to get in my mindset like
this is going to happen often.
You just gotta be able to toughen it up
and just go through it. Yeah. You have a,
an extra vulnerable spot. Yeah. Yeah. And
have you been low leg kicked there a lot.
Yeah, he did it like four
times. Bought low lucky.
It's just like I said, I got to
the point now I just deal with it.
That was in 2007 this is 2019
as 12 years of dealing with it.
You get your point where it's kind of
like, it's not really a pain anymore,
it's just a, just a pesky injury. You
feel it. But some of those injuries,
they'll go in after it's healed
up and take the plate out.
They say they can do that.
But to do that because I got the broken
pins because those pins are so broke,
they got cut like a whole section on
my leg or hear me and I'd be out of
commission for all alone time and
I was like, I'm used to it now.
Is there any benefit if they do that?
I get my whole leg back.
I gave him my leg bag. That's the
only benefit. It's like I said,
I said I can train, right? Yeah. Like
this is going to bother. He's like,
I deal with it when I retired we do all
that, but right now there's no problem.
Wow.
So you have this shift in high school,
you you make it to see are and you're
a different person night and day,
but you're still not the Corey Anderson
of today. So the second injury,
what is the second injury do for you
when you snapped it in the second injury?
That was just,
I mean that just because I
didn't get to show what I can do.
It motivated me that much more than
when I come back, I gotta be undeniable.
I got to show up.
I got to do like nobody knows I can do
because I didn't make it to state my
senior year in high school.
But then we went to team state and I
pinned the gotta took fourth in state.
So I knew I could do it by
just saying make it there.
So when I got hurt my freshman,
freshman year, I was gone.
That was the year I was gonna show people,
Corey Hanson,
which I used to know what you think this,
this and this.
Then I got hurt and they kind of set me
back. You know, is in my mind I was very,
I was sad. Like I remember being
at home, I was emotionally sad,
but when I went to go back and
I couldn't focus on wrestling,
I just put my mind on schoolwork and
that's when I figured out I can do
schoolwork. I finished my freshman year
with a 3.25 GPA. After missing like three,
four months,
I had to make up everything and take
tests and that's not realize like I can do
that too. So that was a more thing. I
got the thing I got out of that injury.
Not so much the athletic part.
I was more motivated to
work even harder next year,
but I found the fact that I can
do schoolwork if I want to. Again,
it's just a mental thing. I have to
take the time to study. I've never,
I had never studied before
that ever then do any homework.
It was I bought somebody his homework or
take somebody knows and try to fill in
the answers just to get someone
to say it was a completion credit,
but when I'd had nothing to do, I
couldn't wrestle. I couldn't, you know,
I couldn't run, I couldn't
go play basketball in the
back, but everybody else,
it was the only back and focus on
our school at the time I came back,
my GPA dropped like two point something
because I hadn't been in class for so
long,
so I had to get audited up,
fight it before the end of the year and
finished with a 3.0 at least I finished
with a 3.25 for that was my, to
make academic. All American was my,
that was my highlight of my freshman year.
I didn't get the rest of all American,
but I had the academic,
all American,
that's I something I can work
on because as a kid, my parents,
my mom and eighth grade bet me $100 I
wouldn't graduate my own mother and she's
my mom and my biggest motivation ever
before myself, before my son came here,
my mother was the hand that pushed
me over everything. She's always,
my dad comes with the work ethic.
My mom was always makes sure you do things
right, you can do this, this and this.
I always helped me.
I struggle with reading.
She's helped me learn how to read faster,
read better and do things to the best
of my ability in the academic world
because sports and hard
work is going to beat her.
But education something you can always
fall back on. So, but I was just so bad.
I used to and I lived next
door to the middle school.
Sounds bad to eighth grade year.
They opened a new high or middle
school up the street from my house.
So I would mess up from school and
don't do homework. I don't know why.
I think I would get away with it.
I'm getting out of class.
My mom sit in the principal's office
because I've done it for a walk for,
they call it according to do his
homework again cause she was on it.
She would call like of course
it messed up in school. Call me.
She had me in summer camp.
I had to go to summer school one year
when I pass all my classes because she
wanted me to get that fat. Like just
cause you pass, they let you pass.
I mean you did good, you passed, but you
got to learn how to work. You're going to,
but that was another thing.
I didn't have the mentality that my
mom wanted me to have when they come to
working for academics and stuff.
So what made you do that? What?
What was the shift that caused that
from the, the injury? This, like I said,
one sick I hadn't asked us to focus on.
It was either that or become a
bum at the school, cinema room,
skipping class and fell out.
So I had to get my grades up if I
wanted the rest of the next year.
So it probably been something
that was bothering you already.
It didn't bother me.
I didn't care about my grades because
I was athletic doing athletics. No Way.
Oh my. It's kind of like the movies have
you competing and they know you're good.
Your assets at team, the teachers help
you. They tried it, they don't give you,
but they'll help you out, take,
you got questions, ask questions.
They won't fail you.
Right.
You know if I bake and do everything
they can to make sure I learn.
So will you realizing because the
injury that may be your athletic career
wouldn't be there and you need,
do you need to get this education
because not didn't have the help I had in
class when I was athlete. They help you
a little more but not on our wrestling.
It's kind of like must GPA doesn't
matter for a team anymore and I have been
missing from school for so long.
When I came back it's kind of like
now I've got a lot to make up for.
I just got to do it on my own.
I was studying,
that's all I had class
and my dorm room class.
From that point on from
that injury then you,
you get your academic work in order and
you start being disciplined in all our
areas of your life and you feel like
that carried over every is world thing
works together. Everything works for
one thing that's come out of that. Okay.
Like first thing we learned orientation.
College coach comes with, we're going to,
my God, we got your athletic scholarship,
but you're here as a student athlete.
And I remember going back and coach at
the same college and him giving the same
speech and he write on the board. Student
athlete. We gonna make it in two parts.
First part student, second part athlete.
So we don't write it on the board.
What does this mean?
So first priority school
after that next priority,
athletics to me after that you got your
family then is making sure you stay out
of trouble and that the last thing,
the very most important thing and to
come to college is just social life.
The rest of that,
everything else comes first and at the
end then you worry about your friends and
trying to be cool and all the extra stuff.
I'm 17 when I went to college,
I graduated high school at 17 so
I'm young. I'm not even an adult,
but in my mind I'm on my own,
I'm doing what I want, blah,
blah, blah. I'm showing,
I'm being asked, you know? Right.
Not like getting in trouble but
not paying attention to school.
I'm not worried about Cora in part I'm
just an athlete. Um, they not going to,
I ask questions, act like I'm struggling
and they're trying to help me out,
you know. But I know they're not going
to give me an f because um, I'm trying.
I really wasn't.
I'm asking questions.
I'm sitting in front of class so you're
not going to give me an f but they going
to make sure I don't, I'm eligible to
wrestle, but I'm not going to fail. Right.
So when you get Andrea,
you realize that ain't there no more
because she ain't got none of the rest
before you all school now.
So now you got you.
You can't say I got practice so I can't,
I can't study.
Was that a big eyeopener for you when
you realized that you can do good at
school too? Yes, 100%. Because then
your whole life when you didn't try,
you didn't care and it had that no child
left behind pretty much before they
made it official thing.
It was always there.
Cause I know I didn't do enough in school,
but somehow I graduated every year.
Somehow I graduated cause
there's always one teacher,
one person I looked off on me.
I guess I've been blessed to
have that in middle school.
Was Ms for met to this day. We still
talk. I go home, we have lunch, breakfast,
whatever. Yes. If it wasn't
for, I probably would have
dropped out of high school.
That's cool. Yeah. That's very cool. So.