Man, this most yearn I've ever held. I
think. Congratulations. Yeah. Was it,
how much can you hold? What kind
of car do you drive? Theo Vaughn,
I drive a BMW,
but I'm trying to get rid of it.
Figure you more for a muscle
car type fellow. Really? Yeah.
I used to own a 1984 Ford escort and
somebody stole my passenger's seat.
God dammit. Yeah. What are they going
to do with a passenger seat? I Dunno.
Probably put, you know, put it in the
living room. I'll be guests at the time,
putting in the forest and jerk off.
Take out
how much comes out in the fucking
forest, Bro. That's where the next,
no wonder swamp thing happened
while I was thinking this,
once they found out that in some plants
some plants contain DNA from salmon
because the salmon were used
as fertilizer by the plant.
As it decomposed,
it got into the actual plant itself
and you can actually somehow or another
through some sort of scientific process
that I'm too stupid to understand.
They can actually detect salmon in
the actual plant itself. We're close.
So if you were whacking off on that
tree and that tree, it's every day.
That's your spot. You went down to that
titty tree and whacked off on the roots.
And then like after a while he did an
analysis and you found your DNA in the
tree itself. Imagine.
Oh, it'd be great man.
If it maintains the information of
everything that whacked off on it.
You have a little son made out of wood.
One day they had a kid in our town one
time does he got made his son of wooden
shirt that I'd tell you that a wouldn't
shirt. Yeah, he made his son a shirt out.
A plywood for Christmas.
What? Yeah, we wanted the kid
to wear it. Oh yeah, he did.
And I remember I was um,
wait a minute,
is it a stiff shirt or is he make it
like little itty bitty tiny pieces of
plywood and weave it all together?
Oh No, I was pretty stiff.
And the dad was a, um, yeah,
like an Elvis impersonator,
you know.
But Dad was an Elvis impersonator at
a casino or did he do it at carnivals?
Not as locally. Oh. Um, but we
didn't even need him that no,
no money in it really.
I think he's probably an alcoholic,
but he had a,
he had four kids and one of them he made,
I was going walking home one night and I
heard him in the garage and he's making
like a son, like a sh like, uh,
for Christmas, like a wooden shirt,
like uh, you know, uh, not as nice.
That one is nice. Wouldn't
shirt. Yeah. Can you get,
but that's a like a sculpture. Yeah.
That's nice. Can you get one more?
That's like a,
like if you go over someone's house and
they have a wooden shirt on a hanger,
like, and they think that's cute. Just
leave. Now people are assholes now.
This kid needed it cause people were
used to beat this kid up. Is that salmon?
Yeah,
it's a framed wouldn't shirt.
It looks like he used to beat him up
because of his wooden. Sure. Yeah.
People used to beat him up anyway
on the bus. Well the wouldn't, sure.
It would protect you from a lot of
shots and it helped and it helped.
He didn't wear that, wouldn't
sure. You better shut the fuck.
I swear to God he did. He's not walking
around with wood over his body like that.
Not Today. That'd be, that would be,
yeah. This was your pads inside of it.
It looks heavy. Fuck no dude. But he
think his dad is Estee Lauder lady.
Yeah. See there's some lady wearing
something there. Okay, but this was early.
It might've been teak.
Teeds way too much attention or posing.
Pretend to be aloof. Short hair by
the ocean. We're in a wooden shirt.
How about a big no, that's
a big no for me. Hey,
do you want to meet my friend Michelle?
She's channeling with her
fucking geometrically patterned.
Wouldn't shirt on what? No, I like regular
people. This kid, his name was Eddie.
Can you look up teak
wood is teak look like?
Imagine if someone was trying to set you
up with that Gal, you'd be like, well,
I'm torn because obviously she's very
pretty. She's sure she's not crazy.
Super desperate. She might have
splinters that her tits, dude,
it was one photo shoot. She doesn't wear
that except when she worships. The ocean.
I don't lie.
Now that's something,
a little more malleable teak or something
like that. What are the kind of wood,
did they have over print shirt?
Now we're talking that print system.
So it was like that but a little
bit more but more real. And uh,
he wore this for what reason did I
look at chest plate? Like
a Roman soldier? That okay.
Was it like how was it a connected
on the waste on the sides rather?
It was just kind of like a long square.
It was almost like a kind of a cereal
box kinda. Where did he put his arms?
Like rest his arms on the side and the
side. Yeah. Fuck your armpits up. Oh,
is limiting. I mean, look man, these
weren't, I mean the man that made it
not a real, you can't do online. People
would find out. They would call him out.
We had to, when I was younger, you could
do anything you wanted to, you know,
people, people were, I don't know, just
more fun and use your imagination more.
When I was young,
you have more fun.
How many kids you see
beaten when you were a kid.
People used to beat their kids probably
like at least 20 I bet. Oh yeah.
But people would fight in the
street. Beat their kids. Yeah. Yeah.
You'd see people beat people up.
Let's be way more common,
but I guess it's maybe we've moved out
of those areas too, but that's true.
People back in those areas are
like, Bro, I'm on the front line.
Shit's still going now from
all it did it did I? Yeah.
We used to see people fight,
man.
I saw this old man get thrown into
a fire one time in a ditch fire.
Their people were burning
leaves throwing right in.
This guy was in his eighties
to Mr Pollito. My God,
why did they throw him in a ditch?
He was fighting a bus driver.
He was fighting our bus driver and
the bus driver through in it ditch.
I don't know why was he swinging
on the bus driver? I don't know.
Whose fault was it? Both of them. Both of
them. I think. I mean, one of, you know,
they were both adults. I mean, look man,
I'm not surprised they were doing
it. Oh, you know humans. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. If you saw him, you wouldn't
be shocked. They were fist fight.
What do you do with like that once
universal basic income rolls around and
there's some stupid people that just
ain't getting any better. Basic needs met.
Okay, so then after that, after you do a
couple of years universal basic income,
then what do you do? Wolves in
the woods. Yeah, let wolves loose.
You've got to thin the
herd. It's insane, man.
Cut some dude out there
jerking off thinking he's
pretty cute hanging out behind
a bush. He just turns and
sees six wolves. Look it up
and they just know what to do next as how
well you think a wolf would attack you
while you were jerking off or now, fuck
yeah, you're all pink. Everything's pink.
He has pink. Dick looks delicious.
When you wearing clothes, it's like,
can I eat that?
I guess I can eat that.
I got to get through all that
fucking bullshit plywood tee shirt.
Once I get through that,
I'll beat the fuck out of that dude.
But if they catch you out there
with just all pink. Oh yeah.
They beat the fuck out of you. Yeah. Yeah.
I hope I don't do anything bad like that.
And they in any of them see me,
you know,
I don't want to be having that kind
of ending you get into by an animal.
I'm going to say right now,
I don't think that you're going to be
jerking off in the woods and eaten by a
wolf. I might be wrong. Yeah, but I would
say that's not how you're going to go.
Thanks for anyone. I like that.
Don't see that in you bro.
I see better things for you.
I like the attitude naked.
You're packer in your hand.
Imagine if like you were about to come
and the first wolf built your cat bit,
your calf and you're like, look,
they're gonna get me anyway.
Let me just keep going.
Shit on the edge.
Maybe the bite and the pain cause you're
about to come. What is your last rocket?
You bust like a more than
usual. Yeah. And you like, wow.
At least I died with my
biggest load ever. Like, Hey,
that's one thing I've always
been disappointed by. Right.
Is the sheer volume of your loads.
Well, it's not much. If you look at it.
Take Zinc and magnesium.
Yeah. Allegedly egg whites.
I do have zinc at the house.
Actually sank.
Supposed to be good for raising
testosterone. Oh, I want that.
The neighbors,
the more you save it up to,
Oh yeah, we gather up more,
but I like to do that. Not
turn off. I want to ride.
I want that dream bus that used to get
super bus. Dude. I want that dream bus.
Remember we knew would bust in a dream
[inaudible] those don't happen anymore,
but they can if you search for
it, if you seek it out, yeah,
but you have to not beat
off for a long time.
To the point we bought it bodies like
this dumb mother fucker can't even jerk
off. Yeah. I'm just going to have
to jerk off for him. Unconscious.
Your brain fucking church. You all
honestly for, what do you think?
Do you think that you're learning
things while you're dreaming?
Because some people think you'd
learn things. We need treatment.
I think that'll be one of the next
hurdles that we get over where people are
able to, uh, be able to take in
information while they're asleep.
This is what I mean. Like they
say, if you have a problem,
something's bothering you,
you should sleep on it.
And when you wake up in the morning,
you'll have a clear, I believe that. Yeah,
I think so too. I think that's
real because I've done that before.
That seems to actually be a good strategy.
If you can go to sleep,
the problem is if something's
really bothering you, like, damn,
I got to figure this out.
Like you might stay up all night and be
exhausted and then you might not be able
to sleep and think through it. You got to
get a higher power to help you out, man.
She got to get you just kind of case
where a higher power comes into place.
Do you think you see yourself ever going
to church again? Yeah, I would think so.
I think Churchill is kind of evolving over
our time and stuff like that. And, um,
would you go to Justin Bieber's preacher?
Carl Lentz, you know, he is. Hey,
whoa. He texted me actually.
Whoa. He's trying to groom you,
trying to pull you in. How's
the dark arts? How low is low?
Do you wear your shorts? Huh? Oh, I saw
you guys make it a kind of this room.
Yeah, that was a little wild. Huh?
So you know him never met him? No.
He just texted each other back and forth.
Yeah. We communicate sometimes. Yes.
That root Hashtag Dick Route.
He looks good.
Yeah.
They're both Kamara to shorts. Yeah. Eh,
Eh, but I've never met him, but
I would go just text each other.
He has to try to meet you and
you're like, not tonight, Bro.
You think he's homoerotic? No. Oh No. I
mean I, that's a weird way of putting it.
You're homoerotic
you always, every time I'm here he's
talking about jerking off the magical
problem. It's like you came in here
with like gay expectation, you know,
I got nothing, dude. I
jerked off yesterday.
I'm not even planning on coming
again for a couple of days.
Do you have a time where like if you've
jerked off and it's been like four days,
like, man, maybe I should do something.
Uh Oh, I get that feeling inside of me.
So it's like a vulture that wants
to flat on my fight. Oh her.
My brain don't want to
be too sex obsessed. No.
Like there's a balance, right? You
don't want to beat off every day,
but you don't want to not be it off
either. Cause then it'll consume you.
But I think I'm gonna
start hunting that dream.
They don't want that
fucking nocturnal bust.
And I certainly did want to start a group.
I'm hunting the L and D's Row. There's
late night busters brother's dream.
Dude. How funny is that
expression? I'm hunting that dream.
I want that nocturnal bus. That's
what I want. Hunting the dream.
But due to imagine you fucking,
are you Jessica?