Alright. I think this, this,
I think you guys talked him about aliens
to fucking really boost your search
engine results on Youtube. I eliminated
from all search engine results,
but I really doubt you'll be penalized
for this and show you should say
something about that. Like you're an
American, you're allowed to talk to me.
Here's are going to say Joe Rogan had
Jones on to say no one died of sandy hook
be as well.
I don't think anyone's going to say that,
but people probably will say some things,
but I think also,
you know the idea that like anybody
should be able to tell you that you can't
talk anymore ever.
If you said one thing that people
don't like or if you do talk,
it has to be only on your side and you
have to be trapped out of all of the
different platforms for social media.
That's a slippery,
slippery slope, you know, and other
training. But here's the thing, I,
you're not a hateful person.
I know you're not a hateful person.
You may have said things that are angry
in the past about certain people or been
angry about a certain event in the news,
but you're not a hurtful, angry person.
If there's things that you
say that they can say, hey,
this violates some sort
of a pattern of behavior.
You're attacking someone,
you're giving out someone's address.
That kind of shit they should be able
to take it down to be able to show is,
that's not, that's not speeches
here. I'm not doing it.
That's what I was going to get to.
There should be a clear set of rules and
you could look at these rules the way a
lawyer would look at him and say, is
this in violation? Is My client arrested?
Well know your client didn't
have anything illegal on him,
and we did a search and we found no drugs
and we found no illegal weapons. So,
but we suspected that
he was up to something.
Like he's talking just
in closing to say this,
I don't want to make myself the
center of this. At the end of the day,
Info wars went from really successful and
huge to light zeitgeisty and shame and
you take any responsibility for any
of that. Do you think there's a human,
I'm not perfect.
Right?
Do you think that maybe it made it easy
for some of the people that were going
to attack you and I've been guilty of
this myself by providing fuel saying
stupid shit contact. Yes. That's
what I'm saying is they say it,
it's, it's, it's global. It's
fun at a big corporation.
This is what I'm to say in closing,
it's come out,
we're going to release this shit,
but the thing is it's all left wing.
That's where it's weird,
but there's a problem.
It's a problem because you have one
ideology that's overwhelmingly and control
of tech and I agree with them on a lot
of things on on social programs and a lot
of it on welfare and universal
basic income and civil
rights and women's rights.
I agree with them on a lot of stuff,
but it's an ideology like any
idea how you have to jump.
They were wrong but it doesn't have
free speech in it. There's a lot of,
there's a lot of y'all.
I just learned all this two weeks ago,
but I got documents. I'll come back
if you want, but you just let it ride.
I've been attacking the left for doing
it and they're the instrumental group
that's carrying it out. He would take
what? Defend if you're right wing fascist,
who you get to go after for each patient.
Do you get the left trunk of you?
Trick them and I'm not working.
Right wing is tricking the left
wing and the shutting down.
Free speech off confirmed.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I have confirmed it's Goddamn
conundrum that the Republican party,
not the the average,
you know tea party people.
The Republican party is blue blood.
It thinks it runs the Democrats
and it learned what was happening and I
can come back for a whole shovey one on
this one. Come on my show about it.
No, seriously. I'll come on your show.
I'm going to be in and
that's another part.
I'm going to be at a Cap City Comedy Club
in Austin. Promise amateur coming home.
I'm coming on are good. I'm coming on.
I'm not just saying this, I swear to God,
dude, I'll bring it to that stuff about
me. I'll tell you the bad stuff about me.
I'm telling you the truth here.
I believe you that tobacco was amazing,
but it was pretty good stuff.
You could transition my problem.
And why did you stand up?
Sure you could crush out show.
I'm not trying to lie.
Good. I'm not trying to like
bullshit like everybody else.
I'm telling you man. I, I I,
the problem is, it's so real.
Like every time I forget what I was
gonna say, what was I talking about?
You being a comic. Yeah. Man. I don't
know how to transition out of this.
What else you got planned?
We will be,
at the point we were just talking about
social media and Youtube and people
would be able to able to being able to
silence people and push their leftist
ideology or the right wing ideology.
He was saying that the Republicans
were manipulating the Democrats,
cause I know you're Shaker
it, you are empathetic real
guy. That's why I love you.
And you were kind of like
couldn't handle it anymore,
which I actually want to be like that.
So then you kind of dolled out.
So I was aggressive
because you look at it,
I have looked at all this stuff and I
have seen with their own perspectives and
their own plans are, and they go to
Congress and they lie about all of it.
They're not liberal than conservative.
It's big corporations lining up
with China as you shared earlier,
to unify the propaganda to
quote influence China. No Dude,
they get all the technology.
We,
they've used our open
society to totally take over.
And so that's what I'm trying to get
through to you is that is that they're
coming after everybody.
Like you said earlier,
when I first met you today that you
walk into the office, I was here,
Tim is for you to go.
I want to talk about the thing you said
about the censorship and how once they
get is to submit. We're broken. No,
it's what you said was it that it was
a slippery slope that if you give in 1%
it's 1% I still have this other other
99% and they just start moving the
boundaries. They started moving in closer
and closer and then 100% makes sense.
People exist in these,
these control patterns.
It's really common. They keep asking me
like, oh, when are you going to give up?
Everything's okay. As soon as you do like
wondering everything's gonna be okay.
What does that mean? What does
it, what does give up mean?
You stopped talking so people enjoy
watching. This is where it gets weird.
If people enjoy watching you
talk and other people don't,
why can't the Bbu don't just not
watch you talk. What is going on here?
He's promoting truth.
He is promoted truth.
But I think what they've done is they've
found these little pockets of things
and planning ahead.
Well that too,
but things that you said that maybe
you shouldn't to threaten everybody.
Like I don't want to put down the route
this up. I Make Jack Dorsey, this villain,
no,
that like we had pool and it's true.
They had millions of people harassing
the stock and attacking him lying on.
He's currently attacking children.
He's trying to attack children at their
houses and so it wasn't the fact that
I've gotten a CNA guy's face and I get
as a shareholder in a company owner,
I'm not defending Jack Dorsey or whatever
his name is. Yeah. What's the guy,
the other guy to want to know who the
other Guy Jack Dorsey's. The Twitter guys?
Yeah,
the jet and there's no other Darcy and
it's all admitted is what I'm saying is
I'm not even that guy's enemy.
I just,
I understand like he had millions of
people attacking the shareholders.
Did you hear about,
there's a chef that makes pastries,
which he's worked there 10
years at Trump's hotel in
Florida and buzzfeed found
out who she was and doctor and said,
she's a cult member fire. You're
like, what does that even mean?
Like why would anybody
harass a pastry chef?
That's a very good question. People
feel like they're a war, you know?
That's part of the problem
with all this shit.
That's why I was saying be reasonable.
People feel like they're at war,
the right versus the left,
instead of just being a bunch of people
talking about trying to figure it out,
at least take on Hillary or Alex shows
or are, or Bill Clinton or Donald Trump.
Well, Shit's winters
again. Pastry chef. Yeah.