The way. It's not mark that joke
anymore. There's a good strong,
well that's the weird wings of a
butterfly that becomes a hurricane, right?
Like we need to go back in your life and
think about weird little lefts you took
or rights you took when I have a bunch
of those. When I had three months ago,
I had a heart attack when I was on the
table because of the good doctor was just
like, uh, you, uh, you have, uh, a
hundred percent occlusion in your lad.
And I was like, I don't know what that
means. He says, your lad is, you're a,
is that main artery that goes across
the front of your heart? He's going, uh,
it's a hundred percent occlusion,
means a hundred percent blocked,
you've got cholesterol is blocked,
there's no way for blood to get through.
And that's what's creating your mass part
of tech. So he's like, we're going to,
we're going to take care of it right now.
He goes, but you're a comic Book Guy,
right? I said, yeah. And
he goes, you'll like this,
that artery that's called the widow
maker. And I said, why? And he goes,
because 80% of cases of 100% occlusion,
the patient always dies.
He's gone, but you're going to be in the
20% because I'm really good at my job.
And he fucking disappeared into my crotch,
one of my groin to my femoral artery and
fucking went up into my heart and put a
stent in that, in that lad. And
the moment he opened up, he goes,
I'm gonna open it up now.
And he showed me what it was,
tiny little mesh wire thing. He goes, I'm
gonna open it. Boom. Suddenly it was like,
I,
cause that artery had been like a hose.
If you bend it and it's fucking full of
water and shit was pushing down in the
heart, which was in turn
pushing down on my lungs.
I had no idea it was
having a heart attack.
I just thought like I couldn't catch
my breath. I thought it was too hot.
It was in between shows in between
two gigs. That was the filming.
We shot them both while we
were going to shoot them both.
We only shot the one because I had the
heart attack and we didn't do the second
one, but it was for, uh,
for the folks at comedy dynamics
and it became a showtime special.
So we were shooting two shows that night.
It was meant to be like an
hour and an hour. But you know,
once you get up there I feel like
I'm fucking rolling. I'm rolling.
So I did two hours and after
the first show they were like,
we don't even need to do the second show.
We can cut an that we're only
cutting an hour out of it.
So you gave us plenty and stuff.
I said,
I got two different hours so
I want to do the second show.
And plus everyone was there.
They were lined up.
And so I took a big swig of
fucking milk cows, dairy drinker,
heavy dairy drinker.
In those days I've since become Vegan ice,
be happy now I'm fucking Vegan.
But uh, I took a big swig of milk,
then I went to the green room and I
chitchatted real quick with Jordan,
who runs our company as Jason's
wife, chase muses, wife. And, uh,
Emily was there, she does my hair
and makeup, so we're Chitchat.
And then I was like, man, I
feel fucking weird. I feel sick.
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
Can you guys get Outta here?
Cause when I get sick I just want to go
off like an animal and fucking die alone.
Like I don't want to be ministered to.
I'm like fuck off and shit.
So they were like, yeah, totally.
And I laid down on the floor
and I felt like nauseous,
nauseated and I never feel sick like
that and wound up throwing up some bile,
nothing chunky but just like
fluid. And so I was like, well,
and maybe I'll feel better now.
Stood up and I looked in the
mirror and I was just swamped man.
Like now as a heavy dude, you sweat when
he fucking breathe. But this was like,
I'd look like I'd just come out of
the pool and I felt really cold.
I couldn't get warm and ship. Emily popped
her head and she's like, are you okay?
I was like, no man. Can you turn on like
a hairdryer and just like draw me off.
I feel fucking freezing cold.
And she touched the back of my neck
while she's driving me. She's like,
you never feel like this. This is scary.
You should do something. I said, yeah.
I said I would still want to
do that second show as like
someone to find a couch,
just find a cash for me to lay down.
If I get like a half hour nap,
I'm sure I'll be fucking fine. And I
couldn't get comfortable on the couch,
couldn't sleep.
And that's when I started not being able
to catch my fucking breath. So you know,
I'm no doctor but like
fucking you think you know,
I know my body and I know what this is.
I smoked too much weed and I've got
too much mucus in my fucking chest.
That's all this is.
So I said,
I better sit up and put my arms up like
this because that will help me breathe.
And Jordan comes around the
corner eventually and she
sees me. She's like, oh,
you're right. And I was like, you know,
having a hard time catching my breath.
I could breathe. I just can't get all the
way to the top and stuff of the breath.
Can't take a full fucking
breath. I was like, ah, maybe I,
maybe we shouldn't do that second
show after all. And she goes,
we already canceled it.
And I was like,
why the fuck did you cancel the
second show? And she was like,
cause I'd never seen you sick like this.
He's gone, you know this, this is weird.
Something's going on. I said,
yeah, maybe I should see a doctor.
And she goes to Sunday night, all doctors
are closed. So we called an ambulance.
I was like, why the fuck did you call
an ambulance? Oh my God, this is don't,
this is embarrassing. She's
like, they're already here.
And six fireman came into the room,
big brawny fucking dude's
when he called paramedics,
fire department comes as well. So, uh,
they're looking at me cause I'm sitting
in the chair with my arms up and like
there were, some of them were young,
four of them are young. And I looked,
they looked at me like, why is silent
Bob celebrating a fucking touchdown?
You know, and she doesn't like all of a
sudden the medics came in and they, uh,
there was a guy and a girl and the
guy puts a cuff on me. He goes,
how you doing man? I said, good, I can't
really catch my breath. And, uh, he goes,
well, we're gonna look at you right now.
Put this Kufanya you ever had this done?
I said, Oh yeah, I know how to do
this. And then the girl had a, uh,
like look like a fishing tackle box.
I had a bunch of leads,
wires coming out of it and shit,
she put that down as heart monitor thing,
you know, they get your fucking blood
pressure, all that shit on one arm.
Then the other thing they put on your
chest to monitor what's going on inside.
So she's like,
I got to put these wires on you as okay.
And I'm sitting in the chair and this
is 40 pounds ago and sitting is no good
angle for fucking fat guy to
begin with and shit like that.
So she just yanks my fucking hockey shirt
and the undershirt up and every tiddy
I have falls out of my fucking shirt in
front of these people and there's a room
full of people and I'm like, oh, lead
fucking shit. And I yanked my shit down.
She's like, what are you
doing? I was like, man,
that's my fucking best friend's wife over
there. She never seen my fucking tits.
My wife's never seen
much. It's like, I can't,
you don't Yank my shirt up like that. She
goes, Hey, get these wires on you. I said,
well, oh the shirt are you reach up
under and put them on my chest. He goes,
how am I supposed to seek?
And I was like,
do you just use my nipples as
guideposts? Like it was, you know,
I've spent all of my life trying to hide
my fucking fat and when your life is in
danger, I've never been in that situation.
But when your life is in danger,
nobody gives a fuck about your fucking
ego and shit. Like their vanity.
So they looked at their info and they
realize, I guess what was going on.
And they were like, we're going to take
you to the hospital just to be safe.
And I was like, don't do that.
That's fucking embarrassing and shit.
And they were like, Nah, we're
so close man. It'll be fun.
You ever been to the hospital?
I was like, no, not really.
Feel like it's all so fuck. It's fun.
He goes, you're gonna have a good time.
I was like, all right. And you know,
I'm a podcaster, so I'm like, look,
at the end of the day, no time is
wasted. Everything's a fucking story.
So if this turns into the opening five
minutes of Hollywood Babylon where I'm
like,
they took me to the hospital and it
turned out it was just too fucking high.
Like it's life's great when you're a
podcaster because there's no such thing as
fucking bad news anymore. Like it hit,
it can hit you on the level of like,
Oh shit, that's unfortunate.
But right away you repurpose
it into like, all right,
well I've got something to talk about.
And this latest setback is just the
longest is just a momentary chapter in the
long story.
Or fucking tell him.
So I was happy to go to the
hospital and not because I was like,
I think I'm dying, but because
I was like, all right, fuck it.
I'll have a story to tell after
this next week. It'll be fun.
I got to the hospital like Dr Laden,
Jaime's the guys now, my cardiologist,
they pulled me into the er and
he's like, hi, how are you?
I'm Doctor Leighton him and said, hey man,
how are you? He goes, well, what's wrong?
What's going on? And I said, I can't
catch my breath. Um, and he goes, well,
that's because you're having
a massive heart attack.
And it was the first time anyone
had said anything like that.
How did he know for sure
if that's what he does?
I think what he knew for sure was when
they put the leads on me and the blood
pressure,
they looked at each other at one point,
but I assumed like in like numbers
that'll show up to indicate that something
just happened and they made this wonderful
call. I've got to find these kids,
give him a hug one day.
Ah,
on the call sheet because we were
shooting that night on the call sheet.
It was a different hospital,
but they took me to Glendale Adventist
because they knew that I was in having a
cardiac episode and that's shy
of one hospital in New York.
Glen Dale Adventist is one of the best
cardiology wings in the United States of
America. So I happen to be in the
right fucking place at the right time.
We were supposed to shoot my
comedy special at the Ryman
Auditorium in Nashville.
Um, it wound up being shot instead at
the Alex in, in Glendale and stuff.
And if I hadn't been doing the show there,
who fucking knows man,
I'm gone to a hospital but I probably
might've fucking died cause homeboy told
me when he went up the heart when I was
in the operating room and he told me
like, they call that the widow
maker and shit, 80%, 80, 20.
I sat there going like, these are the
weirdest Todd's I've ever had in my life.
I figure like, look, you
leave the house, it's 50 50,
you're going to fucking drop dead.
Right.
They get hit by a car
struck by lightening,
you can trip over fucking dog and then
the dog bites your juggler and you
fucking bleed out your look. But I
always loved dogs and you die ironically,
but uh, you know, just stringing
along. But the 80 20 men,
20% chance of life was fucked up,
fucked up thought.
First time I'd ever had
that kind of thought.
And in my head I had to cognitively
reframe it and go, you don't know,
you might've been close to death
so many fucking times in your life.
There might've been like a psycho behind
you with a fucking knife and then all
of sudden you've got a cell phone call
and forgot about you or something like
that. So suddenly our repurposed it the
whole time I was laying on the table,
I'll get repurposing everything,
not repurpose and cognitively reframing.
I was sitting because I couldn't
like at one point they were like,
your wife's on the phone. Do you
want to say you want to talk to her?
After they told me that I was having a
heart attack and that they had to get up
and be fast and stuff.
So they're holding up a phone and I see
it and as the first time a crystallized
where I was like, oh, these, these people
think I'm going to die. Like I didn't.
I was in no pain whatsoever.
I couldn't catch my breath.
They kept asking me like zero to 10.
How do you feel? What's your pain level?
I was like, negative three. They'll
look, you're doing this wrong.
I didn't feel pain. It wasn't like, yeah,
I grew up in the 70s
watching Sanford and son.
So my idea of a heart attack is loose,
but that's big and shit felt none of
the symptoms, no numbness in the arm,
anything like that. I was sweating a,
I threw up bile, a little bit of bile.
Um, I was cold and, and
what was the last one?
It was just fucking shit. You would
never associate with a heart attack.
And like you would associate it with like,
oh, I just, I feel under the weather.
But apparently these are symptoms
of heart attacks as well.
I like to share it because some
cats never heard that before.
And I've seen a lot of people on
social media since we were like,
you saved my life.
Here's why.
Because I talked about the
fucking symptoms and shit.
So while I'm laying there and they go up,
you're growing,
they go up your femoral artery
to your heart and stuff.
He went up and he saw that
it was all blocked. He,
I said later on I was just like,
fuck man.
Like I'd like dropped 80
pounds three years ago.
I've been like walking up a hill mile
and a half every day and stuff. He goes,
yeah,
but the kind of blockage you had you go
to that didn't start fucking recently.
He's gone. That started in childhood and
I was like, man, fucking hostess Twinkies.
And then I remembered we had
no money so I was like, man,
fucking little Debbie Swiss delights
and shit. That's how it happened.
It started with a little Debbie cakes.
I'm with you cause I was raised
Dunham and shit. But you know,
we were trained to like Twinkies more
because they had a commercial little,
Debbie would never
bother with a commercial.
They didn't have a commercial
did day. No, you can't. Well,
the leaders later they did,
but when we were kids,
they didn't because how can you have
a commercial and sell your product,
but they're only 9 cents a bottle?
Easter cake.
It's like a better experience because
they had more of those trans fats that
have trans fats back then. I think
so. And then they could call and fats.