Nobody had ever scientifically
investigated this until an incredible guy.
I got to know cook
Professor Tim [inaudible],
who's at Knox College in
Illinois and Professor Cassa, uh,
made some really important
breakthroughs in this. So
there's two ways everyone listening to
your show has two kinds of motivation in
their life, right? We're
all a mixture of both.
So imagine if you played the piano in
the morning cause you love playing the
piano. It gives you joy, right?
That would be what's called an intrinsic
reason to play the piano, right?
You're not doing it to get anything out
of it. That's just, that's the thing.
You lot of rice, I was like,
you didn't see was like that.
Bu Writing is like that for me.
Everyone will have something in their
life that just gives them joy as they do
it. Right? Okay. Now imagine you
played the piano, not, I dunno,
not because you love it, but because your
parents are massively pressuring you.
It's their dream view or in a dive bar
that you can't stand to pay the rent or
cuts impress a woman.
Right?
That would be what's called an extrinsic
reasons to play the piano, right?
You're not doing it because
that thing gives you joy.
You're doing it to get something
further down the line. Right? Now,
obviously we're all a mixture of both,
but professor Casio showed a couple
of really interesting things. Firstly,
the more you are driven
by extrinsic values,
the more your intrinsic
values are starved,
the more likely we are to
become depressed and anxious,
but quite significant amount.
He also showed as a culture,
as a society, we have become much more
driven by these junk values, right?
We've become much more driven by think
about how Instagram makes you feel. Sure.
Right?
We've become much more driven by
this hollow external sense of it.
Think about something as simple as,
well,
a while ago I was the Elton John's
last night in Caesar's palace, right?
Amazing thing to be at and about half
the fucking room is, is filming it on.
That isn't even looking at Elton John.
They're just watching it through their
phone, that that's a small example.
But you can see what they're doing
in order to display their life,
to invite envy from other people.
They are not living their life.
No one wants to watch your
shitty video about. And John,
there's a hundred thousands of,
uh,
of videos about and John that are
much better than yours, right?
Why are you doing that?
You're never going to watch it either.
You're doing it to say to
other people, envy me, right?
It doesn't make you feel good in that
room actually makes you feel worse.
You're not enjoying the experience and
it makes them feel like shit because it
makes you, you're trying to
invite envy in your friends.
That's a small example of a much wider
thing of the kind of junk values that
have taken our minds.
So the reason that relates to what you're
asking about Brazil is Presser Kasler
shown there's two sets of solutions to
these junk values taken over our minds.
One is, it's like fucking
air pollution. You know,
get the messaging out of your head.
More 18 month old children know
what the Mcdonald's m means,
the know their own Cerner, their own
last name, right? Um, from the moment it,
professor Casap put it to me
from the moment we're born,
we're immersed in a machine that is
designed to get us to neglect what is
important about life,
right?
None of your listeners will lie on their
death beds or think about all the shit
they bought and all the likes.
They got an Instagram.
They'll think about moments and meaning
and connection. That's like a banal,
obvious thing. But we're constantly
pushed to not think in those terms,
to think about, show
it off by spend. Right?
These junk values have
taken over our minds.
So part of the solution is just fucking
get rid of most of this advertising.
Get rid of most of this, you
know, very tightly regulated.
But in doing so,
you limit commerce,
you're limiting people's
ability to sell things. You're,
you're changing the current market that
a lot of people don't have any problem
with. I know this is a
heresy in the United States,
but limits in commercial speech
is fine by me. Yeah. I've,
I think it's fascinating. I think it's a
fascinating discussion, but it is in the,
in a sense it's limiting free
speech as well. I mean that,
and we have a real problem with that.
The problem with it is that as soon as
you start to put any regulations at all
and you know, he say, Oh, you shouldn't
be allowed to advertising to advertise,
even if it's advertising, honestly
about a great product that people were,
we'll have real issues with that.
We already have advertising regulation.
You can't, you can't pop an advert
saying I've found the cure for cancer.
That's what I'm saying. So this is still,
I would argue this is a tightening.
So for example, in London there was a big
controversy, um, a couple of years back.
Any billboards. Exactly. So it was this,
it was a billboard of a impossibly hot
women and impossibly hot man and the
billboards that something like,
are you beach body ready?
The clear implication being,
if you don't look like these people who
you'll never fucking look like you're
not ready to go to the beach. And the
mayor of London City can just said this,
you can't do this. Right. You can
still advertise your bodybuilding,
but that's so silly. I mean, this is
a, it's not an unobtainable ideal.
You're looking at two examples of it,
but there are real human beings. Yeah,
but that's like, I mean, I know
why I started listening. I mean,
I'm not saying that you
have to be that way,
but if you do want to look like
that man and have that body,
it is a possible goal.
Yeah.
I mean it's not possible for the
vast majority of people, right?
Like if they don't have the
time or the effort, it's not,
but very many people have radically
changed their body. I'm not saying,
not saying you should do it.
I decided this is a possible thing to
do and if you're trying to sell fitness,
wouldn't you sell an example of
someone who's really good at it?
Like if you're trying to
sell a business course,
wouldn't you show a guy with a
giant house and a Ferrari? Like,
this is a guy who's done
really well at business,
look at his penthouse apartment
overlooking Manhattan. You wouldn't show,
you wouldn't say,
well that's an impossible goal.
I'm going to show you a person in a middle
class suburb because this is as good
as you're ever going to get.
I think that's a fair point.
I think it's two things going
on, isn't there? There's
the freedom of people to market what
they want to do and there's, um,
it's a nanny state issue that people
have a problem with you by saying that
these are impossible
to achieve body goals.
We already have regulation
at these things.
So people don't call
that a nanny state thing.
I think just this idea of
regulation, these things, but that,
that is not this.
I don't think there's a good example.
What to I was a better example.
So Professor Kassar said there's two
sets of solutions to these junk valley's
problems. There's, um,
get the contaminants out of
the atmosphere sort of thing,
which he says is actually a weaker one
than the second set of solutions is.
So how do we stop people being pumped
full of bullshit, junk valleys, right?
Educate them on what is happening to
them and make it less appealing. Well,
this is the second part and you've gone
to what I think was the most important
part of the research
professor Cassa did see,
was working with a guy called Nathan
Dungan. And Nathan is a hearing to be,
Nathan is a
financial advisor in Minneapolis.
And his job was to work with adults
who were found trouble budgeting and
explained budgeting to them
and help them do it right?
And it gets a call from a school.
It was kind of middle class
school wasn't super rich or poor,
it was a middle class,
uh,
where they're having a problem
that the kids at this school,
we're becoming obsessed with getting like
the latest Nike sneakers or the latest
iPhone or whatever it was.
And if their parents couldn't afford it,
the kids were really freaking
out. Right? So they say to Nathan,
would you come in and just explain
budgeting to these kids? Right?
So Nathan goes in and he tries to explain
budgeting and quickly realize is these
kids don't give a shit about budgetary,
right?
There's something else going on here.
They are so obsessed with getting
these things. So with Professor Cassa,
he designs this program that
led to really interesting, uh,
breakthrough and it's saying
people can try at home, right?
You don't have to do in this context.
So they'd got,
and you can do it just as
adults, but they did it with, uh,
parents and the teenagers,
right? They come in,
it was once every couple of
weeks for think four months.
And at first they just say the first
meeting they had, they just said,
write a list of everything you have got
to have. They didn't define that right.
And people of course say
like a home, a car, whatever.
But quite quickly people
would say Nike sneakers,
the parents would name expensive
things and they got, okay,
tell me how you would feel if
you got these Nike sneakers.
Right. And very rarely,
I only, any of them were like
basketball players where it's like,
I need the jump or whatever.
If that's the right phrase. Um,
it was very off ob almost immediately
it's I'd be accepted by the group.
People would envy me, right? These,
these insights are just beneath
the surface where they go,
who put that idea in your head?
Where did you get that idea?
And of course everyone thinks
they're smarter than the ad,
but giving people the ability just
to see how hollow those junk values,
where that was the first part,
second part was much more interesting
and took longer than I would have in
future sessions. They'd say, well, okay,
given that's not actually
made you feel better.
What are moments in your life
when you have felt satisfied,
happy in a flow state? What are
things that are meaningful to you?
People you know,
a whole range of things.
Playing sports or play music or
reading, whatever it was, right?
And they say,
okay,
how could we build more of that into
your life and less of these junk values?
How could you do more of this
every week and just meeting?
We'd have these conversations
in our culture very often.
Just meeting once every couple of weeks
and checking in with each other and go,
actually, I managed to play
guitar for an hour every day.
I managed on Saturday to take
my kid to the beach and we went,
or whatever it can to stifle materialism.
What it led to,
six is monitored by professor Cassar.
It led to a significant shifts in
people's valleys that they, they, they,
they had a significant decrease in junk
ponies and a significant increase in,
in a more meaningful intrinsic values.
And we know that that correlates with
lower depression and anxiety over time.
The weird thing is I sometimes feel like
with all my, we both my books chasing,
screaming,
lost connection.
So I sometimes feel like I'm giving
people permission to know the thing they
already know.