No close enough.
I'm sure there's no thrill for you.
But do you think that being
in these incredibly tense
environments ramps life up
in a way that you don't get outside of
it? Like did you, did you read tribe?
Sebastian younger look, yeah. And
I met him a few times while he was,
he was when I was having a few problems.
He was, he was very helpful. He was,
wasn't he really good guy? Yeah. I
really liked that guy. Yeah. Yeah.
Before I met him.
And he's got that picture in vanity fair,
like posing with the dog tag and
it's like a muddle looking picture.
Guys were tossed her. Yeah. Yeah. And
then I met him and he was the nicest,
most humble, considerate
guy. He's, he's fantastic.
And I really like that book
as well. Yeah. I couldn't,
I couldn't be a bigger fan of his, as
a human to just do, just very genuine,
really there when you're talking to them.
But that's sort of his take on it is
that, um, and if you're listening,
I know I talk about that book
too much. Uh, I just love it,
but his take on it was that these
people are experiencing life in this
incredibly extreme environment and then
they come back to the rest of the world
and it just doesn't feel real anymore.
So it's not,
it's not thrilling when you're there,
but it is real drama.
You're seeing life and death
drama right in front of your face.
So when you come back,
you think you really want to see
this person and see this film,
try out this new restaurant and
then you get back and you just eat.
Just don't care. It's just feel flat.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, you know, when,
when I was getting the PTSD treatment,
numb, numbness was the word that came out.
More numbness to everything, like
numbness to the danger when you're there,
but numbness back here for the things
that should be pleasurable and should be
providing some kind of relief as well.
Now,
how did the pts PTSD treatment
get organizes through maps?
Are you part of that study? Yeah,
we did a did a short film about,
about Rick Doblin and this, this,
you know, there's this effort to,
to get MDM illegal. Um, but I'd
been in denial for years and years.
Then a new producer joined vice guy
called Steven Bailey and we had the first
idea where he was pitching some,
some of the first meeting when he
was pitching some of his ideas and he
mentioned, you know, this breakthrough
therapy using MDM may for PTSD.
And I just in voluntarily put my hand
up and said I'll do it straight away.
And I was like, gave me an
excuse to actually, you know,
get some help and see if actually done
MTMA recreationally before that. I mean,
yeah, I came of age in London in
the 90s, you know, he was like,
it was like having a pint of beer.
Then what is the difference between
doing it in a therapeutic environment?
I mean, it's, it's, it's
Mtma assisted therapy, right?
The emphasis is on the therapy.
So you're lying in a bed if you fasted
for 24 hours before the therapist knows
you and knows your issues. Um,
so knows how to like politely,
gently nudge you towards the right topic
of conversation, but always makes it,
makes you actually get to the
conclusions. Um, you know,
there are times when I would ask him, why
is this happening? Why do I think this?
And He'd put it back on me and make
me put two and two together. Um,
sometimes you listen to music,
sometimes you put an eye
mask on and you don't sleep,
but you just have a quiet
20, 30 minutes. But it's a,
it's a very intense seven to eight hour
therapy session and the MD may just
enables you to get the benefits.
And all of the veterans and
first responders who took
part in the first round of
trials had been therapy resistant.
Um, and I think the first round,
I think 72% of them got the benefits.
And we're considered PTSD free after,
after the three month trial.
So during the three month trial,
how many experiences do they have? One
a month. One a month or three? Three.
Totally. Yeah. Yeah. I mean the best,
the best example I can
give of how this works,
I had the first veteran I
met had been through it.
He had one session and he'd lost some
friends in Iraq and it felt guilty about
it and always thought maybe if I had done
something different I could have saved
them.
And he imagined being them in in the
first Mbma session and they were saying to
him, why are you ruining your
life? You're alive, you're healthy.
We want you to have a fun,
productive,
full life and enjoy your
friends and enjoy your family.
And he said that gave him permission
and that was what he needed.
He didn't even do the second two sessions.
Wow.
That's a what an interesting
way of looking at, of course.
And that word permission,
because there is so much guilt and just
getting permission to just give yourself
a bit of a pattern. The survivors of
your braking is real. Oh yeah. Yeah.
A lot of people that come back from the
war that lost friends have that horrible
feeling that it should've been them.
That they're not as good as the person
who died or that somehow or another them
being alive is the reason
why their friend was dead.
Irrational thoughts or maybe I didn't
really experience it because I came out
unscathed. Um, yeah,
which is one of the reasons why I didn't
seek treatment for years and years and
years cause I've got friends
who've lost their legs.
I've got friends who were
kidnapped and killed, you know,
so maybe I've only just dipped my
toes so there's nothing, nothing.
I've got nothing to complain about.
What was your number one issue?
Um, I think the numbness to danger and
to, to pleasurable things back here.
Um, I mean like my, my
camera man in Mosul,
we were there when the Iraqi army
beat Isis and it was, I mean,
it was house to house fighting. We were
stepping on bodies to get through rooms.
And at one point,
um,
as with we were with three or four Iraqi
soldiers trying to get to the river to
cut off these two isis positions and
they've got a radio message saying there's
a suicide bomber and a gunman running
down the street towards you now.
So we stepped into this,
what used to be a shop that was
all blown up and smashed a bit.
And I sat down as the two soldiers tried
to shoot this suicide bomber as he was
running towards us and someone said,
IED IUD.
And right next to me under the rubble
was an IED. The day before, I think,
or two days before to French journalists
and Curtis journalists who had been
killed when they stepped on an IED
trying to get out and have ea Manzano,
my camera man just said,
you looked bored. Um,
and he filmed it like we got that moment
on camera and I remember just looking
so bored and I couldn't give a shit
about the suicide bomber, the IED.
I was just bought out of my brains.
And that's when I thought this is,
this is not a natural reaction to,
to what's going on around you right now.
What did you think your natural reaction
should have been? I mean, blood rating,
racing, heart rate, increasing, you
know, um, vigilance, um, you know,
and what did you think at the time
was the cause of you being numb?
Like while it was happening, I hadn't
really thought that much about PTSD.
I just thought it'd
become so used to this.
And one of the things that came up in the,
in one of the last sessions I did was
I didn't think I was him as important
enough to get to get shot and hurt and
have medics rush over to help me and
maybe a helicopter take
the out and, you know, um,
I know that sounds ridiculous now,
but I think part of me thought, yeah,
you're not important enough to have
something so dramatic happen to you.
You're just, you're just witnessing
other people in these dramas.
Wow.
To be right next to an IUD and not
freaking out is pretty crazy. Yeah.
With a suicide bomber riding down the
street towards, I mean that's, and also,
you know, people, people,
one of the reasons you feel guilty is
you do get respect for being brave.
And I would say it wasn't bravery.
I wasn't scared and then did it anyway.
I wasn't scared. I was just
numb and just, you know,
kept looking at respect from other
journalists, from the soldiers.
Like who are you getting
respect from? Yeah. Or,
or people that watched the films
or, yeah. And uh, it doesn't,
it doesn't feel like bravery.
It just feels like you're,
you know, you've, you've,
you've become stupid about
the risks you're taking.
So talk me through this therapy.
So you're fast for 24 hours,
you take the Mtma and then they just
start talking to you about the things that
are troubling.
Yeah.
So you take 125 milligrams and then
when that hits about that a lot,
I think it's a good dose, but then
when it hits, you take another 75.
So overall that, that's a
good dose and that keeps you
up for, you know, six, seven,
eight hours. Um, and then, you know,
the therapist would ask
very brief question. Just,
just knowing what direction to push me.
And I remember the first session, I mean,
I'd thought because of
what I now know was PTSD,
I'd thought because of the job I do and
because there was this kind of darkness
in there,
I didn't get involved with anyone
seriously for a very long time and even
thought I'm not going to have a family
and kids and house and dog and you know,
I just just hadn't even thought about it.
Just assumed that that's not
for me because of the job I do.
And very early on in that first session
after I resisted it for about an hour
and a half,
like was really resisting it for a long
time and thinking it was even a placebo.
Um, but, but there was this wave of
relief. I've just, of course you can,
of course you can have all that.
And it,
it felt like a revelation
because I thought I,
that had been close to me for so long. I
know, seven, eight years, maybe longer.
I just thought now that you can't do that,
that's not for you or you can't put
someone else through that with you.
What is it particularly about MDM may,
what is it about,
I mean I've done it but
I've only done it once.
The is it just because of the fact that
it just alleviates the insecurity and
allows you to look at things
in a more natural sense?
You look at everything as if we're just
talking about having coffee or water,
everything is just easy to think
about on a dress and talk about. Um,
and I think I'll probably
explain it badly,
but I think the science of it is you
have five networks in your brain and,
and I was basically in fight or flight
mode so much that that was the only mode
on you. So even when I'm back in New York,
if someone walks up to close behind me,
I'm expecting a confrontation.
I'm in fight or flight mode all the time.
So your brain is ignoring the other
parts of your brain that provide context.
And that say that bang outside
is just the car back firing.
It's not an id or someone shooting to
the Mtma just allows your brain to,
you know, all the parts of your
brain to communicate. Again,
you're not just in that
fight or flight mode.
So once you get out of
that fight or flight mode,
you can then address things that, that
you couldn't even begin to address before.
And once you've had these experiences
for you, it was three experiences.
They're profound enough that
you retain the benefits. Some,
I mean it looks like I'm in the 25% that
still have PTSD after the three months,
but it still helped enormously.
I mean,
the next day they got me to sit down
and do a video diary and I was kind of
saying, yeah, I thought this
near, this was a revelation.
And I said, you know what,
I'm just,
I'm just smiling now in a way that I
don't feel like I've smiled for years.
Like it feels like my whole face is
smiling and this is the next day,
which is usually a little wrecked.
Yeah,
I think it's two or three
days when you have the,
what we used to call a moody Tuesday, two
or three days. Yeah. But there with this,
there, there's no, there's
no come down. Um, with this,
it's, it's, you know, there,
there,
there's no downside how they give you,
they give you five HTP or
anything while you're, um,
nothing apart from the MD may or may
not. Wow. You have, you have juice,
you have water throughout.
Um, I mean maybe they come
down is related to, you know,
people that used to take it
with just dance and sweat.
Right. All nightly hydrate.
Yeah. Yeah. Maybe. Maybe it's a
Shitty Mtma maybe you just feel shit.
Yeah, I mean the, yeah.
The ecstasy they would've sold in London
would have been the rat poison and
breeze block dust and
all kinds of, yeah. Um,
so I know they're having very
positive results with this.
And are they planning on implementing
this to the public in any terror short
term?
I mean,
is this something that like people
that are listening to this right now,
it's just going to be
available to them fairly soon?
It looks like it should be legal by 2021,
2022,
the third round of officially FDA
approved trials start soon. Um,
that's the first one that involves
people other than veterans and first
responders. If that gets as good
results of the first two trials,
which I'm sure it will then,
then I think it's going to be,
and because FDA gave it
breakthrough drug status,
there's nothing that you know
anyone can do to stop it.
It will be legal by 2021 2022.
That's very good news for a lot of
people that are suffering. Yeah.
It's so difficult for people
to change perspective just to,
to have a break from the normal sort of
momentum of your life and to be able to
stop and analyze.
Yeah.