Should've thrown a knee. Did you watch
the chocolate? They'll fight. Uh,
just the end of it. Yeah. No good. Right.
How old is he now? 50. Yeah. So
there's hope for me. Oh wait.
He lost ships. Well, you've never
been knocked out the way he's,
he's been knocked out so many times.
I don't think I've ever been knocked out.
Not In the gym. Not over flash.
Flash knockdown. That's it. Yeah.
I've had concussions been knocked out
from like falling and the rain falling off
a second floor landing when I was a kid.
Right.
But in finding and never
[inaudible] chucks also,
I think there was an issue with his style
because his style was so aggressive,
aggressive that people
could just set, set, set,
boom and counter like
Rashad Evans did with him.
And so you're getting his momentum
coming forward and the Cheyenne,
we get flat line. He doesn't
change. No, he doesn't.
No evolve.
He had a style that was incredibly
affective back in the day.
Yeah. I think he became
married to that, that approach.
You know the approach that works so
well on Bob Ballou so well on Tito.
In the early fights,
he was just a marauder.
You could hit him in the face of the
fucking crow bar and he would just spit
metal out at you. You didn't give a
fuck. He was so bad ass back in the day.
He relied on that so much. I
remember all the Mohawks. Yeah.
Everybody was a little kid. Yeah.
That's how I like to wear Mohawks.
Back in the day,
people were getting in Japanese symbols
tattooed on their head because of him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's just,
that's that style. There's,
this comes a certain point in time. You
just can't do that anymore. You know?
I think, um, I dunno,
like it's a martial
artist, you know, and, uh,
artists evolve and they're like,
oh, well let me try this new paint.
Oh, let me try the,
this, this new technique.
Let me try this shading. Let me, you
know, start sculpting. Let me try.
And I think with, uh,
especially MMA, you know,
there's so much opportunity
to evolve, just add new, new,
new nuances to you as an artist. I mean,
I think that's what I love about it.
There's certainly is, yes. But
one thing that does happen when,
when guys try to add a lot of things,
like sometimes they'll try to like say
a wrestler will add a bunch of things to
his repertoire,
but then they stopped with the wrestling.
The wrestling is not as sharp and so then
when they go up against a really good
wrestler,
they falter and then they're,
they don't have what brought them to the
dance and the first place. Yeah. Yeah.
But I think that's just, uh, looking at
your opponent and what's in front of you.
And also like being honest
with yourself and like,
like right now I'm looking at
getting back into fighting.
And if I didn't feel the sharpness,
I didn't,
I didn't feel the fire
and not just the fire.
If I didn't physically feel the sharpness,
if I didn't feel the reflexes,
I'd have to be honest myself
and say, okay, don't do this.
Do you think that you were Oh,
100% be capable of being rational and
objective about what you can do right now?
Yeah. Yeah, because I don't, I don't
fight for participation awards.
Like, Hey, I'm a, but there's
some UFC fighters are like,
I'm a UFC fighter. Right.
Yay. I've made it. Like that's not
really making it. You're just another,
you know, like say I'm a world champion.
I'm a the best in the world. Emma that's,
I'm a UFC fighter is like a
participation metal basically like level.
It shows that you're a
very high level fighter.
You're not a champion in your eyes.
You and champion.
That is what's important.
You want to be the queen.
You want to be a top of the hill. We went
to the best of your best self, you know,
self. Yeah, yeah.