The joe rogan experience.
Colon colon cancer. Okay,
so that makes sense. With the animas.
It's no joke. Fuck man. So he beat it.
That's beautiful. God it's, he's young
d at 50 you should all have like,
I had the gate, my fucking colon
leadership up your butthole.
I got to clean but ho they stick
a tube up there. I had a candle.
Did you like wrap your
legs around in your arms?
Like this year there was a private, what's
proud to come there? It's a private,
it's a private question.
Did you let get up?
He smelled like how long he's right
now showing you my doctor smells like
Cologne and he was a really nice
guy and he didn't wear gloves. Yeah,
you're showing us how it's done Joe.
Like check this out.
That's how you do it bro. And his
breath smells like pineapple. Yeah,
that's all I'm going to say.
I was talking to a guy the other day
that had meant breath over shit breath so
confused. Told him that his
breath smelled like shit.
And so he was eating mince but it wasn't
good enough. So it was like I was,
it was, you know what it was like,
man. It was like, it was confusing.
It was like there's two signals
that were clashing with each other.
What's awful for the folks listening
at home that aren't broadcasters,
I'm not naming names,
we're not going to name any names to
broadcasts with somebody who's breasts
because they turned to you and you'd
have to stay close to him to stay in the
two shot. That's a problem. You
can't go, you can't react to it all.
And it is,
I brush my teeth like religiously when
I'm doing camera stuff because I'm in
someone's face talking to them and I've
been on the receiving end of that and
been like this,
you can't do it after shows.
When you take pictures guys,
that's got to be girls. And guys,
sometimes you're just like, God
dammit, I don't know what's going on.
They say when people don't eat a lot,
like if you, uh, yeah. Is that real?
Like if you, a few things I
know with a chronic halitosis,
apparently it's the sulfates on your
tongue. Whoa. There's a, there's a so,
so typically I guess the,
so the chemicals,
I guess the sulfur that everybody has
different compounds in their mouth and for
whatever reason, I don't
know. But they're there.
They essentially what you're smelling
is sulfur is a derivative of sulfur,
some kind of assault.
And it's because there's
a chemical problem in your
mouth and they can actually
address it with yeah. And I
was like, tell him to tell us,
this can also be from bad from liver
disease. So if you have a liver disease,
you don't shut liver disease,
diabetes, liver disease, stuff like about
the breath. Wow. Wow. That's interesting.
Yeah. That's one of the
ways they check. Yeah. Whoa.
And then of course it can be
uh, an abscess behind your
tooth and all that. Yeah,
that's a big one, man. That's
what everyone's [inaudible]
and diabetes diabetics.
Dude, I had a cracked filling and
they took the filling out. Oh.
And the fucking smell that came
out of my mouth, I was like,
Holy Shit.
Cause the,
the filling had cracked
and there was an infection.
I had a wound up getting a root canal.
And so as I'm getting this
list thing like opened up,
they break through this pocket.
We're all this puss and rot is, yeah.
Oh Dude, it was so nasty. Sounds awful.
It like you could hear it like pop
through and then just this fucking shit
breath. They can't fires. My
father is fine. He was sleeping.
His wife said,
you have to go to the dentist said,
why does your breath is so out of control?
And they'd been married for 25 years.
So he goes, Jesus. All right, so, so,
so check this out.
This is so apparently he had an abscess,
a sack of bacteria in the back of his
mouth. Well, when they, when they,
I guess took the tooth out of the
filling out and they popped by accident,
the sac,
the nurse threw up
fucking dentist. The dentist
walked into the room at that moment
and through to fuck up as well.
[inaudible]
was a double vomit fest.
She didn't be better if
she just puked when boom
in the desk walk in. And when
he had his mask on, he went,
he got to got messed up. Just
barely diamond. I like that.
Oh my God,
that's so cool.
I never had the balls to tell
someone that breath stay with them.
You have, if you work with
them, you have to help friends.
I would want them to tell
me like your breath stinks.
I'm going to tell you and I
would want you to tell me.
It's one cool thing about black
people. They'll tell you they will
lay it on the, I have no block
or some shit. Fucking pussy.
I once got head from a
girl. They would, she was,
she would come over and give me a massage.
She wasn't very good looking,
but she was down and give them a song.
By the time you're done with the massage,
she knows she's going to get to,
she wanted to give me oral pleasure
long time ago, but she used her teeth.
Oh boy. I didn't have the fucking
courage to tell her that. I'm like,
I was enjoying it, but I was like, ah.
She's looking at me.
[inaudible] every time
she came over right.
Here we go.
[inaudible]
a girl's pussy can reek and
I'm not going to tell him.
I'm not telling me, I don't know.
I gotta be a gentleman, but okay.
But if you're a girl and you, you have
a problem, you have a yeast infection,
and if someone doesn't let you know,
you're not going to get treated.
Like there's a problem. It's true.
It's delicate. It's a delicate surgery.
What's happening is you're not always
going to get a rational reaction.
Thank you.
Medically I feel much better.
That's not going to be the action
mad at you. Isn't that weird?
They'll get mad at you if they're
pussies. Well, there was a girl that,
I was in New York.
I was a young man and
she was very sexy and uh,
I feel like the incredible hulk,
how music should be playing right now.
She met me with a hat on. I remember
this weird thing. She me with a hat on.
I picked her up and she goes, good. Thank
God. I thought you were going to be bald.
I was like, it was like 20. Thanks.
Thanks. All right, whatever. To ballgames.
And she and I,
we got to business and then she began
to give me oral pleasure after she was,
I had gotten her kind of
naked and she and Harry,
but she had a hairy back.
Like you know,
some people can be super dark
hair and it was far as that.
It was fine for buying firms.
Very girl it was girl for,
but it's still a problem bro,
because they, the hair fanned out.
It started with the back end.
It was on the old rumper still skins and
that was very hard for me to keep it.
I couldn't, I had to avert
my eyes. The only black girl.
What was the instinct to laugh more? To
be like she, here's what the instinct was.
No, she had a big Dick
not getting, but I'm,
no, no, it wasn't. I just kind of, there's
no way I was going to, what do I say?
There's no good way area on your back and
your rump. I mean, you know, I, I just, I,
I just dealt with it. I didn't pull
out a medical book on one girl though.
I liked her. Lots I'd add is
we'll end up being my girlfriend.
I showed her that she had a
B vitamin deficiency. Wow.
And that's why it was a really, that
was problems down there. Oh Wow.
She got all into vitamins. She was
a vitamin freak from that point on.
And you know what? She did her a
favor. I went on a date with a girl,
has the worst breath in the world
and I can't, and she was from,
I knew her in college and I
said to her friend, I said,
what happened with her uncle? You
want me to be honest? So I said,
our breath was so bad I could smell it
when we're standing at the elevator.
And she screamed. She went, oh
my God. We always felt that way.
And they were friends there and I said,
none of you told her her life is,
she'll never find somebody if you don't
tell her. I couldn't tell her. Right.
Guys will tell you quick like a
group of guys and I'd be like, Joe,
you got to take care of this now.
Yeah, yeah. I'm a guy friends.
But you couldn't say it to the
girl cause I just felt, you know,
I would thank you.
I think it's important you,
Paige vanzant loves that jump switch.
Kick that jumping roundhouse.
Kick to the fighting by the way, his
word. Yeah. Yeah. And Paige vanzant.
And who is [inaudible] Clark? What is
her first name? Ooh, nice leg kick.
Jessica Clark. Is that it?
You just make that up? No,
let's go to what you said.
It was like,
it was a chancellor tend to have a
joke to it. Ooh, wow. Superman page.
Manzanas throwing it on
for wild leaping in shit.
Okay.