The Joe Rogan experience far away. Do
you think we are for something like that?
10 years. So in 10 years we're
going to have green people if in,
if someone's so choose,
if someone's who chooses and if it sucks
we'll they'll be able to go back to
normal color. Well if it's,
that's a good question. Um,
if it's with this kind of gene therapy
and it's a small number of genes
probably,
but we are messing with very complex
systems that we don't fully understand it.
So that's why there's a lot of unknowns.
And coming back to your point
on regulation, that's why we,
I don't think we want a total
free for all. If you'll say, hey,
I'm going to edit my own jeans and
you don't want some backyard hustler.
Yeah, it's true. The lab. It's true
cause they were saying about the hulk.
I mean I just think that there are
all kinds of, you know, we're humans,
we're diverse.
Any kind of thing that you can think of.
There is a range and there's,
you know,
crazy on the left and crazy on
the ride and crazy at the top.
So people are going to want to do things.
And the question is,
if with any society,
what do we think is okay and
what do we think is not okay?
And maybe there should be some,
I believe there should be some
limit to how far people can go with
experimenting, certainly,
possibly likely on themselves,
certainly on their future children.
Certainly on the future children. Yeah.
But once you're 18, I think do whatever
the fuck you want. If you realize,
well maybe 25,
25,
we're going to have a lot of 25 girls
with Gills. It's like we probably will.
It's like, it seemed like the tattoo
seemed like a good idea. Yeah.
Well we probably will be.
Um,
so you think we're probably like 50
years away from that being a reality.
So I think that we are,
the genetic revolution has already begun
and it's going to fundamentally change
our lives in, in three big areas.
The first is our healthcare.
So we're moving from a system of
generalized healthcare based on population
averages so that when
you go to your doctor,
you're treated because you're a human
just based on average and we're moving to
a world of personalized medicine and the
foundation of your personalized health
care will be your sequence genome
in your electronic health records.
That's how they know you are you. And
that's how they can say this is a drug,
this is an intervention that will
work for you. When we do that,
then we're going to have
to sequence everybody.
So we're going to have about 2 billion
people have had their whole genome
sequence, uh, within the,
uh, within the da a decade.
And then we're going to be able to compare
what the genes say to how those genes
are expressed.
And then humans become a big dataset.
And that's going to move us from precision
to predictive healthcare where you're
going to be just born and you're going
to have all this information or your
parents love all this stuff about how
certain really important aspects of your
life are going to play on. Some of
that is going to be disease-related,
but some of that's just
going to be life related.
Like you have a better than average
chance of being really great at math or
having a high Iq, low Iq,
or being a great sprinter.
And how do we think about that?
And then again,
a revolution that's already happening.
We're gonna just gonna change
the way we make babies.
We're going to get away from sex as
the primary mechanism for conceiving.
Our kids will still have sex for
all the great reasons. Uh, we do.
And that's going to open up a
whole new world of a gist of how,
of applying science to what it means
to be a human with a lot of new
possibilities.
That's what going to be so freaking when
people stop having sex to make kids and
they make kids in a lab. Every kid's
mean in the lab when not only that,
I think we're going to move to an era,
an era where people who have,
who make babies through sex
will be seen as taking a risk.
Kind of like people who don't vaccinate
their kids where it's natural to not,
it's more natural to not vaccinate your
kids than to do it, but people say,
wait a second, you're taking on
a risk on behalf of your kids.
About 3% of all kids in the world are
born with some kind of harmful genetic
abnormality using in vitro
fertilization and embryo screening.
That 3% can be brought down significantly.
And what happens if you see somebody 20
years from now who has a kid with one of
those preventable diseases? Do you
think that's fate or do you think, well,
wait a second.
Those parents,
they made an ideological decision about
how they want it to conceive their kids.
I think we're moving towards some really
deep and fundamental changes. Sim. Well,
yeah, that's a, that's an interesting
conversation of whether or not
you wonder what if we're ever going to
get to a point where people don't allow
people sort of like, people don't allow
people to not get vaccinated right now.
Like there's a lot of that going on today,
right?
Which is great, right? You don't
want diseases floating around.
But what if that gets to the place
where we do that with people,
with people creating new life
forms? What if you say, hey,
you are being irresponsible. You just
having sex and having a kid. Yeah,
I know that's your grandma did it. We
don't do it that way in 2099. Yeah,
I think it's going to be hard to do that
in a society like the United States,
but in a country like North
Korea, there'll be able to
do that. Or if a country,
if they said, look, um, you can
make babies however you want. Um,
but if you make babies the old fashioned
way and if you have some kind of
genetic, your kid has some kind of
genetic disorder that was preventable.
We're just not going to
cover it with insurance.
So you're going to have a
$10 million lifetime bill,
but you don't need to,
you don't need to require something.
You can create an environment where
people's behaviors will change it.
And then there are, there
will be increasing social
pressures. I mean right now,
you know,
somebody sees some little kid riding
around their bicycle without a helmet.
They're kind of looking at the
parents like, Hey, what are you doing?
How come you're, you're, you
don't have a helmet on your kids.
And I just think that we're moving
toward this kind of societal change where
people will, I believe, see, uh,
conceiving their kids in the lab
as a safer, safer alternative.
And it's not just safety
because once you do that,
then that opens you up to the possibility
of all other kinds of applications of
technology,
not just not just to eliminate
risks or prevent disease,
but you have a lot more information.
So already it's possible to active roughly
rank order 15 pre implanted embryos,
tallest to shortest in a
decade from highest a genetic
component of Iq to lowest
genetic component of is. I mean this
stuff is very real and it's very personal.
What do you think will be the first
thing that people start manipulating?
I think certainly health health is will
be the primary driver because that's
every parents biggest fear and that's,
that is what is going to be
kind of the entry application.
People wanting to make sure that their
kids don't suffer from terrible genetic
diseases. And then I think the
second will probably be longevity.
I mean right now there's a lot of work
going uh, going on sequencing, um,
people,
the super agers people who live to their
late nineties people do a hundred to
identify what are the genetic
patterns that these people have.
So it's like to live to 90, you have
to do all the things that you advocate,
healthy living and whatever.
But to live to into a hundred you really
need the genetics to make that possible.
So we're going to identify what are some
of the genetic patterns that allow you
to live those kinds of, of long
lines. But then after that,
then it's wide open. I mean it's,
it's higher genetic component of Iq,
outgoing personality, faster
sprinter. I mean we are humans,
we are primarily genetic beings and we
are going to be able to look under the
hood of what it means to be human and
we'll have these incredible choices and we
have,
it's a huge responsibility.
How long do you think before
you have a person with forearms?
I think it's going to take a long time.
Couple hundred years. Well, the thing is,
here's how I see it. So the real driver,
there's two, two primary drivers.
One will be embryo
selection. Um, so right now,
average woman going through IVF
has about 15 eggs extracted.
Um, and then in IVF,
in vitro fertilization,
those eggs are fertilized using the male
sperm and an average male ejaculation.
There's about a billion sperm cell.
So managers given it away. Women,
human female mammals are a little
bit or a little bit stingy.
But then the next killer
application is using a process, um,
called induced pluripotent stem cells.
And so Shinya Yamanaka these great,
a Japanese scientist won the 2012 Nobel
prize for developing a way to turn any
adult cell into a stem cell. So a stem
cells, a kind of cell, it can be anything.
Um, and so you take let's say a skin
graft that has millions of cells.
You induce those as those adult
skin cells into stem cells.
So you use these four things called
Yamanaka factors. And so now you have,
let's call it a hundred thousand stem
cells and then you can induce those cells
into egg precursor cells and then eggs.
So all of a sudden humans are creating
eggs like salmon on this huge scale.
So you have 100,000 eggs,
fertilize them with the male sperm
in a machine and automated process.
You grow them for about five days and
then you sequence cells extracted from
each one of those.
And the cost of genome sequencing in
2003 it was $1 billion and now it's $800.
It's going to be next to nothing within
a decade. And then you have real options.
Cause then you get this,
put this whole spreadsheet and algorithm
and then you go to the parents.
They will, what are your priorities? And
maybe they'll say, well I want health,
I want longevity. I want
high Iq when you're choosing
from big numbers like that,
you have some real options.
And then on top of that,
then there is this precision gene
editing the stuff that happened in,
in China last year. And I think it
will, it will be. And the reason,
coming back to your question about
forearms, I think it's going to be varied.
People have this idea that tools
like Chris Berg and abused,
someone's going to sit at a computer and
say like forearms and three heads and,
and wings and, and whatever. But
it's pretty hard because, um,
human biology is incredibly complicated
and we, we, we always know more,
um, the worth the very beginning of
understanding the full complexity of human
biology enough to make
these big kinds of changes.
But if you're choosing from
100,000 fertilized eggs,
those are all your natural kids.
Yeah.
And then you would get the best of
that and then work on those. Exactly.
That's exactly the model. You get
that and then you say, all right,
what if you had like 20 sons that were
awesome and they didn't tell you about 18
of them?
And you kept two of them than 18 of them
shipped off to some military industrial
complex. Yeah. Turn them into assassins.
Any kind of crazy thing you can
think of as the problem, right?
It's all this stuff will be possible.
And so,
and a lot of technologies you can
imagine all kinds of crazy stuff.
And that's coming back to your
earlier point about regulations.
We want to live in
regulated environments mean.
So like now think of the
Internet and you know,
in the beginning days of the
Internet people thought, Oh,
just let the Internet be let you know.
Just let it play out.
It's going to liberate all of us.
And now China's showing how the Internet
can be actually be really actively used
to suppress people.
Facebook is,
is taking people's information and
Google in a way that's frightening.
A lot of people and peers are saying,
hey,
it shouldn't be that these
companies can do whatever they want.
We have to have some way of establishing
limits because not every individual is
able to entirely protect themselves.
They don't have the power,
they don't have all the information.
We need some representatives
helping us with the,
the real concern is the competition,
right?
The real concern is whether or not we
do something with rigging in regards to
regulation.
That's somehow another stifles competition
on our end and doesn't allow us to
compete with Russia and
China, particularly China.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
And so, um, what we need to
do is to find that balance.
And one of the big issues,
uh, for this is privacy.
So if you kind of look around the world,
let's say there's the kind of the big
countries and groupings of countries,
there's three models of privacy.
There's Europe,
which has the strongest privacy
protections for all kinds of data,
including genetic data.
There's China that has the weakest and
there's the United States that has the
middle. And the paradox is
from an individual perspective,
we are all thinking,
well,
we kind want to be like Europe because
I don't want somebody accessing my
personal information,
especially my genetic information.
This is like my most intimate information.
But genetics is the
ultimate big data problem.
And so you need these big data pools
and you'd access to dig these big data
pools in order to unlock
the secrets of genetics.
So these three different groupings,
everyone's making a huge bet on the
future and the way we're going to know who
wins. Like right now in
the, in the it world,
we have Amazon and apple and
Google and those big companies,
but whoever gets this bet,
right?
They will be the ones who will be leading
the way and making a huge amount of of
money on these technologies because
we're talking about is, is it trillion,
multi trillion dollar industry.
Okay.