Why,
why do you think the way you think and
why are you going to say the next thing
you're going to say and is it,
how much of it is biological?
How much of it is your life experience?
How much of it is information that's
dancing in your head? How much is it of,
is you interacting with me? The last thing
that I've said to you? Yeah, so I had a,
I was on the same Harris's podcast be a
long conversation about this because he
is very anti freewill and I think
that it's, I disagree with them,
but I don't care.
I think it's had a blog to be honest,
cause he think he's born with it.
I think it's boring because here's why
I think it's boring because there's two
questions.
One question is how does the world work?
The other question is what words should
be attached to how the world works?
And the first one is interesting and
the second one is kind of boring.
I see what you're saying. I see them and
I agree on how the world works. Right?
But I am what philosophers
call a compatiblist when it
comes to freewill, which,
which is,
I don't think that I have some ways of
thinking my way into overcoming the laws
of physics, right? Like
I'm made of atoms made, uh,
particles that obey the laws of physics.
If I talk about myself as
a large collection of atoms
and particles obeying the
laws of physics,
then clearly there's no free will.
There's just the solution to the
equations and sometimes the wave function
branches and there's now two of me,
but that's whatever it is.
There's no spark of consciousness that
lets me overcome what the equation side
is going to happen.
But guess what?
That's not a fruitful way to go through
your life in terms of talking about
human beings. When you meet somebody
for the first time and you say like,
you know, what do you do? Who are you?
They don't give you a list of their atoms
and say what every atom is doing and
say, let your let go ahead
and solve Schrodinger's
equation to figure out what's
going to happen next. Right? You tell
a story, you say like you're a person,
you know you grew up in a certain place,
you have a certain jobs, stuff like that,
and you dramatically condense the
information about who you are into a few
salient points and among those salient
points are I am a person who thinks and
makes decisions.
Every person in the world,
no matter how anti-free will they are
talks about people as if they make
decisions and the reason they do
is because that's how people are.
That's the best way to talk about people.
It's not like just a compromise,
like if you don't know
the atoms and molecules in
somebody's body and you're not
infinitely computationally powerful
so you can predict the future,
then it's correct to talk about
people as agents who make decisions.
We call that freewill. I
call that freewill. Most
philosophers call it free will.
If you don't want to call it free
will be my guest. I don't really know.
It doesn't really matter to me.
I agree with what you're saying.
I think that makes a lot of sense and
I think that really simplifies a very
complex issue.
I when I looked at it and I have had
this conversation with Sam as well,
I totally see his point and
I think he makes 100% sense.
It's just no arguing with it.
I really think it's,
it's very rational that approach,
but I also think that it's very much
like what we were talking about earlier,
that it's not necessarily just a one or
zero that it's a combination of these
things. Frey will, there has to,
there is some mechanism that chooses
to do one thing versus another.
There's some computation,
there's calculation, there's
debate, there's discussion,
there's a thing inside of you.
Whatever it is,
whatever that process is
that's causing you to, I mean,
how many times have people stayed up
all night going over and over and over a
certain idea, trying to find a rational
conclusion? Oh yeah, all the time.
What is that? Right. Well, what is that?
Is that this will, is that, is that,
this is where the, it actually becomes
interesting to talk about the vocabulary.
We use rice because it becomes very,
very hard to know where to attach the
word I or you when you're talking about
this, like you, we tend to say I made
a decision. Okay that's fine. Right?
I decided to have this can of pure
caffeine that you put in front of me and
drinking. Um, I could have decided
otherwise. So that's the question.
Like does it make sense to say
I could have decided otherwise?
And if you define yourself as the
following list of atoms and particles in a
certain configuration,
then no.
Then the laws of physics said
that that was going to happen.
But I don't know what all that is.
That's not a useful way of talking.
So there's a whole nother way of talking
that says I'm a person and I kind of
like coffee, but I already had a gut this
morning and you know, there's a chance,
there's a probability like you say that
I would drink this and it probability
that I would not. And those are completely
compatible, although they're different.
The only way you get into trouble is if
you mix up those two different ways of
talking.
If you say like I chose to have the
coffee because my atoms were in following
configuration or something like that.
Right.
That's like talking about us as
humans and then switching vocabulary.
He's talking about us as Adams and
that's where you get in trouble get.
It's a weird reductionist take on what it
means to be a person that thinks. Yeah.
Yeah. I think you know, if,
if you say like there's no freewill
and your atoms than I'm with you,
I'm on on board, but no one in the
world goes through life that way. Right.
For good reason and they never will.
It's not going to happen. Yeah.
Well he and you could break that all
the way down to creativity. Right?
Like what when someone sits down and
writes something like where's all that
coming from? Again,
there's feminism as well.
There is an interesting question about,
you know,
how much we will ultimately be able to
unpack and understand about that. Right.
Like right now,
the brain is kind of just a mystery box
to us and there's so much we don't know
about how people make decisions, how
they remember things, how they, uh,
come up with new ideas.
So,
so where it matters is how
we treat people, right?
Like the obvious case is responsibility.
Blame.
Like if,
if you think that a person makes choices,
then you can assign responsibility to
them for making the choices they made.
That's what we do in the world.
If someone chooses to rob a bank,
we choose to put them in
jail, right? And someone,
someone could come along and say,
no one ever does this,
but someone could come along and say,
well,
they're just a bunch of atoms obeying
laws of physics. How can you blame them?
Right? That would be dopey though,
that that doesn't make any sense.
But what if you were a minority report,
right?
What if you could like put someone in
a Mri in a brain scanner and say, yeah,
you know what, tomorrow they're going to
rob a bank. Do you arrest them? Is that,
is that enough? The fact that
their brain was hooked up to, uh,
to violate the law in the future.
Is that enough to sign personal
responsibility to them for that or do you,
or do you do the opposite and say, well,
it's going to happen no matter what.
We can't really blame them.
Well,
and also if you do catch this thought
process is before the actual action takes
place,
is it impossible to correct that thought
process with education or some sort of
awareness training or something where
you could shift the consciousness and a
abruptly sort of disassembled determinism
at its most problematic point?
Yeah, so there's a, there's a
whole kind of, uh, interesting, um,
set of ideas that are very popular
among philosophers right now,
which is the question of moral luck.
Oh,
so if you're driving down the street
and you're buzzed, you're drunk, right?
Maybe you get home fine.
Maybe someone jumped in front of your
car and you run them over because you
don't have the, uh, agility or the
reflexes because you're drunk. Right?
So you're the same person. You went home,
you're drunk and you're driving home.
But depending on the outside world,
you ran someone over and killed them
where you didn't. But in the world,
we blame the person who ran somebody over.
We punish them much more severely than
the person who got home safely. Right.
That's not their responsibility.
They sorta got unlucky there in the world.
So should we blame people who
had the chance of doing it? Uh,
would no one knows the answer
to these questions. These are,
these are tricky things.
Like we're not very good.
We human beings at the thinking about
these probabilistic counterfactual
questions. Yeah. That's a
good one. God is. Yeah. Hmm.
Yeah. What, who are you then? Yeah.
You lucky. Oh yeah. Right. I mean,
so much of what happens to us in life,
we don't get responsibility for,
we were interfacing with randomness
every time we step out the door.
That's right. But uh, can you
treat people that way consistently?
It's hard. Right? It's tricky. I'm not
giving the answer cause I don't know.
I mean there isn't good, right?
Yeah. This is, this is tricky stuff.
We're certainly not like if you lived
in a world where you thought that what
happened in the world was preordained
that there was all the great playing out
as a master plan or at the very least
that there was some sort of a karmic
influence that made good
things happen to good people,
bad things happen to bad people, then
the world makes more sense. Right? Yeah.
I don't believe any of that stuff,
but at least then the world seems if if
there's something random you can attach
a reason why it happens.
There seems to be something to Karma
in that when you do good things,
you make people feel better,
they feel about you better and then they
interface with you in a more positive
way and that sort of like has
this outgoing effect Karma.
That's just a smart thing to do. Yeah,
I think, no, I think that you're right,
that we,
and maybe this is just sort of a Western
posted enlightenment way of thinking,
we tend to sort of think about immediate
consequences for our actions for better,
for worse,
and in the real world sort of generally
trying to be good can often pay back in
good ways,
but the comp,
the woo woo thing is that we're
putting out this good energy,
right and the good energy is coming
back to us and it's a fun way to look at
things. Yeah. Although there's no
evidence that points to it. Yeah, exactly.
Like if I'm in a yoga class and my yoga
instructor is talking about different
energy flowing through different
chalkers or whatever, I don't care.
Like it doesn't bother me like
as long as it makes me, you know,
do that exercise I role, there's
a little, little, little,
but I'm not going to speak up. Let's
put it that way. Right. Of course.
You're not going to stop the class telling
bullshit. I would rather have that.
Then you know, if people want to come
up with an excuse to be a good person,
that's okay. It's funny that
Yoga class is always the base.
That's always where people
go to talk about like we're,
we're, we will comes from.
Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's there because I've
had, you know, I mean if you've done yoga,
you know, like there's
a whole spectrum, right?
Like there's teachers who are basically
just physical therapists and there are
people who are complete crazy hippies.
You know,
you have to think the right
thoughts, you know? Yeah. It's,
but people are always searching for some
understanding of really complex issues
and behavior is very complex issue.
Sure.
Behavior and how you feel like,
uh, you like whether you feel good,
whether you feel spiritually enriched,
whether you feel positive about humanity,
like the,
all these things are like,
we're trouble was trying
to manipulate these states,
whether it's through meditation,
a mindfulness training,
trying to figure out a way to positively
in the interface. You know, it's true.
And it goes back to where
he started talking about
youtube comments because like
I said, I do react badly to bed too
stupid. Youtube what you are being, well,
I mean human being,
but I think,
and I think that the internet does a
magnify some of our bad tendencies,
right? And I think that,
you know, among these,
until I totally include myself as a bad
actor here in the sense that it's just
so easy to be sarcastic and
put people down and you know,
uh, disagree in sort of dismissive
ways and I don't think that's good.
I would like to live in a world
where people, including myself,
even when we disagree with people,
even when we disagree with people who
are stupid and we're not trying to engage
them or improve their
lives, just, you know,
get on with our own lives rather than
trying to have a snarky comeback.
Like I get that there's a purpose
to snark and sarcasm and whatever,
but it weighs you down, right? Yeah.
This is why people complain
about Twitter and social media.
Like it's so much like psychic energy
just gets sapped by reading all of these
complaints on either side has no,
you know, political bias, right?
Like whatever your feelings are,
someone else is making you feel
down on the Internet somewhere.