Melanie griffith,
like her mom to be,
to be hindered was into lived
with live animals. Lions. Yeah.
And I think Melanie Griffith got
a bit or scratched as a child.
Yeah. In her early teens or something
like that. She had to have uh, you know,
facial reconstructive
surgery? I believe so. Whoa.
I never heard there's a movie
that they shot. They shot,
I forget the name of the movie,
but they shot the movie
of them interacting with
the documentary about them
living with big cats. Yeah.
When you watch the video online,
it doesn't even look
real. Like, wait a minute.
Wait, is that real? That's really Melanie
Griffin with lions and tigers and shit.
How many different cats that they have?
Right.
There was a lot. Right. I
want to say there was five.
So the kind of thing you just
asked people. How many cats?
I'm a big kits to be in the Griffith it,
yeah.
Looking at the article.
I think he's a wizard with that.
Google pull it up so we
could see the photos. It's so
preposterous. Look at that.
That's crazy. That's crazy. It's crazy.
She's so fucking fun that looks to,
shouldn't that be the way life is?
You imagine if you're a burglar and you
broken at that fucking house. Holy Shit.
What a mistake.
And you break into a house and you
see a 600 pound African male lion just
looking at you with that
gigantic head of death. Fuck man.
The bizarre tale of Melanie Griffith
and her pet lion. Do they talk about the
attack?
Yeah,
but look at her spitting
water into the big cats.
No one in the family was ever injured
by the lion. No one by that line,
by that one. Oh, Hi Neil.
But Neil certainly could have killed
any of them at a moments notice.
At one point,
he did attack Ron Oxley,
his owner during a dinner party
at his home. Fuck all of that.
After Neil, the family went
on to adopt numerous big cats.
It's resulted in a series of
serious injuries. 57 years old.
Melanie has learned from the
experience and runs a sanctuary.
Okay?
She runs a sanctuary for 32 big cats. Oh
my God. Look at that thing on the desk.
That is so insane. First of all,
does that thing need exercise?
Just to keep it shit together.
Look at the size of that fucker.
You got to feed that guy a lot dude.
And only meet they're obligate carnivores.
You know, they're not like a dog. How tall
he is in the fridge. Huge animal, man.
That's the point where I'm like,
I'm not working here anymore.
He's just laying around their house,
look at the fucking muscles on that thing.
And do you think they're like cats?
Like will they only shit where
they're supposed to? Shit.
You imagine the shit that
shit. Sorry. Once. Yeah.
The thing about the size of this
cat, I mean this is, it's crazy.
It's so big.
It's,
it must be a thrill to be around
something that could just kill you at any
moment.
And apparently lions in particular
are pretty cool with people. Yeah,
that's nuts. They're playing.
The lion has her by the leg.
She's jumping into the pool and it's
a fake biting her. Fuck all that.
Fuck everything about that picture. Put
that on a tee shirt with those words. Yes.
Look
at her. They were friends, dude, they
were buddies. You look at the young,
she looked, she looks, she's a kid.
She's in her teens at this point. She has
giant line in our yard. Um, get,
find the thing cooler was
there apparently than tigers.
Tigers are a little sketchier matters
a little sketchier like you'd have an
easier time owning a lion then? No.
You would have done, yeah. This is,
I'm talking way out of school,
but what I believe is the case is that
male lions are mostly there to protect
the pride. They're mostly there to,
they're not the hunters right there.
The bigger ones. The females do all the
hunting. What are the size of that female.
Oh my God. What's going on there in the
movie? It's attacking her in the movie.
Yeah, that's what I mean. That's what
the link, watch this close call below.
Yeah.
So it's biting her. It's got her mouth or
on the ribs. Is it actually hurting her?
She doesn't look happy. I'm
not showing it as, whoa,
this is crazy. All right, this is
fucked up. So this was in the movie.
They are freaking out to the
line was biting somebody.
It says the father refused to
yell. Cut. Oh my God. Yeah.
Oh my God. No blood was drawn in the lion,
grabbed her hair and pulled her back.
So the line was just fucking with her.
But he is dangerous.
He was once Claude to the face during
the filming that required required
reconnection
the GE story that I'd heard that she
was, fuck, there's so are responsible
and you know this several lines in
this house and it's not just one.
So the lions is their house. Yeah.
The lines are just running shit.
And I think they picked
him and these were,
there were lines that came
from like doesn't show
$17 million on the movie and it
brought back to bargain roar. Yeah.
After this podcast,
get ready for another 50 bucks.
And that's 17 how much?
1971 $17 million in 1971.
Yeah.
This is a nice way to launder cocaine
money, son. That's what's going on there.
What is that today? Like $80
million. Billion. Trillion.
Um, what I was saying was, I
think what happens is that lions,
the male lions don't hunt.
They usually just eat the kill
that the female lions Hunt Day.
They're doing all the hunting. But
with tigers, the male lions hunt,
like they're all hunt and they don't,
they don't operate in packs. You know,
they're not like independent. Yeah.
Rogue. Yeah, they're not, they don't,
they don't operate the same way. Lions
who don't have a pride, you know,
I'll think, I think tigers are
pretty much on their own. You know,
I think the females take care
of the cubs as long as they can,
but I don't think they have these big,
I could be wrong, fine off I'm wrong,
but I don't think tigers operate in like,
like that kind of a group.
Um,
in a world where like I've got a miniature
doctrine that means that somebody
genetically made that
dog smaller. Right. Well,
when you say genetically they're
not doing it through a laboratory,
they're doing it through selective
breeding can, it's remarkably effective.
And then you do that.
I just needed that to get to this point.
Can you do that with a tiger?
Yeah, baby tiger. Yeah. So
could you,
that's what happened.
All house cats have come from some
kind of wild cat that we turned into a
domestic cat. And there's a bunch of
different varieties of cats, right?
The difference between cats and dogs
is that all dogs come from wolves.
All of them. Every one, every
dog, every dog started as a wolf.
Tigers did not live in permanent groups
like lions do. For the most part,
they live solitary lives,
except when females are raising cubs.
Although rarely seen the term for
a group of tigers is a streak. Oh,
dope word is a streak of Tigers
and murder of crows. That's dope.
Um, retire when I was a kid and now I can
tell her mom, if there was another one,
we'd be a streak of tigers. Tigers. Fuck
things up, man. They all fuck things up.
All the males hunt and they're,
they're fast. Fuck an animal, man.
Oh, was this, was this,
got it. It's on youtube. He got
fucked up. We're also roars roar.
This is the whole movie. It's
on youtube if you like. Oh,
I just randomly click to a spot where
they happened to be attacked and the movie
is about how they have these big law.
What the fuck it seems
like I couldn't seen movie.
It's called the most dangerous movie ever
made. Oh my God, this guy's an idiot.
And when you say, they said, uh, father
yelled cut. That was Melanie Griffiths.
Dads,
let's do it.
This is crazy.
There are all these lions are fighting
for dominance and this guy is running
around in between them while
they're filming a shitty movie.
So crazy look get. It's like fuck
you bitch. Stand on my business.
Oh my God.
The blind just wanted them to know that
that little tree branch was not going to
stop him. Jesus Christ up
because it cut each other up,
man. They're biting each other fucking
each other up. It's what they do, man.
And this was a movie that was meant to
show how stupid the guy who has the say
roar is in 1981 American
adventure exploitation film
written and directed by no
Marshall Produced and starring
Marshall and his then wife Tippi Hedren
costarring Hendrix.
His real life daughter Melanie
Griffith and Marshall's real life sons,
John and Jerry.
Oh they were Brady bunch type family.
The film follows a family who are attacked
by a range of ravening jungle animals
at the secluded home of their keeper.
I always thought this was a documentary.
They were literally making a movie with
fucking real lions about how lions were
attacking people.
70 members of its cast and crew being
injured by the many predatory animals used
in the film, including its main stars,
sustaining life threatening injuries,
rating from bone fractures
to scalping and gang green.
Much of the footage capturing the injuries
was included in the final cut of the
film resulting in real blood on screen.
It has been considered the most
dangerous film shoot in history. Wow,
okay. We need to do a fight
companion. The appetizers as well.
Oh my God. Leopards or jaguars
where those jaguars are.
Leopards do know the difference to look
at the tag or they just look at them for
part of the world, but he just, he just
jumped in the boat. Yeah. Congratulations.
Thanks. Thing, hit him in the
fucking face while they have to.
I think you have to get it to think
who's boss that a panther. Oh,
of course it is.
Fuck all this feeling that the tiger
and then now the boat's sinking.
You fuck you. Fuck it. He fucked. This is
life of Pi. Oh my God. Look at that thing.
It's so big. All right. We're going
to do it for the companion. Oh Jesus.
So what we'll do is one day we'll do
a fight companion. Put that movie.
I'm like, save it. Yeah, we'll do it
this week. We're doing roar. Yeah,
we'll do roar.
He me in trouble for that.
Can we get in trouble for
a fight companion for roar
people that do things like
this? Yeah. No, totally. It's a, what
is it considered? It's commentary.
You're fine doing it needs to be seen.
That needs to be heard.
I'm completely educated. I thought it
was documented there actually make,
they were trying to make a fix
of narrative of Pictionary.
I didn't even know there was
a documentary. I just do that.
She had lived with lions and I'd seen
it in a magazine article or something or
an online real dad. That's her
stepdad. Stepdad was fucking crazy.
Could you imagine your like Jamie kitchen
there with the line once you put that
evil on me, Jamie, oh my
God, what are the movie?
Look at all the cats in the room with her.
I don't know how many,
I can't fuck all that.
Fuck all that.
And they were crazy.
And I'm sure the cats are like confused
as fuck by the rolling cameras as well
being like, what is this all about?
Yeah, they're horrible. It's,
I mean those are the,
that's the cleanup crew for the world.
That's what cats are there out there and
taken out as as many of those fucking
zebras or water buffalo
or whatever they can.
And so that's what they
want to do all the time.
And if you're just feeding them
and then you just have met a yard,
they don't even do anything like you.
You got to exercise the fuck out of
those girls to keep them from just,
that kills lust that's in their body.
Like they evolved over millions of years
to get to this point where this through
this enormous hulking,
supernaturally powerful animal that kills
things with its face and you just take
that away from them. It's, no, you're
going to be in the pool with us.
You're going to be in our movie. We are
going to start off in this boat, come on,
hop in the boat and pretend to fight. And
they're like, what? Pretend raw. This cat.
It's like when the fuck did the antelope
show up so I can start jacking fools.
Would you,
you're,
would you agree that since
you do more outdoors,
the activity that may I he running IEE,
you've gone hunting and stuff like that,
your chances of being eaten alive
are far greater than mine. Oh yeah,
100% it's like surfers.
I'm in a 0% chance and most of my
life of getting eaten by a shark.
But I have friends who are surfers who
surf all the time and they fucking love
it and they're willing to roll that
dice cause they like surfing that much.
And I'm like, you know, you can't get bit
by a shark if you don't go in the ocean.
And they're like, we've got the
shark thing figured out and defeated.
Just don't go in the ocean.
They say [inaudible]
worth it. I gotta tell you, man, like I,
there's a bunch of bad ways to die,
but I always felt like the,
the most indignity I would ever feel
in death was if I was something else's
food.
It's one thing if I'm like my body goes
into the earth and fucking the worms and
the grass and shit like that,
but to be someone's fucking
meal is so it's a temporary,
a permanent solution
to a temporary problem.
Your life for their meal of the moment
and they're just going to shit you out in
a couple hours.
And that's why I think it's
hard for humans get their
head around being eaten by
something because they're
like, no, I'm too special.
And then they'll just
going to poop me out.
But that would be the indignity man is
like, fuck, they ate me to stay alive,
I guess. But then it's not
like I sustained him forever.
Like I sustained them for a couple of
fucking hours and they shipped me out.
Yeah.
That is how it works. Right? Yeah. Um,
it's very disturbing seeing images of
humans that have been eaten by animals.
I've never seen an
antique don't want to do,
you don't want to finger is
starting to move toward a
keyboard. Be like, no, no, no.
Classic one of a body that they found
that bears at Eaton and I was horrific.
It's just crazy to look at. Does
it even look human anymore? I mean,
you know what it is because it was still
wearing sneakers and it's still at heck
half of its pants on and it's
still like, you know the one, yeah,
you could see the thigh bone. I mean
the, the, the meat from the bone,
it'd be completely stripped off and it
was just nothing but the thigh bone and
it's just horrific.
You gotta realize like those things,
man, when they get a hold of you,
the amount of like the amount of
power that a bear could generate,
like especially at grizzly bear.
My friend John saw a grizzly
bear kill a moose by swatting it,
swatted it with its paw and broke.
It's back a moose.
I mean, second deadliest animal on
the planet big. Is it really? Yeah,
right after the hip.
And that crazy.
Nobody thinks about it because when
you think about the Moose, you look Oh,
hey rookie,
which hippo is the most dangerous animal
to man on the planet in terms of like
how many people get killed animal.
The second is the Moose. Wow.
Part of the deer family.
Well, that's crazy.