Well, you went and lived in
like last time I talked to you,
you were living in Japan and you
were doing Kendo over there. Yes. Uh,
well you pitch up. Awesome Day. I'm
going to play for the Yankees joke.
I love just uracil and grapple and
someday I want to get in the middle of the
ring and Joe Rogan's
going to saint my name
and I'm working my way up through
Ed Parker's American Kampo system.
And someday I'm going to Japan to learn
from the guys who invented this stuff.
No, I'm putting on a pork barrel, acts
it to make it entertaining. But it did.
And I started exactly like I did Barham
Boulevard making rock and roll with the
Mighty v Mighty van Halen
in the late seventies, uh,
at the Oakwood garden
apartments in midtown Tokyo.
I did not know a single person.
I didn't know a syllable of Japanese.
I had no idea where I was.
And No,
I can't drive on the left
side of the street. I barely
carry a cell phone. Karen,
come on. And, uh, uh,
I suspect that a lifetime of adventure
you do all the traveling come on artists
to artists, your home everywhere
now, aren't you? Yeah.
A lot of ways you are the
comfortable one in the room,
especially if there's conflict,
which there always is and that's
what's the most unsettling to the,
to the tourist travelers.
You're at home when you first start
learning Japanese comes in three stages.
First you watch kids shows on television
because they pronounce everything and
nobody interrupts.
Then you watched the news,
everybody speaks with a perfect accent,
bigger words, nobody interrupts.
And then you start going with me to
the movies in the middle of the day on
Tuesday and Tokyo, it Ginza and
you're the only pale face in the room.
It's all in Japanese and it's the movies.
Everybody's interrupting everybody
shooting, screaming, sirens,
airplanes going by. And if you can
begin to decipher even one character,
then you'll develop yours.
Ma'Am,
do you know how to write it while
you practice that? Certainly.
And think of it as cross training.
All right.
There are a lot of schools,
for example, a Hebrew school,
you always hear about Hebrew school
before you go to bar Mitzvah class.
It's an ancient way of wait a minute.
You got to develop the side of your brain
by correlating designs with language,
with meaning that may not
actually be an English.
Nobody's walking around speaking Hebrew
after all the only four summers of
whack.
But you develop that side of your brain
to where you start to have a capacity to
learn in an accelerated way. So all your
best musicians speak a couple languages.
We are best politicians. Speak a couple
of all your best artists, architects,
all your best design folks and
speak a couple of language.
It's no secret that you develop
that side of your brain.
If your kids don't speak Spanish, get
after it. I had to learn a language.
It's never too late. You'll
see the difference. You don't.
I did every single day. Every time I
called it Roth University in Tokyo,
every morning, two hours,
Japanese class, you know,
speaking the language. I can get things
done for you, but I'm not conversant.
You follow? Uh, the end result
is that it's cross training. Hmm.
Alright.
Longterm memory.
My short term memory
is a little too short.
It gets shorter,
but you'll see the difference in your
ability to remember what you read.
They'll start remembering everything.
You see some things as dangerous because
of the fact that you learning this new
thing. So you're activating this
part of your brain. Oh yeah.
You'll start it off with little
kids in art class for example,
where you take a pencil and you got this,
just a pencil.
What else could it be? Well, in this
environment is a stick shift, blah.
No, it's not. It's a Kubo
time. He's got Joe's rested
now I'm a little girls go,
it's a bow dad. Me, I'm a hero.
I'll say of the day.
And you get start to think in those
terms using actual language movement.
Same thing. At this point in your
career with Jujitsu and grappling,
you have a vocabulary
that starts to expand,
expand by having to learn and
challenge and challenge people.
Marvel at Anthony Bordain gun blessing.
Uh,
one is biggest talent was
to be at home everywhere.
No matter what somebody might
say or a posture or present,
he was able to let it go by when later,
or no,
we'll Duke it out right here.
And he had the capacity to stay
cool in the middle of all of it.
So maybe it's stay cool
school when you think, well,
he just had a fascinating mind
for travel and food and culture,
and he just wanted to know everything
about how these people thought about the
world and saw things differently.
And if I feel,
I kind of feel bad now for
people that don't travel,
I really do feel like you're missing
so much of what a human being is.