Well, it's also this thing, this need
to belong and need to be accepted.
Like we work to be accepted instead of
work to be someone that you would want to
be a part of the group.
And instead of being like really honest
about who you are and how you think and
how you behave and how you operate in the
world instead of doing that and trying
to improve upon that,
you try to project an image of this.
Then what,
here's a question for us.
Why is vice signaling so much more
powerful than virtue signaling?
[inaudible] signaling. Like a person
who had missed their problems,
like an alcoholic who steps up and says,
I've got a real issue. Could be that way.
Or it could be sort of Dan Bilzerian type
Visalia. You wanna know what I'm into.
I'm into hot chicks, weed and
guns and a lot of mines, uh,
tons of money and showing it off.
Well, he's super honest right now.
That's one of the reasons. And you,
he's bulletproof in that regard.
Like you can't fuck with them. Like
you can't say, hey, look at you.
You're just a playboy. He'd be
like, Yup. Yeah. Like girls.
Yeah. It works. Yeah. Um,
what else? I'm nice. Like he's a nice guy,
talked to Dan Bell's area and he's
friendly. He's not bad guy. No, I mean he,
you know, he had, he had this
post, which was, uh, he was,
I think offering a hand to a woman up
the stair and it said, come with me.
I'll ruin your life, but it'll be fun.
No, it was just like, it's so disarming.
Yeah. And I think that this
is also partially, you know,
a secret to your success,
which is that you're a nice guy. You're
really into fighting. Um, you know,
you hunt elk, you're clear about
which ones you're going to kill,
which ones you won't based on
the reproductive cycle. You're,
you're promoting all sorts of things
that people don't want to talk about to a
fairly conscious level.
And it's produced, um,
an incredible level of trust in an era
where all of the virtue signaling gives
way and mean. If you scratch any
person, uh, enough below the surface,
you're going to see that they're
really warning you about themselves.
And so the people who are the
most sort of self critical,
and this is like, you know, I think
I brought this up recently, uh,
on Twitter about Metta honesty where there
was a, in the Castro in San Francisco,
there was a,
a bar restaurant that was
advertising a free food,
naked servers plus false advertising.
And you know,
it was just fun and playful
and as a result, uh, you know,
you had an instant desire to
eat there and to trust them.
And so I think that in this
world of virtue signaling,
vice signaling is really the
growth industry and that's,
that's what's working for good people
because they are more in touch and you
know,
they are going to lie to you and they're
going to do all the self interested
things, but they're not going to
surprise you quite as much. Well,
in the case of Dan Bilzerian, I really
don't think he's going to lie to you.
I don't think that's what he's doing.
I think what he's doing is living like
a guy who's got $100 million and happens
to be 35 years old and likes to bang hot
chicks and fly around in private jets
and live in some fucking
house that he's got.
He bought some crazy house and like
Bel Air, I guess what that weed money.
Jesus is cat.
It looks like you probably cost $100
million or something ridiculous like that.
It's a fucking insane house, but that's
what he likes. You know the guy drives,
likes to drive around Ferrari's and d and,
but he's a nice guy so it's
like, well, where, what's,
what's wrong with this picture?
What's wrong with this picture is
he's doing things that, look at this.
This is his house.
What in the holy fuck is that?
Does he have a golf course when his roof?
What is that?
This is a fucking ridiculous house.
Look at this fucking place he gives
us address out. Is that as a dress?
It's pretty hard to hide that thing. Why
the fuck would he give his address, Alex?
I don't think you can get there. It's
in Bel Air. Whoa. Look at this house.
It's preposterous. Anyway. This is what
he likes. But it, why is that bad? I mean,
look, we only have a hundred years
if everything goes perfect. I know.
What do you give a shit?
Like why does everybody get it shipped?
But they do give a shit.
They give a shit a lot because for a
lot of folks that are working, you know,
making a good living, making, you
know, 50 grand a year, whatever,
that's completely out of the realm of
possibility and his lifestyle wouldn't be
sustainable for them. I mean,
yeah, cause he's taking real risk.
There's no question about
it. When you, you know,
you get everybody stone and then you take
them to fire automatic weapons out and
the desert. Oh yeah. That's real
risk. And also the gambling,
he does a lot of like crazy gambling.
Well, but this is the thing about the, uh,
the relationship with the unforgiving.
This is partially why you're
a UFC and Jujitsu life,
is that when you have a relationship
with the unforgiving, you can say,
you know that guy, that guy doesn't really
know what he's doing, but then you're,
you're in the ring.
You know,
you're the man in the arena and you
find out very quickly whether or not the
trash talking, you know,
paid off or it didn't.
And I think that many people have no
relationship with the end forgiving.
Like you'll take them out on a hike into
the, let's say, the Trinity Wilderness,
and then two hours in, they'll just
sit down and say, I want to go home.
And you're thinking like, okay, you're,
you're signaling something. But there's,
there's no car service and there's,
we're not calling a helicopter, you know,
it just, there's this, if
you live in the social layer,
you're surprised by the existence
of the unforgiving. But.