Well,
the Joe Rogan experience,
you had a injury Yang here,
like a million people asked me to talk
about Ubi [inaudible] so I, um, I,
you still support her
at Uva. I think, yeah,
we're probably going to have to do
something if I don't only argument against
ubi in my eyes is human nature.
The idea that we could possibly take
all these people that have no idea where
the next meal's coming from and eliminate
that and always have a place to stay.
And then from there on,
you're on your own. Yeah.
But that's what universal basic
income essentially covers,
covers food enough for food, right.
You're not going to starve to death.
You're not going to be rich. It's not
like you could just live high on the hog,
but you gotta wonder what the fuck the
world looks like when we lose millions
and millions and millions of jobs
almost instantly due to automation.
Yeah. It's a, it's a really
interesting question,
especially with Andrew Ng's positions.
So there's a lot of economics questions
then ubi, I think the spirit of it,
just like, I agree with you,
we have to do something.
Yeah, the economic seem
kind of questionable. Right?
There's $1,000 a month.
Is that what it is?
I thought for him it's a thousand
dollars thousand dollars a month for 300
million people. So it's difficult
to, not to everybody. No,
because the way I heard him explain
it, everybody, if you're 18,
if you're already getting some sort of
welfare, you wouldn't get that thousand.
You would get like the
difference of the thousand.
So if you're already
taking money in some way,
you just get like an extra 200 bucks,
something like that.
So the thousand gets factored in.
Yeah. Yeah. So if you are wealthy,
you get it too though. And you could
opt out, right? That was the idea.
Yeah. So it's like, uh, like
everything else, it's super messy.
So what is the right, what is the
right amount and how do we pay for it?
And ultimately the problem is,
uh,
helping people,
giving them financial grounding to find
meaningful employment or just meaning in
their life. And the, the main thing
of a job isn't just the money.
It's finding meaning and purpose and
the re derive your identity from work.
I mean that's, maybe that's one
of the downsides of us, uh, human,
human that the biology is,
we kind of crave that meaning.
And the question I,
he has a lot of other ideas
around besides just ubi,
but ubi by itself does not
simply provide that meaning.
And that's a really difficult
question of what do we do next?
What kind of retraining,
what kind of,
how do we help people educate
themselves over their life? Right.
And that's the real question. Yeah. This,
the end and the, and the other balances.
Any underlying all of this.
So one of the things I disagree with it,
uh, Andrew Yang on is
the, the fearmongering,
which I think in this culture we have,
you have to do as a presidential
candidate, that might be part of the game.
But the, the mongering of saying that we
should really be afraid of automation,
that automation is going
to take a lot of jobs.
And from my understanding of the
technology, from everything I see,
that is not going to be as
drastic or as fast as as he says.
And, but then how much do you think
he's exaggerating by in your estimation?
He, well, he doesn't, I mean, not
even exaggerating. What, what, how,
how much do you differ on his prognosis?
I think,
I think he doesn't really
provide significant, like
a specific prognostics is,
nobody knows it's a, there's a lot of
uncertainty. More about the spirit of the,
the language used.
I think AI will,
technology,
AI and automation will do a lot of good.
The question is,
it's a much deeper question about our
society of that balances capitalism versus
socialism and nobody, I don't
think, if you're honest, it,
capitalism is not bad.
Socialism is not bad.
You have to grab ideas from each.
You have to,
there you have to both
reward the crazy broke, uh,
entrepreneur who dreams of creating
the next billion dollar startup that
improves the world in
some fundamental way.
The Ilan Musk has been broken
many times creating that startup.
And you also have to empower the people
who just lost their job because there
were data entry,
uh,
their data entry job of some basic data
manipulation data management that was
just replaced by a piece of software.
So that's,
that's a social net that's needed. And
the question is how do we balance that?
That doesn't have to do, that's
not new, that's not new to Ai.
And when the,
the word automation is used,
it's really not correctly attributing
where the biggest changes will happen.
It's not AI, it's simply technology
of all kinds of software.
It's pretty Dee Dee
digitalization of information.
So a data entry becoming much more,
uh,
much more automated, some basic
repetitive tasks. Uh, I think,
I think the questions there aren't about,
so the enemy isn't there.
First of all, there's no enemy,
but it certainly isn't AI or automation
because I think AI and automation will
help make a help,
make a better world and a salad.
Your spokesperson for AI and automation.
I am. I am. I am Anna for Ubi. I think I,
I think we have to give fun
people financial freedom to learn,
like lifelong learning and flexibility
to find meaningful employment.
But like AI isn't the enemy.
I see what you're saying. Um,
but what do you think ever could be done
to give people meaning this, this
meaning thing? I agree with you.
Giving people just money enough to
survive doesn't make them happy.
And if you look at any dystopian movie
about the future Mad Max instead,
it's like,
what is it?
Society's Gone Fay wire and people are
like ragamuffins running through the
streets and everyone's dirty and that
shooting each other and shit. Right?
And that's what we're
really worried about. Well,
we're really worried about some crazy
future where the rich people live in these
like protected sky rises with helicopter
circling over him and down in the
bottom it's desert chaos, right?
That's what we're worried about.
So suddenly you'd be as a part of that.
Uh,
so providing some backing some what any
kind of welfare program is a part of
that,
but also much more seriously looking at
our broken education system throughout.
Yes. I mean, it's just like,
not blaming AI or technology,
which are all inevitable developments,
which I think will make a better
world. But saying we need to, uh,
do lifelong learning education,
make it a lifestyle,
invest in it.
Not Stupid,
a rote learning memorization that we do.
It's the sort of the way mathematics
and engineering and chemistry, biology,
the sciences, and even art is
approached in high school and so on.
But looking at education
as a lifelong thing,
finding passion and like that
should be the big focus, the,
the big investment.
It's investing in the
knowledge and development of
knowledge of young people and
everybody. So it's not learned
to code. It's just learn.
Mm.
I couldn't agree more.
And I also think you're always gonna have
a problem with people just not doing a
really good job of raising children and,
you know,
screwing them up and, you know,
making kids, there's a lot,
a lot of people out there that
have terrible traumatic childhoods.
There's just to fix that with universal
basic income, just to say, oh,
we're gonna give you $1,000 a month
to hope are going to be happy. I was,
that's not going to fix that.
You know,
we have to figure out how to fix
the whole human race. You know?
And I think there's a very little effort
that's put into thinking about how to
prevent so much shitty parenting and how
to prevent so many kids growing up in
bad neighborhoods and poverty
and crime and violence.
And that's where a giant
chunk of all of our,
the momentum of this chaos that a lot
of people carry with them into adulthood
comes from, it comes from things beyond
their control when they're young.
And that is the struggle at the core of
our society at the core of our country.
That's bigger than raising humans.
Yeah.
Raising and educating
humans making and you know,
making a better world where people
get along with each other better,
where it's pleasing for all of us.
Like we were talking about earlier,
the thing that most of us agree on,
at least to a certain extent.
So we enjoy people. We might not enjoy all
of them, but there's the ones we enjoy,
we enjoy, and you really don't enjoy
being alone unless you're one of them.
Ted Kaczynski type characters.
All those people that are like,
I'm alone or like fuck you.
You are. Fuck you. You are.
And you might like to spend some time
alone. You don't want to be in solitary,
man. He don't want to be alone in the
forest with no one like Tom Hanks and cast
away. You'll go fucking crazy. It's
not good for you. It's just not. Yeah,
people get annoying. Fuck yeah,
I'm annoyed with me right now.
Then listen to me for three hours. I'm
annoyed with me. People get annoying,
but we like each other.
We really do.
And the more we can figure out how to
make it a better place for these people
that got a shitty roll. The dice that
grew up in poverty, that grew up in crime,
they grew up with abusive parents. The
more we can figure out how to help them.
And I don't know what that answer
is, you know, but I suspect
if we put enough resources to it,
we could probably put a dent in it.
At least if we really start thinking
about at least it would put the
conversation out there.
Like he can't pretend that this is a
just capitalism in this country when so
many people were born like way
far behind the game, like way,
way fucked.
I mean if you're growing up right now
and you're in West Virginia in a fucking
coal coal town and everyone's on pills
and it's just chaos and crime and face
tattoos and fucking get
your teeth knocked out,
what are you going to do?
I don't want to hear any of that.
Pull yourself up by your bootstraps.
Bullshit man.
Cause if you're growing up in an
environment like that, you, you,
you're so far behind and
everyone around you is fucked up.
And there's a lot of folks out there
listening to this that can relate to that.
If we don't do something about that.
If we don't do something about the crime
and the poverty and the chaos that so
many people have to go through
every day just to survive until we,
we shouldn't be looking at anything
else where all this traveling to other
countries to fuck things up
and metal here and metal there.
We should be fixing this first.
We're like a person who yells at someone
for having a shitty lawn when our
houses in array, full chaos
plants growing everywhere. It's,
it's goofy. We're goofy. We, we, we,
we almost like are waking up in the
middle of something that's already been in
motion for hundreds of years and we
were like, well, what do we do? We,
is this the right direction?
We'd go, we, okay,
we're flying in this spaceship,
this spaceship earth,
and in the middle of our lives we're
just realizing that we are now the adults
and that all the adults that are running
everything on this planet are not that
much different than you and I,
not that much.
I mean like Elon Musk is way smarter
than me, but he's still human.
You know what I mean? So he's probably
fucked up too. So everybody's fucked up.
The whole world is filled with these
fucked up apes that are piloting this
spaceship and you're waking up in the
middle of thousands of years of history
and no one knows if we've
been doing it right along.
We just know that got us to this point.
So do we continue the same stupid fucking
patterns or do we just take a step
back and go, hey, how should we really do
this? How should we do this? Because we,
yeah, what do you got? Like
50 years left, 60 years left.
We just kind of like hang on
to our rubles into the end.
We're going to clutch our
bag of gold in our bucket
diamonds.
Is that what we're going to do?
We're going to live in our mansions
and fly around in our planes.
And I think,
uh,
through the decades now
we've been developing a sense
of empathy that allows us
to understand that Elon
Musk, Joe Rogan, and uh,
somebody in Texas, somebody
in Russia, somebody in India,
all suffer the same kinds of things
all get lonely. I'll get desperate,
all need each other and
all need each other.
And I think technology has a role
to help. They're not hurt. Uh,
but we need to first to first
really acknowledge that we're all,
we're all in this together and we need
to solve the basic problems of humankind
as opposed to investing in sort of
keeping immigrants out or above law.
These kinds of divisive kind of ideas as
opposed to just investing in education,
investing in infrastructure, investing
in the people, uh, Ubi as part of that.
That could be other totally
different solutions. Okay.
[inaudible].