Losing their job. Maybe one of those
things could also cause this trigger.
We know with all mental health,
all aspects of mental health
or mental health problems.
There were three kinds of calls, right?
There's, I'm a bit lost connections,
which about depression, anxieties, a lot
about this. There are biological causes,
things like your jeans,
real brain changes,
things like the introduction of a drug.
There are psychological causes,
how you think about yourself
and your place in the world.
And then there's environmental causes like
you know, how we live with each other,
things like loneliness,
that sort of thing. Um,
and in all mental health phenomena to
some degree these three sets of courses
play out. So let's think about
even something very dementia.
Dementia has a very, obviously has
a heavy biological driver, right?
Dementia is a physical degeneration of
the brain or a disease like Alzheimer's.
Um, but even with dementia, which has
this very heavy biological driver,
we know there are big social
and psychological effects
that can mitigate it.
So if you're part of a strong community
and have lots of social connections,
if you have a positive self image,
if you speak other languages,
you're dementia will develop significantly
more slowly than if you don't have
any of these factors. Right?
So with things like psychosis,
there's a brilliant person
called Tanya Lurman,
Professor Tanya Lurman at
Stanford University who's
done really interesting, uh,
research and is having listened
to in great detail, but I
interviewed her, um, who,
who,
who's shown.
So we know recovery from psychosis or
schizophrenia is much stronger in African
countries than it is in the United States.
Right?
And it's not a genetic thing because
Africans who come to the United States end
up having the American level of recovery,
not the African level of recovery.
And again,
it's a while since I spoke turnout,
I don't want to overstate my confidence
about this, but there are other people,
there are people I think
including her who argue in part.
What's going on is in many, not
all. Some places it's really brutal,
but in many parts of Africa,
you remain part of the community.
Even if you have these mental
health problems, right?
They have much stronger social connections
is a study that asks Americans,
how many close friends do you have,
who you could tend to in a crisis?
And when they started doing it years ago,
the most common answer was five. Today,
the most common answer is none,
right? It's not the average,
but it's most common answer.
Half of all Americans asked,
how many people know you?
Well say nobody, right?
So a huge amount of evidence,
loneliness is toxic for human beings.
Lonely people as guided a lot of
experiments on this here in la,
lonely people exposed to the flu virus
and the cold virus and the coulds,
um, are way more likely to actually get
them to non lonely people, right? Um,
it's just devastating for your physical
and mental health to be lonely.
There's other things going on.
So I think there's a whole range of
things that are going on with all mental
health problems. I don't know how this
relates to cannabis and psychosis.
I don't want to, I don't know. But we
know with psychosis, yeah, there's,
there's a big debate about
this. Immigrants are more
likely to have psychosis.
The nonimmigrant says there's a whole,
um,
lots of environmental factors playing out,
even in extreme mental health problems.
Like now I wanna stress they're not the
only thing. There are real aspects as
well,
uh,
which are clearly very significant and
things like schizophrenia and play some
role in things like depression for
a lot of people. But, but yeah.
Does that make sense? Was it, I mean,
sort of, yeah. I mean, obviously
there's varying biological factors,
but the cultural factors make sense.
The fact that these
people in Africa are not,
they're not expelled from the community,
so they have a sense of bond and
maybe it's more easy to recover.
And one of the things that you hear about,
part of the problem with mental illness
is that people with Melton mental
illness are pushed away. People don't
want to deal with their problem,
and it exacerbates whatever is
causing it in the first place.