And have you ever heard the theory that
octopus are from out of space? Yeah,
we talked about that. Ryan Cox
the other day. Yeah. I'm not,
I'm not super well read on it, but
like it looks like a damn alien. Yeah,
he was very incredulous. Uh, but you know,
he's obviously smarter than both of us.
Right. So, so he gets to me. Yeah.
It's like me looking at tackling man,
it doesn't make sense.
Of course it doesn't make sense. I'm
stupid. But he's, he's, you know,
we were looking at this eye,
but this is apparently like peer reviewed
published paper about the possibility
of octopus being reintroduced and I
think it has something to do with the way
RNA and DNA is right on them. Right.
I know. I don't understand it well,
but yes,
it's like the thought that the population
came from out of space because of the
DNA sequencing and suggest something
that makes it extra terrestrial
adaptability.
Yeah.
He was super skeptical because he was
saying that they're essentially so close
to everything else here.
It doesn't make sense.
But the other theory was it might be
just this is the path of life. Right.
And the reason why it's so close to
us is that this is the way all life,
even if it's extra terrestrial,
sure gets established. Sure.
I don't believe octopus from out of space,
but I love the theory.
I love the idea of it. It looks like
it's from out of space. You know,
it's just wacky. Well, it's such
a cool thought. Yeah. You know,
that these things came from out of spaces,
so.
Well that's also a thought about silicide
mushrooms from the weirder people that
they came, uh, on asteroids
and their spores. I've heard
that. Yeah. And they've,
I don't know if you know this,
but they've proven that certain,
I don't know about psilocybins,
but certain mushroom spores are
impenetrable to the vacuum of space. Yeah.
They can survive. Yeah. That's, that's
bananas. I pick a lot of mushrooms,
not psilocybins, but I'm a lot of
porcine, a lot of chanterelles. Like I,
I do a lot of farming. It's really
fun. Are you aware of Paul Stamets? No,
I don't know that. He's amazing, man.
One of my favorite podcasts ever.
He's a mycologist a fucking trip
in every sense of the word. Huh?
As super genius.
Mycologist who's the craziest story about
being in high school and what did he
say? Took 20 grams of
mushrooms and climbed a tree,
a lightning storm or something.
Fucking something where you hear
him tell the story in your hands.
Start sweating. No Way. Grams
or 10 grams or 20 grand,
like something fucking bananas. Like
some that would kill Moose. Yeah.
Well it wouldn't kill it,
but it would definitely make it think
it's on a moose anymore and it essentially
changed his life.
Stopped him from stuttering.
He used to stutter and he did this
and he stops done. No Way. Yeah.
I've heard about guys that micro dose
with mushrooms with psilocybins and it,
it heightens their focus and curious
or autism and you know, there's,
I'm not very well read on that,
but there's a whole idea that micro
dosing with these chemicals that are
naturally produced can actually
have very positive effects. Yeah.
There's quite a few people who do
that. That's really common. Yeah. Yeah.
I've talked to a lot of people
that do that really goes with that.
And they also microdose with LSD.
There's a lot of that. Really not, yeah.
A lot of silicon valley people
are microdosing with LSD.
It's funny because the one person that
I know that's done the microdosing
mushrooms from silicone valley, yeah.
People grind them up into pill form.
And in fact a lot of fighters are doing
that now. Really, really strange. Yeah.
So what would that, why would that
help you? Like as a fighter? Is it,
it's not a mental focus thing.
It's a,
it's a physical thing at that point right
now it's gets you into the flow state.
Interesting. And so like with
fighters, the real thing is, um,
it's not just your skill,
but it's your ability to execute
that skill under pressure. All right?
So there's an overwhelming
amount of anxiety.
There's extreme consequences to getting
hit or going wrong. Getting knocked out.
The losing a fight is absolutely
devastating. It's devastating.
Emotionally is devastating physically.
It's devastating. Psychologically.
It changes your perception of who you
are and how you fit into the world. And,
um, that sometimes, and not,
I shouldn't say sometimes oftentimes
impedes performance kind of come back from
it kind of thing.
Well it's not just that the,
the consequences of it possibly go wrong,
make you hesitate and it just,
it's the stress of it
all is very constricting.
It's very difficult to operate
under that stress. Sure.
The mushrooms for some people alleviate
that stress and put you in this elevated
state where they say, and I haven't,
I've never fought on mushrooms,
but they say that when you're on mushrooms
you actually can see what a guy's
going to do before he does it.
Interest.
You have a sense of what
they're going to do.
That's a much more heightened sense than
you would if you were just in a normal
sober state.
So are you picking,
do you think you're picking that
up through like biological cues?
Like you could see the muscles twitching
in the arm before the punch comes or
like what, how do you think that a good
question. I haven't done it. I don't know.
You know, I've never sparred on
mushrooms are like a good idea.
That's a really common,
they say it is a good idea that
the guys who do it love it. Yeah.
Interest and guys of like, you know, had
some really extreme positive results. Huh?
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
I never thought as an athletic
performer that athletic enhancement,
that would be a thing. Yeah.
It's, it's not just the, I mean,
I don't think it makes you move
faster or hit stronger, hit harder.
But I think what it does is it puts
you in the zone. Interesting. There's,
there's states that you
get into where you just,
you can't do no wrong and either usually
very elusive. They come and they go,
you know, you get them like,
um, do you ever play pool?
I did a little bit. I mean,
but you know how sometimes you play pool
for a few hours and then you just also,
you feel you can't miss.
Yeah.
He just have this feeling of
where everything's going to go.
That's even if you're not very good.
Sometimes those,
those will conflict to tree shots,
the zone. Sure. You know, and, um,
that elusive state of like re, and
then sometimes you're like, wow,
I can't believe I'm in the zone.
Then it goes away, you know,
maintaining that flow state. What do
you think it takes emotions out of it?
Like is that,
is that why you're in that state?
Like if you're not emotionally
attached to that shot or that punch,
maybe you can execute it
better? It's possible. I mean,
there's a lot of speculation
of what's going on,
what's causing this elevated state of
consciousness. It's interesting. Yeah.
I don't know.
Maybe I'll just start microdosing on
mushrooms and going out to chase snakes
around.
Maybe,
maybe you would be more in tune with the
environment or maybe I'd get bitten and
die.
That's true too.