Zest. Chad Johnson. He always eats
Mcdonald's and he's doing it. Yeah.
While he's working out right here.
Yeah. Yeah Dude, you can do that. Yeah.
It's all in how much you exercise
with them. Now that's not easy.
Obviously he's eating
healthy food on top of that,
but if he feels like fucking off and
getting a big Mac, he could do that.
And there's no, no performance
benefits, right? Nope. No penalty.
You can do it. So when Floyd
does that, he is doing that.
He really is eating that nuts. Is Chad
still working out? Yeah, he does. He do.
Just for Jack Exercise, just for fun.
He fucking loves it. 22 miles an hour.
It's his comedy. What does he do
these days? So what he'll do is,
I mean he'll like play guys and
like play guys and FIFA online.
He's a great follow on Twitter. It's
hilarious. Oh yeah. I follow them.
It's like hit like a girl.
We'll post a picture and then he'll
say what's wrong with the picture?
She'll be smoking high and be like, yeah,
but your shades at $30. Like, you know,
don't put so much money into your outfit
when the blinds in your house or $30.
Like he'll just nitpick a little things
like, dude, he's hilarious. But his, um,
my guesstimation is, um, this is his
comedy. Like remember you're saying? Yeah.
Yeah. He used to sleep at the arena
or at least at, at the stadium.
He, when he played, he was obsessed
with it. He loved the sport.
He was talking about fighting Anderson
Silva at one time. No, no, no. He's crazy.
He's talking about finance,
football player,
coffee Anderson when he was in his prime.
I think he has martial arts skill though.
I'm not bullshitting south by is actually
he's got for him hitting the pads are
hitting the bag. Yeah. Cause I think
he has real martial arts skill,
like legit martial arts.
But that's the question.
It's like when are these elite athletes
going to enter MMA? Damn. Well they are,
but in small, who's the
small numbers? Well,
Jon Jones is absolutely an elite athlete,
but he's got a 20 inch vertical.
Uh,
yeah, how elite he did.
He's got small calves,
but the fact that he has all small cows
allows him to be six foot four and 205
pounds. Right. You're saying he
was bottom heavy. He'd be two 50.
He'd be a different way, which she could
be, by the way. He could be a heavyweight.
He could bulk up and go up to heavyweight,
but he's got like weird calf
genetics is calves are tiny. Right.
The thing is you don't have to jump that
much in MMA and he can hit you in the
face with a flying knee.
But the,
what he knows how to do and what he can
do physically in terms of his wrestling
and his ability to close the distance
and smash guys at time. People,
he's an elite athlete. I think he
could, he could have done that.
He's his two brothers play NFL.
Here he is.
It's Chad sparring a little
bit. He's in blue, right? Yeah.
Still can't be touched. He
says, well, he's a southpaw, so
let's see this
stay away from Anderson Silva,
so he's full. Okay, let's
good. Good habits. Good head
movement. Yeah, for sure.
I liked the way he moves
hands down over ridiculous.
So he does the duty sparring though.
We don't know shit about him.
That guy might be
terrible. Yeah. You know,
I mean the guy didn't want
to try to go to the body.
He didn't duck in and when someone's
moving their head around like that just
smashed the ribs. You go right after this
gloss of the arms. Yeah. Hit those arms.
So they tried to do with Floyd
man. Yeah. Good luck. Good luck.
Flaws in the game that no
flaws. The flaws. One thing,
it's like we were talking about with Ben
Aspirin that when a guy's a super elite
wrestler,
you think you're going to do something
but he knows you think you're going to do
something. So he does it. You
do what you were going to do,
he anticipates what you're going to do.
He has an answer to that and then you
have to regroup and he's already moving on
to step three.
It's just too many steps ahead of you.
Can there be a guy like with him
that you don't engage on the ground?
Like you just kind of Jab,
stay on the outside. God. Yeah,
for sure. Look, Robbie Lawler, uh,
almost took Ben Aspirin out in his last
fight and it was Ben's mental toughness
and his ability to endure punishment.
Most guys would have probably gone
unconscious there. Yeah, but style bender,
like a guy style bender would be one of
the worst fucking nightmares for a guy
like Ben ask him cause he's super
difficult to take down and on the feet.
He's not going to do anything stupid.
You're going to move forward and try to
grab ahold of the thing and you're just
gonna eat knuckle sandwich after knuckle
sandwich and he's going to slowly chop
at your legs. Wack. Yeah. And you're going
to feel that low calf kick and black.
You're going to feel the
inside of your thigh. Shit.
You gonna try to walk off the pain.
You'll switch stances cause
it starts to hurt whack.
He didn't recognize
he's switching stances.
He attacks the other leg now both
your legs are fucked up. Yeah,
he comes down the middle with a need
of the solar plexus. Now you're hurt.
Try to play it off.
It's just a matter of doing his
game in his instyle vendors game.
His game is keep the fight standing,
fuck you up.
And then Ben aspirins, it's grab a hold of
you. Fuck you up. Drag it to the ground.
Fuck you up.
It's a matter of like who,
who's better at the weak aspect
of the other person's game, right?
Yeah. Yeah. How can I take
advantage? Yeah. It's so crazy.
And no one could be
the best at everything.
So some MMA math is a notoriously
difficult thing to do.
Like say, say if, uh, if Jamie beats me,
but I beat you, but you beat
Jamie. Yeah. Like that happens.
But that's MMA. Math. It's crazy.
Always say that with like, you know,
styles make fights,
but it doesn't work with Floyd.
See Him boxing that styles
make fights only goes so far.
With MMA it's,
it's because of the sports more
comprehensive because there's more skills,
there's more different things happening
in football. Compare to basketball.
Maybe it's like there's more,
there's more tools that can be used in
here that can offset what's going on it.
Basketball, the warriors are going to
beat any team four to seven games. It,
that's just going to happen. I don't
know shit about basketball or football,
so I'm just guessing.
You can be a superstar.
Like there's no one position in football
date can change the game. There's
no, I think at quarterback silver
overrated. And to be honest with you,
I think the most important positions,
authentic defensive line, well,
I'm always amazed at Tom Brady's
body, how regular it is. Super,
super regs, super regular,
but they get it. That whole,
that team gets it. They like,
like I think Tom Brady's like 15th
highest paid quarterback in the league.
It's like, right. But if you look
at elite athletes body, right?
I want to see a dude is
built like Kamar Uzman. Yes,
the UFC welterweight champion.
Yeah. That's an elite.
You look at him, I go, oh,
he's not in the lead athlete.
Looks like a UFC champion.
He's not an elite athlete. When you hit
well, greatest quarterback of all time,
whoa. Where is, see this guy
without a shirt on your father.
You know what?
It looks like a Tom Tom Brady.
Tom Brady looks like. Oh yeah. I mean,
what makes that guy so special as things
like sometimes you know something's
going on. Yeah. He's up
here and I think, you know,
he's got a lot of it up here and
he works hard. It's like, you know,
sometimes the greatest aren't that great
picture of him next to Kamara Uzman
you don't know what it is.
It's like sometimes having all the
natural tools is a to your detriment is
looking at that. Yeah Bro. Come on sample.
Yeah, like a leopard. Yeah, he's ready.
Yeah. Ben aspirins similar to,
yeah, he's got a little muffins.
He's got a little muffin.
Ben aspirins got even worse.
Pull up a picture of Sam
down in wait Ben Aspirin.
Cause he doesn't want to and he's got
it like that. I don't give a fuck.
He's,
he feels like he's so much better as a
wrestler that everybody else is fucked.
Give, give me an image. Yeah, go
to his abdomen looking at that.
I mean, he's got abs underneath that, uh,
that's from one FC.
He looks even worse now.
Yet winning. Yeah. There he goes.
I mean that is not, that's Tom Brady,
man, the ideal male combat body.
You would think that's not what
the ideal combat body looks like.
But he'll fuck shit up. This is a
picture of him with [inaudible] there,
but he's got a shirt on. Yeah.
Ooh, Swan is insane. Lucky for him.
But like this is just some guys that like,
okay,
Francis and Ghana is a perfect example.
Some guys look like a destroyer.
They just look like a destroyer in
Ghana was like six [inaudible] five,
200, maybe more than 65, six guys. Like I
think you were saying earlier about the,
about the uh, Jujitsu, right? Like, and
it's not just in, in this, as in anything.
It's like sometimes the guys with all
the natural ability, they don't have the,
the work ethic to be the greatest because
it comes so easy. You know, it's like,
like we,
we all know comics that are like so funny
hanging out and they're okay on stage
and it's, I think it's be, as
comedy comes so easy to them,
they don't hit the gym. You know
what I mean? Like, maybe it's,
you need that like Jordan, almost like
sociopathic approach to it. You know,
where like, like we were having this
conversation earlier is like, Huh?
Like do you think Jordan's happy?
I don't think he's happy.
I remember when he was
inducted, abducted, abducted,
inducted into the hall of fame.
I think you've got to tell him he was an
abducted in plain sight. And I was like,
Bro, this guy, fuck
he is the goat.
Do you remember when he was inducted
into the hall of fame and he was talking
about writers, he's talking
shit about writers. Fuck yeah.
He wasn't thanking his coaches and his
teammates and it's been an amazing ride
and I feel so blessed and fortunate.
No,
he's still like in fuck you remember
when you said that? Fuck you.
1993 your sports illustrated issue.
You said buy shoes look shitty.
Well he has his furnace race.
Some people have, some people need
that as a furnace. Like they need that,
that competitive drive, you
know? And like, I feel like,
I feel like that happens when you
don't derive joy from what you do.
You know, like you derive joy
from that outcome. You're,
you're obsessed with outcome.
You know, like at least for me,
everything before was outcome, right? It
was like, I'm good if, if I get a special,
I'm good if I'm doing these
things or I'm good if I kill.
And the second I wa I was stripped of
the opportunity to do those things.
I actually found like I loved creating
more and then whatever the outcome was
was extra. Does that make sense?
Right. I think it's a happier path.
I think so too.
But I don't know if it's the path to
greatness as much as the path of the
psychopath, especially when
it comes to competitive sport.
Hundred percent something
about the best athletes.
They all miserable. How they, they
have a fucking self-loathing. They,
and they also have an ego and they have
this, this anger towards the competition.
Like if you beat them,
they would say that if you beat Jordan
and it came pool fucking hate you for
playing again. Yeah, but it
needs it. He's, he operates on,
I'm not good enough, and if
I beat you, then he goes,
all right. I was good enough.
I don't even know if it's that he thinks
he's not good enough is that he knows
he can get you don't quit,
motherfucker. I'm going to get you.
But why does he need to get you?
I Dunno.
He needs to because it's like he needs
to confirm something maybe. Right.
I need to confer. It's constant
confirmation. I need to confirm,
confirm, confirm where it's like, not
that he doesn't believe he's great,
that he wants to confirm it constantly.
It's, it's his little shadow of a doubt.
Yeah. I'm great. I'm great.
He's walking around, I'm great,
and there's a little voice in his head is
going, hey, you might not be that great.
How about when he played baseball?
That motherfucker want to prove you're
the hardest thing in sports hitting a
baseball.
It's the hardest fucking thing.
And he just jumped from basketball to
baseball and was people act like he was
trash.
He wasn't even that bad.
Okay.
He hit like two 50
no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Baseball card I'm looking at
says he was three Oh two at that.
Maybe what it might be for that's for
nine one 85 out of six 15 at bats, bro.
Talking about the hardest thing in
sports is hitting a fucking basement.
The fact that he,
I mean there's a bunch of rumors and why
he even went into baseball first place,
but like that it's that cycles
in Campbelltown gambling.
Some people say, you know, there's,
there's a bunch of different things I
don't want to put out there cause I don't
know. But like it's one of those,
I think there is a balance man.
I think that you could,
I think if you truly love what you do,
like if you love the creative aspect
and then you have high standards for
yourself, then you can achieve both. Yeah.
I think that achieving
quote unquote greatness,
um, and living with misery, I
don't think that's worth it.
No, I don't think that's
where the, for you,
it's like you got one shot at
this man like this, this life man,
like you got one shot at it,
try to figure it the fuck out and it
takes time to figure the fuck out.
But it's one of those things you
can't even really explain to people,
but if you can, I'm approaching this point
in my life where like, yeah, I think I,
I get it.