But I remember when,
uh,
I'm old enough to remember when Cassius
clay beat Sonny Liston. Beat him twice.
He was like eight to one.
That was another fight where a lot
of people thought it was fixed.
The second fight in the
second one in Lewiston,
Maine and hidden punch well was a,
you could see the punch is said.
They said to call it a phantom punch. You
could see the punch, but it was like a,
he called it an anchor punch cause it's
like as listing was coming forward,
he dropped it down on him like that.
And a lot of people say it didn't
land but you could see his head react.
It definitely landed.
The question was whether or not he
decided to stay down once he got hit.
I think he did. If you watch
it just doesn't look realistic.
I can be watched when he goes down the
way he went down seeing maybe legit,
but the way stumbled around it.
He didn't stumble around like a guy who
was central nervous system got jacked
here. We were watching right
here, sixth grade. Lucy,
you got best watch this. I'll get
this pink. See that's a real punch.
100% and the Dra, the him dropping is
real too. There's no doubt about it.
The question was whether that was enough
to take them out. Look at that bank.
It could have, but watch the case. See
if you can find the knockout Jamie,
because the what's not,
what's crazy about it wasn't him dropping
him cause I think that was legit.
What's crazy was how afterwards he
stumbled around like he couldn't move.
Like he couldn't get up. It just didn't
seem real. What did, we just had it there.
Long explanation. I don't know if
they're going to show the actual thing.
Well they just showed him trying to get
up. That kind of looks like Kevin Spacey.
Oh zero wow, here it is.
Here it is. Play, watch.
Here's the punch. Boom. Now Watch.
He goes down and he just sort of laid
down on his back and then he kind of
stumbled around and acted
like he couldn't get up.
They just keep showing it over and over
again. It was 100% of legitimate punch.
And people who say it's not,
they've never seen people get kol cause
people get Kol and all sorts of weird
ways.
It doesn't really make sense.
Like it's a human being getting punched
in the face. Weird Shit happens.
Especially you get punched
on the jaw. Like, see,
people get touched with like a jab.
Sometimes when they go out it
doesn't make sense. And it also,
sometimes here it is, it's
right here. It's also sometimes
it's weird because, uh,
you might've gotten hurt
real bad and training.
So a lot of guys come into these
fights and they're already injured.
They just boom right there.
Now let's watch them stumble around.
So he goes down and he
lays down on his back. See,
this is where I'm not buying it.
This, he just seems like Horse Shit,
but I could be wrong. Now he's
stumbling. See like right there,
that seemed like he decided to stumble
and go down and he's trying to get back
up. I could be wrong, I could
be wrong, but I'm not buying it.
And so, uh, the referee was
jersey, Joe Walcott, who's wow.
A very famous champion. His own now.
They stopped, they stopped the fight.
I don't know. I don't remember.
I don't remember the first fight.
Fifth Round,
I think it was listing,
put some white stuff on
his clubs and he blinded.
This is how crooked the game was
he playing? Did Ali Cassius Clay?
So listen, wasn't above,
you know, cheating.