I got that in Mexico.
I was hoping it holds joints.
Does it do anything it takes to open hall
would be a good size to hold joints or
not.
So is that a joint
or is it a cigar?
No.
Okay.
It's um, marijuana inside
of a tobacco. Okay.
So it's like plush plot tobacco
pause. Never had that. Yeah.
I think I tried one once.
Come on man.
Probably camp cause stockholders,
right? I mean it's legal, right?
It's totally legal.
Okay. How does that work?
Do People get upset at you
if you do certain things?
A backhoe and marijuana in there.
That's all it is.
Okay.
Did the combination of tobacco
and marijuana is wonderful?
First turned onto it by Charlie Murphy
and then reignited by Dave Chappelle.
Hey plus whiskey. Exactly. Perfect.
Balances it out. Oh yeah. Alcohol is
a drug that's been grandfathered in.
Well,
it's not just a drug,
it's a drug that gets a bad rap
because you could just have a little,
it's crate fine. Yeah.
Little sip here and there.
And you just see your inhibitions are
relaxed and it shows your true self and
hopefully you're more joyous. And
friendly and happy and everything's good.
The real worry is the
people that can't handle it,
like the real worried about people who
can't handle cars that can go zero to 60
in 1.9 seconds or anything.
Have you ever considered something that
like imagine if one day everyone has a
car that's on the same,
at least technological standard is one
of your cars and everyone agrees that the
smart thing to do is not just to have
bumpers but to perhaps have some sort of a
magnetic repellent device,
something,
some electro magnetic field around the
cars. As cars come close to each other,
they automatically radically decelerate
because of magnets or something.
Well, I mean now cars brake automatically
brake. Yeah. When they see things, yes,
but look a physical barrier like
okay,
uh, well the wheels
work pretty well. Yeah,
no pretty well decelerated at one point,
one to 1.2 gs,
that kind of thing.
Is there a concern that one day all
your cars would be on the road and there
they'll still be regular people with
regular cars 2030 years from now,
that will get in the mix and
be them the main problem.
Yeah, I think it would
be sort of like, yeah,
it was a time of transition where there
were horses and gasoline cars in the
road at the same time. I been pretty
weird. Ah, that'd be the weirdest. Yeah,
I had, horses were tricky. You know, back
in Manhattan had like 300,000 horses.
You figure like Hello
Horse Lives 15 years,
got 20,000 horses. Dot. Robin Dad
every day. However, every year,
I should say every year is 20,000 horses.
If this 300,000 was his 15 year lifespan.
Okay.
Bagging in the gangs in New York days.
That movie.
Yeah. Yeah. It's a lot of dead horses
and then you need a host move the horse.
Right.
The probably a good [inaudible] pretty
freaked out if they have to move or Ted
hose because you think they know what's
going on. Yeah. I mean it's pretty weird.
No, I would imagine my dragon, this
dead horse around and I'm a horse.
Do you ever stop and think
about your role in civilization?
about your role in the culture?
Cause me as a person who never
met you until today, when
I think of you, you know,
I've always thought of you as being
this weirdo super inventor dude who just
somehow or another keeps
coming up with new shit.
But there's not a lot of you out there
like everybody else seems to be. I mean,
obviously you make a lot of money in.
There's a lot of people that make a lot
of money. He liked that clock. Yeah.
Pretty Dope. Right? This is a great clock.
Yeah. He want one. I'll get you one. Sure.
Okay. Dawn, I like weird
things like this. Oh,
this is the coolest is TGT promotion.
What is his TGT studios?
Tgt Studios. Yeah. Yeah. Um,
to a gentleman who makes all this
by hand. Yeah. It's really cool.
Let's study is filled with where
devices. Well, get ready for another one.
All right. I'm sending it your way.
You want to Werewolf to hook you up.
All right. I, I'll take one. One,
a werewolf and one clock coming up. Do
you think about your role in the culture?
Cause me as a person who
never met you until today,
I've always looked at you and like,
wow,
like how's this guy just keep
inventing shit. Like how do you,
how do you keep coming up with all
these new devices and what do you ever
consider how anew?
Like I had a dream once that there was
a million Tesla's instead of like one
Tesla, there was a million, Tesla's
not Chesley the car, but Nicola.
Oh yeah,
sure.
And that in his day there was a million
people like him who were radically
innovative. It was a weird
dream, man. It was so strange.
And I've had it more than once resulted
in a very rapid technology innovation,
that's for sure.
It's one of the only dreams in my life.
I've had more than one time.
Okay.
Like where I've woken up and it's in
the same dream, in the same dream.
And in this dream,
it's 1940 [inaudible] 1950s but
everyone is severely advanced.
There's flying blimps with
like LCD screens in the side
of him and everything is
bizarre and strange and it
stuck with me for whatever it,
obviously this is just a stupid dream,
but for whatever reason,
all these years that
stuck with being like,
it takes one man like Nikola Tesla to
more than a hundred inventions that were
patents. Right? I mean
he had some pretty great,
pretty fucking amazing ideas.
Yes.
But there was in his day, there was
very few people like him. It's true.
What if there was a million? Like what
is this advanced? Very quickly. Right?
But there's not a million.
Elon Musk's is one motherfucker.
Do you think about that?
Or you just try to not,
hmm.
I don't think, I don't think
you'd necessarily want to
be me don't think. Well,
what's the worst part about you?
People would like it that much. Well,
most people wouldn't, but they
can't be you. So that's like,
that's like some superhero type shit.
You know,
you wouldn't want to be Spiderman when
others sleep tight. And Gotham city.
I hope he's out there doing his job.
It's very hard to turn it off.
Yeah. What's the hardest
part? Might sound great,
but what if it doesn't turn off now I
showed you the isolation tank and you've,
you've never experienced that before?
No.
I think that could help you turn it off
a little bit just for the night. Yeah.
Just give you a little bit of sleep.
A little bit of perspective is magnesium
that you get from the water as well
that makes you,
it makes you sleep easier because
the water has Epsom salts in it,
but maybe some sort of strategy for
sacrificing your a biologic or not
sacrificing but enhancing your biological
recovery time by figuring out a way,
whether it's through meditation or
some other ways to shut off that,
that thing at night.
Like you must have like a
constant stream of ideas.
It's running through
your head all the time.
You getting text messages
from checks? No. Uh,
I, I'm getting text
messages for, from friends.
Like what the hell are you doing smoking
weed? Is that bad for you? It's legal.
It's got to be an approved,
it's not, you know, uh,
I'm not a regular smoker if we'd,
how often you smoke it?
Almost never.
Hmm.
I mean it's, it's, I don't actually
notice any effect. Well, there you go.
There was a time where I think it was
Ron doss or someone gave some Buddhist
monk a bunch of acid.
Okay.
And he ate it and it had no
effect on them. I doubt that.
I would say that too,
but I've never meditated to the level
that some of these people have where
they're constantly meditating all day.
They don't have any material possessions
and all of their energy is spent trying
to achieve a certain mindset.
I would like to cynically deny that.
I'd like to cynically say Tay
just fucking the same way I do.
They just hang out with flip flops on
and make weird noises. But maybe, no,
you know, I, I know a lot of
people like weed and that's fine,
but I don't find that it is very good
for productivity for you. Not For me.
Yeah. It's D. I mean, I would
imagine that for someone like you,
it's not someone like you,
it,
it'd be more like a cup of coffee. Right?
You want to, you have a latte. Yeah.
It's more like the opposite
of a cup of coffee.
It's like a cup of coffee and
reverse. Oh, weed is, yeah, no,
I'm saying you would like more,
more like what would be beneficial to you?
It'd be like coffee. I like to get
things done. I like to be useful.
Um, that is one of the hardest
things to do is it will be useful.
When you say you like to get things
done in terms of like what get done,
you satisfaction when you complete
a project, when something,
something that you invent comes to
fruition and you see people enjoying it.
That feeling yes.
Doing something useful for
other people that I liked doing.
That's interesting for other people.
Okay.
Yes.
So that,
do you think that that is maybe the way
you recognize that you have this unusual
position in the culture where you can
uniquely influence certain things because
of this? I mean, you
essentially have a gift, right?
I mean you would think it was a curse,
but I'm sure it's been fueled by many,
many years of discipline and learning,
but you essentially have a
gift and that you have this
radical sort of creativity engine when
it comes to innovation and technology.
It's like you're just,
you're going at a very
high rpms all the time.
What does that Alexa stop?
I don't know what would happen if I
got into a sensory deprivation tank.
Let's try.
It sounds more concerning.
It's like running the engine
with no resistance that
maybe it's not. Maybe it's fine. I
don't know how I'll try it. I'll try it.
Have you ever is fine? Did we
experimented with meditation or anything?
Yes. What do you do or
what have you done? Rather
I read,
just sort of sit there and be quiet and
then repeat some mantra which acts as a
focal point. It's does still
the mind. It is still the mind,
but I don't find myself
drawn to it frequently.
Okay.
Do you think that perhaps productivity
is maybe more attractive to you then
enlightenment and like, or
even the concept of whatever
enlightenment means. Like,
what are you trying to achieve when
you're meditating all the time? Did you?
It seems like almost like
there's a frantic notice to
your creativity that comes
out of this,
this burning furnace and fruit.
In order for you to like calm
that thing down, he got through,
he may might have to throw
too much water on it.
It's like a never ending explosion.
Like what does it like?
I try to explain it to
a dumb person like me.
Yeah.
What's going on in her end? Never running
explosion. It's just constant ideas.
Just bouncing around.
Yes. Whew. Damn. Yeah,
so when everybody leaves, just Ilan
sitting at home brushing his teeth.
Just bunch ideas bouncing around
your head. Yeah, all the time.
When did you realize that that's
not the case with most people?
I think when I was, I dunno, five or six
or something, I thought I was insane.
Okay.
Why'd you think you were insane? Because
it was clear that other people did not.
What? Their mind wasn't exploding
with ideas all the time.
They were an expressing it.
They weren't talking about it all day
and you realize by the time you were five
or six like oh they're probably not even
getting this thing that I'm getting.
No. It was just strange. Who was like,
hmm,
that's strange.
That was my conclusion.
I asked range.
But did you feel diminished
by it in any way?
Like knowing that this is a weird
thing that you really probably couldn't
commiserate with with other people,
they wouldn't understand.
You hope they wouldn't find out. Cause
I might like put me away with something.
You sought that for a second.
Yes. When you were little. Yeah.
And the other people are wearing,
what are they put me away like when you
were little, you thought this? Yeah. Wow.
Like you thought this is so radically
different than the people that are around
me. If they find out I
got this stream coming in.
Yeah.
Wow.
But you know, I was only like five
or six. So do you think this is like,
I mean there's,
there's outliers biologically.
You mean there's people
that are seven foot nine.
There's people that have giant hands
is people that have eyes that are 20,
15 vision.
There's always the outliers.
MMM.
Do you feel like you like caught this?
Like you have got some
you like on some weird
innovation,
creativity sort of wave
that's very unusual.
Like you, you tapped into, I
mean, just think of the, the, the,
the various things you've been able to
accomplish in a very short amount of time
and you're constantly doing this. That's
a weird, you're weird person, right?
I agree. Yeah. Like what if
there's a million Elon Musk's?
Okay,
well that would be very weird. Ooh,
Woo. Yeah. It'd be pretty weird.
I agree. Real weird. Definitely.
Yeah. What if there are a million
show rockets? Oh, there probably is.
There probably too many.
And
I mean, I think that's the case
with, uh, a lot of folks. Yeah.
I mean, but like, uh, you know, my
goal, I was like, try to useful things,
try to maximize the, probably
the future is good. Um,
make the future exciting. Something
you look forward to, you know,
you know with the,
you know with Tesla were like try
and make things that people love it.
I was like not okay,
I can't how many,
how many things can you buy that you
really love that really give you joy?
So rare, so rare. I wish
there were more things.
That's what we're trying to just make
things that somebody loves. Okay.
When you,
when you think about making someone loves,
like do you specifically think about
like what things would improve people's
experience?
Like what,
what would change the way people interface
with life that would make them more
relaxed or more happy.
Okay.
You really think like when you
thinking about things like that,
is that what one of your considerations?
Like what,
what can I do that would help people that
maybe they wouldn't be able to figure
it out?
Yeah.
Like,
like what are the set of things that
can be done to make the future better?
Like you know,
like,
so I think the future where we are a
space fairing civilization and out there
among the stars,
this is very exciting.
This makes me look forward to a
future just makes me want that future.
You know,
the things that need to be,
things that make you look forward
to waking up in the morning.
You wake up in the morning, you look
forward to the day before to the future
and a future where we are
spacefaring civilization and
out there among the stars.
I think that's a fair, exciting.
That is a thing we want.
Whereas if, if you knew we would
not be a space frank civilization,
but forever confined to Earth,
this would not be a good future.
That would be very sad.
I think
it'd be so that you're sure of the,
the just the finite lifespan and the
earth itself and the solar system itself,
that even though it's possibly,
you know what I mean? How many,
how long do they feel like this sun
and the solar system's going to exist?
How many hundreds of millions of years?
Well, it's probably, if you're saying
that, when does the sun boil the ocean,
right?
About 500 million years. So is, is it sad
that we never leave because in
500 million years that happens?
Is that what you're saying?
Okay.
No, I just think like if there are two
futures and one futurists were out there
among the stars and the things we read
about and see in science fiction movies,
the good ones are true and we
have these starships and we're,
which we're going to see
what other planets are like.
And we're a multi planet species and
the scope and scale of consciousness is
expanded.
Okay.
The Cross many civilizations in
many planets and many star systems,
this is a great future.
This is a wonderful thing to me and
that's what we should strive for.