The joe rogan experience. Just
too many bongs out there. Right.
People still rock the bong though.
Kind of respect that. You know,
it's like driving a manual car. I
never was a guy. It's too heavy, man.
I got shit to do, man. I can't, oh,
the hitch just peeled down or the DAB
thing, the, I got friends in Colorado,
California now.
The first time I ever did with shit.
This is pretty embarrassing story,
but my, uh, my buddy, you know,
they were all like California,
Colorado guys. They roll pretty hard.
I'm not really a heavy smoker man,
to be honest on the road.
It keeps me occupied from time to time.
But if I'm writing maybe, but at home,
you know, there's no need. So it,
the first time I did that shit,
I didn't know what it was.
You know,
I just pulled it like it was a
big old bong rip and they're like,
everybody's face was like, oh,
you know, it was like, I need,
you instantly know you just did something
you shouldn't have. Oh No. And uh,
I was like, ah, fuck man. So I sat
down and looked at a couple of minutes.
I just started getting really cold
and clammy and I was like, Yep,
I'm going to Puke. So I went over
and was like, I'm fucked this guy.
So a puke rightness sink. And I
was like, dude, I got to go home.
I feel like dog shit now. And I'm
pretty sure I'm dying. So I had,
we lived in this apartment and I was like
went out the door and turn the corner
to go down the hallway to my,
and it was full on vertigo like the hall.
Every time I took a step,
the hall we got twice as long was like,
this is fucked up.
My wife was out of the country on
work at the time and I was like,
I remember I was sitting down in the
hallway just like trying to get my shit
together, man. Cause I was, I thought
I was having a fucking heart attack.
It was just like pat, like sweating.
And I remember this voice saying,
get up you stupid junkie. Fuck before
somebody comes out here and sees you,
you know,
sitting in the hallway like a dumb ass
and I managed to like pop out of it and
as soon as I got back to my
place and sit down on the couch,
everything was fine but it was
just so initial and the rush.
I was just like I don't, nobody
needs to be that stone that fast.
I'm sorry,
what kind of milligrams he getting?
He think they just had like
that nail head torch thing,
which is $3,000 glass piece.
I was like,
you guys are taking this
shit way too seriously.
You can be cure and fucking
cancer somewhere right now.
I'm pretty sure if they put the effort,
energy and mind power and have you seen
the laser bongs now some I got a video
sitting in the dailies guy like
a pressure activated laser bong.
He like shoots a beam and ignites
the flower of Jesus like that.
Why is what the fuck's that guy?
Come on man.
The thing is they might be curing cancer
space colonies that somebody is going
to need to build. You know how many
cancer patients who are taking Dabs,
that might be the key out here. Probably
a lot. Get them on it. If I, if I had,
if I was dying of terminal cancer,
that's when you want to be that high.
But at this thing, do
that again Jamie. Yeah.
Oh, that's it. Look at this thing. Of
course he had a fucking, it's the light.
This is fucking insane. Now. How do
you not go blind staring at this?
So he's heating it up. It's
cooking. It's a good question.
And then he takes a big
hit. Wow. Yeah. Anyway,
the, the, the medical strength
stuff. I totally understand.
And that seems like you go blind, like
you were standing at a welder. Yeah.
You know, do you have to wear a
welding mask? Some, some of my very,
very close to my life in my life recently
that went, was dealing with that,
uh, vertigo, no heavy medical
issues, health issues.
And we got him some edibles and uh,
he's like,
it's the only thing that made it okay.
That discomfort.
And so when I had to have a sinus
surgery and we talked about this,
when we played the grammys out here
last year, I was sick as fuck man.
Like I was getting all year for like
the last year and a half on road was
getting his horrible sinus
infections all the time and I will,
I just assumed it was allergies.
Tennessee's really bad about that.
And we'd go to Texas or Atlanta places
in in October when they always crazy
dogwoods are kicking off and I
would lose my voice. And you know,
by no fault of my own,
it became very frustrating from a touring
standpoint because I felt like I was
always sick. You know, it was, cause I
was so we flew out and did the Grammy's.
I was all plugged up, couldn't sing,
obviously biggest gig in my life,
kind of stressing it.
So the label guys sent me to this doctor
who looked up in there and realizing I
probably had my nose broken at some point
or just a really deviated septum when
I was younger. So I like a broken air
filter. But then when they did the scan,
like all of the cavities
were just completely caked
with residual bacteria and
infection. He's like, he's like,
if you get on a plane and fly home,
you'd probably going to get
meningitis. Wow. So we had
to play the grammys. He put,
he like nuked me with all this shit.
I don't even know what he did,
but it opened it up for like a day where
I was able to sing. So the next day,
the whole ban, they flew home. I just
stay out here for like nine days,
I think can go in every morning,
twice a day for Ivs,
for him to clean that shit
out so I could fly home.
So then we came back and did the surgery
to correct it all and like went in
there and scraped and cleaned them all
out and shit. And uh, along with the,
the Septum,
they fixed the Septum.
So I haven't had a single
issue since all that happened.
I haven't been sick one time,
which is like changing my life.
But while I was recuperating,
long story short,
I didn't want to take any of the opioid
or the fucking pills that they gave me
to deal with the pain. I was like,
I'm not taking that shit. You know,
you're going to give me this
for four weeks. Like no, no way.
And so I just got a bunch of medical
strength edibles and my wife and the kids
had to come my way to rent a house.
We had it bad to be here to like recover
and Shit and man just laying in bed
listening to headphones stoned out of
my mind for like a week recovering.
And that's was kind of awesome because
you feel like when you're actually in
pain or when you need that type
of heavy type of alleviation,
what, what it is actually doing
and you in terms of relief.
And it gave me a whole new understanding
and respect for like the medical side
of that shit. Here we are
back on pot again. But um,
and then my buddy who dealt some pretty
serious cancer said it was literally the
only thing that made him feel better. So,
what did it do for you? Like see your,
your terrible agony. Yeah.
Noses off. Fucks all plugged up.
I had like all this galls and shit and
I could feel where they'd been in there
like behind right. Been scraping
and I could just, you know,
so to immediate like all that was gone
and he just sorta get really docile and
euphoric and rely on me
like it's so fucking high.
But like it didn't affect me in a, in
a overdose, he nauseous sort of way.
Like if you need too many edibles cause
your body actually needs it, needs it.
Yeah.
I laid there listening to headphones and
came up with the record I'm working on
now. That's great for me cause it was
like, that's what I want to do next,
you know? Um, yeah, it's uh,
it's a crazy ride, those edibles.
But if you can take that Rod,
you get something out of it and sometimes
people take the ride and the feeling
is just to, to self examine Satori
to Karen Paranoia and to sing.
Sometimes she just can't handle
it on a mass legality issue.
I mean if anything, I know it's
just going to fuck pot up, you know.
But from a medical stance I do,
I can't see any reason why we're
still doing talking about this. Yeah.
You know,
it doesn't make sense.
We were were being fucked over by giant
pharmaceutical companies that are making
billions of dollars and they would
realize how much more money they would be
losing every year.
If marijuana becomes fully legal,
they've already lost money for sure.
I guarantee you there's people that are
buying edible marijuana right now that
would have bought pain pills. They
know it. Also insurance companies,
you know on the job accidents.
Oh he had weed in his system.
We are not going to pay that. So I got my
life insurance now. I man this is crazy.
I did one of the first
interviews I ever did.
I think I talked about like the first
time I moved to Nashville and how like I
didn't really know anybody and it was
just like 2005 and it was a different town
then. So like a, basically I said,
I spent most of my time listening
and playing blue grass and drinking,
which is pretty much what everybody does.
The first year they moved to Nashville,
but then I said like after that,
while I moved out to Utah and got this
job and you got sober was working on with
them.
So somebody put on my Wikipedia page
that I've talked about my struggles with
alcohol and those people
read that shit man.
When I had to get a life insurance policy,
like they showed up,
they'd read all the interviews and like,
wow,
you've been really open about this
and that. And I was like, yeah.
And they're like,
so you do the whole medical test.
And of course that test positive for THC.
I'm on the road all the time.
And I was like, but I don't, I don't
smoke it. You know, I vape or edibles,
like I don't actually, I'm not a
smoker, I've never smoked cigarettes.
But they list you as a smoker.
And now I have like a criminally fucking
insane yearly life insurance policy
because of course like, you know,
they'd say, well a musician too,
this guy's going to die. We can't
fucking, I have the exact same thing.
Yeah. It's insane. Like I
don't know, I don't even smoke
but I'm listed as a smoker
earn.
It's like literally $9,000,
some crazy fucking premium just to make
sure my family's okay if I die on a
business trip.
Yeah. They um, they tested me and uh,
they said well you tested
positive for pot. I go, yeah,
that's cause I smoked pot.
You already know that.
Like what are you doing?
And trying to pretend I'm not really ever
died from smoking pot. No, it's stupid.
It's a dump thing.
Unless you think that I'm going to do
dumb shit cause I'm high all the time.
If that's what you think.
But that doesn't make any sense.
You need to test how healthy I am. Guess
what? I'm fucking healthy, right? Yeah.
I work out all the time. Super healthy,
eat good. I know what I'm doing.
Like you don't know what you're doing.
The problem is you don't know what you're
doing. You're the insurance guy, right?
You don't know what you're doing.
If you knew what you were doing,
you would look at each individual
and go at this guy's fine.
This guy's healthy guys
concentrating on his health.
This guy who doesn't smoke pot
and just eat sugar all day,
this guy is kind of fucked though. Oh,
that guy's a real fuck that guy's fucked.
This guy who's on Adderall because he's
got a prescription for add and you'd
have a problem with that. That guy's
fucked. All these other pieces.
There's a lot of people that are fucked
out there and these insurance companies
that think that a guy who smokes pot,
it's more likely to die.
There's no statistics to back that up.
There's no statistics that say that
people smoked pot or more likely to get
diseases or die of some sort of a fucking
debilitating syndrome that came about
because of overuse of THC.
It doesn't exist,
but they're not even testing you for
alcohol. Didn't even tell. They tell you,
ask you how much he drank, but not
testing you. If you can't test you,
it's on your system anymore.
It's really strange because uh,
in the navy and railroad
there were very stringent,
obviously highly stringent drug policies,
but you know,
drinking your ass off every
night is completely fine.
Completely fine. You know,
don't,
don't smoke a joint at 5:00 PM but kill
that six pack and come in here and build
this train the next
morning. You know, the,
those were always the
guys that made me nervous.
Not only that,
there's like a culture of honor behind it.
Like how much you can handle your drunk,
how many,
how much can you handle your drink.
And Bobby had 17 fucking beers.
A swear to God, Bro. You
would think he had zero. He's
right there. Good for Bobby.
Bobby's an animal. Yeah. Bobby
puts him down like there's like a,
a badge of honor that goes to that.
You Bobby's meanwhile he's taking
something that's completely hindering his
thought process is his stability.
His emotions are all out of whack.
Like he's fucking drunk as shit.
He doesn't know what he's
doing. He's, he's wrestling.
His brain is wrestling
with alcohol right now,
which is one of the weirdest
depressants, you know, awful.
One of the weirdest drugs.
It's a why you spend a lot of time
on the road traveling constantly.
One, you can't really drink,
especially at our age.
It just does things that when you look
at rooms full of people every night that
are Amazon's really drunk or like if
you work with people. Yeah, I don't,
I refuse to,
I don't,
I don't like really let people drink
and my band on the road and it's cost me
players cause they'd rather drink
the and be in your band and it just,
what'd you say? You don't,
can they have a glass
of wine with dinner? Well there's,
there's, yeah, well that's like, you know,
a beer or two to right.
There's not getting harmed as tennis
people that shouldn't drink rye.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Like the guy that has one drink and
instantly turns into a different mother
fucker all together and then by the time
he's on that third one and everybody's
like,
how much longer we got to do this?
There's a lot of those guys out there too.
A lot of people I didn't
know that existed until, uh,
the first time I met one one where the
switch goes off and they get generalize
Jekyll and Hyde drunk, they
get verbalize, verbalize. Wow.
That's a good way to put it out
there. And it gets weird. Well,
and they're moving around like
they're a normal, a woke person.
Okay.