Hello Freak bitches. I
Dunno, but I feel like,
remember when you told me that
story about the monkey that you had,
that you had when you were on fear factor.
Beat my ass that when you held that little
thing you thought this thing's made a
word that that's what I feel
when I get you up on my shoulder.
I'm like, damn, this thing's made a would
absolutely start beep do.
I was telling Jamie, I've,
I think I've told you this story,
I've probably told it to everybody.
I've met that I have a little baby chimp
on the a set of Newsradio like way back
in the day. It was supposed to be
in some stuff that I tell you this,
I probably said it before.
This little motherfucker was on my back
and he hit me a couple times and I was
stunned. I was like, oh no, this
is not what I thought it was.
I thought it was like a
little person like, oh,
this little person thinks he's a bad ass.
Let me just calm him down.
Now he got on top of HR. Just hit me a
couple times. On the back and I was like,
what in the fuck?
I just was thinking it immediately.
I started doing the math in my head and
thinking what it would be like to be
confronted by a full grown chimp.
Okay,
well that's my argument with
the silver back versus grizzly.
You said Grizzly because grizzlies or
even more and more of the fucking bad ass
than a chimp. Grizzly. Grizzly can't like,
there's no way a chimp can
outrun a grizzly. There's no
way. Not a chance in hell.
What's this? I don't know if that's
true. What is a silver back? Full speed.
I seen one of those things.
Grizzly can outrun a soda.
You know it. I'm strong. I feel confident.
I think chimps are faster than gorillas
and I think at grizzly can outrun a
chimp. Jan, I say for me, I think there's
no way the guerrillas getting fucked.
He's getting Denise, Dude,
I'm telling you right now,
big ass and tiering your hands
feel like when they shake mine.
So I would be, I guess I'm not
like a grizzly, but a giant dude
would crumple you like half empty pop.
It would even, it would even be like,
he wouldn't even feel you. He would
go through you like whipped cream fee.
25 miles an hour. Top
speed. What does it say?
Feels like 25 25 similar animals
speeds 34 but it feels like 25 I don't
understand. What that means is
from someone riding it's back.
Get to a different website that says,
is that really what this is?
Oh my God, I love the name.
What PD? Where'd that come from?
Do you know where that came from?
For elk speed of animals.com
a wall PD? Yeah. What does it, where does
that word come? That's what an elk is.
Dude, I but I why? It's
actually a whopping who called
it the WAPA. What does that,
where does that name come from?
I've heard it. It's a cool name.
Wapa he Wednesdays the
Hashtag cam uses it a lot.
Powerful WAPA to Wednesday. Thanks champ.
I said it's silver band.
I don't want to know what my gap is.
What you think of champions faster?
Jump off there.
Don't you think in chip is faster
than a gorilla silver bag. Okay.
Have you seen a silver back come out
of the fricking, the jungle house
told you so? This is what I'm
thinking. Restraints. It's a,
it's just like an archery
argument. Yeah, maybe.
I think the bear gets a heavier
arrow, slower speed, fast Arrow,
but there's not much of a
difference in the speed.
It's real close and a grizzly
bear is so much bigger movement,
so much more mass around like have a
big grizzly is 500 pounds a silver back.
I'm pretty sure. I mean a big grizzly
interior. Grizzly. What does a big one,
like 900 is that really not? I'm not a
mountain grizzly. What did you look it up?
I was there.
The more aggressive ones,
six or 700 and the really big
ones at the coastal ones. Right,
which they call brown bears
first rounders. Yeah. Why
do they call them that?
But because it's the same animal.
Different Specie, is it? Yes. Yeah.
Interbreed or anything bigger? The break.
There's just totally different bear.
Yeah.
One looks like a Volkswagen with hair
and one looks more like a Ford truck.
It's one of those other things where
the the one that has the scary,
your name is like not the biggest one,
which is weird.
Like Brown bear sounded like.
Oh he's so cuddly and yeah,
those buses under brainiac
island. Yeah. Coke Klondike bars.
That's right. What would you do for a
Klondike Bar? I fucking, I'm your buddy.
I live in a place where there's no
vegetables. It's a conspiracy theory.
Told her bears brought that up.
They literally made those to
make themselves look cuddly.
So humans would be stupid
enough to walk up to him.
Do you think it's like a nature trick?
Like nature made them cool to look at
so we don't mind as much that they're
murderers. I would argue
Disney fucking Disney, right?
Like that Bambi movie.
So slower by 10 miles an hour to the,
is there anyone that has that I told you?
No.
But is there any strength of a
silver back versus a grizzly?
I say this saying I really respect grizzly
bears and brown bears cause you know
that.
Well,
Debbie's the concerns of a lot of
grizzly bears and brown bears that were
listening to them and they were there.
They're pumped. I think that, um,
they're all dangerous and ferocious
and I'm thinking silver back versus the
nigger is you think you would win?
Yeah.
Maybe people who listen to this podcast
and he said put it in the Po in the
posts. What we need to know
what people want to know.
I wouldn't want to fight a 38 pound rat.
No.
I be fucking terrified
to fight at 38 pound rat.
So the idea of 38 I just can't put a
number cause that's a fucking giant rat
man. Yeah, but he should
have said 30 40. I know,
but like 38 get it.
What's a house cat weigh like 10 pounds?
No Way. Garfield waste
10. Okay. Like seven,
seven pounds. I'm like that. I would think
something along those lines. Okay, now,
now make it bigger. Like keep
it like a what? What size is it?
Become totally unmanageable.
First off, let's,
if you're not wearing welding gloves
at 10 pound in shape house cat,
you're not fucking like Garfield.
You're talking like, I dunno.
Let's talk about a Conor Mcgregor
Garfield at coming in at 10,
like a real good tiger cat. Like
one of them, you know, those,
those ones like real common house cat
ones to look like a little picture of this
pic. If you grabbed a 10 pound mountain
lion, do you think you can control that?
There's no way. My neighbor, my neighbor,
a 38 pound, my neighbors,
good buddy of mine and he, uh,
he saw mountain lion and uh,
he saw a mountain lion when they was
walking his dogs get these little cutie
dogs. He's walking this little cutie
dogs and he saw this fucking thing,
so its tail and picked it up, picked the
dogs up and ran back to his house. And,
uh, then mark got on a website, got
on a website and found out that,
uh, that, that they attract
this animal and that it, uh,
it had a collar on it and uh,
the tracked it and it got hit by a car
on the five and he's explaining like how
the whole, the whole thing went
down. And I was like, Whoa,
like that you were walking
your dogs and this big ass cat.
I was like 120 pound plus cat.
So the actual cat that had a collar,
he knew that's the one he
encountered. Yeah. Yeah, he saw it.
He saw the collar and then he went on
the website and you can track because he,
he'd found out that this cat had died
and when he found out the cat died,
he went and uh, oh, the sound of whiskey.
Are you good? Yeah, I'm good dude.
Trust me, your Yeti talking a lot of
stupid shit. I never even touch that.
I definitely have. How dare you.
Are you one of those guys bro?
You ain't even been drunk cause
me bro. Quit bullying me. Sorry.
That's my instinct.
What we were just, what,
what the fuck was I just getting to eat?
I had on rat. Oh yeah. Among other things.
So a silver back is
essentially like a super,
a super prime it right. The
most super, super prime. Yes.
But a bear is one of the most super,
Super Freak Predator animal freak out.
Things like if a bear was little,
like a nine pound bear, like the size of
a nine pound rat was trying to kill you,
you'd be freaking the fuck out. If it
was running at like a little tiny bear,
you'd be fucking terrified.
Now think of a giant
one and realize how you,
you are totally defenseless and I
don't think it's going to be that much
difference for Adam will literally think
of a silver back gorilla with the way
they're built and they swing around.
I think if he stood on the chest of a
grizzly can grab its paws and literally
rip its arms out and beat it with it.
Wow. That's King Kong was a good movie.
I agree with you there. I enjoyed it as
much as the next day thinking it Kong.
But I believe that I'm
talking think that's correct.
I don't think they're that strong.
The thumb,
the thumb doves does give an advantage
though, right? It could grab, wait,
it's a little smarter.
Yes. Yeah. Jamie. Great.
But he just the barest way stronger,
way stronger. Way Stronger.
It could smack at once.
I've seen that.
I've seen a grown mountain
grizzly hit a moose and can, yeah.
You told me that, that I've seen you
saw it with your own eyes. Right, right.
Is there any solid information of strength
of a silver back for it and there's
not,
there's just a lot of people have argued
this on the Internet for the last five
to 10 we get dangerously close
to this argument. Seriously.
Why don't they put Thor's hammer
on the ground have and like put a,
put a Taco in it or something to where
a grizzly has to try to grab it and pull
it off and have a sensor versus
the silver back down. Well,
the grizzly would definitely can't grab
as hard because it doesn't have thumbs
like we talked about, but I think,
yeah, but that's relative to a beating,
right?
Who,
how many fighters have a big
ass and a lot of like leg power,
cro, cough versus someone
that's just sheer grill up top.
Let's do go there.
I just wonder how strong a gorilla really
is in comparison to which essentially
like a giant dog. I just think
he's going to get far you crazy.
You think a silver back is
equivalent to a giant dog? A bearers?
What I'm saying is a bear. A bear is
like essentially like a giant house. Wow.
Why would I call it silver backhoe?
Put Dog.
Yeah.