Cause we're going to get through
this next and I respect you.
I what's you guys to yell at each
other for three minutes while I go pee?
I gotta pee too. Okay. As you
don't talk to yourself, just hold,
we'll do it and shit. Well
Shit, I go first. Okay. Anyways,
no one else saying you're bad
questioning. I get it. No, you do get it.
You know why? Because you know, horses
joke for you. Of course. Of course.
Of course. Of course. Alex, you, uh,
you are someone that I could talk to
about the flat earth conspiracy and you
believe in so many crazy things about
the government. You don't, you don't, uh,
you don't believe in flat earth,
but you can kind of understand
where I'm coming from, right? Yeah.
GPS real.
I know airline pilots that
fly from California to uh,
you know,
places like Australia and then you've
got another wing over to Hong Kong and
then they go to mosque and you can fly
anywhere in the world if it was flat.
If it's flat,
it has,
you could go from east to west
just like you could on a ball.
You just don't understand what,
uh, uh, like, uh, like a pizza is,
you could just go anywhere.
Like if,
if you're on a flatter is what
I'm doing a flat travel anywhere.
Gimme two cities, he pointed to
cities, we go back to so much.
I get what you cost you nothing to do
with the patch. I'm not that. No, no, no.
You have the money.
I'm not trying to convince you.
I'm not trying to convince you Alex. My
point is my point. It takes, you got to,
you've got to find it on your fucking own.
There's no way you're
going to be convinced. No,
no one has ever been convinced to.
They have to really find it within
themselves and, and do some deep,
deep what I'm telling you, this soul
searching, if I finance a research ship,
large ship and make a documentary,
I can't go away for three months.
I will pay for you three
months. I'm not bs, you know,
cause to me having money's
not a big deal. He said, well,
you can do cool things with it.
One of them. What's one of the,
can you raise that I to go to the
south? Well, we're gonna need,
we're gonna need a,
you guys go into the food or in orbit.
You go on a cruise ship. This is what I'm
going to do. What I'm going to do, okay?
You raised the money for a trip,
okay?
You do this the deal.
Go Pee.
Go Pee, man. You're going to go see
the plan. What are the high
school? He's the ambassador.
He's the ambassador.
Man will pick ice fields.
That guy's going to be,
and this is what this one
we're going to do, Alex. Alex,
this is Olympia and you
give me 27 entire crew
are going to the edge of the flat earth.
Totally, but it's not going to be me.
I'm going to, I'm going to
designate somebody, not just scared.
We're going to do this. We're going
to do this by Joe Rogan. No, no.
We're going to do this job
and to the and be awesome.
You're going to find the
edge of the world caps caps.
They're knocking things off the drop off
with my iPhone. Yes. Yes. Go pee man.
EOP Don't you have to go? We're
going to send someone else. Alex.
You know what?
We're gonna do this.
They're going to go on it to be
the one that goes here in a minute.
I came here and I pleased they're
keeping babies alive at Taylor, Oregon.
How did you prove that
Jamie pulled some shit.
They admitted them formalizing
it. No, the fuck the governor.
You really think.
Do you really think there's people
out there campaigning for late term
abortions? You think that Shit's
real. [inaudible] six rounded Monday.
Who would campaign for that date?
Look
man,
they're fucking Kelly already.
Marquette's so you're telling me it
isn't real when I had a fucking Goddamn
fucking shattered.
That's a conspiracy theory.
You're fucking top of your about to get it
already born babies.
Stop fucking lying. God fucking damn. I'm
getting pissed now. Don't get pissed. No,
I you saw the dude. It's fucking
kill babies.
Let me,
I'm your fucking bars claim
with the course. I believe that
horse. I believe. Eddie,
let me explain to you when,
let me explain to you.
We went into a long conversation. I
heard it. I heard it. Okay. You heard it.
I heard the whole podcast off
years chasing, playing with it.
Come on and in my psychosis.
Allity is so crazy that I always thought
I was so tough because I have to pay
anymore. It'll piss a little
bit out. Point is the point is,
is that the point is, is that dude,
I'm not the reality. So crazy.
Why are we debating whether the
earth is flat? Dude, they're keeping,
they have human animal hybrids.
There's, there's a fricking,
I have been there when people that work
for the Pentagon say that we go the
laboratory and we meet
with the ambassador,
we have to take higher and
higher doses to meet with them.
They're giving us technology
and the technology work.
I've been, this is going on,
dude. You want to know
this? Listen, relax.
Think about how this isn't real man.
The aliens.
Alex think about what I said I said to
do you think there's actually people out
there did believe that our
campaigning telescopes this into what?
I sucks.
He's fun to hear what I said.
Do you think there's actually people
out there that are campaigning for late
term abortions?
Of course there are,
but I'm making it seem like I don't
believe they are. Get it down here.
I'm being the ultimate skeptic.
Ultimate skeptic words does
that all the time. He says,
[inaudible] right there. I'm threatened.
I'm about Mr. Goody two shoes. Buy them,
keeping babies alive and killing them
and then nobody cares. I fundamentally,
that's what I'm sitting and I'm being
honest here is I'm not like certified with
crazy,
but I deal with this all day long.
I get what joke tries to shy away
and people go crazy. [inaudible]
I never saw that clip of that guy saying
that they would resuscitate the babies.
Then they would make a decision.
You heard about that New York,
a bill that they're trying
to have some big shit.
It's like it's like a
city,
but we're still golf tees.
They're giving a bunch of God damn
fucking organ harvesting doctors control
outside of law.
You heard that piece of Shit fucking KKK
guy fucking governor say we're going to
keep alive after they're fucking bored.
He's like,
cause they want to fucking take their
organs. It's incredible. He's a KKK guy.
That's a quote above cold fudge.
It's so incredible.
Then I did a picture with a guy,
the KKK outfit in blackface.
They elected him because he's black males.
They had that shit and when he messed
up and said we keep them alive to get
their fucking organs.
They used that to deactivate him.
Why do you think fraternities have you
screw sheep and all this and you know
give guys blowjobs that's why
I never joined them because
they want to come back.
Go back, go back. Ah Fraternity.
I'm so happy with this. I
do this podcast. So happy.
I turned down this fucking amazing.
It's fucking amazing.
It was good.
We got to Paris who fucking world order.
Oh my God. Eddie. I got you.
Did you got so pissed off?
I'm so glad I fucked it too,
cause we got some to do my life.
How many jre clips they're going to
make it that do. They're going to,
they're going to put you to music.
They said you pulled up MIT saying
they've got an animal, human pigs.
So yeah, we did. Let's just not forget. We
did listen. Go take a leak. I'm with you.
Listen man, he just kind of freaked
me out about several subjects. No, no,
no bullshit.
He freaked me out about several subjects.