It's so populated and it's
also like, so, um, it's so la,
it's so Beverly hills.
I lived there for 13 years of generic.
Yeah.
There was a wave there that Laird was
having a love affair with for many years.
So we lived there, uh, with, you know,
so he could be close to his
girlfriend for sure. It was strange.
It didn't know every boy
needs their girlfriend. Every
boy needs a wave. They do.
Well girl, you know, just something,
that's what I always think is kind of
natural is at least for my experience is
like,
I don't know if he ever go through this
when you go home I'll let it all go out
and surf for many hours,
like kicking off for five hours at a
time and if their surf and he comes home
and I see how happy he is, like to see
us, he loves us. He's like, oh my girls,
you know. And then about, I dunno,
seven and a half, eight minutes in,
he starts to get this look
on his face like, oh yeah,
I'm in the house with the family.
You know,
I wanted to do a book years ago called
death by domestication because it's like
how does, how do, how does he manage
both of those sides? Like I need to go,
I need to be free, I need to,
you know, chase things in,
like scare myself and do all
this stuff and then, you know,
comes home and it's like, you know,
on the floor laying, you know,
with one of my daughters and,
and being attentive and a great
husband and all these things.
But I always get amused a little
bit by the push pole. Yeah.
Well especially I think with the
big wave surfer mindset,
like a type of person,
those are like some of the freest,
wildest humans on the planet.
It's a very unusual group of people that
rides giant waves of water on the top
of the ocean.
I mean that's a,
that's a crazy thing to delta here
time to really stop and think about it.
Try not to think too much
about it cause I did marry him.
But there is some stuff,
I mean, and, and weirdly,
you know, he's been doing this
so long that you realize hit,
he's actually even more different than
some of the other guys because if you
think about it, he sustained doing
this for right now, 40 years. Wow.
So he's a guy who
he has both.
So what he wants to do is write a huge
wave during the day and then be with his
family at night. And sometimes, you
know, we'd take going, you know,
halfway around the globe or whatever.
And so I think the pursuit
and they have to wait a lot.
That's the other thing. These things don't
come around that often. Right. Um, it's,
it's very interesting to
live with because, um,
there's a,
there's a little bit of suffering that
goes on and sometimes later they'll say
to me, cause he's aware of
time going by, he'll be like,
you don't have a lot more waves. I
need to ride. And I'm like, I know,
like it's a pretty deep,
uh, calling. And now that,
I mean he's been boiling for 25 years,
but now that they are getting
that equipment better,
it's sort of like now we can ride
places that we couldn't ride,
that we're not really attractive for
riding top of the surface of the water,
even if you towed it. So now it's
opened up a whole other pursuit for him.
Um, yeah, it's very, I don't know
why you would go towards that.
No,
like Laird has put me on a ski in front
of a way that's like 60 feet. Right.
And like being on the back
of a ski with him driving.
There's a moment where
you go, okay, I actually,
and I'm sure you've experienced
this with other friends that take,
you may be on up flying or something.
He is, this is what he does, right?
So I'm like, okay, I trust him
more than I'm afraid. That's fine.
I can do that and I'm
going to surrender to that.
I'm not going to torture myself the
whole time. I'm just going to trust him.
And you turn and there's a six story
building behind you moving and you just
think
who would,
who like how has that fun y'all like
how is saying like I'm going to actively
ride that.
Um,
but now with the foils,
because they're actually catching the
energy below the surface of the water.
So foils, I'm not familiar. They
have these things called hydrofoils.
So originally there was a guy named Mike
Murphy who created something called the
air chair and they were,
they'd been putting foils on skis,
water skis and different funky ways.
Like even in the 50s so Laird in
his friend's got an air chair,
cut the chair off and put
us snowboard boots bindings,
quick release. So you'd stand on
it. You're booted in and below.
Is this basically a mini airplane
with a Strut? So for example,
yeah, there's a shot of one and
this is a smaller one. Jamie,
do you have any ones of the big
with the boots? Yeah, I think this
people are using the old time memories.
Did you know what brothers? I seen him.
Wow. He knows about everything. What
are you talking about? He's plugged in,
plugged in, look at him.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Well, what happened to
this dude's head? Oh yeah.
So there's Laird on the left obviously.
So you see how either in
the boots and also he,
the reason he looks so puffy as he
has flotation underneath his wet suit.
So if you hit your head or what have you,
but it's basically a miniature
airplane underneath the surface.
And if he gets into trouble, if they
wiped out, um, they have a quick release,
but now they've gotten this
developed so that he can do it,
uh, without the boots because that adds
an element of danger that cause you're
strapped in, you're strapped in and
your strut is, you know, four feet long.
Uh, you know, that's so
strange looking. Yeah.
But it's what's going on below the
surface. So there's a miniature airplane.
Do you have, Jamie, do you have
any pictures of it flipped up?
I'm sure if you look on Laird stuff,
you can see the bottom,
it's like a miniature airplane
because water is denser than air.
So it sort of like a miniature plane.
And it is like the oracle guys that
do those boats do have made foils for
layered. Um, it's, so that's
what it looks like. Yeah.
So those are kind of more
a low performance ones.
When you see the high performance,
they, I mean, you know,
it's aerodynamics,
hydrodynamics, it's all of that.
So now what you're doing is because
there's energy below the surface moving.
So we think of a wave
like pushing and dropping,
but there's actually the
energy circular energy below.
So now you've got the foil that
can ride that, but you're not,
you don't have drag.
So like they can go,
there's a wave on Kauai
where they're going over, you
know, 50, they go about 50,
they can go up,
get up to 52 miles an hour.
So imagine if you did something, we'll,
you've dedicated yourself to martial arts.
It's like,
but then there's like a new way to do it.
And so he's been doing the
big stuff for 25 years,
but now they're getting any equipment,
right? That he can ride waves.
That actually wouldn't be that great.
But now they're super fun. Oh Wow.
So he gets it, makes them excited and
he's still pursues it. And, uh, that's,
that's on Kauai right there.
And see how it's not even breaking
where he rides it so it can correct.
And it's, it's actually riding the
energy below the surface, which,
you know, for him, he's just interested
in what's the most efficient way. I mean,
look at that. You'd never
intrude in, um, regular surfing.
Be able to,
um,
ride that so it enables them so much fun.
You're flying, that's what they say.
That's, it's the difference. Right?
So they're flying. So that's, I think
keep kept him interested. But you know,
his, his pursuit of this is, it's pretty,
it's pretty, it's a pretty
interesting relationship to watch.
I think it's important. I
mean, as a female, for me,
I think playing volleyball
helped me understand like,
having a pursuit, you know,
like something like I got to go do that.
And I think it's something about living
with a person who has a pursuit other
than, um, like I need a
bigger war chest or whatever.
Right.
That's can be really cool.