The Joe Rogan experience. Do you
watch a lot of standup? Me? Yeah.
I watch it at the clubs. I very rarely
sit down and watch a special. Yeah,
it's true. Do you watch the
special ever? Occasionally.
If like right now I'm working on it
and trying to put together new hours,
so I'm trying to go back and watch stuff.
But for years I didn't watch anything.
Um,
uh,
but like it's funny like the three comics
that I watch are you deleah and I'm
Sebastian because I follow
you guys at the store.
So it's like I'm in the room sitting there
and like you're the only three that I
watch.
Like I could like,
I could like reset your act word for
word and I don't watch anyone else.
It's so funny to me. Well,
I think it's great to be,
again at a place like the store where you
can see all these different styles and
all these different people doing it.
And you also see how we kind of influence
each other in the slightest bit.
And you know that we're all working in
these really hot rooms where it's all
packed. And, but I think it's good
to sit down and watch, you know,
John Malaney when he did his, where
was that? Where was his radio city?
A city or you know, Dave
Chappelle, wherever he did his,
he did his in DC I think. Right? The
big one, wasn't it in DC? I last one,
I think it was in la,
the last one.
Well he did the store with the
belly room with the little one,
the room he did the other one where he's
wearing like the military shirts with
the scene,
the Oj thing we talked about Oj that was
in la and then there was one in Austin.
They may have been one more in DC.
I thought the most recent
bigger one was in DC.
But either way the um, maybe you're right
where, what, well Jamie, we'll find it,
but it's, I think it's, uh,
it's good to see, you know,
it's good to see how
different people do it.
I always enjoy watching Katt Williams,
particularly in the beginning because
you know like a lot of times he'll just
run out on stage and like he's running
around on stage for like five or 10
minutes before the fucking first Joe
comes out and he's pointing at people in
the audience and sweating and going
crazy and it's so different than the way
anybody that I know does it. It's
good to see that too. Yeah. He,
I think the most discussed a
standup special of the past year.
It was not in a net. It was Kat
Williams, his spouse. Did you see it?
Yes.
The one he did from Florida where he
opens up a 10 minutes of Florida material,
15 minutes of Jacksonville material.
That is like apparently
destroying that we did. I just,
I couldn't get enough of it. We watched
watched it a hundred times. Yeah.
But it tapered off pretty
hard. Oh yeah. Yeah.
I tapered off real hard when he was
doing the Trump stuff. It's like,
well this stuff is like half baked.
Yeah.
It looked like it looked like he had
a bit to, that they like made him cut.
And so we had to just
like do the hour anyway.
That's what I assumed from having watched
it. I thought out they do that though.
They don't tell you to do shit.
They don't tell me to do shit.
I don't think they're going to tell him
to do shit. They may have been like,
this is someone, this is already a bit, do
you know what I mean? As simple as that.
I don't know. Seemed to me that it was
almost like he had some shit to say,
but maybe hadn't been doing
a lot of stand, you know, I,
I don't know how much that guy works
out. I don't see him anywhere. No.
I always wonder about those guys. Like
the guys who you don't see in the clubs,
you know, like bill, you know, Bill
Bird saw a special one day, um,
and, uh, we were doing a set
together at the Ice House and, uh,
he came into the green room, like frothing
at the mouth and it, he's like, he goes,
the, the fucking guy, I forget, I know who
he's talking about, I'll tell you later.
But he was like, the fucking guy
doesn't do the clubs anymore.
He doesn't do the clubs.
He goes, is watching this
cringey bullshit. And he was,
he was like angry. And I was like,
you've got to do the fucking clubs.