Weed is tricky in Texas
though, right? Yeah. It's not
legal yet. It's going to be,
um, in California though.
That's right here.
I got that Elan Musk trouble.
We'd, what is that? This is a,
this is what's called a,
a blunt
tobacco on the outside and marijuana on
the inside and nurtured or car shit at
drop. Tesla's stock 6% one day. Oh My, uh,
my manager in PR person out there.
I just literally shitting their pants
right now. But it's legal. Well,
it's legal here, right? Yeah.
There you go. I believe in the law.
It's a hundred percent legal.
Here
it is on a percent. Who's
the dude that, um, oh,
Mike Tyson just brought you something.
His wheat. Is that how it comes?
This is the box of death
and life right here. Well,
Mike Tyson's box of death
and life. Yeah. Look at this.
This is how hard Mike Tyson roles look
at the sides of these fucking joints he
gave me. I know the camera's
not gonna be able to follow me,
but I'll be right back. Ladies
and gentlemen, look at this shit.
Look at the fucking size.
Oh, that's just insane.
That's to you, bro.
I can't tell you that I can't
take it away on the plane.
How do I get on the plane?
Then you just think thinking
you'll appear at the seat. Foresee.
That's the key.
I would recommend any meaning more
than that for me. All right, Jamie,
we'll take one more.
Yeah.
He gave me these joints that would make
you think about people you fingered in
high school and want to find
my Facebook and apologize.
This is just, what is that?
That's a goddamn cigar of
marijuana. That's outrageous.