All right. Can I pause here? Leptin is
produced where? Yeah, Leptin is produced.
Yeah. Let's talk about Leptin a little
bit. It's produced in fat cells, um,
and it's produced in proportion
to the size of fat tissue.
So the amount of body fat you have,
the more fat you have,
the more Leptin you have in the
circulation. And basically what this is,
it's what's called a
negative feedback loop,
which is a really simple engineering
term that works like a thermostat.
So with your thermostat,
you,
if you set your thermostat to 70,
if it starts getting a little bit hotter,
your ac turns on to bring it back
down at the starts getting lower,
ac comes on or the heat
comes on to bring it up.
That's called a negative feedback system
and it maintains the stability of the
temperature of your house.
We have many negative feedback loops
in the human body to regulate body
temperature, to regulate blood pressure,
to regulate all sorts of things.
One of the negative feedback loops we
have regulates body fatness and the
hormone. So your, your thermostat measures
temperature by using a thermostat,
a, sorry, a thermometer,
your brain measures body fatness using
this hormone leptin that's in the
circulation. And then particularly
when your body fat level drops,
your Leptin levels drop and your brain
hears that and it kicks in a starvation
response basically.
And this is the main reason why weight
loss is so difficult because your brain
is like, no, I don't want to be
losing fat. And it makes you hungrier.
It increases your cravings. Yes. Is that
at a certain level of body fat as a sub?
So here's this, just when you're
losing body fat in general,
like even if you're a large
person that's overweight, correct.
When you're losing body fat in general,
your body exacerbates your hunger.
And this is,
this is the thing that's really important
to understand about obesity, um,
is that people with obesity
have a higher set point.
So it's like turning your thermostat from
70 to 80 and then your thermostats or
regulating around 80 people with obesity,
they're not regulating around one 70
anymore. They're regulating around two 50.
And so when you cause a
lean person to lose weight,
you see the same thing is when you cause
a person with obesity to lose weight,
you see this reaction in their brain
circuits that regulate body fatness that
drives them to increase their cravings
and their hunger to the metabolic rate
drops. So it'd be an
evolutionary mechanism to force
you to seek food. Correct.
And not just the forest city to seek food.
That's the main thing.
But it also slows your metabolic rate,
does everything it can to get more energy
in your body and have less leaving.
And it keeps doing that until the fat
comes back. Can I pause here? Yeah.
So when you're eating a sugary
die at a high high calorie diet,
you will produce more fat. Your
body will get fatter, right? Um,
it depends on how many calories
you're eating. If you're overeating,
you consuming a lot of sugar, a lot of
carbohydrates, your body will get fatter.
Correct. Your body will
produce more Leptin. Correct.
So it comes from the Diet.
Um, yeah. Indirectly. Definitely
are. Yeah. Yeah. Pause please.
So the Leptin is produced not just in
response to the size of the fat cell,
but in response actually to glucose
mediated uptake into the fat tail,
which is mediated in part by insulin.
So you come back to insulin,
even with the Leptin, you raise
blood sugar and that's the carbs.
You eat the carbs, you raise blood sugar,
you raise insulin, you raise fat storage,
the glucose, and then you get
more leaped. And um, again,
one of the things you have to understand
about this is everything that says has
two interpretations depending on
which paradigm you're looking at.
And these are fundamentally
different paradigms.
So in Stephen's world, and again,
correct me if I'm wrong though,
the Leptin is signaling few all
availability in the fat cells.
The way I would think of it,
and in my very small world,
Leptin is responding to fuel
availability in the rest of the cells.
So it's basically a molecule that
can tell other cells that there's fat
available and you could burn that fat for
fuel and then you don't have to go eat
or it can tell that there
isn't fuel available. And if,
depending on how much left in there is
the cells and then that what were spawned
by a signal to eat or not to
disinhibit eating behavior, um,
everything we're talking about with
Stefan and I'd first sort of fell out,
I dunno, eight years ago at, um,
the ancestral health symposium when I
acted improperly inappropriately.
But one of the problems I tell,
the way I think you
should think about this,
you have a hypothesis and
this is the fundamental thing.
Is it obesity caused by overeating?
Because we know if you're getting fat
or you're storing more calories in your
expense, that's just the, yeah, that's
like if her room is getting more crowded,
more people are entering them,
leaving. That is the simplest.
But it doesn't tell you why
the room's getting crowded.
It doesn't tell you why the f
you're getting fatter. And again,
what I've been arguing is the why you're
getting fatter part is a bit left out.
And people decided that overeating was
somehow an explanation and then they went
to the brain to look at why
people might overeat. So what I,
one of the questions I asked
to find eight years ago,
and it keeps coming up as if we're going
to blame obesity on the modern food
environment, epidemics
of obesity. You know,
simple question to ask is can we find
epidemics of obesity without this modern
food environment? I mean, that's the
sort of science one o one, right?
And it turns out that
the world is falling.
The first one I've found in the literature
was in 1902 in a population of the
Pima native American tribe,
the PM on living in Arizona and
observer saying these people are poor,
they're malnourished,
they're suffering through famines,
they've been suffering through a
famine for 40 years and famines.
It's hard to overeat during a famine.
And yet the women of the tribe who do
virtually all the work that they were
treated as pack animals and effect,
we're obese.
So now we can disassociate obesity from
the modern food environment and we could
disassociated from,
uh,
this ultra processed foods we eat
and start to ask the question,
what is it about, can we find what might
have driven obesity in that population?
Despite the existence of famine.
So it's from very simple observation.
Once we get into these kinds of studies,
say this in human genome studies,
say that,
um,
I actually rarely do that in my books
because you can find studies that will say
anything and you'll see in the studies,
um,
people misinterpreting them what was the
cause of the population of women to be
obese. So one of the thing that happened
during the very beginning in the 1960s,
the PMO were put on the reservoir.
They moved on to reds or
they were reservation eyes,
whatever the verb form would be.
And they began eating western foods.
And back then it was sugar flour and lard
for the most part and sugary beverages
probably.
So that's a reasonable hypothesis.
And you could find the same thing in
the Sioux native American to population
living on a reservation in
1928 where you had, uh, uh,
both obese men and women
living with malnourished,
stunted children who clearly
wasn't getting enough die,
but they were on a reservation, they were
getting western foods. So ultimately,
you know, the question you ask in
science determines the answer you get.
So the question I was asking is we have
this observation that any population
that transitions to western diet or
western diet and lifestyle gets obese and
diabetic, they, they develop
what's called Metabolic Syndrome,
which is insulin resistance
and all these issues.
And we know that's true
all over the world,
from the annual to the Pima to
south Pacific islanders to Africans,
to European.
So the genetics aren't that important.
The question is what's triggering
it in the environment? And again,
Stephan would say,
well there's too much food available and
it's too palatable and we can't say no.
And I had a lot of problems with the,
we can say no part.
Cause if we're lean it means that they
can say no and they being the people with
obesity. And I don't believe
that's true. And then,
or is it some specific item or
some specific group in this,
these foods that travel
with western populations.
And so the exists the ability.
And today if you look up a dual
burden of obesity and malnutrition,
I have a Dropbox folder.
I could share with you,
there's probably 50 studies all over
the world. You see the same observation,
incredibly poor populations,
malnourished. The children are stunted,
which means they're protein
deficient in their calorie deficient.
And often the mothers are,
the ants are obesity.
Obesity tends to run in the females,
which suggests it has a female sex hormone
related effect that I don't believe
works in the brain because we're dealing
with populations that could not have
overeaten if they could have
overeaten why are the kids starving?
That's sort of the question and know
this was the first thing that I think we
fought about back then.
And it's still,
if you can find populations
with obesity epidemics,
but without the modern food system,
without Snackwells and without
Lay's potato chips, um,
and if you know that they're going through
a famine or you know that the kids at
least aren't getting enough food,
how do you explain obesity and the mothers
without assuming that the mothers are
overheated? Let's pause
right there. Stephanie.
Is there a population of people that
are obese that are not eating a western
diet?
They're not eating being
sugary foods?
Um,
that are obese and that are not
eating sugary foods? Probably not.
Because generally once you have an
industrialized food system that's going to
include sugar,
but there are populations that eat
a lot of sugar and are not obese.
And we should talk about some of these.
Actually let's,
let's talk about the peanut
goes back to the, yeah, sure.
Let's talk about the FEMA first.
Uhm, now Gary has told his story.
He's told his version of the Pima story.
Let me tell the story,
the version of the story that appears in
the scientific literature. Now, the Pima,
um,
originally they were agriculturalists.
They were eating traditionally a very
high carbohydrate diet based on unrefined
carbohydrates. Originally it
was corn, beans and squash.
Primarily they were hunter gatherers on
agricultural. They were primarily Gary.
Okay. They were primarily
eating agricultural foods.
They were also collecting some
wild foods. That's correct. Um,
they were fishing and
eating the skeet pods,
primarily agricultural and,
um,
data are very clear on that, Gary.
So yes, they are. Look, we have data.
I can say things like that to happen
because we're going to die. Well, let's,
let's, let's move on. You think they
ate mostly fish? That's incorrect. Okay.
According to the data, that's, I
remember you saying that in your book.
Something to that effect. But you've
got my book where you load. So anyway,
let's go on. I'm going
to move on here. Um,
now the Pima traditionally
were agriculturalists and what,
what happened basically is you had all
these farmers moving into their area,
settlers, uh, of European descent,
and they diverted the water from
their river, the Gila or healer river,
if he allowed pronounced healer.
And so they were no longer
able to grow their crops,
their agricultural crops
that they were dependent on.
And therefore the government started
providing them with foods to eat.
And these were calorie dense refined
foods. They were like Gary said, uh,
flour,
lard and sugar.
And then they became very obese.
Now there was a population of Pima right
across the border from them in Mexico,
also very similar culturally and all
that then maintain their traditional high
carbohydrate lifestyle and
agricultural lifestyle.
And there've been studies comparing
those two populations and the, um,
ones across the border with their
traditional lifestyle or a lot leaner and
healthier, not surprisingly than the
ones eating lard, flour and sugar. Okay?
But Gary, uh, you seem to believe
that people can gain weight.
You kept referring to famines and things.
You seem to believe that people can gain
weight even if they are eating very few
calories. And you ever refer to this many
times in your writing. Um, and you know,
these are very casual observations
that you're making kind of these casual
correlations and storytelling.
But if you actually look
at the data on this,
what you see is that if you just measure
calorie intake and people who have
obesity,
it is 20 to 35% higher than people who
are lean after correcting for height,
physical activity level. Um, and
that I've got that references.
This is what we're getting. We're getting
a little bit into that means here.
Let me give you an exact number.
Seven, can I pause you guys right here?
So these people,
they have essentially the same lineage.
One group lives in Mexico.
They're not eating these sugary
foods and this a western diet.
The ones that live in America are the
ones that live in America are becoming
obese. The ones that live in Mexico or
not, is that correct? Correct. Yeah,
and so now if you have
someone with obesity,
like I've said that the most accurate
measures that we have suggests that they
habitually consume and
expend more calories and now
Gary's model says that that
is downstream of the fattening effect.
It's not causing the fattening effect.
It is a result of the fattening effects.
Whereas my model says that
that is actually required
for the fattening effects
to occur. It is upstream. So now
what happens? What happens here?
What happens if you reduce their
calorie intake by that same amount,
20 to 35% it doesn't matter if you
do it by restricting carbs or fat.
These experiments have been done.
They lose weight when you restrict
their calorie intake down to that as the
argument,
what you're saying that you consuming
low amounts of calories but high amounts
of sugar does, it doesn't make sense.
You can get obese that way. Um,
so you're saying it's a
cowrie. Yeah, correct.
And that's referenced number nine and 10.
Um,
to support what I just said and I want
to talk about another one that really can
you out on stuff. Yeah, that's what I,
the reason I was using dual burden example
is because we have to explain how those
women were eating all those calories.
So usually women,
again,
it's just often it was intro off in
these studies were done by diabetes
researchers who were studying diabetes
in these populations and the men had high
levels of diabetes in the women
who had high levels of obesity. Um,
to give you an example where
that measurement was done
in Trinidad in the 1960s
and again, all I'm doing, this is the
role I played as I asked the question,
can you find populations that
don't have a lot of food? Okay.
You could say that the obese expend
a lot of energy and they eat a lot of
calories. The question is can they
get obese without a lot of food?
And so can we find populations like us?
Can you find a population
that gets obese without sugar,
which was exactly the question to ask.
So in Trinidad,
in the 1960s there's a
mountain nutrition crisis.
The US government sends a team of
researchers down to study this and the
researchers come back and say, yeah,
there's malnutrition, there's stunting,
there's deficiency diseases.
And two thirds of the adult women are
obese and this is a medical problem.
And the next year and MIT nutritionist
goes to down to do exactly what Stefan
ass for and to actually measure the diets
and obese women and lean women and to
study it. And this is the
population where it's not like,
I mean this is a very poor Trinidad
and population and reports that they,
I think it was 1800 calories a day with
the obese woman reading was actually a
little less than what the lean people
seem to be eating and that it was lower
than what the Food and
Agricultural Organization
considered for a healthy diet.
So again,
what my role in this is to point out
when you have populations like that,
I don't see how the overeating hypothesis
tells me the brain is in control of
how much they eat. Tells me anything
about why the women were obese,
especially when their kids are starving.
This is the paradox of the stool burden.
An obese mother with a starving child,
if they're obese,
mother has to eat superfluous
calories to get fat.
Why isn't she given those calories to
her kids? Because she doesn't need them.
She clearly doesn't eat them. She's
got fuel. So what's going on there?
If you posit a hypothesis as I did where
it says that the obesity is triggered
by the macronutrient content of the Diet,
then you can explain.
I mean there are plenty of animal models.
A famous quote I use in my
books from Sean my year,
it was like the fame leading
Harvard nutritionist who
studied an obese strain of
animals in the 50s he said, my animals
will get fat even when half starved,
they will make fat out of their
food even when half starved.
These are generally animals with
mutations. In the Leptin. Um, it doesn't,
whatever [inaudible] whatever Janet is.
It's kind of the question is if like I
can make fat out of my food at levels of
caloric levels that for instance,
a lean person can't,
then I'm going to get fat eating the
same amount that fat accumulation
is going to be, you know, means I'm
taking in more calories and I expand.
But the point is I'm fro some
metabolic hormonal reason.
I'm taking the fuel NIAID and turning
it into fat and storing it in the fat
tissue. What does your
responses, yeah, so I'm,
my response is that if
you want the best answers,
you have to use the best methods to
answer to answer the questions. Okay.
Do you want a question answered properly?
You have to use accurate methods to
answer that question. Now, as you know,
Gary, it's very difficult to measure
food intake and free living individuals.
Particularly you're traveling to a
country you've never been to before.
It's very difficult to
get accurate measures.
So just because some guy went to Trinidad
and claimed woman, actually. Okay,
it's fine.
Just because some woman went to Trinidad
and claimed that people were eating
1800 calories and becoming obese does
not mean that that's what actually
happened. Now, let me, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Gary, I'm responding now.
We have studies where researchers used
accurate measures to measure calorie
intake in people who had obesity.
Many of these people were saying,
we're only eating 1200 calories a day.
When they actually measured
their calorie intake.
What they found was that
they were consistently eating
more calories than lean
people.
So this,
this phenomenon that Gary describes is
something that is only observed when
inferior methods are
used to measure calories.
But the reason I'm using these
populations, like I said,
I'm just giving you an observation.
Obese mother with a starving child,
the dual burden of malnutrition,
obesity, this isn't one observation,
it's not one nutritionist.
The existence of the starving children
strongly suggests that there's not a lot
of food available and we have to
explain obesity in the motto. You know,
I would like you to respond. Okay,
fine. I will respond to that. Now, look,
I haven't looked at these
studies in particular.
I brought them up eight years ago.
We got in the fight a battle.
We won that last eight years
ago. It ruined our, you know,
it's like are we used to
be buying? So now look, um,
there are many reasons why a child
could be malnourished in a nonindustrial
situation.
And this is,
I do a lot of work related to this and
what you see in nonindustrial situations,
you see a lot of infectious disease.
You see a lot of um,
malnutrition.
So people not getting enough essential
minerals and vitamins not getting enough
protein.
And you see a lot of children who are
just barely hanging on because of this
collection of really bad stuff that's
happening in their lives and set our
sights on. Yeah. Yeah. Parasites, malaria.
I don't know if there's
malaria in Trinidad or not,
but I mean all the diarrhea,
pneumonia, these are the things that we
all had before. We had modern medicine,
great sanitation. And then the
country, like the United States,
30% of kids didn't even
make it past childhood.
And so there's a lot of things
that could have caused that. Gary.
It's not necessarily because you know,
it's not necessarily the reason
that you attribute it to now.
I'm not attributing it to a reason.
I'm just asking. Okay, well great.
Well I don't have the explanation,
but I'm throwing out possibilities that
are alternative to the one that you're
implying quite possible. Okay. So now, um,
I, so again, when you use accurate
measures of calorie intake,
you find that these people with magical
metabolisms who have obesity and don't
eat very much seem to not exist
anymore. Um, and furthermore, I want to,
I want to get this to another type of
study that's really going to differentiate
between this metabolic effect driven
by insulin and the effect of calories.
So we have a lot of studies that compared
diets in which calories were the same
but carbohydrate and fat intake deferred.
And the ones that I really want to focus
on right now that I think are key here
are this studies where they
increased calorie intake.
So they fed people, they, they f
one study in particular. And um,
let's see. I'm going to
give you a number here. Um,
let me see if I can give you
a number here. Sorry. Why
don't you look at that. Um,
can we,
uh,
bring up another issue because what we're
talking about ultimately as why people
get fat, okay, I don't, I
don't want to divert here. I'm
in the middle of something.
So,
um,
now if we want to understand
why people get fat,
we can look at studies that overfed
people on fat or carbohydrate exclusively.
So this one study, um, the first
one that I want to talk about first,
they figured out people's
baseline calorie intake,
figure out how many calories
they need to just to maintain,
and then they increase that by 50% by
exclusively giving them fat or exclusively
giving them carbohydrate. Okay?
Study was, this is Horton. Okay.
Um, give me a yes, a
number 16. Number 16. So,
um,
now if Gary's hypothesis is correct,
these people should have gained body fat
on the carbohydrate overfeeding but not
the fat overfeeding because
that increases your insulin.
It has these effects on your
fat cells, et Cetera. Okay? Now,
these were very rigorous studies.
I want to emphasize that I pause here.
They monitor the, the actual calories they
got, correct? Yes, they were. They were,
they had a baseline. They use prison or
something per month they provide, no,
that's incorrect. This was a different
study. So they had a baseline.
And did they require them to maintain
the same diet and then add additional fat
or additional carbohydrates?
Yes.
So the same food and then they just bump
it up with that [inaudible] it up with
carbohydrate or there wasn't sims. It was
Ethan Sims. What's talking to the mic?
That was,
which study did he do that was not
prisoners? What was the, uh, he didn't
have a metabolic, you know what?
Let me just finish describing
this study. We can, Gary,
that's an irrelevant detail.
Okay.
What's relevant is that you
just didn't implied that.
I don't know what I'm talking
about. Gary are, you know what,
I don't actually know. Maybe it was
in prison, so thank you. All right.
You're welcome. Now. Um,
but it was not the Sims overfeeding
study that was done in prisoners.
That's what I know. Okay. Okay. So what's
the reference? Yeah, it's on my website.
You can go to my website,
uh,
Stephanie g and a.com and it's referenced
numbers 16 and they're both there.
Okay.
So this was what's called a metabolic
ward study where these people were in a
research facility where the researchers
could monitor and control every morsel
of food. So there was no
cheating, no inaccuracy.
And they were measuring changes in body
fatness using a gold standard method
called underwater weighing.
Okay.
And so what they found was that at the
end of a two week period of overfeeding,
the carb in the fat groups gained
the exact same amount of body fat,
exact same amount of body fat.
There was another second study that did
the same thing and found the same result,
independent lab group, very similar
experiment. Three week long.
Instead of two weeks, they found the
exact same thing, same amount of fat gain,
different insulin responses,
different amounts of carbohydrates,
that exact same amount of fat gain.
So this demonstrates that insulin is not
in cars or not what controls what gets
fat into fat tissue.
Calorie intake is what controls that.
So let me explain again.
Remember I talked about everything.
The paradigm you work in
determines the question you ask.
And this experiment is a classic example
because they assume that people get fat
by overfeeding.
So then they say if we overfeed them,
we've just doing what happens naturally.
Everything about the experiment is based
on the assumption that they're supposed
to be testing, which is Ken. People
get fat by overfeeding. And so the,
from the very conception of the experiment
they've built in the paradigm that we
want to test the hypothesis,
I'm on top of it. Uh,
if it's a typical sims experiment,
I actually wasn't familiar with this one.
Oh it was a, it wasn't,
Sims was a James Oh,
JCP and of James Hill was funded for them
from about 1998 to about
2008 by proctor and gamble.
Cause he was in a less dra
shill. I hate to say that, Jim,
I apologize,
but I think it's a fair assessment.
And then when he stopped being
funded by proctor and gamble,
he was funded by the sugar industry.
He's,
and JC Peters was the head
of the proctor and gamble,
Astra and Leicester, which is now
something that no one eats. Yeah,
Lester was a fat substitute and the
problem was you got like run out shit like
that.
But the whole idea of a Lustra
was to replace fat in the Diet.
So every study Helen Peters did implicated
dietary fat as a cause of obesity.
I don't think we could ever use, I
hate to say it, I'm typically, I,
I don't think funding influences
results, but I wouldn't use it. James.
He'll study to make that point that
because you think it's a biased
study that was in everything. Hell,
everything Helen Peters did and one knows.
I mean,
I talked about this in good calories,
bad calories when they reported
their results. I actually,
I did a foyer on James Hill because he
works for the University of Colorado's.
He could actually,
and I got all his documents back and
forth between him and the Lester.
I'd be happy to share them with you
if you'd like there. Rebel that,
I mean him and proctor and gamble,
but he basically held proctor
and gamble for ransom.
You would get a $500,000
unrestricted gift,
and then he would do a study and then he
would ask it and it would conclude that
fat is bad and carbs are good, and
therefore a Lester as a viable product.
Then he would ask for proctor and gamble
for more money before he then published
study.
So it to particularly egregious
example of someone who's,
I suspect it was just his belief system,
he believed dietary fat was bad,
fat causes obesity.
Uh,
Lester is a good thing because you eat
that instead of fat, you don't absorb it.
And then every study he did confirm that,
um.