You mentioned the thing with feet and
I was watching blue planet to the other
day and there was,
it's not a fish apparently,
it's called like a toad of some kind,
but it's,
it hangs out on the bottom
and it has feet. It's,
it looks like a fish that grew feet. It
walks around. Yeah. That's not a fish.
I don't believe so. It's actually a some
sort of toad I think technically. Whoa.
But yeah, and they look like human feet
almost like how his toes and everything.
Well, one of the weirdest things that I
ever saw about the ocean was there was a
theory that was going around a few
years ago that I don't know if this is
legitimate,
not go Google,
that they think that it's entirely
possible that octopus Octopi may have come
from eggs that were frozen and
landed here from an asteroid.
There was speculation that there
was something about the way, yeah,
the way that they pro,
you know,
the DNA and RNA of octopus are so
different than every other animal in the
fossil record that it's almost that there,
there was a consideration that they
might have actually been an alien species
because you know the term,
you know what Panspermia means.
Panspermia is a theory that is pretty
widely accepted in the scientific
community that some life is transferred
through asteroid collisions.
So like that,
say if a chunk of rock slams into our
planet and knocks a chunk of rock loose in
that chunk has DNA on it and the amino
acids and all the building blocks for
life, that bacteria, whatever it is,
things that, some things, you know,
little things can survive in space like
tardigrades little life forms can to
survive in space that they slam into a
planet eventually and then when they do
that, that life is transferred onto that
new planets. Science News. Holy Shit.
The buses came to earth from space as
frozen eggs millions of years ago. Okay.
But this is like the, the express. Yep.
I was trying to, I read it
a little bit, but that's,
that's the most feasible version
of aliens coming here. Yes.
We tend to think of it as it lands and
they're like a spaceman who looks like
George Clooney steps out but he has
like antenna or something like, hi, I'm,
I'm here to share with our,
our planet all,
all tuna or whatever and he speaks
English and all this shit. Like it's,
it's on a, on a biological level
that we almost can't comprehend.
You could go back to that James,
please
look what it says that the extraordinary
claims made an a report entitled the
case of Cambrian Explosion,
terrestrial or cosmic,
which caused by a group of 33
scientists and published in the pro uh,
progress in biophysics and
molecular biology journal.
And the paper suggest that the explanation
for the sudden flourishing of life
during the Cambrian era,
often referred to as the Cambrian
explosion lies in the stars as a result of
earth being bombarded by
clouds of organic molecule.
Wow. I think that's also the theory of
how water got on earth. They came from,
it came from comments,
cause when you see comments,
comments are all water and I think like
millions of years of us can hammered by
comments. Huh? Like you know when
you see the trails of comments,
that's literally ice, dirt and
debris coming off of that comment.
I didn't know that.
Literally the more you know,
the more you know it in a comment,
but it,
they think that about mushrooms as well.
They think that spores
can survive in a vacuum.
So if something like say if some
spores were attached to a rover yeah.
And we shot her off to move to the moon
or something like that and it got there
somehow or another, if there was the
right conditions for that thing to grow,
that they could actually survive the
trip and then grow on the moon or on Mars
or anywhere where would be water
and sunlight and atmosphere,
like invasion of the body snatchers.
Yeah. We'll spores or even weirder. Right.
Because spores create mushrooms and
mushrooms actually breathe oxygen and you
breathe out carbon dioxide.
They say they're,
they're closer to an animal than the art
of vegetables. Yeah. That's uh, that's,
I've thought about that when I've, when
I've eaten magic mushrooms a lot. Right.
It's like I basically just ate an animal.
Well, you also feel like it's taking,
like it's alive inside of you
communicating with you. Right.
Don't you feel like that? Like it's
not as simple as I'm getting high. No,
I smoke weed. I feel like I'm
getting high when I eat mushrooms.
I feel like I'm entering into the thought
process of an alien creature. Yeah. You,
you put on like a space suit on the
inside in a way and, and you're,
you're evolving a certain way if only for
like seven or eight hours or something.
Yeah.
Do you ever microdose now I have friends
that do that and Ron White's big into
that. Oh, is he? Every day
you'll have found [inaudible] but
good kind of medicine. Oh my God. Ron.
Ron White kills me, man. I just,
you just pick their most random name
you could have, but I'm just like,
that makes perfect sense.