Spoken alliance. It's not a secret,
it's just, it's not there. It's there,
but it's not, nobody's talking
about it. Do you realize,
I'll just give an example.
Okay.
If you needed more reasons to think
that Columbus was a dick. Okay.
Let me add one to it. When we
were kids and today, I know,
I know,
but actually I do have something smiley
redeeming to offer about Columbus if you
have the time. I just want to,
okay, let's start off with that.
Do you want me start out with that?
How do you want to do it?
I'll do the dick part. Okay,
so on his third voyage,
he's in,
by the time of his third voyage,
he had already planted enough Spanish
flags that Spain had already begun to set
up governments and infrastructures in
these places that he had a compound
basically conquered and so,
so in one of the places was it,
it's in the book accurately,
but I think it's Hispaniola.
One of the island today he has
to get back is it's third voice,
1503 1504 he's got to get back to Spain.
He doesn't have enough resources,
not enough food for his crew.
So he asks the natives,
would you please give us some of your
stock that you have collected from your
farming?
Now this particular group of natives only
makes exactly the amount of food they
need to tie to the next crop. They
don't have surplus. So they said, no,
we don't have surplus. Sorry.
Columbus knew that one week,
hence,
coincidentally there was gonna be a total
lunar eclipse with a moon in its orbit
around Earth,
enters earth's shadow.
The full moon enters earth's
shadow and disappears.
And that the geometry of that event,
it's just a simple lunar eclipse,
but the geometry says that sunlight
passes around earth through earth's
atmosphere and takes on sunset colors
that Leech into Earth's shadow giving the
moon. If you can see it at
all, a deep red amber hue,
almost the color of blood Columbus set.
And he knew about this cause he had
read the tables, the eclipse tables.
All right? We, we'd known enough about
the solar system at the time too.
We got that. Okay. Actually back then,
it was just the known world with Earth
in the middle of the known universe.
But that didn't matter. The rhythms
of the universe, we're known.
He says to the natives,
if you do not give us food,
my God,
which is more powerful than your God
will make the moon disappear and it will
turn blood red. That will happen in
one week. You have one week to comply.
Some of them were skeptical of what
you can't. What other sets? Shit,
we got to do what this guy said. Look
at the ships. They came in, their guns,
their power, their, their
culture. Look what they've got.
Sure enough,
right on cue.
The moon begins to disappear according
to that. That is a famous woodcut.
Um Oh, you got this. Oh those
viewing the video of this.
That is a famous woodcut.
And notice the natives bowing to him
and he stands proudly cause he knows the
science. He knows the
astronomy. He knew this.
And so he invokes this to dominate
people who are not yet scientifically
literate.
And within seconds of this beginning,
they bring him all the resources
he wants. And he gets, and I don't,
we don't know what happened,
you know,
back at the island whether the
people survived the winter,
but he got back to the island,
that that is one microcosm of a set of
ways that the universe has been invoked
in this. I'll give you another example
of Los Alamos, one of the national labs.
They today as basically
since their inception,
are charged with tracking the
nuclear arsenal of the United States,
our nuclear power, the, the nukes
that would go into nuclear weapons.
They think about this.
Do you realize they hire astrophysicist?
I had colleagues work in there. You
know why? Because there's our room.
There are two rooms. I mean
I'm, I'm, I'm simplifying this,
but basically there are two rooms adjacent
to one another and a computer between
the two of them,
the most powerful computers in the world,
and there is code running
on those computers that
calculates the energy yields
of hydrogen fusion.
That's exactly what an astrophysicist
cares about when stars blow up.
Okay.
The Sun is undergoing nuclear fusion right
now and that's how it's making energy
and when the, when high mass stars
dies, they exploded supernova.
This is a natural thing going on.
Then you ever in the universe on the
other side, that's a classified room.
They're calculating yields of hydrogen
bombs and they have lunch together and
they compare notes. The government
doesn't always have the best people,
but if you hire some of the best people
to do whatever it is they want and
they'd calculations happen to relate to
a military project there you have a two
way street in progress. Why do you
think the Hubble telescope that the,
the,
the mirror issues not withstanding,
which were ultimately fixed
when it was first launched,
why was that so successful?
There were versions of the
Hubble telescope previously
launched by the military
looking down that,
that the model for that telescope had
already been conceived and built and was
operating. Then we say, oh, we want
one of those. Okay, but we don't,
that's not public that this is going on.
We designed, the telescope gets designed.
It has the benefit of previous versions
of it. Having been used successfully,
but looking down and we look up,
this is the perennial two way street of
astronomy in the old days and in modern
times,
astrophysics and the invention of the,
you haven't said anything yet or you
just, you look, you're a good listener.
I'll should I keep, just keep talking
and by preventing you from interrupting.
Don't worry about me. Okay, fine.
Galileo perfects the telescope.
He learned that it had just been
invented in the Netherlands.
The Dutch were were up opticians.
All right,
so they invented the telescope and the
microscope within a couple of years of
one another. This transformed science.
When did they invent the eyeglass?
The reading class, the reading
earlier than that, but I don't,
I don't know when the real advance was
putting two lenses in line with one
another. Sounds trivial in modern
times, but that was a huge leap.
Conceptual leap and what you
would accomplish and in so doing,
depending on how you curve them
and how you grind them, grind that,
the shape of those lenses you would
get a microscope or telescope and,
and we're off to the races.
That's basically the birth
of modern science as we now
think of it. And, and, and,
and conducted. Because you
say to yourself, my senses,
I don't trust them to be the full record
of what's going on in front of me.
You pull out a microscope. Oh my gosh.
Leeuwenhoek he got the microscope guy.
He thought he got a drop of pond water,
puts it under his microscope just to
think to do this. It's just water.
Why do you think that's something
interesting to do? He said, I wonder,
he was curious.
He puts it under and sees little what
he described as Anna macules happily,
uh,
swimming.
And I'm acute macules these are like
the Amoebas and paramecium and Oh,
it is. And so he writes a
heat reports on this too,
to the scientific authorities.
And they don't believe him.
They say, uh, you know, [inaudible] uh,
we think you might have had too much
gin before you wrote this letter.
Why would anyone believe this?
That there's entire creatures,
an entire universe of creatures
thriving in a drop of pond water.
And so the way science works is
one report does not make it true.
You need verification.
They send people to the Netherlands to
verify his results and there it was the
birth of microscopy and then they
looked at everything sells, you know,
they need vocabulary to describe what
you're now seeing. Well that was the, the,
the,
the journey down small.
Then the journey went up big and
Galileo perfects the telescope.
He looks up, he's like, Whoa, I see
craters, mountains, valleys on the moon.
The Sun has spots.
Venus goes through phases.
This became the Corpus of evidence for
earth going around the sun in Supportive
Copernicus's idea that earth
went around the sun. My point is,
what was the second thing he did
with his telescope? He telephone. No,
they didn't tell me.
He contacted the Doge of Venice,
invited him to the clock tower and said,
look at what this instrument can do for
you. As we look out into the lagoon,
you can identify a ship's intentions,
friend or foe by its flag 10 times
farther away than you can with the unaided
eye.
Venice bought a boatload
of these telescopes in the
service of their military
defense,
and this was a source of money to Galileo,
and now he could go look at the universe.
This has been a two way street ever
since. People have looked up. So,
so this is, this is an accounting of
that. This is, it's and, and it's it,
it goes on and on the first
x ray machines for airports,
you're old enough to remember.
Why would they put in because
of hijackings to Cuba,
basically that they were armed hijackings
of airplanes of American carriers to
Cuba. And Congress said, we gotta do
something about that. Oh, by the way,
there's a company in Boston called
American Science and engineering that was
building an x ray detector,
small enough to put on a satellite
to observe the universe in x rays.
And because no one had zipped, we've
used visible light, but not x rays.
That's a branch of the
electromagnetic spectrum.
We think if they're black holes out there,
their region surrounding
them will give us x rays.
It's a new window on the universe.
And then they said,
oh my gosh, there's a call for
x ray machines at airports.
We've got the technology that we've
perfected to put it up frickin satellite.
So the technology for those ones,
you walked through the airport
initially came initially? Yes, yes, yes.
There was a two way street. There was, oh
my gosh, we need this for security. Oh,
by God we would, we were
using, let's, let's,
let's apply that technology
to these detectors. Well,
that's been a lot of the stuff
with the space program. Right.
And a lot of the stuff that they devised
for use on the space station and so
many other technologies have
trickled their way down.