I was,
the World Cup was on today.
I went to get a cup of coffee and they're
the World Cup on and these all these
guys are gathering and
watch the World Cup.
To me it's just some dudes running around.
I don't know what's going on. I don't,
I don't. It's fine. It's great, it's good.
But for them it was
clearly and for the world,
for all the people watching in the stands
as an elevated level of passion for
that. Now, if that was your thing,
I would say maybe you can be a commentator
or maybe you can be a player or maybe
it could be someone who produces one
of those soccer shows or something like
that.
There's just plenty of gigs for that.
But if that's your thing and
instead you get into shoe sales,
like Al Bundy, you know, after a while
that shit chips away and you're like,
this is not what I like. I like is I want
to play soccer. I want to watch soccer,
I want to talk about soccer,
I want to commentate on soccer.
You got to find the thing and that ula go.
Not everybody can,
a on soccer dad is true but is also
a loser mentality like someone can,
yeah. Not everybody can, but how many
people try? That's the other thing.
Like people say, not everybody can
be successful comedian. You're right.
How many people try though? Right? It's
just not that many people try. You know,
more people could do it then,
then try.
I think there's a bunch of people out
there that could, I always tell you about,
I've told you about this guy. My friend
Dave Dolan, who was a, uh, my boss,
he's a private investigator. When I was
a kid, I got a gig driving him around.
He needed an assistant. Really? He got
a Dui and they took his license away.
He needed a driver.
He was the funniest guy I've ever met.
He's right up there with Joey Diaz.
Wow. So funny man. And you know,
not no aspirations for comedy at all.
And his cousin was Billy Downs who
was one of the owners of the comedy
connection in Boston.
So his,
his cousin was a former comedian who
owned the comedy club and just randomly
became friends with them
from an ad on like, you know,
like one of those newspaper ads for
the job seeking a private investigators
assistant and wait, that sounds
like a cool job. Oh Wow. Yeah. So,
but this guy easily could have been a
comic, like 100% could have been a car.
He's a,
he was a funny fucking dude and he was
always the guy that if a bunch of people
were saying around,
he would say something like
totally ridiculous looking
in the eye and say it and
everybody would be laughing.
It was just natural.
He was just a naturally funny
guy. Just, just didn't do it.
Did he like being a private investigator?
Loved it. Loved it. Loved busting people.
Cheaters. Mostly people who were cheating
on your insurance. That was mostly,
it was, there was a few of them. One,
he got one guy who kept asking him to
take pictures of his girlfriend getting
fucked by this giant body builder dude.
And after awhile I was like, hey dude,
enough with this kinky shit.
I'm not giving you any more
fucking pictures through
that. The dude, he's like,
get the fuck Outta here with this. He
goes like, what else do you want bro?
I got the pictures that are going to
get more pictures. You fucking idiot.
That's so funny.
That's so funny that why didn't the
guy just hire a photographer? Right.
Well the guy, he was this like
really wealthy but diminutive,
very non masculine man and he had this
bombshell girl that he had figured out a
way to get a part of and but she was
just getting drilled on the side.
Did she know he was getting pictures
taken? I don't think she did. No,
I don't think she put it.
It sounds like to me it sounds like
a fetish game where he's like, oh,
seems like a bit of it. I don't think
it was. I think it was just a weak guy.
Didn't know what to do because
they would be on the beach.
He get pictures of on the beach making
out and stuff. You're like, he got,
he got enough pictures. A
lot of these guys. I mean, I
don't, yeah, I don't know man.
I just,
that to me sounds a little bit like,
well that's what he thought a little bit.
He thought the guy was
a little bit of a freak,
but at the end of the day he was
like, look, come on. You know,
it was fucking heavy Boston
accent, Bro. I got you.
You fucking pictures did to make a move.
Right.
We're not taking any more sale at Saks.
That's a shit job.
I wouldn't want to do that. He'd love
busting people. That's not his thing.
He didn't really like,
that was rare.
Most of the time he worked for insurance
companies. Most of the time it was like,
say if you were married and you are a
woman and you had a different maiden name,
you would get injured on the job and then
you would start using your maiden name
and take a job on the side while
you're getting workman's compensation.
So people would get
double paid. Whoa. Yeah.
And they would have to leave their jobs.
Like people would leave their
job super early in the morning.
So we would camp out in front of people's
houses where we would get there at
four o'clock in the morning
when everybody's asleep.
We'd sit in the car across the street
and we'd wait sometimes earlier and we'd
wait and we'd wait and we wait five 30
roll around and then you'd see some light
go on and they like, he's up, he's up,
he's up here, he goes, here, he goes,
this motherfucker's going to work and
this is the guy who's supposed to be laid
up in bed and we catch them like working
as a roofer carrying shingles up a
ladder when they're getting disable
a disability insurance. So it's,
that was a really common thing.
Most of it was disability insurance man.
What a fucked up state
of life to get into.
Or you're doing insurance fraud.
Like that's a,
that's a sad existence to like getting
to that spot where you're like,
I'm going to get, I'm going to give it
to the man. I've come up with a scheme,
honey, you know some of
them, the comedy store,
I probably can't mention their names.
I'm just not like that man.
See this is the thing, like it was nice
people, they just didn't know better.
And I don't say that like they're stupid.
I say that like they're just dating.
I don't think they're going to get caught.
They didn't think it was that big a deal.
They didn't think through it very well.
Or if there was one lady was
so nice, she uh, he had a scam.
This was a scam. Safe.
Your license plate number.
He would write down your license plate
number and then write down one that was
really close to it and write down another
one that was really close to that.
And then he would knock on your door
and he'd say, I hate to bother you.
But my girlfriend was in a car accident
and the police report where they had the
witnesses driver's license number,
a,
some coffee got spilled on the report
and they don't know exactly what the
license number is. There's, we've
checked these two, it's not them.
I have a friend who works the DMV and
they hooked me up and then you tell her an
injury. Oh, I'm sorry. What? What
happened too? Is She okay? She's okay.
But she did this. Oh my
God, I had that same injury.
You tell them the injury that they had
that's giving them Workman's compensation
and uh, yeah, I had the
saint. That's terrible.
Do you guys want to come in
and have a cup of coffee?
She invites us in the fucking house.
Strangers.
This is what people did
in the eighties dude.
They invited people in the house
like pilgrims. Yeah, these crazy,
this lady invited two guys into her
house and he spins or a yarn about his
girlfriend being injured and she said, I
have the exact same problem. And he said,
well, what happened? She said, well,
I was on the job as a flight attendant
and I fell down and hurt myself.
And he goes, well, you're getting
paid, aren't ya? And she goes, oh,
not all am I getting paid,
but I'm also working under my maiden
name and another job. He's like, Oh yeah,
great, great idea. Way To
do it, lady is so nice.
And we got out of there and I was like,
man, we can't turn her. And he's like,
fuck car. She goes, wow. She goes,
she's a fucking crook. He
goes, that lady's a fucking
crook. Know she's so nice.
She let us in her house. She gave
us coffee. That's the car. I love.
That shit man.
Via Nice has somehow become synonymous
with not being dangerous or a crook.
That's a really funny thing.
It's like cause being nice is like,
that's like a really
great costume to put on.
Like if you want to camouflage yourself.
Yeah, and you're a Predator, right? Yeah.
You know the way light
tiger,
she wasn't a predator.
She was just a lady who didn't think it
was a big deal to rip off a corporation.
People grow up thinking
corporations are faceless,
nameless entities and you can
extract money from them. Yeah.
Think that's the way it is.
People think of some liability lawsuits.
Like you slip on some water in the hallway
and a big building and you fall down
like, oh, I'm hurt. I'm real
hurt. You guys didn't protect me.
My balance was compromised and
I fell on your ground. Somebody,
somebody puts some water on your ground.
I'm not responsible for this.
I'm going to sue, sue, sue, sue. Yeah.
It's fucked. It's bad that, that, that
woman was making a terrible mistake.
And your, um, your friend Dolan,
dynamite, dickless, Dave Dolan,
he comes over, he helped, he
helped her, he helped her,
he helped her out because
like that kind of shit,
that kind of life like stealing,
you want to create like a,
you want to create a version
of that woman were like inside.
She didn't feel alone, at least a little
bad, a little better, a little weak,
a little off balance of course.
But reality,
the reality is she didn't
feel good about that probably.
And that's not a great
way to live, man. And,
and so by getting corrected
by the universe in those ways,
you know, I think it's, it's, it's a
good thing. I'm glad that, you know,
some things aren't illegal, for
example, but they are, you know,
like obviously like we agree on some
of these things, right? Those things,
it's fucked up to bus people
that if you're stealing in a, in,
in, uh, in that, in that way. I
don't know, man. No, you're right.
No, you're right. But I would have never
turned her in. I would have said this,
I can't die, would've never been a
good private investigator. I just,
I feel like a lot of those people
and I was one knee at the time,
21 at the time, at the
most 21 I think. Um,
at that time I was really well aware of
like the re the neighborhood where my
grandparents grew up. Right. Like, and,
and being around them and being around
my parents who grew up in the 60s and
then my grandparents who grew up,
I mean they were,
they were here in the
depression and they just,
there was a different attitude
about opportunity. Like
everybody was poor. Right?
Yeah.
Everybody would like take advantage of
every opportunity and if you've got an
opportunity to run a scam,
yeah, you did it. Yeah.
And that's a terrible
thing that happens in,
in poor communities is that people
do think of like insurance scams,
this kind of scam. Like, you know, you
got to think about it like it's a score,
you know, think about it. Like it's a
score. I've heard guys say that to me.
I know older Italian guys, look, you've
got to think about this. This is a score.
Okay, can't fuck this up.
You've got an opportunity here.
All you have to do is you go to the
fucking chiropractor. My backers,
they can't tell you why your back hurts.
Nobody knows why you're fucking that
Kurtz. Which is true. Yeah. You know,
you would go to a chiropractor every day
and say, my back is fucking killing me.
I got a shooting pain down my leg.
They can't prove it or disprove it.
Next thing you know,
you get a $35,000 check in the mail.
Right? Yeah. I, you know, man,
here's the thing. Number one,
I feel like I have to say this,
I would not have turned this fucking
that woman in if I was not a private
investigator, but that'd
be in Dolan. Ethically.
You had to turn her in.
Cause if he didn't,
he would be guilty of stealing from the
person who was giving him money to do
the job. There was never a question right
then. That's what he did for a living.
He was turned around.
Yeah.