Now,
before the podcast started,
you were telling me that you wrote a
30 page paper on the Carnivore Diet.
It's not a paper. Well, it's, I
definitely spent about 30 pages.
I thought about it for a long time.
And yes,
there's 30 pages of thoughts
and references. Were you
stunned that this became,
I mean, this is a very recent thing.
Yeah. People were just eating meat.
Well,
at first when I was,
I think Dan told me about it like
couple of years ago even like,
and I thought there's no way I was like,
I just ignored it,
but craze barely have time for
that. Right. So, yeah, I definitely,
um,
dismissed it when I,
when I first heard about it.
But it's definitely been something
that has gained a lot of traction,
you know, sending disturb you
that it's getting traction. Well,
I definitely have concerns.
Um, you know, I think that the,
the most important question really is
what is attracting someone to try such a
very restrictive diet.
You know,
that potentially could be dangerous
without published evidence or any sort of
long term studies and things like that.
So I think that the first question really
is, well, why are people doing this?
And so looking on the Internet and try to
like read about people's anecdotes. Um,
it seems as though a lot of people are
drawn to it because they have some sort
of autoimmune problem and uh,
so they try this diet and it
improves their autoimmune symptoms.
And I see that seems to be a real
common theme in you, at least if you,
if you look in the blog is
peers and stuff like that. Um,
so that's I think kind of a good place
to start where it's like, well, you know,
what are people doing this
for? And then, uh, so that's,
that's kind of an important
question and I'm so,
so further reading about this diet,
it sort of sort of think about,
well, okay, well what's going on?
It's really important when you have
like something that leads to a,
an effect to understand the mechanism
because the mechanism is you know,
what's leading to this effect.
And so if you can do something that's
potentially not so dangerous or risky,
then understanding the
mechanism will help you.
Because then you can find other
ways to do it. Right. And so, um,
if you look at at uh, published
studies on people that eat low carb,
high protein diets, um, what's
pretty common is that there,
there's changes that happen in a
variety of different endocrine factors.
I'm like, you're less insulin that's
changing your satiety and hunger hormones,
Leptin and Ghrelin and people become
more satiated and they actually eat less.
And this has been shown in multiple
studies so people actually eat less when
they're having a higher protein diet,
which makes sense too because protein
is more satiating, uh, as well. Um,
and also there's also been studies
on what's called food habituation.
Uh,
we're basically,
so habituation is when you're
constantly exposed to the same stimulus,
you sort of have a decreased response
to that stimulus where there's been
intervention trials where people are
given the same food every single day,
both non obese and obese people versus
people that are giving the same food once
a week. And the people that are given the
same food every single day, they just,
they start to eat less calories,
so they start to eat less naturally
started to cal work, restrict themselves.
Um, so I mean, and that's,
it's kind of like a dietary
monotony because sort of thing.
So I think there are any,
you know,
if you read and the people out there
on the blogs talking about this diet,
they say, I'm like, I'm eating
less. I only eat twice a
day. I'm fasting. You know,
so that's,
people are talking about that as well.
So I think there's published evidence to
kind of explain that. And also there's,
you know, people thing. Yeah, I eat less.
So that's an important point because
one thing that's really known to affect
autoimmunity is caloric
restriction and fasting.
Like it's probably one of
the most well known, um,
technologies that you can intervene and
have improvements in autoimmune disease.
So,
um,
some of that has to do with the fact
that you can sort of reset your immune
system. There have been animal
studies and human studies,
a lot of this done by doctor
Valter Longo at USC. Uh,
he's done some prolonged
fasting, um, in animals.
And also there's been sort of like a
fasting mimicking diet done in humans,
which kind of very low calorie diet.
This sort of is meant to mimic fast.
Um, and those have shown that, um,
you basically kind of crossover because
fasting is a type of stress you cross
over into this like stronger
stress response where you're
not only like cleaning
away all the gunk and the sides of cells.
People talk about a toffee g lot
when they're talking about fasting.
You clean away things like damaged, you
know, pieces of DNA, protein aggregates,
things like that. Mitochondria
that are damaged get cleared out.
But you also sort of start to clear away
entire cells through a process called
apoptosis. And in animal studies, what's
been shown is that if you do, for example,
a 72 hour fast,
you can clear away about 30% of
the immune system and, and, and,
and re replenish it with like brand new
healthy immune cells and literally like
Oregon's shrink when,
during the fasting and then they'd like
re-expand because you're activating stem
cells and you're, you're, you know,
basically replenishing all your
damaged old cells with new ones.
We'll vaulter is shown in this
animal studies. Also autoimmune, um,
uh,
cells tend to be selectively killed off
and replaced with non on immune cells.
So he's also done a clinical study,
a pilot clinical study with people
with multiple sclerosis doing this fast
mimicking diet for one month,
sorry for one week. And um,
there there's symptoms improved.
Also a ketogenic diet was done side by
side and Ketogenic Diet also improves
symptoms of autoimmunity. So those both
were done in humans. So I think that, um,
you know, understanding that, you know,
some of these mechanisms that are at
play and not fasting itself and calorie
restriction, both have been
shown to approve autoimmunity.
You may be tapping into something there
by eating last. That's one possibility.
Um,
in addition,
there's been clinical studies
in humans where they were done,
they were basically fasted for 24
hours every other day for 15 days.
So they had like a total
of seven days of fasting.
And these are also people
with multiple sclerosis.
And there's profound changes in the
microbiome that started happening.
And this was an in line
with basically, um, having,
you know,
a lot of anti inflammatory cytokines
basically producing immune cells that are
really important for preventing
autoimmunity called t regulatory cells and
things like that. So that's another
really important thing to consider is,
you know,
the microbiome because the microbiome
has been linked to autoimmunity in
multiple, multiple studies. I mean,
it's been linked to arthritis.
It's been linked to multiple sclerosis.
It's been linked to other
diseases like Parkinson's,
which is not really autoimmune. But,
um, and the point of this is that,
you know, again, understanding
mechanism and realizing, you know,
there's other potential factors that could
be leading to an effect, right? It's,
it's actually, um, the,
the changes in the microbiome are really
important because there's actually been
a few animal studies which
have led to phase one,
phase two and phase three clinical
trials that have been done in humans.
So humans with multiple sclerosis,
we're treated with [inaudible]
cycling and antibiotic,
and they'd been basically the antibiotic
was shown to improve symptoms and
multiple sclerosis.
And because there there's good bacteria
and bad bacteria that had been linked to
autoimmunity and getting rid
of getting rid of bacteria,
the bad bacteria is going to
probably lead to improvement.
And that's what was shown first and the
animal studies and then in human trials.
So humans, I'm taking with
multiple sclerosis, taking
Munis cycling for two years.
So basically they had improvements
to delay the onset, um, uh,
progression of the disease.
Then after two years,
those improvements went away probably
because you're wiping out the microbiome
and eventually you're
also getting rid of the,
the good bacteria and so that
things are going to catch up, right?
So you're not just,
you may be getting rid of some of the
pathogenic bad bacteria with antibiotics,
but eventually, like you're also getting
rid of good stuff. So longterm, you know,
you may not have those same improvements.
And that,
and that's a very interesting and I
think it's really important point to
understand, um, with, with
something like, you know,
change is very profound changes in the
microbiome when it comes to someone just
eating meat. Um, so one
thing to keep in mind with,
with the microbiome is that basically a
bacteria really are good at adapting to
their environment. That's why antibiotic
resistance is such a big deal.
And when you,
there's been human intervention studies,
when you take a human that goes from
a high fiber diet to a low fiber,
high protein or vice versa,
you get changes in their gut microbiome
that happened within 24 hours.
So within an hour you actually start to
have doubling of populations of bacteria.
And within 24 to 48 hours,
do you actually start to lose other,
so basically other bacteria start to die
off. And this is at the species level.
It's really hard to change.
The phyla of the file is more
linked to longterm dietary patterns.
Eventually you can change file as well,
but it's been shown that
people that go from a, um,
a more high fiber to a high protein diet,
they tap changed their microbiome.
And these changes are a lot
of the microbiome, you know,
bacteria that are fermenting a variety
of fermentable fibers start to leave and
you actually start to get bacteria
cropping up that ferment amino acids.
So the amino acids, amino
acids, simple sugars, thoughts,
those are mostly absorbed
in the small intestine,
but some of them make their way into the
large intestine. And there's a whole,
you know,
group of bacteria called putrifactive
bacteria and they ferment amino acids.
And some of these species of,
of putrifactive bacteria has
been linked to colon cancer. Uh,
there are much higher and colon cancer
patients. Animal studies have shown,
you know,
causal links where they can basically
regressively cause a polyp to,
to form a tumor.
Um,
and that's because these bacteria are
making things called pewter scene and
cadaveric [inaudible],
which are damaging their Gina toxic
agents that damaged the DNA inside your
colon cells. And so, um,
people that are typically eating
like a omnivore type of buyer,
whether eating protein and they're
also eating fermentable fiber.
If they're eating the fermentable fiber
that's facilitating the growth of lactic
acid producing bacteria, it, that
limits the growth of putrifactive B.
So if you're, if you're, you know,
bifidobacteria, lactobacillus,
s mutans as Thermophilus,
those strains of bacteria,
the lactic acid producing bacteria, which
you'd be getting if you're, I mean, you,
you'd be facilitating the growth of if
you're eating plants fermentable with
fermentable fiber,
you're going to limit the growth of
putrifactive because they can't grow with
lactic acid because it's not like,
you know, you have, it's not a huge,
huge concern. But the question is,
what happens when you're only eating?
I mean, I'll ask him, you're only
getting amino acids, you know,
so is there a long term?
So if you're, if you're,
if you're killing off
potentially some of this, um,
pathogenic bacteria and you're having
this effect where a positive effect,
what's going to happen long term, it's
not known. I mean, this died. I mean,
it hasn't really been
studied at that level. I've
been a few people that have, have
anecdotal stories about doing it for 10,
20 years that are online, but it's very
difficult to track. You know, I mean,
it's, it's that you have to
take them at their word for it.
They've eaten nothing but meat
for 20 years. They feel amazing.
But there's not very many of them.
There's a, yeah, there's a, well,
there may be more out there,
but it's in terms of like what
I've come across articles,
uh, you know, uh, just, uh,
social media profiles, people talked
about the positive benefits of it.
It seems to me that people that are
talking about the positive benefits are
talking about it within a one
and two year window. That's,
that's what we're really dealing
with a lot of. Um, Sean Baker,
Dr. Sean Baker who is probably the leading
proponent of it or one of the poster
boys of it along with Jordan Peterson
and his daughter Mckayla. Uh,
Jordan Peterson has daughter Mikayla.
They're different in that they were
dealing with severe autoimmune issues. Uh,
his daughters had two joints
replaced but before she was 18,
she had her,
well she had her ankle replaced before
she was 18 and I think she had her hip
replaced shortly after that.
And um,
Jordan has had some pretty
severe autoimmune issues
and depression within both,
both of them.
Those things were cleared up.
But as you've talked about
multiple times before on this show,
depression has been linked to
disorders in the gut biome. Right.
And this is something that you feel like
may be contributing to this as long as,
as well as both of them also got very
lean. Jordan lost a ton of weight.
He's back to the weight that he
was when he was 25 years old.
And I've eaten with him and the guy eats,
he eats a lot,
but it's a lot of meat just like he'll
eat like a 30 ounce steak, you know,
which is just crazy. It's a
crazy amount of meat. But um,
I don't know how many times he's
doing that a day. I don't know.
Yeah. Yeah. I think I, you know,
going back to the, the point,
it's like there are other,
in understanding the mechanism is
important and there's a lot of potential
confounding factors,
right?
And that with any anecdotal data is
extremely important to consider. I mean,
people can't even neutrino scientists,
nutritionists and just people can't even
agree on the best diet because a lot of
these epidemiological and observational
studies, which don't establish causation,
have an enormous amount of confounding
factors. And it is freaking,
it's so hard to like control for that.
I mean, just as a perfect example,
we've talked about this before
on the podcast, but you know,
the vegetarian versus
people that eat meat,
one of the really large
studies that was done and, and,
and doctor Valter Longo was part of that
study looked in at all cause mortality
and cancer mortality.
And it was lower in vegetarians,
but they decided to take
the mediators and say, okay,
what about within this group?
The people that are healthy meat eaters
are people that are, you know, not,
you know, not unhealthy. So they're
not obese, they're not sedentary,
they're not smoking and
alcohol, not excessively
drinking alcohol. Those people,
when they took out that
those confounding factors,
the mediators had the same mortality
as the vegetarian. Yeah. Same Cancer.
So confounding factors are so important
and that with anything with anecdotal,
you have people that are
exercising like crazy.
Exercise has also been shown to change
microbiome, independent of diet, um,
in a positive way where you're actually
producing more of the bacteria that are
producing things like lactic acid.
So, and fasting does the same thing.
And so you have people that
are fasting. So, you know,
it's not like you can't do other things
if you're on that type of bed to,
to sort of help with the
microbiome. But I think, again,
if there's a way you can do,
you know,
if there's a way that you can get these
benefits without having to do something
so hyper restrictive and we'll talk
about, I mean, I have concerns for that.
We can definitely get into that. But,
um, then you know, why not try that.
And you know, the thing with like, for
example, doing like a prolonged fast,
you know, once, once a quarter,
once every couple of months,
depending on how severe your
your issues are. I mean, there's,
there's been benefits shown with
that. Like an aging, like, you know,
so people that have been put
on this fasting mimicking diet,
they have improved biomarkers of aging.
They increase their lean muscle mass.
I mean, so like I said, an animal studies,
and you can't directly translate the
animal studies to humans because rodents
have a really fast metabolism and
if you fast them for 48 hours,
they lose 20% of their body weight. Where
humans only lose like one or 2%. I mean,
that's like clearly, you
know? Yeah. So, yeah,
so you can't,
I mean,
it's obviously you can't completely
translate everything that's done in a
fascinating road to humans,
but there are definitely
organs are shrinking and then
literally regrowing after
the fast is over. Like it's like
this rejuvenation process, you know,
and it seems as though selectively damage
cells are killed. In fact, this whole,
like there, there's a whole, um,
doctor Valter Longo showing, um,
that cancer cells are really,
really susceptible to dying when they're,
when you do like a, a prolonged fast or
even a fasting mimicking diet. And he's,
he's,
he's shown this in animal studies and you
send a couple of clinical studies, uh,
were, were patients with cancer
were treated with standard of care,
but before their standard care treatment,
they were fascinated for up to
72 hours. And what happens, um,
what he's shown in animal studies happens
is that because the fasting is a type
of stress, all your healthy cells increase
all these stress response pathways.
They make more heat shock proteins.
They're increasing antioxidant
production pathways. Antiinflammatory,
they're doing all this really good stuff
in response. Cancer cells can't do that.
They're like screwed up.
And so they can't activate
those stress response pathways.
So it ends up killing them.
So what you end up happening,
happening happening is that when you're
giving another genotoxic stress like
chemo or radiation,
your healthy cells become more
resistant to the damaging effects of the
radiation and the cancer cells
become more sensitized to the death.
And so what he's shown in his pilot
studies in humans is that basically, um,
the humans that were true, that were, uh,
that were treated with
the standard of care,
I think it was chemo and also fasted,
they had less neutropenia,
which is the loss of like neutrophils,
which is the side effect because
you're losing normal healthy cells.
They had less of that happening, uh,
less myelosuppression. Um, so I mean,
anyways,
the point is that I think if you can
find a way to get positive benefits,
you know,
without having to do something so risky
and potentially dangerous and unstudied
um, you know, I mean unstudied
in a really scientific way,
you know, controlling for compounding
factors. And all sorts of longterm,
I mean just all of that,
it's really important.
Well then just comprehensive breakdown
that you just did is something that's
really lacking from a lot of
discussion of this carnivore diet.
And from the proponents of it,
it's almost like a lot of them are going
into it blind folded. They'll like, look,
uh, it seems to be working, so I'm
just going to stick with it. But
again, when you're talking
about most people's cases,
you're talking about one year, maybe
two years, sometimes even less,
where they're having these benefits.
And as you're saying,
it's entirely possible that they're
setting themselves up for some potential
longterm damage.
It is. Um, it is, it's
definitely possible. And
again, at the end of the day,
there's no data, there's no data. So you
can say for sure. Right, right, right.
There's no data,
but I have concerns and we can talk
about those concerns for sure. I like to,
but you know, the thing is
understanding mechanism, like you said,
going in blindly. I mean, you have
a hypothesis and it's like, okay,
your hypothesis is all plants are bad.
Yeah,
that's what I keep hearing and it's
like, wow, that's a hypothesis,
but what about all the other things that
are potentially happening while you're
doing this diet and you're fasting more,
your microbiomes changing,
like dramatically changing and
those things all have been known.
Multiple studies have shown in humans
and animals mechanistic detail to have
benefits on autoimmunity, on aging
in general, on brain function.
I mean all sorts of things, you know,
so it's mechanism is so important.
You have to realize that that's
the whole basis of science.
Understanding how the world works around
you, understanding how your body works,
mechanisms like, right. You
have hypothesis and it's very,
and I understand it's like someone
experiences something positive. It's like,
well this must be, this is it.
This is the end all be all.
But you have to realize
the shits complicated.
You got to understand the mechanism.
You may be doing something
long term that potentially,
I mean it really hasn't
been studied. Yes. Yeah.
Well, that was one of the, I mean
I had Jordan's daughter Mikayla on,
who's had some pretty dramatic
results from this carnivore diet,
but she's giving essentially
nutrition consulting to people,
but she doesn't really have a
background in it and she's in,
she doesn't have the information
that you just distributed,
like what you just said to all these
people listening and that the way you're
describing the,
the mechanisms and the benefits of
fasting and all these different various
things that are happening inside your
gut and all these different things that
are happening with healthy
cells and damaged cells with
fasting and that this is
mimicked by this restrictive diet.
And then this is all absent
from the dialogue. This is
all absent from the dust.
And this is one of the things is
disturbing the most disturbing for me.
It's like I get that they're seeing
positive results. I get, I don't know.
I know I can, I deny that they're
receiving, but when they start saying,
uh, you know, plants are bad and there's
a, you know, like my friend Chris,
he's always talking about the
war on carbs. He's having us.
He's also got Chris Bell,
he's got autoimmune issues as well.
He's had both of his hips replaced
before he was 35 and you know,
severe arthritis.
And he is leaner than he's ever been and
benefiting greatly from this carnivore
diet. But you know, he's, he's like,
he talks about it like he uses
Hashtag war on carbs, you know,
and he doesn't eat salad, he won't
eat greens. Greens are bad for you.
And I'm like, man, I don't
not sure that's correct.
I think it's so important what
you're saying. And um, there's a, uh,
a researcher online that
I've been in contact with.
[inaudible] name's Kevin Bass and his,
uh,
at bass or bass B a s s not sure which,
how do you pronounce it?
But he also brought up this possibility
that it could be a calorie restriction
that these people are dealing with.
And that is essentially some of
the same mechanisms that are the,
the positive reactions from fascinating
that you're, you're dealing with here.
And I'm very happy that
you're saying the same thing.
Yeah, I think that is one very strong
possibility. And that is something,
you know, there's lots of
hypotheses here and you know,
given all the data and there's lots of
positive data about eating plants as well,
you know, so it's, it's really hard.
That's one hypothesis and that seems
to be the one everyone's sort of
gravitating to. Hmm. Um, you know, if,
if someone is also wanting to reduce
their, their glycemic load and all that,
I mean there's, there are other, I mean,
eating just a modified Paleo Diet. I mean,
I eat something like a modified Paleo
Diet where it's like I'm eating,
I'm eating fish,
I meat meat,
poultry and then a lot of leafy
Greens and cruciferous vegetables.
Now you can do something nuts, you know,
or you can do a ketogenic diet and like,
they're, like, I just
talked about the study, um,
that was done looking at the fasting
mimicking diet and humans with multiple
sclerosis sclerosis. Um, there was,
uh, the same in publishing the same um,
paper.
There was a study they studied that
put patients on Ketogenic Diet for,
I believe it was three months and it
improves symptoms of autoimmunity as well.
Was it comparable? Yeah, yeah.
Improvements. Yeah. Yeah. Interesting. So,
you know, the ketogenic diet or modified
ketogenic diet is also, you know,
there's also concerns with that. Not
everyone responds very well and you know,
the micronutrient deficiencies
have been a concern,
but you can actually eat a lot of,
um, vegetable vegetables, the green,
a good ones that are, that are low in
glycemic. So spinning my concern exactly.
My concerns are much, much less. Yeah. Um,
and there's, it's been studied a lot more.
I mean,
at least there's been lifespans studies
in animals on cogenic diet where it's
like improving, you
know, the way they age,
it's improving their cognitive function,
brain aging, extending their lifespan. So,
you know, if people are looking
for, in addition to, you know,
wanting to help with their autoimmunity
issues, you know, there's also,
if it's like, well, I also just don't
want to have a lot of insulin response.
I want to lower my glycaemic
levels and things like that. Um,
it seems like a much better option than,
than doing something completely unstudied.
And so,
um, you know, I think that's
a really good place to start.
And obviously not disregarding
everyone's anecdotes.
And of course she's also the placebo and
no seatbelt effect, which are very real.
I mean,
extremely real.
It's why a lot of drugs don't ever make
it to market is because they can't beat
placebo.
You know,
where it's like people think they're
going to get a positive response from
something they can.
And the opposite is true.
People think they're going to get a
negative response for something they can.