Yeah. Uh, [inaudible] Belfort's now go
into one fc and uh, looked good again,
looking sexy corn all filled out.
Did you see Eddie Alvarez is I, yeah,
he got fucked up. Yeah. That
dude he fought Timofey um,
now stoking Nastia Liukin I think is
his last name. But the guy's a beast.
That one FC show was legit.
Yeah. Have you watched it?
I've watched just highlights.
I uh, I don't have time.
I don't tell him to watch all
the UFC fights this time. Um,
so it's hard to kind of,
to watch the other cards as well,
but once in a while watching Beltour
I'll watch one FC. Damn. Look at that. I,
oh my God. His eyes fucked up. Oh my God.
That's terrible. That's
a terrible injury. Yeah.
That looks like it's split his eye
lid. It did. Oh my God. Jesus Christ.
It's split his fucking eyelid,
dude. Oh my God. People,
people don't realize like
that side of it, like, I mean,
that's fucking touch your face. I mean,
you had a little bit of an MMA fight.
You know what it's like, not
really. You did, it was a fight.
Is a fight against another comedian
comedian up. Very impressive. But Hey,
it was, he had taekwondo black
belt from when he was 14 years old.
Take that back to taekwondo black belt.
No,
I seen people forget how to do shit,
man, if you'll all bullshit aside.
But they also gave out a lot of taekwondo
black belts that are 100% portraits.
It's part of the business.
Even if they're not,
if you're not giving your belts out,
how are you not going to
get people to come back.