The Joe Rogan experience is,
is the end.
The way things operate
is not something that's far from optimal.
It's something,
it's not something that
sucks but it is very,
is very good,
very optimal heart to beat in the
sense that the like for example,
mortality,
right eye is death important for creation,
for, for his death. Important
for us. Human beings for life,
for us as a society is important for us
to die. Like if you could live forever,
would you live forever?
I think miss out on the possibility
that there is something,
well I had this conversation with CT
Fletcher yesterday cause you know he
survived the heart transplant a year ago.
You're in two days ago. I think it's,
what do you think?
I think I think mortality
is essential for everything.
So I think the end, we need
the end to be there. Right.
But do you think that we need the end to
be there for the overall health of the
human race or the or the all the organisms
on earth or do you think we needed to
be there because there's something else?
Do you think there's something else
that happens to you when your body stops
existing? Do you think your consciousness
transcends this, this dimension?
I think,
uh,
I think I'm not smart enough
to even think about that.
That's a great answer.
So I think everybody on earth has that
exact same answer if they're being honest.
So you're talking about atheism and so on.
I used to think atheism
means what I just said. So,
but it's more we know so little.
Uh,
so the, the only thing I know is
that the finiteness of life is, uh,
the Broadway, just a school that train,
that has this poster at the, at the,
at the opening, which is a hunter
s Thompson quote, which is, um,
uh, for about skidding into death
sideways. No one's a good one.
Uh, no for all moments of beauty.
Many souls must be trampled,
something like that. That's a fucking
great quote. God, I love that guy. Yeah.
So basically for beauty,
you have to have suffering.
I do not disagree with you. I do not
disagree with any of the things you said.
And I think there's always a possibility
that human beings are the most advanced
life form that's ever existed in
the cosmos. There's always that.
That has to be an option if we are here,
right?
If we can't see any others out there,
and even though you know there's the
Fermi paradox and there's all this
contemplation that if they do exist,
like maybe they can't physically get
to us or maybe they're on a similar
timeline to us and they're also,
it's also possible as as it might sound,
that this is as good as it's ever gotten
anywhere in the world or anywhere in
the universe,
rather that human beings right now in
2019 or as good as the whole universe has
ever produced,
we're just some freak luck accident and
everybody else is throwing shit at each
other,
right?
There's 15 arm caterpillar people that
live on some other fucking planet.
They just tossed her own shit at
each other and they never get any,
they never get any work done.
But we might be that.
But even if that's true,
even if this beauty that we perceive,
even if that,
that this beauty requires
evil to battle and requires,
are seemingly insurmountable
obstacles you have to overcome.
And that through this you see,
achieve great beauty.
That beauty is in the eye of the
beholder. For sure. Objectively,
the universe doesn't give
a fuck if rocky pizza,
Apollo creed in the second movie,
it doesn't give a fuck.
It's nonsense to
everything's nonsense too.
And when you look at the giant
ass picture of what beauty is,
if the sun's going to burn out in 5
billion years, what beauty is that?
If there could be a hyper Nova
next door that just cooks us. Ugh.
So that's like the book sapiens.
Uh, yeah. That basically,
we've all,
one of the things we've created here is
we've imagined ideas that we all share
ideas of beauty, ideas of
truth, ideas of fairness.
We've all created together. And it
doesn't exist outside of us as a society.
And no, it only exists to us.
Yeah. To us it does exist.
And this is where I think the
beauty of being a person truly lies.
It lies in us,
our appreciation of us.
We appreciate people in a profound way.
Like we were talking about Hendrix,
I probably,
I don't know how many hours of Hendricks
I've ever listened to or Richard Pryor,
how many hours of Richard Pryor I watched
and how much that affected me as a kid
watching live in the sunset strip. That's
what got me to do in stand up comedy.
We affect each other.
A Ct Fletcher who was on the podcast
yesterday who's just incredibly
inspirational guy,
you watch his videos,
you want to lift the fucking
world and throw it into
space, you know? I mean he's,
he's so powerful.
We appreciate each other.
We appreciate people. So all those
things you're saying are real.
Like for us, they're real. For us,
my concern is not that my
concern is that we are outdated.
My concern is not that there's not
beauty in what we are. I'm a, I'm a,
I am big appreciator of this life.
I appreciate human beings in this life
and human beings. Their contributions as,
as a and as I get older, like
particularly like over the last few years.
I just started doing a lot
of international travel.
I fucking appreciate the shit of all
these people that are living in this
different way with weird and shit and
weird smell and foods and I like to think
like what would it be
like if I grew up here?
Like these are just people but they're
in this weird sort of mode. You know?
I think we're insanely lucky that we have
this enthusiasm for each other that we
have this into like for your work man,
I have this deep enthusiasm for
what you do. I'm fascinated by it.
I love being able to talk to you and pick
your mind about like you're out there
coding these fucking vehicles
that are driving themselves,
artificial life on wheels.
I don't think any other animal
appreciates each other the way people do.
I mean I might be wrong.
People do, right? Yeah.
I might be wrong about dolphins and whales
mean maybe they love each other just
as much as we do just in a different way.
But what,
where does AI fit into that?
So your worry,
I'm worried that we are Australia peer
thickest and AI is going to come along
and make us look stupid.
The only reason why I was trying to
pick Australia pithy would be cool.
Today's we found a gang of, I'm on an
island somewhere. We were like, Holy Shit.
They survived.
They never evolved.
They're on this island just cracking
coconuts and just eating fish,
whatever they can catch,
that would be amazing.
But everyone documented or undisclosed
discovered uncontacted tribe,
they're all homo sapiens, all
of them. So it's like, you know.