The Joe Rogan experience.
Remember going to watch,
I remember watching fights on Hbo.
I just remember that,
that let HBO boxing being
such like a emblematic thing
for, you know what I mean?
Like it's so recognizable.
So like pay per view, Hbo,
so them get out of the game is so strange.
It's kind of like the
revolution that's happening now.
The last fight I went to with you at
UFC, now their ESPN, what does it plus?
ESPN plus. That's what it
is. Private paid service.
It's a subscription service.
Right. Look on Netflix for sports,
but it's not just UFC fights.
It's a bunch of other stuff. Wow.
All kinds of shit stuff. They just
won't show on ESPN at all though. No,
they sometimes show you mean
it's ESPN content? I guess.
So you could watch some fights that
were on ESPN plus later they'll probably
show them on the ESPN. Sort of like the
same thing with Hbo pay per view. Yeah.
You know, but, um, I think
what HBO did with Paper View,
it was brilliant where you
would have the paper view,
but then let people watch it for free.
A week later you're just
going to make more fans. Yeah.
It's like you're not going to
lose money on the paper view.
I'm just going to make more fans.
Well that's the whole idea of like a,
that's why this, this, this
is funny. I was going to talk
to you about this anyway,
I just moved and I cancelled my
directv. I'm done. I canceled them.
I cut the wire and I'm just doing
like a Hulu live TV, Internet shit.
All the years of hearing people being
like cutting the court caught in the car
and I'm like, I don't know man.
I like it now. Fuck it. I love,
I love what I'm doing now.
And I gotta Tell Ya,
I can get all the shit that I want
for cheaper than I had it before.
And it's just way more convenient now.
I used to be so tethered to being like,
I'll never give up cable now. I'm like,
fuck it. I don't want it anymore. I don't,
I don't want it.
This has been the best version.
I'll always have a blockbuster
card. Oh yeah. It'll never go away.
It'll never Hollywood
video, dude, I want to rent.
If you put all your money in that he
like I'm telling you in 20 years this is
going to amount to $15 million.
I got fucking plan.
Do you think people invested in Netflix
when it was the DVD subscription service
and that, you know what I mean, like early
on and now they're still getting the,
the revenue dividends of what Netflix
is now. I wonder about that. Oh yeah.
I'm sure you do.
Like that's gotta be the best money
cause it was worth nothing back then.
It was just another subscription
video service and they had,
there was a ton of them.
I mean red box.
I did my first Netflix special in
2005 Oh my God, there's one left.
Oh, I think I've seen this.
Yeah, there you go. Yes. In
Oregon, Oregon, bend, Oregon.
That's so weird to last.
Blockbuster.
They went from 4,855 stores in 2008 to
one store in 2018 that is the craziest
demolition of a business I've ever heard.
I wouldn't have ever heard of what other
business in our lifetimes vanish like
that. Like A, like I've
come like a storefront.
I can't think of something that that
went away that quickly. Industry gone.
It was just, it was a part
of our huge weekend. Yeah.
You go to plot buster. Huge.
What do they got right? You anything
about this? He'd look the cover.
I don't know that. I never even
heard of this one. Ever saw it.
Maybe it's good watching like obscure
Dolph Lundgren movies that were made in
Italy. Yeah, you would. You'd get to
pick out shit that you're like, ah,
this looks Kinda dope. We'll see.
Back then the gamble was fun.
The name meant a lot.
Yeah.
Like it was like this guy from dances with
wolves. Oh, okay. I remember that guy.
I can that. Cool. You'll take
a chance. Yeah, you will.
But I think that's happening
again now with Netflix.
I'll take a chance with shit now that
I've never heard of because Netflix,
you pop up all these different
titles and you'll go, hmm,
I'll try this fucking shit. I just
started a new show I just tried to show,
okay.