Yeah,
I mean,
I guess that's like what it must be to
just be in the Amazon itself as well.
Right.
And you're sharing the jungle,
not just the rivers and the
lakes or whatever's out there,
but the actual jungle itself, it's,
it was incredible. The jungle there.
So we were in Columbia and Amazon and
like talk about untouched by people.
There has been this kind of ongoing
going conflict in Columbia for many,
many years. So we were the first
westerners to go there and over 60 years.
So the village we flew into, they
literally never seen white people before.
And then we went 200 kilometers from that.
So like middle of nowhere they
want to touch you tell yeah,
hair because their hair was very
dark and very different and like,
I'm not particularly fair,
but just to touch like the hair
and see the blue eyes and stuff.
They were just a lot of friendly,
super friendly.
Like the culture was very stoic. Like
there wasn't a lot of smiling or crying,
you know, there wasn't like
a lot of emotional exchange,
but straight away they came and greeted
us like shook hands, you know, said hello.
Um, it was really cool. Wow.
That's gotta be, you know,
how do you set something like that up?
Do you have like a liaison that
does like acts as a go between,
between you and the tribes? Um, yeah,
so we did in this case have one guy who
communicated, I speak Spanish, Spanglish,
I guess. Um, and they all speak
Spanish from back in the day.
So we set it all up. It's part of
the wildlife stuff that I do. We,
we literally flew a DC three,
a World War II cargo plane into this
cocaine dealers airstrip. And then God,
that's how we got there. I mean like
mind blowing stuff, cocaine dealer,
a former former former, yeah. Well,
you know, too CBD, it's still Columbia.
Right? Exactly. Um, so yeah, I was, that
one was really cool. It really remote.
How crazy is that?
They learned Spanish from people who
came over on boats from Spain and it just
stuck. Isn't that nuts and took
over the whole like regions. Yeah.
The whole world and,
and series this tribe in the middle of
the Amazon that has this language from
another continent and Brazil,
right from Portugal. Right.
It's really incredible when you stop
and think about it. I mean it's,
it's incredible, but it's also
part of, it's a little sad,
like why wouldn't you have loved to have
heard what their original language was?
Oh, I was literally what it
sounded like. Well, they did.
So it's funny because when they didn't
want us to understand what they were
talking about, they would switch
to their native Indian language.
So they still had,
they were bilingual,
a community of 25 people that have
never left, and they're bilingual. Wow.
It's amazing. Now their native
language is what, what does it,
it's an Amazonian Indian dialect.
I, I honestly don't even,
they might have said the name,
but I don't recall it.
What is the name of their tribe?
Uh, also not even sure they're,
they're so isolated. They're unaware
of what country they live in.
They don't even know that
they are in Columbia. Really,
really, they're just like,
to them, they're Amazonian, they're not
Colombian. Ecuadorian Brazilian there.
They're Amazonian, whoa. Yeah.
You know, they just stay,
they stay.
And the village we were in is literally,
I think it's all over 200 kilometers
from the next next village of 15 or so
people and they don't have fuel. They
don't have, you know, they'd just
in this pocket and they just
substance live and they're
all barefoot, right? Yeah.
Do they have those crazy splayed out
feet? Big Feet? You know, they're,
they're not very big people.
They're like small Indian people,
but really big kind of useful
feet and the way that, you know,
they could run up and down trees and
climb stuff. I mean it was unbelievable.
Like so much more athletic than you
could imagine. What imagine right there.
They've been doing that their whole life,
their whole lives.
Now when like when I say splayed out feet
when I'm talking about is that people
that walk barefoot in the jungle for long
periods of time with their whole life,
their toes spread out and their feet
almost looked like a hand. Oh, no way.
I did not pay enough attention.
That might've been the case,
but I didn't know this at their feet.
Exactly. Yeah. It's kind of weird thing.
Stare at Dude's feet. Yeah, for
sure. But um, yeah, Steve Rinella,
who's a good friend of
mine told me about that.
He was in Guyana and is the same thing
and they actually got some pictures and
videos of these people's feet. But look
at these guys up there. Hello? Oh No,
I didn't notice anything like that.
Yeah, this is the, uh, that's uh, oh.
How do you say that? Horror. Not Horani.
Horani Horani sounds right.
Or Ani,
you think where Ani Horani Indian
splayed feet. So it's very strange.
Like it's the kind of the opposite of
what happens to women when they jam their
feet into those little pointy
shoes, whether they get the, the,
the toes kind of smoosh onto each
of the La fee. Yeah. It's horrible.
Instead of that,
they're all like crazy spread out.
What in the fuck is going
on there? Because I talked
to his hands, I think would,
yeah, the tops hands. But the bottom
is like would feet, but that's,
that's gotta be like what?
Our feet are supposed to be
probably right, right. Yeah.
Fic Ass toes that actually have muscles
in them that move that you can use like
a tool like your hand.
Yeah.
So when these guys just can climb up
trees with them so they grip the side of
the tree with their feet like a
hand. Oh, I mean I didn't notice,
like I say the feet just like that
specifically, but the way they could,
like everything's covered in mud
down there. Right. It's all wet.
It rains every day. And they could
run up and down these tree trunks,
like to get up and down the village.
And here's me and my crew with our
awkward cameras and stuff and where it's
slipping and sliding and falling over
and like they're, they're literally like,
what's wrong with these people?
Why can't they walk?
We must have looked like infants to that.
Right.
And you guys probably have like boots
on and Shit fucked up and oh totally.
Yeah. We're wearing, you know, muck
boots and my one buddies got waiters on.
And you know,
we think we're all hard and cool because
we got all this gear and they're just
like running around in shorts barefoot.
It is so fascinating when you see
people that don't have contact with the
outside world. Like, um,
I'm sure you're aware of that recent
story of the missionary was killed by the
people in north central island.
Absolutely.
Which is one of the weirdest places
cause they've branched off from Africa at
60,000 years ago or something like that.
Right. When you're around these people,
like what,
what do they do if they get injured?
So funny you asked that because we,
we kind had that same
question. Right. And they don't
leave. They stay in the village.
They have a shaman at the village who
blessed us with a crazy green powder and
that's a whole nother story. But they
have a showman and he is their doctor.
However,
he has no access to any Western medicine.
So it's only his learning knowledge handed
down through generations plus jungle
powders and whatnot. And um,
and that's it. So we actually,
we spend today because we had a medic
with us doing like kind of village help if
you will. Everybody had ringworm,
everybody had respiratory infections. Uh,
there were a lot of lady problems in the
village that our medic had to deal with.
I mean there was a lot of health
issues and you don't even realize it.
Write something down before I forget.
I'm sore as totally unrelated. No good.
There's a doctor named Peter Hotez that's
coming on the podcast and I have to
follow up on him. He, when you start
talking about the people in the jungle,
he was, he's a actual, a doctor who is a,
he specializes in infectious diseases
and jungle and tropical climates and he's
like, everyone's infected with
something. Everyone, everyone,
he'd have a heyday down there. I'm sure
it's probably been, yeah. But um, the,
so when these people have ringworm
and all these different infections,
do they treat it? Do they have like
some natural pathic cure or some shit?
I think it's kind of a 50,
50,
like a lot of it they don't treat
because it's just part of everyday life.
Like when I say everybody had ringworm,
I meant everybody had it.
So I don't think there was
any kind of treatment or cure.
It was just kind of part of
it, part of them, but other
things, you know, the, the,
the witch doctor or the Shaman was trying
to treat and then we kind of went in
and we had like medication for ringworm,
so we'd dewormed everybody and with the
Shamans blessing and he was like super
excited to have western medicine
in the village. And what'd you use?
Like Lamisil or something like that? I
couldn't tell you. Um, I think it was not,
it wasn't topical.
I think it was like a Wehrmacht like
a pill that you take that kills the,
kills the worms.
The weird thing about that is like,
don't you, you leave and then
they're going to get it again. Right?
I mean there's only so much you
can do, right? Yeah, totally.
That we were having the same
dilemma and it was like,
do we interfere because we're from the
outside world? Do we help? And, uh,
we talked to the sham and through our
translator and he said, please help,
please help. So we gave, including him,
everybody just dewormer but you know,
they'll just come back.
Yeah.
And also they probably don't understand
the consequences of taking some
antibiotic that's going to do some weird
shit to your whole biome. Right, right,
right. And these are all that stuff
too. It's such a moral dilemma.
You're there and you're like,
I want to help. Do I, is it
helpful? Is it hindering?
Our medic was like, it's undeniably
going to help, you know, they need this.
And so we got, we went for it and
it was, you know, it seemed to help,
everybody felt fine, but we
were only there a couple of
more days before we left.
So who knows? Wow. When
you're talking about ringworm,
like these guys covered in it, they have
big patches of it. Like what's it like?
Feet and legs had big
patches of it. Yeah. Yeah.
And this, if you don't know that's the
same shit that's athlete's foot. Oh,
I didn't know that. A ringworm and
athlete's foot of the same kind of funk.
Oh yeah. That's why, uh, they people
tell you to pee on your feet. Oh,
I thought that was just for fun cause
it depends on what you're in. But uh,
I think that's a, the idea
behind it is that you're, um,
somehow or another you're killing
the bad bacteria. You, uh,
you're pissing on your feet
and you have athletes, what,
that might be horseshit maybe. Yeah.
With me, you always have to check.
Um, yeah, definitely give
that a little see. But, um,
it's a real common thing with Jujitsu.
Gotcha. So guys, all the maths,
that's real common.
So just it guys get it and there's people
really fuck up or they like put bleach
on it and a bunch of different things
to try to kill it and winds up getting
worse. And also it fucks up all
the natural skin flora, jock, itch,
athlete's foot and ringworm or all
types of fungal skin infections known
collectively as Tinea, Tinea, tinea.
They're caused by fungi called Derma
trow fights that live on the skin,
hair and nails and thrive in
warm, moist areas. The jungle.
So it seems like they're
just going to get it
it. That's just what it sounds like,
you know? But what do they do for it?
I didn't see them treating that at all
and when we pointed it out they're like,
yeah, yeah, we know about it. You know,
they were more concerned with
things that were like dire,
like there was an infant and maybe not
even maybe three years old and he was
hacking up a lung and he was
asthmatic according to our medic.
So my, our medic gave them like an asthma
medication and he just said, you know,
if he has an attack where you kind of
breathe, give him this and like you know,
to be super real with you.
When we walked away our medic was like,
I doubt he'll live to see adulthood.
Oh Man. Yeah. And will you given
them inhalers? Did you give him,
I'm not sure to be honest.
What it was that he left with him.
And what about like injuries? What if
they break a leg or something like that?
What do they do? I don't
think anything was any,
I mean you got to think these
people are climate trees
constantly fall, get bitten by stuff.
There's tons of venomous snakes out there.
It's wet, it's muddy, it's slippery.
They're building stuff out of very
rudimentary tools. I mean it's, it's nuts.
They have to get injured.
It's so interesting that we have this
understanding of medicine and doctors and
hospitals,
but that's probably pretty fucking recent.
Oh, of course. Yeah. I'll,
I'll tell you a story. Joe.
I was in a Myin Mar early,
late last year and we're down there
filming this thing and this kid,
like 22 year old crab fisherman
gets bitten by a crocodile crop,
grabs him by the arm,
grabs him by the thigh death roles so
it breaks the arm and like, I dunno,
15 places, compound fracture, the real
deal. I could show you pictures out,
it'll blow your mind and we hear about
this and we're minutes away. We just,
it's kind of one of the similar situations
where the first westerners to be
there in a long time.
We go bombing over at high speed and
we get there and the mom is like off
mourning the death of her child, but
her child is sitting there still alive,
like they have thrown
him off and it's mom.
His mom is literally mourning
the death of her child and he's,
he's lying there conscious.
But like in total shock,
fortunately just because of the situation
we had a speedboat, everything else,
we bandaged him up. You know, ted tried
to keep his arm stable and his leg stable,
put them in our speedboat and it was
six hours by speedboat to a village that
had a or two to a hospital really. And
so he got there and his life was saved.
But I asked, we asked the people in the
village what were were you going to do?
And they're like, there's
nothing we can do. Wow.
So he was just going to bleed out or
go septic. And that was the end of it.
Ooh. What a fucking
rough way to go. Right.
How did he get away from the crocodile?
Uh, I don't know. I think he was
just hitting it or hammering on it.
He was crab fishing in the water
and it came up and grabbed him,
rolled a few times and at some point he
escaped how we even got back in the boat
and made it back to the village. I have
no idea because his leg was shattered,
his arm was shattered. It was
brutal. And it was a canoe, you know,
it wasn't like he had a little motor
or a wheel to drive canoed back.
One of the most disturbing
stories I ever read was, um,
these guys were kayaking in an African
river and the guy in front of them got
grabbed by a crocodile and that
it went under and the like,
it like plunge like a bobber as the
crocodile pulled him out of the bottom of
the Kayak. Yeah. I'm
like, fuck, that's awful.
Imagine being the guy
behind him and washing them.
Yeah. And knowing that
you're pretty much helpless.
Did you see any jaguars or anything?
Uh, I've never seen a Jaguar.
I've seen a lot of la. I'm from Africa.
I don't know if you knew that, but,
so I've seen a lot of lions growing
up. My family did safaris. Um,
and then I've seen, you know, mountain
lions here in California, leopards,
stuff like that. I've never seen
a wild Jaguar. Really? Yeah.
When you were in the Amazon,
I think they're really elusive.
I know there's areas
that are our hotspots.
All of the locals were very nervous and
kind of knew about them. Like, you know,
I went out for Bush walks at
night and stuff and I'd just go,
me and one guy with a camera and
a, they were like, oh, be careful.
Like pedigree also in a very
dangerous, don't do it. Um,
but Predator Grosso means very dangerous
belly grow, so like danger. Yeah.
And I'm so we just go and,
you know,
I'm not trying to act like we were
tougher than them or anything.
We would love to have seen one,
but they were very aware of them.
So they were there. We just didn't
happen to run into one sort of
mountain lions. Exactly. Yeah. Like
they say that mountain lines are like,
if you live in a place that has them,
you know,
Wyoming or Colorado or
something like that, they know
where you are. Right, right.
They might be around you all the time
and you might rarely see them. Exactly.
Be Driving home and see one
skittering into the, into the,
gosh, there was a nuts video, I
think it was from the La area.
Did you ever see it where the security
cams picked up this mountain lion that
was walking through this
like very residential
neighborhood and you'd see like
people would walk by and then 30 seconds
later he'd like dip out of the shadows
and then dip back in and then the next
set of people would walk by and nobody
had any clue he was
there. Yeah. It's crazy.
Was a giant Predator can move around like
that. Right? Yeah. So when you're there,
what,
what would you have done if someone got
bit by a venomous snake or a spider or
something like that?
Did you guys have any antivenom?
Were you prepared for something like
that? I mean, that's my department, right?
Like, as the wildlife guy
that's, that's Kinda my,
my department is make
sure nobody gets bitten,
make sure nothing like that happens.
And we handled very,
very many venomous snakes and caught
anacondas and all kinds of great stuff.
We did have like my main camera,
Guy's name's Mitch,
he got absolutely lit up by these
wasps one night and we all were,
we got like 12,
14 stinks each.
But I look back in the canoe at one point
and his eyes are just super swollen.
He's bright red, he's sweating. I'm
like Mitchie okay. He's like, uh,
his throat started to close up.
He was having an allergic reaction so we
had to hit him with anti histamines and
I, I'm not actually sure if the medic
administered the Epi pen or not, but uh,
he was like,
we're in the middle of the jungle.
We're six hours from a village that's
then a full day's travel by a charter
plane from a hospital. I mean
middle of fucking nowhere. And uh,
and his throat's closing up and think
that's why we take a medic with us.
Thankfully we had this emergency medic,
he administered the Anti
Histamines and Mitch was okay,
but these things do happen to ever like
while you were on these crazy adventures,
do you ever out there going,
this is the last one? No, no,
no. Whatever. No Way, man.
I love it. I live for it. Wow.