Suge knight gear May,
you know what else in my body does?
If I'm in a room and I'm supposed to
be awake, you ever get like sleepy?
Sometimes if I get sleepy,
my Dick would get hard.
It's like,
it's like my biggest look out
around the
area.
Well sometimes I'll be in writers'
rooms that I get sleepy and my and start
getting hungry.
Oh fuck.
So then I'll try to go to the
bathroom to throw board on my face.
But now I'm slightly
like a wreck getting up.
So making sure nobody's looking at me
right. Like some freak. Yeah. Yeah.
So I'm like always in there. Always
pull my shit down. But isn't that funny?
Like everybody knows you get an erection.
Everybody knows you get erection. Right.
But if they get an erection near
that, I'm like, what the fuck? I know.
I know I had a boner. Sorry. Sorry.
It's human nature, but you can't,
especially in mixed company.
Yeah, yeah. Especially today. Nah,
you can't day to day,
man.
Just think about all the sexual harassment
that people just sort of like that
was there the way they behaved.
Yeah. Yeah. The office,
that was their thing.
And now you see now you can't do that.
Why they went to the office,
like they couldn't wait to get the
work to chase whomever was there,
pinch the secretary and a blood.
Um, I mean it's, you know,
my mom had a thing like that when I
was a kid. I didn't understand it,
but somebody was, you know, she needed
the job. So what I will say to, you know,
um,
women watching what my mom did and she
just kept elaborate notes so that cause
she knew it was gonna be his
word against hers. And you know,
predators don't keep notes,
man. They don't keep note of it.
So mom was like October
8th, Duh Duh, Duh, Duh.
They, you know, she was
protected and so, wow,
just don't try to go off memory
like that. You know, if the shit,
even if you're keep notes man, still
you against them. Yeah it still is.
But back then boss, whoa, but
still once you, cause that's how,
who I think, who had somebody
else had no, the Weinstein thing.
Somebody kept like notes and
that's why I mean, cause you,
when you have a lot of money you can
definitely litigate it. Like it is.
I'm sue under the law. But
when something like, you know,
and I think his legal team looked at it,
they were like,
you better go to Europe for some deep
counseling cause deep. However they,
you know, Europe counseling,
it's a different level.
That's the leave the continent.
Right. Hey my head on straight.
I'm gonna stay over here. Yeah, I had be
able to do that. It's crazy. Well look,
if you look at like the Kevin Spacey
thing, like that's how he would run a set.
Apparently he'd be on the set and
he'd just be grabbing dicks. Yeah.
That's what they're all saying. I
mean, I don't know if that's the truth,
but all the people in
the house of cards set,
this is what all the complaints are coming
out was that he would like grab guys
dicks that we're taking them places and
he'd have like a PA that had to take him
somewhere. He reached in his pants and
grabbed his dick. He was just a dick.
Gregory grabbed,
um,
whose dick was it that he grabbed like
some famous dude, uh, Richard Dreyfus.
He grabbed his son's Dick
and with him in the room, ah,
he was just a crazy dick rubber
stop maniacs. Crazy wrong.
Dick grabbing off the reservation.
Ah,
and I think this is their social
environment as well as their working
environment, right? They're constantly
around all these people and they're,
they're in this king roll.
Yay.
If you're a star of a show that you're
the executive producer of and it's a
giant hit for Netflix and you're the king.
I'm Frank Underwood,
the king of House of cards and all
the people rely on you for their jobs.
This is one of the things they're
saying about house of cards is that 2000
people could be out of a job.
Exactly. Which is crazy. Yeah.
So this guy was like at the epicenter,
like he was the,
the king of 2000 people.
So he would show up at work and you know,
see his ego,
grab your ticket,
the king,
you know.
And I think that is like
natural male predatory behavior.
I think when a man gets into a position
where he's the king and all these people
[inaudible] maybe we
get you something sire.
Like if you're on a set and
you're like the big star,
all these people are
stumbling around sire. Maybe,
maybe we get you something sire.
Like you start thinking like a king.
Like if you're Harvey Weinstein,
like think about all the people
that cover it up for him.
He had it written in his
contract was crazy. I mean,
but also just think of that work
ethic man. Like you know what I mean?
He like to work that hard.
And then the part that trips me out is
when people would show up to the victims
ago, tell me everything we're going
to, we're going to take them down.
And then those people were investigators.
Did they go, I work for Weinstein Bitch.
Like you better not,
you know how fucked up it has to
have you walking around in the world.
But they're predators, man. And
they look for like, you know,
it's this weird shit, but
it's like if you, you know,
they had like a parent or something like,
come on baby, do you think it's safe to,
you know, meet with him at three in the
morning and they were like, mama is cool.
It's going to be fine. Trust me.
Why don't you trust me? You know?
And then when something happens,
they feel like they can't say
anything because they don't want the,
I told you so. Or they don't want to,
oh well, whatever it is. And then that,
that moment can turn into two weeks
and not saying a year, six month,
then you living, you
know what I mean? And,
and so that's how it can happen
when you're just so embarrassed,
you know what I mean?
Or you don't want to embarrass
or hurt other people at times.
Sometimes people don't say anything
because they don't want to make their
parents feel what type
of way, you know? Yeah.
There's a lot on a lot of women that
had been rape victims that the stigma of
being a rape victim,
excuse me, publicly is a,
it's so hard. It's so terrifying.
They don't even, they'll like,
I'll just let it slide. It's, and it's,
it's like man, it's horrible. It's,
I mean,
so I'm personally,
I'm happy that people are
finally speaking, you know,
coming out. Cause it's, it's,
it's a lot of jobs open and up.
I'm really happy that people are
finding that courage to just, you know,
speak that truth and hope we'll see
what happens on the other side of it.
Will we be a healthier society?
Well,
I've been saying this for a while that
I think that eventually we're going to
get to a point we could read each other's
minds. I really think that's on the,
on the horizon.
I think it's just a matter of time before
no one can ever do anything like that
ever again.
And I think that's what you're seeing
now with like this Harvey Weinstein Shit
and the Kevin Spacey Shit
and all this other stuff.
I mean you see varying degrees of it.
Some of them seem pretty innocuous.
Like Al Franken just likes to grab butts
when he takes a picture. It's like, ah,
not the best practice,
but not the worst thing in the world.
But I think we're going to get to a point
where all of this is look back on like
wearing powdered wigs or slavery or
any crazy old shit that we just don't
tolerate anymore and just nutty
behavior that you just can't do anymore.
I think we're going to get to a point
where you're going to be able to talk to
someone and you're going to be able to
see what's going on in their head and you
will, you would have to be a
real piece of shit to victimize
gross. I gotta stop. You
know what's interesting too,
I think this is a direct reaction to
us not communicating with one another.
You know what I mean?
It's a day like today,
like everything is texts like my
boys at a single day, you know,
they getting girls to texts, like,
have you talked to her yet? Now Ryan,
but she's sending me like all of this,
the number. So you're not really, yeah.
And then I think can be taken out of
context, what have you, but, but yeah,
it is getting to the place where you're
going to have to be really clear with
your intentions, like American to see
it. You can be OCD tension. Some people.
Oh Wow.
You know another thing I think that is
ridiculous and I'm not pro prostitution,
but I think it should be legal and I
think if it was legal you would have way
less of this gone. Oh yeah. Wanelo
yeah. Cause that's what it is, right?
It's just that release and people need
to craziness. It's forbidden shit.
There's a lot,
there's a lot of factors going on.
But I think one of the things that would
change is that people that want like
ugly dudes like Harvey Weinstein, it just
wants sex and he could just go get it.
But I think for him it's like a power
thing to definitely mean he was banging
all those really hot like famous chicks.
This drug dealer told me a long time ago,
it was two things.
He's talking about men. It says
two things, man. Understand
as weapon or a secret.
And if you came with they ass,
you better get a secret. So,
and that's uh,
you know,
I feel like Harvey doing that shit to a
lot of people because they became huge
stars. There's no reason for them
to ever have to respect him again.
You know what I mean? But he was like,
yeah, but you, you know what this is,
you know, take my whatever,
whatever his, well apparently he,
he wouldn't negotiate it into
deals. He would say, if you fuck me,
you'll get more lines. You'll get
parts who get this and get that.
And so it's like, I mean, but
that is like my main was like,
so what, when do you know your worth?
Right. And when you know, well,
if you, you know what I mean? I'm good.
I don't need this here
over here or I've already,
the work I've already done like my,
my last work paid for all this shit.
Where are you getting your money?
You're getting your money from
something I did. You know what I mean?
Like instead of thinking about it like,
oh you can give me more money
cause like you sitting on this,
you got this sweet from my performance.
You know what I mean? Like right.
This dude wrote you didn't do shit like
literally came up with this guy wrote it.
This guy shot it. Yeah. Yeah you ain't,
that's what's interesting. He's like,
he's not the creative guy at all. No, no.
Just the money guy that fucks the women.
Yeah. It's weird. It's weird
man. It's weird how long
you got away with it for it.
For decade after decade after
decade. It's, it's, it's crazy man.
It's almost like the floating like
every person that you look at like,
Oh man, that person doesn't know. It
shocked me the most about Matt Lauer.
That motherfucker was making $20 million
year 25 I heard it was 2,500 2028
years. 28 and they had to
pay him. They had to pay him,
pay him out after the last contract.
They said I was just reading.
They don't know if it's going to be
finished. There was 2018 contract,
but he also was getting
flown a helicopter rides too,
is like a Hamptons house so we could
spend more time with his family or
something in between dam outlet or
meetings as to what would happen.
All of them. All those cats get paid out
though. What's the Charlie Rose Gate?
When he had to step out, did he
get paid out? But he was on PBS.
It probably wasn't getting paid.
Riley got a lot of extra money. Right?
Riley paid 30 $35 million in a
sexual harassment settlement.
What the fuck could you have possibly
done? Just think about it. In fact,
they're like, okay, okay, I'll give
you 35 million. You shut the fuck up.
Like 5 million is a j Lo House. Hold
up though, Joe. This is fucked up.
But that victim should
be a motivational speaker
that motivates. Yeah. Talk to
other victims that I had to pay.
First thing I did was I limped around,
then I pretended I couldn't walk good. And
I always get nervous. I'd have to
sit down 35 I appeared vulnerable.
It worked out. Yeah. Oh, that's,
I mean that's wonder what he did.
I mean it was just one,
I mean another one,
I think he paid a 12 there was like
several different ones that he had to pay
off. Like this guy was on a rampage for
years and years. Yeah. He's a trick man.
He was on the streets. He's a trick
that pays well. He's a house money.
35,000,035 come on man.
And everybody already knows you're a
freak. So it's like you wasted 35 million.
Like everybody knows you're a freak. Yeah.
And so who do we, where do you start?
Like is it the platform who, who gave
them the platform and that guy, you know,
I think it's a bunch of things,
but one of the things that I think it
is is that that world is so sexually
charged.
All the men are like these powerful,
wealthy men and all the women are hot
as fuck and the off short skirts on and
they're all talking about like,
like American value and it's
all conservative values.
It's all super simple brass to right
behind closed doors as button popping.
And fucking
crazy snoring.
I see lips, Woo. Maca
being a PA, Chrissy. That's
what's so puritanical. Tuto man,
they don't teach,
they don't teach six education like to
younger kids is never cool to talk about
this shit. So there's definitely
that. But it's also the suppression,
the ones that are like super religious,
super suppressed.
Those are the ones that have this date.
You have a need for an outlet. Of course.
Yes. Yeah. And I feel like
it's, it's equal. Right?
So the amount that you put out,
you equally have,
you know what I mean? Like
that. Uh, who was that guy?
The senator or congressman with the
fuck it was, it just got busted like uh,
having, he was an anti gay. Oh yes.
And he turns out he was, he
got busted having sex with
a dude in his office. Yeah.
Inappropriate behavior. And
they called it, they had,
it was very convenient
and they give him the x.
Here he is anti Lgbtq lawmaker
resigns over gay sex scandal.
Republican state,
Ohio State Representative Wesley.
Oh, Wesley Wesley Goodman. He may have
also previously assaulted an 18 year old.
Hey, hey, assaulted. Is it like Kevin
Spacey type of salt? Like Dick Grabbing?
No To word assault is, oh
man. Words are violent. Hello?
Your words are violence
touch you? No, no, no.
Your words are violence.
Okay.