Some border restaurants actually
deliver across the border. Okay,
so you live across the border.
Now that won't work. We
won't deliver. That's great.
If you deliver across, the board
isn't working. If you don't deliver,
Oh don't cross the border,
you're fine.
What about if you use one of those
third party delivery services?
You know where they use an app and they
order something and the APP would be the
people who are actually doing delivery
would be responsible. You would not. Okay.
As long as that. As long as that
company's based New York state.
So this keeps all the money
in New York state. No,
it didn't give all the money in,
you know, stay good amount of it.
It gives the small business owner a
shot at competing as large businesses,
which almost always cross borders. Right.
Gives farmers a much greater incentive.
Yes. And to be more farm
to table. The less stuff.
Now I've got to help my farmers out. My
New York state farmers are hurting badly.
That's one idea.
But the second thing is you want to
treat farmers like small businesses and
they're not,
which means they don't get the SBA loans.
They don't get help and
get treated that way.
It does not work when you treat
him like small businesses.
But next I want to completely legalized
a hemp and cannabis and I'm going to
have, you're talking and I want to
regulate them like onions, onions,
like onions and my joking like onions,
onions.
Here's the reason why a lot of onions
coming out of New York. That's right. Yes.
So my onions and no one cares. Bingo.
Exactly correct. And here's the issue.
There are three reasons why I want to
legalize hemp and cannabis and most of the
things you want to get high.
No,
the only drug I use is cannabis is
cannabis is a caffeine. Oh, cell.
This is the only drug. Freud. Yeah, I
like that. That's about cannabis. I know,
but if I use cannabis, I
would happily tell you. Right.
So I don't have him to hide. Why not
happily tell you can use it. Not My thing.
I get paranoid and worried about the
school system. When you get hired.
I think I talk even more.
I don't want to talk even more.
Do I know I would have not
not be introspective. You
might sit back and go, God,
I talk too much. Yeah, maybe then I
can mushrooms and I could have this.
I've never done mushrooms. Mushrooms
are, I feel like I've talked too much.
So maybe, maybe I should try them one
day. I've never done mushrooms. Mushrooms.
That makes me uncomfortable. Yes.
Yeah. I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm 50.
Yeah, I'm 51 there we go. You've
never done mushrooms? Never.
So somebody came up to you go,
Larry, you want to do some mushrooms?
And you're like, no man. One day I want to
be governor. That's what I was thinking.
I was seven and I thought Debbie governor
went to a fucking seven year old.
Oh, that's what I'm saying. Are
you hanging around? You got it.
You don't understand why, where I grew
up, when I grew up where I can go up now.
I grew up in south Bronx. Oh, even more
crazy. It was crazy. And then Tim dog.
I don't know who, Tim Dogs,
sorry, I haven't been in the
Bronx. South Bronx. Sorry.
I haven't been in the Bronx and
many years I'll address. But anyway,
wasn't secure. Reference Mushrooms
and marijuana. Yes. Thank you.
You've never smoked pot?
I have not. No. Never.
Never have what I can't ever have
behind you, bro. Sorry. Never had.
What kind of square are you? Didn't
snow. No Pie. I am mushrooms.
Acid? Nope. Do you want to try it? Maybe
one day. Liver right now. No, not now. No,
no, no, no. I'm running a campaign, my
friend. Oh yes. But they kept paying.
It would help you then. Odds are no
talking to them. The seventh. Okay.
And I'm a seventh to be forward. I'm
not against any of these things. Right?
It's your body. You own your body.
Okay. So if I, if I tried cannabis,
now don't drink either.
You don't ever drink,
not even a glass of wine with dinner. If
people are around drinking, I'll drink.
Right. But I don't, I don't
have any alcohol in my house.
I don't drink unless all
those were drinking. Okay.
I'll socially drink again. I,
I'm getting out of bed
with Theresa will drink.
You are focused for most of your
life has been what business? Uh,
first it was military.
I was a marine for seven years and then,
and then it was business.
Yes. So you're just uh,
keep your nose to the grindstone kind of
guy? Yes. Done. How else could I do this?
Have you seen my campaign?
This is the,
the last three gubernatorial campaigns
in New York state combined didn't raise
$10,000 combined.
I raised over a quarter million already.
The last three gubernatorial candidates
combined didn't do anywhere near the
amount of stops I've made
and I stuck too much.
Like how much is Cynthia Nixon
raise a 1.7, I think male, you know,
he didn't that crazy. People getting
behind sex in the city a lot.
There's a lot of that menopause money out
there, bro. I need some of that I guess.
I Dunno. It's flipping it around. My
point being yes, nose to the grindstone.
I'm doing this. Of course. I believe
it's lily. No mushrooms though. Huh?
No Mushrooms? No. Maybe later.
No wait till November 7th.
And then once you hit, then maybe
we'll see maybe your party with me.
Maybe if I win, I can't do it while
while I'm governor. That would be,
that would be, that
would be not, not cool,
but marijuana isn't it legal in
New York state? No, still not.
You have to have serious
diseases, right? That's correct.
Medical and you fix that of
course. Why the point? Yeah,
that seems really propositive.
My whole point on cannabis and hemp is
heavily because of farmers also, right?
Small farmers right now, yes, particular
has yes. Holy uncontroversial.
And it's a fantastic commodity.
It's good, it's good for the soil,
it's good for the environment.
And the best thing is if you treat
small farmers like small businesses,
they can now specialize and they can
specialize in hip and then also create
products in their farm.
Then with specialized hemp products,
they can do that and create
niche industries. Right.
And we see that in New York
state with both coffee and um,
and breweries we said already
happening in New York state.
And you would have the same sort of, uh,
incentives for them to sell in New York.
Absolutely. Yes. So particularly hemp,
which would be incredibly beneficial with
zero controversy. That's correct. Yes.
Of like psychoactive effects.
It doesn't have people,
people would be very happy to do
that. Right. But cannabis too,
because I want you to be able
to create cannabis products,
but there's something else and that is,
there are a lot of people in this country,
but I'll talk about New York state
specifically who have chronic pain.
And right now they have three choices,
one opioid and maybe get addicted to
suffer, which I don't accept all three.
What people tell me,
and for some reason that again,
it's only been women who've told me this,
they walk up to me and say, you know,
Laurie,
I hope you can legalize marijuana because
I smoke a little at night so I can go
to sleep. What about CBD? CBD is legal
in your state wasn't? I don't think so.
It's not, I don't think it is fucking, I
don't, you know, that's a good question.
I don't think it is. That's
crazy. Swipe medicinal. No, sorry.
It's probably medicinal CBD. Probably
minute. That'd be my assumption.
But CBD has no psychoactive effects,
no side effects. It comes out of it.
It comes to cannabis, right? So I,
I think we'll look it up real quick.
I think it's just,
I think it's medical in New York state.
So we do have some sort of a
doctor's prescription to get CBD.
So my point is if it's onion, you
can grow it in your backyard, right?
Great medicine. Your backyard,
right? If we heavily, yes,
if we heavily regulate cannabis
and or hemp, big business wins,
small business loses guaranteed it
will become big business cronyism.
The small farmers collapse.
It's the wrong answer, right?
So we need to make that happen.
And people already spoken it and
maybe you don't want to smoke it.
Why don't you have an edible?
Why don't Ya, I have liquid.
Why don't you have whatever's your thing,
you don't have to smell it.
If you want to smoke it,
please smoke it.
But there's many ways of of taking
advantage of, of both THC and CBD,
which you prefer. And look,
it's your body, not mine.
And why in the world what I want you to
have to live with chronic pain if you
don't have to write anything.
I'm not about being right, Judy,
because CVD again is not
psychoactive. Isn't legal. Yeah. Okay.
It is legal in New York. There we
go. It's pretty legal everywhere.
CBD because of the fact that it doesn't
have any psychoactive effects and it's
fantastic for people with arthritis. And
so we go, older folks are, I mean, shit,
I got Ted Nugent taking it. How about like
that? He's never even touched anything.
10 Nunu related does.
He likes my Facebook stuff.