Yeah.
Now what,
what's the deal with marijuana in
the [inaudible] MMA much legal now?
Um, the, they don't in season, out of
season. Yeah. It's fine. They just, they,
they've lowered the um,
acceptable level or the they've raised
it rather like what you could have in
your bloodstream. You basically just
can't be high the day. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's another interesting one.
I mean that acts,
especially THC acts on a lot of these
mtor pathways, you know, that's,
that's the same thing with a lot of
these anti aging compounds, right?
Like wrap a myosin or you know,
metformin to a lesser extent acts on
that mtor pathway and inhibits it. Right.
But again,
it's,
it's short term with something
like marijuana and you
also get this pain killing
effect.
And there was,
I forget if this was a study or if it was,
if it was like anecdotal,
but it's almost like a
higher thrill seeking effect.
Like the endocannabinoid system when
stimulated shuts down some of your,
your, your sense of fear when it comes
to experiencing a new adventure. Really.
And so you actually,
you actually go adventure seeking more.
And when you look at like ultra runners,
um, anybody who's competing in a,
a non,
a complex activity in which they might
have already developed the ability to be
able to be in the zone,
right?
They've put in their 10,000 hours of
practice and they're able to just kind of
check out and go into automatic mode.
When you combine that with the pain
qualling effects of something like uh,
you know,
in most cases like a THC CBD Combo is
what a lot of ultra runners are using.
I'm not sure what what they'd use in,
in MMA right now,
but ultimately you get a good effect.
But,
but the loss of reaction time and the
loss of the ability to be able to perform
complex tasks,
which they proven like flight simulation
studies dictates that it's still not
that great of a drug if you are going to
be doing complex tasks. Question though,
when they're talking
about reacts and Studies,
are they talking about reactions studies
for people that are acclimated to
taking marijuana? Are they talking
about it with people where they take a,
someone who's a sober person and they
introduce him to marijuana and there's
this overwhelming effect of it because
one of the things that happens to people
that aren't accustomed to THC is the
freak out effect where they're just like,
oh, they're not comfortable with
the experience. After a while,
the way it's described,
and again this is all anecdotal,
but by people that are accustomed to it,
they say you just get good at being
high and see the reaction time thing.
I don't buy,
because a lot of strikers,
a lot of a kickboxers they train
while they're on marijuana.
It's very common.
A lot of in reaction time was
done on pilots and there's,
there's a few more blinky lights in
the cockpit than, than a mat. So sure,
that might been more going on for sure.
But, but that's the, the question is,
are they experienced stoners or people
that are freaking out and maybe the
reaction time is they're spacing out
and they don't know what the fuck this
experience is like. And there they
might have because of it. You know,
there's a lot of uh,
really overwhelming sensations that come
with that marijuana high and a lot of
them,
you know,
you call paranoia or over sensitivity
and sometimes you get paralysis by
analysis when you're under the influence
of those things where all the acute
versus chronic effect.
But you Jitsu personally,
my personal experience would
you do to in marijuana is,
it's an enhancer and I've argued this
that I think it's a performance enhancing
with, with CBD CBD, no,
just marijuana. That's what,
that's what a lot of endurance
athletes are. You know, like,
like folks in the ultra running community
and now like they'll use like a trace
amount of THC combined with CBD,
like four to one to attend to one CBD
to THC ratio. And I think, you know,
now with the farm bill
and increasingly gallery,
I think this idea of developing sports
performance supplements for athletes who
aren't competing in sports,
whether that is band are going to be
steered in the direction of like high CBD.
And then some of these other novel
molecules are like CBG or CBN. These,
what are those? Yeah, there's,
there's all these different I that
but not just turpines. Yes, CBG,
CBN or cannabinoids.
THC eight is an anti inflammatory
that's totally different than THC nine
[inaudible] he's from orally ingesting
in are from smoking it or vaporizing.
They actually are now isolating these in
labs almost like organic chemistry and
you,
you can take hemp or marijuana and
and you can actually isolate specific
compounds and then combine them.
So you can take like you
could take like CBG CBD,
combine that with other
terpenes from like whatever.
Let's say lavender and Valerian
and camomile and make like a,
like a es de stress
relaxation type of compound.
Or You could do like a,
like a THC but a the eight instead of
a THC nine and combine that with like
cinnamon and peppermint.
Maybe some caffeine or creatine or
something like that to make like more of a
pick me up type of compound.
But I think that's,
that's the wave of the future
when it comes to a lot of these,
these marijuana companies that are
developing stuff for specific goals.
I know a lot of folks that are trying
to CBD that use it for inflammation,
especially athletes like it
with a little bit of Thc,
they seem to think it's more effective.
You know,
there's some sort of a combined effect
of the THC with the CVD. Yeah. Yeah.
They call that the a, the
entourage effect, you know,
when you have all the different
turpines and the endocannabinoids,
which one's turtle? Yeah. Which
one's the turtle has no clue. So, um,
there's hundreds of different,
different cannabinoids, right?
I don't think there's hundreds. Well,
I think there's at least dozens.
I don't know about hundreds. How
many of them, I mean, if you,
if you look at a chart of the different
endocannabinoid they've actually
discovered, if you were to just
Google on a 300 hundred 13. Yeah.
Yeah. So it's a lot. It's a lot of
fucking could have noise. I wonder. Yeah.
I wonder if they'll be able to like
design something that gives you the high
without the paranoia or gives you the,
you know,
the various effects without
spacing out. Yeah. Yeah.