Yeah, it's a problem. You know,
like when you're thinking
and talking at the same time,
there's a bunch of words bouncing around
in your head and you're just trying to,
and you think you're saying the right
thing when you're, you know, it's,
that's why intent is so
critical. George Carlin. Yeah.
And magic words are so fucking dangerous,
you know?
And that is what I'm going to
tell you about later. Yeah.
You know about a specific
comedian that we know and love.
Well,
George Carlin was absolutely amazing.
Well, he wa he would, not only
was he absolutely amazing,
but people don't have to you,
you almost have to have lived during the
time where he was getting arrested like
Lenny Bruce before him.
But to understand how significant he
was when he was doing that seven dirty
words, you can't say on television.
Like back then people were like,
what the fuck is this guy doing?
Nigger, I was, I was far left men skin
tight, black, you know, sheruts the virus.
Uh, you know, the virus, punk rock
bands, Antifa lag, things like that.
I was trying to think of,
it's been so long.
I'm trying to think of some of the band
shirts we used to have. And uh, man,
we were, we were angry and pissed off
all the time. I grew up like that.
And then over time I learned,
I went through a ton of
really important life lessons.
One of the first and most important was
I was a young skateboarder in Chicago.
Really looked up to some of these
older guys who were really good.
I went to Catholic school
when I was younger.
I ended up becoming this punk rocker
guitar playing far left skin tight,
you know, skateboarding, angry, Eh, no
flags, you know, fuck the government.
And then I go to, this dude's house
was just really great skateboard.
He's got a picture of Jesus on the wall.
And I immediately scarf like, um, um,
you know, high MIT. I was
like, I was like, what do you,
what do you like a Christian or something?
And he goes, no. And I was like, then,
why'd you have a picture
of Jesus? And he goes, oh,
I just thought like a story about a
dude traveling around helping people was
kind of cool. And I went, oh,
that's a good point. Wow. I was,
I was like, I was like, wow,
maybe I don't really understand.
Maybe maybe this means something
different to other people.
That show means to me.
Well,
if Jesus was an Indian man that
had wooden beads and you know, and,
and was a, a Hindu God, we
would love him. You know,
it'd be like Shiva Vishnu.
We would,
we would think he's the
most amazing thing ever.
It's the fact that if you look at what
Jesus preached and what he was all about,
I mean it seems pretty Ra I think it's
about is spiritual and loving and it's,
it's about, I mean it, his,
his whole ideology that the
Jesus of the Bible. Yeah.
And he was essentially about loving your
brother and treating people as if they
are you.
And,
but this, this for me,
like I bring this up,
cause it was kind of a formative moment
where all of a sudden I realized was my
ideology predicated on assumptions was I
was I holding these views because other
people told me to hold them. Right.
That I actually understand it.
There were some positive
things on the other side.
And then I slowly moved over to more of
a center left position. And you know,
now what w the reason I bring this
up is I looked, I watched that video,
I tweeted this, the video of George
Carlin, cause man, George Carlin, uh,
I used to watch this video was my,
my,
my mom would put them on and my mom's
been a hippie liberal, far left,
all that stuff. And you'd
probably consider a conservative
by today's, you know,
measures the way things have been going.
Now they look at, you know, Kevin Hart,
he said a bad joke 10 years ago. Get
'em out. Like, could you imagine, I,
God forbid, what would happen with George
Carlin's routines today? They wouldn't,
they would be running all of
his old routine saying, no,
you've got to ban him from the shows.
He literally called
these people the n word.
Why was it that George calling go onstage
and talk about how Republicans were
dom and how religion is crazy.
He was clearly on the left his whole life.
And he said these things that by
today's standards would be considered
conservative. Right. And so for me,
it's a weird thing to go from
being on the far left as a,
as a young person that was around
like 19 or 20 I started to become more
moderate and then to see them
today being extremely offended,
like people used to be in the fifties
and sixties to go from being on the far
left as a,
as a young person that was around
like 19 or 20 I started to become more
moderate and then to see them
today being extremely offended,
like people used to be in
the fifties and sixties.