The Joe Rogan experience. So I'm
gonna say listen to people too much.
Corey mean that's the problem. My wife
said all the time, like every morning,
she's like, no negativity today as
she always stay the fuck off line.
That's what you should do.
Now I'm doing the hunting stuff and
I'll pose this stuff. It's like,
as I got to put it, it pops on my
pop up in MMA questions. Yeah. Like,
or at the top of the screen it dropped
down or pop up in the notification or I
get an email notification. Somebody
say, you see half of it and I'm like,
don't open. Don't did I drive
and I wanted the rest of his day.
It could be a good thing. It might be
bad. And actually open it up later on.
If somebody is saying something bad, it's
just like, like my wife just said, shit,
if I got it, just don't pay
no attention to it. But yes,
you're, you'll allow negativity into
life that you don't need. I mean,
you think about your camp,
you got all these positive people,
all these motivated people, all
these professionals, you know,
exceptional human beings,
right?
Everybody training and grind together
and then you got schmoes that are
contacting you on Twitter or Instagram
or whatever and just saying a bunch of
nonsense and that could fuck
with your head. You know,
and these are not people that would ever
say that if they were in front of your
face. It's, it's a, it's a gross way to
communicate. It's just, it's not a hell.
It's like,
it's like passing by a shitty fast food
restaurant being drawn in to eat and
then you eat and you're like, God, why did
I eat that garbage? It's the same thing.
It's like you're eating, it's like
fast food for your brain. It's,
it's so tempting because you just want
to read those comments and most of the
people are probably good people
who are fans, most of them,
but all it takes is 10% assholes and
never want to look at your comments again.
One out of 10 it's not hard
to get 10% 10% assholes.
It's like pretty damn good
in the real world. You know,
if you only run into one out of 10 that's
an asshole in or one out of a hundred
even if it was one out of a hundred
and your comments have shitty,
you don't want to read those comments.
It's just for a fighter man.
It's so much of it is about mindset and
just being focused and not having any
distractions. And I think those comments
are a giant distraction. You know,
you don't need anybody telling you
what to do. John, Mark fucking Henry,
you've got Ricardo Elmeda, you've got
all these world champions around you,
like you don't need any, any
other information. You get
in plenty of information,
you know, fuck all that shit.
You shouldn't even look at it.
You should post and just run away. Just
post something and don't even look out.
Keep going. Just keep going.
Just I got to work it.
I know I've got to work on it
because what you're saying right now,
all the things you were saying about
beating Glover about beating Alere Latifa
yet, but you're saying it like you're
arguing with somebody. You're saying like,
someone told you you can't do it,
but who gives a fuck what
they said you did do it.
So why argue with someone who clearly
doesn't know what the fuck they're talking
about anyway, right. But in
your head and you're like,
they said I couldn't do this.
Like, see, you still have that.
It's he know what I'm talking about
because I have that battle 100%
because mark and they tell me all
the time like, Bro, quit feed.
Don't tell you where I come
from. Smart. Me and my brother,
we always had that mentality.
Like people were like,
you're talking to this and this.
Yeah, we weren't the type to,
we ain't gonna sit there
and talk back and forth.
It was like my first respond to anybody.
He's talking shit like, all right,
put your hands up. Let's all
right, I'm ready to fight.
Or you say I'm gonna prove you wrong.
That's telling me my time.
Like they always say at Corey couldn't
do this. You wouldn't do that.
You wind it is my whole life.
Like in college, like core,
you're not good enough to go to Miller's.
We only take five guys on team and I'm
guaranteed coaching going to take you
where the two years I was there,
I was the guy I went to middle
of the first pick. Every time.