Um,
out of all the years you've been doing
your show and all the years you've been
given advice. Ha. How did
this catch me outside girl?
How did this happen?
All good.
I know all the different shows.
But you made a monster. Uh, no,
I mean it's my moment of
infinity. No, seriously.
This girl comes home with her mother and
her mother actually brings her own of
course.
And she's a train wreck and we work with
her and we send her to this ranch for
like four months.
Right.
She goes for a long time and
makes a complete turnaround,
does a really a great job.
They say she's become a leader.
She's working with all these
girls doing a great job.
And then she graduates and I remember
this last shot when we do this,
this piece at the ranch,
she jumps up on this fence and is smiling
and everything and waving it all one
night home with her mother one night.
And her mother's finding people that
are trashing her, the mother on, on uh,
the social media platforms. Her mother
tracks him down, backs into who they are,
gets their phone numbers, calls
him up, yelling into the phone,
calling them names and stuff,
gets the daughter involved,
one night crashes.
So they come back for a followup like,
I don't know, month or two later.
And when they come I say, okay,
we're going to have him back. They walk
out, I have the audience completely empty.
I have nobody there to play
too. I mean, 250 chairs, empty,
nobody in the house, but me, the mother
and the daughter, that's a good move.
And they go, whoa, where
is everybody's? Well,
you don't need anybody. We're just here
to talk and you know, keep things rolling.
Right. And they were dumbstruck, they,
there was nobody there
to showboat for play too.
And there's like a 15 minute interview.
They had nothing to say. And off they go.
And then this phrase
that got turned into a,
you know, whatever, a meme
or whatever they call it, um,
it just went crazy.
And what she was nominated for a grammy or
Siri. I'm serious. Uh,
so I'm, I take no credit or blame. I,
you know, I just did what I could and
haven't seen her saying, I wish everybody,
well maybe she'll turn so
maybe it'll grow her up.
She'll turn some paucity valve. But I
hope so. Well that's a very good attitude.
Very healthy attitude for you. But it
is when something goes viral like that,
something strange that for whatever
reason it catches and takes off. It's,
it doesn't make any sense. It's a
very weird thing. It makes no sense.
She's on a billboard on sunset, a
giant billboard. Oh really? Huge.
Enormous billboard.
It's like one of those sides of the
building billboards where they, you know,
they put the graphic up and
it covers the entire building.
It makes no sense. Seriously. Seriously.
And there's people curing cancer and
you can't find him with both hands.
Exactly. Nobody has any idea who won
the last Nobel Prize for science,
but you know, more power to her. I, if,
if she can turn into something
positive that she have talent.
Have you ever heard any of her music now?
I have no idea. I've either seen
her on your show. Thank you.
I appreciate you bringing that up.
Sorry.
But it's just so strange that one
train wreck could for whatever reason,
catch on and then all of
a sudden it's gigantic.
Yeah.
They say that somebody signed her and
paid her millions of dollars seriously.
Like
close to a million dollars from
a makeup company. Really? Yeah.
Oh, well, okay. There you go. I
mean, if that's happening, right,
like what would your advice be
then? Would your advice be, Hey,
get your shit together and
stop being crazy? Well,
she's making a lot of money off of being
crazy and her opportunities before that
were probably severely limited.
Well, they had to be. And
what I hope now that this,
even though this certainly is a quirk,
what I hope now is that she's surrounded
by mature people with business heads on
their shoulders and development people
that will actually guide this in a way
that it's not 15 minutes. Yeah. You
never know. You know? That's what I hope.
Well,
everybody thought the Kardashians are
going to be 15 minutes and it's been 15
years.
Yeah. But there's been, you know,
people make fun of them and there's
some good things here to make fun of.
They do things to be made fun of.
But there's also from very smart business
and branding that's gone into that as
well.
Oh, 100%. And you know,
and I was actually very impressed with
her that she actually went to the White
House to talk about prison reform for
people that are unjustly accused and are
being been in jail for too long
for things that they didn't do.
And that's something
she's actually passionate.
Yeah. And I know Kim and she's
actually a very nice girl,
very smart and all.
And as I say,
they've done some very brilliant
branding and it's certainly paid off.
It's just so fascinating when something
catches like that girl, what is her name?
The catch man of science?
Uh, Danielle goalie or
something? Yeah. Yeah.
Cause I didn't know her
as the catch me outside,
but if she didn't say that one phrase.
Yeah.
And she just said that I think to her
grandmother or somebody in the audience.
I know it didn't even register
with us at the time. Wow. It was,
it wasn't a standout phrase in the
interview or anything. It just pass by.
Somebody just grabbed it and,
and then it became a meme. Yeah.
What a weird world we
live in. Yeah, no kidding.