Well, let me think. It's the
wrong way to think about it.
What do you disagree if anything
with what he said so far? Well,
so far what he said, it hasn't been
particularly reveling the Tori, um,
the,
uh,
I think we have to step back
for a second because you know,
while the low carb community might have
a more better understanding of where we
disagree,
um,
I think the greater community that Joe
Reaches might not so fundamentally with
Stefan saying and what the research
community is saying and the conventional
thinking in this field is that the brain,
and correct me any point I get this wrong,
but the brain regulates,
does the fundamental job of controlling
how fast we are and the way it does it
is by controlling or miss controlling
our intake and our expenditure and the
different tents up in fat tissue.
Is that fair to say for the most
primarily intake, but yeah. Yeah.
So Stefan has a brain centric view of
the universe and the community community
at large does as well.
So if we go outside and we walked down
in Ventura Boulevard and we see someone
who weighs 400 pounds,
um,
they've clearly taken in more calories
than they should have opened the course
of their life and it's been
stored in their fat tissue.
And Stefan says,
I think would say that the problem is in
their brains ability to regulate intake
to expenditure. Is that
correct? Yeah. Okay.
And let me, I have to fix my headphones.
So how are we going to do this?
I'm getting feedback when I talk. You're
getting feedback? Yeah. It's just weird.
Couldn't be the,
hold on one sec.
For those who don't know, I'm
hearing impaired. As I say, kindly,
my kids would say deaf as a post, so
better. So I took off my hearing aids.
It's a little better.
Okay.
So what I've been arguing, so I come
along my background, I'm a journalist,
I'm an investigative journalist
with a science background.
Okay. That's what I do.
And I'm curious, and I've gotten
a lot of, you know, and I,
my first two books were studying
what's called pathological science,
which is about people who got the wrong
results in science because a lot of
times scientists do so by,
I'm very sensitive to this.
And as I was doing the
research for my first book,
which took five years,
what I noticed in when you
take a historical perspective
is that the research
community studying obesity
was very focused on the brain.
They just assume that
that people are gluttons.
And I'm gonna use some
socially unacceptable, uh,
language, because in part,
that's how they thought about. And
in fact, when you read the, uh,
obesity literature from
the forties and 50s,
it's shocking the way these people
talked about people with obesity.
And the assumption was
they're gluttons are,
they're neurotic or they're anxious
or they're just, you know, but,
but it was all brain center.
And when they got to the 1960s,
the field was being run by psychologists
and psychiatrists who are trying to get
people with obesity to eat less.
And it,
my favorite example is one team
that was trying to get the,
they got the wives to stop having sex
with the husbands if they didn't lose
weight every week and
that would motivate them.
I think even you pointed out that sex
is a greater motivator in your book.
Then tasty foods.
It didn't say it was greater,
but I said it was on par.
Par So,
and I'm going to just read you a,
I won't read you that the,
so there was this, while the
obesity research community
is focusing on the brain,
there are people studying fat metabolism
endocronologists they study hormones
and hormone related disorders
saying that the, Oh yeah,
fat storage and fat mobilization,
the burning of fat and the human body is
controlled by this very diverse set of
hormones and enzymes and the nervous
system is involved in well and our body
does a very careful job of the site of
basically orchestrating how
we use fields after we eat.
And the implication was,
and I think Stefan kind of stepped into
this with the very first thing you said
till the assumption was obesity is a
disorder of excess fat accumulation.
So today when you read the literature,
the article's officer obesity's
a sort of energy imbalance.
You take in more calories
than they expend.
There were still the best scientists in
the field. The best physician scientists,
which they look obesity is the
disorder of excess fat accumulation.
Let's look at what regulates fat
accumulation. The human body,
some people are programmed or dysregulated
to store more fat and if their store
more fat, they're going to, their
behavior is going to respond,
they'll be hungry or they'll eat more,
there'll be gluttons all of these things.
So it was switching the causality
instead of the brain determining energy
balance and that determining
fat accumulation.
The idea was the sort of,
let's see,
what regulates fat accumulation
that's dysregulated. If I have a,
if I give birth to a daughter who weighs
a hundred pounds at age four I'm not
gonna worry about how much
he eats and exercises.
I'm going to worry about what's going
on with fat accumulation and this young
girl that her body is just
as if you give a, you know,
if you have a child who's six foot
eight when he's six years old,
you're not going to worry about
how much he eats an exercises.
You're going to worry that he's over
secreting growth hormone. So the idea,
basically what I've done,
my role in this is to say look
in this vitally important period in
the 1960s the 1970s when obesity we
searchers came to understand I'm fat
metabolism researchers came to understand
the of that sells the obesity.
People were convinced that the problem
is in the brain and those obesity people
eventually grew into the world that
Stefan got his PhD in as the neuro
biological world where you study what's
happening in the brain and you ignore
what's happening in the fat cells and
fat mobilization and fatty acid oxidation
and Ted Stuart.
And when you look at that,
you find a whole world of places in
which people can pre be predetermined,
you know, be driven to
be fat. So, for example,
when I was in high school,
senior year in high school,
I weighed 195 pounds and I
played football and my brother,
two years older, wait 195 pounds
his senior year and played football.
My brother never got more than 195
pounds and I went up to two 40.
We both ate as much as humanly possible.
You know, as you could imagine,
that's what high school athletes do.
My brother was always lean.
I was always trouble. My brothers stayed
late and it became an endurance athlete.
I became a football player
and I lifted weights.
I put on muscle easily and I fat knee.
Slowly he didn't.
Um, the conventional wisdom would be the
reason I went to two 40 and he never got
the one 95 was that my brain
was different than his.
My argument is our bodies
were fundamentally different.
So if I see somebody walking down
the street and weighs 300 pounds,
I don't worry about,
I don't think about what the problem
is with her brain regulating intake and
expenditure.
I think about what's,
why is her body driving her to be
300 pounds? So that's, I think,
kind of the fundamental
difference. Um, and is it,
is it the brain that can't do the job
or is it the body that can't do the job
and the brain is responding to
what's happening in the body?
Yeah. Is this a reductionist perspective?
Cause I mean, isn't it a holistic,
I mean holistically you're looking at
the entire machine of the human body.
The idea that the brain is somehow or
another separate from the body is saying
it's separate.
The question is the brain driving
what's happening in the body or is it
responding to a 10? So, um, and you know,
the brain of course does respond a lot
to what's happening in the body and we
can talk about that and how that
works. Um, but you know, I think it's,
we can tell stories,
but the things,
the thing that differentiates a story
that's true from a story that is not true
is evidence. And so, you know,
you talk about the difference
between your brother and you.
This is where that genetics evidence comes
back in that I was talking about your
brother and you only
share half of your genes.
We know that genetics has a strong impact
on who has a greater susceptibility to
body fatness and nut than others.
And we also know what the genes do
that underlie those differences.
And they are primary. I'm not done
Gary, let me finish jeans. Those jeans.
Nope. Nope, not right now. I'm, I'm
in the middle of saying something.
Those genes are um, primarily related
to differences in brain function.
That is what the genetic say.
And so that suggests that the reason why
you had a greater propensity than your
brother to become fat probably has to
do with differences in genetics that
relate to brain function. That is what the
research says. Okay, very actually look.
So when you talk to him about two 17 year
olds that way, exactly the same amount.
Like how do we know how much they
consumed in calories? I mean,
we don't have any studies.
We don't have of course,
but I mean I could guarantee you we
both paid as much as humanly possible,
but eventually my mother who never got
over one 95 and I apologize for bringing
you up on the air.
I know you don't like that used
to say that he never gets stuffed.
He just gets bored of eating after
a couple of hours. Okay. Okay.
But I may be even though like maybe
if you looked at it scientifically,
you ate more than him or maybe
you ate more sugar, more carbs.
So that's a difference. So the,
that, those are the two hypothesis.
Why don't I pause? [inaudible] is my body,
and this is what Stefan is. Cypress. I
want to just, the thing I wanted to read,
how much,
I'll ask you the question,
how much of the variation in human
obesity to those genes explained?
So if you look at the genetics
of, no, I didn't ask how much.
Yeah, your question. He needs
to let us talking. Yeah, you
got to love Tamales, Gary.
Um,
so if you look at the genetics of obesity,
what you find is that from twin studies
and family studies that measure the
overall contribution of genetics,
about 75% of the differences in body
fatness between individuals is due to
genetic differences between
those individuals. So, you know,
1995 America,
if you just take a cross section of
people and you measure how much is genes,
how much is environment,
about 75% is genetic.
Now we've only identified
a small proportion of the
specific genes that underlie
the propensity to obesity.
And so if you look at the percentage
that we have specifically identified,
it's a very small, and that's what I
refer to in my book. How much it's like a,
right now I think it's up to about 10%
it was 3% when their book was pumped.
Yeah, that's correct. They
did 7% absolutely. Yeah.
The latest. Yeah. Actually,
let me cite the, uh, so the
study, they're not just a second,
I'm going to cite this study just a
second. I'm going to cite this study. Uh,
this study is under reference number two.
So you can,
you can go check that out.
It's about 10% and these genetic
studies are advancing very quickly.
And that's why in the three
years since I wrote that,
we have explained a lot more than we
did at the time that I wrote that.
And so we have a portion of these genes
identified and what we're seeing is that
most of that portion that we have
identified relate to brain activity.
And so that tells us that primarily the
differences between individuals that
determine differences in body fatness
is about differences in brain activity.
And no one should be shocked about this.
The brain generates all
of our eating behavior.
It generates all of our physical activity
behavior and it actually regulates
body fatness. No one should
be surprised by this. I am.
And I was. And how were you surprised
when you get, if you disagree with, well,
virtually everything,
but, um, let's begin with
track back now. The, um, okay,
so drugs that explain obesity 10% with
the argument that I was making and the
argument I continue to make. Imagine
if you don't, we'll take Stefan's,
uh, car medicine's Stefan. He says,
Stefan, can you say that right?
It's okay. I'm not saying that, but I
mean just people don't get confused.
Thank you. The, uh, if
it takes car now and,
and somewhere in the 1970s I, I've
used the car, now I'm for this too,
but I don't think it's as appropriate.
But when we to think that somewhere in
the 1970s the aliens didn't notice that
there were humans driving the car.
So now they're trying to solve the
problem without the humans involved.
Why did you do some cars
drive faster than others?
And they come up with all kinds of
hypotheses and some of them can explain it
even when they interpret the hypotheses.
One of the common problems at science,
it's called intellectual face lock.
So what I've been arguing is in effect,
the obesity research community
left out of its research,
1960s era endocrinology,
the hormonal metabolic regulation
of fatty acid metabolism,
oxidation burning.
And it sucked when they did it.
Pretty much everything they've done
since has been interpreted incorrectly.
Just like the aliens would interpret the
car problem if they never noticed the
humans. So, um, and
Leptin is a good example.
So Leptin is discovered in 1993
and when Leptin is discovered,
obesity becomes sort of a
legitimate field of science.
Until then it's a bunch of actually
mostly psychologists studying and,
and now it becomes a subdiscipline and
molecular biology and all the molecular
biologists jump into the field and
they assume that would let them, does,
is controlled the brain signals how
much fat is available to some kind of
satiety or fueled deficiency,
um,
hormone.
And as such,
they studied the brain and they studied
the action of Lipton in the brain.
Now in 2002,
Jeff Friedman who gets credit for
discovering up perhaps incorrectly,
um,
publishes a paper in the journal Science.
It's saying perhaps as much as two thirds
or more of what Leptin does is done in
the periphery in the body.
And what Leptin does,
it's a hormone that sort of is,
is secreted in response to how
much fat you've accumulated.
And then does it stimulate the brain to
tell you to eat more or less depending
on how much fat or it
also works in liver cells,
which are the cells that were studying.
And the assumption is it probably doesn't
all cells to tell yourselves to burn
fat. So it makes perfect sense if
there's fat available in the fat cells,
now you've got a signal telling sort of
influencing the other cells of the body
to burn fat. So now you've got a hormone
that could work in the periphery, in the,
in the, you know, below then neck
or it could work above the neck.
But you've got a community that's
almost exclusively studying in the head.
They don't know they're human drivers
down here. So that's what they do.
So even in this world, the, I don't,
I think I know the genome paper,
I'm Stefan is
probably referenced on his
[inaudible] a number of fescue.
That's the heart's research. Is
that, uh, I, I don't remember the,
so they had two papers cause it's what
you cited in the article you coauthored
with Rudy Leibel.
So I have two papers.
One is genes associated with obesity and
one is genes associated with body type.
So with body type, they're all below
the neck. They're all you know,
fat metabolism basically.
And the Musk, you know,
the genes had aspects of your body
that you would expect to be controlled.
Like when you build up muscle and you
have to take an excess energy to do it,
it makes you hungry.
I don't think your brain is regulating
how much muscle you're building other
than your drive to go to the gym.
Basically your body is responding
to the stress on the muscle.
All the things you do in the weight
lifting, it's all below the neck.
So the argument here is again,
simple.
When these people looked at body type,
it was insulin regulated
genes for the most part,
growth hormone, all of these things.
When they looked at excess body fat,
they decided they were in the head.
But the question is when they looked,
they're programmed to think that excess
body fat, it's caused by overeating.
So they look in the brain,
did they do the same kind?
And I was going to call
the researcher involved.
I never got around to doing it saying
if body type body shape is determined by
these genes and doesn't it make sense
that x has variations of body shape,
we're going to be determined
by the same genes.
And did you do the same kind of searches?
I don't actually know how they
determine where the genes work.
It's the same kind of searches. They just
came up with different sets of genes.
So they didn't start with any assumptions.
They were just finding them the
questionnaire where the genes work.
So there's a common phenomenon,
all of this like with Leptin gene that
everybody thinks about working in the
hypothalamus seems to work in every,
can I respond to that? [inaudible]
talking cause you say this in your head,
you say this in your book,
I'm prepared to respond
whenever you're done. Okay.
In your book you say that gene's work.
Yeah, the body is very, basically,
it puts a different mechanisms to work
as many places that can in there these
homeostatic feedback loops,
you know, something happens.
Your whole body has to respond.
So a gene that my work primarily on
one cell is scattered all over the body
because every cell, and it'll do
different jobs on different cells.
But if you think that the problems
in the brain, that's where you look.
So you get this kind of intellectual
phase lock where that's what we do.
That's what we study. And
neurobiologists studies the brain, uh,
the Daniel Kahneman,
Stefan like suicide,
Daniel Conaman as well had this concept.
What you see is all,
he's a Nobel laureate, uh,
cognitive psychologists.
What you see is all there is.
Okay. And basically if
you're studying the brain,
that's what you look at if
you're studying the gut,
until we all get trapped into that on
some extent. And what I'm saying is,
even in these studies,
so Stefan and Stefan wrote a book about
the hungry brain that is supposed to be
about obesity.
But in fact,
you never mentioned anything about the
metabolic regulation of [inaudible].
It's just not there.
And I would argue it has to
be there even if it's wrong,
if it's not there,
the absence of it.
Like you can't talk about Leptin without
talking about what it might be doing in
the body. You can talk,
you know, so there's a,
the edits put me in a very odd position.
So Stephanie is kind of the defender of
the Orthodox and I'm the one who comes
along and says, look, you guys
just, you missed it. You screwed up.
You had psychologists and psychiatrists
running the field when the
endocrinologists sob that and then
you'd discovered Leptin and it became a
molecular biology problem.
And you're now divorced from the very
simplest observations about obesity.
You know, so we can do huge
genome wide association studies.
They sound remarkable.
But if I were to ask a simple question
like why is it I get fat here?
Yeah, the love handle thing, it's in the
back with man. It's not in the front,
but it's here and not here.
I don't see what the brain has
to say about that. Um, okay.
So as you mentioned,
there have been different genetic
studies that have looked at body fat
distribution versus total body fatness.
So total body fatness is what we're
talking about when we're talking about
obesity.
Uh,
body fat distribution is what we're
talking about when we're talking about the
fat being on your hips
versus on your wrist.
Now what we see is different
sets of genes that come up.
So body fat distribution,
we actually see insulin,
a related genes, so people that have
a central body fat distribution,
so body fat around their waist tend
to have these insulin related genes
that are driving that.
But when you look at total body fatness,
the thing that causes obesity,
what you see is that those genes
are dominated by the brain.
And the really cool thing,
the point I want to make about the
genetics research 10% that means might be
tolerated by the brain and
say, look, come on Gary.
It is unbiased. That's the really cool
thing about it is that they're just,
this is whatever genes are popping up.
These studies do not care about what
you believe about what causes obesity.
This is just whatever
genes are popping up.
So it's unbiased and that's what they're
saying. And I'm not done here, Gary.
Now I want to talk about,
um, you mentioned Gary,
that may be Leptin is
having important actions,
not just in the brain but in the
body. First of all, I'm glad,
I'm flattered that you read my book
and I'm glad that you acknowledge the
existence of Leptin. Now this is good. Um,
but now you say that researchers focus
on Leptin actions in the brain because
we're phase locked and we
can't get out of our, you know,
blinders of thinking about it in terms
of the brain and that that's why we focus
on left and action in the brain.
The real reason we focus on left and
action in the brain is because it has been
demonstrated that it's effect on body.
Fatness are via the brain.
There are actual experiments
demonstrating this,
and I'll explain how
these experiments work.
This is all in the scientific literature.
So if you knock out the Leptin receptor
only in the brain or only in the
Hypothalamus,
you get obesity.
So that is what tells us that actually
the brain is the key site of action.
And particularly this part of the brain.
It tells me, Hey, Carrie, Carrie, Carrie,
please let him talk. He let
you talk. Yeah. And that's it.
So I mean you get the same obesity if
you knock leaped and how to the brain and
particularly out of the hypothalamus
that you get if you knock it out of the
whole body.
So that shows that the brain is this
site of action that is causing this to
happen. And this is no surprise. We
have these mechanisms worked out.
We know specific groups of neurons
that are receiving the left in that are
controlling or appetite that are
controlling our metabolic rate.
We have many of these neuro
populations worked out in mice.
We understand these systems so well
we can control specific popular tiny
populations of neurons very
precisely caused them to eat a ton,
to stop eating, to gain fat, to lose
fat like the animals are marionettes.
I mean that's the level of understanding
we have right now of how these systems
work. So, I mean,
all of this evidence is converging on
the same thing that the brain is central
and that fat cell metabolism. I'm just
not seeing the evidence for that. I mean,
Gary,
if you want to cite specific evidence
demonstrating that that is an actual cause
of differences in body fatness between
individuals in the general population.
I'm awaiting that evidence and I'm happy
to sit here and listen to you cite the
evidence that demonstrates that.
Correct.