You drive in in Australia? No,
no bill. Just so seeing the,
I was just saying that with the
site, it was just so weird, you know,
just everything was so awkward
and immune was Craig. We went,
I went for a run and they're freaking
parrots and like anger Rusi Shit Dude.
Like just regular like it's like our
seagulls and crows. I'm like Ryan,
cause like rainbows,
like two can't stand next to me.
Australia is a weird place man.
Yeah, it was. It was crazy bike.
My time clock was screwed up.
I went to work a couple a couple of days
later and like Mao was still like 40
later and I was still like
messed up. It was bad. Yeah.
I could fuck you up for a week or two,
but you know,
it's worth it just to go to Australia.
Amazing. It's a great place. Yeah.
I have a bunch of family there.
When you have a big fight with a guy
like saint Mark Hunt, well, you know,
could be a brawl and that turned
out to be a five round fight. Right.
Was it a fair four and a half? Yeah,
he stopped him in the fifth. Yep. Um,
when you, you have a fight
like that and you know this is,
you're in there for the long haul.
Do you plan on like staying for
days after the fight to recover?
No, I actually wanted him
to get home but I had,
I was a bad boy so he wanted me to do a
couple like promotional thing went down
here. They put, they get to see my family.
So I have family Australia
other than Melbourne and Sydney.
Oh you have family out
there. Oh no kidding. Yeah.
So we hung out with for a little bit.
It was cool.
Did you see that video that they posted
a yesterday of these guys in Australia
with a 39 foot boat and the
sharks went by those 20 feet long.
You see that video?
It's fucking insane video cause the shark
is almost as big as the God damn boat.
They have this 39 foot boat
and they have an overhead,
like a drone footage of the
sharks swimming around the
boat. And I like cheese.
I definitely shit my pants and that
one, it was not much you can do. I mean,
you don't have a whole lot of options.
Yeah. Wow. It's like 20 foot shark.
That's crazy. Fuck all that. And
that. Australia has a ton of those.
They're all over the place. Yeah. I mean
I, I was talking, math happens a lot.
Apparently. 18 foot shirt
next to a 21 foot boat. Oh
fuck that dude.
Oh my gosh.
Those videos like those whales and stuff
that sprout up. Yeah. Whoa. You know,
like right next to the boat.
Yeah. What does this one Jamie,
18 foot shirt next to the 21 foot
boat. Oh my God. That thing is big.
Jesus Christ. It's huge. And it's
just swimming next to the boat going,
can I eat you? Hmm? How do I eat
you? I'm not sure if I can eat you.
God Damn Kid. Get back, get back and
was your son get back? You little fuck.
Sit down. Jesus Christ.
It's a shark. Yeah,
they're there.
Did you see the video of
the guy was diving the real
recent video and I like hit
the back of the a chemo and
thumped the back of his head.