The Joe Rogan experience,
you know, like, Ooh,
it gives me like serious anxiety when
I find out that someone got a Vegas
residency. I go, how many nights a week?
Six,
six nights a week at the stratosphere.
It sounds, I mean, somebody told me David
spade was thinking about doing one. Oh.
And he went to go see Louis Anderson
who was doing one this before, baskets.
And he was like, it was just the
saddest thing I've ever seen.
That was like Carlin's last
stand was a Vegas residency.
Did he have a Vegas residency? Yeah.
Where was he at? I forget where he was,
but he had like a meltdown where
he like went off on the crowd,
just like talk to calling him all
pieces of shit. Really. And Yeah.
And then had to go to rehab was like,
I'm addicted to painkillers, like,
and then on the giver, I don't
they ever performed again. Well,
he died before he died.
Like he was performing when he died.
I mean,
I think he was at a hotel,
I'm pretty sure he was sleeping in a
hotel that he was performing at when he
died. I believe that, but I,
cause I had done that last
special he did was terrible. We,
he's like reading half of it. Oh, I
didn't see that. It's, it was, it was,
it was just like, you
know, a swan song for him.
But I think that was after
the Vegas residency, so
must've been doing more. Yeah,
his schedule was very,
very hectic and unusual.
He was doing one hour a year,
an hour specialty would film
and he would write it all out.
Like he would write it all out
and then tweak it a little bit,
but it was more of a monologue then it
was like set up punchline jokes and he
seemed to,
he was falling into this more like more
of a social commentator in some aspects
than he was a stand up towards the
end. You know what I mean? Oh yeah.
Someone told me that he,
a lot of the reason he did an
hour every year was because, uh,
the tax problems with the IRS
was coming out in hard. And uh,
so we had to be working that much
and it kind of made them miserable.
You know the story about
his nine 11 story, right.
Um, tell me where he
recorded a special called.
I kinda like it when a lot of people die.
That was the name of the special,
and he has his whole egg closes with a
big long 20 minute thing about like when
he hears about people dying,
he liked the more the better.
And he filmed it on like September 10th
and then the next day came in and was
like, we've got to,
we've got to cancel this,
but no one can ever see this or hear
this and now you can get the album.
But even in the album, he's
reading it. They like it.
They destroyed the actual footage from the
taping. Really? Yeah. They destroyed it.
Oh. He was just like, there's no one
can ever see this. Wow. According to,
in Vegas at the MGM Grand
on September 9th and 10th,
September 9th and 10th. That's
crazy. Yeah. What was it called?
I kinda like it when a lot of people die.
Jesus Christ,
he woken up the morning
of September 11th and go,
did I manifest this? Yeah, look at that.
I kind of like it when a lot of
people die. And so the audio CD,
it's just him talking. It's
like him working out the, uh,
wait a minute.
It's a streaming.
I like the audio streaming with Amazon
prime's audio. There's no video of it.
I'll look and see if there is some,
some person who works somewhere.
It might've preserved it. I mean,
I feel like I would've heard
about it. I mean, like I said,
I listened to the bit and it's, he's like,
I've got to read, this is how I do it.
So it's like a very early version of
it. But, uh, it's not great, but I mean,
I can't,
I can't even imagine taping a special on
September 10th he had some dark moments
in his career.
I took some friends to see him in
1988 at the Hampton Beach Casino.
I think that's what it was called
in Hampton Beach, New Hampshire.
It's like a place where people would
go up for vacation and we went to see a
George Carlin there way back in the day
and he always had the same opening act
and the same opening.
I kind of knew even back then cause I was,
I guess I was an open miker then
I was just starting out. Um,
I knew there were certain guys who took
people on the road with them that were
terrible. They took people on the
road with them that just didn't,
they weren't good comics,
but they made them look like heroes and
[inaudible] they were friends with them
or because he just wanted to have like
the worst comic ever go up before then?
It's a good question. You know,
you'd have to, I guess it would vary,
but for sure there's certain comics that
like it when people go on in front of
them suck. They do, they
want that, you know,
there's certain comics that you see them
taking people on the road and you look
at it, you're like, what the fuck?
You're taking that guy with you.
Like what are you doing? Why? Why are you
torturing people like that? Yeah. But, uh,
the opening acted better than George.
Like he had terrible set.
He had this whole rant that
he was doing cause he like,
he had an unquestionably one of
the greatest comics of all time,
but he had hours that were just not good.
And there was a period of time where
it seemed like he just missed it.
Like it was like,
it was missing,
whether it was his personal
life was off or whatever it was.
But he had this whole rant that was
like, fuck this. And he was like,
and fuck Israel and fuck comedy clubs.
Like he was saying, fuck comedy clubs,
like this is like this whole bit.
And he was reading it off of a yellow
legal pad and the whole audience was like
standing there like not understanding
like where this was going.
Like we're waiting for the jokes. Where's
the hilarity? Whereas it, and it wasn't,
it just didn't exist.
And my friends were mad at me really.
I had taken him from where we live.
We lived in revere and we all drove all
the way up to New Hampshire. Like, yeah,
we're going to go see George Collins is
going to be awesome. And it was terrible.
It's funny,
I remember Louis Ck and like an interview
years ago was talking about how he
took the pressure came off of
him to always have a good show.
But you said audience members love
saying, Oh, I saw George Collin once.
And he was, but they really
loved saying, you know,
I saw Carlin once and he was horrible.
Like they,
they still get the experience and the
story of it and that that's it's theirs
forever. You have to worry about
doing a bad shedder though.
If they say you were funny. I think it's,
I think to see a legend bomb would be,
uh, would be great. Well,
if you are a Carl and fan,
you've got to see those. If you went
to see him live a bunch of times, yeah,
he had those rough spots, man. You know,
it's, um, it's one of those things,
if you're going to do an
hour of stand up every year,
you're going to have some rough ones.
There's just no way around that. Oh, 100%.
It seems like that's just,
I mean it can be done.
I think it can be done.
I mean,
I think you can put together like I'm
six months in from my last special,
I think I could do another
special in six months,
but it wouldn't be as good as my
last one, I don't think. Yeah,
I just don't think it would, I just
think you need time. Yeah. One a year.
It's crazy.
It's insane.
Like the guys like Jimmy Carr
who while they're touring,
they're writing jokes and just putting
them away. So at the end of the tour,
when they taped the special,
they have all these jokes they can go
through and look at and then start the new
tour from that. That seems like I like
to sit in my set, you know what I mean?
I just want it to be focused on that and
not always be writing the next thing.
But some people who are just like,
I'm just going to go up and talk.
And it's happening a lot now.
I think with like the
prevalence of Netflix specials,
people just want the money and they're
famous enough they can just go up and
just get through it. And I'm
like, this is your legacy. Yes.
Why would you want to put
out a bad special ever?
I don't care what they're paying you make
sure it's great. I feel the same way.
And I feel like those people that
watched that, when you do do that, man,
if you don't acknowledge
that you fucked him over,
they're never going to trust you
again. If you don't say, hey look,
that one wasn't a good special. I
gave it a shot. It just wasn't right.
It didn't come out right.
I thought it was pretty good.
And then the taping didn't go
well and if you don't do that,
they're not going to listen to your man.
They were like, this is my best work.
Like this is, Oh, this
is your best work. Yeah,
well the fuck you can fool them
once. And I mean, like if I want,
if I went on tour right now and just
did the same material from the special,
like people would be like, okay, but
they're not coming back the next time.
You know, they're gonna
get mad at you. Yeah, yeah.