But some stuff's real out.
Well,
I love the way you communicate this
because it takes into consideration human
nature. And like I loved Dawkins.
He's fantastic. I think he's very,
very, very valuable. But he
likes to call people idiots.
And the problem with that is people
go, fuck you. You're an idiot.
Like is a natural inclination when you
insult people to argue back and to sort
of dig their heels in. Yeah.
And a, you don't do that.
And I think that's very important.
And I think that it kind guy like Dawkins
just gets frustrated from all these
years of debates with
people who are uneducated,
are saying ridiculous things and
he's a bit of a curmudgeon, you know,
when he seems to be softening
as he's getting older. Well,
he's an evolutionary biologist and
that's the, the front line in some sense,
isn't it? Yes, that is. Yeah. I mean,
you think about particle physics is
that you don't get a lot of shit because
people don't understand
what you're talking about.
Evolutionary your biologies.
Right. That so I understand
his frustration. Oh, I do too.
Having said that, you know, I've kind of
softened a bit over the years actually,
because now I think at this point,
both in the u s actually and in Britain
and in some other countries, we are a,
an a point, you've sort of alluded
to it, where everybody's angry,
there's a lot of anger and a lot
of it is justified by the way,
who could talk about that, you know,
income inequality and all those things.
So it's justified anger.
But it seems to me that there are people
of goodwill who need to band together
to diffuse the anger.
Now Society's otherwise we won't have
countries like the United States. Yes.
As United States, cause it's United and
everybody, and you've got the United,
the American flag there.
You know,
there's a sense of belonging and identity
and togetherness in a country which
you've got to preserve. And so
I've stopped actually, um, picking,
I used to, for example, quite
enjoy picking fights with
Deepak Chopra on Twitter.
You know, and it's just
for me to laugh, you know,
and you just do it and he says some crazy
stuff, then he's end. But I've sort of,
I've stopped doing it going well,
but relative to some of
the other people is a,
he's someone who means it means well.
Yes,
I don't agree with virtually
anything he says. However,
he's a well meaning person. And so I've
started trying to seek common ground now.
That's why I get, for example, gave a
talk to the bishop's asked me to call me.
I don't agree with them on the framework,
their theological framework,
but they mean well, most of them. Yeah.
So I think seeking consensus and
diffusion, anger, as you said,
is it is incumbent on all of us,
especially people like us
who have a public voice.
We need to diffuse some of
this anger because otherwise
it will consume everyone.
Yes.
I've,
I've tried very hard to evolve in
that respect and just get better at
communicating ideas and get better at
understanding how people receive those
ideas. And I think that's, it's there's,
it's easy to get lazy and
to insult and to yeah.
And he's fine. He's fine. Yeah. Well,
especially me. I mean, I'm a comedian.
That's part of what I do is insult people.
Yeah.
But I use it funny for humor.
I want to entertain people.
That's the whole idea behind it.
But I think in terms of like discussing
ideas especially that are so personal to
people like religion. I've, I've uh,
I've reexamined the way I interpret
these ideas and the way I owe.
I talk about these things. Yeah.
That's uh, it's interesting. There's a,
I did a BBC program at age to,
I was asked to do it on the,
this thing called the
wreath lunches at the BBC.
The BBC had done to his 1952,
I think it was.
And Robert Oppenheimer did them in
53. And it was, it's fascinating.
You can get the transcripts online,
they're free and you can get one recording
of the five they taped over the other
four. Can you believe
it? Why they raised them?
Because they wanted to tape for
something else. It's just unbelievable.
But one of them exist often home are
given these latches. Oh my God. I know.
But you can read thick from Katie by
more tapes and virtual veteran muscle
didn't do the, they tapes
over them. Bertrand Russell's
cause tape was so expensive,
but he talks crazy.
But it's brilliant. It's called
science in the common understanding.
And they weren't very well received
because he thought it was going to talk
about the Manhattan project.
So they thought it was going to talk about
the atom bomb. You know, cause he was,
he ran it basically.
But you didn't,
you talked about how
thinking like a scientist,
which means thinking in the way that
nature forces you to think can be valuable
in other areas. And it's a, that's an
insight in itself. The great thing,
the unique thing about science, there's
nature forces you to think like that.
You can't have an opinion.
Can I have an opinion about gravity?
We jumped to build and you can
hit the ground. That's it. Yeah.
It doesn't matter what your opinion
is. And he said, so if you think about,
for example, quantum mechanics. So,
uh, sometimes you think of as Pascal,
like an electron,
sometimes it has to,
it's a point like object may behave
like a little Billy a bowl thing,
the pool ball that bounces around,
but sometimes it behaves
like an extended thing,
like a wavy thing and nature forces you
to hold both ideas in your head at the
same time in order to get a complete
picture of the object there a description
of an electron. And he said that's the
valuable thing about quantum mechanics.
You know,
unless you're doing electronics,
I'm inventing lasers and you
don't need to know this stuff.
But if you want to learn how to think,
it's valuable to be forced
to hold different ideas in
your head at the same time.
It's really teaching you not to be an
absolutist straight teaching you the
example he uses his,
cause he was,
I think he has had problems with McCarthy
and all those things. Didn't he say,
you think he's still, he's writing in
the 50s. So he said you can either be,
you can be a communist,
which in his definition would be that
you think the needs of the many outweigh
the needs of the few. Right. So say
society is all that matters. Oh,
it could be a libertarian or right on
the far conservative and where you think
that the individual is the only
thing that matters then that's it.
But actually of course,
to have a function in society,
you need a mixture of the two and
we can wait it one way or the other,
but you need to hold both ideas in
your head at the same time. And that's,
he said that one of the most valuable
things about science because it forces you
into modes of thought that are valuable.
And that's what we're talking about here,
which is one of the absolute
positions are always, uh, uh,
uh, just uh, a blinkered sort of
subsets of what's actually happening.
You can't understand the world
by being an extremist. Yeah.
You got to hold all
these views in your head.
Well that I find that so often on this
podcast because I talk with people I
agree with and disagree with and I always
try to put myself in the head of the
person that I disagree with.
I will always try to figure out how
they're coming to those conclusions are
where they're coming from.
Yeah. And I think it's so,
it's so important to
not be married to ideas.
I got a conversation with
someone about this and they said,
sometimes you change your opinions
a lot. I go, yeah, I do. I do.
Because if he's a bad thing, I'm
flip flopping. I'm not a politician.
Like I'm not flip flopping. I'm thinking,
yeah, I'm not sure. I'm not sure. Like I,
I will have one opinion on a thing,
whether it's a controversial thing,
like universal basic income. I'll change
my mind 100% in two weeks. Yeah. I'll go,
no, no, no, no. Now I think
it's probably a good idea. Yeah.
And then I'll go back and
forth. No, no, no, no, no.
People need about eight to his cruise.
It seems they need motivation. They need.
And I don't know, I bounce
around with these things. Yeah.
But I've tried really hard as I've gotten
older to have less absolute opinions.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh, Richard Fineman,
another great physicist or a similar
essay at a similar time to Oppenheimer.
And he also worked on the
Manhattan project and it's
called the value of science.
And I think that was 1955 and
they both shared actually, uh, uh,
a surprise.
I think that they were still alive
because they thought that the power they'd
given to the politicians,
the atom bomb would destroy everything.
They didn't think that the political
system would control it. And he did.
So that's an emerging malleable thing.
Yeah, we're still here. But in, in,
in that essay, he said the, um, the, the,
the most valuable thing about science
is the realization that we don't know.
And he said,
he said in that statement equals signs
a satisfactory philosophy of ignorance,
by the way. And he said in that statement
is the open door, the open channel,
he called it.
So if we want to make progress,
we have to understand that
we don't know everything.
And we have to leave things to future
generations and we can be uncertain and we
can change our minds. And he said that
that's, that is a great last line.
I can't exactly what he says,
but he said it's something like it's our
duty as scientists to communicate value
of uncertainty and the value of freedom
of thoughts to all future generations.
That's the point.
That's what freedom of thought means.
Freedom of thought means the freedom
to change your mind. In fact said.
That's what democracy is.
If you think about it,
democracy is a trial and error system.
So it's the,
it's the admission that we don't know
how to do. It therefore will change.
Every four years will change the president
or every eight years will change the
president. Why? Because the president
who doesn't know how to do it.
So someone that's there will be someone
better that comes along and then someone
worse and someone better,
but it's a trial and error system and
he's right and it is right that that is
the open door.
That's the,
that's the road to progress is
certainly better than humility. Yeah.
One of the things that I love so much
about Bertrand Russell and about Fineman
was how human they were. There were
very human mean fireman, like the play,
the bongos and chasing girls. And
Bertrand Russell was addicted to tobacco.
He would talk about how he
wouldn't fly unless he could smoke.
Like he had to get us was back when they
had smoking sections on airplanes and
he had his pipe and he just
refused to fly without tobacco.
He couldn't imagine being without tobacco.
And like that's so strange for the Joe,
a brilliant guide to be addicted to such
a gross thing. Yeah, you're, you're right.
Because I think these, these are
people that found existence joyous.
Right? They wanted to know,
they just wanted to know stuff.
They didn't want to know
everything because you can't
know everything. Right. Um,
you know that I'm,
I suppose that's what you think about
what the job of a scientist is. It's to,
it's to stand on the edge of the known
because you're a research scientist.
So if there's nothing to know,
then you've got no job. Right.
So you have to be naturally
comfortable with not knowing. And I,
if there's one thing I
really do think we was,
how do we begin to patch our
countries back off again?
One of the reasons I think in education
is to teach people the value of
uncertainty,
of not knowing it is not weak to not know.
It's actually natural not to know.
And that's one the problem
is with religion is to say
that you know when you do
not, or to say that you have absolute
truth and absolute knowledge of something.
Yeah. When it can't really exist. Yeah.