Clinical trials. Yeah, just in
clinical. That's right. That's right.
Now wasn't there a Lyme disease vaccine?
But the problem was it was actually
causing people to get Lyme disease.
So that's a talk about
controversial topics.
So there was a Lyme disease
vaccine that was developed, uh,
actually from a colleague of mine
at Yale University than it was,
and they licensed it,
I think it was to Glaxo Smith
Kline and they developed it as a,
they called it lime rex. It was
a, the Lyme disease vaccine.
And actually most of the studies suggest
that actually worked pretty well. Uh,
the problem was there were a number of
people who felt that the vaccine made
them worse, or they said they had chronic
Lyme disease, that it wasn't effective.
So it was really a market perception
problem more than anything else.
And ultimately, uh, it hurt the
bottom line of the company and they,
they withdrew it from the market.
Friend of Mine's Dad got the
vaccine and then got Lyme disease.
They think he got Lyme disease
from the vaccine. Probably not.
Probably is a weird word. When someone
with Lyme disease that's being nice. No,
he didn't get Lyme disease.
Impossible. Impossible.
Cause Lyme disease is
caused by the Lyme bacteria,
the spiral [inaudible]
called Barellia Burgdorferi.
And the vaccine is not a live vaccine.
It's a recombinant protein based vaccine.
So it's not.
So there's nothing in that vaccine that
could've caused this adverse reaction
that they directly attribute
to that vaccine? Probably not.
That's what you're saying. Well I
don't know the patient. I don't,
I haven't examined the intimacy.
I hate taste swear.
I mean that's the narrative
that household, well again,
you know what's reinforced by a lot of
negative information out there on the
Internet. It's also reinforced by the
fact they pulled the vaccine. Yup.
Well they pulled the vaccine
not because it wasn't working,
but because of market perception
and and all that sort of,
and that was a time before the number of
cases of Lyme disease have really taken
off. So strange to me because they
didn't pull the measles, mumps,
rubella vaccine because of perception.
Why would they pull the Lyme disease
vaccine? Because of perception.
I think the reason was
is because, um, the,
the cost benefit equation works a
little differently. Um, with measles.
Measles is a killer disease.
Lyme disease was not a killer disease.
And people now in some
cases it seems to be, uh,
connected to a host of other ailments
to correct like Lyme disease.
It just exacerbates a
bunch of different maybe,
possibly even existing health
issues. Well, you have to
be careful, you know, the,
the, and this gets into another
controversial rabbit hole.
I'm not sure we want to get into
or not today, but, um, you know,
the Infectious Disease Society
of America for instance,
has come out with a strong
statement saying that there's
really no such thing as
chronic Lyme disease. And, um,
the scientific evidence does not support
something called chronic Lyme disease.
Yet there are lots of people suffering
with chronic debilitating illness who
claimed that it's caused by Lyme
disease. So this is something that, um,
is out there right now. Why is
there a debate like what is, what,
why are they saying that there is no
such thing as chronic Lyme disease?
What's their evidence?
The evidence is that there's no evidence
that they can detect spiral Keats in
the body in many cases, uh, uh,
people who have had Lyme disease don't
have persistent evidence of having a
antibodies any longer to,
to the [inaudible]. So, um,
it's a whole different area,
right?
But they do have this chronic inflammation
and pain in their joints. They have,
somebody starts breaking down,
they have something,
but it doesn't seem to the Infectious
Disease Society of America, uh,
which is one of the leading infectious
disease bodies and our country.
And I'm not an expert on Lyme disease,
so I'm not too comfortable going there
with you are saying that there's no
evidence that,
uh,
that that's actually associated with
active infection with Lyme disease.
And what are they, how are they
describing it and what, how are they,
so in other words, we'll, so
what's causing all the decent
unknown unknown. I know,
but isn't it bizarre that these
same people got Lyme disease first?
And then how about these host
of issues afterwards? Well, the,
I guess part of the problem is in some
cases they had Lyme disease first.
And in some cases they really didn't
have Lyme disease. Unfortunately,
there are a number of
unscrupulous healthcare
providers and even physicians out
there that are making the misdiagnosis.
Either they're making a misdiagnosis
of Lyme disease, or in some cases,
they're actually taking everyone who
comes through the door and diagnosing them
with Lyme disease. I'm sure you're
aware of the lone star tick,
the allergy to red meat. Yeah.
Right. That's really fascinating.