That. I'm a fan of that one.
I'm not a fan of investment.
What I have a question about is,
is there a some buddy in charge of what,
what's permissible and what's
not according to a certain
code of conduct and do
they have a political
agenda? So in other words,
so if I put out something
that has profanity or maybe
I'll stand up clip where I
want to get people in, it's,
it's a clip that is offensive to said
person touched possibilities. Yeah,
they can go, Nope, we're stopping them
from doing that. But see with the,
with the dudes with their
shirts off flex and shit,
when they're trying to get clients,
that's fine. And they can promote,
reach other people outside their
followers is what it should be.
But if you have 100,000 followers,
it should reach all 100,000 then
that's what's crazy to me. Yeah.
They're going to lose everybody.
There's going to be a new Instagram.
If they started doing that shit and it
gets out of hand, people just leave.
Well there's, you know, it's
shadow banning is right. No,
there's a concept of shadow banning and
I don't know if this is Jamie would be
able to speak to this better than me.
Is that ever been proved that they
actually do shadow banned people?
What's that? Or is that it's they
[inaudible] is that if you say we're on
Twitter and maybe you were conservative
and you said a lot of rude things about
liberals that maybe they would decide
that although it doesn't violate the
terms of service, what you do is, uh,
makes them uncomfortable.
They make a moral judgment and they
decide to limit your engagement talking
about, yeah, this is somehow
possible. This is possible.
But is that like a hater?
It's all in what you're saying
with the paying of of post two.
It happens similarly there too. If
you were an account that never paid.
Yeah. And once you pay, once
you give him five bucks, you're,
you're like flag now as an account that
will pay and change your engagement.
Twitter, it's Twitter. You
don't across the board. Yeah.
You can pay on Twitter too. How do you
pay on Twitter? Do you pay on Twitter?
You don't have to, but there's an
option. You can pay promoted tweets.
It's a promoted tweet.
The top trending topic for the
last year or two is a paid,
it says paid or promoted. Really? Yeah.
You just had to go into it
because they get money now.
That's how they're called. Who's been
banned from Twitter? A lot of people, man,
he fucking is the most famous [inaudible]
Benjamin's been banned from Twitter.
He has and more conservatives are
conservatives, but liberals I've been to,
there's liberals that have put out
death threats. They'd been banned,
but in general they should be lopsided.
I don't know. That's a good question.
We should find out what is the,
what is the press should be banned being
banned. That's a good question too.
Is it to incite violence or is it
the violate the terms of service and
definitely if you incite
violence, that's definitely a no,
no racial slurs or no-no racist.
You can call someone a fuckhead.
You can call someone a fuck head,
but you can't call him like a
Guinea fuck head. There's like,
there's certain things you can say
and certain things you can't say,
but it's a lot of it's, yeah. But then
some of it's pretty black and white.
Like if you're like, man, I want to
go socia blow up that fucking school.
Fuck those kids. Of course, the
racist stuff. Yeah. Yes. All of that.
I think you gotta regulate the hate too.
If it's just bullying and shit like
that. We just ban them. Well, it's like,
here's the question and this
is who gets to decide who,
what's hateful and what's not.
And then the problem is they keep pushing
it further and further and further and
then even just insults or hateful,
even even like this guy is a dumb ass.
Yeah. That's hateful. Saying
someone's a dumb ass. It's hateful.
I mean they're going to,
there's only so far you can,
you could keep going
down that road. Right?
You want to make sure that you have
free expression and you don't get free
expression.
If you ban people from saying things
that just don't seem that bad to me.
Well, I mean Alex Jones, you think a
Hispanic, I'd like to see what he says.
Sandy hook stuff. Sandy. But see, but
here's the thing. Getting sued for that.
Anyway, here's the thing. Yeah. He
was already getting sued for that.
Like what did he say that got him?
I think something happened that he did
had nothing to do with even what he said.
He confronted them at some events. Right?
And he was yelling in the back and that
happened after he confronted people in
Congress. Well, he's got a,
Alex Jones has a regular
on a former CIA officer,
dr Steve [inaudible]. He has him
on like once every six months.
That's where he got the Sandy
hook information was from him.
That dude is on video as a
CIA guy know about Sandy hook.
The fuck would he know that's a dumbest
fucking thing that Alex Jones has ever
done. It's also a moral, and
there's parents who said,
fuck dr Steve [inaudible],
second guy fucks whatever.
If he said it didn't
fuck [inaudible] yeah.
You have to always wonder
and you would you, I mean,
I'm not making any accusations,
but you'd have to always wonder
when you hear a story like that,
why would someone say
something so ridiculous?
And why would someone try to convince
someone like Alex Jones of something so
ridiculous? And I think there'd be
two reasons. One to discredit Jones.
If you could talk him into
repeating what you said,
if you think he's willing
to do, that's interesting.
You can easily discredit him and it
would be a really good way to do it.
Like the best way to do it. Okay.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Whether he's right or wrong,
whether he's right or wrong,
doctors deep paternics said it
several times on the show, so,
but he's not Alex for Alex to believe
him. No, it started like this,
that crazy Eddie,
he's hearing it from a guy who
was in the CIA started like this.
It started out crazy for him to
believe in a guy from, you know,
he may or may not be right, but it
started with Alex actually saying, uh, uh,
he said, unfortunately he goes
something to the effect of I saw it,
it was very sad. And then,
but unfortunately I've seen a lot of
soap operas and I've seen a lot of and,
and,
and I know an actor when I see one and
that's where it started with him and he's
being, you know, he's being sued
by Connecticut. He's in trouble,
be a good acting coach.
But remember he knows an actor
[inaudible] in court and they said,
what the fuck? Basically what the
fuck are you doing? He goes, listen,
I say a lot of things just
for entertaining of course.
Like it's just for the during,
is that his trial with his wife?
He did admit, he's like,
I don't believe it.
A lot of that I just say
he's got a business. Yeah.
Well that's the thing about
all a lot of nutrition people,
a lot of these people is you make
money. You make money in this,
in this business. And
whether, whatever it is,
whether it's being a political pundit,
whether it's being attainment
or an exercise guy, you
make money having answers.
If you're somebody who's more scientific
and says, I dunno, it depends.
Maybe you're not going to make money.
When you say bone broth cures cancer,
you're going to sell
books. When you say, uh,
my plant based diet is proven to
do blah, blah, blah, whatever,
you're going to make money.
If you say, I'm going to,
I'll help you lose weight and keep
it off in four month, take my money.
You're not going to say,
Hey, I'm a nutritionist guy.
It's going to take you two years.
We're going to try to change it.
If you gonna have bounce backs, you're
gonna have plateaus and being realistic.
Yeah, nobody's going to buy that shit.
This you Dawn guy has gotten a
movement man. So, but with, uh,
with Alex Jones, is he banned for life
or I don't know how a business, well,
I mean, he still has his website.
He's got a big lawsuit
he's got to worry about,
but it shows they got rid of his show
happen all the farmers and shit. No,
the only thing that happened is they
pulled him off of YouTube and they pulled
him off at Twitter and Facebook to an
iTunes and he's got a major lawsuit with a
law firm that doesn't compromise.
There's tears. There's two guys,
there's two guys that are being sued over
that. Uh, Alex Jones and a guy named,
uh, Wolf gang Helbig. He's
also, he's also being sued.
That guy, his job was to
prepare schools for, uh,
school shootings. So he came out and
he started saying that too. So he's,
he's breaking apart. He started
saying that San Diego, he's getting,
he's getting sued along with
Alex Jones. Oh my God. Well,
but they didn't show up for when you
went to court. They'd never showed up.
So they dropped the case. What
about one thing about that law law?
It's kind of weird now
that they're, they have,
why would Sandy hook be fake? Let's not
talk about this stuff. Oh, I don't know.
I find it fascinating. Well, like why
in the world would it be fake though be,
I know you get rid up like
what's the conspiracy?
Zero zero thoughts that that is fake.
But I do have thoughts on why someone
would try to get other people to say it's
fake. And this if there's any,
if there's anything that's ever going
to convince you that conspiracy theories
are stupid, it's making
up a fake conspiracy,
an easily provable fake conspiracy
about a real tragedy. That's a nice,
simple psychological
way to discredit people.
If I thought you were a dumb
ass but you had a big voice,
I might talk you into saying some shit
about something that's not real and have
you convinced it's real. So you spout
it out, you look like a moron, right?
And that discredits
everything else you said.
And you have to be really careful
with a lot of these stories.
There's a lot of these,
these conspiracy theories that
literally start out a joke.
They start out in four Chan and a lot
of these chat rooms as trolls and then
before you know it,
it becomes a real thing that's said
over and over and so said over and over
again and then morons get ahold
of. But [inaudible] true, right?
Like he's a smart, we can all
agree he's a, I don't agree.
What do you mean you don't think he's,
I don't know to do what he's doing.
Listen, I don't ever talk
about stuff [inaudible] no, no.
You would not say he's a dumb person.
I don't know. I, I can't speak.
Pretty articulate. Yeah. He's
not stupid. Like I'm very,
very sad that he said that Sandy
hook isn't real. I fuck with him.
But I always enjoy being around that guy.
You would say he's articulate smart
guy. Right? He's a fun guy too. Yeah.
So I'm just saying for him to,
it's not like you can just honey
Dick and be like, dude, Sandy hook.
Like it would have to be something.
He loves conspiracies, man. You know,
he really does.
And this is the problem with someone
who likes hunts out conspiracies.
You're going to love them, you're
going to, you're gonna look for them.
[inaudible] numerology and the
Bible. You can find any pattern.
This is the problem is when you have
a vested interest in them being real,
when it's your business, because
there are a lot of them that are real.
So the problem is if you have a vested
interest in them being real and you
exclude information that would point
to them not being real and you use
confirmation bias and you fuck up and
then you try to convince other people that
you're correct. This is
something that people will fall.
[inaudible] I'd love to hear you on.
You're super quiet about all this,
but if you're a conspiracy theory,
which ones have been proven correct?
That many, right? There's plenty.
Absolutely. There's big ones like Enron,
you know, there's big ones. There's
big ones. You know, there's uh,
many documentaries and books have
been written on the Enron conspiracy.
These guys got together and they figured
out how to make a kajillion dollars and
fuck people over. And it was a, it was,
it was breaking the law and
they knew it was breaking law.
They conspire to do it and by names
and phone so you can take, take them.
There's wise people to think the 2008
hires, housing crisis, that that was the,
that was all on purpose. These guys built
this bubble up and it's proven though.
It's not proven. It's not
proven. The housing bubble was,
there've been great books written
on it by Michael Lewis, his book,
the big shorts, a good book
on it. But they, you know,
there's been a lot of research on that.
Too many bank. Is there any proven ones?
But it all, it all depends. Bread
and despise again. No, no, no, no,
no. And he knows his shit. It all depends
on how much circumstantial evidence
makes you throw up some red flags.
Like some people they just don't
see the red flags and some people,
their red flags go up right
away. So it all depends.
Like when you say is there any
proof? Well, um, you don't need,
uh, I mean at,
at a certain point when you
have circumstantial evidence,
at a certain point it adds
up. You know, you know,
if I'm one of case,
pretty suspect JFK suspect is super,
there's no look Jeff K's a
perfect example, right? Yeah.
There's no actual proof of the
conspiracy that there was a, you know,
multiple shooters or the CIA and
the mob. There's no actual proof.
But there's a lot of circumstantial
evidence. Well not all depends on,
it all depends on how much circumstantial
evidence do you need for any
particular conspiracy theory
where you go, Oh shit,
there's enough circumstantial evidence.
Like if there was a murder, right,
and you were being accused and
only one person said, you know,
I saw Brendan like four blocks away
from the restaurant where his friend was
killed. If just that one person saw it.
That's one piece of
circumstantial evidence. That's
not enough to convict you.
But if a hundred people said they saw
you two blocks away in the parking lot,
none of it alone, none of it
standing alone will put you in jail.
But at a certain point, enough
circumstantial evidence,
we'll put dudes in jail or if enough
people tell the same story about you with
Cosby, it was the same
story over and over.
It's like not all these women can't be,
they're all telling the exact same
story about the same MOU. Well,
not only that,
Cosby had gone to court and had a lawsuit
sealed and paid her woman off. Right.
I get it already had been to
a deposition so that, yeah,
so this was a part of the whole thing
was that he had to come out and uh,
you know, the,
the headed defend that in his most
recent trailer bill Clinton too.
I just got done watching those
Monica Lewinsky tapes. Yeah.
Bill Quinn was a freak. Oh yeah. Dude.
Do you know that the only problem
with like being, but like,
it sounded like Alex Jones who makes a
lot of money off his conspiracies and
things, is that if once he says something,
I know a pretty good fan of his Alex.
And, um,
what the problem is once you say something
and you have that big of a following,
right. So let's just say
you float out of conspiracy,
but then you look at evidence and you
start to realize maybe I overstepped my
boss, we all say things we wish
we hadn't, or we all say things,
but now you've got a whole movement behind
what you said now to try to pull back
with turn that 25% of the whoever it is
against you and that can be a liability
too.
So one of the things about being a public
figure is you can say something and if
you're selling product and selling
your show on you better be all in.
You better stay all that.
So you become a prisoner to your own
kind of first impulse or your own first
sort of like no matter how Atlanta,
especially if he's also an entertainer,
it's also this rush to say you'd know
something when you don't know it is a rush
to say there's a rush to say we
absolutely know this happened.
We absolutely know that happened cause
[inaudible] to get it from
somewhere. He has his sources.
What gets probably got information
on on the, on these, you know,
these tragic events or
something like that,
or you don't think there'll
be looking at Brandon? Listen,
I think he has some people in trouble.
No, I'm not. Don't take your bait,
Eddie. He's floating the
fucking huge worm out.
[inaudible]
come on this show and try not to
talk about conspiracy theories,
but I always get sucked back into
them. I always get sucked back to
that, where I'm not, but look, look,
he's there. Legit question. I don't know.
You're asking super
crazy, legit questions.