Um, my thought is I'm in negotiation
or in discussions right now,
and I talked to you about this too,
about building an APP and what I want to
do with the APP is have a set amount of
money that you pay per month.
If you want to sign up for the APP and
you get the podcast with no ads, right?
So you could either get it from iTunes
or whatever you Google play or Google
podcast or you can get it from the APP.
And if you get it from the APP,
you pay x amount per month and you get
the podcast with zero ads and it'll
stream live. I'm going to figure out
how to, when to do both of those things.
My thought going into advertising when
I first, when I first did the podcast,
I've been doing the podcast now for nine
years and when I first started doing it,
there was no ads for the longest time.
It just costs money.
It costs money to for bandwidth,
it costs money to put it.
But I was doing it for fun and
I didn't care and I had my life,
my revenue was coming from other
sources. Um, a few years ago, uh,
I decided what I was going to
do was cause it was getting ad.
The first ad requests was the
Facebook was a the fleshlight rather.
And you were the first person to request,
I killed them to not have the
flashlight on your podcast.
The first podcast that
we did can prima Donna
allows it made sense. I mean they
were disgusting. ADDS to, I mean we,
we would get ridiculous and, and
be really silly. And those ads,
it was just the juxtaposition.
I just,
just knowing that the Mike
would go hot and then, you know,
15 seconds before he was still
be ringing in their ears.
If you want to jack off
with this fantastic device,
here's Sam Harris neuroscientists,
but moral philosopher,
the fleshlight experience,
some pretty significant
positive impact from that.
I mean their business went through the
roof because of the podcast. I mean,
they're really sold a shit load of
flashlights where they told me like some
ungodly number, like 50% of
the flashlights they were
selling was codeword Rogan.
I don't want a picture too much of the
armies of people using their product,
you know,
so word got around and then as the
podcast space started expanding,
then advertisers tentatively we're dipping
their toe in my philosophy and it's
still holds like 2006 or seven or Jamie,
it's 2012. I wasn't, the
first time I was on here,
it was 2011.
Wow.
[inaudible] nine 10 was all right.
You were probably on before. Yeah,
you're probably on around 2010 or 11.
There was no other ads other
than the flashlight with you. Um,
and then the fleshlight dropped off
when we started asking for more money.
They are like, oh, I think we
hit the point of no return.
But my philosophy getting
into advertisement was, uh,
I'm going to do whatever the fuck I
want to do 100% and have no impact
whatsoever on the content of my podcasts.
Like whatever advertisers that I
choose, whatever advertisers that, uh,
I make deals with,
they have to understand that there's
no way I'm changing the content of the
podcast. And if I lose them,
I lose them. I don't care.
And that was the thought process going in.
So I never hit up a snag like this
cash App Jack Dorsey thing before where
people think that the reason why I was
easy with him was because of the fact
that he sponsors the podcast. It's
a very obvious conflict of interest,
but I, but people have to realize that
if they churn out off your podcast,
you've got just an endless number of
advertisers waiting in the cash out.
Not a very logical opponent is just
one way of looking at it that they,
they buy a lot of ads.
They do buy a lot of ads.
We do have a good relationship with them,
but I don't need them if they went away.
I have too many ads.
And that sounds gross to say,
but it is a fact.
I have many more ads than
I have spots for ads.
So if they went away would not hurt me
at all financially because I put a limit
on how many ads I do per podcast.
I also don't ever interrupt a podcast
with an ad. I don't do that. Right.
And because I don't do that,
that costs me money.
But I just feel like the experience of
listening to a podcast unbroken is so
much better than listening to a podcast.
We'll be right back with this
word from Casper mattresses.
You know it just feels gross. But
in the beginning I'm like, look,
you know where it is, you can fast
forward but maybe you're into this stuff.
Maybe you need stamps.com may,
maybe whatever the fuck you need the,
those are the ads.
They pay a lot of money.
I'm going to take that money and I'm
going to do whatever the fuck I want.
And if these guys decide,
oh you smoke pot or you're
too controversial or you
talk about this or talk
about that, we're going to drop you. Okay.
That's my philosophy and I've lost
ads. I've lost sponsors. Okay,
I don't care. But if I lost the
cash APP cause it was too hot,
hard on Jack Dorsey or Jack Dorsey
comes back and I'm too hard on him in
grilling him about these people that
have been censored. I hope he doesn't,
but I like him. He's nice guy. I want to
know what the fuck's going on there. I,
in fact,
I'm having Tim Pool come on tomorrow.
10 pools and investigative journalists,
independent journalist who was a,
used to be with vice and he knows a lot
about the censorship issue with youtube
or with a, with a Twitter rather. And
he knows about youtube as well, but uh,
with whose censored and why, who
is removed, who's been d platform,
why they'd been d platform and where the
inconsistencies and you know, where, why,
why is it skewing so heavily,
right. Where the, the,
the people on the right are the ones
who are getting banned and the people on
the left are getting away with a lot
of crazy shit. So we're going to,
we're going to get into
the weeds with that.
And if the cash APP hears that and
they decided to drop me as a sponsor,
I don't care. I really don't care. This
is a major source of income for me,
but it's only one source is one of the
things that being a standup comedian,
working for the UFC and having a podcast
and then have a podcast with ads on
Youtube and, and having ads that
are on the regular podcast itself.
I'm free in a sense too.
I have plenty of money.
It's not whether or not I'm starving
or worry about paying my bills.
I'm free to do whatever I want to do.
Well also I should be
clear like I don't think,
because this can sound
totally sanctimonious and, and
it's not intended that way.
I don't think my scruples
around at reading it as on
my podcast apply to you or
Tim Ferriss or many other people.
I mean like Tim is the ultimate example.
Tim is somebody who's brand on some level
is what I'm gonna do is I'm going to
go out there and find the best
shit in the world, the best shirts,
the best workout equipment through us.
And I'm going to tell you about it.
So I want to know what Tim
has mount, right? So if Tim,
if Tim is reading an ad for something
that is totally brand convergent for him
and I think you're very much in a similar
situation if you're talking about on
it or whatever it is and it's your
own you own part of on it. Right?
So it's like I should also be clear that
I say no to a lot of ads that I don't
want. Like there was one, there was
a Uber for babysitting. I was like,
get the fuck out of here.
What are you crazy?
You actually said that got
recommended to me by somebody. But uh,
it sounds like it sounds, it sounds
like sounds like craigslist for babies.
It sounds like a disaster
waiting to happen.
There has a been a few that I've
said no to like quite a few.
Some of them that are just boring.
I'm like,
I'm not reading that are not selling that,
that's stupid.
But also you're a comic who can send
up ads. I mean, so like, I mean,
I think bill bird does this where he kind
of trashes the ad as he's reading it.
And because of that he lost nature box
cause he told people to go eat apples.
Really? He's like, go eat a
fucking apple. So it's, I mean,
that's totally like,
and that,
that's something that's a tool you have
in your wheel house that has a affects
down the list.
Like it's,
it's one reason why you can stream
live without really worrying about it.
And I, I feel, I can't like, so it's
like, I mean, at the end of the day,
like if things go completely haywire
on your podcast, you can say, listen,
I'm a fucking comic. What do I
know? Right. Like you can just,
you can just pull the rip
cord. Yes. And you're fine.
Right, right. I can't do that.
Right. Like, so like you
can't say I'm a moral I, yeah.
So I can't say that I say that
all the time. So I mean, I can,
and there's certain circumstances
where I should, but if like,
I should avoid those circumstances.
Right.