When you look at any other kind of car,
like if you buy a Chevy or
if you buy even a, you know,
a Porsche or something like that,
you can find these little mom
and pop fix it chops. Right?
You can find them all over the place.
Absolutely. All around. You know,
you go to a West hills, there's a bunch
of places that fixed cars, right? Hey,
did something wrong with my transmission?
Can you look at it? No problem.
They put it on the lift. They go, Oh,
you've got a leak here. You've got this.
He got that.
But the Tesla,
you're on your own son that's
either bring it to Tesla.
I know man or Nada and I get
it from their point of view.
They don't want a bunch of people monkey
around with their shit. Yeah. But,
but even like Mac,
like you can go to the genius store,
which is gross genius bar. Yeah.
Whatever the fuck that name.
And that's gross genius bar picture.
Let me see your Ikea tests.
That's a bit pompous.
Met some of them people that again are
not geniuses smarter than you, whatever.
So you can either go there or you can go
to these little mom and pop max doors.
Those do exist and they're not approved,
but they can fix your computer.
They get shit done, they get shit done.
So that's the goal for me. So, you know,
I'm starting my own shop. I'm showing
a shop called the electrified garage,
and that's like, Ooh, I like it.
Yeah. Not Bad. How's good name?
I got some swag for you too. Um, so,
and that's the biggest thing is because
there's no mom and pop shop to fix
Teslas. Right? Like right now
it's the only game in town.
They're pumping out what,
like 5,000 cars a week now I photos a
week. Right. Which doesn't seem like much,
but for a small company, it's insane.
That's a lot. And he's got a day.
It's 30 days. It's a lie. It's like,
what, 20 20,000 a month? I don't know,
5,000 a week. Oh, heck yeah. It was like
20,000 a month or so. Geez. About that.
So, um, and then all of these thousand
cars is a lot. It's a lot of cars. Right?
That's a lot of fricking cars.
I think they're too busy.
So it's social right now.
You know, there's only two places
to fix tussles in my state.
So when someone's like, Hey, I want
to get my car fixed, you called test.
So they're like, yeah, that'll
be about, you know, maybe a week.
I get you in like every two weeks.
Oh, you get you in in a week. Yeah.
Get you in a week, maybe two
weeks, sometimes three weeks,
sometimes a month. Yeah.
People weight loss,
man. So that's the goal.
So I'm opening it up and it should be
open department of about a month or so,
and then we'll drive people there.