We really do need to get back to
some kind of productive discussion,
productive politics where the far right
disowned near lunatics and we disown are
lunatics and we get back to work
about whatever the ocean's plastic,
whatever it is that we're talking about,
because right now the
discourse is corrupted it.
We're not doing what we
need to do in the academies.
These people are continuing to pump out
this nonsense that's totally untethered
to reality. It's a huge problem.
I'm sick of it. You're sick of it.
We're all sick and we're sick
of, I'm sick of it. I've had it.
I've had it with these folks.
It just doesn't seem,
it doesn't seem like it's
sustainable. It's it. It's,
it seems like some weird,
it's going to run out of energy towards
eating itself constantly eats itself
like we did.
The thing about the people of color and
the black indigenous people of color
that they fragmented.
You see when you get into the critical
race literature that it's like, okay,
so you're brown or you're black,
but you have slightly lighter skin,
slightly darker skin, slightly
darker than that. Really dark.
They have different levels of privilege
and it's just cutting things apart.
The idea though that this is going to
create some kind of a coalition that can
then defeat, you know, the plurality
or something like that is ridiculous.
So what do you see?
You see this stuff's starting to blow up.
You see the Democrats bleed seats,
they've lost like a thousand legislative
seats across the u s since Obama got
elected in Oh eight how are you going
to get your agenda if you don't have any
legislators, if you don't have anybody
elected. And so then what happens?
2016 I can't say that the
reason that Trump got elected,
because there's lots of reasons
it had something to do. No,
I will say I had something to do with
this because every conservative person I
know that's not just a reactionary is
like, and I live in the south east man.
I know some conservatives,
most of my friends are conservatives,
cause I don't have a choice if I,
if I want to have friends that they're
going to be conservatives who lives there.
So I talked to them and they're like,
Oh yeah,
they're tearing down this kind
of statue. Oh yeah. It's tough.
And it's not like they're tearing down
confederate statues are talking 10 on
Thomas Jefferson. You know?
It's like there. George
Washington, George Washington.
Halloween's a problem. Then I didn't
know. You didn't know how his problem,
what are you going as for Halloween?
I'm a shark. You're a shark.
My kids are mermaids.
My problematic. Oh God.
If they're mermaids and you're a shark,
you're definitely taking like a
dominant and power position. Power.
They pick my outfit. I don't
pick my outfit. I have kids. Oh,
they tell me what I am. That's
an issue, but I don't know.
I'll try to figure out a paper for it.