The joe rogan experience
her though.
I think Jack Black was good and he's
got one of those Farrah Fawcett posters.
Gut check. I just look something up
weird. It's not, it's sort of related.
The Jurassic world.
Did you see that movie when it came
out a couple of years ago? Yeah.
It's the number three all time grossing.
Thank you.
Hey Fuck the godfather. Chris Pratt.
If you want archery lessons legitimate.
It does. I bet he does
legitimate. You know,
did you see that in Instagram posted he
put up of is a sheep or a lamb that he
killed.
He had put a bolt to a ted and you know,
and chopped it all up, but people
freak the fuck out. You didn't see it.
Did Chris Pratt Scott some balls.
I saw him post a picture of a rub in
on a tree. Oh, he hunts and he said,
uh, said something about trolls. Yo,
what's up Chris Pratt here now the 2018.
What's that?
This is like a rap rapping that
sounded like this. The new album.
No, Pratt rap. He um,
he does though. Go down.
That's not it.
There's a video where he shows the
lamb that he's actually taken apart.
This is hill in the video it says it.
Okay.
When I ate it all.
Well, no, there's what I
meant. Their photographs.
She's actually photographs
of the butchered lamb and
people lost their fucking
Shit, man. That's, that's not it.
There's actually like photographs of the
meat and like there's a roast and the
roast is there. It is, right.
The one in the middle. Yeah,
and this one gets a legitimate,
I don't know if that's
necessarily this glory land.
They came from his assuming honestly,
sounds like it says,
look at all this glorious food.
We will eat off him for a month.
His wools becoming yarn as we speak.
He lived a very good life.
He was groomed and shorn
his hooves medicated.
He wormed and no antibiotics necessary,
surrounded by laughing and loving humans,
including children to whom
they provided such joy nozzle,
pat and loved every day. No stressful
travel to his final destination.
Trauma free.
Just a touch of a u s d a certified
wan to his head and he goes to sleep.
The other sheep don't even notice.
It's like unplugging a TV.
Then Waka Waka, he's got a
butcher named Wacom. Wacom,
my Bush or Waka Flocka side job.
Then walkouts or wrapper.
It is definitely,
you're so white walking my white butcher,
we're not magic. You definitely want
right now the meat is for friends, family,
and gifts.
Soon though it may be available to my
followers as we test recipes and open up
to market. Oh my God. He's got
a murder animals for a living.
Got To get some things dialed in first,
including murder,
murder of sheep. Just kidding.
Like he is. I eat meat.
That's a glorious.
How get the balls in the sky.
When has a,
a list actor ever considered opening?
I agree.
A meat shop and showed a photo on his
Instagram of the honest procurement of
meat in an honest way. Did you see
that post I made today? No. W what?
Which one?
My, I have my airplane mode on so
I can't post it, but I think, um,
I made a post, uh, it was
a Google search that I did.
Okay.
There was 21 independent,
um,
legitimate scientists that found that if
you ate 50 grams of processed meat per
day,
your chance of cancer was 18% higher.
Holy Shit.
Just think of that number now is at
nitrites. What is it? What are the,
what are they thinking?
It's causing that, right.
Well, awesome. Yeah, that
part wasn't clearly defined,
but I would definitely think
it was preserved based, but
they don't really know though.
Right. They know it's processed meat.
It's really dangerous. Yeah. They
don't know what it is exactly.
But that's what's awesome
about how you and I hunt.
I posted it specifically to actually
some access backstraps from Hawaii last
year. Um, because I think,
I think it's maybe ignorant for people
to automatically make a post saying,
you know, you're a killer just because
you post a picture of, you know,
free range, organic meat that
you decided to choose a touch.
Um,
versus looking at it.
I know what you're saying,
but you got to look at it
from their perspective. I do.
Even if they're not right.
And there's no right here. The thing is
there's there, right? And you're right,
it's everybody's right. That's, that's
really what's fucked up about it.
Like an animal does have to
die, you know, that is a fact.
And that does bother people,
including you and me when it happens.
If people don't realize that, but
that is true. They don't. But the,
the understanding at the end of the day
is that this is the cycle of life and
this is what life is really all about.
So they're right in your right,
but this whole,
this expression of outrage,
like you should be expressing that
at Burger King. You should be,
and not Burger King. Just, you
know, I'm not singling them out.
Anybody that has fast food, which
I've eaten many times. Yeah.
If you want to live in a
society of 20 million people,
you're going to have to live in a place
most likely with this model where you've
got in and out Burger. And I like in and
out Burger. I like them. They taste good.
I go up there, we went there in
Vegas, they've got damn good. Right?
It's hard to beat.
So I don't necessarily hate those things,
but you have to understand what
all this really is. You know? It's,
the whole thing is crazy. You're
here for a very short period of time,
as are these animals,
all of us are trying to stay alive.
All of us are freaking out.
One of the things get eaten,
and we're all just going like, well, I
just want to be the best version of me.
I can be your right hand
there. Right? They just,
they haven't experienced what they,
they have decided that
an animal should not die.
There's no way an animal should
die so that they can live.
And if they can live that way,
that's their choice.
They're welcome to that choice.
They just don't understand
the merit of your choice.
[inaudible]
okay.