It says, belt are rigged it to protect
their investment. Ah, Paul daily.
You're a monster. When he's,
when he's on, he's a monster.
There's no man on the planet who,
I mean,
think about what he did to Lorens Larkin,
right?
Lorens Larkin is a really
tactical striker and Paul,
daily time he lands that fucking left hand
on you. You, you forget your childhood.
It's been fighting. He,
he's been disappointed.
He says MMA politics and Beltour
protecting their investment, uh,
fell one three rounds to, to my opinion,
I've beat that full, really close fight.
I can see how he thinks he went
three rounds. So like if they,
you have to daily Mikaila, fine. We
all lost the fans loss. But if you,
how he says three, I'm like, all
right, that's fine. I don't know. It's,
it was a bullshit fight
all the way around. It was,
it wasn't the best fight wasn't a
lot going on. Well, I've nothing,
nothing wasn't a bit cautious is,
and two blue belts grapple daily,
kept trying to gala daily,
took him down.
Then he lost position once an MVP
got on top of him and beat his ass,
got his back. I thought he was gonna
choke him out to the rear naked there for,
yeah.
I was amazed that Paul Daley was
able to take them down though,
and we really made some big
improvements in his wrestling. I mean,
I guess maybe felt like after the John
Fitch fight, if you can't beat them,
join them. What a great did. This
was a great fight, man. Yeah. Wow.