The Joe Rogan experience.
Yeah.
I don't have that confidence
to waste the audience's time.
Do you know what I mean? Like I like,
I'll see Chris rock. Yeah. Precisely.
A friend of mine and he'll go up and
you just like with nothing and just sit
there and the very comfortably
for 45 minutes and just, and just,
and just kind of talk and look for things
and has no problem with it whatsoever.
And I let it this. He'll go.
What else? What else? And
don't like stare at the sky.
Look at the ground. I can't, you know, who
was the master at that was Damon Wayans.
Oh my God.
Who a lot of people forgot a lot of
people forgot was one of the FEC and still
is one of the best comics ever.
Damon Damon was a goddamn murderer in
the nineties. Oh, I loved her coming up.
But I remember going to the Haha cafe.
Uh,
they would do it like a show every
Tuesday and my friends would run and Damon
Wayans would always drop in and
do an hour and ruin the show.
Like he would have no material.
And he would just attack people in the
crowd by the time he was off stage,
like the audience was
furious like they were,
they went crazy when he came out and
then by the end they were just like,
why is he doing this to us and be like,
we were like,
aw fuck Daymond Wayne's this year.
It was so funny.
Somebody like looked up to as a kid
and like loved you. Just like, aw man,
this asshole again. Wow. That's crazy. I
wonder why he was doing that. I believe.
I mean I guess it's probably cause he
couldn't do it at the store anymore. Yeah.
What, how, how many
years ago was this? God,
I mean at least at least 10 1213
years ago. See that puts it. That's,
that makes sense, right,
because that's around 2005 yeah,
that's like probably he
stopped going to the store.
The store probably tightened up the way
they used to because they used to just
let anybody just draw.
Like Eddie Griffin would drop in,
wasn't on the mic,
wasn't on the schedule.
He would drop in at 9:00 PM and get off
stage. At 3:00 AM and that was real.
Yeah. Yeah. That was real
six hours that would kill me.
And uh, and then when he was
done he'd be like, who's next?
Who's next to you? He didn't six hours.
What's the longest that you've ever done?
I think an hour and 40 minutes.
Maybe a little longer.
And I don't remember,
but I think an hour and 40 minutes
probably the longest I've ever done. Yeah.
Yeah. But that's too long. Too Long. Yeah.
An hour and 20 is more than anybody
should ever have to hear you talk. Yeah.
And even that, it's like pushing it
and what I like I like, I like to do,
when I do like a theater I two an hour
or an hour and 10 and I just want,
I just want to just start and then finish,
just come on,
go ready.
And then for one hour,
I want everything to be tight and concise.
And I would way rather have an hour and
10 minutes that people really enjoyed
versus an hour and a half where they're
like an hour of it was really funny
because then it leaves you with this even
if it's the same hour, that extra time.
And I also just think the audience
doesn't want to see more than an hour of
comedy. And it's like people were like,
oh I did three hours the other night.
Like why the audience must have hated it.
Like Chapelle used to drop into
the cellar, he and like Dane Cook,
we're going back and forth.
Like who could do the longer set?
Like ever world record. Right.
They have like world records. Yeah.
And then I think Bob Marley
eventually broken or something. Uh,
Bob Marley from Maine.
I didn't do like two days on stage and uh,
but Chapelle was down there
one time and I was like, Oh,
I'm gonna go check it out. And it
was like almost unwatchable. Yeah.
Cause it was like the pacing that they
have that you have to do in order to be
on stage dot long.
And he was funny but it would be like
not funny for long stretches then a big
punchline and then back into it.
You're like all right.
Like the show when Dave was on hiatus,
right.
That was when Dave kind of like took time
off a comedy for a long time. He can,
I mean kind of like he wasn't doing
specials but I think he was doing like
surprise shows. Like he was always,
always kind of on tour in weird venues.
He's still doing that now. It was not
always doing like big, big giant theaters.
So like he'll just want to book
like a 20 seat room and uh,
make his agents crazy.
Well he's been doing,
he's been doing the lab at the Improv,
that little tiny room, which is what,
50 50 seats maybe. Yeah, he
did it. A Zs did it. That's a,
that's a place where comedy dies.
That little fucked up room.
I have always hated that room. That
room sucks. Every deck on the planet.
When people are like, oh,
you can try new stuff.
It's like I can try the new stuff
in the main room for a good crowd.
Like why do I want to do
this little terrible room?
I don't know why it's even the,
well,
it's a weird one was because the belly
room is perfect. The belly room works.
Yeah, but some way, for some reason that
lab seems like why is their comedy here?
What is, why is the door right there? Why
is this treat right there? What is this?
Yeah. What is this here? What do you
got going on here? Everything about it.
It's bad.
Like I was trying to tell them,
I go and turn that into the comics screen
room like, no, there's good comedy.
Then I'm like, shut your
mouth. You shut your mouth.
You turn that into the comics cream room.
Yeah.
They used to be where the bar was from.
I know they used to be like where
everybody's hanging out before the show.
It was great.
It was great,
and he'd go in the other room to go on
stage and you would go from that part to
go on stage. Now everybody goes
from the front door to go on stage,
so you're trapped in that little hallway
and you're like, where are the fuck?
How do I, where do I hide? Yeah.
Yeah. There's nowhere to hide.
That's why I love the store so much
because there's so many places to hide.