Yeah. And I mean like I like
Tyron was man, there's a,
there's this thing too where you,
you get to a point where you have to,
you're the guy who has to provide,
you're the guy who has
to hold up and it's not,
not necessarily people saying
you have to do it or you,
you feel that sense of responsibility,
you know? And, and in, in my family I,
I felt that I feel that
sense of responsibility.
Like there's one that your family when
you were growing up. Yeah. And you know,
like I like when I say I
come from humble beginnings,
your like being raised in Nigeria like,
and it wasn't like the village
village where we lived in huts.
We had a house but it wasn't really,
we didn't have plumbing, you know,
we had to go to the well or get water.
We electricity was rare.
That's a scarce thing,
you know?
And it's where we,
even when we came here,
when we immigrated here
yet life got a lot better.
How old were you when you came here?
About eight years old and it was
hard to adjust to the school system,
you know, because kids
were kids. Kids are mean.
I haven't talked with the funny
accent and kids would tell you, hey,
why don't you say this to the
teachers? Hey, hey bitch, call her.
And I was always in the principal's office
because I had no idea what that means
and things like that. So the kids
are cruel. I had dealt with all that.
You know in English when you came here.
Yeah,
we spoke English but it pigeon English.
So we knew that in all were
colonized by the European.
So the English is the
word root of the words.
Root words aren't from the European.
So we knew English,
but it's just our take on it.
Uh,
and so how much different is pretty
different? It's very different.
Like if I was talking with another
Nigerian, I was speaking patient English,
you would pick out words,
but it's a little different.
But can you say something in pigeon
English? Yeah. And like I said, nothing.
I right now we just sit down here
just talking to you. You're not,
so she's down just to talk just
a [inaudible] not be any tea.
That's how I was. Cool. Yeah, it does.
It if like me and Israel out of Tonya was
talking like it, it'll be mad cool. Oh,
right, right, right. Like we speak it
to each other. So going from that to,
you know, be in essentially raised and,
and, and going through school. And,
and one thing that, um, man, I haven't, I
really haven't ever shared with anybody,
you know, very, very few people know,
is that my father has been incarcerated
since 2009 and this is the first time
really out, um, you know, ever
talked about it like my dad was,
um, it goes through a test to just
adjust the system here, man. It's so, so,
so crooked and it's so backwards. Yes,
of course. We're fortunate. Like, ah,
there's so many things that we're thankful
for living here in this country that,
you know,
you can sleep at night in your house and
not worry about somebody breaking in,
robbing and killing you,
you know, for the most part.
And to where and we're thankful for that.
We're thankful for the opportunities.
But my dad was a businessman and
my dad built one of that, uh,
uh, a very, very big business in Dallas.
The owned like an ambulance company and
you know,
it comes to a certain point where
people just don't want you to be your,
you're an immigrant and you're succeeding
in a certain business there where it's
kind of like people don't care about it.
People don't want you to be there.
And you know,
I was one of those situations who,
where my dad hired the people that he
thought were the right people to do what
he didn't know the job to run his company.
While he can tend to a certain things
like us, like his family day to day,
different things I cared about to where
they run the company into the ground and
not because my dad was
the owner of the company,
they put it all on him even though
the people that were doing, you know,
the things that were really wrong and
the company admitted to doing the wrong
things. But what the court is saying is
that, oh, because you own the company.
So ignorance is,
it's not an excuse.
So because of that we're going
to sentence you to 15 years.
So he got sentenced when
he didn't know crime.
It see the thing is the business again,
it, my dad owned the ambulance company.
An ambulance company.
Yes.
So it was a transportation for
emergency and non emergency. You know,
and one thing that he hired,
these are like the paramedics,
the EMS to run the company because these
people that, that know the business.
So he had people that he
hired from that acquired,
he acquired from a different company.
But you know,
one thing that I will say
is my dad's ignorance is,
is he didn't really do as research
well enough on the guys that he hired.
So you hire certain guys and now these
guys are running the business and these
guys are like, yeah, we're gonna make it.
We're going to help you
grow this business. Like any
business, man, fuck yeah,
I hired the right people. Yeah.
Help me grow the business.
So now they're helping. He's there
doing that. If he thinks, okay,
I trust these guys.
They're taking care of the business and
the the most disappointing heartbreak
and thinking about the
businesses. My Dad, they're not,
they're not the one who does the billing,
the billing for the business.
They contract a difference as an
outside company to do the billing.
So it's not them doing it.
So they're doing the runs,
they're sending the notes to them.
This is the runs we did to you guys build
the government or whoever else to pay
us. My Dad's the owner. He has people
that are doing all this. He's not,
they're running the day to day.
So eventually they go
under investigation on,
we're investigating like I think maybe
like 15 patients or something like that.
I don't know the exact number.
I have 15 patients we're investigating
for these runs or whatever that would
build this building on them.
And so they put it all in your
investigation and they're like, okay.
After a while they come back
and they said, all right,
we'll give you your stuff back.
Like, we didn't really see anything,
but we'll give you your stuff back after
they shut it down for a little while.
So damn, now I gotta go back.
So my dad's like, ah, fuck it.
I'm getting out of the business.
They already killed my business for me.
So now I became one of the biggest
company. But you shut down for so long,
you've lost in what you've worked for.
So now he's getting rid of and getting
out of it. Then they come back later,
few years later for the same
thing that you've already said.
You're good here to have your stuff
back. They come back and said, no, we're,
we're going to prosecute you for this.
So now those guys,
I, and I've, I've seen it. This is
obviously how the feds work now,
those guys that you caught,
the EMS and these guys that
were clearly did rose was wrong.
You gave them a deal and say,
hey,
we caught you guys because those guys
started their own company doing the same
shit. So they get caught. Now
they're like, okay, we want that guy.
So you guys basically gave
him a deal to say, okay,
that guy was in on it and my dad's life,
and I guess they offered my dad a deal,
a plea deal,
which his lawyer didn't really tell him
about because he had a court appointed,
a lawyer, a lawyer. So he said, no,
I didn't do shit wrong. Why would I
take that deal? Which would have been,
I think maybe like five years was
the deal or something like that.
What does I know? I didn't do shit
wrong. Why would I take five years?
So he goes to trial and broke.
We've seen murderers,
we've seen all these people that are
defraud the government and like start more
hedge fund guys. Billions of
dollars get bill. They said no,
they wouldn't even grant him bail.
My Dad's a citizen,
like turn over his passport and
everything. They said, Nope,
I'm not going to give you a bail.
We're going to hold.
You want to freeze all your accounts.
You can't really fight the case.
So you're stuck there and now
your family's left with nothing,
with nothing, no money
in the account, nothing.
And so my dad is deal with that and they
just threw the book at him and I'm like,
you know,
we'll give you 15 years.
And this was 2009 and he's
already been in for 10.
He hasn't been in for 10.
And one thing that
really killed me was um,
one thing, uh, it was a part,
a part in a trial where, um,
the lawyer would basically telling the
judge like, this guy's an upstanding guy.
No correct curd.
You know,
he has kids look at his kids
and how well they're doing.
His older son is in college.
The second one is in college.
The youngest is about to being in college.
These kids are all scholarships,
student athletes,
great student athletes.
And the one thing that killed
me was the prosecution was like,
the reason that is is because he was
defrauding the government from this money.
That's why they're in
college. And I was like, wait,
my dad is not paying for us to be in
college. We're all student athletes.
We earned these,
we worked hard earned scholarships
as far as to being college.
The defense didn't say that.
They even fucking say like,
you have a court appointed
attorney. I think he did. Yeah, Bro.
My Dad just got railroaded,
man. And it was like,
and it was so heartbreaking
to where you're telling them,
man that has raised his family,
raised his kids to, to work hard,
get to a place in life and you're telling
him that the only reason it's there is
because he cheated and it was just one
of those things that added a chip on my
shoulder at all, man. It,
there've been so many moments,
that attitude put chips on my
shoulder with everything that I like.
I've been through so much that I just
internalize and I compete with all this
energy and so two for that. You,
you telling my dad that? Yeah.
Like you're going to sit down and I just,
and,
and obviously of course I researched
more and more into that because I was so
heartbroken after that. Like money,
like you just going for what?
For how much you're saying not even up
to almost a million. They would, they,
they just piled a lot of money
on. They're like, oh, this,
this and that for a little over other
sane little over a million total,
which is nowhere near that.
You gave him 15 years when
these guys had fun guys that,
that you found guilty for manipulating
these markets for billions.
You give him six months house arrest if
that and you're saying you're going to
give him 15 years. And I
started researching, I'm like,
a lot of these judges have stakes in
these prisons and to what they do is they
give a lot of time because they
get paid per prisoner. That's,
and we know that story about that
guy and um, Pennsylvania who was, uh,
who was a judge and he was doing that.
He was sending kids to generally he was
extending their sentences and giving
them sentences for nothing.
And it turned out he had been getting
paid by the person to seek a lot of them
down the river.
Yeah,
I heard a lot of them get kickbacks
and different things from that.
And so to put people there,
as you become more and more famous,
you can shed more and more light on this.
Yeah, man, it's your dad do for parole,
man. I don't, I don't even know. I
think soon listen to this podcast alone.
You talking about this could very well
bring someone forward that wants to help
you with the appeal. Yup, man. And my
mom, my dad actually wrote, cause when,
don't know Obama administration,
there was that whole clemency
deal when they were doing.
And my dad actually wrote a letter,
actually have that later.
I don't know where I put it,
but he wrote a letter to him and it
was when I read the letter, man, I, uh,
I can help a cry about it
because my, my dad, um,
it's my dad cares about his family so
much and when I go see my dad because my
dad is so proud of me and I'm,
and I'm so proud of him. I mean,
he raised us so well and um,
to go see him in there.
And I mean,
it's not like he's sitting
in the maximum security,
but for someone to tell you that you
can't go home to your family at night for
[inaudible], you've got an ear, you've
got to sleep. When we told you to sleep,
we got it. You got to eat when
we you to eat for 10 years.
And when you know I didn't do anything
wrong because I chose to say no,
I didn't do anything wrong. I'm not
going to take this sentence you give me.
They say okay fine,
you're going to sit in there for 15 years
and there's nothing you can do about
it. As a man. It broke my heart man.
And then when I think about it some I
just hold the name cause I, you know,
I try not to cry about it,
which I'm just like screw it.
I've have different situations that
happen in life. I'm like, you know, but I,
I ate that one up on the shoulder.
I put that chip on his eye.
You know what they're going to say that
the reason I'm here that was scholarship
is because my dad, they're saying my
dad got money. A little bit of money.
Are you serious? What about the freaking
hard work that I did to get here?
What about all the Times that I sat in
a fricking hotbox my bathroom upstairs
with a trash bag on because I knew that
I needed to get a pound off the next day
in order to be able to wrestle at this
JV tournament. What about all that,
you know, that didn't make any
difference, you know, the reason,
the only reason it was
there is because of that.
What about all the times my brother ran,
worked hard to make national team when
he was playing soccer or my little
brother getting numerous scholarship for
a division one football everywhere like
that. What? So all that put a chip on my
shoulder, Joe, to where it was like, man,
I got to succeed at all costs. I
don't, I don't really care. And where,
where did this happen? Where was this
trial in Texas and Dallas, Texas.
Not the best place to have
the trial happen, but uh, uh,
it happened in an Amana and
put a sour taste in my mouth,
but um, cause he file an
appeal, um, and it follows them.
Peel one time they didn't even look at it,
man.
It was like one of those things where
it's like that judge, they put you there,
you're there. That was his domain.
They didn't even look at it like, hmm,
who care?
Cause I feel like you're using the system,
you're UFC welterweight champion.
But I think that they treated him like
that because you're an immigrant in the
system. Get in there and that's,
you know, and Joe led to wrap that,
put that on.
That's part of what this
next fight symbolizes to me
is the attitude that a lot
of people have towards immigrants as
people are forgetting that Americans or
immigrants from that conversation, the
last podcast. People are forgetting that.
Yeah.
And to where countries yet to where
people have this attitude towards we're
Americans. Go back to your country,
you know, you know, go back.
This is a free country. You
are this and that. People like,
I always heard that growing up,
I always heard that and I always I,
the more I research, I'm like, what? What
are you talking about? First of all, this,
this whole attitude when you walk
into a nail shop, get your hand, feet,
nails done. Who, the majority of the
people that run those nail shops, Asians,
I'm not saying all of them in the world,
in the country,
but the majority of them in Asians,
but there's a lot of people
that look down all of it. Like,
I'm not washing your feet. I'm not
going to do your nails. Nolan's people,
I take pride in that because that
provides for them in, they do that,
you know, but people, people condemn
it. That's not a job people want to do.
When you go to these
hotels and certain things,
who are the main people that are the maids
that clean up the hotels? A lot of um,
immigrants.
We take pride in them because now we're
in the country in a better place where
we can provide for families.
Those are jobs are a lot of people
so called Americans, the whole Colby,
Covington, whole persona
art. Like I'm above that.
I'm above that. That's the
persona. But then at the same time,
people now want to cry. All the here
taking our jobs. Let's build a wall.
Let's keep them out. They're taking
our job. No, they're providing,
they're helping this
country get to its height.
The fact that you could come here
and have someone do your nails,
so will clean your
house and wash your car.
Someone do all this for you is part
of what makes America so great.
One of the greatest nations in
the world and the fact that they,
we want to build a wall. You want to keep
these people out. You can't come here.
You can't bring your culture,
your stuff here.
It just saddens me and it upsets
me as part of what this fight,
when it happens is fight represents
for me because I feel like that's the
attitude that this young man has. He's
entitled to, I'm, I should be UFC champ.
You're soy boy.
You know you can't,
you don't want dessert or you can't
hang with me. Boy, that's his attitude.
You can't do this boy, first of all,
who's your boy? I'm a grown ass man.
Don't fucking talk to me like that.
And that's the attitude that he has.
I'm entitled to this. I mean, I should
be the champion because I am this way.
I'm American. I'm this. And Ah, Bro,
we're all American here.
And so this fight is greater than just,
Oh, me beating up a guy that's
talking a lot of shit. There's a,
there's this fight means a lot to me.
So when I get the chance to put my
hands on that guy, let's just know this,
the wrath of every immigrant that
I've stepped foot in this country.