The joe rogan experience,
right. Dude, I tell you,
I support all the trans rights
and everyone doing all this stuff.
The only thing that I ever go like that
doesn't seem right is with athletics.
Oh yeah.
That's the only thing where I feel like
it's not that I don't feel like someone
should be able to play
any sport and compete,
but like when a dude at transitions
to becoming a woman and I was like,
I play basketball now. It's like, come
on, man. Yeah. Like I get it. You're,
you, you have the right to
live your life and play.
But like you have all those skills that
you developed as a man and now you're
playing against frailer,
smaller, you know,
like that to say that like
you can't bring that up.
That that's offensive is ridiculous to me.
Well,
especially when it comes to fighting.
Fuck yeah, man. That was the big one.
And that was where I really understood
like how bizarre and defenses for that,
how cult like this,
this ideology is.
I'd like to see you transition to a
woman and fight women fun fucking to have
what, 12 murder charges. That would be the
fun part. It doesn't make any sense. No,
of course not.
The bone structure is so different and
people that deny that are fucking crazy.
I know. That's that. That is
silly man. What if, what if
I like transition, whatever.
Anyone a man and does a powerlifting,
well,
people have done that and they're winning
and breaking all these records they
are and why are we like,
why are we not stop and being like that
doesn't know that it doesn't cause we
want to save people's feeling.
Exactly and silly.
What's really fascinating is in the
process of being super progressive,
you you go towards the most
maligned part section of society,
which is like transgender people and
so everybody else who also has been
marginalized by society, like
women, women get put on a d,
they get put in a less protected
category then transgender women,
so a man becomes a more
protected class of woman.
Yeah. Then natural born woman herself.
That's very interesting. That's crazy.
That is. It's very true. Also, yeah,
it's crazy because all these women that
got beaten up by that man who became a
woman,
started fighting in MMA,
fought two women before ever disclosing
the fact that she used to be a man
because she said it was a medical
issue that had nothing to do with them,
which is just shows you how completely
insane the logic behind all this.
She's still fight this. She
hasn't in a while, but uh,
now everybody knows she lost
to a woman who she did. Yeah.
An actual woman who wound up, uh,
yeah. I said actual fuck off. Yeah.
People were like,
but that's,
why wouldn't you say, but that's
wild, right? That a woman beat.
She's not good. No, she's not good. She's
not a good fighter. No, she's just strong.
Yeah. Like there's nothing you, you
don't look at her and think like, oh,
she fights like Chris Cyborg or she
boxes like Claressa shields. No,
she's not that unbelievably talented.
She just physically way different.
Yeah. She's a fucking man. Some
man for 30 years had children.
This was when,
when I knew it was crazy.
I got in a conversation with someone
and online with this woman was like,
she's always been a man.
I go,
even when she got another woman pregnant
and had children with her and she goes,
yes. Even then she was a
woman. She was a woman.
She was a woman that fucked another
woman and got her pregnant. Okay.
Why just hang up. What? Yeah,
what are we doing? I know,
like this is so crazy. You've got
to tap out of those conversations.
And Bruce Jenner,
when he transitioned to Caitlyn Jenner
and then eventually got his, his surgery,
right. Or her surgery become, she
said even before the surgery though,
it didn't change anything. I
was always 100% a woman. Okay.
Then why get surgery?
Well,
it because you thinking that
gender is just with Genitalia,
that'd be a mistake. You
personally, what is it?
It's gender is not just genitals.
It's in your mind. Right.
So, so it's also, it's facial
reconstruction. Fucking stupid.
And I just let you know how dumb that was.
So what is the difference?
Someone said that, uh, there's
gender and then there's,
there's biological sex and that gender
is the operating system and biological
sex is the hardware.
I hundred percent agree.
It makes sense.
Outrage over transgender female
weightlifter who destroyed your rivals by
hoisting 19 kilograms
more than the runner up.
Now she's a contender for the Commonwealth
Games. Yeah. Yeah. Guess what?
Oh my God. Look at the size of her.
Fuck Laurel's it got damn gorilla.
So major international weightlifting
debut in Melbourne's about fun.
See the hounds more than the second place.
Yeah.
What in the fucking Holy Hell. Oh
my God. And look at the size of her.
Fuck.
Can you imagine if you're a biological
woman who's been training and working
hard all her life?
Yeah.
And then all of a sudden you have to
compete with this and you're like,
I'm first place like, and she's giant.
Like look at the size of her head.
Her formerly male head.
Yeah. That's a giant woman.
That's just the way to get metals.
Well, it's sandbagging. Yeah.
That's what a lot of it is. That's fucked
up, man. That is, that's what it is.
What a lot of it is, people don't
want to admit they're sandbagging.
If you don't know.
What it means is like you would get
that in martial arts tournaments,
like say you would have a tournament
and the tournament would be um,
like for blue belts only,
which was like one rank above white belt.
And then guys would be like a black belt
in judo and they would enter into the
blue belt division and dump everybody.
Right.
And so like I don't have a belt in that.
Right? Yeah. But he's sandbag and like,
you know what they're doing. Yeah. And
everybody knows what they're doing.
You see that shit and you,
you see there's,
there's a lot of that where people just
want to win and the way they can win is
by competing against people that
are not in their same level.
If you don't think that people do that
when they switch over from being a man
for 30 years and then competing as a
woman and not tell them and just start
smashing these women.
So obvious,
there's something in that that
you don't understand. Athletics,
you don't understand competition.
You don't understand sandbaggers and
you don't understand the kind of people
that wouldn't tell people about
that in the first place. Sure, yeah,
but they don't want to look
at it that way. They want to,
everything has to go through
the filter of being progressive,
so you have to err on the side
of being the most open minded,
the most liberal and the most progressive,
which I'm honored percent for.
If women want to fight a transgender
woman, if a woman wants to,
I think you should be able to ride bulls.
I think you should be able to skydive.
I think you should be able
to do fucking bungee jumping.
I think you should do a lot. You should
be able to do a lot of ridiculous,
crazy dangerous shit. You should
be able to do flips with BMX bikes.
Why shouldn't you be able to fight a man?
Yeah.
Why shouldn't you be able to
fight a transgender woman?
A woman who used to be a man. You
should be able to. If you're a man,
you're up for it. Yeah. If you're
a woman rather than you're 130 lbs.
You want to fight 130 pound
hundred percent, man. No,
no transgender, no nothing.
If you want to do that, you should
be out to, you should be allowed to.
I don't advise it.
I think it's a terrible idea for you.
You're going to get pummeled. Well,
if it's a good fighter, there's just,
what is this? What's going
on here? Bodybuilder. We
just tell him he Jens power,
the thing that the article says,
this person can't decide to compete as
a man or a woman and this is what they
look like. They can't decide whether
to compete as a man or a woman.
That's what he used to look like
on the left. Yeah. Fucking hey man.
Then oh my God,
it was super jacked and now
he is on the right and the Z,
but he looks like he's still
a man, says he hasn't, uh,
Trans Chan transitioned yet
still lives his life. Both.
He lives his life as both saying,
this is where you're seeing that there's
some of these fucking people that have
mental illness,
but there was an episode of radio lab
where this one guy who's also a girl,
um, switches back and
forth and under pressure.
He changes like he's Paul or rescinded
and this is what on what radio lab's
podcast and radio lab is so fucking left
wing and I love them. They're amazing,
but there's so left wing
and so progressive that they
are unwilling to note and,
and even even address the
proposed generous nature of
this fucking person who's
like, I just switched now. I'm Cindy
right now. Now I'm back to Paul.
Went back to Paul in the conversation
in the conversation like I just turned
over like, Oh, you did? Oh,
you're this special creature that
can just go back and forth and,
and switch genders or are you fucking
crazy? Paul Slash Cindy. Yeah.
We would never have violated
pages wishes in the story.
It's an unfortunate understanding.
What did what he did, he pulled up
there note and when they had to
change the whole story member,
they had to go back because they got mad
that they mis-gendered them and their
original
podcast, how they miss gender
if she goes back and forth.
They had to keep up at the moment.
So,
so they mis-gendered how
were they called her?
A him or him or her.
Which one's the mis-gendering
a miscommunication was between the
reporter and the actual person they were
talking to.
Yeah,
the person's fucking crazy.
You can't just go back and forth and
back and forth like cut the shit.
You know this,
this whole thing is just preposterous.
It'll remove references to the
name she no longer recognizes.
Does that mean that afterwards,
afterwards she decided to go full female?
That's what happened, which
is so me, Craig format.
So at one point in time during
the show she's, she switches like,
come on man, Paul now and Paul now. Now
back to Cindy. Cindy, Cindy's light.
You can Cindy's Lewis. He doesn't
care. Psychiatric help at this point.
At one point in time we will see that.
Here's the thing,
you're not allowed to say
that when it comes to gender,
when it comes to anything else, if you
like, oh, I recognize it as a wood Elf.
I'm a Wood Elf, you know? That's how
I, that's how I identify. I'm a sprite.
I should be in the forest flying around
with the butterflies. Like people go, Oh,
you probably has, how's an
issue? Okay. Schizophrenia. Yeah.
But if it's a guy who's built like
Brock Lesnar who's like, you know,
I've always identified as Amanda, small
thin woman and people are like, yeah,
who damn cool. Yeah. You should respect
that. Yeah. We should respect that.
When it comes to gender.
Gender is a weird thing that we allow
all sorts of very illogical behavior.
Yeah. Like these 78 plus
gender step, but by the way,
they're adding more. There's more
like they will, there weren't enough,
there's more gender pronouns
now than ever before.
Like if it's a guy at a bus stop
who was like, I am the president.
You don't go like, oh, we should respect
the fuck out of that right now. Right.
You're just like, oh my identify
as as the leader of the free world,
they should address that. No,
you're supposed to be like,
hey, stand over here. Yeah.
When it comes to gender, we're supposed
to, we give like a lot of leeway.
Let a lot of things slide,
get this true. Yeah,
and I think it's for good reason.
I think the good part of it is that we
recognize that there are people that
really do wish that they were a woman.
It would like you to call them a woman
and why not let let the guy become a gal
and then maybe they'll be
happier that way. And it shows,
I guess shows acceptance and kindness on
our part to just allow that to happen.
True.
But the problem with that is is the
goddamn slippery slope and lot of this
weirdness that's going on is people
trying to control other people's behavior.
And one of the ways they try to do that
is try to get you to use words that
they've made up. Yeah. This is where
you're seeing how preposterous it is.
The level, the number of
pronouns is also 78. I mean,
I until recently and somebody saying like,
I don't identify,
like I understand that concept.
It's not too hard to understand,
but where it's like I also have free
reign on a hundred words that you should
possibly know to address me by.
Yeah. It's like, what do you fucking,
why are you bothering everybody?
You know what it is that what you get
off on when you become special that way?
Yeah, of course. You get special
rights, special privileges,
special attention you get.
It's just special consideration.
And I remember, I'm trying to remember
if my, uh, yeah, on my, yeah. Yeah. I've,
I've had on my profile on
Twitter for a long time.
Like if you read my first bio sentence,
I'm a comedian is as Comedians,
Zim Zer pronouns.
But nobody respects it.
Well, I didn't even know Zim. Zim is a
big one. I know it was [inaudible] z.
H. E r or z. E. R. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Those are these motherfuckers.
There's just so many.
The fact that one of those guys could
just become a woman and just enter into
women's weightlifting competitions
and they would be like, oh,
she's a woman. She's
always been a woman. God,
she beat the competition by an
astounding 600 pounds. Really crazy.
Yeah. Beat the second runner up by
40 pounds. No big deal. It's normal.
Super Normal. It happens. Yeah.
No, everybody does it. No,
no. We're going to look back on these days
and it's going to, it's going to be a,
an astounding
sort of observation on mass mass thinking
like group think like what happens
when people are scared of
expressing themselves honestly and,
and expressing controversial points of
view because of the time and the culture.
Like what it, you know, what,
what ramifications it has.
Like, by the way, here's,
here's what's weird. I'm, and I
don't know if it's good or bad.
It's not a judgment call,
but I am,
I know so many people whose
children are now transgender a lot.
Yeah. Like five or six.
I didn't know any before.
Like all those growing up haul in
California. Yeah. Yeah. Wow. Well.
One of them in Canada, but yeah,
really important. What's this?
Toronto fewer ease.
Jessica Plat is this CW Hls,
first openly transgender player.
Now.
She used to be a woman and now as a man,
used to be a man now as a woman and she's
playing women's hockey. Okay. Fuck that.
That's crazy. You know five people. Yeah.
Talky. Guess who's an all star this?
Yeah. Jessica. Yeah. Take, take that
fucking mountain from the game of Thrones.
Put them in skirt.
See?
See how many people he plows over like
God damn human bowling ball. Oh my God,
that dude. It's so fucking crazy. It's
just if you're going to play sports,
there should be. Look there. There
are physical freaks that are women.
There's no doubt about that.
There's some women that are just physical
freaks and there's some women that
also take steroids.
That's,
that's another very controversial
issue because you have women that are
ingesting large amounts of male hormones
and changing their physiology and then
they also compete against women,
but then there's women or just women.
What about them?
How about looking out for them?
How about not letting them get their head
smashed in by Matt Fairman times down
to, it's not fair, but
it's also, it's it just,
it just shows you how silly people have
gotten and about how weird we are about
looking at things and that everyone is so,
and it because they don't have,
they don't really have a
personal stake in the game.
Everyone is so concerned about being
viewed as being incredibly progressive and
open minded that they don't
want to criticize those.
It's really interesting point because
if you really put yourself in a
competition you care about say
like it's important to you to win.
Imagine yourself competing in something
where it's important to you to win and
they go,
but then we're going to have this person
in and those are the circumstances you
would, you'd be the first one. It'd
be like, fuck that. That is not fair.
And those women get taught called bigots.
Yeah, it gets, it's really strange. Yeah.
That is very strong.
As women get like attacked online.
Like there's a bunch of women that didn't
want to fight that transgender man who
became a woman in MMA and they got called
bigots and transphobia and that and
the transgender people,
that community,
and he's like super aggressive about
defending that intellectual turf,
defending that idea.
See,
that's an interesting place is like where
where you go because you have to have
empathy for let's say this transgender
person who was like, I want to compete,
and you're like, yeah, you should
be able to compete. But how has,
how has the circumstance fair to both
sides, you know, to those women that,
that are rails upon attention.
Part of,
part of the wanting to compete is also
wanting attention and wanting everyone to
know that you're a man or transition
to a woman and that there's, look,
there's a lot of energy in that.
There's a lot of people that are
paying attention to that and,
and anybody who says no,
that's preposterous. People,
they want their privacy when it comes
to these matters and they, they're not,
they don't want to be open to the
ridicule bullshit bullshit. They, they're,
they want attention a hundred
percent that's why they're competing.
It's what you're doing.
It's why they're letting everybody know
that the first openly transgender woman,
it's a lot of this is about, I mean
some of it is about transgender rights.
It's about transparency and showing people
how many of those folks are out there.
A lot of it's about horse shit. Yeah,
there's a lot of attention. A lot of it.
I mean for you to sign up for that
competition when you know him,
what's what to pay attention getting
especially things like power lifting and
MMA,
like
to deny that there's some sort of
a difference in the male frame.
There's also a lot of horse shit when it
comes to like what actually happens to
the body during transition and how much
strength you lose and how much bone mass
you lose and there's a woman
named Dr Ramona Crut sick,
I think that's her name and
they interviewed her and
she's one of the very few
people that's been interviewed about
this as an actual endocrinologist.
That's not a gender
transition doctor does.
That's what a lot of them are.
A lot of the people that talk
about these things and have these,
these discussions about these
things that are hashtag experts,
they're actually transitioned doctors so
they have a vested interest in sort of
expressing the ideology that there's no
physical advantage and that these women,
you know,
they,
once they have been under these hormonal
treatments for x amount of years,
they become physiologically a woman and
there's no distinction between them and
a biological woman.
But this one woman,
doctor Ramona crut six she wrote a an
an article for, I want to say it was,
it was either SB nation are bloody elbow,
I forget what it was,
but they interviewed
her and she was saying,
not only do you not lose
bone density but you,
you maintain it because you're taking
estrogen. And she's like, well,
the idea is that like a man is
more bone density, they're thicker,
they're built different,
and that you would lose a lot of that
in your transition to being a woman,
but you don't lose the bone density
because estrogen is actually what causes
people to maintain their bone density.
When they're older, when they were women,
like that's one of the things that
happens to women when they get older,
they get osteoporosis.
What part of the problem is that your,
your body doesn't produce as
much estrogen as it used to.
And so you have a lack of bone density.
One way to heighten that,
it's to supplement with estrogen.
It actually maintains bone density.
So it's a good argument,
but they're not the same as men because
they don't have testosterone anymore.
And if they're not taking
exogenous testosterone,
they're definitely gonna have
a disadvantage against men.
But they still would have an advantage
against men about against women rather
than mechanical advantage of course.
But there's also a mental advantage.
There's a reaction advantage. Um,
the reaction time is quicker with,
uh,
with men than it is with women.
Like there's a bunch of weird three d
space recognition advantages that men
have.
It's like,
and then there's the thing that
people want to pretend that there's no
difference between men and women. There's
that group, you know about that group.
No, but that seems like so stupid to
even entertain the idea. God, that's,
this is a common thing among the most
ridiculous of the progressives is that
there's no biological
difference in the sexes. What,
how can anything that's so
dumb, but I, it is dumb,
but it shows you how insane
a lot of this thinking is,
is that this group think this mass
progressive thought process. Yeah.
That they just accept things that,
that are totally irrational and
they repeat them as ad nauseum.
Like we played this
one clip where there's,
it seems like it's a transgender man
to a woman to man who's saying she was
talking,
there was a Jordan Peterson debate and
she was saying there's no biological
difference between the sax. I'd be happy
to unpack that for you. Oh, really? Like,
Oh, you'd be to unpack.
Yeah. Biology. Sure.
And just no difference at all in
our biology is no, it's not real.
Okay. There's no biological
basis. And in sex and Jen, what?
Right. What did I say is this is
an extra big it. Yes. I'm sorry.
You transphobic. Are you a big it?
Is this an, this is an expert? No,
but she's teaching at a college.
Oh, that's yeah, that would fall,
but that's what a lot of
go, well, that's going on.
There's a lot of that going on in
colleges where people are teaching
unbelievably ridiculous shit. I got
pace. Yup. Go for it. Go for it.
[inaudible].