That were worried about ecosystems
that we really are, that's fine.
That's where we're worried about
invasive species on when new species get
introduced to new ecosystems.
It's like we were just
talking about this yesterday.
A everglades like people
are doing whatever the fuck
they can to get the pythons
and the African roots.
They,
these assholes have released pythons and
there's a real fucking redneck Jurassic
park going on in the middle of Florida.
Yeah, we care. Yeah. I lived in Miami man.
And at the time I lived in Miami. Talk
about did radio out there, right? Yeah.
Why 100 miles after fear factor after
fear factor lay into me that big gig after
all dog food back there. Well radio was
radio back though. Oh, he's real. It was,
it was like huge man.
Uh,
but I remember they had these lakes and
if you go back like 10 years ago and
look up Florida,
people were just jogging around lakes
getting snatched by alligators. Yeah.
Alligators did not give a damn. They
would just snatching people. Yeah.
And I was like, why are
people jogging? Like,
really? I like stopped jogging. Well,
definitely don't jog near the water. No.
And that's the thing,
like I believe like eight people
within six months got snatched.
Just jogging my real, oh, 100%.
Probably about eight to 10 years ago,
just jogging.
I didn't know that.
That there was that many
deaths ever from alcohol. Yeah,
there were getting snacks.
One of my favorite ones was a guy who
was running from the cops near Miami and
he was in a stolen car,
parked his car on a bridge,
jumped off the bridge and landed
on an alligator. Alligator.
Jacked him in front of the cops and they
were just sitting there going, well,
there you go.
Guilty.
Imagine that jumps off the bridge.
Splash.
That would be this. Oh my God, Dude. Oh,
that guy I didn't even notice until
last minute. No, that's what I'm saying.
Like that happens in Florida at that time.
That is so crazy.
That is such a big thing that
eats deer and shit. Look at,
it opens its mouth on him, but meanwhile
it tries to get away from people. Well,
what's interesting to do,
didn't even speed up. Yeah.
Like, I'm just gonna talk off,
probably really tired.
He was on it for a while
to fuck these things,
man. Fuck these things.
But the craziest thing is we were showing
it yesterday that pythons eat them
alligators hole but not dude one python
eight this fucking big ass alligator and
it blew its body apart.
Apparently another aligator came along
while it had it in its body and tried to
eat the python.
And so then it was like this disaster of
a python with an alligator inside of it
with no head.
Oh yeah man.
But the whole thing was that this python
at eight the I'll get and then once
they eat it, they can't move cause
they gotta fucking 900 pound alligator.
But you love that shit. I can't take that.
I know you do. You do problem with, um,
I just,
I do lots of animals eating other animals.
Like think it's important to
recognize that we're, we're,
we're very insulated from what the
fuck is going on by cities. Yes.
And that in houses and cities and
even towns, even if you have a town,
it's rare that a fucking wild Predator
makes its way into your town, but man,
that's the whole rest of the world. That's
the whole world, including the ocean.
Everywhere is all just predators and prey.
Predators and prey. Predators and prey.
We've figured out a way to
insult, but, but in insulation,
the problem is when
we're isolated from it,
we neglect it as an aspect of nature.
We put it in some weird box like,
oh my God, this is weird. No, that's not
weird. That's normal. That's normal life.
Normal life is big things.
Eating littler things you don't respect
it got really don't respect it when you
don't see it. Like, yeah, my
parents want to go to Africa
on a safari. I'm like, man,
you can have that. Yeah, I
would go if I got one of them,
like Jurassic Park mobiles that
they have with, it's all a circle
roll around the [inaudible].
Can you say that?
You see these people are
just in regular jeeps,
jeeps where lions just walking
by. I was like, how dumb are you?
And most of the time nothing
happens. No most, most of it.
But it could be one or two times where if
you're in it, you know until years ago,
a woman who worked on game of Thrones,
she was there on vacation and she got
pulled out of her fucking cuss. Right?
She rolled down the window to take a
picture in the cat came and snatched her
out of the car. But don't you think
people kind of liked that deserve it?
Like people that roll down
windows and not safer?
Like that's like people jumping in the
pit at the zoo the other day to take a
selfie. The roll down the windows
thing I think is really just,
it's what we're talking about that
you're not around it enough so you don't
understand what it is. But do you
have to be around it to know that hey,
these are wild animals and think
they can get away with shit.
They've never had anything happen to them.
Like if they've never been punched,
oh this, this, this is a cheetah.
Cheetah's are actually not.
They're actually very curious
and then not dangerous to people.
So this dude has no idea this thing is
in his backseat. No, he's filming it. Oh,
he's filming it. So that's why he's
not moving. The tool don't move.
I think so man.
I think the move is don't move.
You don't want to scare them.
You definitely don't want
to go, hey man, no fuck.
You don't want to do that and
have a fucking rip your face off.
They don't have flaws.
They don't have claws like a cat does.
They're more like a dog. Yeah. You
know, there are a weird animal.
They're like a weird cat dog thing.
You know, there's super, super fast.
Like I've never seen one run in real life,
but apparently people who I
know that I've seen it say,
you can't believe how fast it is. You
know? One thing that blew me away,
I was reading about it,
that hippopotamuses kill more people
a year than all the animals combined.
All of them. All of
them. Yeah. All of them.
It's just like people
just like don't respect.
Hippopotamus is they're fast and they're
strong and they'll rip you apart.
They're like a giant pig.
Yeah.
They're in the pig family cousin
to a pig or some shit. Yeah.
And they're vegetarians. Yeah.
Like they're just killing people.
Estimated 500 people per year. And
that guy, they killed five, 500 a year.
They're aggressive and they're very
sharp teeth. And not only that man,
people think there's 750
kilograms. What? What is that dude?
What's that in pounds. That's more than
5,000 pounds. 2.2 times that. So, yeah.
Oh my God. That's as well. People don't
respect cause they think they're slow to,
so when they see them,
I think they run like 24 25 miles per
hour were like a a hundred a person that
runs a 100 yard dash in the Olympics.
I think average around like 29 to 30
miles per hour in a way is hippos.
Oh 19 okay. So that's still
fast. Yeah. You're barely
getting away. Well that's me.
I probably can't run 90 miles an hour.
I know I could. I'll probably get eaten.
[inaudible] fuck.
Can you imagine?
You're like 20 yards away from
this thing and you're like, ah,
it's not going to be, and then
it just runs up on you. Well,
they say if you ever get chased by an
alligator too, the thing is to Juke them.
Go left and go. Right. I know.
Yeah. That picture's terrifying me.
That scares the shit out of me. That
scares the shit out of me. I mean,
look at that guy. He's, he's,
he's launching himself in the air trying
to get away from not look at that.
Yeah. They chase after boats in
the water. They swim fast. Yeah.
They try to fuck you up, man. They
try to fuck 500 people a year, dude.
Hippos husband sees hippo
bite out wife's heart. What?
Oh my God. Oh my God. You Mad.
You wife falls into the water and you
see the hippo rip open the rib cage. Oh,
I would be a hippo.
Punisher.
I would go back to Africa every year and
kill out every one. Every one of them.
I'd be responsible for hippo extinction.
They'd be like, you can't do that.
I'm like, but I'm Gunna stop me.
I'm killing all the hippos.
Why not?
I'm killing all the snakes
for if everybody and anyone
knew got killed the first
day that something gets killed
by a fucking python in Florida.
When a human gets jacked,
we should send in the marines.
Just go through the fucking
swamp and killed them all.
Just like they're the enemy.
You just get a giant line of human
beings go through and kill those fucking
serpents. They're in the Bible. Okay?
They're in the Bible. Snakes elite,
your baby, they will go
through your patch. Them all.
I mean are they get cocky with monsters
living in your fucking neighborhood?
Is there any purpose of them
though? Yeah, they kill rats,
but the problem is in that area,
it's not established for them.
So there was this rich ecosystem of
mammals and reptiles talking about
everglades right now.
Okay.
It used to be there was some snakes
like cotton mills and stuff like that,
and there's alligators,
but then there was like march
hares and raccoons and skunks.
God, they're all gone. They're
gone. There's nothing left.
There's just anacondas look at
the pythons and Nile crocodiles.
Now if this got, let me have
the one eating a fucking, well,
let me ask you some alligator
and be honest with me. If,
if that guy got eaten like a guy
that actually tracks reptiles,
do you feel sorry for him? Like if
you putting yourself in harm's yeah,
because I want that guy to be out there.
One don't can to kill those. Yeah.
Monsters. If you ever look into
an eye of a snake and you go, oh,
this thing doesn't give a fuck
about anybody. It's like it doesn't.
I was watching this video
of a crab and it's a crowd,
a mother crab just sitting
there eating its babies.
It had like thousands of babies all
around it that had just hatched like a
couple of weeks ago and it's just sitting
there eating it's babies and I'm like,
yeah, yeah. Fuck you.
You're going in the boiling water
and I'm going to crack you open your,
if I heard him scream when
they go in and dream. Oh yeah.
I don't think they're really screaming.
I think it's probably air
escaping their body. Look at this.
Can either look good or she's
eating her kids. This is crazy.
I was,
I was at a friend's house and they'd
caught crabs and they would throw them at
and I think they scream,
man. I think it's like, no,
I forget who had the vocal cords.
This is like, what does this,
what does Alan is video Jamie for people
to just listen. It says a monster.
Red Crab eats babies. The
dark side of nature. Yeah.
She's an asshole telling you Joe, you
think they scrape? They make a noise.
When you put them in a hot boiling pot
of water. What is the bottom of her?
She's just got a charcoal
briquette stuck under her.
Doesn't that it looks like one of them.
The babies go there.
They can't see some in that.
Come right back out. So gross.
She's such an asshole. She was sitting
there eating her kids. He like that.
Anybody would give a fuck about crabs.
Oh No.
I'm going to sound like I don't
want them to go extinct, but I,
that's one animal that we in our house
kill ourselves and no one has a problem
with it. It's like if they
brought him a rabbit and you,
you gotta throw it in the water,
like fatal attraction.
If like that was the only way to keep,
nobody would eat wrap. No, no, no, no.
And we throw them in
like a lie. A lie, a lie.
I'm telling you, they're in the
water that most of the time,
most people don't even bother taking
off the mother. Lobsters. Lobsters.
We do not give a shit about lobster.
You
get in there,
get in there fucking bug you.