So when you're dealing with some certain
accusations when it comes to human
beings like this, Chris Hardwick
things. And a perfect example of that,
I mean he was just reinstated
yesterday by AMC and um, yeah,
that's a weird one because she wrote the,
it was an ex girlfriend that
wrote something about him.
Yeah, I read that. Well,
she clearly didn't tell the truth about
some aspects of their relationship.
She cheated on him and that's why he
got rid of her or broke up with her.
And then she also said he was just
terrible boyfriend and he did all that.
But then there's videos of her talking
about what an amazing boyfriend he was
while they were together,
about how he stayed with her
in the hospital and slept
by her bed. And it's like,
and she was also,
she had a bunch,
a host of mental illnesses that she
described in their video about like not
being able to drive down the street with
the windows open because she's worth it.
Germs going to get in her car.
And some of those she recovered from
and some of them she didn't like.
It's an Oh,
there's another problem with people when
it comes to when they're talking about
things they might not even be
allying. Yeah, they just might be.
They just might have a
distorted perception of reality.
That is another problem with human
beings when it comes to any sort of
interaction between two people,
especially after a break up.
I think the way that a person can view
the time they spent with someone can very
much change based on,
you know,
their current situation or how
that breakup happened. 100% yeah,
but on both sides. The, the
real problem though is what,
what we were saying is that human beings,
it's very difficult.
I can't read minds. You can't read
minds. You can't look into memories.
So we're relying on a person's description
and then we have to rely on what we
know about them, what,
how, how, what, what,
what we know about their ability
to describe things accurately,
what we know about their perceptions of
reality. They're delusions there. There,
there, there, there, there clarity.
It's fucking super tricky.
I mean, my rule of thumb,
what I would say to people is,
unless you know the two people,
I don't think you can ever
really know what happened.
So in that case of say you leave and Jamie
tells you, I said something about you,
you're probably going to go with
Jamie, right? Cause you know him.
So I would say the same. He's a little
crazy. I'm like, I'm like, oh yeah.
I mean it's for sure.
If I didn't know you and Jamie told
me you did something fucked up,
I would side with Jamie.
But even that's weird cause like
if I'm not there, if I don't know,
if you say I didn't do anything,
I'm like well maybe one day you'll be
my best friend and maybe a of one day
Jamie turn out to be a fucking psycho.
I was like,
remember when we used to think
Jamie was okay, he's fucking crazy.
But that's the thing too.
I think sometimes with,
I do empathize with some of the women
who say if this happens to the men and
people say, well that's a nice guy.
I know that guy. That's my buddy.
I've known him forever. But you
didn't date him. So how do you know?
You don't know, right? Yeah.
You don't know. God Damn it.
It's fucking tricky. You know, if
you ever seen that episode of black,
do you ever watch Black
Mirror watched one episode?
So everyone tells me how amazing this
show is and I think it is amazing.
But I saw one episode that really freaked
me out. So no, it was the one about,
um, it was actually about a of the boy
who was a pedophile and then he was being
watched and blackmailed creeped me out.
But there's one called crocodile.
Okay.
And it is easily the most disturbing
episode of a television show I've ever
watched in my life.
And it,
it has to do with technology that
allows people to read memories. Okay.
And I'll leave it at that because
I had no spoiler alerts here,
but until fucking dark stays
with you after this one does,
this one's dark. I mean this,
I mean I can't, I can't,
I will give too much away if I talk about
it, but the concept is that you can,
they have a machine and they set this
machine up and through this machine they
can literally read your
memories until that happens.
We really don't know.
And you know,
there's been things in my life where I
looked back on it and I had a perception
and then I went to the place
where I grew up and I was like,
I don't remember it looking like this. I
don't remember this being so close. Oh,
the streets right here. This
is where the house is. Oh.
And then you have to kind of like
remap your memories. Like, okay,
we got to clean these memories up and
try to figure out what's accurate and
what's not. But then this is,
I'm just talking about like this,
the neighborhood where I grew up in,
but what about your adding in emotions?
Then you add,
again,
painful emotions because of breakups
and perhaps suicidal thoughts and
yes, time. Sure. I mean,
it's been absolutely proven that eye
witness testimony is the least accurate
piece of evidence that any investigator
can ever use in terms of like trying to
figure out what happened at the scene of
a crime or anything involving any sort
of trauma.