There's a sense in which as
we create those environments,
we actually change ourselves as a species.
There's this a set of ideas that's known
as gene culture coevolution and the
idea is that we create certain
kinds of cultural environments.
Those kinds of cultural environments
advantage certain ones of us making those
of us that are born with
certain abilities better off,
which then leads to those
environments being created even more.
Let me give you some eggs,
an example of that.
The most famous example of this is
something known as lactase persistence.
So many people,
not about half the world can adults can
drink milk and the other half cannot.
They get lactose intolerant. Well,
why can you drink milk as an adult?
Have you ever thought about that?
Like why?
Why are you capable of drinking milk
as and adult? In our ancestral state,
actually up til about 10,000 years ago,
only babies could address to digest
milk because only babies had milk.
Babies would suckle at their mother's
breast and have milk and then they'd be
weaned and then they would never drink
milk again. There'd be no milk to drink.
There was therefore no reason for any
adult to be able to digest lactose,
which is the principle sugar in milk
because there was no lactose in your diet.
It didn't encounter milk,
so human beings were able to digest
lactose when they were babies.
They lost that capacity.
All human beings,
when they got to about two or three
or four or five, when they wean,
they no longer were able to just
milk to the enzymes in their body.
We're programmed as it were, to only
work when they were infants. Well,
about between three and 9,000 years
ago in multiple places in Africa and in
Europe,
human beings suddenly domesticate animals.
We domesticate milk producing animals like
cattle and sheep and goats and camels,
and now all of a sudden there's a
supply of milk around us because of our
cultural innovation,
because of the thing we invented,
we created the domestic
breeds. Now we have milk. Now,
therefore those among us who are mutants,
who are born with the
ability to have our lactase,
the enzyme that to just
lactose persist into adulthood.
This is known as lactase persistence.
Those of us who had that would have a
survival advantage because we could have
another source of calories that the
rest of the people in our group couldn't
consume that couldn't
drink milk like we could.
And we had a source of unspoiled
water during times of drought.
We could drink milk.
Everyone else had to drink this filthy
water that they didn't have access to.
So those among us who had these qualities
could reproduce better survive at a
survival advantage. It turns out
that this has happened several times.
This is when well documented.
The genetics of this has all been worked
out several times in the last three to
9,000 years because of a
human cultural product.
We have evolved to be a slightly different
genetically and it doesn't stop with
cows.
I think that when we invent cities about,
uh,
over 5,000 years ago, we, so we did, we
invent agriculture about 10,000 years ago.
It's debated exactly
when we invent cities,
but between five and 10,000 years ago,
we started having fixed settlements.
Earlier you and I were talking about
population density and having to live with
other people,
which is not our ancestral state,
not packed and not with other people.
We always lived as a group, as socially.
I think that as we invent cities,
people with different kinds of brains
are better able to survive in cities.
So now that we've invented cities where
advantaging people with certain kinds of
brains, and therefore I think in
a thousand or 2000 or 5,000 years,
just like the milk example,
there'll be different people as a result
of something we humans manufactured
that we made. And I could keep giving you
examples of this. There's a, in the book,
I have an example, another example of
a, they're called the sea nomads. They,
they live in the Philippines. These
are people who, uh, don't live on land.
They live on houseboats that sail around
the Pacific for thousands of years.
They've had this lifestyle and
they die for their food dive.
So they forage on the seabed.
They are the world's best free divers.
They spend hours per day underwater.
They can hold their breath longer than
anyone else. Uh, and they, they do do it.
Nothing except with
weights and wooden goggles.
They dive down into the seabed
and forage and they hunt.
They hunt underwater with spears.
Okay.
They hunt underwater would spirits.
It's mind boggling. Wow. And, uh,
but they, uh, have evolved,
have different spleens and different
oxygen metabolism than you and I
[inaudible] so those,
among them that could survive the dives,
fed their families,
made more babies.
And now we think this happened 2000
years ago. There are different,
the ones that couldn't died.
So their invention of a
seafaring way of life,
their invention of a way of living at sea,
the boat technology,
the spear fishing technology,
the intervention of those
technologies creates an environment,
cultural environment around them,
which modifies natural
selection and changes the kind
of genes that those people
have.