The joe rogan experience.
Yeah. I was looking at the,
like the map of the way we fly. We fly
so we can't see it the entire way. Yeah.
Which is bullshit. Yeah. Plus it
was cloudy, which is also bullshit.
That would've been cool. I even asked the
guy, I'm like, which way do we go? Yeah.
That would be fucking awesome if
it flew over that thing. Yeah. Ooh,
fuck. Living on a volcano
though, man. Good place to
visit though is beautiful. Oh,
stunning. Yeah. Great. And where we were,
we were on the nine and the
nine is an interesting place.
3000 people, 20,000 deer. Right. And,
and so you do the math, you think,
hey, this is going to be gravy. Dare.
It is way more deer than
people. But God, it was,
it's tough. It's tough
hunting. Hunting for sure.
Well this is one of the best examples,
um,
of if you want to make an argument for
hunting like this in certain situations,
this is probably the best example.
You must control the population of these
animals. They don't have any predators.
And they evolved around tigers. They
come from India. So these axis deer,
they were a gift from a Hong Kong
to King Kamehameha the fifth.
I saw your history lesson and 1860 and
I was getting it all into it today and I
want to make my post about is
awesome. Um, so they, what did they,
what was the number that they shoot?
How many did they should a week just to,
just to feed people and control the
population had 1500 but not a week was it?
No, I think it was 30 a day. Oh, okay.
Yeah, there was saying the shoot 30 a day.
Right, because they have
to go at night. Yup.
What's night night vision scopes and
shoot dose. Yeah. Just to take 'em out,
just to take him out. So many deer.
When we were there at night, um, we got,
first of all we got, I got
super lucky. Thanks to you, you,
you let me take that deer. But when
white one we landed, we went to Scout,
we got out of the car,
we went and looked around and within
five minutes we saw a buck feeding in a,
in a doable spot.
Not creeped in,
it was total it w w it just gives you a
distorted perception of your chances of
success. Yeah, because for the next five
days I got nothing until the last day,
but in 15 minutes I got the first deer.
But when you get there,
you realize how switched on these things.
So like there's, there's nothing
like these things. It's a, you know,
I've hunted in Africa and in the antelope
there are pretty quick also just like
that, but just because of lions and
hyenas and yeah, just, just super jumpy,
twitchy. But these deers,
very similar. Just quick,
when we were leaving that night when you,
and me and Adam were in the truck and
we're leaving and we turned the lights on
the truck and you could see hundreds
of deer in front of us. Yeah.
It was the craziest,
like it was like a crowd being led out
of a concert or something like that or
basketball games,
basketball games over cause it is just
that they're coming out of the, yeah,
crossing the road into the open field
where we'd been hunting and it's just
hundreds. You can't imagine if you haven't
been there. You can imagine if you,
if you move there or if you
just went there for a few
days, you'd kind of get it.
You'd be like, okay, what do
you do about these things?
Well you can't give them birth control.
I mean they eat grass.
So like how are you going to stop
them from breeding? You're not,
so what are you going to do? Are you
going to introduce tigers to Lanai?
That would be cool. There may be the
only way to do it other than hunters.
And they're going to start eating
people just hunting. And it's,
it's such a destination for
just getting good deer meat.
And I was thinking about it too,
that stretch.
Where are those hundreds of deer
cross the highway? You know, that's,
I mean it's a straight as can be.
You can see, I mean great visibility,
but the speed limit is 35.
I think it's because deer are always
jumped out in front of cars there.
People would be dying. So it's, it
seems like, why is it 35? This is like,
you should be 70, but so many deer. I
think it's also because they're like,
where are you going? Yeah, slow down.
There's no hurry. What's the hurry man?
Relax. I mean 3000 people on the island.
Maybe that, yeah, that's part of it too.
That island. So relax and the people
are so friendly. I was an awesome,
awesome place. It was a,
um, anytime I go on a hunt,
I mean I'm thankful for the experience
and, and for seeing the animals,
but also meeting the people, you
know, Alec, Bob, the butcher.
Um, they're just like these
people that are ingrained in your,
in your memory and you know,
that's it.
That's such a special part of the trip
also. Yeah. The experience is very,
very unusual because there's really
not a place like that that I know of
anywhere on the planet that's just a
small island with a small population of
people and a massive population of the
most delicious animals in the world.
And even though there's so many of them.
Good fucking luck getting one. Yeah.
We had our friend Ben O'brien,
he went home empty handed.
He was so one of us in a group
of very experienced hunters.
I mean other than me, everybody in that
group is super, super experienced. Yeah.
You know,
and still is no cake walk.
These things are switched on and now dodge
arrows like during the matrix. I mean,
it's crazy. It's a, there's no
gimmie's. No, I mean it's a,
you can do everything right. You
can, you can think in your head.
While I travel all the way here, I'm, I'm
here to hunt. I need to take meat home.
It doesn't matter those deer,
there's no gimmie's.
They're trying to stay alive and
they know what's up. They get hunted.
I don't know if it's every day because
when their, when their antlers fall off,
you know the bucks probably are hunted,
but because they're
killing doe is at night.
They're hunted most days out of the year.
So they are as well as wired as it
can be. I mean, because they're,
they're used to being pursued. Yeah. It's
different than say like white tail deer,
whitetail deer seem to kind of know
when hunting season comes around. Yeah.
Like when they're velvet drops off and
they rub their velvet off and then the
females start coming into season,
that's when they get fucking sketchy and
nervous because they know that guns are
going to be going off from, the arrows
are going to be flying their way. Right.
But you catch them during the summer.
They're just kind of chilling. Yeah.
These things are never challenged polar
in the winter after season, they're just,
they're more focused on food and putting
on some weight to to make it through
the winter. So other than hunting season,
they are more chill. But these things,
I don't think they ever get a day off.
They don't get a day off and they can't
give him a day off because if they just,
if everybody said, hey man, this
just need these animals and then man,
if they did, they would all die either
of starvation or they would die.
They had to eradicate the goat population
on the island because people brought
goats there and the goats literally had
decimated the vegetation to the point
where the island started going into
a drought. I don't understand this,
but somehow or another, if you
eat all of the vegetation, the,
the rain stops falling in certain areas
where there's a lack of participate,
precipitation or condensation doesn't
gather because there's no no leaves to
catch capture it.
Or one of the ladies who lived there
was explaining it to me why they had to
kill all the goats. Oh, I see. And
she was like, trees were dying,
everything was dying. And they're in
the process right now of a, in Maui,
they have this gigantic area that they
are trying to eradicate deer from and
they want to fence it in to let the
forest regrow because the forest doesn't
have a chance to regrow with,
again,
same animal access deer because they
just eat all the little baby trees.
It has a little trees are coming up.
They just chew those fuckers
up and that's what they eat.
They shoots and they want the new
browse. Yeah, yeah. New Growth. Yeah.
Okay.