Hello Freak bitches, intelligent
conversation about that, right?
Because the lefties say,
oh,
too much inequality and they need to
be listened to because the evidence is
quite clear.
If you let the inequality ramp up enough,
the whole system destabilizes because
the people at the bottom think fuck it.
We'll just, we'll just flip the
system upside down. No one wants that.
Like right wing conservatives
don't want that.
So cause you could make a
republican argument and say,
don't let the inequality in
your neighborhood get out
of hand because the crime
rate will skyrocket.
And the,
the empirical evidence on
that is overwhelmingly strong.
Inequality drives crime.
Now you can say,
you can argue about why,
but the fact that it does
is that's not disputable.
So we can have an intelligent discussion
between the left and the right and the
discussion would go something like this.
You need innovation,
you pay for innovation with inequality,
but you need to bind inequality
because if it's too intense than things
destabilize, it's like, okay, we can agree
on that. We've got the parameter set.
Now we have to,
now we have to start thinking very
carefully through how to do the
redistribution issue. And we don't know
how to do that. So you might say, well,
we have a guaranteed
annual income for people,
which I think is a horrible
solution by the way,
but it addresses the right problem.
The problem is is that
we're hyper productive,
but the spoils go to those at the top.
And some of those resources need to be
funneled down to the people who have zero
so that they have an opportunity to at
least get to the point where they can
innovate. And so the bloody whole
bloody thing doesn't wobble and fall.
And we could we,
and I would say in some sense that's
what the political discussion is about.
But we, we've, we've skittered off
into these radical oversimplifications,
which is something like, well, if,
if you have more than another person,
you're an oppressor and you're evil,
and if you have less,
it's because you're virtuous and
victimized. And that's just a nonstarter.
So you you think that there's a real
problem with like something like a
universal basic income? I think
it's horrible. I do. Well.
I think the idea that the solution is a
basic income is not a good idea because
I think the problem is deeper than that.
I,
I don't think the fundamental problem
is that people don't have enough money.
I think the fundamental problem is that
human beings in some sense are beasts of
burden and if they're not given,
if they're not provided with a place where
they can accept social responsibility,
social and individual responsibility
and an honorable manner,
they degenerate and die. That's the
opiate crisis in west right now.
Like men need men who are,
men don't need money,
they need function and we've got
a problem. One of the problems is,
for example here, here's an ugly stat.
I think I told you this once before.
It's illegal to induct anyone into the
armed forces if they have an Iq of less
than 83 and the reason for that
is the, the, the armed forces,
despite having every reason to draw the
contradictory conclusion has decided
that there isn't a single thing that you
can be trained to do in the military.
If you have an Iq of less than 83 that
isn't positively counterproductive,
that's 10% of the population and
we're producing a culture that's
very cognitively complex like,
what the hell are you going to
do if you can't use a computer?
Like if you can use a computer,
you're at least in the game if you can
really use when you're hyper powerful.
If you're not literate
enough to use a computer,
you're at zero 10% of the population.
The Conservatives say, well,
there's a job for everyone. If they
just worked hard enough. It's like, no,
and increasingly know and
the liberals say, well,
everyone's basically the same and you can
train anyone to do anything. It's like,
no,
you can't.
I want to go back to the inequality
point here because if you look at this
biologically, actually I think it
reveals a lot. Why are we, I mean,
we know from,
uh,
from careful study that people are
motivated by the degree of inequality more
than they are the, the absolute
level of wellbeing that they have.
And there's a very good,
it's tragic,
but a very good evolutionary
reason for this,
which is if you are working on some
piece of land and your neighbor has the
adjacent piece of land and they're
doing twice as well as you,
it's because they know
something you don't, right.
And so becoming focused on what they're
doing that you're not doing is a
rational thing to spend your time on.
So you can figure out what it is
that they know that you don't.
In the modern environment,
this is a catastrophe because
who are your neighbors?
Well,
you've got some box sitting on the wall
of your living room that has a totally
artificial portrait of other people
who may be much wealthier than you.
And it's broadcasting in as if you're
looking in their window right in the
adjacent house. And so you think
you, you're being triggered to,
to think that you're
doing something wrong,
that you might fix when in fact the
solution may not be, first of all,
the person on the other side of
that screen may not be for real. Um,
but even if they are, they're not
living in the same environment as you.
The technology is interfacing with,
uh, with our, our brains badly.
But so we have the perception of
massive inequality economically.
We do have massive inequality.
You're arguing that the solution to
this involves some sort of massive
redistribution as solution, I would
say solution. But nonetheless,
redistribution is wildly
unpopular for various reasons.
And so what we've got now is a situation,
this is speculative,
but what's really happening
is that austerity is being
used as a threat to keep
people who would otherwise rebel
against the inequality in line.
And my fear about this is that this is
exactly the conditions that are going to
trigger that,
uh,
tribal population against population may
hem that we were talking about at the
beginning of this conversation that
when people have the sense that the,
the burst of growth that they
were experiencing is now over,
the natural response is to turn on those
who are not as powerful and take their
stuff.
That this is a totally indefensible
but nonetheless biological
pattern of history.
And that if we want to avoid that,
we have to stop sending the signals that
trigger us to imagine that we've just
run to the limit of the
opportunity that we had discovered.
And it is now time to look and see
who can't defend their position.
How are we sending these
signals? Well by, um,
basically failing to provide enough
wellbeing that people's perception of the
inequality is reduced
to a tolerable level.
What's the argument for
universal basic income?
It's certainly certainly a strong
one. And I, you know, it's also,
it's also a good argument for equality of
opportunity, right? Because people are,
people are actually not as resentful
about the success of others as you might
expect. They're resentful about it
if they feel that the game is fixed,
but they're also willing to
consider the game long term.
So lots of people will say, look like
I'm stuck at not zero, I'm stuck at one,
but my kids might make it to
four and that's good enough.
And that's been the American
dream. Right? And, and that's,
that's a really high power antidote
to inequality. It's like, well yeah,
there's some inequality. We need it to
keep the generative mechanism going,
but the game is fair
and you can play it too.
And there's some reasonable probability
that either you or someone you love will
be successful. So that, so
it has to be a straight game.
And that's why ethics is so important
to keep this landscape stable.
People can't play crooked games and the
rich shouldn't be fixing the game if
they want to hold onto their money. And
the problem is, is that some of them,
although not all,
some of them are fixing the game and no
one's happy about that. And no wonder,
you know,
and,
and I guess that was evidence to some
degree by the 2008 collapse because it
seemed,
and,
and I'm just as uninformed
as the next person. So I'm,
I'm what I'm capable
of commenting on this,
it seems from the outside that the rich
disproportionately benefited from the
restabilize [inaudible]
of the economic system.
And people are not happy about that
and they shouldn't be happy about that
because it indicates that
there's something fundamentally
rotten about the game.
So you could say,
well,
maybe people can tolerate necessary
inequality if the game isn't raked.
And so that's why everybody has to act
in a matter that indicates that the game
isn't rigged. And that means they can't
rig it. That's really what it means. So,
and so we're also being driven
into this inequality corner by,
I would say by the postmodernists and
the neo Marxist because they say this is
the pernicious thing. They say, well,
the reason that some people have more
than others is because every hierarchy is
based on arbitrary power
and they're all oppressors.
And the reason they have the money
is because they stole it from you.
And there's some truth in that
because there are some criminals.
But when you get to the point where
you fail to distinguish the productive
people from the criminals,
which is exactly what happened
in the 1920s in the Soviet Union,
you better bloody well what watch out.
Because when you radically make things,
egalitarianism going to wipe out all
your productive people and then you're
going to starve.
And so that's,
that's one of the doom end scenarios
that awaits us if this idiot process of
polarization continues. And what I find
reprehensible about the universities,
and you're tangled up right
up to your neck in this,
is that the universities are actively
agitating to produce people who believe
that all inequality is due to
oppression and power. And that's just,
well, first of all,
it's technically wrong,
but you guys both operate in that system.
So what?
Here's the problem. No,
I, as far as I know,
nobody has properly studied the question
of what fraction of the economy is
actually crooked rent seeking,
right? Not Productive.
And I fear that the answer
to that question is that
it's an awful large fraction
of the economy, not because
of some, uh, conspiracy,
but because opportunity is finite,
but con Games aren't.
And so anybody who can find a mechanism
for transferring wealth from somebody
else for doing nothing,
finds that mechanism and that
thing is, is ever present.
Whereas discovering the next big thing
that's actually productive is, you know,
something that goes along in fits and
starts. And so if we were, I mean really,
you've described it very well.
We've got a battle between two
characatures of what's true,
right?
Are there either the market is wonderful
and it's producing great stuff with
very little corruption or everything that
makes people on equal is the result of
corruption. Both of these
things are wrong, right?
Markets are marvelous engines for figuring
out how to do something really well.
They're brilliant at this, right? And so
people who see that fall in love with it,
understandably because
they're so good at it,
but what they're terrible at is telling
you what you should want or what you
should do, right? If people tell markets,
here's what we would like to accomplish,
and then the markets tell us, well,
how do we accomplish that best?
That would be a very viable system
that would not result in massive rent
seeking,
resulting in everybody feeling that all
of their misfortunes are the result of a
rigged game, which is so massively rigged
that when they check, they see, yes,
that is actually large, large to large
extent what we're suffering from. Um,
but they want to throw the
baby out with the bath water.
And so they want to throw out
markets entirely, which you know,
would be a terrible mistake.