The Joe Rogan experience.
Yeah. I don't know, man.
You guys weren't so far ahead of the curve
though. You know, I mean you, you were,
you had weeds, songs like when,
like what year that was, uh, the,
the first album was in [inaudible] 91.
Yeah.
And we started riding for that
album probably a four years prior.
Wow. And uh, you know, the
weed songs, those came about
because we were, we'd heads,
you know, we just fuck, fuck
it, let's be ourselves. Right.
A different thing now for people
that were, were fans because uh, I,
when I was listening to you,
I was just getting ready to move from
Boston to New York and back then you would
hear about new hip hop bands
from like friends. Yeah. Like,
like it was all word of
mouth. Yeah. Man, for sure.
I would hear about it like somebody that
I think somebody I worked out with had
it and I was like, what the fuck is
this? And then like, that's Cypress Hill.
I was like, Damn. And we were
trying to be different, you know,
I'm not sound like a typical
west coast, you know, group,
because a lot of a lot of west coast
groups at that point, you know,
what the labels were looking for were
Nwa, you know, types and you know,
things like that. Like either,
you know, gangster, west coast,
gangster rap,
they were looking for that or
either the kid frost Chicano type.
And we didn't want to do that. We don't
want to a foot hold ourselves like that,
you know,
mugs being from New York,
he wanted to sort of blend both
worlds, right. So, you know,
we went with,
with the east coast type sound with La,
you know, type of slang mixed with,
with east coast slang. And so people,
you know, they were like, where
the fuck are these guys from?
And people thought we
were from Cypress Hill,
New York because there's a Cypress
hill down there. And, uh, you know,
people just didn't really know at first
because we were one of the first groups
that didn't put our images on
any of our first, um, you know,
any of our singles or, or our art covers.
We never did like the, the shots, like,
you know,
that,
that were existing at that time where
it's a clean shot of the group or the
artist or whatever. We were
always on some, you know,
cause we were metal heads too,
you know, before the hip hop.
We liked the obscure metal albums.
So we didn't, we were like,
we're not going to put
ourselves on the covers.
We're just going to do these crazy
obscure covers and make people, you know,
try to guess who we are. Be Mysterious,
Dan. We talk about longevity. I mean,
you guys,
you guys have been around a long fucking
time and Craig is dropped off at all.
It's crazy. You know. Um,
we, we didn't expect it.
We didn't know how long I run would
be. We just kept working. You know,
we always had a strong work ethic. We
were never the types just to sit around.
We're always doing something, you know,
mugs is always making beats. Um, you know,
I'm always writing to something,
I'm always into one project or another.
So it was always just about keeping
busy and, and that, that, uh,
suited as well. It's crazy. 28
years later still banging it.
It's crazy. When you say 28 years,
28 years later from your first album,
man, again, you guys never dropped
off for a second. Not once.
You were always there. You have to
be consistent in hip hop, you know,
in music in general,
especially like if,
if there's a time where radio stops
playing your music or you know,
as MTV stopped playing music videos
in and they went for more, um,
reality show type programming, you
got to, you got to stick out there.
So for us it was, you know,
constantly doing shows.
We didn't put out as many albums as we
could of, but we thought less was more,
you know, instead of like drive
in the music into your heart,
like a steak or something like
that. We would just, you know,
let everything breathe for a while.
And there was, there was a time where,
you know,
we sort of let go of doing everything.
It was like a six year period where
we just kinda took off. We, we didn't,
we weren't away completely.
We're still doing like sporadic shows
here and there to keep up the profile,
but we weren't like touring.
Yeah.
Okay.