I go back and forth with conspiracies.
I have a love hate relationship with
conspiracies. I love some of them.
Some of them are fascinating.
Some of them like, okay,
what the fuck happened there? You
know, but, and then some of them work.
I can't do this anymore. Yeah,
I didn't. When I was younger.
I used to think about it, but then
I think when I had a kid at, well,
I don't have time for that.
No time for nonsense and
becomes very precious.
This becomes food.
How exactly not over here worrying
about the fucking Illuminati.
I don't even know what that means.
What's the Illuminati? Exactly. I'm busy.
I kind of go, but I get how people get
sucked into that rabbit hole, you know?
Yeah. No, no, no. I could see it. I
went into a rabbit hole the other day,
but with aliens, I watched three
alien documentaries in a row.
I Raja this one on Bah Blah czar.
Who was the guy who claims that he
worked at area 51 very compelling.
Very interesting. Because at the top, but
that's the one you would suggest. Yes.
That's the one I would suggest.
It's called area 51 Bob Lasar
area 51 and flying saucers,
I think it's called. It's on iTunes
right down. It's fucking good.
Take notes because there's some things
that this guy knew that it's almost
certain that he worked
where he said he worked,
that he worked at area
51 the question becomes,
he told all the truth about all these
things that have since been proven to be
true. Um, weird. So he gave,
he gave first cut at those truths, right?
Yeah. Well he did a long time ago too.
He came out about this like 30 years ago.
There was a Nevada.
Tell heard about this Bob. He would. He
would. He was worried about his life.
Here's what happened.
Apparently the guy was working in this
area doing research for whatever the
government wanted them to do, an
area 51 what he did there, who knows?
He gets fired from this job and then
takes his friends to this viewing position
in the mountains where they can
see them flying, flying saucers.
He was telling them they fly them
at his base. I'm going to bring,
you guys were going to watch it. He, they
videotape this on old school VHS tape.
You can see these flying saucers
flying around area 51 and he says,
these are not w not being
piloted by a, uh, by aliens.
These are being piloted by human beings,
but that these are real devices.
These things are real.
It's a real vehicle.
And they got this real
vehicle from some other,
some other civilization from somewhere
in space and they had nine of them.
It sounds like total
horseshit when you hear it,
but then you watch the video and
so the questions come like, well,
how did he know that they were going
to be flying these things up there?
How do you know they were
going to do them on Wednesdays?
How do you know where to be and where
he could see it? How did he know?
How did he know about the biometric data?
How do you know about element one 15
he was talking about this element,
this manmade element that it's a real
element that they've now identified.
But when he was talking about it in 1981
knew what the fuck he was talking about
or 1984 or whatever it was when he was,
when he first got interviewed about this.
So when this guy is bringing this
stuff up today and people are,
are looking back at all the different
things that he said that have since been
proven to be true, especially
the existence of area 51,
the, the government had to,
at some point in time in the 90s,
they had to say that they own the base
and say that it did in fact exist.
The, uh, top secret area
or the, uh, do you know,
like there's a do not enter
zone or they'll pull you
over and arrest you if you
get past a certain spot.
They wanted to broaden that area so people
couldn't be watching their crafts fly
around like Bob Lasar was.
And when they did that,
when they expanded the territory,
that's when they had to actually
admit that the base was real.
So he was proven to be correct on so
many different things that he said,
like explain how they get them out there,
explain what the research was.
And he said that they had these
things that run on some, they,
they manipulate gravity in some way and
they're very small because these aliens
are very small little creatures. Like a
child, like a eight, 10 year old child.
Huh. It makes you go, what the fuck man?
Like I, so he talked about, he said, well,
he saw them, he knew
how they operated. Wow.
The things that he knows that are true,
that that turned out to be true.
That how could he have known them if
he didn't work at area 51 or the most
compelling aspects of it.
And the fact that area 51 was at one
point in time by the governments take it
didn't exist.
And then it was like a legend.
And this was when he was talking about it.
And so watching this documentary
and seeing this guy 30 years later,
still basically saying exactly the same
thing with a bunch of things have been
proven. Have improvement. Cynthia. Yeah,
that is intense. It's a trip, man. I mean,
if the government really did at one
point in time have some craft that it got
from another planet, like what the
fuck man? But the thing is like,
how would we take that?
How do you think people would
take that if they found out?
How do you think that handle that?
If they really knew there was something
that was so sophisticated that it could
visit us from another planet.
It could be here in minutes,
g land in the White House lawn and
do whatever the fuck I wanted to.
You couldn't even shoot it with bullets.
How would
people take that?
I think that people would just keep
going on like with every other scare.
I think so, yeah. I
think, okay, there's, um,
there could be a media that's supposed
to hit us. Right, right. I mean,
how do people take it? I mean,
that's what they're saying.
They said it could happen. I think it
would be a fuck fest in the streets. Yeah.
But what they say they say
could happen. I mean, you know,
if you saw one common yeah,
but I'm saying that if you saw one
company because you don't see the alien
coming, if people realize that yeah, these
guys could show up. Right. I don't know.
I remember the conspiracy that um,
when I, I remember, I do remember that.
I remember that when they would be like
these booklets of like xerox stuff going
on, like the one about aids and stuff
like that. Maybe that one. Yeah.
That one had be going for a while.
The con, the AIDS conspiracy,
the Irish stroker
memorandum. Oh yeah, yeah.
People are used to hand those out.
Right.
Don't try and tell people that
aids was a hoax, not a hoax.
That it was like all this stuff memorized.
I always got to host a government
conspiracy. Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
Way Out for a while.
I remember I was video I was making,
I was making copies and passing along
guys. That blew my mind. Wow. There was a
one doctor at one point in time that
was trying to say that that HIV does not
cause aids and we had him on way back
in the day early on. Was that guy's name
Duesberg? Dr Peter Duesberg. Yeah.
Yeah. That's what it is. Our man,
I just remembered it.
He is a professor at the University
of California Berkeley I believe.
I think he's a Bot biologist and his take
was that HIV does not cause aids that
would causes AIDS as a
compromised immune system.
That HIV is actually a weak virus and it
shows up in the immune system so people
that are already compromised.
That's why you're finding it in these
people that it's not the cause of their
immune system being compromised.
Compromise.
It's a symptom of it and that with these
people are really dying from is there
their whole system being fucked up by
drugs that either they're taking AZT,
which destroys their body. You
know, it was a cancer medication,
like a chemotherapy that was so powerful
is killing people quicker than the
cancer was.
And then they switched it over to using
it with people that had aids because in,
in the early days they would
call aids the gay cancer.
There was all these different,
like they were trying to figure
out what it was and what it did.
And early on this guy was saying this
and we had them on the podcast and people
got so mad there,
there were so mad that given this
guy a platform to spread his,
his propaganda in his lies. And I was
like, wow. But he is a professor, right?
He has done like legitimate cancer
research. He's, you know, I mean,
don't you want to listen
to them? And, and I,
I wanted to get someone on to debate him,
but nobody wanted to debate him.
It was like trying to get someone
to debate a Holocaust denier. Like,
nobody wants to give them the platform
and when he wants me to talk to them,
which I understand, but
those, those kinds of,
I mean it's very highly unlikely that
all these doctors are incorrect in her
hiding the fact that HIV, you know, and
then now the fact that they've got these,
um,
HIV medication,
so basically they can take people and
make them HIV negative now. Right.
Then they have like a couple people
have tested HIV negative after her
medications. Yeah. I
Dunno. I'm too stupid.
Too stupid to understand what's really,
yeah. That's, that's for me
that I know that I'm like,
when I watch some of those things,
you know, they, some of them,
they will like lead off
with these statements and we
all know and we know this.
I'm like, I don't, I don't
know. Yeah. I don't know.
Yeah. There's too much to know.
Yeah. Yeah. How do we get
in the subject of AIDS?
I don't know where we're talking
about conspiracy theories.
And that was the one that I, that one,
that one when it was back in what?
[inaudible] 89 or something. 88 when
those little pamphlets are growing around.
Yeah. I was like, yeah,
well marijuana and conspiracies
go together like cookies
and milk. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Right. This is nothing
like we, it starts your,
your gears turning and you start thinking
that's where a lot of people start
thinking conspiracies are
against them too. Right.
You get high and they start thinking
that the world's closing in on you.
Everybody's watching you surveillance.
But do you don't probably don't feel like
that when you get high. No, I'm okay.
Yeah. Yeah, I do. Sometimes
I kinda like it though.
You know why I like it? Cause it
ends and when it ends you feel great.
It's almost like a, a brutal
brain workout. Like you,
you go digging deep into your psyche and
find out all the things you're scared
of. Right? Yeah. No, it's like it's work.
Yeah. It'll work. You like took a look at,
you said, and you know I never thought
about me from that angle before. Yeah.
I like to do it. I'm going to clean up
mine. Yeah, yeah. Clean up your shit.