Now, let me ask you
this, cause this is the,
we're in the biggest crisis
in terms of immigration,
in terms of national discussion.
The biggest discussion of it than I can
ever remember right now with this wall
shit where the government is completely
shut down and no one's budging on either
side and all these government workers
are not getting paid and psalm because
Trump wants $5 billion for this wall.
I'm not,
let's just,
in an ideal world,
it would be ideal if the way the world
worked was the way America works,
where you can just go every you want.
That'd be the ideal world.
If the whole world was America in the,
in the sense of you can go to New Mexico,
you didn't have to get paperwork signed.
You don't have to know.
It has to tell you whether or not you're
allowed to go visit or not go visit.
He just drive there. That's,
that's a nice thing about America.
It's almost like Europe, but you don't
need a passport. Not In, it's like Europe.
I know you guys have been around
longer and all that good stuff.
That's not what I mean. I mean in terms
of there's a bunch of different fields.
It's all speaking one language,
but there's a big difference between
visiting Montana and visiting Miami.
You know,
if you go to billings,
Montana and hang out with the local
folk at a coffee shop and then you go to
some fucking crazy after I already after
hours party in Miami on Miami beach at
four in the morning and p did, he
shows up and fucking, you know,
and as all these celebrities and people
are doing coke on the floor and like
what the fuck is this?
This is a different world.
It's a different world and it's a
bunch of these different worlds.
New York City's a different world.
You know, La is a different world.
You're allowed to go there.
Wouldn't it be great if the
whole world was like that?
You can just kind of go wherever you
wanted to go and it would all sort itself
out. The idea is you can't
because it would fuck up our
quality of life and would
make us less safe.
And I get the argument.
Certainly you don't want to
bring in criminals and murderers.
You don't want drug dealers making their
way into this country and starting gang
violence and all that stuff. Yes, you're
absolutely right. And to deny that,
I think it's pretty fucking foolish.
Yeah. I think it's a matter of like
there's a lot to it. It's a fluid.
The border is always going to be fluid
and it needs to be fluid. You know,
we need the immigrant spirit of coming
in and a lot of them do start small
businesses when you know, and again,
when they're brought in legally. Um,
and so how do you, how do you create
a flow of people that is good for us?
Cause they say most of the immigrants
that come here are the smartest,
sharpest people,
most driven and wherever they're from.
So we're actually drawing a really good,
you know,
they talk so much about the criminals,
but the truth is most of them that
are coming over here are the ones that
probably have the most to
offer to this country. Well.
Exactly like our parents' generation.
Like our grandparents,
like my grandparents. Like when did
your, your grandparents come over here,
it was it your grandparents
or 1910 my grandparents. Yeah,
mine as well that your grandfather was
one of 13 and 12 of them came over here
and they lived in a two
room fucking mud hut.
Somehow they kept finding the money
to send one kid over at a time.
Like usually when they were about 15
horse. Crazy shit. Yeah.
See that kind of shit is what I'm
talking about. Like those kind of people,
shouldn't they be allowed to come here?
That's how this thing got started. The,
the real problem is that their
spots that suck as the real problem.
It's like we were talking
about like white privilege.
White privilege is not the problem.
The problem is racism.
Racism doesn't exist in everyone's exactly
the same and then we're okay and then
we don't need to worry
about white privilege.
What the real problem
that you're not getting,
you're not getting racist things thrown
at you the way black people are. Yeah,
for sure.
But that's not the problem.
The problem is racist things
being thrown at black people.
It's not that I don't get it right.
It's say you get it right and it's like
it took to highlight the fact that it's
not happening to me. I get what
you're saying. But the real pro,
I think it's a distraction that the
real problem is the racism itself.
The real problem is the,
when you see actual Nazis in 2018,
2019 actual ones,
real ones like not,
not just dressing up cause they
think it's a hoot. We, oh mom, rebel.
I'm fucking hell. The road, I've got a
piece of tape under my nose. The same,
there's a fucking people
that aren't really Nazis, but
they're dumb. Yeah. Right.
But then you see real Nazi
in 2019 you're like, okay,
that's real racism.
Yeah.
Now when they go into,
uh,
I was in Portland and they said there's
regular clashes like once a month
there's a demonstration and it's either
the alt right having a demonstration and
then the a,
what do they call them?
The something far Antifa Antifa show up
and they have regular fights and it's
fucking Nazis.
God Damn.
Oregon's a fucked up state
because it was originally,
there were no black people allowed in
Oregon. That's the, that's the, you know,
cause now Portland is, is
very progressive, super
progressive, super veracity,
but there's no black people there.
So it seems there are, it's,
he feels a little hollow that
when you're there rubbing shit.
I just did New Year's Eve shows there and
they were, they were, it was all white.
It was all white. It was weird. That
is weird. There. Dot. If I was black,
I would go to Portland and a second,
you'd have so many friends instantly.
Everybody wants to high five.
You have you over for dinner.