Tweet,
like first of all,
what is it about Nigerians that
do so well in this country?
That's one of the things,
if you look at like Nigerian immigrants,
like successful ratios of,
of different immigration groups.
Nigerians in particular are
extraordinarily successful
upon immigrating to
America. I think it's a family.
A family thing is like when,
when your family's decided and we get the
opportunity to move to a better place,
right?
The thing is that the whole persona is
we're going to be able to sustain this
forever. So my kids are not going
to just play around in sports.
Cause that's not guarantee.
What is guaranteed is the fact that
you're going to go to school and you're
gonna become a doctor because you're
going to get a job anywhere world that you
want. That's why majority
of them are doctors, right?
Majority of doctors engineered because
these are jobs that high demand jobs.
You always going to get a job
anywhere. Yeah. And so that's all.
That's all we push.
You're going to be a doctor or are you
going to be a a Nigeria? I'm an engineer.
None of them are saying, you're going to
be a professional athlete. My parents,
hell no.
They didn't care for that.
Like I lied to them the first couple
of years that I was wrestling.
I didn't tell him that.
You know,
my brother is a doctorate in pharmacy
in Dallas. My little brother,
you know,
could have gotten the NFL who was a s l
a football player played at University
of Houston and University of Arizona.
You know, my sister now is in college.
She's in nursing school in college.
Like that's just what we push.
We want you to get a job that you can
provide for your family forever. Yeah.
They remind me of Koreans and a
lot of ways. Absolutely. Yeah.
Super hardworking and appreciate once
they've gotten to a place like America
where there really is no
ceiling on the possibility.
You could do anything you want once you
get here, if you work hard. Absolutely.
And then this is,
that's another thing that's dear
to my heart is one of your Nigeria,
like when you're in a situation that
we were sad, my mom was a teacher.
My mom owned a store to to a little
convenience store there and we did little
jobs on the side were told certain things
on the side and on top of it raising
three boys,
rowdy boys like that.
That's what we, and in the school we
did, it wasn't like, oh there's the card.
The bus is going to pick you up at
three 7:00 AM to go to school. Nah,
the school was two miles away. Three miles
away. You walk in, you got get going.
Don't be late cause if you got,
if he was late he was going to get
a whooping before school started.
That's how it was and especially the
education system is so high because you
miss,
you miss a couple of answers on the tests.
You had to go out and get a sweat and you
are going to get whipped in school for
the answers that you missed. That
would be you in school. Yeah,
absolutely. The teacher, the teacher,
the teacher was on, first of all,
it's not teacher, his uncle and aunt,
that's your uncle and your aunt in school.
They knew your parents did to your family.
They were going to whip you in
school if you decided to, to mess up.
And that's how it was. So that's why
there's a lot of these smart Nigerians.
They'd get out and if there is no
freaking job or we've got to somehow make
money, it's so fucked up cause I
don't want people to beat kids,
but God damn when you put kids
under that kind of pressure,
my parents put me in Catholic school for
one year and I got excellent grades and
afterwards I was fucking terrible,
terrible man.
And I remember my stepfather
said something to me, he said,
your grades were only good when you
were in Catholic school. I was like,
this guy was fucking terrified down. I'm
like, I'm like, it ain't a good move.
I mean, it's like they were
threatening me all the time.
They wanted to beat me and make
me sit on a nail in the closet.