Do you think there's ever going
to be a time in, in humans,
like whether it's a hundred years from
now or a thousand years now where there's
no war?
Yes,
yes I do. How do you see
that happening? Well,
it's going to start with the cop cars
with flags on them and then they're going
to patrol her hat.
I think it would be technology and I
think it's a matter of everybody becoming
more comfortable if you can,
if you can have people,
this is like a Thomas
Friedman idea that if,
if you want to stop like people
fighting in the Middle East, uh,
give them all the comforts
of a good society,
let them be able to go eat McDonald's
and sit in a coffee shop and all of a
sudden you don't want to fight as much.
And that means prosperity.
That means popping.
So I think technology,
if you can bring more water to
people and there's less suffering,
if climate change doesn't
Jim ruin all of that?
I think if you can prop these
people up and give all these people,
if they can rise, then
there's no sense. I mean,
we're in a point now where there's fewer
wars than ever before on the planet.
Sure. So we're headed in that
direction. So I don't see why not. Well,
as a thought exercise,
let's look at it this way.
What makes anybody
decide to act as a group?
What makes anybody like if, why
would we decide to go? Like if,
if right,
what negotiations should we be having
with someone in Germany? Like why, why,
why are we having a conversation about
anything you live way the fuck over there
on the other side of the ocean.
What would make people act as a group
and go over and try to fuck with somebody
else that's in another
place? Well, people can be,
people can definitely be rallied
for any cause most certainly.
But do you think this is my thought,
that there will come a time where
that kind of rallying doesn't work,
that people will stop believing?
I mean,
this is one of those very bizarre ideas
that the systems that we've established
for, for human civilizations, whether
it's countries or cities or, um,
continents, right? Whatever
it is. These systems,
once all the boundaries that kept
people from freely traveling,
although once those are dissolved the
country anymore, they keeping this,
keeping it together now is the fact
that it's air travel so they know when
you're coming in and they
get to check your papers. Oh,
you're flying in from overseas. Arguments
to papa was only one way. Motherfucker,
you've gotta land right here,
right in this spot.
And then we take each individual and
we say, can I see your paperwork?
What do you got? Who are you? Where
are you from? Where are you born?
Do you have money or you're a drug addict.
You ever been arrested?
And then they're allowed. They could still
do that that way. If that didn't exist,
if it was way easier to go to Germany,
there was a technology
that would allow you,
like a person like you or made the
same way we could drive places.
We could just fly into
somewhere and land anywhere.
You don't have to go to a fucking
specific location like an airport or get
through a road that takes you to some,
you know,
some checkpoints station like when
you're trying to drive from Mexico.
Just if people could fly. Yeah. If people,
if people flew anywhere they wanted to go,
if that technology existed,
good fucking luck keeping people from
coming into your city. Good luck.
All those rules are out the window.
All those immigration rules that
doesn't exist anymore. Can't exist.
People can go anywhere.
They want to write it,
but what are you saying that gives you,
well,
the gives you the interaction with
human beings like and that in a way you,
you won't be able to get them as a group
as easily to go after another group.
Right. Because now there's no country
basically. There's no like thing to,
we're not part of this that has to
go fight that. Right. We're all in.
We're all one now here's the do have one
person lives in a great spot and didn't
want to give up their oil. Right. Right.
Then it becomes a problem. Right. Come on.
Resources. We're all in this
together. Those people in Alaska,
you know they got all that
fucking oil, bro, here's happened.
Here's two things though.
Here's two things of why it might not
work once technology thousand things,
but yeah, but I only two
that I can think of. Okay,
let me hear a one.
Italians are Italians and Germans are
Germans and Mexicans are Mexicans and you
get around your people and you feel it
and you know it and I know who you are
and we're part of that tribe and we're
part of that thing and it doesn't matter
that we grew up somewhere.
I just know you as an Italian and I'm
an Italian and I am with you and that is
very different from that Turkish
guy over there. That thing,
that very human thing.
Chemistry thing of your own blood,
your own thing. I don't think
that's going to go away for Bro.
You're old school and you bake bread.
I didn't. You're talking nonsense.
You're really into old things. You know
what I mean? I do love all the time.
You fix your eyes without glasses,
you'd be like, Nah, I like the class.
Make you feel like, I think I put
them on and get ready to go to work,
but I think that's a real thing. I think,
of course, than cars and your friend did,
your friend, you give him, hey,
it's not that bad and the shit is
actually really good for fertilizer.