The Joe Rogan experience,
but the celebrity aspect of basketball
is so huge. And like in baseball,
not baseball. I can't, yeah, you're a
rod and it's still theirs. But five,
10 min, Max, 10 guys on the court.
And if you do anything cameras right
on your face. Yeah. Versus you.
Here's the thing about baseball.
This was pointed out to me,
the website deadspin did this thing
where they were like pointing out the
problem with baseball today. They
went around, they ask people, Hey,
can you name what's the most famous
baseball player that you could name?
And people were like, Derek Jeter, a
rod, big Papi, Manny, Manny Ramirez,
retired guys. And if you ask people they
could match. If they're a baseball fan,
they'd say,
someone from my team,
or maybe they'd say Mike Trout or they'd
say one of the guys on the Yankees.
Right. But there is no a rod [inaudible]
like level celebrity right now.
What happened? I don't know
exactly. I can't. I'm steroids
given back the steroids.
No one's getting hurt.
What the fuck is the problem?
We're not talking about fighting,
we're talking about baseball.
Give him the steroids.
The best part about that stupid
games with someone hits the ball.
Does the steroids make them hit the ball
better? Yes. Okay. We'll give it to him.
Yeah. The fuck are you guys doing testing
for that? Performance enhancing drugs,
man are the craziest
the debate about that.
We've never done this on the show
because I, so I'm not like, um,
you shouldn't fully boned up.
I would like to,
I've thought about it in the past
cause cause the, the divisions,
it's like the rest of the drug war,
right?
The divisions we make between the things
that are acceptable and not acceptable
are so arbitrary. Right? So the example
I always use is like, okay, why don't,
why don't we like it?
Performance enhancing drugs.
Not everyone has access to
them. So they're unfair. Right.
There are bad for your health and we
think they're on natural. Right. Okay.
So yeah, they're, yeah,
they're cheating. Yeah.
Well those are the reasons why we think
they're cheating. Right? Well it's also,
but there's some drugs you can
take that aren't cheating. Right?
Like you could take advantage
is the reason why it's cheating.
That's the primary reason. So here's, so
let me give you a counter example. Um, uh,
for runners, right? Uh, for endurance
athletes, like I like running,
I'm a shitty runner, but I like
it. I think it's a fun sport. Um,
so I follow it a little bit. Uh,
so runners, endurance, you know,
the big thing is like how much you're, how
much oxygen your blood can hold, right?
If you train at a high altitude,
then you can increase that. Right?
So there are these runners,
the American runners, right?
They live at a high altitude,
they live super high up, you know,
in Colorado or whatever. Right? And
then when they're not there, they train.
They're all year round. They buy a place
there. And then when they're not there,
when they're competing somewhere else,
they sleep in a chamber that
simulates low altitude. Right.
How is that not the same thing as taking
a performance enhancing drug? Like they,
they, you know, that's not a, it's
not illegal to do that. Right? Right.
It's unnatural,
right?
It is an unfair advantage
because not everybody can
afford one of those chambers.
And I'm not gonna say it's bad
for your health. I don't know.
But it's certainly as weird for your body
is taking a drug I would think. Right.
So why it's not.
Why do we draw the line?
Cause it's only like living it out to two.
It's really just simulates low out.
So it's not like taking the CEO EPO,
which would be the drug that would
simulate that which I've got recent
experience with. Not Personally, but
because of the UFC just had one of its
champions stripped because of testing
positive for EPO and then
we're just finding out now
they don't test for EPO and
everybody that it's very expensive and
so they do it based on the athlete's
biological passport and what they think
are changing variables that you know,
for whatever reason it triggers their,
their interest and they start testing.
Additionally, it's a big deal to, it's a,
it's a serious drug.
I mean it's a serious endurance drug
but also has like some serious health
complications.
People have died from taking it.
A young guys in their twenties in cycling
have gotten strokes and died from EPO,
but there's no health negative effects
of sleeping at altitude. It's just,
couldn't you afford to live there? Can you
uproot your life? No. If you can't, yeah,
it's an advantage for that person over
you. So I'm just saying we, we have, uh,
we have sort of an are like,
yeah,
it's sort of an arbitrary w where we're
drawing the lines is not consistent and
it's kind of one that is a big one.
Does that in terms of uh,
the impact on endurance,
it is a big one.
They actually saying now
that they think the best, um,
best course of strategy is to train
at low altitude and then sleep at high
altitude. They think that when you train
at low altitude, you have more output.
So you're putting in more repetitions
because you get more oxygen so you have
more work and then you get the same
effect by living at [inaudible].
So you get, you'd get up there and sleep
and you don't have to train up there.
And if you train up there,
it's actually slightly less valuable
than training at low altitude and staying
up there damn cause whatever.
I'm whenever,
whenever I'm stands in more high alto
like I just did a weekend in Denver and I
was like going on a run up there and it
was like obviously torture compared to
like being here in la but I was like oh
I'm getting strong cause I'm running at
high altitude. That's not true.
That really fucks with me.
Well you just really simple
for me. Thank you. It's work.
It will help you but it's if you are
a net like athletes or we're literally
working for one or 2% of an advantage
occasionally on many occasions when you
are living at high altitude
and training at sea level,
they think that that gives you a slight
advantage because you can put more work
in,
especially for fighters.
They think that skill work and repetitions
and drilling is one of the most
important aspects of it and you can
just simply get in more repetitions.
You get in more drills. Yeah. But they,
you know, again though, you're right,
cause this is sort of a
performance enhancing thing.
You're not just living and just being
yourself and then showing up and
competing.
You are engaging in this activity that
re significantly raises your red blood
cells, significantly raises your
oxygen capacity, Changes Your Cardio,
your vo two Max changes. No. Here's,
here's the weird thing is just this,
there's this weird idea
in sports and look,
you know shit love more about athlete
athletics. Cause then I do, it's not my,
it's not my real forte but I do,
I do enjoy.
And the thing that's
always weird to me is that
we have this idea that like there's some
kind of level playing field that the,
there's this like baseline
human that we can just say,
well you've got to be at the baseline.
Right? Yeah. And humans are so variable.
You're always going to
find these weird cases.
And when you try to adjudicate it gets
really weird. Like, do you know about,
you know, Castro's Romania?
Do you know who she is? No.
Uh, no. I do know this story,
this story pisses me off so much.
So she's a, she's not a marathoner.
She's a middle distance runner. I
believe she's south, South African. Um,
she's like the best in the world
at the 200 meters. You know,
I actually got to see her
because, uh, my, uh, uh,
I went to the Prefontaine
classic in Eugene,
Oregon with my dad to like watch the big
track meet, you know, best in the world.
People, this is like a Olympics,
you know, not qualifier,
but it's like the Olympic caliber
athletes saw her. She's incredible.
Just like one of the best in
the world. She's got, um, a,
uh, uh, she,
her whole life has faced
accusations that she, uh, that her,
that she's a man basically,
um,
because she has like an elevated level
of testosterone and this is their natural
body. Right? And so she's had to deal
with people saying, oh, we gotta,
we gotta do a, do a sex check on
you, which is humiliating and like,
also completely unscientific, you know,
like, what, what are they going to do? Um,
and, uh, like a sex check. We want
to look at her genitals. Well,
here's the weird thing, man, is that,
yeah, they want to look at her genitals,
first of all, which is humiliating to
have that happen. If you're an athlete,
you're like, people have to be in the
room. This is, this is the problem, right?
How do you judicate that? Right?
Right. And also, there's such a thing,
I don't know anything about
her personal situation, right.
There's such a thing as Intersex people,
right?
Where when you look at their genitals,
you can't tell. It's not like, hey,
just look at their junk. And you can
tell, right. This is a real phenomenon.
Like 1% of people are Intersex,
right? [inaudible] hi. Uh, I,
I was speaking off the top of my head,
but it's higher than you think. You know,
it's definitely hard. It's a non
zero number of people, right?
Intersex people are a real
thing. Um, and so, uh, so,
but so she got past that,
right?
They stopped challenging whether she
was like a man or a woman. They did it,
but it was on toast center.
Uh, I think you might be
right. Yeah. Um, but so she's,
she's had to deal with that. That's not
fair, right? She's a physical outlet.
She's a physical outlier.
And now the IAF,
which is the organization that runs
all, it's like FIFA for track, right?
They run all track.
They have tried to put forward a rule.
I don't know what the status is right now
because it's being challenged, but, um,
they've tried to put forward a rule that
says if you have a testosterone level
over a certain amount,
you have to take a hormone changing
clothes to change your hormones and she's
going to fall under that.
And so they literally want to change
the body that she was born with because
they're saying your body is unfair
to her. How fucked up is that? Right?
It's crazy. It's really, really
fucked up. And, and so the thing is,
when we make those decisions about
what's fair and what's not fair,
there's no baseline.
Human is always a value judgment.
And when we're excluding some people,
that's almost all,
we always need to look at that and say,
are we discriminating?
They're definitely discriminating against
Castro, Romania. And is this the IOC?
That's what does doing this. I A F,
which is the IOC is the Olympics.
IAV Olympics aren't doing this,
so they don't have an issue with her.
I don't know what the Olympic policy is.
The Olympics is fucked up.
We do a whole episode on the Olympics.
The Olympics is fucked
up in a lot of ways too.