The Joe Rogan experience. When
you think about the future? Uh,
at least me though one, let
me tell you my concern. Yeah.
I'm worried that rich people are going
to get a hold of this technology quick
and they're going to have massive
unfair advantages in terms of intellect,
in terms of physical, athletic
ability, all, I mean we,
we really can have a grossly imbalanced
world radically quickly if this happens
fast, when we don't understand exactly
what the consequences of these actions are
until it's too late.
And then we'd try to play catch up with
rules and regulations and laws. Yeah,
that's a very, very real danger. And
that's why I've written this book.
That's why I'm out speaking
everyday about this,
this topic because we need
to recognize that if we have,
if we approach these revolutionary
technologies using the same values that we
experience today where, you know,
we're here and very comfortable,
but just down the road there
are people who are just,
who are living without many opportunities.
There are people in parts of the world
like Central African Republic where
there's just a warzone kids
are born malnourished. Um,
if those are our values today,
we can expect that when these
future technologies arrive,
we'll use those, those
same values. So it's real.
And right now we have an
opportunity to say, all right,
these technologies are coming whenever
we do these technologies that are coming,
there's a better possible future
and a worst possible future.
And how can we infuse our best values
into the process to optimize the good
stuff and minimize the bad stuff.
And certainly what you're saying is a
real risk thing of what happened when
European countries had slightly better
weapons and slightly better ships than
everybody else. They took over the world
and dominated everybody. And so, yeah,
that's very real.
That's the government's need to play
a role in ensuring broad access in
regulating these,
uh,
these technologies to make sure we don't
get to that kind of dystopian scenario
that you've laid down. Well, it's also
in terms of governments regulating things,
like why are they qualified?
Who are they? Who are the
governments? So just people, right?
It's people that are either elected
or the, uh, you know, or, yeah,
some sort of a monarchy earn.
You're,
you're dealing with either kings and
queens and sheikhs or you're dealing with
presidents.
And we've seen in this
country that sometimes our
presidents don't know what the
fuck they're talking about.
Right?
So who are they to disrupt science
to s to disrupt this natural flow of
technology?
Well,
we decide we need somebody to do it.
We need some representation
of our collective will,
but just to avoid some of the things,
like you're just like you just mentioned
that that's the reason why humans
banded together and made these kinds of,
the of made created governments.
And the reason for democracy,
especially if you have more
functioning democracies,
is that your government in some ways
reflects the will of the people in the
government does things
that individuals can't do.
And I know there are a
leather libertarian arguments.
Well everyone should just like, if you
want a little road in front of your house,
either go build the road
and pay some somebody. But
there are a lot of things in,
even in that model that won't get done.
There are a lot of kind of big national
and even global concerns that you need
some kind of,
uh,
of regulation because what we're talking
about is the future of life and life on
earth. And there have to
be some kind of guardrails.
And that's why what I'm arguing
for is we really need a bottom up.
And I think we every person,
and that's why I'm so thrilled
to be here with you today, Joe.
Every person needs to really understand
these revolutionary technologies like
genetics,
like AI and all of our responsibilities
and opportunities to say,
hey, this is really important. Here
are the values that I think that, uh,
that I cherish.
And just like you said,
I don't want it to be that the wealthiest
people are the ones who have kids with
higher iqs and live longer and healthier
than, than everybody else. And then,
so we have to raise our voice and our
needs to be a bottom up process and a,
in a top down process.
And it's re it's really hard.