Have you ever read any Terence Mckenna?
I know you're familiar with something
called the stoned ape theory. No, sorry,
not Mckenna. It was, uh, he was a,
an ethnobotanist and he was also a
psychedelic adventure and he had a theory.
And the theory was that the,
what you're talking about,
this climate change,
uh,
that also coincided with a
doubling of the human brain size.
His theory was that one of the things
that was in play was that these apes would
experiment with different food sources
as they moved into the grasslands.
And there was a lot of undulates and
these grasslands and it's silicide
mushrooms, which we know existed back
then would grow in these grasslands.
And that these monkeys,
these apes rather started consuming
silicide mushrooms and it led them to be
more creative.
And it also led to specific traits like
the development of language that eating
mushrooms, um, in low doses
increases visual acuity,
which would lead them to be better
hunters are more perceptive.
It also leads them to be Hornier,
which would most likely
involve more breeding,
more sexual activity
and possibly select the,
the ones that chose the,
the mushrooms would maybe possibly breed
more than the ones that didn't choose
the mushrooms because they were more
into it. Then we're more social,
more sexually active. And
he has a series of, uh,
like his brother Dennis,
who's still alive,
detailed it on a podcast we did the very
first podcast we did in his brother is,
is,
is an actual scientist and detailed it
in terms of how silicide and affects the
brain and what areas of
the brain it, what, what,
what actually takes place when you're
under the influence of this and that it
could very potentially have led to the
development of language and that this,
all these things in play, the
throwing arm, the, uh, you know,
developing these new social networks,
uh,
with where you need to communicate with
each other along with the harnessing of
fire along with the consumption of
psychedelic mushrooms on a regular basis
because they were incredibly
frequent and very edible.
All right, that's total trip. I've
never heard of that. Fascinating.
Like that's a really good
example of some random thing.
If it really did play that role,
how random that is,
that these freaking things happen to be
growing there and that they happen to be
attracted to them and ate them.
We know that animals like to get high.
I'm elephants will eat
these fruit that have,
well the drunk in this case it
overripe and, and um, become alcoholic.
We know that animals will do that.
You've seen jaguars that
consumes psychedelic plants
and they lie on their back
and stare at the sky and there
don't, no. Oh, it's amazing. But you,
you know what I have?
WASC is no, I wasco is a,
it's a way that uh,
these people in the rain forest develop
untold thousands of years ago of
developing an orally active
version of dimethyl trip to Maine.
Do you know what dimethyltryptamine
dimethyltryptamine is the most potent
psychedelic known to man.
It's incredibly potent drug that is just
intensely hallucinatory gives you these
insane visions and it also is pre,
here's the Jaguar.
It's really crazy.
And this is in the Amazon.
These jaguars eat these plants
and these plants, uh, are they,
they have the ingredients of Iowasca
and these jaguars are known to eat these
things and then trip
they're fucking balls off.
They eat them and there are pupils dilate
and they roll over on their back and
stare at the sky. I mean,
they're clearly high, right?
So this is something that you're going
to say. Yeah, this is one of my say.
So this is what Iowasca is, is
dimethyltryptamine like, look,
it's kind of cool watching
this Jaguar trip balls.
They just stare. They see shit that's
not there. I mean, or it is there.
Maybe there's some still traveling.
It's amazing. So what Iowasca is,
is w there's dimethyltryptamine,
which is this incredibly
potent psychedelic drug is
produced in the human body.
It's produced by the liver.
It's produced by the lungs.
And they also believe it's
produced by the pineal gland,
which is literally your third eye.
The pineal gland in certain
reptiles actually has a rep
retina in a lens. I mean,
it's like an eyeball.
And they think,
and the Egyptians called
it the seat of the soul.
And they think that this is
one of the reasons why they're,
they have this obsession with this
gland in eastern mysticism is somehow or
another,
they figured out that this is the gland
that produces this incredibly potent
psychedelic truck.
This psychedelic drug dimethyltryptamine
also exists in thousands of different
plants.
The problem is when you consume it orally,
your body produces something in your
gut called model Amy and oxidase and
monoamine oxidase breaks it down.
So what these indigenous people figured
out is how to combine one plant,
which contains this psychedelic
compound with another plant,
which contains a natural Mao
inhibitor called harming.
So they brew this all together,
much like they did with the cassava,
which we have no,
no idea how they figured that out.
They brew this stuff up together and
they create this psychedelic t called
IOWASCA and Iowasca.
Now they have all these trips where
people go down to Peru and take this stuff
and trip the fucking balls
off. And this, uh, this,
the combination of these things,
um,
leads to this incredibly potent trench,
really transformative experience,
which is impossible to describe.
And that this, this a psychedelic
drug. Why, why didn't I bring that up?
What was what we were talking about
how maybe chimps in are these early
ancestors did something similar,
which pushed them along this
path and starting to communicate,
how do I get to DM tail?
W W how did I get to Ios Guy?
There were a couple of
links in that chain.
Maybe it was because of animals that get
high. That's that. That's what it was.
So this is what this, that's
exactly what it was. It was, yeah.
The Jaguar getting high
on Dmt, that's what they
think the Jaguar is doing.
Just the Jaguar consuming
this stuff. He's, it's making
them trip on DMT in DMTs.
I mean, it's fun. It's really exciting
and variance. So Robert Trevors is,
is wonderful biologist who started a lot
of the kinds of work that we're talking
about going in the 70s calls these sorts
of things. A phenotypic intelligence,
right?
So evolution gave you these
pleasure centers in your
brain so that you do what's
in your genes, best interests, and kill
the animal or get the girl or whatever.
And that makes you feel good.
And so we tend to like the things that
are good for us and dislike the things
that are bad for us. We don't want
any feces we do on eat a steak, right?
So there's cases like this where it
short circuits that it goes right to the
pleasure center, even though what
it's doing, it's kind of irrelevant.
But this is a case where
maybe it wasn't irrelevant,
maybe it actually caused these animals
to then change the way that they behave
to become more sociable.
Right. It's very possible.
Something like that played
a role along the way,
which is why if you replay the sequence,
the vanishing rainforest 10 times,
only one time does it maybe
lead to anything good.
And the other nine times it leads to a
bunch of dead chimps. Yeah. Well the,
the process was probably incredibly
slow, right? Over millions of years.
The climate did alter.