This whole cult thing. I don't get
it. So don't is a weird one, right?
Because it's all like
crystals and healers.
It's all people looking to be spiritual
that they've given up on traditional
religion,
but they seem to need that sort of vibe
and so they get into like spiritual
stuff and channelers and healers.
Have you got in that stuff? My mom,
I know it all day long. One
all about channeling, bro.
That's my thing. Channeling.
Yeah. All right. I mean, no,
no. I think we, I really
do believe, and I've,
I've been believing this
more and more lately though,
that our understanding of what
our memory is is a very limited,
and that the reason why
people are scared of things,
some things is probably because there's
some sort of genetic memory of someone
that they knew.
Like I bet your kid will have somehow
or another that knowledge of that
motorcycle accident and that fee.
There's,
I think shit like that goes
through DNA. Yeah, I do.
I think that's why kids are
scared of monsters. You know,
why his kids scared of monsters?
Why aren't they scared of bullets
or fires or you know, like why,
why they're screaming,
they're,
they're scared of something that
I was scared of growing up. No,
there's animals used to eat
people. Yeah. That's what I think.
I think monster's represent
like Jaguars and shit.
Like you'd go into the jungle and try
to get some water and you get jacked.
That's our ancestors.
All of our ancestors,
every single human being on this
planet came from Africa. All of us.
100% of us. Everyone.
Absolutely Shin, black, white.
All of us got eaten.
All of our ancestors in our DNA.
It's wired that cats out there,
bro. What are you afraid of?
Monsters in the dark. Those are cats, man.
We got jacked by cats like
all the time. Yeah. Yeah.
So that's why everybody is
scared of things under the
bed. What's in the closet?
They're hiding their cats.
Big Cats looking to get you.
I don't know about that.
This was very scary for a moment,
but I don't believe in that.
Why do you think that animals
have instincts, right?
Like here's a perfect example,
but we have instincts, right?
But what kind of instincts?
Animals have weird instincts.
Like they all sniff each other's assholes.
They all piss on spots where
other animals did. They don't.
Nobody had to teach my dog how to do that.
My dog,
I got him when he was six weeks old and
I've had him for two and a half years.
That mother fucker will sniff something
and he see somebody peed on it.
He pees on it. But he learned that from
his, he didn't learn that from nobody. No.
He learned that from his dog people.
What's it like when you came over here?
He didn't know Jack Shit,
so he myself oil.
You're saying you learned that from us?
No, I think it's in his DNA. Okay. Yeah,
I get that.
But what is the DNA like?
Doesn't your DNA carry some traces of
information onto your own children?
Like what I noticed in my children,
they share certain weird traits that
I have that I don't feel like like a
obsessive compulsive traits that I don't
think they see because don't really
bring that home. Like, especially
the workout stuff and like some,
some things that I really get kind of
psychotic about martial arts stuff. My,
my middle daughter has that in a crazy
way and I'm like, Oh okay, this is me.
If I was a girl, like if I was a little
girl, this is me. Like what is it?
So is this my memory
that seen her or is it,
do I have like some weird obsessive gene,
which is,
it is the DNA because I see my son,
he's only two, he just turned two.
But he makes facial expressions and looks
like he does certain looks that I do
and, and my wife goes, he's
acting like you right now.
Do you think he's acting like you?
Cause he sees you act like that or he's
acting like you cause he knows in his
head that that's how he's wired like that.
Because when I watch it,
he doesn't know like a lot of this stuff
he does, I don't eat, I don't even do,
he just does like my mom all, I'll come
over and she'll watch them. She Go,
you know, he's just like you when you
were this age and it's so weird. Yeah.
It's in the DNA. It's in
something, right. Whatever it is,
whether it's in cellular memory,
DNA,
some sort of genetic
information gets passed on,
but the parents of the child,
you can say that about athletics though.
Like if you get too, that's
a little different though,
but it's in the DNA. Yeah.
It isn't the DNA, but it's not an
ethereal thing. Like a thought.