The joe rogan experience.
College athletes generate a lot
of revenue fucked. Yeah. Okay.
Athletes are getting pimped out.
Yeah,
a hundred percent especially in
like football and basketball. Well,
you were telling me what I was talking
to Jamie when you went to Pete about the,
how big the game was that you went to see
fucking God. And I was saying, is there,
what about baseball's
baseball? Like down like, no,
nobody gives a fuck about college.
Baseball. Basketball is a little bit,
you said March madness. Definitely. Those
are, those are the big college football.
Get that big time. That's the end. It's
worth billions of dollars. Many billions.
Yeah. Yeah. Which is crazy.
Those kids aren't getting paid.
That doesn't make any fucking sense.
Well, I got a free scholarship, Joe.
I gotta go to school for free and
oh great. Get $25,000 a years.
Where the free education,
fuck you. I tend to agree.
I said there's a couple of kids,
like a interesting story that
came out earlier this year.
He's on one of the teams that did really
good. UFC or UCF, I'm sorry. Yeah.
You see ups kicker was a Youtuber as
the season started and he got in trouble
because he was making profit
off of his likeness on Youtube.
So they took away his ability to do that.
He got kicked off the team
and I think he left the team.
Oh my God, you fucking monsters. What did,
you don't own people that,
that's what drives me crazy.
It's like you don't own people.
They're providing a service that makes
you an extraordinary amount of money and
yet you are keeping all of it like debt
Patino thing, 1.5 million to school.
I give him 10 grand, 10 grand. Is it out
of the money? That's a lot of money. Oh,
that's the argument.
I know.
I think that the thing about assholes,
the people who um,
who really argue the free education thing
and like how that should be of value
is because they ain't worth a shit.
That's why they think that's awesome.
Like your skill level is not impressive
and you don't generate millions and
billions of dollars.
So you go,
it's fucking $100,000 worth of free
education there. It's like, yeah,
but like I'm bringing in 10 million
to the table, bro. That's the thing.
And here's the big thing. How much damage
are they getting in that four years?
How much damage they're doing to
the body and football in high level,
division one FBS football,
lot of those dudes are playing and they're
playing basically with, you know, the,
the, the next NFL players.
So yeah, they're, yeah,
they're fucking each other
up fucking each other up.
And the odds of their body getting
damaged to the point where they can never
compete professionally are
very hot. Oh, definitely. Yeah.
So if you think of like there was
a statistic about NBA or excuse me,
NFL players,
like how many of them make it into
the fourth year and it's very low,
but not for long league. Very call
it. Yeah. That what they call,
that's the nickname for the
NFL. Not for long. Yeah.
The average NFL career is like three point
some seasons. Right. So think of that.
You're,
you're basically trying to do,
to outrun that through college
and then make it into the, yeah.
That's why you really,
from a business perspective,
you really have to support guys coming
out of college early to the NFL. Oh,
100% I mean there's people who are like,
some people I wrote about roads,
garage or the fuck Outta here. I read
a book. Yeah. Well I'm balling page.
I'll go back, go back with my
free time, man. Yeah, go back.
You're still only going to be 25
years old when your career is over.
That's fucking nuts. I know. There's
millions on the table. Millions.
22 come on.
Hello.
Give her think about how
poorly you would handle that.
I think about it now a lot.
If I had been 22 it's almost like
here's $10 million. I'd be like, wow.
I would definitely not have been like,
yeah, dude. Able to handle that. Well,
yeah, I think about that
hardcore or think about like,
what if I won the lottery when
I was 20 like what? Go nuts.
You go nuts. Yeah. I got diamonds
in my jacket, man. Check it out.
Diamonds on my teeth is,
my buttons are all done diamonds
on Monday co definitely. Yeah,
I think,
um,
it's like we were talking about earlier
about a guy being rich and having rich
children struggles. Fucking
very important for you.
Yeah. It's very good for you. It's very
important for you. It builds character.
It builds, resolve, respect
now. Yeah. Yeah. Respect money.
That like how many professional athletes
who wink millions of dollars work out
as hard as my friend Cameron
Hanes. Right? Think of that.
That fucking guy's a regular job.
Dude works for Department of Water and
power and Oregon. Does he really? Yup.
Nine to five regular job
during his lunch hour.
He doesn't work nine to five.
He works like seven to four.
And one of the reasons why he's got an
extra hour in there is because you runs
during his lunch break.
So he takes like two hour lunches
and runs for two fucking hours,
runs the hills and then comes back and
finishes out the rest of the eight hours
of the day. What that did, it feels
good all day though to savage. Yeah.
It doesn't feel good. He doesn't
want to feel good. Does it be pain?
He likes all the time. Yeah.
But he's happy. He's happy
in pain. I don't know, man.
I mean not, he gets shipped grimacing
in pain. He's like, this shit hurts.
There's like it.
Yeah.
[inaudible].