And he now studies were
recovering eyesight. Really? Yeah.
What about to damage dies?
Yeah. Really. Yeah. Uh,
so I don't want to freak out because
I know a guy who's got significantly
damaged, die from fighting. Well
I can tell you what we've done.
Um, and this is work we're
writing up for publication now.
We've done a few things,
three things to the mice.
One is we've pinched their
optic nerve and crushed it,
which is a test for
growing neurons in the eye.
And we find that with our reprogramming,
we can make the nerves be just like a,
a newborn baby. They grow back. Uh,
and then we also tested on
glaucoma pressure in the eye.
We increased pressure in the mouse as I,
and they lose their largely their
eyesight and we can recover that.
And then we also test old mice that
don't see very well and we also seem to
improve their eyesight almost
back to normal. So what,
I don't think we'll be going
to nursing homes anytime soon,
but what we are doing is running
clinical trial on this. Um,
and so we're looking to do that in early
2020 in the clinical trial will be on
people with glaucoma
or various eye issues.
The plan is Glaucoma first.
Um, but it could work for
other, uh, damage written as,
as well even broken spinal cords
where we're thinking of trying. Wow.
And that's just one part of the body.
Imagine what it could
potentially do to the rest of us.
Do you feel incredibly fortunate
to be living in the century? Uh,
I do every day, but I would love to live
next century cause it's gonna be, yeah,
but you're,
what's cool is you're kind of at the,
the tip of the spear pushing this
stuff right now. Like you're,
you're going to be one of the guys who
gets to see this stuff get implemented
from your actual own research where
it didn't exist before. Uh, yeah,
that's pretty damn cool.
Better than like living a hundred
years to now where you just take it for
granted. Like a trust fund
kid, you know? Yeah, I have it.
Just imagine what she can do
in a hundred years. You can,
well maybe you'll be here. Where
on the one on the OT? Yeah,
you might be 150. We'll say.
I think there's a chance
someone will be, well, it's,
it's a good chance you're going to be,
I mean,
you're the one who's going to know well,
so here's my philosophy.
I'm not going to let anyone try technology
until I've tried it first. Really?
I was taking in and then
pause because you're,
you're currently doing
something like that.
I'm not doing the three programming yet.
That's a little dangerous.
But the others I've always
wanted to know first.
My eyesight is starting to go because
I'm 51 now. And uh, like when I read,
like if I had to read this book,
I got a Nick Christakis his book
from sitting here reading this book.
If I don't have reading glasses on, I
got to do this. It's a bit of a struggle.
You're gonna be able to fix
that. So potentially in the
mice we can, you can, we,
we don't give them books to read, but
their eyesight improves. We can test that.
How do you do it? Uh, there's
a moving screen. No, I don't,
I don't mean how to you,
how do you know, how do you test
or not, not how you test rather.
How do you improve their
eyesight? Uh, we've,
we've put these reprogramming genes into
a virus which is already used to treat
genetic diseases in the eye and we inject
it straight into the master's eyeball.
This sounds like the beginning
of a horror movie. Yeah.
I think it's actually
are an awesome movie.
It's the awesome part that I'm focused on.
Well,
if you're going blind one injection
from your doctor and then you take an
antibiotic,
turn the genes on for as long as you need
and you get your eyesight back.
That's not horrific at all.
That's a pretty incredible, how far away
do you think you are doing it to humans?
Well, 2020 will be the first
safety study we hope. Wow.
Yeah. But the, the crazy stuff, the
future is, if this all goes well,
you have an injection in your vein,
let's say when you're 30 and then those
viruses infect your body and they sit
there dormant until you need them.
So when might you need them?
You might have a car accident, turn
them on, can turn them on with just a,
an antibiotic in a drip or in a pill,
or you start to lose your eyesight taken,
take an antibiotic. So you put them in
your body almost as an insurance policy,
and then you have the option to turn
them on in the future. Exactly. Wow.
That's what we do in the
mice. Now, with every action,
we assume there's some negative
consequence or potentially
negative consequence.
Right? Uh, we always assume
that, but it's not always right.
So with the molecules that we've
been testing for years now,
I can imagine we haven't seen
any downside, just longer
endurance and protection.
So there isn't always a downside
to these things. In fact,
if you just think NMN is replacing a
molecule that we lose over time as we get
older, it's just becoming, you
know, it's fairly natural process.
No downside exercising and dieting either.