But what would doctor heard is talking
about is in the first chapter of the book,
which I guess you haven't read.
Um, and I really should have a
copy for it. Stupid of me. Um,
I got a copy of my bag.
So that's really smart though.
So this is fascinating to me.
The,
the British colonized India,
and they set up what they call lunatic
asylum was really psychiatric hospitals,
sort of very primitive
psychiatric hospitals.
And they were really initially
for soldiers in the Indian
army and they were run
by British doctors.
And what these doctors really
as early as like the lead 1850s,
1860s noticed was that a lot of the people
who showed up in these hospitals were
showing up with Cannop, what they
called Ganja. Actually in India,
it's called Ganja or bong, which is
a very weak preparation of a, of,
of basically, uh, uh, uh, Indian hemp,
just sort of low grade
cannabis. Um, and so,
and so they started counting and they
realized the 20 to 30% of the people who
were coming to asylums
were heavy cannabis users.
And that was way more than alcohol.
It's more than opium.
And it's really fascinating.
Doctor named, uh,
George Francis William Humans wrote a
book in 1908 and he looked at the evidence
and, and it is amazing to hear
how he described schizophrenia,
how he describes cannabis,
how he describes the cases of
violence around cannabis. It's like,
it's like any psychiatrist today.
Certainly any forensic psychiatrists
like my wife would, would like,
everything in the book
would ring completely true.
And it was so fascinating to me to stumble
on this and realize this is something
people have been talking about
for more than a hundred years. So
could we agree that there are some
people where cannabis is not a good idea?
Absolutely. Right. We can agree
that, I think we all agree.
We're also agree that some
people can't eat peanuts.
Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. Right.
And yeah, it's not the same thing though,
but yeah. You know why peanuts kill you?
That's, yeah, it's more dangerous. So
these like second 600 a year. Yeah.
People die from peanuts.
So I think more people die from cameras
as a result of that homicide and the
suicide. Okay. Well,
there's no correlation.
There's no paper that I know somebody
has got to do the work. Wait a minute.
But why are you saying that then?
Because I've looked at enough data to
tell me you think marijuana is causing
homicides. Oh yeah. This
is what the book is about.
But in how so and what was it causes
paranoia and psychosis in people.
And paranoid psychosis are huge
risks for homicide and schizophrenia.
Studies that refute that was noticeable
starting. No studies that refute that.
Paranoia and psychosis are
huge risks for homicide.
Schizophrenia is a 20 x 20 times Joe.
Well Jamie,
I sent you a document, uh,
yesterday. I mean there's,
there's multiple studies that show that,
you know,
marijuana laws are not associated
with any type of violence.
Marijuana law was just
talking about the drug.
So the use of the drug,
which could possibly trigger psychosis,
psychosis and schizophrenia,
which are correlated with murder.
Is that what you're saying?
They're not correlated their triggers.
That's absolute fact triggers because
of the paranoia and delusions and you
think that someone's out to get you and
they're not. Absolutely. I mean the,
the out of the numbers, the, okay,
so the numbers are, if you're,
if you're have a diagnosis
of schizophrenia, uh,
you are 20 times as likely to commit.
Homicide is somebody who's healthy.
Now it's actually worse than that for
cannabis. Okay? And here's why. What,
so the National Alliance for mental
illness and the mental illness address
advocacy groups hate talking about this,
why they hate talking about it obviously,
because it stigmatizes people with
mental illness. So what they say,
and this is true,
is if you have a diagnosis,
but you're taking your anti-psychotics,
even though the side effects might be
unpleasant, you're in treatment, you're,
you're,
you're not using recreational drugs.
Your risk for violence isn't that high.
It's not that much higher than a
healthy person. Okay? And you know,
fortunately healthy people
don't commit murder that often.
The problem is if you've, if you think
about the math for half a second,
if there's this one group of people who
don't have a very high risk for murder
or serious violence, who,
because they're not using,
because they're on anti psychotics,
it means that the excess risk in the
people who are using and who's untrue,
psychosis is untreated.
It must be spectacularly high.
And the numbers bear that out.
So,
so there's a really good
study from last year,
2018 it's small group of
patients in, um, in Switzerland.
Switzerland is a safe country,
has a low base crime rate,
but 50% of the people who were using
cannabis and had psychosis over a three
year period committed violence
in that group of people.
That's mostly 20 somethings.
Well, you know, there's, there's a
study here and I just sent it to, uh,
Jamie and it's, it's titled, um, risk
factors for violence in psychosis,
a systemic review and Meta analysis
of 110 studies. So, you know,
that's quite a few studies. Okay.
So, um, you know, let me just,
just read a part of it out too.
So violence was strongly associate
with a history of polysubstance abuse,
strongly associate with diagnosis code,
mid substance use disorder and recent
substance misuse and moderately associate
with it. History of alcohols misuse,
a history of substance misuse,
uh, recent alcohol misuse, recent drug
misuse and a history of drug misuse.
It was unclear if there was an association
between violence and a history of
cannabis misuse. So again,
this is 110 studies,
uh, they very carefully looked at at all
of the different risk factors as to what
could trigger violence. Just let me
finish Alex. And what they said again,
it was unclear if there was an association
between violence and a history of
cannabis misuse. Right?
So that's 110 studies. So
cannabis use in there is going to get
locked in with poly substance use because
a lot of people use are going
to be using other drugs. Uh,
Holly substance means multiple
substance, alcohol, cannabis, exactly.
Everything else was found to have
significant statistical signal.
And I have not just mine to study
that a doctor heard assignment.
I'd like to look at it
without looking at it.
I can't push back as hard as I would like.
What I can tell you is that I have
many studies in the book that show that
cannabis use is associated with
violence in people with psychosis. Okay.
And more broadly,
it's associated with violence in the
general population in large studies,
in studies of high school students and
bullying in studies of people who were
vacationing in Ibiza, in, in,
in studies of young men
in China and the UK.
There are big studies out there that
show cannabis use is associated with
violence, Ibiza, Ibiza.
It's been a busy place.
Let's say of ether.
I got grilled over there for that.
They get manager,
I suppose to just said it,
some dignitary or royal person had a lisp.
Right?
Isn't that how it all starts at true?
Yeah. Yeah. I believe so. Noted. Yeah.
The way the people in Spain pronounce
words was directly affected by this one
person apparently. But
um, so this, uh, these,
this correlation,
um,
between people that have
schizophrenia and using cannabis,
how do you,
is schizophrenia a diagnosis?
It's purely based on behavior
basically. Yes. It's a clinic. There's
no blood test can do a brain scan.
It's basically how you behave and,
and what'd you tell the doctor
about how you're feeling
and then what about our message?
Our eyes are,
it's very subjective because you're,
you're asking someone basically
a series of questions. I mean,
it's no different than, you know,
depression really. I mean, you, you just,
just asking someone a series of questions
and then you know, based upon that,
which is very subjective than you're
going to make a clinical decision.
Whereas when it's like a blood
test, like if someone, you
know, passes, uh, you know,
a certain amount of hemoglobin A1c,
you know,
depending on which
chart you're looking at,
then you're going to call that person
pre diabetic or diabetic. But, you know,
unfortunately we just don't have those
objective measurements. And again,
that's why, you know, Alex was saying
earlier that, um, that, you know, the, uh,
they couldn't really figure out,
you know,
how many people in the United
States had had schizophrenia.
And I understand that. But at the
same time too, I mean, it's okay to,
to adjust,
you know,
the way that you diagnose someone over
the course of the years and you learn
things because,
you know,
you could easily say that almost everyone
has some type of mental illness and
people should understand that,
you know,
there's seven different basic
human emotions. You know,
I've talked to this for,
it's, there's, there's anger, there's
contempt. Uh, there's, there's discuss,
there's fear, sadness and happiness.
That's seven. So, you know,
depending on which way surprise goes.
I mean, six out of those seven are,
are negative, right? Because we're
wired to basically detect threats.
So, you know, um, w when
we're, we're making, you know,
the, all these diagnoses,
I think we have to be careful because,
you know,
some people are calling themselves
to press and some people are calling
themselves anxious when really,
you know,
they're just not dealing with basic human
emotions that they need to understand
and need to deal with.
Like,
people are getting angry about being
angry or like depressed about being
depressed. They, if you
feel one of these emotions,
just kind of sit with it and just kind
of reflect on it. And I think, you know,
that's a much, much better way to kind
of kind of tea to tease things out.
But you know, to come back to my
original point, I think that, you know,
more people are understanding that um,
you know,
we don't just need to give out a pill
for everything and that, you know,
everyone shouldn't just be labeled as
having a mental health diagnosis because
if things just keep going the way
they are, you know what, what's,
by 2040 it's going to be like 50% of
people are going to have like a mental
health disorder. So like people just
need to understand that life is hard.
You got to deal with these emotions.
Sometimes it's not that big of a deal.
And that's why for subs, for some folks,
and that's why I'm such a big thing of,
of Jordan Peterson because you know,
he's, he's, he's kind of tough on people.
Let me stop and shook his Jordan
Peterson was on Ssri is for years. Yeah.
That's interesting. Yeah, it was a
long, long time. I mean like for a long,
long time as was his family.
And what's crazy about him,
it was what got him
off is a carnivore diet
diet where he only eats meat with salt
and drinks water and the healthier than
he's ever been in his life.
And that is a,
another massively controversial subject.
Let me push back a little bit because
I think people as controversial as the
book has been about, uh,
about cannabis and psychosis,
this violence issue is even more
controversial. And obviously for,
for a fair number of people,
it doesn't really,
it doesn't sync with the stereotype
and it doesn't say it with how they've
experienced cannabis
use. Right. So I think,
I think alcohol's a really
interesting comparison. Sorry,
the Canadian,
well you have to go national.
We were talking about,
my wife's actually from new family.
So you feel age as an understand
marijuana recently and decided to say,
you can't say Newfoundland
trained myself to say that way.
You're telling me I'm wrong.
Just pulled up.
Marijuana use increases violent behavior.
50 year study finds casual link
between cannabis and subsequent violent
behavior. A new research published, uh,
online in advance of print of the journal.
It's like a psychological medicine
concludes the continued use of cannabis
causes violent behavior as a direct result
of changes in brain function that are
caused by smoking weed.
Over many years,
researchers have long debated a possible
link between the use of and violent
crime in contrast to alcohol,
meth, and many other illegal drugs.
The mellowing effects of cannabis scene
unsuited to promoting violent behavior.
However,
ample,
ample previous research
has linked marijuana use to
increased violent behavior.
The sticky problem in such studies
are that many confounding factors,
cofounding factors, uh, involved in
interpreting this correlation. So,
so look,
okay,
it is very difficult to determine whether
or not any statistical correlation
between marijuana use and violent
behavior, our, uh, cash causally linked,
or instead the two associated,
uh,
or instead the two are associated
through some other factors such as
socioeconomic status,
personality traits are many
other variables that are
related to the propensity
to use marijuana.
MMM.
So I, I think that's a fairly good
summary of the, of, of the issues.
What's up James?
The study came from 411 boys
who were born in 1953 in London,
97% of which were Caucasian.
And all of them are raised
in two parent households. So,
so, you know, so those
people are relatively stable
if they're the two family,
two parent households to hand parents
beat to shit. No, it's possible. But so,
so let me so, so, so I think
the alcohol comparison is again,
a good one because anybody who's ever
been in a bar at 9:00 PM and gone back at
2:00 AM knows that alcohol
disinhibit people, right.
It causes fights, right. It,
it makes people loud.
It makes a lot of fucking too.
It's good and bad.
I don't know if that's good.
I mean sometimes it's alcohol
and sex are a terrible idea.
It certainly causes some sexual violence.
Sure. Okay. But at the same time,
everybody knows that you can have a drink.
You know,
you can have a beer at the back of your
barbecue, you can have glass of wine.
It doesn't mean that you're going to
get in a fight and you actually might
enhance your conversation,
social lubricant, all that
good stuff, good stuff.
And you might even know people.
I mean,
I do know people who I would say
have a problem with drinking. Okay.
But it's mostly they're sitting
at home drinking scotch,
watching baseball until
they fall asleep that night.
Now that's obviously not a
healthy way to use alcohol,
but it doesn't make them violent.
But we know on a population basis
that alcohol causes violence.
It causes drunk driving,
it causes problems.
And it said that in this study
that I quoted earlier, but it's,
it said that alcohol again, they didn't,
or sorry, cannabis, they weren't sure.
Right? So, okay, so this is again,
I would like to read the paper that
you're quoting from because I have so much
other research. But here's, here's
what I'm saying about cannabis. Okay.
Cannabis for a lot of people.
Yeah, they can just smoke
it. And as people, you know,
many people who have tweeted at me,
the only thing I attacked
was a bowl of Nachos. Right?
And so and so that's true for some people,
but that can be sent with the alcohol as
well. That's exactly logical variables.
There's so many studies that say that,
that the cannabis laws have
actually decreased Crimea.
She gotta let me finish. Let
me finish. Let him finish.
Go ahead Alex. So, so
even though for many people,
cannabis isn't going to cause violence,
that doesn't mean it can't cause
violence in some people especially,
or at least could be a factor
of at least could be a factor,
especially with the kind of
violence that I am talking about.
And then I write about in the
book, which is again, so alcohol,
it may be makes argument into a brawl.
It makes a brawl into something
where somebody picks up a stick.
It makes that into something where
somebody pulls out a knife, it escalates.
Cannabis is different.
Cannabis Causes Paranoia and psychosis.
And it certainly causes
us things temporarily,
even if it doesn't cause them permanently.
So a distortion in reality that could
lead to you doing something terrible and
it's usually to somebody
you're not actually fighting
with. It's a family member.
The worst cases that I've,
and I've really seen a lot of these cases
are basically innocent family members
who are just in the way.
When somebody loses touch with the
reality and literally things like this,
my 85 year old grandmother
is going to kill me,
so I better stab her to death first.
That happens.
It happens a lot.
And if you look at the amount of violence
that people with psychosis command on
a population level basis,
it looks like people with schizophrenia
commit about six to 10% of all the
murders in this country and it looks
like people would sort of broader diff,
more broadly defined psychosis.
Again, bipolar with psychosis,
other psychotic conditions,
temporary psychosis,
they might be responsible for as much as
20% of the violent crime in the United
States.
That's a lot of violent crime.
And what I'm saying is that it is
quite clear that drug use mediates that
violent crime. In other
words, if you're not using,
you can keep your impulses in check, but
when you do use, you become dangerous.
Sure.
So when we're talking about
biological variability,
if we factor in schizophrenia,
essentially what you're saying is that
there are people that have schizophrenia
that don't commit violence,
but that they're much more likely to
commit violence if you add some sort of
psych medication, whether it's
marijuana, whether it's something else,
it perturbs reality for them.
And particularly marijuana
because hotbox bring down the
recreational drugs, the worst cases
of all our cannabis and a stimulant.
Because to the they both like cocaine or
meth. Exactly. Yeah. So when you get that,
you get paranoid from
two sources and you get,
the only good thing about cannabis from
this point of view is it kind of knocks
people down a little bit,
but meth brings them right back.
So is it fair to say that what we don't
know is that we don't know whether or
not these people like this young band
with his terrible story from Connecticut,
we don't know whether or not he would
have become a schizophrenia and exhibited
those symptoms without the marijuana.
We really don't know.
But we do know he did with it.
That's, that's correct. And,
and what I would also say is
that for somebody like that,
and this is quite clear
on a population level
basis with people with schizophrenia,
is you've got to
discourage them from using,
really have to be discouraged because
it brings out the worst. Right. And,
and you know, somebody said this, uh,
a friend of mine of old friend of
mine from the New York Times said,
so every time there's a hurricane people,
some people on the right say,
well you can't prove that global warming
cause that one hurricane that would've
happened anyway and he and there,
right,
you can't prove it and you can't prove
that any one case of psychosis was caused
by marijuana. But when you look at the
big studies at the population level data,
the association is really clear and
everything points the same way and the
synthetic cannabinoids k two and spice,
those can clearly produce
psychosis in people.
And people with psychosis tend to slip
back into it if they use at some point
you got to start to say to yourself,
why does everything go the same way?
Yeah. I also have a personal friend and
I really didn't think about this guy,
but there's another personal friend
that I know that is a martial arts
instructor that had a psychotic break.
He became schizophrenia and he's a regular
marijuana user and the people around
him associated that with that.
And in fact people that
are regular cannabis users,
we're trying to get them
to stop using marijuana.
If hired close to pricing on the edge,
any use a little bit of cannabis
for sure it can be Tyson can.
This guy was not on the edge
when I knew him, when I knew him,
he was very rational,
very rational.
But something happened
somewhere along the line was he,
did he become a pretty
heavy smoker over time?
I do not know because we don't
live in the same area anymore,
but he got really heavily,
uh,
really heavily medicated and did some
really crazy shit and want to being
hospitalized.
And this was not the case before I'm
in whatever it was that triggered him.
I mean it, when I was around
him, when he was younger,
I would have said he's a total normal guy.
And I would have never saw that coming.
He was a heavy marijuana user, heavy,
heavy. But I don't, I don't know how he's
doing now. I hope he's okay. But we're,
you know, we have mutual
friends and uh, he became uh,
schizophrenia and, and you know, you
will see, you know, cases like that.
But you know, when you do look
at a lot of the larger data on,
on cannabis and violence, I mean
it's just, it's just not there.
Like there's lots of data
that suggests that, you know,
medical marijuana laws for example,
can actually have a decrease in overall.
I mean,
I think that's a study that says it
gives no comfort to the people who lose
their children because of the
psychotropics. That's right.
And those studies are really bad.
So the place that you can criticize
a bad though, because there,
because state level data is not great,
the place the book has been criticized,
right?
Mandra.
There was a rand review though in 2013
and I mean that again that state by state
conclude that marijuana use does not
induce violent crime and the links between
marijuana use and property client
crime are thin right there.
I think we all agree that marijuana
use by itself with people that aren't
schizophrenia probably does
it induce violent crime,
but with people that are schizophrenia or
people where it triggers schizophrenia,
it could potentially induce violent crime.
My friend did not get violent,
although he did do a violent thing.
It wasn't to a person. I think.
I think we have to be really careful
because there's no, just like with diet,
just like with food and
you know like a allergies.
All of these different variabilities
when it comes to human beings,
I think we have to be really,
really careful about lumping all people
together when it comes to how they get
affected by various compounds. So the
state level, if you want, I'll, I'll,
the place the book has been criticized
in my mind sort of the most fairly is it
points out that in the four states
that legalized first, which is Alaska,
Washington, Oregon, Colorado. Um,
if you look at 2013 and then you compare
that to 2017 murders and ag assaults,
violent crime,
um,
are up substantially in those states
and substantially more than in the u.
S can I stop you there?
But is there a possibility
there's a correlation between
organized crime because
one of the things about selling marijuana
is the people that have always been
selling marijuana have been criminals.
When you make things legal and estate,
the people that were selling
it illegal flock to that state.
And that's been proven to be true,
that there's,
there's a direct correlation
between people being robbed,
that there was also a significant
problem with credit cards and banks where
everyone was having to do all
their transactions with cash.
There was a lot of violences
was associated with
marijuana in regards to that
and also massive increase in population.
And that's the way,
the reason why,
why Trump has actually not really
against cannabis in some ways,
it's because he feels that if we
have medical marijuana laws that,
especially the states that are,
that are border states,
that the crime's gonna drop and drops
a lot tremendously. And it has dropped.
They did a study last year
and it dropped over 50%.
It's all around drop 7% in
Arizona. And then again, you know,
Benjamin Hanson, who, who's,
who's an economist, the wrong
data. So for his charge,
okay,
so he,
he said that the murder rate did not
demonstrate that marijuana legalization
increases violence, then it may have
actually demonstrated that legalization,
it's slightly decreased fonts.
And he thinks that,
that the reason that there was
an increase in the murder rate,
particularly in Washington,
is because there was a large income gap.
They say that Washington has
a 10th largest income gap,
uh, in the United States.
But that's why, how did that
change corresponds to the
murderer? Good question.
I'm so, I haven't, you know, I didn't
get to speak with Benjamin to about this,
but sounds like confirmation
bias. Well, he, I mean if that,
that is one thing that has been shown to
increase mental illness like we talked
about and can definitely increase
violence, is when you have an income gap.
But how's the income gap shifted?
That directly correlates to
the legalization of marijuana
because during the scene, because
during the same period, the income gap,
particularly in Washington in increased,
so he that
the corresponding number, right? So
he feels that, that it's likely more,
more to that. And I mean
he, I mean, I understand,
but I mean you have to respect this guy,
man.
I respect him because I know what he did
with his data and telling me what to do.
This, this is maddening to me. Okay. Okay.
Violent crime in those four
states increased more rapidly
than in the u s period
between 2013 and 2017 who Jamie
just posted the conjecture aside,
no credible data exists.
It supports a significant association
between the increase in violent crime and
marijuana legalization.
Furthermore,
study suggest that so far violent crime
decreases in states with legalized
medical marijuana until new
research credibly suggest otherwise.
The claim that a demonstratable link
between the two exists will remain
classified as false, so that's just
not true. Okay. I know it's Snopes.
Okay. And I know we trust
Snopes. I don't trust them that
I was going to say that too, but they
give all of their their sources. So again,
by daily. So do you, are
you, where are these sources?
I've read this stuff and
what's wrong with them here?
Let me just go back to what I'm saying.
Yeah, please do it. 2013 Oregon,
Washington, Colorado, Alaska.
There are 450 murders
in those four states.
There are 30,000 agg assault period.
Okay.
2017 Oregon, Washington, Colorado, Alaska.
There are 620 murders in those four
states, that's an almost 40% increase.
There are 38,000 agg assaults at the 25%
increase. If you adjust for population,
you still get big increases. In
Denver, 2018 almost 70 murders.
There were about 35 and 2013 Seattle,
27 2018 there were 34 35 murders.
There were,
I think 19 in 2013 these
increases are real. Okay.
Now now, now, okay.
Can we say that marijuana
legalization caused those increases?
We cannot yet there are
other possibilities and
you're, what are those? Um,
well, one positive first of
all, population did increase.
It's also possible that these states,
quote unquote imported violent crime and
other ones that you've got a population
of transients coming in in part because
marijuana was legal and those people are
likely to commit violent crime.
And on top of that organized crime,
people that are selling.
Absolutely.
There may have been some people who are
exporting to, to Nebraska, to Minnesota,
to other states.
There's crime associated with that.
But what I am saying is that
unequivocally, unequivocally,
the people who said legalization
is going to decrease violent crime.
And people did say that.
And Cory booker in 2010 17 said it,
he said that it actually had decreased
violent crime in states that legalized.
And he didn't say it it randomly,
he said it when he was introducing
legislation to legalize marijuana on the
federal level. Those people are wrong
and they need to stop saying it. I know.
And by the way that
Oregon economists used,
he used the wrong data set for his charts.
Okay. He used, I used the real numbers.
Okay.
The FBI homicide numbers,
he used numbers that include
justifiable homicide, no police,
because the FBI report that the murder
rate went up 1% from 2015 to 2016 as
compared to the nationwide,
which one was 7.9% and then it dropped
by 11.6% between 2016 and 20 seconds with
numbers. Do not know what
you're talking about. Okay.
Those are FBI numbers of breeding and
not know what you're talking about.
The numbers are clear. Okay. I
use them reading them right now.
2016 release of FBI uniform crime
reports from Oregon. Okay. Yes.
Oregon. You're not reading the
reports from the United States.
You're picking one state
for women showing something.
We'll state that has legalized medical
cannabis over the entire country from
that time period too. So to pick those
four states where marijuana was legalized,
sort of Cherry picking,
no,
that it's picking every state where they
were legalized and comes to the whole,
to the whole country. The whole country,
the whole country. You'll see similar.
Is it a similar increase? That's
what I'm trying to show. Yes.
If I'm trying to pull back so we can
see the hole. The hole. So first of all,
that's a violent crime.
Crime,
a violent crime and that ag
assaults, aren't they? No. So so,
so the four categories of violent
crime or murder, agg assault,
robbery and rape. Rape has sort of
gone sideways the last few years.
Robberies actually have gone down.
It's murders and ag assaults that are
interpersonal violent crime. Okay.
Just to go back to this Oregon economist,
because this maddens me,
he used a Dataset that is not
the standard data set to report.
Murder rate is a difference.
He used the data set that
includes justifiable homicides,
meaning I'm in my house, you come
in, I shoot you and kill you.
The police don't charge me with
anything and police homicides but gets
published. Let's not let an
interrupt. Let me finish the,
those two categories of crime are not
likely to be impacted by cannabis use.
Cops are not smoking when they're on
patrol. I hope. And if you are using,
you're very unlikely to have your
murder viewed as justifiable homicide.
The fair comparison is the base murder
rate in the u s and that's the number
that I used. And I am telling you,
I mean, I, I know these numbers,
I sleep, I wake up with
these numbers, cannabis,
the for cannabis legal
states on a per capita basis,
crime murders rose 31% on a per capita
basis in those four states over the 2013,
2017 period. Maybe, I'm sorry,
I said 31. Maybe it's 29%.
So maybe I say I woke up in the,
anyway,
the the for the u s
it's 18% 29% versus 18%.
That's the gap.
And I am not saying that I know that
cannabis legalization caused that gap.
What I'm saying is people need to stop
claiming that cannabis legalization
reduces violent crime. It in, it has
increased in those tasks. You in those
states was at universal, the increase,
was it almost identical? Yes.
At Alaska was the most, uh,
then I think murders went up
more in cow in Washington. Uh,
and what's also
interesting, Joe, if you're,
if you really want to go into the numbers,
is the gap actually widened year by year.
So that's sort of what you would expect
if this is the result of a psychometric
effect.
In other words,
a psychosis causing effect
because cannabis doesn't
cause psychosis right away.
People break down.
But if it's causing heavy use and
some of those people are sliding into,
you know,
paranoia and psychosis,
you'd sort of expect the gap to increase
over time. And that's what's happened.
Okay. So, you know, I'm gonna go
back again to the Netherlands. Okay.
Because they've had,
you know,
cannabis legalized forever and they have
one fifth of the homicide rate that the
United States does. And they also have
a lower cannabis use. That's true.
They also, but still, you know,
one warrior for kickboxers bus,
but,
uh, one, one fifth. I mean, it's still,
it's, it's pretty drastic overall. And,
and again, you know, Alex, you know,
you know, I appreciate some of the,
are we talking about the
correlation between cannabis use?
One of the things that we have to accept
in America is that when you're in a
place like the Netherlands has a
long and accepted history of use,
people are accustomed to it.
So I think things kind of even out.
I think one of the things that we're
dealing with with the United States is
people that have just,
they don't,
they don't have a long
history of experience and it
becomes legal and then they
use it.
And maybe some of them,
like we're talking about don't have
a tolerance for it, have too much.
And like I was talking about with my
friend who's like this really cotton,
the one who, uh, had an edible and
became suicidal and fucked up for weeks.
You guys very confident, very
articulate, very intelligent. He's not a,
not a Weirdo, not a non transient
extreme, extremely successful.
You know,
I think there are,
there are variables that we need to take
into consideration and there's certain
human beings at exhibit a pattern of
behavior that's directly correlated to
cannabis use that I don't experience.
So if I,
I could say from my own personal biases
that that's bullshit. That's nothing.
It doesn't do anything. I've been
smoking for years. Doesn't do shit.
Well you probably don't have one of those
three genes that we were talking about
and you probably also to, um, you know,
don't overuse or you have
some type of, you know, um,
legitimacy as to why you are, you
are using it. And you know, one,
I want to keep going with this, but
you know, at the end of the show,
I think that we should make some type
of like recommendations for people just
because I hate when you know,
you have this big three hour podcasts.
Then at the end of it it's just like,
hey guys, just be safe. You know,
it's like,
fuck it. Let's have some type of like, um,
recommendations. Like I love
the podcast with, uh, with,
with Chris Kresser and Joel.
Right? But, um, at the,
at the end of it was just sort of like,
hey guys, do anything there can die.
I think most people realize that one
person was going on data and the other
person was. Yeah. I mean, I,
I find it so fascinating that now
when you think back through your,
through your life, you've,
you've thought of somebody who,
who was affected and
there were several people.
I'll bet I'll bet as you think about it,
you'll think of more people maybe.
But those are the big ones.
And like I said,
my friend who is a martial arts instructor
was a pretty significant issue with a
lot of our friends.
We were trying to figure out what
was wrong with him beforehand.
He was sending me these videos that
didn't make any sense. And uh, I was like,
what in the fuck is this? Like, uh, I'll,
I'll explain to you more off air so
I don't have to uh, out this guy.
But what will the,
all La,
a lot of people that were close to
him were really seriously concerned.
And now is it something that would have
happened anyway? I don't know how he,
he's in his twenties. How old is
that? Late twenties. 20, you know,
that's right around the age.
So it is a little,
a little bit late Ish. Like, cause
like I said, a lot of the studies,
even when you look at the
ones on adolescents, like
for sure it's, it's below,
like they've,
they have done studies like below 18 is
worse than say below 25 blow 15 is worse
than say 18. Like the
younger you go, the worse.
And He seems to be fine now
and it's,
uh, you know, I'm not an expert on the
subject, but it's because of this, um,
if somebody called pruning
that we go through,
so everyone goes through this and
basically if your adolescence,
you're going to drop off some,
some weak neural connections to kind of
pick up some stronger ones. So, you know,
it's the best way to kind of explain
it. Um, when you use cannabis,
you can potentially
accelerate that process.
And then because you
accelerate that process,
you don't get those good neuro
connections. And then, you know,
people unfortunately, you know, develop
things like psychosis and, um, and,
and schizophrenia. So, you know,
that's kind of where, where they were,
where the issue lies. So, you know,
one thing that I am very happy that we're
talking about and I know Alex will be
too, is that, you know, we want to
discuss the benefits and in this podcast,
make sure that people understand that,
you know,
I believe that marijuana is Madison.
It's an excellent medicine. Um,
but the other thing though too is we do
want to mitigate the risks because there
are real risks out there. So, you
know, I do appreciate, you know, um,
US talking about adolescence and
making sure that they do stay away from
cannabis, especially that's like twice.
I've read these, you know, these cases,
there's a case file sometimes then,
you know,
the kids started using when
he was 11 and you know,
it's like that kid never had a chance.
Right. I mean, and obviously the,
oftentimes these are kids coming from
disadvantaged backgrounds anyway,
but you know, they're using by
11 it's 16. They put a, you know,
put a gun to somebody's head and
pull the trigger. I mean, the, the,
the pre adolescent and early teen news,
we got to do everything we can to stop.
The problem is, yeah, like if you, if you
smoke pot in junior high, like say seven,
eight, nine, like you're probably
going to smoke pot in high school.
Like that's the know what I mean?
That's what I saw when we went out,
when I was growing up.
And you know,
even when I was home for Christmas
for a few days, like yeah,
a couple of my friends even talked about,
you know, um, some people that we knew,
you know, smoked a ton of pot in high
school and like now like they're there,
they're crazy or they're not really
doing too too much, you know?
So you do have to,
because with the,
I think we're dealing
with a lot of ignorance.
We're dealing with a lot of ignorance
when it comes to biological variability,
right? We, we,
we don't really understand how a lot of
these different things affect people,
including like just diet and what, what,
what causes depression, like how much,
how much of what we constitute or
what we just decided as depression.
Is Inflammation a poor gut health?
There's a lot of variables. A lot of them.
Marijuana is absolutely one of
those variables. And uh, again,
I don't have an issue with it. I liked
it. I love the stuff, but it does,
it doesn't fuck with me,
but I'm also honest and so I see these
people where it's pretty obvious to me
that something's going on and that
marijuana is not a good idea for them.
And I just think, you know,
like I said in the past,
I myself have been guilty of using this,
uh,
this sort of a blanket description of it
as being a positive influence and that
it's a good thing for people. I don't
think it's a good thing for everybody. No,
it's definitely not a good thing for
everybody and it's definitely not a good
thing for the people who have those
genetics that I discussed earlier.
And you know, also too,
like, you know, if you,
you need to have some type
of like self awareness,
like the people who you know don't
do well with cannabis, you know,
you shouldn't have your,
to have your friends tell you that he
came in like you're not doing too well.
You should be able to figure out yourself.
But that's hard for people.
I mean that's one of the most
difficult things for people to do.
Is it self upset, self assess to be
objective? You know, it's a real,
I've obviously,
I've heard from a lot of people who used
heavily and seen other people who've
used heavily in the last month.
And I think it's very interesting why
people continue to use when they're
getting paranoid and, and you know,
the, the most cogent argument,
and again, I'm, I'm not, you know,
I've smoked a handful of times
in college and after college,
I actually don't think I'd be comfortable
using high THC cannabis now knowing
what I know. But anyway, so the
people, the most Godson, Ryan here,
okay,
I'm going to get hot box.
I'll give you the shit that,
but,
but the most, the most cogent arguments,
I thought it was so interesting.
This guy said, well, you know, my
friends, I talked to them and say,
I'm paranoid now,
but I'm going to smoke through it.
I'm going to smoke so much that I'm
almost comfortable being paranoid.
And I think that's a dangerous thing
to do to your mind, cause you're,
you're sort of counting on being able
to step back from that and stop using.
Yeah, that's a, that's a
silly, we're looking at it. Um.