Now there's no public support
for lobbyists, right? There's no,
there's no people out there that are
super psyched that lobbyists are out there
and exerting their influence on our world.
But they obviously have enormous financial
backing behind them and they have
incredible influence in our,
in our culture.
But if you had some magic wand that you
could wave across this system and fix
it, wouldn't removing lobbyists the one
of the first things that you would do?
No. No. Why? Why so? Well,
because look, you know, Congress,
especially in the current government
legislates on a whole bunch of issues that
they don't have a clue about,
right?
They don't know squat diddly about
99% of what they're legislating mouth.
They need information.
Um,
one of the other things Gingrich did
was to completely may C8 Congress's own
information service.
They used to have a really powerful
information service that help congressmen
figure things out.
All of that basically gone.
So they rely on outsiders to come in and
help them understand it. Now, my view is,
you know,
that's an imperfect system because there's
great inequality among the quality of
lobbyists.
But if all lobbyists were doing was
providing information like, congressman,
here's what's going to happen.
If you pass this bill,
like these jobs will disappear or this
lead will reappear in the water system if
that's all they were doing.
That's a really valuable thing.
Information to the Congress to help
congress decide but to do is an essential
part of making democracy work.
The part of lobbying that
is the corrupting part where
they become the mockers
for the money. Not so much that
they give it directly, but you know,
they call their clients and they say,
you need everybody at the c level in
your corporation to send $2,700 to this
person,
and they steer it like that.
When they become the kind of source
of a resource for members of Congress,
that's when they have this influence,
which is not related to their argument.
So you know, I've met lobbyists who,
who hate the system as it is right now.
They'll say things like,
look,
I want a system where I win because my
ideas are good. My arguments are better.
I don't want a system where I win because
I'm able to channel more money than
that guy. Cause that's not a
democracy like a democracy should be.
These representatives are listening to
us and then they do the right thing based
on what they think helps
their constituents,
not how much they're going to
raise if they do this over that.