Well, it's so clever because
it's so comprehensive.
There's so much involved in it and the
fact that they're willing to do this for
years and years before they really sort
of activate the political aspect of what
they're trying to do. It also, it's,
it's strange that they're so sophisticated
about our culture because we don't
know a goddamn thing about Russia.
The average person knows Putin, bad,
evil, warlord, Crimea. He
invade. You know, like we, we,
we have like a four year old's
understanding. Like if you had a,
if you just grabbed a person,
random person that's your college
educated person and ask them to describe
what's so bad about Russia. Wow. It's like
communist over there or something. Man,
I'm Elaine [inaudible]. They hate us.
First of all, they have bombs like this.
There's so little
understanding of their culture,
but yet they know so much about hours.
That's one of the weird things about
being an American. When you go,
when you travel overseas and you realize
how much they know about our elections,
how much they know,
we don't even know who the fuck
there was running their country.
We don't have any idea,
but they know about Trump and they know
that Hillary did this and they know that
Bernie wants to give the money away. And
you know, it's, it's crazy. It's, it's,
it's weird.
And these people must have
like a deep education on, uh,
American culture,
American politics and man,
do you think they're training these kids?
Yeah,
absolutely.
I would.
So they did a couple of things that
came out in the Mueller indictment.
First of all,
a couple of people actually came here
and did a road trip around America.
Oh. Literally just to
learn when to Texas. Yeah.
Basically telling me where
you keep the beef jerky
that was in the, uh, one of the, I
think the Mueller indictment of a,
from February 28 teen,
there've been three kind of big documents
that have come out to from eastern
district and one from Mueller on,
um, on how, how it all worked out.
I think another misconception is
this notion of $100,000 in ads.
They spent $18 million in 2017,
I believe was the stat that came out
during another one of the Mueller
indictment's. So they're
not just, you know,
the money's not just going for
the salaries and the ad buys.
The money's also going for.
Um,
they were talking about using kind of
consultants and this is where you get at
this thing that comes out during the
standup or they're like black people who
are LGBT don't want to
see white LGBT memes and,
and this degree of granularity,
that degree of sophistication,
but then also what you see them doing is
engaging one on one and that's where it
crosses the line from social media
operation to this as much more like,
uh, like spying. You want to watch the
Americans? No. Oh, I love that show.
You should definitely go
to that. Great. It's great.
There's too many things to watch. Totally.
But what's interesting is the, um,
it, it does paint a pretty
interesting picture of like this, um,
this couple under deep cover that are
engaging with and pretending to be
Americans and forming relations.
Jen, apparently it's
based loosely. Unreal.
Yeah. That's what I've read
also. But what you see in the,
in the Mueller indictment is the text
messages is the messenger or the Facebook
messenger messages where they're going
back and forth with real activists and
they're saying things like, um, you
know, hey, my ad account got shut down.
Can you run some ads for me?
Or the,
hey, I want to help your protest. Um,
we're fellow black lives matter activists
and we see you're running a protest up
and I think it was like Ethica
or something, Binghamton,
how can we help you?
We can give you some money for posters
and they're sending money for posters or
they reach out to a Trump
supporter and they say like,
we think it'd be really funny to have a
Hillary Clinton impersonators sitting in
a truck, flatbed truck that's made
up to look like a jail. Let us, um,
if we give you some money, will you find
the Hillary Clinton impersonator and, um,
put her in jail and do this
Hillary for prison thing.
And so this is where another thing that
they did was using Facebook events to
create real world protests.
So they're not limiting it to shit,
posting online and making
people feel tension online.
They're actually sending people out
into the real world to have in street
violence.
And so one of the things that they did
was they coordinated a Facebook event, um,
one for the Texas secessionist
page and one for the,
there was a pro Muslim called
United Muslims. And on the same day,
at the same time in Texas,
they have a rally to support,
um,
Texas culture and resist
the Islamicization of Texas
across the street from a
rally to defend Muslim
culture. And so they, like,
there's literally no,
they just create these Facebook events
on these pages and then they promote them
with ad dollars and other
things. And, and you literally,
if you go and you look at the
Texas reporting from that day, um,
I don't remember if it
was dozens or hundreds,
but a sufficient number of people showed
up that they had literally on opposite
sides of barricades,
police officers in the center screaming
at each other because one group is there
for the resist the Islamicization of
Texas and the other group is there to like
defend Muslim culture. And
so you get to, you know,
two opposite sides of the spectrum
in the same place at the same time.
And you literally insight like
a mini riot. So they, there,
there were about 81 of these
events where they were holding, um,
black lives matter style rallies for
victims of violence, police violence, um,
memorials for people who were
killed by police officers. You know,
things that real Americans would do.
But this wasn't being done by
real Americans. And that's,
that's the insidious thing, right? Is, is
how does, how does Facebook detect that?
How to,
how to you when you see this come to
defend Texas culture and you're a diehard
proud Texan, you know, you're not thinking
like somebody in St Petersburg is, is,
is organizing this.
And that's the, I mean,
I think that the idea that
this was just some memes,
um,
is just not,
it doesn't respect the significance
of what they were trying to do and how
effective that they were with these
other things where even if they're just
trying it out just a little bit,
just working to see what works.
They're always experimenting.
They're always trying to find
ways to create that tension. Um,
and that's the thing that I think
is so interesting about this, right?
This evolving, this idea of an information
war where these tactics evolve.
Um,
and you are really at a disadvantage
when it comes to actually detecting them.
Yeah. And on the outside, if you're
looking at that, you'd say, well, okay,
what is their objective?
Why would they have this Texas a session
as page across or rally across the
street from a pro Islam rally?
Why would they do that? You know,
if you're on the outside you think about
the amount of effort that's involved in
doing something like this. And they are
also doing this with no leaders, right?
There's no one there that's
running it when they get there.
So all the pro Texas people go here,
we are looking over there.
So if the mother fucking enemy,
I think
couple times there were comments on some
of the like archived pages and things
where you could see the
screenshots of people being like,
dude you hell it is all come out there.
And like nobody
showed up who is in charge. You know,
they're probably throwing a lot of things
against the wall hoping that they set
it up.
It's on something
stacks.
Will you see this on the,
there was a page called black matters
and black matters was interesting cause
they went and made a whole website.
So they made a website. Black matters,
you ask.com which I think is still active.
It's dormant.
They're not updating it,
but I believe you can go and read it.
And it was designed to call attention
to police brutality type things.
And so they had this
black men or is us page.
And then there's the black matters
Facebook page, the Twitter account,
the Instagram page, the youtube
channel, the soundcloud podcast,
the tumbler,
the spacebook stickers.
They had Facebook stickers that look like
little black panthers. Like little, um,
little cats. Yeah, a little black
cats. They were actually really cute,
very well done.
Um,
so you have this entire fake media
ecosystem that they've just created out of
whole cloth,
all theirs.
And then what they start to do is they
start to put up job ads and so it's
Cumbia designer for us come be a come
write for us come photograph our protests
come. Um, you know, they
have like a kind of like, um,
black guy dressed in a cool
outfit like hipster, you know,
holding a sign like join black matters.
Um,
you see them go through a couple of
different logos the same way you would if
you were starting a media brand.
Um,
they start posting ads for,
do you want to be a calendar girl?
Send us your photos on, do you want
to be on a black reality TV show?
Send us video clips of you.
Um,
do you like they begin to do real
work to ingratiate themselves with the
community that a physical fitness thing.
It was called black fest and
the idea was that it was, um,
kind of vaguely militant desk,
um,
in that it was supposed to teach a
black people how to handle themselves at
protests, should there be police
violence, how to fight back.
And they actually went and found a guy,
a physical fitness martial arts guy,
and they were paying
him via paypal. So, so,
so he was running classes for the black
community under this black fist, um,
brand. And they would like
text him or call him. He,
he played some of the voicemails
on TV. Actually I heard them, um,
after my report came out,
I think they tracked him down and um,
and he just talks about how they,
yeah, they just pay pal them, you know,
a couple hundred bucks every
time you ran a fitness class,
what was the voicemails
like? It was, I'm a little
concerned the police say you'd,
you'd be,
you'd be surprised they actually had a
youtube channel with two black men named
Williams and Calvin and there was this
channel Williams and Calvin and actual
book actual yeah, they
hire these guys, um,
to be a fake youtube
channel. Um, and it was a,
it was called a word of truth,
I think was what the name of it.
And so Williams and Calvin
and these two guys would, um,
would give their word of truth and
their word of truth was usually about,
you know, how fucked up
America is, which I mean there,
there are very real grievances underlying
all of this and that's the problem,
right? They have things to exploit, um,
writing these things for these
gentlemen. I imagine. I mean,
imagine they were definitely paying
them and they organize the channel.
It seems likely channels organized.
Yeah. That particular one,
I think that they were actually,
they were in on it.
They knew what they were doing.
That guy,
one of the guys who was in that channel
popped up again in 2018 right before the
midterms. Like, maybe even the day before,
I'm trying to remember the timeline here.
Um,
and he made a different video saying
he wanted to, this was amazing,
saying he wanted to leave the internet
research agency kind of. So he was saying,
um, basically, um, I'm
tired of doing this work.
I want to,
I want to do a leak,
I want to show you all of the things at
the Internet research agency has done.
And so they actually put out this.
So this guy who had been in
the Williams and Calvin video,
so people recognize his face in the
2018 midterms goes and says he wants to
leave and he's going to leak
all this information and sorry,
this damn cough. Um, and he
wants to to like confess,
I don't remember all the specifics because
it was right before my thing came out
and I was so busy working.
But um, but yeah, he,
he pops up again and he is saying he like
wants to expose the truth and I think
most people didn't cover it,
didn't pay attention. Youtube,
shut down the channel and deleted
the video immediately. Um,
I think that it was seen as another
influence operation. You know,
you don't trust the,
um,
so even his intention that he's going
to expose it was probably just another
level. Well, what wound
up coming out, this was,
this is so convoluted.
I'm sorry.
I know it's like hard to
explain without visuals. Um,
what they wound up doing was
they did drop a bunch of docs,
so they did release a pile of documents
in which they claimed they actually
hacked the Mueller investigation.
Mueller had nothing.
And so this is again another kind of um,
convoluted piece of this where
they do release information.
And so in this particular example,
they release information that we
believe they actually got through legal
discovery.
So the documents that the investigation
provided to one of the indicted Russians
were the documents that they then leaked
claiming they had hacked the Mueller
investigation. So they're constantly
doing these things to generate press,
generate attention, create just that
degree of people don't know what's real.
Um,
or they read the headlines that are
then released by the more propagandist.
We overt Russian propaganda and they
think that that is the true story,
that, that, that, that is, um, that,
that the Russians hacked the Mueller
investigation. So there's always this, um,
how do we create fear, uncertainty,
and doubt? How do we throw people off?
How do we come up with these
extremely convoluted spy games, um,
that leave people feeling unbalanced,
that make people wonder what they can
trust, who they can trust and what's real?
And even as somebody who
looks at this stuff, you know,
day in and day out for years, um, I,
I do still regularly get surprised by the,
uh,
by the sheer kind of ballsiness
and ingenuity of, of, of, you know,
some of the stuff as it,
as it comes to light.