Oh, because I know I don't want to
jump into a car with a fucking man.
Listen to me. I just leave
fucking and leave. Uh,
Aspen, I owe like $80,000. I
got eight people looking for me,
the cops and looking for me.
I go from Aspen to boulder.
I needed jobs. So I take a job
making Joe, I'm not kidding,
one 60 a week,
60 hours as a fucking Shag,
which I'm the guy that takes a car from
you and the body shop when you pull up,
takes it. And I wash it. And
then they start to body work.
And then after they'd done the bodywork,
I'm the guy that washes it and it'd
be do that for three or four months.
Then they'd turn you into a detail and
I passed the test and I became a detail
and $160 a week. Oh, it was
fucking garbage. I was starving,
starving. But I was good.
And I became a detail.
The detail of them was commissioned and
you made a hundred to a buck 50 a day.
And you know, I was enjoying it, but
the guy I had as a boss was dead.
His name is Dirk Jordan.
He was just a big dog.
He was one of those guys that was one of
us. But when they get a manager's job,
one that I'm back there washing the
fucking car and I see a dead rat,
I pick the fucking ran up and he
had his jacket hanging by the door.
I put the dead rat in his
pocket of his jacket. You know,
meet though. I go home, I get
stoned, I don't know nothing.
The next morning he comes in,
Oh,
and this cat car is fucked up.
Like he hit like a poll.
He went in his pocket to get a cigarette
and he pulled the fucking rat out and
he fucking just went crazy. It didn't
like a Paul. He came in running,
I know who did this.
I'm going to get to the bottom of this.
And he kept blaming some other guy.
Oh my bosses. Okay. Fuck man.
That's one of the worst relationships
ever. A Boston employee,
one of the worst relationships.
Some guy gets to tell you what to do.
He's the fucking,
he's the head guy at the office.
You got to listen to this fuck head.
That is one of the worst positions to
be in working for a guy who's a deck and
that power that someone would have,
you know, if you were, you moved on up,
it became the office manager.
You can control people's future
control where they get a raise,
how much time they get off.
You can make the decisions whether or
not he allowed them to do certain things
was fucking terrible.
Was the wars boy that's come on be clean.
But all of them was boring.
Distraction.
What was the first guy you looked
at and said, you know what,
if I ever see outside of the, I'm going
to you up. I never said that. But uh,
guys in construction they would
get real Dickie. I did one time,
there was a guy when I was a teenager
that was talking to a bunch of shit,
he would hit me with a hammer.
Yeah, there was a cause he got,
he got aggressive with me and it was,
it wasn't in a way where um,
I deserved it.
He was just bullying me and I was like
1617 but I had already had a fuck load of
fights by then like taekwondo
fights. I was like, dude,
I'll kick you in your fucking head.
Like you talk a bunch of
crazy shit to me like this.
Like he was talking to me in a,
not just a way like a boss employee.
He was talking to me in a way where I
was going to have to quit, but I never,
never, never said I was
going to do anything to him.
I didn't like threaten him and say I'll
see you after this and I'll fuck you up.
I said, don't talk to me like
that cause I could fuck you up.
That's basically what I said.
Well but there was,
that's the thing about construction is
like there was a lot of like man to man
type conflict.
Like it wasn't unheard of to hear about
street fights between guys who are
working together.
They got pissed and pushed each other
and punch each other in the fucking snow.
You know,
dudes carrying a roofing tiles.
One guy knocks another guy over
or something. They start fighting.
That shit happened all the time.
There's a lot of the people
that were doing labor too.
We're like real dirt bags.
Like there's this one guy that
I did labor with. Um, I worked,
my friend Lee Roy Rodriguez and his buddy,
they had some business partner.
They would take apart old houses
and Redo them. And Leroy was, uh,
one of the black belts at
the, the Taekwondo Institute.
He was a bad motherfucker.
And uh,
Leroy got me this Gig and uh,
I worked with these guys labor and in one
of the guys we work with lived in this
fucked up, abandoned building and will
not abandoned but stripped out building.
I mean there was parts of the
building when there's no floor,
it was all fucked up.
Half the walls were missing.
They were redoing the whole building
and taking things out and fixing things.
This guy lived there and he had a mountain
dew jug filled with malt liquor and
he would drink it warm all
day and he'd had the shakes.
Everything he did to do have the shakes.
He was just drunk all day on a
crazy job site where like, you know,
there's no floors sometimes
everything's all fucked up.
You have to balance when you're going
from one room to the other because they're
tearing down parts of the wall.
And this guy somehow or another fucking
slid on through drinking the entire time.
And I remember thinking like,
these are people that have
made questionable decisions.
It makes you want to go back to college,
makes you want to get a
degree when you're around.
A lot of these guys like laborers
and stuff, like, you know,
some of them are just like me.
They're just young guys who
need a Gig and they need money.
And some of them are dudes have been
doing it their whole live and they're 50
and they're drunk and yeah, and their
body's calling for terrible by yourself.
Yeah. I don't know if I want to do this.
I definitely knew I didn't want to do it.
I definitely knew I didn't
want to do it. Well, you know,
to be a carpenter is a different gig.
You know,
like a real good carpenter that's a
skilled craftsman and an artist. You know,
you're putting together things that's
different, but the Labor Gig was not like,
you didn't really have to know anything.
You just had to be big enough
to listen to them. You know,
big enough to like pick things up.
Can you go get that?
Go get me that bag of cement.
Go dig deep. All right,
you guys going to take nails
out of these boards now?
And it was like that kind of shit. You
just hung out with the weirdest people.
Matt, worst guy. I remember Joe
Rogan. I was clean from coke.
I was clean about 90 days. I was
really trying to turn my life around.
I answered an ad construction,
a carpenter's helper.
He hired me. I went and I first
day you had to work for free.
Worked for free. Yeah. So I
said, okay. I agreed to it.
I met first.
They worked for free.
I cut this stuff and you got to go get
lunch and the whole thing. Yeah. Okay.
I did it. I passed and then
the guy would say, okay,
meet me at a diner at eight
and when I go get paid,
he'd say, what's those hours? And I go,
you told me to meet you yet 80 it was
like no one should be or windshield time.
So let's say the job,
we didn't get to the job by 10
that's when you start getting paid.
That's when I started getting paid
and I was, you know, I was at,
I was really trying, I lived with a friend
that wanted to give them rent money.
I was trying to put away some money.
I forget what he paid me.
Then he made me pay for my own lunch.
Then one day he said,
where's your weight belt? Your, you
know, work belt. I don't have one.
He goes, okay, I'll pay.
You have to pay me the
for the materials plus 30%
30% yeah.
You're a fucking scumbag just to have
like a claw of fucking hammer and
something else.
I forget what it was to work for him to
worry to have your own tools I saw and
stuff like that. And yeah,
there was always a thing,
whether it's union or non union,
you know,
there was a lot of the work that I did
when I was a kid was non union and a lot
of the people didn't want a union.
They felt like the union guys,
they had it easier, but it was, it was
too expensive and people didn't want to,
you know, use certain people. So
it's, it was like a real debate.
Like what's better for every mile?
The union people,
you have to have a certain mind nine unit
cause that works, the balance it out.
Right.
So everybody makes money.
But it seems like in some things like auto
workers, they don't fuck around. Right.
You know, everybody has a story,
breaks,
glory time lists.
If a job opens up, how do we
get it? You got to go on a list.
Rogan has lone minority than Diaz.
He started nine months before Diaz.
He gets the job. You know, it's not about
knowing all that shit. Well that dude,
I'll never forget that news name and
what he did and the scumbag he was to me,
but I'm Fridays,
he would make me feel bad like he goes,
so how many hours did you work?
And I can go 38 he got enough,
I'm paying you for 30 and he bullied
me, this guy. But every Friday he go,
this Friday I'm going away.
I'm going here to fuck my wife in the ass.
And he was always an asshole. And then
all of a sudden I got my construct,
my check,
I got this check I was waiting for and
one Saturday I'm sitting down, I'm like,
I'm sick of this motherfucker.
I'm going to rob his house.
And I jumped the fence and
I kicked the back door.
And he was a guy that
bought hot shit on the side.
He stole a sack of Shit.
And he must've had,
I dunno how many fucking bottles
and cases that dom bearing yard.
So I fucking ran up to the call and the
call my buddy go meet me at this address.
And I took every bottle of
dom Perignon and he had,
and I sold them at liquor stores.
I took his checkbook. I mean,
I buried this fucking guy just by how
bad he treated me with such a fucking
scumbag.
Never bought lunch.
He was always making crate, you know,
he's always making little fucking remarks.
Well,
that's what we were talking about earlier.
What are your heads when a guy gets into
power, that's a piece of shit. Oh my God.
It was such a fucking show him.
Yeah.
I remember I had this tee
shirt for a long time.
I used to wear it and smile every time.
Jay Chess or some shit like that.
Fuck him.