The Joe Rogan experience.
Well that is the one area of your life
where you've got some or furry in control
and that's, yeah, that is
what on the bow is like the,
well I can stop myself being like, uh, uh,
watching pornography. I can stop myself
using drugs if I want to. Like, you know,
we have some support and that's
what that this book here, mentors,
we should talk about you in only for
a paragraph. You know what I mean?
It's not too, it's not like,
uh, like literary fellatio.
It's as a small nod of your, uh,
of your influence in impaction.
I talk about how we have light and latent
qualities within us that are sometimes
hard to realize on,
on without support.
But if you find a mentor in an area
where you're looking to improve,
they can get kind of energized,
awakened energies within you there on
your own you wouldn't be able to use.
I had a really recent experience of it
where I was sort of like freaking out
about something.
I spoke to like a,
a mentor of mine and like the way that
you sort of spoke to me was like sort of
aggressive, like a sort of an
aggressive, that's not going to happen.
You are not afraid.
And like it sort of woke up the
part of me that's feels that way,
that has that kind of,
I would say sort of a male certainty
are kind of grounded energy.
He was able to sort of like direct at
me and like in that moment in myself or
but welded, I wasn't
able to do it, you know,
and needed to resource it
externally in a moment.
So this is how I sort of feel
like your individual journey.
I'm interested in how,
because I'm guessing with your
background in martial arts and stuff,
men or ships seems pretty much stitched
into that you must continually be
looking at someone learning from someone,
trying to equal them or whatever it is.
Yeah.
The good part about that,
as you get good at learning things and
you get good at listening, you know, uh,
as a martial arts student, you don't
just listen, you listen very intently.
You bow, you say, sir, you
know, I mean there's a,
there's so much discipline
involved in the, the,
the act of learning.
Yeah.
And so much reverence and respect
for people to know more than you and
appreciation. So, uh, that,
that helped me with pretty much
everything I ever wanted to learn.
I just would listen very
intently and I don't think, ah,
maybe I could figure it out better.
I will.
I'm very good at listening to
people that are good at things.
That's interesting. Did you
first get into like, you know,
I've picked up stuff over
the various shows that, of
yours that I've listened to,
but would you say that your inaugural
rural interest in martial arts came from
kind of domestic distress and stuff?
We have a difficult home life and,
and not a good relationship
with your Stepdad Mri.
There was that, but it was, was also
moved moving more than anything.
Anonymous does a nice guy,
but it was stepped out.
It's always a weird situation.
You know?
No one likes the dynamic of someone
having sex with their mother.
I remember I had similar
feelings about my [inaudible].
I don't want to like,
no, of course I'm in a
bad way. Not just what was really hard
was moving a lot and running into bullies.
That was way harder than anything else.
So there was a time in your life where
you felt very presumably vulnerable. Yeah.
Not grounded. Didn't have any friends.
Constantly moving in new neighborhoods,
meeting New People and uh, you
know, and when you're a young boy,
you're a teenage boy. Teenage boys are
fucking dangerous. Yeah. Made it worse.
They're the worst.
You see a group of them.
Now I'm talking about my country for 1314
years old are across the street. Yeah.
Loneliness. Well, young boys are just,
they're always looking to impress each
other and the, the, they have these,
if you want to find real toxic
masculinity, it exists in teenage boys.
Yeah. And it's mostly
exaggerated, didn't men,
the way it's described as
mostly exaggerated in terms
of the way the media talks
about it,
but in its purest form and teenage boys,
they get together and they start light
and frogs on fire and doing shit.
They do things because they want to like
one up each other and they feed off of
each other.
Like what one boy would do is so
different than what five boys would do,
what five boys would do.
It could be horrific,
but with one boy would do on his own.
It's very rarely there
because what you know,
you have to think about yourself
and think about is this right?
And you objectively analyze the way
you're behaving and I'm like, um,
yeah. People wouldn't be proud
of me if I did it this way.
When you're with five other boys and
you're all rambunctious and fill with
testosterone and piss and vinegar, you
wind up doing crazy things. This is I,
you know,
when I hear something like that,
it's difficult not to think that it's
of course relative relative to us,
the behavior of adolescent
mouse is reckless and crazy.
It's not impossible to conceive of
an intelligent that would look at the
behavior of adult human beings
and think, oh my God. Yeah,
all what's governing these people? What
principals are they using right now? Like,
what's the end goal to like what are
you trying to accomplish with your life,
with your existence,
with your time?