Based on what some,
based on what we voted on,
like if people really knew the
information involved in like the safety of
marijuana. It does it freak you
out, you? Of course it does.
Does it make you paranoid? Yeah, 100%
but does alcohol make you an asshole?
Fuck yes it does. Oh yeah, but do I think
that everybody should have all of it?
CBS reject Superbowl that based on the
benefits of medical marijuana? Well,
in their defense there's probably a bunch
of people or stockholders and there's
a lot of decisions that are
made that are made by lawyers.
I just want it just before people get
angry about something that CBS decided to
do.
You have to understand is CBS is
responsible for the employment of untold
thousands of human beings.
They're going to have bud
light ads right next to this.
They will or whatever and they will.
They will, but bud [inaudible],
Bud light ads are not going to affect
anyone's bottom line. I don't agree.
I don't agree,
but I just want people to understand
that part of the problem is that the
business aspect of this has
not been fully established.
Once it's fully established,
CBS and all these people are going to
realize it isn't any different than bud
light.
It's not any different than anything.
You can get fucked up on bud light
if you just drink 20 of them,
you can't fucked up. You can walk
into trees. We do it on, you know,
cough medicine or what
else? Anything. I mean,
how many pharmaceutical drugs
can you get fucked up on?
And do we deny that some people who have
like serious injuries benefit greatly
from pain pills? No, they definitely
do. The thing about it all,
all is you gotta be honest and let
people form their own opinions.
And part of being honest about it,
about these things is tell
them the pros and the cons.
Everything has a pro and a con,
including a whole people banging
it out and nursing homes.
Exactly. Getting Committee, uh,
you know, it's not good. The, the,
the pro and the con is my dad's a pro
banging old ladies in nursing homes,
but the con is he's probably got some
stuff on his little wiener down there.
He's probably passing
to biological footballs,
but he's not getting pregnant.