And have so much money. I'm sure.
Look, it's a good move and rightly so,
that Bayzos dude's burning money. You
can do whatever the fuck you want. Yes.
So much money.
Although his girl has half now she's
third on the list of richest Chakachak
Chuck. Yeah, he has that dimey
piece with them now though.
Hulu has gotten that game too for
live stuff, so there's not that.
It's like everyone is playing the game
pretty soon. It's going to be over.
Imagine if you're trying to
do a shoot a sitcom right now.
Could you imagine if a guy got divorced
from a woman who was like a duchess or
some shit and made out in the
deal as good as Jeff Bezos,
his wife was gonna make it out to be sick.
Does she initiated like $1
billion or something like that?
She had way more inability.
Get Billy Young son.
They said as soon as they divorced she
going to be like top 10 richest in the
world.
Yeah.
He gave her like 25% of its stock
or some crazy shit he get. Yeah.
Like, but they did start together
like his room. Yes. Listen man. Yeah.
She deserves it. But it's
hilarious. It's so much money.
Like damn.
She banked on it correctly.
She's hanging out with that dude when he
was like 24. Go on this fucking psycho.
Have you seen that around the world? Have
you seen that? Yes. That picture. Yes.
Yeah. That is amazing. That's, I
want that. Send me that picture.
I know you're a picture.
Do me a favor and send that to my phone.
I need to see that. Isn't that
great phone? I'm going to,
I'm going to put that as my,
uh,
I'm going to replace the American
flag with that in that great.
I'm serious end. He's like,
and he's like shaved his head.
Trt on malice,
bawling.
Just look at that banner on the wall.
Look at the,
just the little [inaudible]
banner. Look at him there, dude.
And have you seen his new
girl? What's up? Holla? Sure.
That caught you about $40 billion,
but you gotta be happy. Yeah.
He looks like he's enjoying us.
When you have 80 billion, what's 40?
Who gives a fuck, how much can you
spend? And by the way, I spend it.
Do you think he's going to, he's,
here's the problem with that dude.
He might be making so much money that
you think about it like when did Amazon
even start? Was it 15 years ago? I mean
what second ago? It wasn't that long.
I don't know what's going to be like 15
years from now when he's on fucking gene
doping and they got them
back dated to a 24 year old Bayzos
Tj's Chin looks thicker is he's got a
shoulder caps Ron and she's going
to be 85 years old running shit,
looking 30 how much money do you need?
He'll have that guy billion,
billion dollars. Like how much
money? This is my point. Like if,
if he stays healthy and is enthusiastic
and still has like this drive to
succeed,
how much is going to be worth how when
you start getting that kind of momentum.
That's why companies like that's why you
get people like Elizabeth Warren but I
don't know too much about her politics.
But one of the things that
I do know about her is um,
she wants to shut down or break
up some of these big companies.
You know there's a,
yeah,
I forget what big companies
she was talking about but
that would be an example.
Like yeah, just too much
power. So much about,
she'd probably want to break them up.
It's interesting cause it's
like you see like what is,
when you see capitalism play out right,
you see someone, they start a business,
they want to kick ass,
they want to make a lot of money and then
they do and then they keep calling and
then they get to this point where
they can make more money more easily,
more often. And they just
keep going, keep going.
And then they get to this point where if
you hit the right river at the perfect
time, but the most ambitious
person ever at the helm,
and you've got this fucking boat running,
running down this river,
just pass and everybody, that's
where you got Amazon with Jeff Bezos.
It was the perfect guy at the perfect
time with the perfect adjusting to the
role of scrooge McDuck he's,
he's making, he's like,
Elon wants to make a rocket shop.
Give me a rocket ship. Correct.
It's an ego thing. Why is he going
to need that work spaces too though?
You have nothing to do.
Like what challenges does he have?
That one click is the shit. If you
need something, it's the Shit Amazon.