Right. Well, I'm going to blow your mind
with my technology in this conversation,
which I just read an article
yesterday that in uh,
China face recognition is the thing that's
gonna stop your fantasy of everybody
just loving each other and going around
in China there with face recognition,
they're able to recognize and
categorize Muslims in the country.
There's like this one sector of Muslim
in China and they're with all this face
recognition that they're seeing, you
know, from your phone, from everything.
They're starting to catalog
the enemy and they're,
and they're going to be able to police
or sharing information and hotels and
everybody and they're all
now through this network. No.
What type of person just walked into this
building and whether they're friendly
or they're the enemy and that thing,
that face recognition thing is PR could
end up splitting us apart even more.
Hmm.
Oh,
Tommy Tommy with his
technological facts here,
China's big brother
surveillance technology isn't
nearly as all seeing as the
government wants you to think.
This is kind of like a,
they might be able to upgrade
it though, can't for sure.
Yeah. That's one point. Oh,
when your phone unlocked
with your fingerprint and
it blew your mother fucking
mind, you're like, bro,
it's roots. My Fan Guard.
Even worse. My pinkie five
fingerprints on this motherfucker.
It'd be like I said,
as I get to do the side of my thumb
and it's still knows she has glasses.
The Cop,
what do you mean with that is a cop.
It's a cop with Google last,
it's got some sort of
face recognition thing.
It's like that time Tom Cruise movie
minority report. Whoa. Was that
real? Yeah. Nope, not Tom Cruise.
Tom Cruise is definitely in there. I
don't know, but it looks real. That's,
you know, I, I try to Google
glass on once I actually oh yeah.
Through a whole UFC weigh ins wearing
Google glass. How was filming it? I guess?
Um, ah, it wasn't ready.
It wasn't ready and I think that's
why they haven't upgraded it. Oh yes,
let's hold off because this is not
working like it's been a while.
It's not new to that Dorky shit and
people got super uncomfortable when you
around them.
It's like holding a camera and everybody
walked around with a fucking camera
everywhere.
I think they'll have something eventually,
but I have a feeling it'll be
something where there's a technology,
like we were the outside.
You can't see things from the inside.
You can and then they'll show you images
like directly in front of you on the
Lens. So like you wear
glasses like your glasses,
but it'll show you things right, right
in front of you, like right. Yeah.
I got one that I heard that I don't know
if I understand and believe that this
is real,
but I've just googled it and I found
something that makes it seem like it's so
the next version of the VR headsets are
supposed to have brain tracking in them
and that sounds super scary,
but it's already like being implemented
and tested and get a knock on your door.
Are you think about as beating
off what is wrong with you, man?
We thought you were a regular person,
but you're beaten off
a hundred times a week.
You imagine if they wanted to
have a talk to you like Mr Papa,
you watched 14 hours of pornography
this week. That seems a lot. Yeah.
I think your mother would think
that. It seems like a lot. I mean,
I don't want to talk to her. Well they
say employers are going to do that.
Insurance companies are going to do that
and they're going to be able to tell
them much or beaten or how much you're
beating off, how much you're working out,
how much you're sleeping,
whether and what. Look at that,
whether we choose to
share only good stuff.
That's like Google when they said
don't be evil. Yeah, abandon that.
Once you start making money,
they fucking pain right over that side.
Maybe a little evil. What is
evil man? I mean what is evil,
evil Schmiegel we're going
in that direction. Yeah, man.
It's going in that direction.
It's all go into some sort of a
wearable thing that connects you,
but a weird thing that like everywhere
you're going and they're picking off your
face and then you're going to be able to,
they're going to know exactly what
you are and who you are and you know,
it's a strange,
it's strange,
but it isn't any more strange than our
lives today in comparison to people that
lived in 1920 like we were talking about
earlier. Yeah. This is way weirder.
Weightless, super weird. Way weirder.
We're in a weird town already for sure.
You just don't,
it doesn't get into the hands of people
that can really mess with you. Oh yeah.
The people at the money put the
money and all the control. Yeah.
They are going to be cool with
it, right? Yeah, that'd be great.
That'd be all right. Yeah, that'd be
fun. Everything's going to be fine.
Do you have a Alexa in your house?
All the, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. My kids do.
My from my one friend is
always trying to tell me,
just get that out of your house.
It's listening to everything that you
say and everything that he's doing bad in
that room.
It's,
I had a question about the neuro link
might be coming on soon or whatever.
I was thinking about like if,
if it got to the point where like say
we all got it and then everyone you knew
had it and there's like a
thousand people that have it.
When we hit a oh like a threshold
point, we were like, eh,
not everybody should have this.
We're good at this point right here.
How would you ever deny people
something like that? The cost.
It might be really expensive to know.
How would you,
I know you can't deny people that won't
like say if someone's coming up and they
want to try it and everyone else has it,
that would,
that would create a giant problem.
That'd be like if you said that with
cell phones too many people have cell
phones. We have to stop you no
more buying cell phones. I know.
That's why I sort of think
like that. There might become
a big problem with that.
Why? What is, but hold on a second.
I don't understand why you think,
I just sort of think that if,
uh,
in the theory that you're really going
to let thousands of people have instant
access to the world's knowledge
at their fingertips, at a,
at a thoughts like instant,
that becomes too powerful in the wrong
hands and the people that might have at
first might see the future problems
of that. I'm just, I was wondering,
I was thinking way too
far. Jamie goes high. Yeah.
[inaudible] you got high watch superman.
She answer. You say it was like,
no, that probably won't be a problem or,
well, no, I can't stop it though. I don't,
that's what I'm wondering.
I don't think that anyone can say that.
Not going to be a problem. Yeah. I don't
know. I mean, what is a problem though?
It's going to be something, it's
going to be a something, yeah.