The Joe Rogan experience. Good for
the UFC. It's good for everybody.
Her mom's mind, people say, oh,
did you ever think about going Belloto
one and my mind is great fighters
everywhere right now. I still think the
number one and all of his in the UFC,
number one martial arts and UFC,
and right now that's my goal. Yeah,
that's all great, but I'm here to be the
best. I can go to one and make a killing.
I go to bed to try and
get my sponsors back,
but I'm in no rush to leave here
because I want to be the best. Yeah,
like after I proved that there was
nothing else, and then it's like, okay,
now I'm ready for the money.
Then that's maybe an option,
but there's no competence
in terms of prestige. There's no
context. If you get the UFC title,
you're the best.
That's it. There's no question I
got. What about the villa tour?
This isn't is because dibella toy chant,
while especially John Jones absolutely
went on in your division.
You know in your division you have
one of the best guys of all time,
if not the best guy of all,
Thomas and champion.
So when you see a guy like
John at the top of the heap,
is that,
is that motivating to you to just ramp
up and even harder because you realize
that the guy who was a champion in your
division is not just the best light
heavyweight of all time, may be the
best martial artists of all time.
They're ramps up so much like I,
well I'm riding a bike in my basement.
I got the air down bike and a stationary
bike and I got the project and I'm down
there only thing on fight pass
and I watching him fight pass.
I'm usually watching Jon Jones,
you know,
to see him dominate another guys
and that you just hear that bite.
You can hear the,
the pedals are putting on weight gain.
So I can go from raw some crazy and
like I don't even be looking down at the
clock and just here had aired
the fam picking up right now.
I didn't realize it till like it goes
to break and I slow it down in our heart
rates and not just Washington just like
this. Like I want to get there. I gotta,
I gotta beat him to be the best, so I
need to work hard for you to take on him.
You can't take away what he does
in the sport. What is his outside?
His personal life, that's all he say.
She say, I have my words after the,
the California stuff,
we went to two 26 or whatever fight was
in Vegas and got moved here because of
his lifestyle and drug tests
and all that extra stuff.
However you want to code it up, his
past, you know, I'm done with it.
I had my words there, the fact that
he kept using God and Jesus and this,
this and this,
and I'm a golfer and got read my Bible
every morning and I don't like the fact
that you can, that he would do
that. I'm like, I'm not want it now.
But at the time my worries
was the fact that he did that.
And then at the same time I
want to interview with us.
I want to thank God and is
that kind of rubbed me wrong.
And then we flew on a plane
together and like I said,
I saw the way he was acting
when he came on a plane.
Like we not doing this because of him
like all day at a time bothering me and I
was a pent up anything else on
mills going into that fight?
That was something on my shoulders.
I have posted something cause when the
UFC called me right before I got on the
flight and he's like, oh don't come all
the way to Vegas now I've got my wife,
she's eight months pregnant.
Like she's 30 weeks, whatever.
She can't travel after this.
She's struggling.
We all them bags and y'all call me
and I'll say don't come this and this.
Go back home. We're going to fly you out
again. Like I'm not doing this again.
And then when they get to they will, we
can get you here but we get you to Cali.
But we can't take your wife
like what? Like, well you,
we your ticket in the code you take like
no, fuck that all because Jon Jones,
that's what got me mad that so they're
trying to save money pretty much flying
people because we as all,
we was literally walking down
the wrong way to the plane.
When they call him a can I turn around?
But then when we got like, okay,
you come here but we
can get you to category.
We couldn't get you get a wife to Cali.
Like my wife is 30 weeks pregnant.
She's here when she's coming like,
well we don't know what to do because
you bought her ticket, isn't it?
Like what do you mean you don't know
what to do? Get her another ticket.
Like I paved my family. What about the
people that's on the way right now?
Like God, I got to find the own way
and that maybe around week five,
week of the fight, the thing of the
things that you have to think about,
do you know fucking with,
that's the last thing I'd worry about
God and then I get there and they said,
when you get, make sure you got your
workout. If you don't have your workout,
schedule the Pie set already. As
soon as you get there, go do it.
I did mine like a month and a half
ahead of time. I'm all, I'm like I said,
I'm punctured. Like I like
having stuff done. Yeah,
I'm getting ready to go to the piano.
I'm packing my bags and I get a call. Oh,
you can't come to the Pei.
Why?
John just came in and said he wanted
to work out so we closed the gym down.
You're not allowed.
Y'All call me two months ago.
Told me to set my schedule
to come ahead of time.
I'm really get ready to walk
to my Uber that's outside.
And you said I can't come now. Like
I, sorry. Nothing we can do is John,
why can't you work out the same place
with John's working on the same thing when
connoisseur and I'm there in
the summer and kind of show up.
They're coming until there. But you gotta
leave like just throw. Yeah. Really.
You all got and kindness. I just got
locked up on the sidewalk come. Yeah,
they have security guards block
the stairs off and everything.
Yes. Yeah, exactly.
And like you heard somebody say big place.
Yeah,
but you can go to the
cardio room and the weights,
but you can't use the upstairs with
the cage in the bag and stuff is,
you can't use the,
if he's in the cage security best there,
so you can't go up there. Oh fuck. Is that
about mass jazz to people? I don't know.
My Pete, I'm an independent contractor
sir. But yeah, like that stuff.
It kind of rubbed me wrong and
that's what I was kind of like,
if I was a champ I wouldn't
want that. No. Yeah,
I mean I want people to be able to see
what I'm doing. Security, I don't know.
You know, you got to think about how
much death threats that guy must get,
how much shit he must take. You
know, and he's just popular as he is,
as famous as he is,
maybe just has overzealous security maybe
and they just want to tighten it down.
So they didn't want anybody up there.
They kept was.
So that was the first time I've
ever cursed at a UFC employee.
Like [inaudible] I was Kurt like going
on like y'all want me to change my whole
workout scheduled fight week.
I'm cutting weight too.
You know like it's not just
John like we understand bit,
I'm going to fuck up at night, I
don't care. What are you doing?
I need to go up there and get a workout.
My coach's meeting me there from the
airport but we can't do it antibiotic
corridors.
And the guy kept hanging up cause I was
going on that is when her and call her
back and I was like Yo.
And then people would hit me up like
I'm glad you actually voicing it.
So I'm hearing around the PR right now,
everybody talking about how you're mad
if somebody texts like I'm glad you
actually speaking out cause everybody
else kind of like, okay. Like no,
like if it wasn't for my wife being there,
I probably wouldn't check the same.
But I see the way she's struggling to
carry this belly around. She's hurt.
She's eight months. She could just
give birth at any time. So the,
I'm sure it's like all that and my
baby's Miller's. Sure. Really? Yeah.
It was revving me up and my wife
can't like Cory just stop, calm down.
It'll be okay. This isn't this. Like,
I think the fact of being okay with
the fact that they laid in one person
dictate at all. Like we're all equal
and I treat it as like a number.
He's Jon Jones, but we're number
4,722 right. You know what I mean?
I don't like that. He's John. I'm Corey.
Like I was telling wheel on the way here.
Reason. I love rose number units
cause I've never seen that from her.
She's a champ.
But you would see her and she act just
like rose before when she was in Invictus
did.
She doesn't change.
I don't want to have special
treatment from her or from anybody.
If I was a champ,
treat me the same.
You know what I mean is some
people are different I guess.
I don't know if it's John or his camp
doe is doing it or UFC is doing or
security or what,
but it rubbed me wrong that
we aren't equal anymore.
No, that's understandable. But that's
also got to give you some motivation.
Exactly. I got 'em told
them in the area. Other one,
I'll sit on the plane and I was really
directly behind Jon Jones. I see said,
hey Bob and Sally just looking.
I looked at my wife and
she's like struggling like
falling asleep but struggle
to fall asleep. I looked at the top
of his head, the back of his head.
I was just like, it's time for change the
torch. Like my brother always said like,
you're good and you know
you can be there by about,
I feel like when I come to those
top guys like John Jones and Gus,
you doubt yourself just a little bit.
You ain't sure that you can get them yet.
You know you're good.
But you feel like this was before
like before they leave fight,
you get there and you, you feel like
you don't think you're ready for that.
But I'm telling a wash you bro, I
know that you may have, you can do it.
And I sat there and saw him Baba and all
the frustration going through my mind.
Six o'clock in the morning we had to
get up and catch a plane cause his guys
isn't necessarily show up on time.
He still was late to that
and they was just like, I,
if I'm the champ I don't want this.
Yeah,
I mean I don't want no special treatment.
If you tell me sign up ahead of
time and keep your scheduled.
I expect that if we get down to scale
first come first. So first come,
first serve. If I show up
late, put me in the order I am,
don't put me up front because I'm the
chance because I was the first or second
person there. I'm on my way to scale
and John was walking down the stairs,
fully dressed.
We went back to the commission room
and I remember people in blue shirt
campaigns like hold up, hold up.
Now all the sudden John come in,
he could do all the paperwork,
he wants scale and he was out.
He was the last person down.
How's the, he's first like,
it wasn't that big of a deal,
but the fact that I don't like that.
Well it's because he's headline
in the card, right? Yeah.
Giving them special tree is John Jones.
There was,
I got the phone with this John Jones.
They hang up like, I don't like that.
It's still, he's still a person. Well,
he's a great person to be Corey Anderson.
Hundred percent it's coriander and
changed the tide. It's coriander score.
Annison but treat me know, don't
give me treatment. Beautiful.
That you have that attitude. What? When
you look at John, you look at John Skills,
like what do you think you need to do,
if anything different in your life or
in your training or where do you need to
get to where you think you could beat
him? Just keep getting better. Leo.
The TFA five must've been a big
boost. 400% every fight. Lash,
every fight. Even the ones I
lost it. I had been a boost.
Could you go back and seek,
tell me a fight. I've been
getting beat up Joe, right?
I've never been a fight where somebody,
they're all core. You're too smart.
You're not good.
There's never been one fight in my career
where somebody straight manhandled me
and push me around. You know what I mean?
I talk about this, this and this. Uh,
he's the greatest issue.
The greatest day.
I was watching the UFC main event last
night hotel and they had Dick Glover,
Rasha fight and this and this and this
note and closes clover that globally as
Glover's at nothing like upbeat,
Degas, you know, I use on,
you're talking about hope. Don't give
a little tip or Johnny Walker Blue TV.
He's super good. This is
nice. But at the same time,
I was thinking when you said it, but what
about Korea? And I was like, here we go.
Finally.
Somebody's always got to talk.
They talk about how good these guys
not in beat them all. You're like,
I'm that guy coming into the radar
and they don't expect me to do nothing
because I lost the Gian Volante my third
four fight, UFC two years of my career.
You know what I mean?
Uh,
Jimmy man with Jimmy Ma told wheel
on the way here to Jimmy Manual.
I was the only fight.
I will say a guy beat me.
He didn't man handle me,
but in my head from his highlights
and it's like you said on Instagram,
Breen comments, and I'll let what people
were saying in reading and seeing,
get in my head to think that if there's
got touches me, he's gonna put me out.
And where are you going?
So fight thinking there.
I literally got touched in my mind
was already set. Like if I get hit,
I'm going out. And I,
I think subconsciously,
like I have myself so doubted
that when he hit me in my mind,
just like in panic kind of shut down
because I remember when I hit the mat,
like I wasn't, I was abroad.
I remember I was out.
But I remember seeing his feet walk away
and I remember when I can see clearly
and I thought to myself, it happened
exactly what I'll put them on my,
if I got hit, it happened and
that's right. That was it. Yeah.
It was like I can take,
I can take it to anybody.
And I think Osp was more dangerous
than Jimmy because he can kick,
he explosiveness isn't the amp punch now
did everything right and just slipped
into the punch the wrong way. But I
was manhandling don't put three rounds.
I mean, it's simple mistakes because
I didn't have the discipline yet.
In three years of my career I hadn't
learned the discipline and focus that it's
a 15 minute fight. Right? I
can win 12 minutes of it all,
but one mistake and it's all gone.
Well, the experience of making those
mistakes and realizing what they are. And,
and then when those moments come up again,
and you deviate from the game plan,
and you do go to your right
and you do move the wrong
direction, you know, you'll,
you'll catch yourself.
You'll realize it's,
it's the experience of competition
for a fighter is there's nothing that
substitutes it. He could have great
talent. You can have a great mindset,
but the experience of
competition is like nothing else.