It's like when you try to
get people to do things,
they're less likely to do those things.
As soon as you are angry at
them that they're not doing it,
they're going to go the other way. People
don't like being told what to do. Well,
it's just like if somebody wants
to get sober, right. Right.
If you, if they are ready. I work in
jails. It's one of my part time jobs.
So what are you doing? Jails. I
do substance abuse stuff in jails.
So if you, um, if they're ready,
everything you say you're like a guru.
If they're not ready,
it doesn't matter what you say. Right. So
I do groups in jail. I teach meditation.
I also teach a goal setting.
I've been doing it about six years.
I've been in the field of
substance abuse for awhile. And um,
it's very rewarding. It's not, you
know, you don't make any money,
but it balances the life. Yeah. You know,
I don't want to sit around all day. Most
comedians, that's what they have to do.
You know, they work at night, right?
So, yeah, I work at Plymouth jail.
How often you do it. Uh, two or
three days a week. Yeah, that's good.
So it's not,
not every day now.
And I take the summers off
too because it's intense.
Yeah. I mean, I've had groups,
you know, I had one guy,
he came in and you do it.
You'd do divide people, ethnically
white guy, but six, six, big fucking,
you know,
it did state time.
It was all jacked and he's wired and uh,
he started complaining about the
place and uh, I said, hey, this isn't,
I teach them to breathe, you know, like
that Guy Haas you had on your show.
But I teach them a different method.
It's just you breathe in for, you,
hold it for you, let it out.
It's just a calming breath.
So anyway, this guy, I said,
hey, it's places in a hotel.
He stands up. He says, yeah,
I'll take it. I know it's not how
I said, let's do up breathing.
Relax. But a lot of guys, they can't see,
they can't see themselves.
They can't see contradictions.
I, one guy, he was in, it was
a Muslim, right? So I said,
so you guys pray like five times a day.
How do you know when to pray
and listen to this Joe? He says,
the guys said, well, if I'm
doing a heist in the afternoon,
you know I'm gonna miss that prayer.
You don't see any
contract that can amazing.
The Guy,
the big giant guy that was angry or did
he have a certain amount of time before
he got out? What was he in
it for? Life? No, no, he was,
he was on his way out. He
was coming close. That's when
guys get the most anxious.
How long have you been in four.
He was in for about 17 years.
It's a very polite society.
Really?
Prison society is very polite
because every little thing,
just picture your,
you're trapped with all these other
guys and a lot of mental health shit,
a lot of stuff. But every little
thing has picked up on and reacted to,
you know,
it's like that scene and heat between
Dinero Pachino where they just reacting to
each other. So you said, can
you please pass the salt?
Pass it because at any minute,
that's what I tried to teach us.
It's about impulse control at any minute.
And anything can happen. You know,
you're dealing with a bunch
of very impulsive people
that also have a very short
fuse there. There used to violence.
Why is one way of acting out?
So what I say to them is,
I have the same thing,
but it's not through violence for me,
it's like texting or something, you know,
I react or I drank, you know, so
it's, it's about stepping back.
Dang Gum. Yeah. It's hard when you
get tripped up with you, but the,
the mind listens to the breath.
That's the key.
Rather than going up in your mind,
take that breath and you know,
like when something's happening,
like a car crash or something.
First impulses, hold your breath.
Don't hold your breath, let
your breath out. I mean, a
lot of traditions have this,
you know, Tai Chee
prawning um, in, in Yoga.
So yeah, breathing is critical.
It's everything. When Wim
Hoff teaches it, you know,
if you follow those methods,
you can,
you can really change your
physiological state. You can,
you can get out of a lot of things.
It can get you through a lot of things.
You know the thing that I don't buy those,
that fucking cold water.
I don't want to go onto the
Arctic like him. Holy Shit.
It's because you live in Boston.
You get God allergy to call it.
My friend Mark Grata. He's ready to go.
He's done. He's been there for too long.
I know a lot about this weekend.