G about that fucking
dude in Colorado today.
He killed a mountain lion with his
bare hands. He smothered it to death.
It get jacked him while he was jogging,
he was running on the trails and
mountain line grabbed him from behind.
He got to struggle with is 80 pound cat
and wound up suffocating it, I guess. Wow.
Fucking bad ass jog or just,
yeah. I want to know on a toddler,
just call them them all a
Fokker bars. Net fuck you. Fuck.
It would have to be like Derrick
Lewis or someone you know, like,
so I can't picture anyone else being able
to do that. Maybe he's a Jujitsu guy.
Yeah,
we see him.
I've seen him when my kids were really
young in Calabasas where I live,
I saw one like just pacing back and forth
and my back fence. Oh, lime Jesus. Yeah.
They're out here, man. They're out here
and we see coyotes and deer all the time.
But mountain lions, that's,
that's next level. Scary. Yeah.
A friend of mine just sent me a message
this morning when, uh, I was, uh,
when I posted that thing on Instagram
about that guy that killed it and he said
he was running on this fire road and he
realized he like felt weird and looked
over and 20 feet away from him was a
big cat right above him on this ridge 20
feet. So that's basically us to
that wall. Big Cat just looking at,
and he said he waved his arms to look
bigger and to think just walked away. Wow.
Ah, I carry a knife when
I run, I carry a fucking,
uh, half face blades.
It's got to like a loop.
You could stick your thumb into it so it
stays in your hand. And people are like,
why are you running with a knife?
What the fuck are you doing?
Like you don't need it until you do.
And when you do you want to have it?
Didn't someone get attacked by a coyote
and hidden hills like running today?
How do I hear a story about that?
But I mean I've ran in my neighborhood
before and up to coyotes ran right.
Pass me the creeps. Yeah, they usually
don't mess with like humans, you know.
Well we had a problem with them killing
chickens cause I have chickens in my
yard. Yeah, I've lost a bunch of
chickens to coyotes were they were,
they were on top of the chicken coop,
poem tiles off of it and they're creepy
little fuckers math, but they're little,
you know, these are like 35 45 pounds.
They're not very big, but they're creepy.
There's something about their little
wolves and they're looking at you and
they're trying to figure out a way like
what can they eat? What can't they eat?
They're out there scraping, scraping and
grinding. They're sneaky. That gangster.
Like I saw one of my friends,
a dear friend of mine,
he lost both of his dogs
to coyotes and he had,
I think he had like surveillance of it
and one is in the yard and he's playing
dead and then his a dog's approach,
what they think is dead.
And then basically like his home,
he comes out of nowhere and
attacks on the end. They both,
and the one that's playing dead attacks
and both of his dogs were a rap.
How big was dogs? Small. I
mean, they were smaller dogs,
but now he has like big German
shepherds and he's, you know,
he's kind of like a bigger dogs
now, but it was really sad, man.
It is a very, very, very crazy, yeah,
they,
they figure out some way to work and
cooperate together without communicating.
It's very interesting.
Like if it wasn't so sad that
they're killing someone's pat, it's,
it's really kind of fascinating
that they're so smart
that they would play dead.
There was a guy that used to work at this
pet store that I go to and uh, he, uh,
also worked in a veterinary,
I'm center,
a medical place and a pit bull came in
big at one of those big Jack pit bulls
just covered and cuts. It
cuts all over its body. And,
uh, the owner was, you know,
they asked the owner like,
what the fuck happened? He
goes, I don't know. He goes, I,
I came home and he's covered in cots. I
really have no idea what happened to him.
So stitch the dog out, but hundreds
of stitches all over the dog's body.
Then he takes a walk outside of his house
and he follows his dog's blood and he
goes up into the hills near his house
and he finds nine dead coyotes. Wow.
That pit bull was starr apparently tear.
And he said it looked like Vietnam.
It looked like a fucking like saving
private Ryan just ripped apart coyotes.
Nine of them.
This motherfucker just went mall and
they must have been so bombed out there.
Like when look at this dog. Yeah,
there's nine of us. We're good.
We got this guy and then you see this
fucking fire hydrant head just, well
that doesn't feel pain. They,
they've engineered those things.
Like there's some pit bulls. This is
pit bull. Uh, if you go on Instagram,
I think it's, I am the hulk.
That's, that's the name of the,
it's a 200 pound pit bull. Like
they've gotten them to 200 pounds. Now.
It's the most preposterous thing you've
ever seen in your life. It looks like,
like, like Brock Lesnar, if
it was a pit bull, it's like,
it doesn't even make any sense.
You look at it like that.
A pitbull used to be like a 35 pound dog.
These to be small.
They look at that thing. Why in the
fuck? Imagine if a coyote saw that.
Fuck
those bull mastiffs.
There's fucking scary too.
Yeah. I had a master if he passed
away recently, I was 13 years old.
We had to put them down then. It was
really sad. He was, he was a great dog.
Mastiffs are so sweet. Look, look
at the size of that fucking dog man.
Just yoke to just crazy
200 pound pit bull.
It's just so crazy.
They make them that big now. Like a
hundred pound pit bull used to be a bit.
I had a 90 pound one. It was a big dog and
I was like, wow, that's a big pit bull.
I'm like, yeah, it's a big pit
bull. This dog's 110 pounds bigger.
Maybe it doesn't even make any sense.
Wow.
It's a fucking tank. Yeah. But that,
that's one of my favorite coyote death,
death stories.
This guy going up into the hills and
find all these dead coyote is just laying
in a pile. They tried to ambush
them. What they would do,
they tried to get one to come
out and try to get chased,
and then the one would run, and then
the other ones, ones with jump it.
There's like a gang.
It's straight up.
That's crazy that they think like
that though. That they've actually,
they have actually have
strategies. They're savages. Yeah.