Right,
there should be massive.
So social pressure against those kinds
of noxious political commitments.
But if someone misspeaks or it's an off
color joke and they weren't as like,
they weren't trying to offend
anyone and they're just, you know,
they wish they could take it back and
like, and, and, and that links up with,
I mean, did you say you must've
seen the norm macdonald? Yes.
I mean that was brutal. Yeah. Right.
Like at what he was, you know,
he knew he couldn't use the word
retard. Right. Because it's like that,
that's gonna get them in trouble. And so,
I mean, it, it, it's hilarious. In fact,
what happened. Okay, so he was, he was
on Howard stern show, wasn't he? I think,
I think so. Saw a, he was, I could have
this wrong, but the gist of this is,
is right.
I believe he's on the Howard
stern show and he was a bounty.
Use the word retard. So, so,
okay, we'll walk this back now.
Now it's coming back to me.
He was defend.
He was talking about his friend,
the,
the ordeal that Louis C K has gone through
in this just massive exile experience,
right. That there's massive
social shunning. Uh,
and he said he,
he was describing it in a way where it,
he then got accused that he was cared
more about what Louis CK was going
through. Then the women who felt it
felt very victimized by Louis C k.
And that was not his intention at all
apparently. And so when he went to, uh,
to clarify this, he was
about to say, but you,
you'd have to be retarded to think
that I cared more about Lucy Kay.
His ordeal than the ordeal of
these women who had, you know,
felt like their careers got derailed.
Right.
But as the word retard was come a retard,
it was coming out of his mouth,
he tried to course correct and because
he doesn't know what the fuck he's
talking about. He says you'd have to
have downs syndrome. Right, right.
Which is worse, right. As more
specific. And of course, like,
and then you've got all these
parents with down syndrome who are,
who have kids with down syndrome
who are just, Oh my God.
And so now he's just, he's, then
he was, he showed up on the view,
right, with this, this, uh,
uh, on, on this apology tour.
And I mean, that's just amazing video to
see him on the view surrounded by these,
these four women who know he's not a
bad guy. Right? Like they're trying,
they're trying to,
they're throwing them a lifeline after
lifeline and he's so beaten down. Right?
Yeah. And he's so walking on eggshells
and you got Whoopi Goldberg, you know,
trying to just pull him back,
you know, from the lions.
And, um, it should be, I mean,
it should be so straightforward.
Like it does it,
is it part of norms,
goal to cause pain for parents who
have kids with mental disabilities,
right? No, I mean like, and
like, like you, you can look in,
you can look into this guy's eyes for t
for 10 seconds and know that this is not
the big at, you're worried it. Right.
Right. Of course, you know, and um,
and yet people just want him destroyed
overnight. I don't know if they still do,
but it's like the moment like it
was, you know, I think it was a,
a real concern that has his show would
get canceled and be like, this wasn't,
well it hasn't been there
just for a second season.
And one of the things that's
maybe that's part of the problem.
It is part of the problem. He was,
he was devastated. I mean, um,
I'm very good friends with Adam Egan.
He's a guy that runs the comedy store,
is the talent director at the comedy
store and he's been on norm show.
He was on norms.
He was like norm sidekick on a show.
He's a very good friend with norm.
And norm really suffered from this in a
way that he never suffered from anything
in his career in terms of
like his own personal feeling.
Like he was devastated by it,
by the blowback and a reaction.
And he wanted to come on my podcast
and talk about it. But Netflix is like,
get the fuck Netflix had no press.
Don't do anything. No press.
Okay. So the fact that you
can't talk your way out of gas,
that's the fucking disease.
Well,
the problem is not that you
can't talk your way out of it.
The problem is that they wouldn't even
let him attempt to talk your way out of
it because they,
I think they realized that norms a maniac
and norm is a maniac in the best sense
of the word was one of my favorite comics
and he's hilarious. Fucking hilarious.
But he's also completely crazy in
the best way possible. Right. Norman?
I randomly in some strange way randomly
were seated next to each other on two
separate flights. Oh yeah. Just
randomly. It's crazy. Like norm again,
like this is crazy. And we had a great
time just talking the entire flight.
And um, we were talking about cigarette
smoking or like, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I used to smoke. I'm so glad I quit.
Fucking terrible for you, you know? Yeah.
I mean it's just, but I always wanted
a cigarette and then it'd be gambling.
I want a cigarette, but I quit. Fuck, fuck
cigarettes. Like how long did you quit?
And you're like, ah, I've, I haven't
had a cigarette in years. I'm like, oh,
that's great. We land at LAX.
He goes right into a store
and buy cigarettes. I go,
what are you doing? He goes, all that,
talk a cigarettes. I just want one now.
He was lighting it on the way out the
door. He couldn't get out the door.
He lit it before he did.
You know the automatic door
he was before it was opening.
He was lighting that cigarette. I
was like, you crazy. But that's many.
Many comedians are incredibly impulsive
and this is norm. I mean he just,
I mean he's got such a,
he's so off kilter.
He's got a sort of Garry Shandling and
create like you don't know what's going
to come out of his mouth extemporaneously.
Yes, but okay, we, we have to be,
let's put this back into
the diversity Olympics.
We need some respect for
neuro diversity. Yes. Right.
There are people who are somewhere
on the spectrum toward autism, right?
There's people who are there spectrums
we don't even know about. We are,
we haven't named for sure and everyone
is in some weird spot and people
misspeak, right. There has to be a way
back to say that's not what I meant.
Right.
Like,
like this is like offending people of
this type was not my intention at some
level that has to good enough unless,
you know,
we open your closet and we see that
you've got swastika is all you know,
everywhere, you know, and um,
so I think we have to, we have
to hold the line here, you know,
and very few people are in a position to
be able to do it. I mean, he's, you know,
like you know, Netflix, Netflix
doesn't feel it can do it. Well,
Netflix is just so terrified of continual
blowback and they just thought like,
if we're going to save this show,
the way to save it as to get him to stop
talking because he's just going to just
take his other foot and
take other people's feet and
stuffed them in his mouth
as well.
I think one thing that might help to
illuminate our understanding of how people
behave is what you really enjoy talking
about and you really definitely changed
my way of looking at things.
Um,
that they're really essentially
the concept of free.
Will's a very flawed thing and that you
have to really take any consideration
who a person is right now and what,
what has caused them to be this person
right now and that a lot of us are
operating on this really
bizarre momentum of,
of our past and our behavior
and our genetics and life
experiences and all these
different variables that really
need to be taken into account.
This idea that you are autonomous and
you are the director of your own life is
true to a certain extent,
but it's also very complicated,
much more complicated than
we would like to admit.
And when you're talking about something
that happened when you were 17 like
Brett Kavanaugh or something like that,
like, yeah, but Jesus Christ, you know,
you're going to hold a 55 man,
55 year old man accountable to something
that he did when he was 17 it wasn't a
crime and you're not exactly sure what
happened. This is all very strange.
This is a very strange stuff.