Cism that slamming this baby into the
water. What? What race is that what?
I'm Greek Orthodox. Yeah.
Fuck that. That's crazy shit.
Somebody said,
I think Sigora sent me that like what
is that for babies in a pool and that
light just popped up. Let's
end all this baby stuff. Right?
That's how horrible thing that they do.
They smashed that kid into the water
and pick them up by their arms and smash
them down in the water again.
They do it a bunch of times
and then they cut his dick.
Dick don't look pretty bro. Nope.
Cut it up. One day old Dick.
Which kinda up man slice, slice and dice.
I was glad I didn't have a boy cause I,
I I you, you have, you have two
girls. All girls. All girls.
Three girls. Three girls.
If you had a boy, would you give
to the circumcised? No. See I,
I was glad I didn't have to make
that stick me like I am Catholic.
I am, but I was like, what I do
that to know son? I don't know dude.
Sometimes they lose their Dick. Sometimes
it gets infected. It happens every year.
Every year the shotty little circumcision,
Joe kids get infections from circumcisions
and they lose their Dick every year.
Also, kids, this has
happened multiple times.
Kids have been circumcised
by a traditional,
you know what is it a Moyle or with a
rabbi and the rabbi's had herpes and
they've transferred it because the
rabbi asked to suck the kids, Dick,
stop bleeding. Yes, they
still do that. Yes, yes.
They still do that and
they still defend it.
It's a traditional way of doing
it and you're giving it herpes.
People have given the baby's herpes and
the kids have died from it. She says,
yeah, they've died from it.
Yeah, I didn't know that.
Still was gone down to they suck the
baby penis and there's a fucking video of
this one rabbi explaining the necessity
of doing this because it's the part of
the ancient book. It's in
the Torah, wherever it is.
Robert Baker estimates 229 deaths per
year from circumcision in the United
States.
Bollinger estimates approximately 119
infant boys die from circumcision related
each year in the u s 1.3% of all male
neonatal deaths from all causes are from
circumcision.
These are several cases.
There are several case reports of
death in the medical literature. Yeah,
people die all the time from circumcision
or just understand that folks,
this is an elected unnecessary surgery
that you're doing to a fucking baby and
there's no medical reason to do it.
[inaudible] AIDS prevents people say
stupid shit like that. Fuck. It does.
It does.
It doesn't make any sense.
There's a lot of people that are doing
it to justify the fact they've done it
forever and try to come up with wool
hygiene. Wash your Dick. You dirty bitch.
So big water.
Wash your Dick.
I watched the guy at the gym one time
is the old dude stood underneath,
you know the hand dryers?
What? His balls? Yeah.
He rolled his circumcise dick down to dry.
The
dryer I got. I was like,
there's a fucking, there was
a good move, Dude. That's it.
Dude.
Doesn't have any shame at all.
I don't know if those numbers are accurate
that you just read or that we just
pulled up, found another article
talking about it. And this is a,
an Australian link to the talking
about the same information.
It says that sweat by it or according
to the study that not all deaths that
might be circumcision unrelated
are officially recorded. Oh,
there might be more. So the hide it,
I guess they call it something else.
They say it's an infection or something
like that. I mean I, yeah man,
it's unnecessary.
It's barbaric.
You're going to look back on this a
hundred years, 500 years from now.
And to make fun of it the same
way would make fun of powder wigs,
but it's even worse because you
doing it to babies. Babies can,
he didn't have any of you say by the
time they're adults, they're like,
what happened in my Dick? Exactly.
Like, oh we just thought it was ugly.
We had you cut. Cut. Yeah.
I mean I would, you should.
I mean you should be, that's a decision
a person should be able to make.
Cause I feel like every guy at the age
where they were old enough to make that
will be like fucked. I'm not doing
that. I'm not doing that. Do you,
do you know that they, um, some guys
are trying to grow their circumstance,
their forced kin back? Yeah.
This is what they're doing.
They're taking the skin that they have
the regular skin around their dick and
they're stretching it out and there's
all these devices like the lip poll and
the poll shit.
They're trying to get it to go back.
So that taken like the base of their,
their Dick where it was cut and they're
pulling that skin up a little bit every
day.
I'm not kidding Matt.
This like devices that they have
you pulled your pants?
Yeah.
So they believe by,
it'll reattach and grow.
Well it looks weird. It looks
like a turtleneck. They'd
never really looks like,
like you know, it's not a
single layer of skin at the top.
You've got a double layer.
Now you got a rolled layer.
You do have skin at the top. But
it's like, you know, fucking,
it's like a blanket. It's
not like a sheet. Right.
I can't get, I can't get over. People are
doing, I guess people do everyday. Why?
Why? There's a whole community of
people that are trying to grow.
Their force came back,
they're really angry and they feel all
this pain and emotional pain from the
fact that cut their dick cut when they
were a little baby and they had no say in
it and apparently it makes your Dick
Dick less sensitive when you do that and
your Dick is naturally self lubricating
the head of your Dick is and as soon as
they cut this for skin
off then it dries out.
Then you know we're used to dry dick.
I was like they tried,
I got plenty of that but apparently
regular discs, if you don't cut them,
they're moist.
The tip like you pull that force came
back and that tip has got like a layer of
mucus on which is why you got
to clean it and cut it off.
Jesus Christ. That was man.
Yeah, it's a weird practice man.
It doesn't make any sense.
The fact that it's still around in this
day and age with all that we know and
all the risks that we know about where
kids actually do get sick and die from it.
That's a real thing.
It happens every year.
Who knows how many people are out there
that have fucked up dicks that are just
because some asshole ancient
tradition that we passed on.
Just supposed to do it. Yeah. Yeah.
My friend did it to his kid. He goes,
I don't want my kid to have
a weird looking dick. Like,
what are you talking about?
You right.
How often you're going to be
looking at how are you going to,
how are you going to train that kid?
Do you,
do you really think that that's
going to fuck with much? Yeah.
When he goes to the locker room and other
kids are going to stare at his dick,
I go, what? I, I've been in locker
rooms a piece of shit. Nobody cares.
Nobody. I don't give a shit. Joey Diaz,
he calls his dick the Cuban egg roll.
He wasn't,
he wasn't circumcised.
I Seen Diaz is Dick East
at least a hundred times,
at least a hundred times and pull out
his dick for punch lines of jokes and um,
uh, gee, you know, we're hanging around
in the parking lot or something like that.
He'd call, I've got pictures
of him with his pants down,
like carrying somebody on his
shoulders and his pants are down.
It doesn't have any underwear on
and you see his dick so crazy.
But nobody liked was going to go,
I'm good hanging out with you.
I could see you for skin. How come
you didn't get cut, right? Yeah.
Like what kind of kids?
You know what kind of kids you're
bringing your kids around? Well, they,
they're going to tease him. We can't. Your
kid can't take a little teasing. Yeah.
Hey, I'm sorry, my Dick Dick and
get mutilated by that witch doctor.
That's the fuck. Yeah, exactly.
Exactly. Your Butcher Dick over there.
Fucking intact right here.
What did it feel like when that
oil was sucking on your yeah,
that's when you were two days old.
That's the,
that's the thing I didn't
know it was still going on.
Obviously do they circumcised babies
still, but I didn't know that.
Do they defend it and say it's
an Orthodox Jew tradition?
I wonder if Ari got his
dick suck when he was a bit,
there's a hardy was hardcore.