Hello Freak bitches schedule
on Saturday and Sunday.
Do you allow yourself some leisure?
I'll sleep as long as I want.
And I listened to different records
during the week. I listened,
I do protein listening, which is records
I haven't heard yet. And so just,
you know, you have to really
concentrate on the weekend.
I do carbohydrate listening,
whereas records that I'm familiar with
that I just like to listen to. How so?
Just like a sort of a light
thing. Well, just like songs,
albums I've had for 25 years that I
still like to listen to. And that's like,
you know,
Chile and soup and bread and potatoes and
then during the week it's Shashimi and
clap pushups. You know what
a strange life you have, man.
Yeah, yeah. It's very original. I'll tell
you that. It's different. Yeah. If you're,
you know, be weird. Live.
Where'd you know? Weird is
this weird does, I guess? Well,
you get involved in relationships and you
getting a girlfriend or something like
that and they realize they're
getting involved with, they're like,
oh Jesus Christ, who is more
what I'm getting involved with.
And I realize I can't hack it because
here's the awful thing about being an
adult in a relationship, just seeking
to be an adult in a relationship.
I have found when I was young and
I was a boy and I was dating girls,
it's boys and girls and she's an idiot.
You're an idiot.
You do dumb things and
when cheats and whatever,
then you hit a certain part of your life
where she's a woman and you're a man
and you have adult expectations and you
can't be running around being an idiot
with someone who kind of wants you to be
at the table because they are sincerely
giving time of their adult life to this
thing that you were doing together and
when you come in still thinking you're
in ninth grade and she's coming in like
this is part of what my life is,
is being with you.
I have never been able to answer that
in a mature enough way to where I would
have been able to maintain it because
like say next weekend if I had a
girlfriend, she might say, it's Friday.
What are we doing? I'm like, oh,
watching me write for four hours.
And so that's not the way to be.
You can't do that.
And so I can't be a good persons
other half because I'm always,
the work has always attracted me
more than coming home to someone.
Wow. Like, I can't stand the idea
of someone of living with a person.
I can do it on the bus cause it's
das boat. And we're like, you know,
going down the road. Um, but I,
I never would want to like wake up
and she's there and I have no aversion
to, they look to your
right. She said, well,
it's every day here we are together,
just not wired that way.
I would be a drag. Like, you haven't
spoken to me in 20 hours. Huh?
I didn't notice. And I'm just
a work oriented. And so, and I,
I'm not interested in wasting anyone's
time. I'm not interested in being mean.
I'm really not into it. And so I, I'm not,
the woman was hitting on meal
while ago and I said, ma'am,
I'll call her ma'am. That's a problem.
She was very persistent. And I, I said,
ma'am, um, I'm like a
hunting dog. I'm a dog.
Just not the kind you pat,
you know, I'm just not,
I'm just, I'm sorry. Uh,
you should stop because she's
imagining holding your hand,
coming to your spoken word shows,
going on,
going to dinner with you and talking
about your day and you're like in front of
your fucking crazy speakers
and your writing and yeah.
Hoping the phone doesn't ring right.
Uh,
I unplug it on the weekends except on
Sunday. My best friend, since I was a 11,
12 and he was 11, we're
still best friends. He,
you ever heard of the band flew Ghazi?
Yes. Okay. Well, Ian Mci, the like,
he's my best friend and we grew up
together doing music and everything and we
talk almost every Sunday. And so, uh,
we've been best friends since
the Carter Administration. Wow.
And so Ian will call on Sunday,
we'll talk for a while.
Otherwise the phone doesn't ring. If
it does, I'm like, oh no. Why? Well,
I thought you liked me.
Why are you calling? And so
I,
I thought you liked,
if you liked me, he wouldn't
write me. But meanwhile I'm,
I'm contentedly just working away.
Okay.
Yeah.