Because with a lot of people they take
time off and then they come back and you
wonder what they're going to look like.
But one of the things that I was very
hopeful with you is that you've always
been almost a martial artist first and
a fighter second and that you're always
learning and you're always
practicing. Like you, you,
you would always take time in between
camps and you would, you know,
do Jujitsu in Brazil or you would be
constantly practicing your Moitai.
You're always trying to
learn and improve your game.
And I was thinking when you came back it
was like if you were saying that you're
a better than ever, I'm like man, he
might be better than ever. Like you,
you are willing to one guy that I believed
because a lot of times guys come back
and like man he's been out
of the game a long time.
Who knows how hard he's been training.
Cause a lot of fighters
when they're not in camp,
when they're not preparing for a fight,
they don't,
they don't like to train that
much cause they, they the, the,
the grind of camp almost.
Whereas I'm like,
you know how you see a lot of fighters
after they retire, they get really fat.
Yeah. And you're like,
wow, how could he get fat?
Like I was looking at my Donna the other
day, there's a picture of my Donna's um,
uh, Chino, Mondo. Dot. Madonna. He's
got a Instagram page. He's fat as fuck.
He's got a cigar.
He's drinking a whiskey mean he just
fought Floyd Mayweather a couple of years
ago.
He was ripped and this,
they retire and they don't
give a fuck anymore though.
I don't want to do this anymore.
But you,
I knew you were still training cause
I would see like an Henzel Gracie.
But the guys who were
training with you there,
and I knew you were
training with Donna her,
I knew you were constantly training
and you look good. So I was like at,
when I left off, like more
than four years ago, I, uh,
I knew I wanted it to come back.
Uh, the guy was not in an APP.
He place had a lot of personal problems
and I should have even stopped earlier
then after my fight with Hendrix.
If, if I would have stopped earlier,
I would have maybe come back
earlier as well. Uh, it was,
I was,
I felt like I was like kind of a feeling
of a cluster claustrophobic feeling,
you know, like it, I was, I couldn't
breathe well. I couldn't sleep well. I,
in my mind eye too much pressure or
personal property. There's so much stuff,
a lot of stuff happened to me that it's
still too early in my life and for the
respect of some people I know
I couldn't talk about it.
One day I will all mixed together.
I knew it was a drug issue in
the sport. I feel, I felt it.
I did feel well and uh,
I was trying to perform
under those condition and it
was catching up to me and,
um,
I did it.
But the reason why I think I didn't
lose the edge is a lot of people,
because we do an extreme sport,
it's like what we do is kind
of a life and death situation.
It's not because there's a referee,
but the spirit is the same as a glazer
gladiator or a person in the war that
goes toward, he thinks he's
going to die, is the same spirit,
even though it's not as anything.
But we'll go over there and the same
spirit that we're ready to give it or give
it all is such an extreme
feeling that wants,
you don't have that in your life.
Life kind of become boring.
You feel like you're not alive anymore.
So that's why when people stop,
they retired and I tried to come back.
A lot of the people they fall into drugs
because I want to catch up to that.
They want to feel alive again.
So they want,
they need that sensation
that they add previously,
but a couldn't get it back unless they
do drugs or they do something crazy
extravagant. The thing with me is
I knew I was going to come back.
Uh, and also I always like to
train and keep myself in shape and,
and I never did drugs. You know, like
I never did the other drugs. I drink,
I drink sometimes for my birthday.
Last Saturday I went out and I was
completely wasted. Okay. It is what it is.
I like to data rate myself sometime I'm
not perfect. Just have a little fun.
Exactly. And I, what's the goal of doing
this? If you're not enjoying your life,
what's the goal of it? Right. And
know people to fight. It's like, no,
I don't like to fight.
And that is another thing I like to talk
to you about people's eye and why you
do that if you don't like to fight. And
it's like, because I like my lifestyle,
you know, that it gives
me, but that's why people,
I believe if we come back to what you
would say, that's why I think people,
they have our time to come back after so
many years because they fall into that
trap.
They need to feel alive so they,
they find ways to that them in,
make them feel alive. But it's the,
it's the interior.
They tell your rate themselves denied the,
I didn't do that. I did not do that and
I would never will. Hopefully I can.
It's not my thing, you know? So
when you decided to come back,
how far out did you decide? Like, but
you, you, you took four years off. Yeah.
How many years in where you were like,
I think I'm ready to come back.
Uh,
when I see USA USA DEA and the drug
testing program being implemented and
implemented, then I saw a lot
of, a lot of about deflate. Yes.
A lot of dedicated.
Huh?
Like did you feel vindicated when you
saw like some of these people just,
I feel a little bit of a, I mean, it,
it feels bad to wish people bad luck
to get some kind of recognition,
but that's not what I want. I want
to do. I don't wish people bad luck,
but if you cheat, you cheat man. And they,
a lot of people get cut. And finally,
a lot of people in the beginning,
including my own friend,
they think like I was talking to some
of my own friend, that they say, oh,
you're paranoid. You become paranoid.
You need to take a break. You,
you're going crazy. Just retire or
get out your the day you're paranoid.
Because I was talking about it a long
time before Hendrix and they had,
everybody was disregarding me,
but none when it happened,
a lot of it that champion fell and
then a lot of the erode in the sport,
they got pointed out with their
fingers, hey, he's a cheater.
So now it become real. So when
I saw that happen, it was,
it was for me beginning to start and
now it's time to come back. You know,
because I'm, I'm a guy of, uh, of uh,
if I said something, you know, that's a
big, I'm going to, I'm going to do it.
I didn't want to come back when the sport
was dirty. I, that's one of my thing.
And so when I, when I,
the site to come back,
I add a big dog with one of my trainer,
John Than Hour and a m.
And for us there were my two main
guy and they're like my friend,
I brought her with me. I
mean I'm, I'm undefeated with
these, with these two guys,
you know, and they, they're like, well,
I need them when I fight series knowledge
between those two men and they mixed
together is crazy. You know, there are
two different person, very different.
They both have a um,
um,
they both studied philosophy.
It a variant and trusting people for
me to talk with because they have two
different mentalities, you know,
they see the world different ways.
So I like to have both of
their, uh, expertise. And um,
so John, John, he told
me, he said, listen,
he said you always have tree
big criticizing criticizes
when you were fighting.
It just never went up a
weight class. You never, you,
you people to say that you were kind
of borrowing your too much. Siri,
cerebral with technical.
You,
you don't want to take on
this as a rerelease w which
made that fight boring and
also you don't finish your appointment.
You know,
that was one of my big
criticizing criticizes.
I decide to come back and we change the
way I was training because the way you
train reflects the way you fight.
You know, people say, Oh, I'm gonna,
I'm not going to train too hard.
I'm going to do this and training,
but when it's time to five I'm going
to step up. There is no step up.
You're just going to do what what you
did everyday, you know, investment.
So I decide to change a few things and uh,
to correct those three things and that's
what happened. You know, I'm, I'm,
I'm happy it worked. It worked
out well, but that was my goal.
I wanted to come back for something that
excite me, something that was different,
something that was unique
and rare, you know, and,
and I didn't want to come back to do
the same thing I was doing before.
And that's why I decided to come back.
When you came back, first of all,
you came back and fought a very tough guy,
right?
You fought a big Michael Bisping at 185
pounds. But what was impressive to me,
it's like you didn't look
like you were gone. Like you,
like right away you, it felt like you
felt right back into the groove again.
You didn't look out of place,
he didn't look uncomfortable
and you were showing things,
especially different things with your
kicking and your movement that we hadn't
seen from you before.
You looked like you had improved.
I was tested. And then the training, uh,
even if harass some of the
guys for Russell went through,
tell them like he whispered to them as,
hey, if you knocked out George inspiring,
I'll give you money. Or you know, things
like, yeah man, his eye, he's crazy.
He's crazy. If I rest is my worst,
send me in training sometime. You know,
he tell Dale, he tells people, it's like,
yeah, few, few Bj for you heard George,
I'm going to glorify you. You
know, I'm gonna, we're gonna. Wow.
I'm going to talk about you and you
know, hey, we're going to be Ip.
That's the opposite of what a lot of
people think a training camp should be for
a champion. It depends what kind of, you
know, we don't train like this everyday,
but for my heart sparing, I have when
I'm training for a fight, two days,
uh, for my last training camp at two days
that it was like hard sparring that was
called, we called it should bucks
fight, should shoot bucks fighting,
which would put the big loves,
the addition pad and his feet to floor.
Once we touched the floor,
we step and we go back up.
And that was the area of expertise.
We're, Bisping was the most uh, uh,
competent, the striking department.
He's going to hit that Flores. Why?
I uh, I was, I was,
I was bringing in a lot of good guys for
aspiring with me. Uh, and in, in, in that,
that and that particular training,
it's hard to find someone that is exactly
like, like, are you going to fight?
But you can find a guy that does things
better than him in that particular area.
You know,
I cannot find a replica of Michael
Bisping was complete as much as Michael
Bisping. But I can find a
guy, for example, that I guy
for coming from Spain is,
his name is Cesar,
is a k one fighter and he's big guy.
He's like 205 pounds and he's big and
he's very, very good kickboxer so add him.
During my training camp,
I flew him from Spain.
I had a different bunch of guys that I,
that I,
that I was training with and all of
these guys that I was training with there
are not like Michael Bisping,
but in a certain area that
I was training with them.
It could be grappling or, or a shoe, uh,
shoe box or a different,
different areas that are,
they could be just as good or
maybe better than Michael Bisping.
So that's how I do my training camp. Yeah.
You know, I remember when you brought,
how do you say his last name?
Scott [inaudible].
Is that just not Charlotte Scott
Buskey yeah, the character. Indeed.
When you brought him to work with you
on the ultimate fighter and he would be
partying all night drunk and show up
at the gym the next day and still fuck
everybody up. Yeah. And did that,
so that guy influence your,
this your idea about just be more relaxed
and training and just not worrying
about it as much. Yeah, but
he's at the front like it,
it's a total different
extreme, you know, like,
like I don't believe in that extreme.
But John [inaudible],
I remember the producer of their show
with the ultimate fighter when he wasn't,
he was supposed to stay one week
and when he was about to say,
the producer was telling me is,
hey,
can we keep him for the rest of their
show because he was a good TV, you know,
so I'm like, I don't know.
I'm going to ask him. And,
and the in the same time like it, a lot
of the people in my thing, they were like,
man, okay, that's enough. Now we got what
we need and that, and I was like, yeah,
I like him, but he's just kind of a, you
know what? I need to kind of babysit him.
And the same time,
the knowledge that this guy
add an e he gave us was just a,
a big, a big edge, you know?
And, um, but as I shall,
he is a different extreme, or Joe, I take,
there is a center line that
you need to keep, you know,
that's what I believe. I believe in
life. It's not white. It's not black.
It's always green there. There's middle
zone for everything, I believe. Yeah.