So I figured something out that
I thought I'd tell you about,
just took me like 30 years to figure
out and I figured it out on this tour.
So there's this old idea,
you know that you have to rescue your
father from the belly of the whale, right?
From some monster that's
deep in the abyss.
You see that in Pinocchio for example.
But it's a very common idea.
And I figured out why that is.
I think so imagine that we already know
from a clinical perspective that you
know,
if you set out a path towards a goal,
which you want to do because you need
a goal and you need a path because that
provides you with positive emotion, right?
So you set up something as valuable,
so that implies a hierarchy.
You set up something as valuable,
you decide that you're going to
do that instead of other things.
So that's kind of a sacrifice because
you're sacrificing everything else to
pursue that.
And then you experience a fair bit of
positive emotion and meaning as you watch
yourself move towards the goal. And so the
implication of that is the, the better.
The goal, the more full enrich
your experience is going
to be when you pursue it.
So that's one of the reasons of,
of that's one of the reasons
for developing a vision
and for fleshing yourself
out philosophically because you want
to aim at the highest goal that you can
manage. Okay? So you do that.
And then what you'll find is that
as you move towards the goal,
there are certain things that,
that,
that you have to accomplish
that frighten you. You know,
maybe you have to learn to
be a better speaker, a better
writer, a better thinker.
You have to be better to
people around you are,
you have to learn some new skills and
you're afraid of that whatever cause it's
going to stretch you if you,
if you pursue a goal and it's,
and so that'll put you up
against challenges. Okay?
So all the clinical data indicates,
well,
the opposite of safe spaces as
Jonathan Heit has been pointing out,
that what you want to do when you identify
something that someone is avoiding,
that they need to do because they're
afraid you have them voluntary can
voluntarily confronted. And so you
break it down. What you try to do,
if you're a behavior therapist,
as you break down the thing,
they're avoiding into smaller and smaller
pieces until you find a piece that's
small enough.
So they'll do it and it doesn't really
matter as long as they start it, you know,
then they can put the next
piece on in the next piece.
And what happens is they don't get
less afraid. Exactly. They get braver.
They get, they get, it's like there's
more of the you can and here's why.
So imagine you do something
new and that's informative,
right?
There's information in the action and
then you can incorporate that information
and turn it into a skill and turn it into
a transformation of your perceptions.
So there's more to you because you've
tried something new. So that's one thing.
But the second thing is,
and there's good biological evidence for
this now that if you put yourself in a
new situation,
then new genes code for new proteins
and build new neural structures and new
nervous system structures. Same thing
happens to some degree when you work out,
right? Cause your, your muscles
are responding to the load,
but your nervous system does that too.
So you imagine that there's a lot of
potential you locked in your genetic code.
And then if you put yourself in a
new situation, then then the stress,
that's the situational stress that's
produced by that particular situation
unlocks those genes and then
builds new parts of you.
And so that's very cool because who knows
how much there is locked inside of you.
Okay,
so now here's the idea.
So let's assume that that scales,
as you take on heavier and heavier loads,
that more and more of you,
you get more and more informed because
you're doing more and more difficult
things,
but more and more of you gets unlocked.
And so then what that would imply is
that if you got to the point where you
could look at the darkest thing,
so that would be the abyss, right?
That would be the deepest abyss.
If you could look at the harshest
things like the most brutal parts of the
suffering of the world and the
malevolence of people in society.
If you could look that,
look at that straight and and directly
that that would turn you on maximally.
And so that's the idea
of rescuing your father.
Because imagine that you're like
the potential composite of all your,
all the ancestral wisdom that's
locked inside of you biologically.
But that's not going to come out at all
unless you stress yourself, unless you,
unless you challenge yourself. And the
bigger the challenge you'd take on,
the more that's going to turn on.
And so that as you take on a broader
and broader range of challenges and you
push yourself harder than more and
more of what you could be turns on.
And that's equivalent to transforming
yourself into the ancestral father into
all because you're, you're like
the, what would you call it, your,
the consequence of all these living beings
that have come before you and that's
all part of your biological potentiality.
And then if you can push yourself,
then all of that clicks on and that
turns you into who you could be. That's,
and that's the representation of
that positive ancestral father.
So that's why you rescue your
father from the belly of the beast.
So you think that this ultimate
goal of sack of sacrifice and of,
of risking your life in order to save
someone who's truly important to you,
that this somehow or another maximizes
your potential as a human being? Well,
I think, I think you can think
about it religiously too.
So they think about it this way. So
in the Christian story, for example,
you have Christ does two
things that are met. Messianic.
One is takes the suffering
of the world onto himself.
He's not some weird idea.
Okay, so what does that mean?
Let's think about it psychologically.
Well, maybe it means that, well,
that's your job is the world's full of
suffering and you should accept that as
your responsibility past,
present, and future.
You're supposed to do something about
that as much as you can about it.
And maybe you start with your own
localized suffering, you know,
put yourself together. But then you expand
that outward and you decide that it's,
you're not a victim of that even though
you know your part and parcel of it.
But you're,
you're the potential solution to that.
And so you accept that as
a responsibility. So that's
part of taking on load.
That's part of bearing across.
You could look at it that way.
The cross is sort of a symbol of the
place of maximal suffering. Okay.
So you accept that as a challenge,
not as a,
not as something that
you're victimized by.
Maybe you accept that as the price
of being. Okay. So that's one,
that's one responsibility.
You're responsible for addressing
the suffering in the world.
So that could give you some meaning,
seemed to me.
And then the next thing
is there's a story.
Of course the Christ met
the devil in the desert.
And so that's the
encounter with malevolence.
So that would be the other thing because
the two major problems that people face,
obviously our suffering,
tragedy and malevolence.
And so that's the other thing that
you're responsible for is that you're
supposed to look at the capacity for
human evil as clearly as you possibly can,
which is a very terrifying thing.
You know,
that causes post traumatic stress disorder
and people that aren't accustomed to
it and in the mythology that's
associated with the encounter with evil,
it's almost always the case that the
entity that does the encountering,
even if it does it voluntarily,
is is,
is hurt by it.
So the Egyptian God Horus for example,
who's the I and the Falcon,
the thing that can see and pay attention
when he encounters is evil. Uncle Seth,
who's the precursor of Satan,
he loses an eye because it's no joke
to encounter malevolence you know it.
It can really shake you,
but the idea would be that if you can
face the malevolence and you can face the
suffering,
then that maximally that opens the door
to your maximum potential and then the
option, the optimistic part
of that is, and this is,
this is why it's so useful
to peer into the darkness,
let's say the optimistic part of that is
is that although the suffering is great
and the malevolence is,
is deep,
your capacity to transcend it is stronger.
So what you get out of the most negative
viewpoint is the most positive possible
consequence because one of the things
you'd like to know if you want it to know
something deep about yourself is
that you could face the worst,
that there wasn't prevail. And I
believe that's Cape. I believe that's,
I believe that,
that people are capable of that.
I think that despite how tragic life
is and how malevolent things are,
that fundamentally our spirit,
let's say, has the capacity to,
to confront that and to fix
it, like psychologically, to,
to,
to confronted courageously,
to be able to bear up under
that if you do it voluntarily,
but also to address it not only
to deal with it psychologically,
but to deal with it practically and
that we could make things much better.