You're an interesting story man, because
a, not just because your personality,
but because you're, you've come back
from mental illness and you very,
very open about it. Yeah.
Know, I think that's, it's,
that's a very unique thing where I'm,
I remember when you,
when you beat Klitschko and won the
title and then you kind of went off the
rails and I thought you were just
partying. You know, when I heard about it,
I thought, wow, I made a shitload of
money, became the heavyweight champion,
all the pressure and the press and all
the craziness. But it was more than that.
It was more than the,
it started off like I'll suffered with
mental health problems my whole life,
but I didn't know what it was. Cause I
never had no education on the mater. Uh,
money wasn't til after the Klitschko
of, hi, I'm very massive hockey.
Then I ought to have a even worse hello
Louis slow that anyone could ever have.
Um, I'd wake up and I think,
why did I wake up this morning?
This is coming from my money. You want
everything. Money, fame, glory titles.
Our wife, our family, kids, everything.
But I felt as if I had nothing.
I felt there was an empty gaping hole
that was just filled with gloom and doom
and I just was, one bad thing happened
to me after another, within seven days.
The IBF stripped me of that title because
I couldn't defend against gloves. Golf.
He was a nobody because are
very much closer if Allodynia,
but the IBF wasn't expecting
me to beat Vladimir,
so they took that clause in there anyway.
Thinking bloody may is going to want to
defend against class coffee because I
won. They, they stripped me of the belt,
which then none of my reason within seven
days of the fight. Yeah. That's insane.
How can they require you to fight
within seven? No, they didn't,
but they required me to,
to go into negotiations and you didn't,
so just not going into negotiations to
sign the strip you within seven days.
Yeah.
But they knew I couldn't go
into negotiations because
already much clothes boxes
a dirty, but I was stuck in between
a rock and a hard place. Yeah. Um,
and that's what happened.
That was one belt, God.
And then my team and the coach,
coach team or carrying all about
where the flight was going to be.
It was going to be on a cruise ship
in Dubai. It was going to be here.
It was going to be there.
Time was dragging on a cruise
ship. A cruise ship. Yeah.
There were some ma'am,
Arab billionaire who wanted to make this
fight in exclusive fight for him and
his buddies. No. Uh, come on. Seriously.
This fight was heading for a cruise
ship. That fucking oil money, man,
they've got some money and if they can
afford it, do it. That's what I say.
That would have been the most hilarious
scenario ever for a world heavyweight
title fight a bunch of Arab
billionaires on a cruise ship.
Wow.
So they strip you of the IBF belt.
You going in negotiation with Klitschko
for the rematch. Rematch never happened.
Pretty much. Didn't happen
initially because I went
over on my uncle in training.
Um,
I was in Harlem training full three
much and I was running up on the heavy
terrain and I went, oh, from ankle
sprain, my ankle. Quite badly.
So we had to postpone the folly. But by
that I was off like say three months,
gain his uncle right. And all up. I just,
I just didn't want to do any more of
your army. I didn't have the desire.
The fire wasn't burning no longer to
fight and I was suffering with depression
the whole time. Even in training
camp before I sprained my ankle,
I was depressed as depressed, could
be on a daily basis. And I think,
why am I feeling like this?
I don't have no reason to feel like it.
Some people will say, oh well each
attention seeking or whatever,
but unless you've
experienced what I'm saying,
it's sort of impossible to understand
where it had been aware of come from.
And it just went from bad to worse.
Um,
I hate the drink heavily on a
daily basis. I hit the drugs. Um,
I was out all night, team of women
of the night and not coming home.
And you know,
I didn't care about boxing.
I didn't care about living
at just wanting to die.
I was going to have a good time
doing it while I was doing it.
I used to drink and take drugs to get
away from their depression because when I
was drunk or high then I wouldn't,
uh,
I wouldn't think about being depressed
to fall about being a boxing champion or
I'm, I feel great. But as we
know when the drink was off,
it only leaves you with a bad
hangover feeling even more depressed.
But someone who suffers
with mental health,
the worst thing we can do to escape
it is take drugs or alcohol. But yeah,
that's the most common approach.
And that's the common approach because
people we don't know cause it's not spoke
about. And this is why I want to
spread the word on mental health.
So when other people are in
this position in the future,
they know where to go and they know
what to do because there's a blueprint.
Well,
Kudos to you for doing that because so
few people have the courage to talk about
their struggles when they go through that
because it seems like a weakness. Yeah.
You know,
it's,
it's very powerful that you are willing
to do that and just be open and honest
about it. There's a few people out
there that are doing that now. You know,
our friend moral Rinaldo,
he's gone through some,
some serious mental health issues and
he's very open about it and talks about it
quite a bit now.
When you were training for the first
Klitschko fight for the fight rather,
did you have it then?
Not really,
no,
but I was set focused on what I wanted
to do and that was beat Vladimir
Klitschko.
I believe when you've got a goal in mind
or from being a child all your life and
you do that,
then I was like obviously lost.
I was almost like I didn't have
anything more to do in my life,
although I could have carried on and
defended the belt some, whatever.
I wasn't really interested in doing that.
I'd beat them on.
I'd always wanted to do because
when I was an amateur boxer,
I used to watch flood in May, Klitschko
on TV as a world heavyweight champion.
And I always aimed, he was my target
to beat and want to finally beat him.
It was like climbing Mount Everest and
didn't have anything more to prove and
the fire was dead.
There was no fire.
I was forcing myself to fight and I always
said I didn't want to be one of those
people who just fought for money because
there's plenty of people with money in
the world, plenty of, but who knows
him? Um, the reasons for me fight,
and it's not for money or,
or for belts or glory,
a fight because I don't
know anything else.
Have always been a fighter from
being born to being 30 years old.
Now it's all I love to do. I don't
have any of a passion. I've locked.
The Lord knows I've locked. And if I
had anything else that was going to our,
I could do, I'd be doing it.
I just, I tried retirement.
I was 27 or retired on the second Monday
in boxing heavyweight history to retire
on beaten as a world champion
like rocky Malsiano before me,
but it wasn't enough. I was like,
I am lost without this fight game.
I tried golfing, I tried clay pigeon
shooting. I tried four by four in,
I tried going to strip clubs,
bars, restaurants, everything,
and it was just like I had this emptiness
inside where I just wanted to fight.
Well,
in comparison to what you've accomplished,
everything else has to seem pretty dull.
I mean,
until you step into the ring
with Vladimir Klitschko,
who is widely considered to be one
of the greatest heavyweights ever,
and you boxed his face off. I mean,
that was a beautiful performance.
It was shut him down. It was
weird. It was weird to watch them.
It's like there was moments
in that fight where he just,
he just looked like he didn't
know what to do with you.
I'm going to say it again on
December. The first, like I said,
to flood demand has said the
same thing to Deontay wilder.
You fought the Americans, you fought the
Mexicans. You fought the Europeans. Paul,
you ain't never fought the
gypsy king before. I said,
it's straight Tivola than me. I
said, you look in our king. I said,
who ever for king before? He said, no. I
said, we fight him on now. And he said,
you're going to lose to one.
Well he's lost before,
but he's lost because he got clipped
and hurt and stopped and I was very
impressed with him actually in the
Anthony Joshua fight because he came back
from getting badly hurt
and almost put Joshua away.
But the fight with you is different
because you just outboxed him.
And he was known as the guy who
would box and hold, Jab and hold.
I mean he was one of the most
boring heavyweights of all time.
Fantastically successful.
But from a spectator point of view,
you watched some of his fights and like
Jesus Christ, he would jab you, grab you,
Jab and grab you. I mean that was his
thing. Right hand grab you a worked here,
25 title defenses.
I mean it was very successful,
but that shit didn't work with you.
It didn't for the first
time in his whole career,
he was fighting to somebody who
was not just bigger than him,
but more often I take who could move more.
Yeah.
So money wasn't just
looking for one lucky punch.
I knew going into the fight in
me, a flight there, everybody,
all the rest of the opponents
and 25 men before me,
I'd a one in trying to do the same thing,
trying to knock him out. And he got,
he's got so many of a,
a weird defense where he puts both arms
out in front of him and it's almost very
awkward to London.
That chain where big punches so far.
I'm not going to do that.
Not gonna make that mistake.
I'm going to outbox him on Ecmo, me
teams. That test is not a good idea.
We've got to go to Germany to try now.
Box a super champion and try and win on
the cards. Are you crazy? I said, yes.
I said,
but if I wasn't crazy I won't be great.
And I went over there and outboxed
him. Um, nobody, nobody apart from me,
brother or my father fought.
I could do it. You know,
even people who were close to
me and camp there were like,
they were very unsure of
what was going to happen.
I may be me. I always had a little
smile on my face because I believed it.
I believed I could always beat flooding.
Man College go.
I even told Vladimir years
before, when I was 22, I said,
I'll beat you one day in manual
steward told him to God, rest his soul.
He said, Tyson fury is the
heir to the throne. He said,
when his time is ready, will beat you
straight to him. Probably me or hate it.
He hated it. Manual talking about me like
her, but he don't it either way. Well,
I'm sure it was good
fire under him during training as well.
Now you,
you were focused for that fight.
You were,
you were prepared and afterwards,
was it just the realization that you
would accomplish this incredible goal?
It's set into depression?
Was it you didn't know what to do next
or was it just that your focus was now no
longer on this unattainable?
You know,
like in almost insurmountable obstacle
in front of you becoming the heavyweight
champion of the world. All of a sudden
you did it. Then the depression kicks in.
Yeah.
Molly conditioning train a Christian.
He said to me before the clutch go fight.
He said, what will you do after you win?
I said, probably be depressed
for a long time. He said, why?
I said truthfully as I was
almost expecting it and I
didn't think I'd ever box
again. Even the day after the Klitschko
fight, sky's boss interviewed me,
the UK broadcaster, we put it on and
they said, what's next for Tyson theory?
I said, I'll probably never box
again. I knew. I said to me,
dad and my brothers before the fight,
a week before the fight, I said, win,
lose or draw.
I said,
this is probably going to be my last
fight cause I knew the fire was going.
I didn't have that hunger anymore.
Had the hunger to beat Vladimir Klitschko
bought not to carry on and continue.
And I said I didn't want it to
be about money or financial gain.
I wanted to be the best of my time, beat
the best man. And that's what I did.
And I was a honoring me worded.
I didn't box again until
two and a half year later I decided to
make a comeback because I was sitting
here 400 pounds,
drug addict and alcoholic.
By the way, I'd never taco drug in my
life until I got to 27 really? Never.
Not smoked weed. Not, not morphing.
And what drove three roads?
What were the drugs of choice
once you won the title?
Cocaine was the usual one and that
was it. Really. Cocaine and alcohol.
It's like roll, it goes
crazy. Drug drug and alcohol.
[inaudible] but you know,
I look back on it now and I think
what I changed that I wouldn't,
I'm not many people will,
well,
this man's crazy for saying
that on our radio show,
but I wouldn't change a thing because
I know it was supposed to happen and I
needed to be tested to see
what type of character of us,
although I did all those mud things and
I went for a wall up time and I tried to
commit suicide and I, how'd you
try to commit suicide? Well,
I'll tell you what
happened. I, like I said,
I was waking up and I
didn't want to be alive.
I was making everybody's life a misery.
Everybody was close to me and was
pushing away. Nobody could talk to me,
talk any sense into me at all.
And
I'd go very, very, very
low at times, a very low.
And I start thinking all these crazy
thoughts. And this start near the,
and I was in Macau. I bought a, bought
a brand new Ferrari convertible, um,
in the summer of 2016 and I was
any animals on the highway on this,
a strip of highway where I am, I'm at
the bottom of about a five mile strip.
There's a massive bridged across as the
beltway and I knew that and I got the
car up to 190 miles an hour hours heading
towards up bridge and I didn't care
what no one will sink in. I didn't care
about her to me family, me, my career,
people who friends, anybody. I didn't
care. I didn't care about nothing.
I just wanted to die so bad.
I give up on life and just as it was
getting towards up your ward 90 in his
Ferrari in a crushed like a
coke come by way if it a bit,
I heard a voice say no,
don't do this. Tyson,
think about your kids.
Think about your family and your little
boys and girls growing up with no father
and everyone saying your dad
was a week mum. He left his,
he took the easy way out because he
couldn't do anything about it. And I've,
before I turned into the bridge, I, uh,
pulled on the motor and I was shaking.
I could feel myself shaking and I pulled
over and I was all nervous and didn't
know what to do. And I was frightened
and I was so afraid. And the fall,
that day, I'll never ever, ever try or
think about taking me on life ever again.
And I didn't. I went and got help
from a delete in psychiatrist,
doctor in the UK and my dad were not with
me. And she said to me that she said,
can I have a word alone with
you, John? He said, Ms. Dot.
Told me what she said when he came out.
She said, hey, is not to be trusted alone.
He's an imminent death risk.
That's the highest level of suicide risk
that she'd ever assisted. And she said,
without his faith,
he would have been dead a long time ago.
But she said faith alone ain't gonna
hold him cause that's going to break.
And once that goes,
he's done.
So without pop me duds life terror as
well because he was checking up on me all
the time.
He wanted to be with me 24 seven it was
even sleeping in my house with me and
married man before kids. I was
in a right state. I'll just,
I just, I, I want it.
I just didn't want to live anymore and
I had everything that a man could want.
There wasn't nothing I didn't have,
but it meant nothing. Nothing meant.
And even I felt worthless on the
longer it went on, the more it,
it hurt inside and Amorosa it and
everybody, everybody gave up on me.
Before farm we fall.
I was definitely gonna die and I was
going to kill myself and after that I,
I tried. I was thinking to myself, you
know what? I need to get better and eat.
I need to do something.
But every time I tried to go to the gym,
I don't know if I say no, they say
for anymore, I'm not going to do this.
I didn't want to do, I'd drum,
I'd run 200 yards and pull up.
I wouldn't even get a mile. I
think. Oh, can't be bothered.
I don't want to do this.
Boxing is not for me.
I hated boxing at one stage in 2016
early 17 I wouldn't have done a box in
flight for this room full of
diamonds. No Way. I hated boxing.
I won't watch on the TV. I won't
read about it. I hated boxing.
I've done it my whole life and I
didn't want no part of it anymore. Um,
I was out drinking. I didn't gag,
give up taking drugs like I said.
And it come to a point or
was doing that for 18 months.
I made a life and I
was out 2017 Halloween.
I was a 400 lbs,
dressed up as a skeleton and I go
to this fancy dress party in it.
I'm looking around and I'm thinking,
these are all young kids compared to me.
I'm 30 and I feel like I was the
oldest guy in there like 29 I was like,
what am I doing here?
Is this what you want for your life?
And I thought to myself,
this is not me a number.
How many people told me before this
while I was going wrong, what was due?
And you need to act to your life.
You can only change your life
if you want to change it.
And I left and everyone said, are
you going? Oh, early said, yeah.
I left at nine o'clock I went
home and I got back home.
I didn't say anything to the line, but it
went straight upstairs into a dark room
and I took burse. Chief
had skeleton, so tough.
I W I was sat there and I got on my knees
and I was praying and begging God to
help me.
And at this point I'd never,
I've never begged or cried
to God to help maybe for her.
I prayed a lot all my life, but I'd
never been in this physical state before.
I could feel tears running down my face.
My chest was wet with tears because
I knew I couldn't do it on my own.
It wasn't possible for me because I tried
and tried and tried and ended up back
in Nepal.
But drinking,
I almost accepted that that was
going to be my fate and alcoholic.
So I was on my knees in his bedroom.
Um,
after praying for about 10 minutes,
I got up and I felt the weight of the
world was lifted off my shoulders.
And for the first time in years I
knew it was going to make a comeback.
And I called my wife,
I said, Paris parish,
it's a ball she follow was drunk
coming home from the pub. I said,
Monday morning I started to regain
mission to try and get the heavyweight
championship of the world book. She said,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Because before this,
every time I'd have a beer,
I'd come back and I'm going to be the
heavyweight champion of the world again.
Cause it was,
it was the alcohol talking.
So I was like the man who called
Wolf a thousand times on this,
this jeep had Korea that I,
that I was leaving on the past
thinking about years before glory days.
And after this prior I got up, I
said, all right, this is going to be,
she didn't believe me one second, but
even when I speak to her now, she says,
that night you told me that she said, I
earn a difference in your voice swimming.
[inaudible]
next day I phoned up
Ben Davison and I said,
I don't want to go back downhill route
when the same trainer, same promoter,
say many things and everything's
got to change as it.
It's going to be a new Tyson fury
and we called it return or
the mock mission and as I
went out that morning after
phone in ban and arranging everything and
went out for a run in me sweatsuit out,
I had ambitions of running two miles.
I got about five minutes into the wrong,
stopped on a walked
and while I was walking,
I can't run on TIF up to 400
pounds before I'm going to walk,
I'm going to get out and walk.
While I was walking,
I was flicking through on my phone on
Instagram and or sees this video of
Deontay wilder say in Yep.
Tyson theories finally done that because
the week before I'd been a boxing show
in Manchester or something,
and the press took a picture
on mean it was like everywhere,
this big fat out of shape, ugly, bald,
that it bearded white as a sheet mom,
I was like a state and Aidan this video,
yet after seeing this evidence at Tyson
fury, I finally know he's finished.
It can never come back.
And if he,
even if our water fought him and
he's a day out and knocked him out,
and before that he was
talking about Mike Tyson.
Now we'd not Mike Tice and I
went around and I fought myself.
That was very disrespectful to talk about
someone who's not even from your era
and one and divide them and all that
sort of stuff when there's no possible
chance. So, and stuff. You know
what I've ever do, fight you.
I'm going to give it you for that reason.
And then when I saw this other video of
him saying things about me and that I
couldn't come back and he'd give me that
much more motivation to return just so
I can beat Deontay wilder.
So I had all these court cases on as well.
I was being charged.
We've taken performance and unseen drugs.
Nandrolone swimming had never done,
I had, I had nandrolone enemies system.
It's fruit juice, naturally antibiotic,
but they say my levels were elevated,
do Uk d UK Anti doping said
there was no case to answer,
but all of a sudden I had a big water
case on me that took nearly three years to
sort of tout and by, I mean everyone
said you're getting in Hotmail,
Donnie is on you getting a 12 year
bomb. And I said, you know what?
Well you've been 12 years
not just for an Angelo.
I refused them as well.
I was in a bad mood one day and the
drug test and people come in the gym and
I've told them to fuck off. This is when
you were training for your comeback?
This was when I was out with training.
Yeah. When I was just all the time,
I was fat and out of shape and not train
and I was still being run them drug
tested by UK Aad. Really. That's why
I tested positive twice for cocaine
and everyone said no,
he never getting back the but the boxing
board of control spending my license in
the UK for the cocaine, um, use.
So I aren't a court case looking
at [inaudible] band forever.
Basically spantion the doctor
made me medically unfit to fight.
So that was after I forgot about that bit.
When I was rescheduling
the Klitschko to fight, uh,
the psychiatrist phoned up and she
says, look, he is medically unfit.
He can't fight anybody, don't
want to live, nevermind fight.
So it was medically deemed unfit to box,
suspended by the box and motor control
for the cocaine use and out an underlying
case on me on a refusal case.
And by the way,
it was racking up millions of
dollars in lawyers' face too.
But I was so confident
that I was going to,
everything was going to be okay
because when I was down on my knees,
I just knew that it was going to
be okay and everyone was like,
what's the point in training and doing
anything with you when you're not,
you can't do anything. You're not
in a position to do it. I said,
everything's going to be all right.
Don't worry.
Court case comes along in
December. We go. They say, right,
this car case has dragged on
insufficient evidence. Get rid of it.
We both agreed that we was going to call
it quits on the case and I go my way.
They got as they pay their legal
fees, I pay my legal fees. Dawn,
that was a drugs case out the
window. Finished the suspension.
I had a meeting with the border
control in the UK and they said, look,
if if you can get past medically
fit by doctor mentally,
then we'll reassess your case. I'm telling
and denied. So I said, right, no problem.
I phoned up with a psychiatrist
or seeing people who would,
who had spoke to all these doctors,
three or four different doctor, Phil's,
Dr. Jones, whoever else said, or
I need to, I need reassessing,
reassess me, Bang, pass
with flying colors.
I went back to the border control
handed in my certificate by all these
different doctors, examinations,
physical and mental. They said,
we have no other choice but to give
you a license reinstated, Bang.
So it was three of the biggest
obstacles in my life at once.
We're all done within a
month or two straight away.
Then not just an easy
task of losing 160 pounds,
whichever of got overall I'm other things.
Losing weight as a fighter was something
that I'd done that tron. Anyway,
so that me and Ben sat about losing this
hundred and 60 pounds along the way.
Back home. Spoke to Frank Warren. He
became the promoter I'm frank had, right?
You've had a long time at the ring.
You've abuse your body.
Let's get your four or five comeback
fights just so you're ready. I said, okay,
no problem. How one called might
fight hard, the other combat fight.
I said to frank, I don't need any more
combat fights. Make the wild of right now.
No, no, no, no, no. He said, let's have
a couple more just in case. I said,
I'm telling you, make the wild a fight.
So this is where people don't understand.
I've picked Deontay wilder. He
didn't pick me. I picked him.