Let's, let's be clear, the Anti Vaccine
Lobby owns the Internet right now.
What does that mean?
What that means is they've got,
they've put out now by some estimates,
500 anti-vaccine websites.
So that every time you put the
word vaccine into a search engine,
whether it's Yahoo or Google, you're
going to get anti-vaccine misinformation.
That's number one. Second, we
know now it's amplified, um,
social media like Facebook or
other forms of social media.
So a third, um, you know, look
at the Amazon site. I mean, it's,
it's incredible. So my book, this
book, the good news is, it's,
I think it's, right now it's the highest
rate of pro vaccine book on Amazon.
The bad news is overall
it's ranked about 20,
because there's 19 other phony baloney
anti-vaccine books. So that's the,
Amazon is the biggest purveyor now
of anti-vaccine books. And wait,
it gets even worse. Then you also
have, now they've become politicized.
They have political action committees
and multiple states lobbying state
legislators about, uh, um,
fault with plying them with false
information about what vacs vaccines do.
So,
and,
and the problem is we don't have a
robust system of pro vaccine advocacy to
counter it.
So we don't really hear as much as we
need to from the federal government,
from the CDC, from the surgeon general.
So unfortunately in this country,
that defensive vaccines false to a
handful of academics like myself,
you know, I'm an academic,
I wrote a book. What,
what chance do I stand against
this major, uh, media empire.
Why do you think that exists?
Why do you think there is this major
media empire that's against vaccines?
That's a great question. What's the
motive? What's the motivation, number one,
and number two, where's the
money coming from? Right, right.
There's real money behind this is
millions of dollars behind this to put out
phony documentaries and phony books.
What's a good phone he
documentary to point to? Well,
I'm a little reluctant to do it.
Say it because they're so litigious and,
and uh,
and you know,
I don't have the means to defend
a lawsuit and things like that. So
these documentaries,
I usually don't mean specific aims are,
I understand these documentaries.
What do you think their motivation is?
Do you think they earnestly believe that
vaccines do cause harm or vaccines do
cards? I autism. I don't know.
I mean is there some kind of
other agenda that they have?
I mean we do know in some cases that um,
the some elements of the anti vaccine
lobby or promoting phony autism therapies,
right? They're doing terrible
things like this thing called MMS,
which are bleach and amongst
whites. Yeah. Bleach,
giving bleach enemas to catch you
couldn't to children the children bleach,
bleach because they're
cleansing the immune system.
A cleansing them of toxin
though it's really awful stuff.
And they're doing culation therapy,
which is very dangerous. What is that?
That's where they, they claim, you know,
kids are overdosed with toxic metals,
so they give a chemical that actually can
collate the metal, but it can kill it,
your calcium and then put you
into a fatal Arrhythmia as well.
They're also who is doing this
culation therapy. You can Google it.
It's a or whatever search engine
or these doctors like suns,
some cases there are doctors unfortunately
or other health professionals.
And what is, I mean, I'm sure you've
studied evidence late. It gets worse.
There's no evidence. And then, and
then they're doing hyperbaric therapy,
which is really bad. So insomnia,
hyperbaric therapy is bad. Well for,
it doesn't do anything for
autism, that's for sure. But it's,
it's good for recovering from injuries
and yeah, there's certain selected sir.
But who knows what, who knows what it's
doing to a young kid, right? I mean, so,
so you shouldn't be doing that. Um,
the then the other then that's one.
So how much of this is being driven by,
um,
financial motivation peddling these
phony autism therapies? I can't say.
My sense is that's not
the big piece of this.
There's also some reports now Russian
bots and trolls that are amplifying this
and sewing political instability
in the country. But again,
you add that all up the phony autism
therapies, the Russian bots and trolls,
to my mind,
that really doesn't get our arms
around the big driver of this thing.
So I think we really need
some good investigative
journalist to look into this.
Well do you think that there's something
sort of a concerted effort or do you
think that it's just a bunch of people
that really believe that vaccines do
cause autism?
They don't truly understand the science
and they haven't talked to someone like
you and maybe they have this idea that
cemented in their mind and they're not
willing to look at it objectively and
look at the full spectrum of possibilities
and look at the science behind
what you guys are saying.
Because in their head they've
been saying vaccines cause autism.
They've been saying it for so long
that once someone gets that and they're
connected to that, it's very
difficult for them to shift gears.
V People have a really hard time
not being married to an idea. Yeah,
no I agree that and um,
you know,
when I talk and I spend a lot of time
going around the country giving, uh,
what are called grand rounds lectures
to hospitals and medical schools,
pediatric grand rounds.
So I've had the chance to talk to a lot
of pediatricians and nurses and nurse
practitioner even and more
and more than a few parents.
My impression is most of
the parents are who are,
who are called to be so called vaccine
hesitant as the word of the day are not
really deeply dug in. I mean, you can,
you can have a conversation with them
and explained to them like we're talking
now in a very, you know,
nontechnical way, you know,
the evidence showing vaccines don't
cause autism and the lack of plausibility
given, uh, that it,
that it begins in pregnancy and
they'll vaccinate their kids.
There is another percentage,
and I don't know what the percentage is,
whether it's 10 15 that are deeply
dug in and are wholly invested in this
conspiracy theory that the,
that the government is in cahoots with
the pharmaceutical companies and Blahdy,
blahdy Blah. And then if you
try to talk them out of it,
they just think you're part
of the conspiracy. So it's,
it's sort of a no win approach
there, but, but most parents,
you can have a good conversation
with most parents. Um,
it's not necessarily even most
parents, right? I mean, what,
what you're dealing with is these people
that maybe they're into a bunch of
different alternate therapies,
a bunch of different kinds of cleansing.
And you know, there's a lot
of that nonsense that you
find online where, I mean,
look, there's legitimate, but I, but I
guess, but I guess my point, I'm sorry.
That's okay. Please go ahead
now. But I guess my point is, um,
parents don't get the chance because
they're so inundated with phony
anti-vaccine information that they do
a Google search or whatever, you know,
whatever search they do.
So what do you think should be done?
Should there be a pro vaccine documentary?
That makes sense.
I think,
thanks for that question.
I think there's three things that
need to be done. I think first of all,
some of this anti-vaccine media empire
needs to be dismantled, dismantled,
dismantled, and that, again,
whether they're wrong or
right, like shouldn't, I mean,
it seems like there should be
some sort of a debate, right?
Like if there's someone who's saying
that there's some evidence of vaccines
caused debates, you're saying there's no
evidence of vaccines caused debate. Uh,
excuse me,
that vaccines cause autism.
And you're saying there's no
evidence that vaccines cause autism.
There should be a debate where there
some sort of a like some sort of a
monitored conversation where you can have
you versus someone else and break this
down. Yeah. But that, that has, that's
a two edge sword too because you know,
then it gives some false legitimacy
to the anti anti-vaccine side.
It's like debating the smoking caused
cancer. Yeah. But doesn't that,
isn't there already a problem?
I mean it seems like if there's this many,
if you do Google search and
you're just overwhelmed with anti,
it seems like the fight has already been
lost. If that's the case. That's right.
So giving them legitimacy looks like
it's not necessarily giving them a
legitimacy.
It's giving them,
you give you rather a forum to
dismiss their legitimacy. Yeah.
I mean, I think, you know, part of it,
what has to be done is, I mean, and,
and this gets into all sorts of First
Amendment issues and I'm not a lawyer,
but you know,
the,
the idea that Amazon now is putting
out all of these phony books and,
and phony documentaries or
they're just a distributor, right?
They don't have to go over every book
that they sell with a fine tooth,
but maybe they should, I
mean, not fine tooth comb,
but maybe there should be some screening.
Maybe Amazon may be Facebook should all
be hiring chief scientific officers to,
you know, putting some stops
on the dissemination of,
of information because it's
harming children. Right? I mean,
this is the reason I get
passionate about it. Um,
the reason I actually wrote the book
because it's kind of interesting,
I it actually before all of these big
measles outbreaks that we've been having.
Yeah, I noticed that in
Texas there was, where I,
my laboratory is at Texas Children's
Hospital and Baylor College of Medicine,
we noticed that there was a steep increase
in the number of kids whose parents
are opting them out of getting vaccinated
to the point where in Texas we have
over 60 almost 60,000 kids not getting
their vaccines in the state of Texas.
And those are the ones we know about.
We don't know anything about
the 325,000 homeschooled kids.
So we probably have over a hundred
thousand kids not getting vaccinated,
all because of this
misinformation campaign.
And I was really troubled by the fact
that there was no response to it and that
drove me to write the book.
So the point is now Texas is very
vulnerable to measles outbreaks.
And I say measles more than the others
because that's the most highly contagious
disease. What are the danger
of a child getting measles?
So is there any benefit to a child
getting measles in terms of their immune
system? No, there's no benefit.
And that's one of the phony books they
put out called Melanie's marvelous
measles. I mean it's, it's awful. So,
um, uh, what did they say in that book?
They say build your immune system. It
does not. It does not. It's remember, um,
after,
so let's go back a little bit.
Smallpox was eradicated in the late
1970s through vaccination. One,
smallpox was eradicated.
Radica measles was arguably the single
leading killer of children globally.
2.6 million children died every year.
And measles because it causes measles,
pneumonia, measles and cephalitis talk
about permanent neurologic injury.
That's a bad actor. Measles,
uh, and then deafness at all.
And then through global
vaccination campaigns,
we brought it down by the year 2000
to about half a million kids dying.
And then the gates foundation put up $750
million to create the Gavi alliance to
global lines for vaccines and
immunization. We've brought
it down now to 100,000,
but now measles is coming back.
Europe's a disaster right now.
We've got 80,000 measles cases in 2018
in Europe and now it's coming back to the
u s and so my worry is this meet the
anti-vaccine media empire isn't it started
out as a fringe group, but now it's
really effecting public health,
allowing a deadly disease
like measles to come back.
Do you think if there's some sort of
definitive evidence that shows to the
general public like you could,
you could show it to them like
this is what causes autism.
We've narrowed it down to these genes and
it, it has nothing to do with vaccines.
If you give these vaccines to
people without these genes,
there is no way they're
going to get autism.
They get autism specifically because
of these variations in their change.
You just,
you just summarize the book,
but I mean we need more than a book,
right?
It does disturb me when I hear about
all these kids getting measles and,
and not just measles, but it means in
some places polio has made a resurgence,
you know? Well, polio in know
we're down to about three,
three countries that still
have transmission, a wild
type polio. It's Nigeria,
Pakistan, Afghanistan, so hopefully
we're getting our arms around polio.
But measles is now come back,
roaring back with a vengeance.
Having people contracted
polio outside of those areas.
I mean those are the areas where it's calm
every now and then. Some cases pop up.
We had some in wherever and this could
get it onto a whole nother topic.
Wherever there's collapse
in health systems,
infrastructure such as during two
from war, political instability,
these diseases can come back,
they can come back.
And the people that are vulnerable,
the children that are not immunized.
That's right. And when you're immunized,
you're not vulnerable. That's right. Yeah.
This is,
it's a really confusing thing for people
because on the outside they w people
always want to think that big Pharma,
but I've,
I've said some terrible things about
big Pharma and the reason being is
painkillers because painkillers and
antidepressants and there's the Ssri is
which are over prescribed and the
painkiller one kills me because I have no
people directly that have been addicted
to these goddamn things and the doctors
are passing them out like candy. So
people look at big Pharma as being, oh,
these are the monsters that push this.
They're also the people that give
you things that save people's lives.
There's a lot going on there.
I'm, I'm no big defender of, uh,
of the big pharmaceutical companies.
I mean,
one of the things that the anti vaccs
the insults at anti-vaxxers hurled at me
as they say,
I'm a shill for industry.
They say I'm a secretly taking money
from Merck and Glaxo Smith Kline.
It's all crap. I don't take a
penny from them. And I, and I,
and it's not even how do you get paid
just by the, from the university,
they get paid by the university.
And some of that, uh,
some of my salary's offset by not
grants from nonprofit foundations.
Um, then, uh, this is like the
national tropical diseases, right?
And then they say,
I'm secretly making millions of dollars
for our vaccines for hookworm and
schistosomiasis and chagas disease with
all that money. Because my wife says,
if only that were the case, right? These
are diseases of the poorest of the poor.
I'll never make a penny on these
disease. And in fact, you know,
one of the frustrations I have with the
big pharmaceutical companies is we've
gotten a lot,
made a lot of progress of their vaccines.
We've gone all the way from discovery
through early phase process development
and manufacturing an I and d filing
with the FDA investigational new drug
applications. But we're in and
kind of stuck at phase one,
phase two clinical trials because we
don't have the big Pharma money to take us
all the way to licensure.
So I've had a lot of meetings with the
big pharmaceutical companies to see if
they can partner with us.
And so far that hasn't happened.
So is has there ever been any discussion
or any interest in creating some sort
of a,
a compelling documentary that's pro
vaccination that can counter all of these
things?
Cause there's,
there's quite a few health related
documentaries that I know are horse shit
because I've talked to
actual real scientists and
clinical researchers that say
like all these things they're saying are
wrong and this is why they're wrong in
this. You could show this the
wrong. And then when someone, Hey,
I saw this documentary, it says it, all
you should eat is toast. They could say,
listen man, you've got to go here and
watch this, and it'll show you why.
That's nonsense.
Right.
Is there anything like that right now or
was there any discussion? Not right now.
There are some discussions,
but we're a long way off from that
and the problem is the anti-vaccine
documentaries are being distributed,
widely distributed, widely sold,
and and those people that are talking
about it. Here's the other problem.
Whenever I talk to someone about it was
I've been doing this a lot lately where
I've talked to some of the
about something. They're
passionate about it. I go,
what books have you read on it? And it's
like, wow, I saw this documentary. Well,
very, and there are, in
fact, there's 19 I bullshit,
19 ahead of mine write books that
are written by actual researchers,
people that have spent decades in
labs understanding what's going on.
You don't really,
you know,
you don't get a lot of that from the
people that are anti anything. Right.
Well, that's, that's what
I wrote, the new book.
It's a very confusing thing for parents
because you're scared. You know,
you have this little tiny baby that you
love more than anything in this world.
And then the doctor say,
Hey,
we've got this round of vaccines common
and you're just terrified that you're
going to do something to your child is
going to turn your child into a someone
who's compromised. Yeah.
And, and the point is, um,
problem is these diseases
her back now and so they're,
the urgency to vaccinate is now more
than ever. I mean remember right now,
look what's going on in Vancouver,
Washington right now where the measles
outbreak is underway. The ones who,
who are at greatest risk,
our infants under the age of 12 months,
not yet old enough to get their vaccine.
So that if you're a parent right
now living in Vancouver, Washington,
you're terrified.
You're terrified about taking your baby
out the Walmart or cause they break that
vaccine cause they're,
that we'll never get the right.
So now the disease is coming back because
the older kids are catching it and the
entity and the anti vaccine lobby uses
terms like personal liberties and medical
freedom.
Well where the personal liberties of this
parent now who's terrified to take her
in when you say his or her
infant anti vaccine lobby? No,
I know that Robert Kennedy Jr
is a, he's a, he's a big one.
He's a big one and he seems
like a very intelligent guy.
How could he not be aware of the science
behind this and what is he getting
wrong? What he's getting wrong is
just about everything. Um, you know,
he's formed an organization called
children's health defense and um,
and it start, he had a press conference
about it, I think it was September,
October of last year.
It is probably one of the best organized
anti-vaccine groups out there now he's
doing other things other than vaccines.
He's doing a lot of things about
environmental health and things like that.
I don't know any part of that business.
I've only followed what the,
what he does with vaccines. But
it's all, it's all nonsense.
Why is he doing this about vaccine?
It's don't know what's his book? I mean,
you have to ask him what,
what's his motivation?
He be a guy that you would want to have
a debate with or have a discussion with.
But again, I mean, I'm uncomfortable with
the idea of a debate because it's like,
it's like debating,
I dunno,
it's like debating our Holocaust denier
whether the Holocaust exists. I mean,
not that this rise, I understand what
you're saying, but if you're, again,
I want to bring this up. If
you're, you're complaining,
there's 19 books ahead of yours
that are anti vaccine books.
You've already lost the battle.
Like it's time to regroup
and maybe regrouping would
be confronting someone with
actual scientific information
mean you are a real doctor.
You're a guy who actually studies this
and you're a man who understands the
science. You're legitimate
academic. You could,
you could actually put a dent in
this with a real conversation. Yeah,
potentially. Potentially. Yeah. I
mean, what would he be able to say?
Like what is his take on
it? Well, remember he's a,
he's an attorney and he's
a, he's very clever. Right?
And now he knows how to presumably
knows how to do arguments in court.
And what am I am a scientist.
Do you think that he wants to deceive
people or do you think that maybe he's
just incorrect his accumulation of data?
Yeah.
I can't say what his motivation
is, but, um, his, uh, his,
his information is, is
highly misleading. Hmm.
Now, what else is he,
when you say the lobby,
is this an organized thing?
Good question. Again,
we need somebody who really wants to do
a deep dive in this and kind of dissect
out the pieces to
understand. Um, but it's,
it's impressive what you've got out there
in terms of the hundreds of websites
and the amplification on social
media and everything else. Is it,
are there just one or two or three groups
behind it or is it a random collection
of organizations that that
needs to be looked at.