Hello you on. Hi. Charlie was crazy man.
What's happening? Yeah, good. I've just,
we're just saying we want to cover the, I
uh, I've met a note to myself that says,
talk slow, talk American because although
I spend about half the year here,
we British people,
there's a reorientation where you
suddenly realize I was once in a, uh,
an Ihub in cactus Arizona and I
was saying to the woman, right,
like I'll have some pancakes, whatever
it was. And she kept looking at me going,
what? I know after about
literally three minutes, she goes,
do you speak English? That's like,
let people fucking invented it. Right.
But no one was there to laugh at my such
cause they didn't understand what the
fuck I was saying. Arizona is a
strange place. I really love Arizona.
There's great parts. Like Phoenix is
amazing. Tucson's a great place too,
but it's a wild west sort of a state.
It's one of those weird hold over states
and have a lot of weird old school laws.
Like, like a, I think you could just
walk around with a gun. Yeah, you can.
My main experience in Phoenix
was in Arizona in fact,
was going out with a group of women
who were made to go out on a chain gang
wearing tee shirts saying I was a drug
addict when members of the public mock
them in Jira at that right.
Cause written this book about very
spoke about the war on drugs and I said,
Joe Arpaio, sheriff our Pio, no longer
sheriff now thankfully. But uh, yeah,
and it was, yeah, Arizona is a
deeply weird place. It's weird.
A lot of really nice people,
but it's 150,000 degrees. Yeah.
Well literally almost nobody lived
there until I conditioning was invented.
Right.
You see what I once met a horrendous
mistake in fact in Phoenix where I had to
walk somewhere and I could see on
the map it was like a mile away.
So it's not just walk,
it's fine.
And I got like halfway there and people
are literally stopping that car is going,
are you okay?
Because the only reason anyone would ever
walk in eggs was basically if your car
had broken down the car to them. I might
have actually just chosen to walk. Right.
Plus you're so white guy.
I'm literally like a tomato
with a Brazilian who would
literally just look up my
body and laugh and be like, you're
so white. How can a human be so like,
right. I don't always, I
never have a nice color.
Like I'm either this albino
color or red rock. I never,
there's no rich brown hue
that none of my ancestors,
the Scottish and Swiss. So they never saw
the sun. Right. And none of my ancestors,
my friend Jamie was over my house
once and he's not this friend Jamie,
different friend Jamie who's
a British as well. And um,
my daughter who was a at the time,
I think she was like 10 or something
like that, she goes, she goes to my wife,
she goes, mommy, he's so white. She,
and she goes, yeah. She goes, no, no,
like he's white, like
paper. So from then on,
Jamie became Jamie White,
like paper,
very accurate description of my
lack of pigment is currently true.
It's funny that we, how much we
appreciate the English accent though.
The English accent is like one of the
best tools for selling things to very
gullible Americans.
Whether it's like people benefit from
constant positive discrimination in the
United States.
Right?
It's like having a 10 inch Dick just
having a British accent people cause they
like, oh my God, you got an accent at
all. Humans have accents. I've just got a,
you know,
let's say to provide itself a cherished
one we looked at were really into it.
It makes you feel like you're
more sophisticated. You're,
you're more well read. They're
more aware of the world. I mean,
I just am sophisticated
and well ride anyway. No,
but you've got this
called stood. Um, yeah.
Coastally people ascribing to you much
better qualities than you actually have.
But what does it work in
reverse? Like in, in England?
What is the reaction to American
accents is it's mostly discussed, right?
I don't know. There's a
mixture. Americans, we grow.
I always think like the relationship
with Britain and America,
it's like I'm one of those police mirrors
because we grow up constantly looking
at the United States, right?
We're constantly staring through.
We are immersed in American culture,
right?
When Americans look back cause they're
just seeing like a reflection of
themselves.
I mean Americans watched Downton Abbey
and know about like the queen or whatever,
but there isn't that two way dialogue that
there is that the, the, the, you know,
the, yeah, so it's a slightly weird,
so I think we feel very American,
right?
And I spent half of the year here and I,
you know,
every now and then you come up against
these deep cultural differences that
you're just like, oh fuck, okay. Right.
This is really not my culture. Right?
And it's those moments of disorientation
or a really strange, like,
give me one if for an example.
Well,
there's a question that Americans ask
all the time that I have literally never
heard of European ass, right? I asked
the question, what's your story? Right?
Every American,
you can go to the most crusty,
right wing person coming out and Mara
Largo or a kid in West Baltimore and you
can say, well, it's your story.
And they'll have an answer.
The only context I can imagine a British
person saying, what's your story?
Would be in a police interrogation.
It would be an extremely hostile question.
What's your story? Right? It would be,
you just wouldn't ever say it, right?
We don't Americans narrativize their
lives in a way I absolutely love.
And as a journalist who writes books about
like depression and addiction and you
want people to talk about their lives,
it's an unbelievable gifty, right?
That people will tell you,
I've never once been on
a bus in Mississippi and
sitting next to a woman and
within five minutes of chatting tell,
she told me about like her two
miscarriages, how her mother hated her.
And I thought if we were
switched where my dad's from,
you wouldn't tell me this until we got
married and maybe not even that. Right?
So there's a level of candor and
storytelling among Americans.
It's one of the best things
about this, this, this, you know,
fucked up an amazing place. I just love
it. There's something about, there's a,
there's a kind of a narrative openness
that's very different about this place
than Europe, anywhere in Europe. Now
when you talk to people in England,
you guys don't have the
same level of social media,
not social media, but of
um, reality television. You
have some like big brother,
but you don't have it to the extent that
we have it here. Right? Yeah, it hasn't,
well, I mean your country has literally
been taken over by reality television,
right? We have a relative
term president. Uh, no,
it hasn't conquered the whole
culture in that way. Well,
he's a reality television president, but
he's sort of a game show host president.
Like that's how I used to describe
myself and I was hosting fear factor.
They were like, you host a reality
show, Mike, sort of, it's a game show.
It's just a fucked up game show.
It's like Trump was hosting a
game show essentially. Right.
It was a contest. It wasn't like
keeping up with the Kardashians.
That's in true reality show because
there's literally nothing going on other
than these people's lives and whatever
orchestrated bullshit they put in to make
it more interesting. Yeah. I
hadn't thought about it that way.
I think this class because,
but I think that's part of the thing
that it was getting to about Americans
always wanted to give you their narrative.
They always want to give you the story
of their life. So when someone says,
what's your story? They already
have it ready. You know?
Cause it's almost like we feel like
we're in some sort of a small television
show all the time or some
sort of small production.
It's like almost a part of our who we are.
Yeah.
Every American can thinks that the
star if their own movie. Right.
And I forget who said this,
but someone realize, you know,
sometimes in life you realize that
you're just the extra, right? Yeah.
You'll do the, you're in the corner of
the shawl. Right, right. And, um, yeah,
I think that's true.
And I think that's,
that's not as true of British
people or I think there's certain,
how to put it. Like there's a
certain kind of self deprecation.
You're taught as a British person,
you're taught.
And I had to kind of unlearn it living
here. So what would be examples? Uh,
I forget where I read this story,
so maybe it's not true,
but I remember in it years ago, so we
had these terrible subway bombs in 2005,
I'm sure you remember for young British
men go onto the London Underground and
murder, I think it was over 50 people
and two weeks later, another group of,
um, jihadis tried to do the same thing,
but they hadn't built the bombs very well.
So they go down into the subway
and the owl, there's a loud bang,
but it doesn't connect with the detonator.
So there's a loud bang but
doesn't actually blow everyone up.
Obviously people freak the fuck out, as
you can imagine. Right. And I forget,
maybe this isn't,
maybe this is a story that someone
told them that wasn't factually true,
but he's, I think it reveals
something very, very,
something about British character.
Cause if I remember rightly, um,
three of the bombers escape on the escape
on the day in a court like a few hours
later and one of them's caught on
at the time, right. And someone,
I think it was an off duty fire officer
in the story chases after them for ages,
chasing after the guy for ages while
everyone else is running the fuck away and
you can't just the guy and
he throws him to the ground.
And what he said to him was that the
opportunity fire officer says to the
attempted suicide bomber,
you rude, rude man. Right.
And what I love about that is like the
idea that suicide bombing is just like
bad manners. It's like it's just
impolite, right? Or even a better example,
which is true. It was reported
at the time, definitely was um,
during the riots we had in
2011, uh, in London, um,
there was one place,
I forget where it is,
where they broke into a luxury goods
store and they could only make a,
it was a very strong window so they could
only make a hole in the corner of the
window and it was caught on the security
cameras that the rioters formed a to go
in and look at the store.
Right.
That's how deep the idea of like Keurig
and making a line is in British culture.
Even in a riot where like,
I don't know,
I think you where you were before me right
there. I've got to chill out in front.
Isabelle Bank. Hey, he lives in,
he lives in London and she liked if I
her phone to be able to, she read that.
I'd be like, you fucking English. You
don't know how to riot this and I'm Roger.
Probably a Q. What's wrong
with you people? Right?
You guys don't have black Friday sales.
Do you know? They've just started. Yeah.
It's an unfortunate business. Might
be the end of you. Humility. Exactly.
We're not going to make it.
We survived.
The Nazis were not fucking
survive in black Friday. Right?
There's something about those deals when
people get that bargain and then they
open that door ready, go and people pile
through. All humanity gets tossed aside,
get you in this line to the
fucking financial desperation
of ordinary Americans.
Right?
It's a little bit of that,
but it's also the competitive nature of
those things where you're trying to grab
the few remaining items that are 25%
off and even saving for this TV for six
months,
and there it is right in front of you
and you charge and people are fighting
left and right. It's awful. It says
it's just a terrible way for people to,
you know,
interact with each other.