To, to understand if we can innovate
off of it. Yeah, maybe. Yeah. Um,
what did you think when they found that?
Um,
Flores man on in Indonesia?
It's amazing. I like,
I'm not an anthropologist,
so you know,
that's not quite been 100% that zed 100%
agreed upon because I've only seen kind
of headlines. I, I'd have to defer
to you guys. I think there was one,
there was some scientists
that was disputing but,
but essentially they were talking about
a three foot tall hobbit, like man,
kind of cave dwelling. Yeah.
That little person, yeah.
Existed alongside human beings as recently
as like 14,000 years ago. Right, right.
Which is like what I, I think it's
completely believable. I mean they're,
the Khoisan people in the Sahara
desert are tiny, you know, there,
there are big like four
feet. Ah, and until the,
you might have to double check this,
but I believe until the 70s
people used to go and hunt them.
Maybe it was earlier,
we just sixties or fifties but you could
go and hunt this primitive sized human
being as like a PA, you
know, as like a hunt,
like an old Englishman with
it's big mustache and his
musket would go hunt these
people. Whoa. And now we have
an understanding that, you know,
there are people like you can't fucking
go and hunt them. But like what's to say?
There weren't tribes like that all over
the world that other people used to hunt
that drove to extinction.
Jesus Christ. Right.
What would say the name of it again? So
Jamie, you got it. You got Koi sanding.
Yeah. Let me see what these people
look like. They're, in my opinion,
they're beautiful. Like
you'll see what you think. But
they're, they're very small.
They're desert dwellers. You know, there's
not a lot of resources in the desert,
so you don't get huge. So they're
perfectly adapted to the desert life.
They really used to hunt them. Yeah. And
they look just like people. I mean you,
you'll have,
but they're still around.
Like these aren't an extinct race.
There's still there. Oh Wow. Yeah.
If you ever seen the gods must be crazy.
Yes. Yeah. It's like those people,
those were kind of taller, coy
sand, but those are Bushman.
So who are these people that used to
hunt these? Like I say, I kid you not.
It was like the old English explorer
would go and conquer Africa and,
and hunt these people. Like they were
an animal, you know? Fuck crazy. Right.
And this was until the 1970s that might
not be right. That sounds too recent,
doesn't it? Damn, that sounds horrific.
Yeah. You might need to check that.
But it was not as long ago as you'd think.
You know what I mean?
It was like very recently they were
still under under hunting can they're
people, Jesus Christ. Yeah. So that,
that's probably what happened to a lot
of the non homosapien human type people.
I would think so.
And even if it's not like for sport
it's for competition or resources or you
know what, any reason and that's,
that's human nature. Conquer. Yeah.
Fuck man, that is so dark. Right.
They would go and hunt small
people with a rifle. Yup. You know,
not there photos of people like
posing with the dead ones. Um, again,
I'm not an anthropologist. I'm
not sure. Yeah, it's brutal.
Yeah.
So what are the pockets of the world are
like mostly unexplored or could perhaps
contain some of these animals? South
America for sure. Central Africa for sure.
There's some very remote parts
of like Russian, Arctic, um,
Norwegian Arctic. Um, there's areas
in Asia that are still unexplored,
believe it or not, regardless
of their populace, there
really are deep, deep China.
There are some very unexplored areas.
Uh,
northern myin mar ecological hotspot,
nobody goes there very impenetrable.
I read something about sort of some part
of the world where they thought Tara
doctorals might still exist.
There's so many of those things.
I don't know that one specifically.
There's, especially doing what I do,
I hear them all the time. Right? Oh,
you got to go look for a big foots are
Taryn actos or whatever. Mamet's it's,
it could there be a large
reptile that perhaps flies? Sure.
It's possible. Is there a terra dactyl
as we know it, I highly, highly doubt it,
but a large reptile that can fly, it
would be a fucking trip they were around.
Right. So do you think it
would be something that we
don't know about? Like, yeah,
basically I think there's enough pieces
of this world that are unexplored that
there are still nega phonic
to be discovered. Not a
lot. Not a lot by any means.
And I might get ridiculed as I go back
to my scientific community for saying
this,
but my belief is there are these isolated
pockets where small populations of
Megafaun is still exist that we
don't know about. Whoa. Yeah. Well,
South America is, I mean, how much of
South America is actually populated?
I mean, you look at the size of the Amazon
jungle or something and it's, it's the,
sure there's, there's
communities and stuff, but not
that much. I mean, it's there.
Australia, you know, if you're not
on the coast, there's nothing, right?
There's all these huge chunks. Papa,
when you're Guinea, same thing.
Nobody goes up into the highlands there.
They just found a dog there. As you saw.
I mean,
there's crazy stuff.