Hello freak bitches,
got back in with Alex and spent a little
bit time hanging around with him and
Roger Stone and so on and got really
interested in the kind of dynamics of how
Alex and Trevor communicate to each other.
But I'm wondering if you've seen
Alex more recently than I have now.
Alex has been my friend since 1998 yeah,
I was at his custody trial not long
ago. And you were brought up, you were
smoking pot on my show. He was smoking
pot. Just chesting it. How she,
George Soros makes the weeds
stronger. That's what he said.
He said that in this custody
trial. That's exactly what he said.
He said he tests it once a
year just to, cause he's,
he's weird because he's always
there when that happens.
I mean D I mean, come on man.
What's really funny is we drank whiskey
on the show too and no one gives a shit
about that. It's way more destructive.
It's the pot, whatever it is.
The self reflective. Yeah.
Paranoia, inducing marijuana.
It's a real problem. But I now wonder,
so he says that Trump called and
just after the election thank him.
And I'm inclined to believe that's true
cause I don't think that's the kind of
thing that Alex would lie
about. But have you got any,
if you come to any conclusion about
whether there is a connection between Alex
and Trump now?
Cause I'm beginning to think maybe
there just isn't any more that may be,
but I could be wrong. That's
a good question. I don't
know. I mean first of all,
I don't see how Trump can have a
connection with that many people.
I feel like the job of being the president
has got to be so insanely demanding.
The idea that he likes, he's taken
a few moments out of his day.
He's got his feet up on the chair with
a laptop and he's on info wars.com it's
like God damn,
I've got to call Alex and find out what
the fuck's going on with this child.
A slavery thing on Mars. You know,
where are these slaves?
Tell me where we're on Mars.
I think it benefits everyone to think
that it's cause it makes an X Trump look
bad. So it benefits people on
the left to say that Alex is a,
is connected to Trump.
It kind of benefits Alex,
I think for people to think it too,
cause they aggrandized his him.
Well it helps him in a way. I
mean it's like the people that,
there's a bunch of people
that enjoy Alex, right?
So some of them enjoy it for the theater.
There's a theater element
of it all. You know, I mean,
and it's all doom and gloom
and yeah. And then some of it,
some people enjoy because like Bohemian
Grove occasionally he's correct.
Like Bohemian Grove was a real mind
fuck when you see all these super rich
people were in robes,
right? In effigy. Yeah.
I was in the crowd with all the
old men of wealth in Dallas.
Don't freak you out and you see those
people. One thing freaked me out.
I'm like, Alex came out of out
Bohemian Grove night with uh, with,
with a varying interpretation of, of what,
what was your interpretation? My
interpretation is basically with,
with one caveat I'm about
to caveat there. Okay. Um,
my interpretation was that it's just like
fucking, you know, skull and bones or
[inaudible], you know, those
are all creepy, right? Yeah.
And they want to Nevis that does seem to
be amongst the American ruling elites.
That does seem to be a
proclivity for ritual. Um,
maybe a, maybe amongst the British
elites as well. I'm not sure about,
but that's in itself psychologically
interesting. I think secrets too, right?
So it's like why? So
that is interesting. Why,
even if the ritual at Bohemian
Grove, I, I, you know,
and I would contend that
contrary to what Alex implied,
they weren't actually sacrificing a child.
You didn't say they were
sacrificing your child.
Then you said at some point
and then this video. Yeah.
It couldn't be real copy be ladies
and gentleman. It couldn't be real.
He probably was so jazzed up that they
were actually dressed up like monks,
people,
the hoods and they have the Moloch the
owl guy when he was actually there,
I mean that probably ramped
up his love of conspiracy.
Oh solid three or 400%.
It was hilarious cause you know
we went in separately to to um,
cause Alex got it into his head that
maybe I was part of the Bohemian Grove
deep, deep inside. Yeah. Like the
wicked man that I was like learning.
And then some, he would be the ones who
were first in the Valley at the hour.
So he went in separately to be,
he went in far the undergrowth
and I went up the street,
I just went in the driveway,
gave the security guard or kind of
viral the world wave and then we went in
there. That's all you had
to do. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The guy so often the case.
Yeah. So white house.
And then we saw Alex and Mike Hanson,
who was his producer at the time,
walking like towards us. And I was
with this local lawyer who had,
who would we talked up with?
And I was like, um, Hey,
you know Alex, Mike, how you doing?
And they were like, keep walking.
There's cameras in the trees,
there's hours everywhere.
And then there's no walls. Yes, because
we felt like the owls were cameras.
They got it into their heads
that the hours at Bohemian Grove,
the hour motifs that Bohemian Grove, uh,
was indicative of the fact that
it was like molec the owl guard.
And it was like some sort of satanic.
But actually I would say that the
reason why there's all those hours,
cause I saw like stuffed hours
in display cabinets and so on.
But I think it's like, I think
it's an owl sanctuary. So
anyway, they stuffed on
that. I'll say for me,
I presume it died of natural
causes. [inaudible] shit.
He fucking sanctuary. If
they kill it then stuff it.
So it's sorta like a Norman
Bates mom and psycho stuff.
But what was odd that night was
one thing that the artist moment,
and this is where I will,
this is where my memory of the
night does tally with Alex says,
is that for whatever reason the people
in the crowd were really into this,
this ceremony land. There was a sort of,
they were really fired up diet. Let some,
I remember this old guy walked up
to me before it started and said,
are you a first timer? And I went,
yeah, I do. Oh, you've got to love it.
You've got to love. It's like
burn and burn him or something.
Something along those lines. Uh,
and, and it did make me think,
and then I looked behind and there was
Alex and Mike why died looking like they
would ruin, you know,
the belly of the beast.
And then there's all these
old preppy men like wide-eyed.
They were really into it too.
I felt like the only sane person in
the entire Redwood forest, I was like,
the only person who's thinking
this is just fucking ridiculous.
It is ridiculous. But, but they
were into it. It was that moment.
It was that moment of revelation actually
that then led me to write the book
that I wrote after that book, which was
the metastatic goats, which is about,
you know, um, soldiers tried to kill
goats just by staring. And then,
cause I did, cause I remember lie, um,
I remember thinking I was
actually, I was in Belfast.
I was giving a talk about my book them,
which is where I talk about all of
that stuff. And somebody said, okay,
so I know what you think of it.
This woman in the audience said,
I know what you think. I know you
think this is like ridiculous.
And I know that Alex Jones thinks is evil,
but what about the people in the crowd?
What were they thinking about it?
And I thought that's a
really good question.
So that's what led me to write a book
about like a rational thoughts in powerful
places, which is what led me
to rap MedStar guts. When you,
when you're there and you see that there
really is this giant stone owl and they
really do have this bundle of sticks that
they're burning and everyone really is
wearing these robes. Like,
I mean you had a big part
of you how to be like,
how many of these fucking things are
going on that we haven't infiltrated?
And that's true that there's a, there's
a photo of it there. This is real.
I mean,
they really do have a giant owl and they
really do burn some sort of a sacrifice
in front of this owl. And there's
a speakers that are, uh, there's a,
there's a one point this is a lesser,
um, documented part of the ritual.
At one point there's a guy in leaf covet
later Hosan appears in like a stage cut
out at the Redwood tree and starts singing
this cat of allergy to nature. Like,
Oh, trees. So leaves.
So that's how it starts. That's
before of the men in robes turn up.
So it's like some weird pagan nature.
Literal covered later hose and Joe,
how much would you give to be in one
of those skull and bones meetings?
See if they actually like film each
other's suck index or something.
There's just something that goes on
where they have like something over those
guys supposedly. Yeah,
the conspiracy theory.
That's the means to engage in gay sex.
I do believe these things happen
for a reason. Like, you know,
skin and bones accessory reason
being they have something over you.
It could be that, or it could
be just this weird sense,
this weird of psychological need that
people like Ivy league people feel they
need to like have a sense of superiority.
And one way to do that is to kind of
create the secret rituals to get them a
sense of like, you know, grangeiro
for the people that's possible.
Now a guy like Alex Jones stumbles upon
something like that or infiltrates it
and finds out it is real. I mean,
that is justifying to such a,
an enormous, enormous level.
Yeah. But I'll expect, here's my,
my truck with Alex and all of this
is that it wasn't like the Alex,
all the fucking crazy shit that we saw
that night wasn't enough lucky hat to
like turn it up to 11 of course. Yeah.
I need apply that we had
possibly witnessed an actual
human sacrifice and said,
of course. But that standard, that
standard Alex Jones one-on-one,
but it shouldn't be styled. It
shouldn't be. But I mean, I mean,
think about all of the
exaggerations exaggerations
that take place in the media,
whether it's on the left or the right.
There's this rampant exaggeration. Well,
it's funny you should say that.
So did you watch Alex being interviewed
by Megan Kelly? Yes I did. Yeah.
Well that may be enough. You know,
they phoned me a couple of days before
the broadcast back in Kelly's people
cause they were panicking. I remember
there was like a lot of criticism.
They look at Ang food for having
them on in the first place. Yeah.
So they called me up and they basically
wanted me to give them as much evidence
as I could. The proof that
Alex and Trump were, you know,
aligned and they would talk to each
other and so on. Called you. Why?
Because you'd went to Bohemian grow
with them. I went to pay him and go,
but then I also put out this little
Kindle single last summer called the
elephant in the room in which I'm trying
to trace like the relationship between
Alex and Trump did via, and it's kind
of in this interesting stuff. But,
um, so I answered the
questions as best as I could,
but I don't know that much about exactly
how often Trump and Alex told to each
other. I don't know either. I'm not
even really that interested in it.
It was as odd as it is.
Like I have a very fucked up
relationship with Alex in, in that,
and he's actually my friend. And so when
I see him, it's like, what's up man?
What are you doing? I give
him a hug and people go, Oh,
he's a monster or hockey, be friends
with them and this and that. And like,
I don't know. Yeah, I just base it on
my interactions with them. And yet,
does he say fucked up things? Yeah.
It was the most disturbing thing that
I didn't even know when he did the
podcast. I didn't know that he
was a Sandy hook denier. Right.
So apparently he's backed
off that since, uh,
being confronted by the facts. And,
and there was a horrible article that I
read about a father who was actually a
conspiracy theorist until his
son was killed in Sandy hook.
And then he got death threats
for lying and presumably for,
from info Wars. And that was
so, so just so sad. Yeah.
That's just so hard.
People look for fucking conspiracies and
everything and I don't know what it is.
I have friends that have this
issue. I don't understand it.
Things that can be easily explained.
They look for a conspiracy.
Anything that happens in the news,
there's gotta be a different story.
Like sometimes shit just happens
and when that shit happens,
the news has a story. It doesn't always
have to be some sort of nefarious plot.
But these people also think that the
government is filled with idiots. Well,
I'm sorry, but you
can't have it both ways.
You can't have a bunch of incompetent
fuck heads who pull off the perfect fake
world where everything you see is some
sort of an elaborate played out scheme in
order to manipulate you into either
buying this or voting for that.
Like there's a weird inclination
that people have to uh, not just,
not just some conspiracy theories but
almost everything to think everything is
some part of some crazy plot.
I'm not sure I understand it.
What you said about like, you know,
biases and untruths and like across the
media on the left and underwrite remind
to be if the mechan Kelly
thing. So, um, you know,
so they phoned me up obviously in a bit
of a panic cause they were getting like
so much grace I said, and then they
reedited the show like frantically,
just before weaponry edited it. How
did they change? Well, I don't know,
but what I do know is like, yo,
I saw the final product and the final
product was basically Meghan Kelly,
like looking incredibly poised, saying,
um, you know, you're wrong Alex,
you're wrong about this. And then
it would cut to all it's go up. But,
but I haven't cut back to
Megan. So all they did was lie,
edit Alex at his most sweaty and stuttery
and then Meghan Kelly at her most
poised to perfect. What did you see?
Did you hear the Alex Jones a audio,
the leaked audio that he released? Yes.
Or they were sort of buttering him up and
conning him? Yeah, she was saying, uh,
personally I was saying, I don't,
I'm not here to make a hit piece.
I just want to know the real you.
And although they did rent it, so I,
I wonder what the original program would
have been like cause they felt forced
to basically by him. Yeah.
Well they felt forced by like the
people pushing back against them,
doing it all by him, uh, to then
put out this shitty, you know,
10 minutes. I basically was in Megan
Kelly's corner. I would have told her,
first of all, don't ever go to NBC.
Listen, here's the deal. Like you,
you made your bones as an ice princess
on this conservative network and do you
think they're just gonna
accept you at NBC? Right.
People are going to resent
you. They're going to hate you.
Like you're the lady that chastise
people for saying that Santa Claus
potentially wasn't white. I remember
that. I don't remember that. Oh my God,
it was something where
they were saying they were,
there was people talking about Santa
Claus being black and I'll never forget it
cause she was on TV going, you
know, listen, Santa Claus is white.
Like then I'm like, what the fuck
the fuck are you talking about?
Santa Claus isn't real. You crazy bitch.
You can't say Santa Claus is white more
than you could say cat in the hat is
red. They're not real things.
You know you can decide that.
You know like the cat in the hat in
the book is always white. Okay. Yeah,
you're right. Good point.
But is he black? Is he white?
What does the cat in the hat?
He's got a hat is red and white.
What color is he though? Hmm,
I think he's black, right?
Is he? Okay. All right. It's not porn,
but what's important is that like her
whole thing was being this spokesperson,
this ultra hot spokesperson
for the conservative movement,
but also being someone who's ruthlessly
smart and articulate and capable of
shutting down these stammering liberals
that day or go and question her,
her narrative, and then all of a sudden
she's on NBC. Like you can't do that.
That's a terrible move. I,
they're not going to accept you.
This is not going to work.
And the ratings have been
horrendous and now she's free.
And now they pulled the show.
They pulled the show early,
but it just goes to show like, you know,
we rightly attack people
like info Wars for spreading,
you know, outright lies.
Yes. But we on the left,
like Megan Kelly editing that segment
to make it look like she was poised and
perfect. Perfected all Alex does this
stammer and sweat. What's very hard,
very hard sell saying that
Megan Kelly's on the left,
she's on the left now what? I mean, the
mainstream, the main season that NBC,
so the main stream has its own tricks.
It's like, it's not an outright lie.
Like Alex would do, but
that, you know, panicky,
selective editing is
its own. Well I would,
I would have imagined that that Joel,
in the interview between
Alex and Megan Kelly,
Alex would have said some
things that were, you know,
eloquent or all or sentence without
Istomin in a swag. I'm sure. Yeah,
I'm sure.
Well here's also the problem and having
any sort of a conversation about Hey,
sort of difficult subject and stuffing
it into seven minutes or whatever it is.
It's ridiculous. Yeah.
It's an ancient way of communicating and
now that we have the internet and Alex
has shown with his own show, you know,
that he can go and rant
about something and you know,
for 15 minutes or whatever it is like,
and with no limitations
or restrictions like it's,
it's a better way to communicate.
And one of the things that I wanted to
do when I had Alex on the podcast is I
wanted people to see the Alex that I
know because there's no other way to see
him like that. I wanted to get them drunk.
I wanted to get them high and I wanted
to have them talk. And my friend Eddie,
who's just so in a conspiracy,
he kind of fucked some of it because he's
just so when a chem trails and proving
the chem trails are real,
but it was good overall
because it's like he was,
Alex is so crazy that
even Eddie was like, what?
It was a couple of wallets where
Eddie turned to look at Alex. He goes,
what the fuck?
Like when he's talking about
interdimensional child molesters and it's,
I wanted people to see
him the way I see him.
He's a fun guy that I
like hanging out with.
Do I think that he has a
lot of influence? Yeah.
Do I think he says things that he
definitely shouldn't say? Of course.
Especially the Sandy hook stuff. I mean,
I think this inclination to
always look towards conspiracy is,
is, is, is dangerous. It's
harmful. Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's,
it's, it's dangerous in
that people are easily led.
And if you get people thinking
that everything's a conspiracy,
the real problem is they don't know what
the fuck a conspiracy actually is when
it's in front of them and it's real,
and there's a ton of them that are real.
So when you call, you're crying
Wolf around every corner,
and then all of a sudden you
turn a corner. Like, Holy
shit, that's a real Wolf.
No one is listening. So I agree that
that's my frustration with Alex too,
is that he has a conspiracy template
and whatever real world event happens,
you can shoe horns into this kind
of simplistic template. Yeah.
[inaudible].