It's almost like the word fuck,
right?
Like you could stub your toe and fuck all,
you could see a Ferrari go fuck yeah,
it's do you know in Brazilian it's the
word com they use for that. Wait, what?
Yeah, it's whole. Huh? Paul? Huh. Okay.
So like you know like someone will catch
a guy on a choke and I go pull high.
Like that's a good thing. Or
You gonna fuck up yourself.
You're like, ah, Paul, hi.
Yeah, my keys Spanish say
[inaudible] yeah, that's
mother bitch. It's like a good,
it could be a good thing [inaudible] but
that makes sense. Like mother, bitch,
goddammit.
But come doesn't even make any sense.
Like I was trying to put my
feeling of it when you come,
it's like that is the sensation.
Like that was so good.
What can you do that almost felt like
me nutting and it could be bad in that
like you Dick Trick Ya and the fucking
this girl you've been trying to avoid and
then you come and you'll be doing that
is there's regret. What I did, everybody,
every women will never
understand post nuts syndrome.
I understand syndrome because this
is something exclusive to us. Yes.
Like I don't know. I like you until
I come Sha. It's true, right? Yeah.
You do not know. And it's, and
that's why it's so fucked up.
Like when you know women think we're
fuck boys were pieces of shit is dudes.
It's like you don't get it. I think I
like you. Everything I'm saying to you,
I believe. Right. And my Dick is just
like, yeah, we're going to planned out.
You know what I mean? We, let's see.
And there are times where you
not and it's like, damn, yeah,
you realize you've made a mistake.
Especially if the woman is really into
you and you're really not into her.
And you're like, oh, I made an error. And
then you do feel like an asshole. Yeah.
But if you say that to them, they're
like, yeah, fucking asshole. I'm like,
I'm just being honest with you. Analogy.
I got tricked by genetics. Yeah.
Why can't that be my biology?
Why can't I feel so for women,
let me explain what this is
like. Yeah, you have this,
it's like finding out your guy was poor.
This is what it's like.
This is how I describe it.
Having an erection and getting excited.
It's like sitting in the backseat
of a really long bus. Okay.
And there's some other guy
up there driving the bus.
Most of the time you're driving the bus
now when your Dick is hard, when you,
dick is hard.
There's some other guy driving the bus
and all the windows are rolled down.
There's papers flying around the horns
honking time and you're looking at life
taking place through a dirty windshield
a hundred feet away from you.
And you're like, do you even
know where the fuck you're going?
We passed the stuff and your Dick's like,
just shut the fuck up and calm down.
I got this.
And then when you come,
all of a sudden the fog parts and you're
at the front of the bus holding the
wheel and you're like, what? What am
I doing here? How did I get here? Ah,
and you look down at your
Dick, you motherfucker, bro.
It's been a werewolf. Yeah,
it is being aware of water, right? Isn't
that what it's a metaphor for? Oh yeah.
This ravenous creature,
you're running around doing crazy shit
and then you wake up in the morning naked.
You're terrified. Covered
in blood. Yeah. Well, fuck.
Sometimes. Sometimes. God dammit.
What did I do.