The Joe Rogan experience coastal
bears. That's the big ones. You know,
brown bears and grizzly
bears are the same thing,
but brown bears are way bigger and the
reason why they're way biggers cause they
live on the coast.
So just eating fish and dead whales
launched and anything else they can get
there. Fuck. Gorging on fucking
fatty, fatty, heavy foods.
There's an awful video and awful Jamie,
I'll find it of a grizzly that's
pulling black bear cubs out of a den and
killing them and eating them.
And the mother is trying to stop them.
He's trying to stop the grizzly from
eating her babies and he just swats her
away. Like she ain't shit. I gotta
say it's awful, dude. You shouldn't,
shouldn't play it. It definitely can't
play it and you shouldn't even watch it.
I'm gonna Watch the screens
that they make and it takes,
it's a long ass video and she's trying to
fight him off, but he's like, fuck you,
I'm eating your babies.
That's one thing that bothers me the
most about the anthropomorphization that
people do with animals is
that their stance on bears is,
I don't want people to hate bears,
but I want people to know what a bear
really is versus what they think it is.
I think they're sweet.
They eat honey and they're sweet and
they're nice and they don't really fuck
shit up. They, they're amazing.
I'm a big fan of bears,
but they all cannibals. They're
all Canam. Bears make me feel like,
of course there were dinosaurs. Bears
are like, that's just a fucking dinosaur.
Well, it's a a beast as what it is.
It's a beast in the purest sense.
Any beast make reminds me that we
definitely had had to have dinosaurs,
that that was just a small dinosaur.
Now nothing like a dinosaur is far, far,
far for Fart creepier.
They don't have any hair.
I don't trust anything with no hair.
You don't have any fucking hair?
I have a little,
I got on my face ugly,
but I don't trust anything that like
his hair, lips, any hair on its body.
What other animals or what do you mean
like fish or hairless like a snake.
Everything in the waters hairless.
Yeah. I'll trust those Fox. None of it.
None of it. That bottlenose
dolphin, Nebraska.
Pinterest found you don't trust that
Dolphin. That's a weapon from Russia.
That's awesome.
They want to put a bomb on that thing.
I've had a Russian strap on. It's back.
That's the whole Dan spoke Russian.
It had a Russian strap on its back.
Stope like the whale that
they're talking about.
They think the Russians had trained it
to get close to boats to that it could
hit the boat and blow it up.
Stope you don't care. I care.
Some things are cool.
I'm not rendering of t rex hair.
I didn't see that live here,
but I thought they think it has feathers.
I don't have to think those are fed.
Look at that. It has red hair by the way.
At the front of its face.
Well, that's the other thing.
They think that it might've been
because they think they might've been
scavengers. T rex was a ginger with
freckles. Where did you find this?
Jamie's holes. You fucking Dick Gould.
That no ginger's that are assholes.
How about a done story? They're all over
the place. Judges that are assholes,
you can't not find,
look at this.
Like you might have had facial
features like a vulture.
They think it might have been red in the
face cause they really don't have any
idea what I mean when you see these
colored drawings, they just take chances.
They just, they're all made up.
The um, university of Bozeman,
not the University of Bozeman,
the natural history museum in Bozeman,
Montana has a raptor that on one
side of it they had feathers on it.
Try to give you like an
alternate perspective of
what it might've looked like.
So they had this raptor and in one
side of it it looked just like an,
like an evil bird.
It's really cool cause they,
they know now that's what it looked like.
They know now that a lot of
dinosaurs had had feathers.
They've actually got fossils
of dinosaurs with feathers.
So they know that the idea
that all dinosaurs were
these reptile looking things
is incorrect. Some of them literally were
birds. So the birds that you see today,
whether it's a peacock or
chicken or something like that,
they're fucking dinosaurs.
Yeah. That's what that is.
It's a dinosaur that survive are the
ones that are bigger than a chicken.
Didn't really make it, but the ones,
you know, why did the small ones maker,
they will hide that when the impact of
the crater a hit the world that it was so
devastating. They killed
almost everything. Yeah.
Phil and whatever was left,
whatever, scrounging, scavenging
little creature that was left,
evolved and became us.
We used to be a mole.
We used to be like a shrew
65 million years ago. That's
what these people, these,
these nonbelievers,
this is what they think.
You think it's ridiculous that
you think you came from a monkey,
you to know what they did
from Joe. I know. You know,
this is how crazy these liberals are.
You know that it's crazy to think you
came from monkey believes motherfuckers
take it to another level.
They, they're so crazy.
They think you came from a shrew
[inaudible] you were a lack,
a little mole cannot character.
Yup. Yup. Yup, Yup, Yup.
And then that became a monkey and then
add the monkey becomes you all that shit
inside of 65 million years.
Get the fuck out of fucking wild.
Crocodiles are a hundred million
years old. So crocodiles are the same.
The somehow or another we went from being
a fucking true to being a person who
knows and loves Jesus and more art shit.
That's it right there.
That's where that thing.