He was like way deep in the TAC.
Oh yeah.
Nice uppercut by canal.
He was definitely like a big check tax
trouble before we got bailed out with a
fight in the past. Do you
think they reimagine? I think
the rematch they should.
Why not?
I think Connor would have to beat somebody
good in a boxing match and he would
also have to have a real training camp,
I think.
I think boxing's over for
Connor. Oh, I don't think so.
That is one more fight like that cause
people will buy it kind of went to the
10th round. He got fatigued it there's
still a motive for people to buy it. Yeah.
I mean look,
he,
he went the very first fight against the
greatest hour and so many of you didn't
like to bag. You're right. Yeah, you're
right. You're right. There's that too.
But the thing is if
there's a legit big fight,
like say if Canelo Alvarez steps up
and says that he wants to fight Conor
Mcgregor, Conor, I'll do it.
He might be a smart,
I think Connor made me realize
you've got to specialize,
but actually you can't do both.
Especially the difference
between Canelo and Floyd.
Floyd was just a brilliant boxer.
Canelo is a murderous puncher and
he'll fuck you up. He'll hurt.
There's also a promotional difference
to Kyron. Flood are pretty much,
they're very similar guys,
and they both understood what
they were doing promotion wise.
I don't know if Canelo is that guy.
Well, he's not gonna promote it that way,
but he's got, oh, look that up
or cut. That's his genius. It's,
he's got the support of the American
people love again versus Mcgregor.
Okay.
Ooh, look at that upper cut. I don't
know if Mcgregor would take that fight.
No,
that sounded good.
Fight for him either neither Canelo
or Lufkin's a good fight for him.
It's a terrible fight for him. Those guys
are different. They're, they're, they're,
they're this, you know, like,
look at the way these guys fight.
[inaudible].