Maybe help other people being more
okay with yourself? Like what,
what bothers you about yourself? Uh, I
just wish I just felt more comfortable.
Moen scan a lot of times, you
know, cause I feel like, um,
I would be able to be more effective
as a person if I could just,
they kind of get, oh, not
toil in some of my own,
you know, the small self worth issues
or like lack of confidence at times.
You know, I wish I could trust
my instincts and I'm wasting,
my instincts were like better
calibrated so that I knew when I was,
what if I was doing like, okay in good
stuff. Then my insides like told me,
you're, you're being okay. You
don't have to worry. You know,
there's a lot of things going
on there, right? One of them,
the big one is almost always
from your childhood. All,
most feelings of lack of worth and self
worth come from that feeling as you're
developing as you growing up.
Yeah.
You feel like you're not loved or
you're not appreciated or you're,
you criticize too much. You feel like
you're a loser and really be concise,
psychologically can be very hard to shake.
And even as people get older,
sometimes they still, they still
claim to this thought that they're,
they're a piece of shit because there are
a piece of shit in someone's eyes when
they were eight and there were 10.
That's a real problem with people, man.
And that's one of the reasons why when
someone gets bullied when they're young,
it can be so devastating because it's
happening when you're in high school or
junior high school and it becomes
a defining moment for you. Yeah.
Yeah. It's to do that. I was scared. This
one kid really also bad. This one kid,
one of the reasons why I got
into wrestling this kid, uh,
like we had this confrontation in a locker
room and I didn't think were going to
fight. Like I was just totally bluffing.
I Dunno what, what I said or what he said.
I don't remember. But I do remember
him getting me in a headlock,
throwing me on the ground and then
leaning like he was gonna Punch me in the
face. But deciding not to and I
didn't know what to do. I had no,
no martial arts skills,
no nothing. I haven't,
I'd never wrestled anybody before.
I didn't know anything.
So there's nothing in you
that like any reaction?
I panicked and no idea what to do
and I think and I've thought shit,
I didn't think he was going to do that.
And now here I am on my back.
I'm traveling, God dammit, I
got to learn how to wrestle.
I got to learn some
martial arts or something.
So then I started taking karate and then
I started taking wrestling like right
after that. But I, I avoided
that kid every time I saw him.
I see him on the other side of school.
It looks even through the breezeway and
I've always knew where he was round.
I got to go around,
I want to see that guy that threw me on
the ground and could have punched me in
the face. It was almost like
more humiliating that he did,
could have punched me in
the face but he didn't.
But that bullying and that guy doing that.
To me,
that fear of like being um,
just helpless made me get into
martial arts. I was like, fuck this.
Like I got to figure out how to fight.
I don't want this to happen to me anymore.
Do you see as the benefit?
It was a lucky situation to like,
he didn't beat me up. It could've been
way worse. It was not that big a deal.
It was an easy school to go to.
Like my school wasn't hard,
even though there was some
criminals that were in that school,
like some kids get shipped into,
there was some bad kids and one
of them got charged with murder.
Like right after graduating. We
were like, whoa. Our friend Kevin,
we knew this dude and he killed
somebody and we're like, whoa. Oh yeah.
Everybody was like, whoa.
That guy killed somebody.
I think he was one year older than me.
Yeah.
He murdered somebody like right
after high school. Yeah. This kid,
we knew he was on the football
team. We like knew him. And then,
do you ever think he would murder
somebody? He was a tough guy.
He's a scary guy for sure. Like a
powerhouse of a person, like a tank.
Um, I didn't know him well though,
but I, you know, I'd say hi to him.
But it's one of those things where when
something like that happens to you and
for me, again, it was very minor,
just I was just scared of this guy and
he didn't do anything to me. Horrible.
Just threw me on the ground. So when don't
want you to beat your brains, I mean,
if somebody could hold you down like that,
I could do,
could a beat my face and I wouldn't have
been able to do shit. Are you grateful?
In a weird way that he didn't, they're
not grateful looking back for sure,
but it was enough. He just let me know. I
was, you know, I don't know what I said.
I made a,
said something stupid.
He might've said something stupid and
wanted me to back down and I didn't.
So he just grabbed me and threw me
on the ground. But the fact that he,
that he did it and could do it led me to
make one of the biggest decisions of my
whole life is getting
involved in martial arts.
It's didn't want that feeling anymore.
Like if someone gives me a hard time,
I want to be the one who can
decide whether or not this
gets violent or who gets
hurt. I don't want to leave
that into some stranger's hands.
It might be a fucking psychopath. If
it's in my hands, no one's getting hurt.
We're going to be fine. Like there's
a video of Matt Serra from yesterday.
Matt Serra,
uh,
there was a drunk and altercation with
some fucking dude in a food court.
Matt Serra,
who is a Brazilian jujitsu black belt,
like at one point in time when he was
competing, he was one of the best,
presented it to artists in the world.
Then on top of that,
fun MMA knocked out George Saint Pierre
won the welterweight title and he's got
some dude on the ground and
he's just saying, calm down.
Calm down to guys, look, I'm gonna
fuck you up. I'm going to fuck.
But it's hilarious to watch like,
look at this look good, play good,
and play the volume.
He's like, I'm going to break your
fucking face. He's holding his wrist.
I love how he has a shirt on the guy's
face. He's like, calm down, calm down.
It's like he's putting a crying baby to
sleep and so the security guard comes
over and says, let him go. He goes,
okay, you're going to control them.
You got to control them reasonably.
You're going to control you.
Are you ready to control him like he's
not? He's standing up and he's fat
and let me tell you something mad.
Sarah's one of the nicest
fucking guys on the planet earth.
If he has to do this to you
in a restaurant and he's
a restaurant and he's got
full mount on you, you fucked
up. You fucked up dude, but see,
you're way better off with
Matt Serra in that position.
Then that drunk dude on some guy
who doesn't know how to fight.
It could be that too.
That drunk dude could just be a real
mean violent person who wants a beat
someone up if he gets him down.
So if there's guys like you know
who aren't into that kind of,
so you've found getting into martial arts
are really kind of led you in like a a
way where you felt more calm,
confident in case things got into a
uncomfortable situation that you would be
okay. Yeah. Well look, you're always,
you're always going to be nervous
in life when something's important,
whether it's going on stage or
something difficult life. Do you know?
Difficult things make you nervous.
It's like there is an anticipation.
There's an understanding of the difficulty
of something you're about to pursue
and whether or not you're going to fall
short or whether or not you're going to
succeed.
That shit makes people nervous.
But the physical confrontation
nervousness is a bad one. That's a,
that's a like that is a paralyzing fear.
Fear of being bullied or feel are being
hurt and you can't do anything about it.
That devastates people, that puts
them in a deep, deep depression.
So it's really important to learn.
I think,
I think every young man
should learn how to fight.
I think there would be way
less fights because of it.
And I don't think you have to be a
mean person to learn martial arts.
I think it's a skill and I think you
learn it and then once you start getting
good at it, it started actually
starts to actually becoming fun.
And the people who practice it with you,
you become close with you don't,
you don't hate the people that
you're practicing fighting with.
They become some of your closest friends.
Yeah. And I think it's a, just a big,
it's a giant confidence boost to know
that you can do something difficult and
get better at it. That's,
I think, just that alone,
it has massive benefits for people.
Yeah. You know, I can sense that.
And I remember watching a video
a couple of years ago actually,
if you like getting a belt or something,
they gave you a,
as some Dojo or I'm not sure what the
correct terminology as it might've been a
BGA probably watching when I got my
black belt. Yeah. Maybe that was it.
But anyway, it, yeah, like all the guys,
there was a lot of guys around it just,
and I know that cocoa does it. Joey does
it. Oh, he loves it and you love it.
Why don't you do it?
You're a strapping man.
You talked to Eddie Bravo about going to
do it one day. So he said, uh, he said,
yeah, he said, come down one day and
he'll, you know, get me into like,
one of the beginners classes I think
I need to do it would fuck yeah.
Giving made me feel a little bit
more, um, you know, like you said,
some of them are just,
uh, I don't know. Some,
and especially like if people get
bullied and then they don't have like a
brother or they don't have a friend or
they don't even have somebody to go like
talk to, to be like, aw, man.
And then their blooded, he'd
be like, oh, that's okay.
You know, like, that's, that's,
that can make, you know,
then that person gets stuck inside
themselves just feeling like, you know,
like they're not going to
be okay. You know, Tara.