My attention span I think
has been shortened. Yeah.
I'll sit down to watch a movie at home.
I'm mean in 10 minutes I'm reaching for
my phone. Yes. I'm not a heart surgeon.
There's no emergency that
need, you know? Right, right.
It might be just be checking Twitter
again or concern, you know? Um,
so it's a perfect storm. Yeah. Of
distractions and we now know is,
is addictive. So yeah. How
you turn that around. I,
I mean it feels like there's a little bit
of a movement of people to switch that
stuff off and just read a book
or go for a walk or, but yeah.
You got to have real
discipline. No, I mean,
you're fighting against our fucking
heroin addiction, man. Yeah. It's crazy.
And everyone else is addicted to oh yeah.
So you're not part of the
conversation if you're not.
I walked into a restaurant the other
night and everyone was looking at their
phone. No one was looking at each
other. I'm like, I'm in a movie. Yeah.
This is a movie. So I'm posted
public some. Yeah. I mean if,
if instead of looking at their phones,
if everyone was just looking at the sky,
you'd be like, oh my God,
there's a real problem. These
people are sick. Yeah. Yeah.
Something wrong. You know, if everybody's
just sitting there with our hands open,
like staring up at the sky and sitting
next to each other, you'd be like,
these people are sick. There's something
wrong. They need help. Instead they're,
they're looking at nothing. Yeah. They're
checking their feed over and over again.
Someone's complaining about Captain
Marvel being a woman. Hey. Yeah.
And all the experts. Are they the
ones getting followed on there? Oh,
I don't know who in experts, experts in
whatever, you know, the ones who already,
or are we looking at them?
You know, it should be this,
this free flow of information where
you can find out anything in your hand.
What an incredible thing. Yeah. But it's
not that. It's definitely not that well.
I think there's two things.
I think, one we didn't earn,
it is just given to us.
Right?
It's not like we did all the work to
curate all this technology and put it
together and figuring out how
to implement it in our deal. No,
we just went to the fucking Verizon
store and picked up a new phone. I mean,
that's, that's what most people are
doing. Yeah. And because of that,
it's almost like being, um, like a
trust fund kid or something like that.
It's just all given to you. It's
all handed to you all this, I felt,
I feel the same way
sometimes about weapons.
I feel like the discipline required to
learn how to use one and create it and
build it,
and then understand the responsibility
of actually using it on a human being.
All that shit's out the window. You just
go to the store and buy it. You know?
There's no requirements of you other
than you never killed anybody yet.
Have you written, driven over anybody in
your car? No. If you're robbed a bank, no.
Okay. Yeah. You beating your wife?
No. Okay. Here, here's a guy. Yeah.
It's fucking strange.
And this as,
as a human being,
the,
the lack of discipline
and accountability that,
that we have in this ultimate access to
all these things constantly and many of
them become just massive distractions.
And yeah,
this in some ways is,
is the utopia that people have dreamed
of during the for generation. Sure,
we're free of war. You're not going
to get attacked in your house tonight.
You're not going to starve and you have
everything you could possibly need.
So you'd think we'd become the perfect
human beings in the absence of all those
things that would have
killed us in the past.
I would have made life hard in
the past. Yeah. And again, that's,
that's not what we're doing.
Well,
I don't think we operate very
well without legitimate conflict,
without legitimate conflict in terms
of like actual things you need to worry
about. Like I, when I used
to live in the east coast,
one of the things that was really
noticeable was that when it snowed out,
people were nicer. They help people and
they're broken down the side of the road.
They were nice to each other.
There was a sense of vulnerability that
we are all deeply entrenched in this
winter nature thing and we've got to work
together, otherwise we can't survive.
Yeah.
You know,
and I think that applies to all aspects
of life that when there's no real
danger, people become
extremely frivolous. Yeah.
It's amazing how quickly we
become lazy and complacent. Um,
and actually the flip side of the
negative stuff I was saying earlier,
some good days I'll come back
from Yemen, Syria, wherever.
I'll go out and I got a cup of coffee,
coffee and I'll read the newspaper
and I'll donate and I'll think, man,
I'm the luckiest man alive. Yeah.
The flip side, I can do this.
Cause you do experience these horrific
environments so you can appreciate it.
Yeah. And the fact that we can, you know
what I mean? Within a few hours here,
we could have one of the best meals.
Yeah. Possibly in the world we could,
you know, it's, you know, it's,
that's fitting incredible.
So on good days that you can, you
can, you can appreciate that. Again,
this is you coming from these bad things.
So it puts it in perspective. So yeah,
I was just trying to try to back you up
and say, yeah, like if you, if you're not,
if you're not protected from all of that
stuff then you can get to appreciate
the basics. Again, I was on
this trip and Prince of Wales,
we camped out on this island.
It rained every day for six days,
seven days. I mean we were
soaked, you're soaked,
everything soaked your sleeping bag.
So tent soaked,
everything came back
home and it felt so good.
Like I'd never felt the
sun like that before.
Like the sun was just this like this
magic love glow that the sky was pouring
down on the city. Everything felt
so happy and I realized like,
well you can't really appreciate this
until it's taken away from you. Yeah,
it's taken away from you.
Then you understand what
it is. So then you want to,
when the kids of today grow up,
what are they going to be
like when everything has
just been at their fingertips
from day one forever. Forever. No mystery.
They don't understand
bullshitters either because like,
like when I was a kid, people just a lie
about shit and you really didn't know.
You're like, man, I don't know.
He seems like he's full of Shit.
You couldn't just yet have to go
to an encyclopedia and you know,
and actually read the information. Now you
can go, okay, what year did this happen?
And you pull up your phone kit
though. Fuck Outta here. You know,
people lie about being in the Olympics,
they lied about this,
they lied about that.
They'll, yeah, it's um,
it's good in that we have ultimate access
to information for people that use it
and understand what it is and appreciate
it. It is good. But to your point,
if there was a way to actually filter
and say this is verifiable, this, yeah,
this contains seven things,
which are absolutely bullshit.
We have no doubt about that whatsoever. If
that could exist. Wonderful. But I mean,
Fox, I've tried it. A few
people have tried it, used to,
it still feels like you end up
being described as, you know,
being on one side of the fight.
I almost feel like we need some
sort of organized discipline,
like maybe like a
mandatory volunteer work,
cleaning up impoverished communities
are mandatory volunteer work doing their
like, but I don't want people
to have to do things like, um,
I'm conflicted on that too, but I don't
want people to have to do that. You know,
like when there's countries that
have mandatory military service,
they seem to have an amazing feeling of,
of patriotism in those countries and
appreciation in those countries because
they actually do have to join the
military for two years or whatever it is.
We don't have that over here.