Like Edson Barboza but then you know,
it's an instrument.
Edson Barboza you saw once he
realized he was going to survive,
like when it was like two
minutes left in third round,
maybe ish site the first round. He's
like, I'm getting, I'm getting fucked up.
Just gonna I'm just going to survive.
Right.
But then when there was called
minutes lots, he's like,
no. And he was like, okay,
I'm gonna fight again.
I want to make it through this shit.
I might as well if I were
to make it through this,
I might as well just fight back.
Right.
And so he started fighting back really
hard like the last two minutes. F tried.
He certainly tried,
but there was a period in the middle
where he like had resigned to just taking
an asshole. Well, I think he was
just, body was just not responding.
He was getting so fucked up and you
could see the pace that Habib put on them
hard first round,
like halfway into the Round
Barboza is like Jesus Christ.
You see the look in his eyes, get that
thousand yard stare. It's like, Whoa,
what I signed up for.
This guy's on another level.
I mean he really is on another level.
I'm fascinated by him
fighting Tony Ferguson and
apparently they're going to do
that now.
It's sitting happened April.
I don't know if it's going to be for
the interim title or the actual title
within. They're going to strip Connor.
They're in a weird way. Beats Up Tony.
That's just my [inaudible] and I've
underestimated Tony before so I could be
wrong again. I just think, I
think it's the, again, Trump card,
I think Tony is kind of one of those
guys where he's pretty good everywhere is
pretty damn solid wrestling,
high level Jujitsu. Uh,
but I see Khabib dressing me and
better than Tony's wrestling.
So it's going to end up on the ground.
And I think Tony's going to think he can
submit him because his Jujitsu is very
high level.
But I think it'd be one of things where
it could be just good enough not to get
submitted. And then he's going to land
damage and land damage, inland damage,
inland damage.
And Tony's going to get close to a
submission and close to a submission,
close to a submission
but not quite get it.
And then all this damage is going to
just accumulate and accumulate and
accumulate at. That's kind of how
I see it going. It's fascinating.
And I also think it's
fascinating now that could be,
but has changed his training
and has a real nutritionist,
had no problem making weight.
Yeah.
So all the factors that played into him
getting removed from the last time they
were supposed to fight, pulled out
of the car, those kind of overblown.
He only missed weight one time.
He only missed w wait one time.
But his body shut down when he's making
way for the Michael Johnson fight in a
similar way. But he still did
the Michael Johnson fight. Yeah,
but it was the same thing happened
during the way and it was a rough way in.
But there's been other guys
who missed weight many times.
I mean if we go to a Johnny Hendricks,
Johny Hendricks, Melvin Gallard,
Calvin gasoline, and they missed
it by a long with, so yeah,
I thought the QBE thing kinda overplayed.
He must wait one time.
He had some injuries which
sucked for him. Um, but it was,
that was happening for a
world title fight, you know,
they were fighting for the interim title
him. He misses, wait. Yeah. I mean,
and so it was one of those
where he probably just like,
it was like okay for him to make it,
but be difficult and they just got
just a little bit too big. Actually.
Was it for interim title
when he was supposed to,
I don't think it was the original
time. It was Kevin Lee, right?
That was for the world, Tom. Yeah. Yeah.
Or interim title job that, Oh yeah.
The whole, that whole division
is kind of fucked up with Conner.
Not even knowing whether or not he's
fighting it. They're going to strip him,
right? Yeah, mostly I think
so. I would imagine, unless
Connor says, fuck it, I'm in,
I think the best comeback.
Fuck it. Fuck it. Fuck it.
I want to keep me belt. I know the best
course of action strip Connor let, let,
could be even Tony fight it out.
And then if Connor wants to go back,
give him a title shot that's going to
happen. Whatever. Well, I think the,
what would be the most lucrative
thing as Connor versus GSA?
Shut up Joe on a fight. GSP. Oh, you do
the one that I want to be number one.
I don't want to fight Tyron cause we've
been your friends for 20 years. Uh,
I wanna fight GSP that
that's who I want to fight.
Do you think that they would set that up?
They would know.
They would try to set up GSP versus Tyron.
Right.
That would be the big super fund.
GSP doesn't want to fight anyone who can
hit hard because he's worried about the
brain damage. So yeah,
I don't hit that hard.
Yeah.