I think,
I think the first time we spoke as I
had written that thing about Louis and
after Louise and the whole news,
but Louie [inaudible] you
had all that love that piece.
But there was so honest.
Yeah, it was on Facebook.
What's where I did a lot of my best
way to explain what you were saying to
people that didn't read it after
Louis. A lot of people, uh,
were rightly criticized and conduct
and you know, the whole me too thing.
That's all valid and true.
100% needs to happen.
But then there were people that were like,
you know,
Louie was never funny or
literally was just, you know,
of course he got all these things. He was
a white guy or, and I'm like, wait, what?
And they were like, well, he
said this word I don't like,
we'll look at this joke.
And I'm like, guys, a week
ago he was a comic genius.
We all agreed on that. That was a
widely held belief. Now out of nowhere,
he's not that funny.
And,
and these people are tweeting this from
parking lots where they're performing
some of the shows in la, or I'd
like someone's driveway, you know,
and which is fine. I do them.
I have no problem with that.
But they're getting on Twitter
and knocking Louis from
the back of a parking lot
where they're doing a show. But what
you, the reason you gave for why? Well,
because these, there's, in any industry,
people are going to get
ahead by being agreeable,
by having the right opinions,
by crowd sourcing their opinions,
by taking the temperature of the room
and going, how does everyone feel?
And those people are,
you know,
they're careerists are very
good at office politics.
They're very good at
having the right friends,
but their contributions
are never really important.
Our long lasting because they never get
great because they don't take any risk.
Because I think greatness is something
you have to risk constantly to get to
that level. So a lot of these people
do very well. They make money, they're,
they're successful,
but they are careerist and
they're looking for comfort.
And so when it was comfortable and safe
to attack Louie and to bring Louie down
and to elevate themselves,
they did it.
But they didn't do it when it could
have hurt their career a week earlier,
you know?
So to me it was very disingenuous and
the fact that more people weren't calling
it out,
and I,
and I made that point where I said the
same thing on the other side of people
who styled themselves like
I'm a free speech warrior,
I'm this anti PC in their
whole entire persona is,
is that the need to say the n word?
They're like,
I can't do a joke if the punchline isn't
fact. Like they're like, we have to. Yeah.
So those to me are kind of
the same people and they're,
they're the people that are just trying
to arrange the world in a way that
allows them to succeed.
Those are the types of people also,
like you were talking
about the actor in the,
you mean they're putting on a facade?
Yeah.
That's not who they've adopted a
predetermined pattern of behavior.
100% that predetermined
pattern of behavior might be,
I'm a guy I drink every night.
We go hard. I'm an artist,
I smoked cigarettes, I don't give a
fuck. I'm not trying to get on TV.
Yes. So to me it was like
incredibly disingenuous.
You had all these people and a lot of
them are angry and they're doing fine.
Yeah. Like some of them are telling
like some of these people are,
have their own shows and they're getting
angry at Louie and getting angry.
And I'm like, there's a, there's a real,
because here's the thing are you should
fear told me something made a lot of
sense once he goes,
it's,
it can really be a waste to get into
this type of business and ended up in an
office writing for show you
don't care about in a job.
You hate punching a clock.
And that stuck with me and always like,
it might be harder to go the other way
and to build a fan base and to do what
you want,
but it's gonna be,
it's gonna be better in the end
and you're not going to be angry.
You're not going to be resentful.
And I think a lot of the people that
were were against shitting on his comedy,
not so much his behavior,
but it's comedy are people that are,
would want more in this than they have.
And they're resentful at
guys like Louie because it,
it's not fair how talented he is.
Well, it's not just how talented he is,
his work ethic, every factors,
the risks that he does take.
I mean, he, he says controversial things.
He always has. Whether you agree or not.
Like one of the things about
the Parkland thing, you know,
when he got in trouble
about, uh, you know,
say that all you did was put some
fat kid out of the way. Yeah.
That is so consistent with his material.
The idea that anybody's saying
like, oh my God, he's punching down.
Like you need to go review his material.
Right.
Because he said a lot of
risky shit because it was
funny and he had really good
points about it. Yeah. No. Is
that something that I would
joke about? Probably not,
but he did. You wouldn't talk
about fat people? Uh, yes I would,
but I don't think I would joke about
kids getting shot. It's a tough take.
Yeah. Funny. But that's what
I, yeah, but I think he could.
I think honestly we were,
you're dealing with first
of all the embryo of a bit.
I mean he's really only been doing
standup again for a couple of months.
If back then it was even less and I think
ultimately his idea that bet is that
bit rather is that kids today like they
want to be a VA and have them and they
have 78 different genders and why am I,
why are you interested?
You're interesting because
you didn't get shot. Right.
That is his take on it and he probably
with overall reaction and anticipation of
reaction probably would have
eliminated that part of the bit. Sure.
And you know what I'm saying,
like you know how it works and destruct.
I think part of it is too,
I was attracted to comedy because
of guys like Bill Hicks or Patricia,
that people that can think the
things that those guys said.
You could only say on a stage
if you were really funny. Right.
That's what I love about comedy.
Me Too.
That doesn't mean that
everyone has to love that.
There's people that love it for a
million different reasons. Sure.