Because the people that
get involved in it,
part of the reason why they get involved
in it's virtue signaling. Totally.
And I've been asked like,
you know,
as I've been prudent promoting
the book by a lot of people,
like what have you done in your life to
change? You know, and it's like, well,
I'm flying a little bit less defying,
really makes me feel guilty.
But otherwise I basically haven't
changed anything because I do think that
politics and policy are the most
important impact you can have.
And I'm like spreading the word,
whether I eat like a couple
of fewer hamburgers a year,
it just doesn't really matter that much.
But the idea that you would ask a newcomer
to the movement to demonstrate their
commitment by making themselves the most
optimally committed that they possibly
could be, that's just going
to alienate so many people.
And this is obviously an issue where we
need more people engage in a more direct,
profound way. So I think for me, it's like
anyone who wants to care about climate,
who wants to vote about climate, like
come on, like, yeah. Um, and I think that,
you know, Hollywood can be really
important here. Um, I mean,
since I've been out here,
I've been,
I have a couple of meetings about shows
and stuff and I do think that we've had
really corny storytelling
about climate change. Um,
and that there are actually opportunities
for like really incredible new kinds
of storytelling.
I mean,
in the book I write about this story that
happened a couple of years ago where,
mmm.
You know,
anthrax that was,
had killed a reindeer in Russia
in the early 20th century.
The reindeer was frozen and permafrost
for the entire 20th century,
permafrost melting,
the reindeer thawed,
the anthrax was released and killed
at least one boy and a number of other
reindeer in Russia. Wow. And that is true.
So in the ice in the Arctic ice are,
you know,
we know of rock is like a
record of geological history.
Ice is also record of geological history.
So they're like the bubonic
plague is trapped in ice.
The Spanish flu in from 18,
1918 that killed hundreds of
millions of people is trapped in ice.
There are diseases trapped in the Arctic
ice from before humans were around,
which means that humans immune
system have no experience with them.
There's so many horror movies you can
make them at this subject. Um, Holy Shit,
I didn't even think of that. I didn't
know that the Spanish flu is trapped in.
Nice. Yeah. I mean,
and there have been instances where
like in lab conditions anyway,
they've revived bacteria that
are millions of years old.
Um,
one Russian doctor literally injected a
bacteria that he had revived from like
35,000 years ago.
It had been frozen for 35,000 years.
He brought it back to life and injected
it into himself. Why would he do that?
Just to see what would,
that's a fucking marvel comic book.
That's how you become like the,
the red skull or some shit. Yeah.
Well that's what I mean about this.
This story is so big.
It's like the world that we live in
in the next couple of decades will be
completely transformed.
Like we will be reading about
diseases coming out of the Arctic ice.
We will be reading about tropical diseases
arriving in Copenhagen because now
are there because the temperature allows
them to live there and the way that
they never lived before.
We will be reading about climate conflict
will be reading about, you know, um,
I mean all this shit, it's, it's,
it's everywhere. It, you know,
air pollution increases the rates
of autism and Adhd. It changes, um,
the development of babies in utero.
It's like, it's all encompassing. Wow.
The disease in the ice things
really freaking me out.
I never even considered that.
Yeah.
But that is something to think about
along with the methane and carbon is going
to be emitted into the
atmosphere as it melts. Well,
let me tell you the story. So,
um, there we now, so there was,
there this species of antelope
called a saiga antelope. They, um,
they're mostly in Siberia.
They're kind of dwarf antelopes and
they've been around for millions of years.
And, uh, all of a sudden in 2016 or 2015,
they literally all died. It's called
a mega death. The entire species died.
They're extinct. They're
now extinct. Jesus. Um,
and that happened because a bacteria that
had been living inside their guts was
changed by temperature conditions.
It was an unusually hot,
unusually humid summer. And this bacteria
that had been living inside them,
presumably for millions of years
comfortably as a kind of peaceful,
cooperator became a killer
and killed the entire species.
Now we have inside us
countless bacteria and viruses.
Scientists believe
millions in every human.
So our guts are full of bacteria
that do our digestion for us.
They monitor our moods.
They're there. You know,
there are some scientists who think it's
really misleading to even think of the
human as a unitary animal rather than a
kind of composite creatures with system.
Yeah.
And most of those bacteria and viruses
are not going to be dramatically
transformed by a degree
or two degrees of warming.
But there's so many of them.
The chances that one could,
it's hard to dismiss that and whether
that would mean we'd all immediately go
extinct,
probably not.
But what if that means suddenly
schizophrenia increases by 15% because
schizophrenia is related to,
um, a bacterial infection
called toxoplasma guts,
bacteria Toxoplasma Gondii. Um, well
that's that cat parasite. Yeah, exactly.
Schizophrenia is related to
that. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
I'd like triples your chances of
getting schizophrenia. Wow. Yeah. Um,
and our bodies are so complex,
such intricate ecosystems.
Like you say that if one
little thing gets disturbed,
it could have really
catastrophic impacts on us.
And that's true of the planet as a whole.
I think that's,
that's one of the big lessons of my book
is that this is such a delicate system.
It's been stable for all of human
history and now it's not stable.
What that means for how we live,
we don't know yet,
but the changes will be significant,
will be profound.
But it's also true of the individual.
You know,
our bodies will be living differently in
a world that's two degrees warmer than
they are today. We can't really
predict what those impacts will be,
but they could be quite traumatic and
they could be things that we can't even
imagine stay because they're,
you know, by some counts,
millions of bacteria inside us that
we haven't even identified yet.
Jesus Christ, you're freaking
me out, David. God dammit.
It's a crazy world out there.
Not just crazy, but it seems like
when, when you're talking
about things like this,
when you're talking about climate change
affecting our actual gut parasites or
our gut biome, and that this literally
could change the way human beings behave.
I mean, these are all things that I've
never heard discussed and it just,
it's really terrifying,
really is, you know, I mean,
and part of the problem is people hear
like, oh, relax, everything's fine.
This is this constant thing that we do
where if it's not effecting us currently,
right now in the moment,
there's not a fire in front of us.
We don't worry about it.
It's a weird compartment,
compartmentalization thing that
human beings do. Yeah. And, um,
it's, you know, you'd think that evolution
would have trained us differently.
You think that evolution would have
trained us over time to have at least some
longterm capacity. And I guess we do
have some long term planning capacity,
but it's, um, we choose to think
we're in really short term ways.