I'm going to jump right off into
a different train cart here.
Has Law enforcement ever asked you to
keep certain people on the platform even
after they violated your rules?
Uh,
not that I'm aware. So then
this, you know, to the,
to the next question pertaining to bias,
you have the issue of Antifa versus
the proud boys and Patriot prayer and a
Twitter permanently excised anyone
associated with the proud boys antifa
accounts who have broken
the rules repeatedly branded
known cells that have been
involved in violence all still active.
Okay.
Is there a reason? Well, with the proud
boys, what we were able to do was, um,
actually look at documentation
and announcements that, you know,
the leaders of that organization had made
and their use of violence in the real
world. So that was the war we were focused
on. And subsequent to our decision,
I believe the FBI also designated that's
not true. It's not true. That's not true.
No. Okay. No, that's not true.
Yeah. You know, the proud
boys started out as a joke.
Gavin McInnes, Anthony [inaudible],
who was a part of Opie,
and Anthony knows his own show,
tall told me about it.
It happened on his show because there
was a guy that was on the show and they
made a joke about starting a gang
based on him, cause he was a very,
a feminine guy. And they would call
him the proud boys. And I'm the,
they went into detail about how this
thing became from a joke and saying that
you could join the proud boys
and everyone was, you know,
it was like being silly to people joining
it and then it becoming this thing to
fight antifa and then becoming infested
with white nationalists and becoming
this thing well in, in, in
many ways it hell it was,
but it's been documented how it started
and what it was and misrepresented as to
why it was started.
I think there's some things that
should be clarified about them,
but Gavin has made a bunch of
statements that crossed the line.
He claims he claims to be joking. And so
that's, that's what he did on my podcast.
He was talking to me about Antifa,
the Antifa was blocking people like
Ben Shapiro's speeches and things along
those lines and stopping
conservatives for speaking,
you should just just
punched him in the face.
We're going to have to start kicking
people's asses. And I was like, oh,
this is the risk,
not just irresponsible but foolish and
short sighted and it's just a dumb way to
talk. So then you have the antifa groups
that are engaging in the same thing.
We've, we, you know, the famous bike lock
basher incident where a guy showed up,
hit seven, uh, he hit seven people
over that with a bike lock. Um,
they subsequently release his name.
I'm going to leave that out for
the time being. You have, uh,
other groups like by any means, by
any means necessary. You have in, um,
uh, Portland for instance, there
specific branded factions. There is a,
the tweet I mentioned earlier where
they doxed ice agents and they said,
do whatever inspires you with
this information. And I mean,
you're tagged in it a million times.
I know you probably can't see it,
but you can actually see that some of
the tweets and the threat are removed.
But the main tweet itself,
from an antifascist account linking
to a website straight up saying like,
here's the private home details,
phone number addresses of these law
enforcement officers is not removed since
September. So here's what
you end up seeing is, uh,
again to point think one of
the big problems I have in
this country is the media
because it was reported that
the FBI designated probably
was an extremist group,
but it was a misinterpretation based,
uh, a sheer wrote a draft saying with,
you know,
the FBI considers them to be extremists.
The media then reported hearsay from the
sheriff and the FBI came out and said,
no, no, no, we never meant
to do that. That's not true.
We are just concerned about violence. So
the proud boys all get purged. And again,
I think, you know, Gavin's
a different story, right?
If you want to go after the individuals
who are associated with that group
versus the guy who goes on the show and
says outrageous things and goes on Joe's
show.
But then you have antifa branded sells.
Like what I mean by that is
they have specific names.
They sell merchandise and they're the
ones showing up throwing mortar shells
into crowds.
They're the ones showing up with,
with crowbars and bats and
whacking people. I was in, uh,
Boston and there was a rally
where conservatives were
planning on putting on a
rally.
It was literally just like Libertarians
and conservatives antifa shows up with
crowbars bats in balaclavas
with weapons threatening them.
And so I have to wonder if,
if you know,
these people are allowed to
organize in your platform.
Are you concerned about that?
Why aren't they being banned when they
violate the rules? Yeah, absolutely.
We're concerned about that. Has the FBI
designated them? That's a domestic terror,
yes. Oh, I'm sorry.
Homeland Security in New Jersey has listed
them under domestic terrorism. Okay.
So, so here, here, I understand
there's a conundrum in that.
The general concept of Anti
Fascism is a loose term.
That means you oppose fascism,
but antifa is now they have a flag,
they've had a flag since the Soviet,
you know,
so a Nazi Germany in the Soviet era
and they've brought it back there.
Specific groups that I'm not going to
mention by name that have specific names
and they sell merchandise. They have
appeared in various news outlets.
They've expressed their desire to
use violence to suppress speech.
There was a centralized
organization the same way that I,
I hear you on proper ways but like where
they have like tenants that are written
out and there was a leader in like uh,
no it's not the same but there
are specific brand itself.
So that's why I bring them up.
Specifically I realized, you know,
someone showing up to a rally wearing
a black hoodie and sunglasses.
We who are you gonna ban?
But there are groups that
organize specifically call
for violence. They, they,
they pushed the line as close
as, as, as lightly as possible.
They advocate sabotage and
things like this. And you know,
when the proud boys go
out and get into fights,
they're not getting in fights with
themselves. They're, you know, so, uh,
I should point out that the,
they decided to call for violence based
on Antifa calling for violence based on
Antifa actually actively committing
violence against conservative people that
were there to see different people's,
it partly started because in
Berkeley there was a Trump rally.
So actually after my low got chased
out of the Berkeley, they were,
there was $100,000 in damages.
I mean,
there's a video of some
guy in all black cracking.
Someone on the back was on the ground
looking like they're unconscious.
So these conservatives see this and they
decided to hold a rally saying we won't
back down. They hold a rally in
Berkeley and then Antifa shows up again.
I understand. You can't figure out who
these people are. For the most part,
they're decentralized, but
then a, this insights, uh,
an escalation. You then get the rise of
the base to stick. Man, they called it,
this guy shows up in armor with a
stick and he starts swinging back.
And now you have two forming.
So while I recognize it's much easier
to ban a top down group, there are,
you know,
the difference I would get I guess is
why when you look at the proud boys,
it's straight,
top down vertical.
You look at Antifa and there's different
cells of varying size and their
different accounts. So
I have to, uh, to like,
I guess the argument I could make as if
you're going to bend the proud boys by
all means for under your justification.
But if you look at a specific channel
that's got 20,000 followers that cheers
them on, right? These are people
who throw mortar shells into crowds.
Isn't that advocating for,
you know, terrorism and
incitement to violence? Yeah,
absolutely. So I guess the question
is how come they don't get removed?
Well, in the past when we've
looked at, um, Antifa, we, it's,
we ran into this decentralization issue,
which is we weren't able to find the same
type of information that we were able
to find about proud boys,
which was a centralized leadership base
documentation of what they stand for.
Um,
but absolutely.
I mean it's something that we'll continue
to look into and to the extent that
they're using Twitter to organize any
sort of offline violence that's completely
prohibited under our rules and
we would absolutely take action.
Why Gavin was band did,
was there a specific thing that he did
or was it as an association with the
proud boys association with the problem,
you know,
he's a abandoned that he's not only that
he's disassociated himself with it and
said that he'd completely got out of hand.
He doesn't want to have
anything to do with it.
Yeah. And I think this is a great again
test case for how we think about getting
people back on the platform.
Yeah.
In the long term.
He's an interesting case because he's
a really a provocateur and he fancies
himself, you know, sort of a punk rocker
and he just, he likes stirring shit.
I mean [inaudible] when he came
on my show last time he was on,
he was dressed up like a Michael
Douglas and falling down, you know,
he did it on purpose. He brought a
briefcase and everything. I'm like,
what are you doing? He's like a Michael
Douglas, some falling down like he's,
he's a showman in many ways and he did
not mean for this to go the way it went.
He thought it would be this
sort of innocent fun thing
to be a part of and then
other people got involved in.
And then when people call for violence,
the problem is they think that that,
you know,
you're going to just hit people and
that's going to solve a problem.
It just creates a much more,
much more comprehensive problem.
I, I, it's important to point out,
Gavin said has had meant like he said
things way worse than than Alex Jones ever
did. Sure. Whether whether you want to say
it's a joke or not, he said things like,
you know, choke him, punch him
directly. Uh Huh. Yup. But he did.
But I guess was the primary reason for
getting rid of them was what you thought
that the FBI had designated
them an extremist group?
No, cause we did it many months in
advance. Oh, okay. Yeah, I was just
so he just, it was just his
association with the proud boys.
I don't recall. And I would have to go
back and I don't want to misstate things.
I don't recall whether those statements
that you're referring to you have
Gavin's we're on Twitter
so they weren't, um,
there's another, you know,
when it comes to the
weaponization of rules against,
like Gavin isn't creating a compilation
of things he's ever said out of context
and then sending them around
to get himself banned.
Other people are doing that to him,
activists who don't like him
and it's effective. In fact,
I would actually like to point out,
um,
there's one particular user
who has repeatedly made
fake videos attacking one of
your other high profile conservatives.
So much so that he had to file police
reports, harassment complaints,
and it just doesn't stop, you know? So
I guess I'll ask this to this regard.
If someone repeatedly makes
videos of you out of context,
fake audio accusing you of
doing things you've never done,
at what point does that bantible yeah.
Again,
if it's targeted harassment
and we can establish that,
it's just a really hard thing with a US
determining whether something is fake or
not. Well, it's also when
things are out of context,
you still have video of the person saying
that I agree that it's out of context,
that it's disingenuous,
but it's still the person saying it
and you're making a compilation of some
preexisting audio or video.
So I think in the instance of Gavin,
like one of the things he said
was like a call to violence,
but he was talking about,
uh,
like it was in the context of talking
about a dog and being scolded. Yeah.
So he was like, hit him, just
hit him. And then it's like,
it turns out he's talking about dog,
like we're doing something wrong.
And they take that and they snip it and
then it goes viral and everyone talks
flaggings and you got a band. This guy
still got, I understand. Like, you know.