I've never seen anything like,
um, maybe um, maybe a prime Roy.
Yeah. You know, maybe it was different
too because it was technically awful.
He just had such reflex when they went,
that's when he got melted because,
because he never, he didn't jab.
No, he didn't do anything. Right.
Brown took a lead, lead left hawk.
What rights from weird angles and it
worked cause his reflexes were superhuman.
He was superman and then as soon as
they deteriorated a little bit and in
fighting you can deteriorate a little bit.
In baseball you're going to tear.
Got Roy would really got Roy my opinion.
I'm a giant Roy Jones Jr fan.
He's my maybe one of my
all time favorite fighters.
What really got Roy is when we went up
to fight genre wheeze and then he went
back down Tarver he was depleted,
depleted.
And I think when he went up to fight Ruiz,
he might've had some Mexican supplements
in the system. Wink, wink, nudge, nudge.
Sure. Yeah. I mean he was like 200 and
plus pounds overweight or something.
Look good. I think he should have
retired after that one. Well,
he definitely should have consulted with
an endocrinologist to try to figure out
what,
how his system was.
And then the weight cut down to one 75
must have been brutal cause he was smooth.
He looked like shit. He
lost all his muscle tone. He
just didn't, he looked like,
and he was shredded in the 90s exactly.
Yeah.
He looked like a guy who's system had
been shut down with the thing that these
guys don't maybe don't recognize if they
take some shit or if they, you know,
even if you just cut too much weight,
your body stops producing hormones. Sure.
Your body is all fucked up. You're
on, you're on your way to die.
Your body is telling you what
the fuck are you doing now?
So if he was 200 plus
pounds when he fought Ruiz,
then he has to cut down to one 75 30.
Yeah.
And who knows how sophisticated
his methods were. I mean,
some fighters today are
amazing at doing that. I mean,
they know how to do it correctly.
They know how to rehydrate correctly.
And boxing at least has the,
um,
the benefit of not having Usada
in place like the UFC does.
The UFC has a real problem with a lack
of Ivs and these guys can't rehydrate
correctly or the way that they want
to. It is dangerous. It is dangerous.
But in their defense,
it's,
it's also a way that they can detect a
whether or not someone's cheating. Okay.
Cause when they're using ivs, you
can mask a lot of shit. Right? Yeah.
I didn't think about that. Yeah.
That's why they do it. Okay. Yeah.
They just won't let you do it.
So when,
I don't know what happened with Roy
when he did put it in. You're not,
can't take anything
away from Tarver either.
Cause Tarver almost beat Roy
the first time you fought,
but then fucked him up second
fucking fluids head. Yeah.
And the famous words, any excuses
died, Roy, right before they fight you.
Anything like that? He was so confident.
I don't think he gets his due either. No,
he doesn't. He doesn't. He, uh, he had
some great wins. He had some great wins.
Um, he's still at it too, right?
[inaudible] something like 46,
47 he got popped for steroids. Yeah. So,
well Duh.
If you're 45 and he's still looking good,
there's something going on. The only,
the only person I truly believe in,
I realize you'll, you'll think I'm
biased because of where I'm from,
but I don't think Bernard
ever did anything.
I don't think you did anything either.
Bernard just lives clean
and I've seen him, uh,
order grilled chicken and get chicken
that was fried by accident and peel the
fry off of it rather than just go,
oh, just this once. I'll do it. Right.
Watched him take it off to just, you
know what I mean? To not eat that.
It's just insane. Dietary
in the gym, you know,
I agree. But the Joe Smith fight was sad
to watch. Of course. That was, that was,
uh, the Kovalev fight was
sad. I was ringside man.
I love Kovalev but it's, you
know, affiliate legend like,
ah man, this is rough. You know,
it's crazy to see how deep into his
career he was still successful. Like,
I wrote a blog article about the
Kelly Pavlik fight cause I'm like,
I don't remember how
old he was at the time,
but everybody had
already written them off.
My brother and I were there like Publix
is going to beat the dog shit I've been
on.
And he gave him a fucking lesson lesson.
He put on a clinic where people have
to realize he was technically passed.
His fight is primary fucked up. Tito
Trinidad. It was 36 yeah, that's,
it was 36 and 2001 that was two weeks
after nine 11 that fight and he was 36
that how crazy is that? Yeah. What
was he when he fought Joe Smith?
50 50 maybe.
Maybe 51 definitely 50
crazy. So he was, he,
I say he lasted 15 years longer than,
than the average guy,
you know. Well how about when he came
back and boxed Roy Junior? Yeah. Well Roy,
when Roy beat him the first time it was
beaten him with all those reflexes and
then when the reflex is slid off,
clearly I'll with just
fundamentals. Yes, perfect.
Mccann's Roya didn't have them.
He didn't have them. Yeah,
just relying on what was once
there. Yeah, but it wasn't,
he was a shell of him for his,
of his former itself. Well,
it was also the Glen Johnson fight was a
scary knock out. He was on Queer Street.
Yeah.
Well he was just flatlined and astral
traveling after the got knocked out by
Tarver. Yeah. Then there was not that
much time in between those two fights. No,
it was just, it was the next
fight. Yeah. Yeah, and he and that,
those knockouts where you are,
you're out on your feet before you hit
the ground and your head hits the canvas,
which is two shots and he was stiffened
up. It was sad to watch. It was. It was.
That was really, I thought that
was going to be the end to me too.
And then he started fighting like
in Russia, sanctioned over there.
And he's a Russian citizen. Yes ma'am.
Bizarro world Russian pussy involved.
He's got to have some total
over there, man, to do that.
When you're talking about Larry Holmes.
I looked up his Wikipedia.
His last fight was in 2002
butter bean is 51 or so,
and he put it on butter bean
10 round fight. That's crazy.
And Corey Potter being can crack
that big motherfucker hit hard. Hard.
But Larry, just that snake, that snake and
I, you're not getting through that. Yeah.
Pop.
Every time he tries to come in and bunk.
I remember that when due to where those
golden Palestine was the first person he
did it and the Tito fight man. It was that
the first, yeah. Yeah. That was so weird.
Someone did it in the UFC too. They wore
that shit on their back. It's odd. Yeah.
Put it on your trunk. So you're
going to do it, I guess. Wow.
You don't get as much
money, but it's, it is.
I Know Bernard got 50 k to put on his
back and he bet on himself against Tito
real. Yeah. And you know, he was
a huge underdog. Everyone dial.
Everyone thought Tito was gonna whoop
his ass. Everyone. Everyone there wasn't.
You know,
I was jumping off my brother's couch.
Yeah. He fucked him up. Yeah, man.
Yeah. Bernard was a special athlete.
He really was absolutely special fight all
time. Great. For sure. Yeah, definitely.
Yeah.
And it was interesting because I used
to watch him when he was in his thirties
and he would complain about crooked
promoters and all these things.
And my thought was, man, it's too bad.
This guy like missed his prime. Right.
And then he did what he did and then
he did what he did after the after,
cause he got,
he was in jail for like strong arm robbery
and got out and Kinda like wallowed
in obscurity. And then his shot was
that Roy fight, you know, and I,
and we were like, Oh, you got your
shot. I guess that's it. Yeah.
It just got better and better with age.
Just show man.
It's like the rarest thing in anything.