Well, you got also realized Dj
Dimitris just got shoulder surgery.
So he's still rehabbing from that,
you know,
and who knows how long that's gonna take.
I don't know how complex the shoulder
surgery was, but yeah, that's, you know,
still interested in that fight. I
mean, it's a, it's a big one for, uh,
for Demetrius. Jonathan
especially, you know, he needs
that extra little push over.
You know how Shannon gave him some tips,
some tricks when we were still in the
media towards together for the talk shit.
No, not necessarily to talk
shit, but you know, cause he, he,
he's not going to be able to come out
and just talk shit. He's kind of style.
It's not his style. It
don't work, you know. Uh,
but to round out his game a
little bit, boy, let's say that,
I know what you're saying because I,
and I'm gonna go back to the
most well rounded fighter.
You got to be able to promote to, you
know, you've got to be able to see,
people want to want to see you fight too.
And that thing is a stress.
It's a, it's a stressor on you and you're
on your, you're training, like you said,
you got to get up at 6:00 AM because when
you do it, you get more media requests.
So you get,
you get to have those interviews more
and that's a stress and it's something
that you, Barron at your opponent
don't necessarily have to, you know, a,
a guy like Conor does a lot more media
than, than his opponent though of course,
it's a bigger stress and you know,
if you can handle all those stresses
and still go out there and compete, uh,
then if you shy away from that,
I got to take that away from you as far
as being the best power fire fighter.
You know what I mean? That's
interesting. But if it's not Demetrius,
and who the fuck is it other than
George and George isn't really fighting
[inaudible] for sure.
John Jones, you know,
I think George's fighting right
now either. Oh, you saying right,
right now in the sport because John,
I mean it's up there. I mean, I don't,
I don't think John took PDDs and
people give me a hard time about that.
I don't think he did.
I think he took something tainted just
based on what you saw to has said about
the levels pre and post test.
I think you fucked up and us
that money up man. Oh Man.
I was fucked up money,
but he could still,
he could still come back
and be much bigger. Uh, you
know, like I say controversy,
especially when you know, especially when
you're black in America, controversy is,
is, is one of the best things they
can have until you really, well John,
when he's loose and when,
you know,
like when him and Daniel were in that
press conference and Janet was talking
Shit, he goes, I beat you after I did
cocaine with Josh just himself. I mean,
he's huge. He's, he's, he's,
he's going to be the biggest, uh,
he could already been the biggest
star v cell from the beginning.
If they don't really
suspend him for very long,
100 comes back within a few months.
It's entirely possible that he could
come back and be the biggest still of all
time. I think he's going to be way
bigger. Uh, especially after, like I said,
controversies is a great one. When
you're black in America, they really is.
It's not just that, it's
like for John, like how much,
how much more focus will there,
I mean my fear is that he's going to s
somehow now there's sabotage again and
that, that this is not just this,
that these lessons sinking in
because there's been so many of them.
The car accident where the, you know,
broke the lady's arm and she's pregnant
and he runs away and then slamming the
car into the tree. There was so
many. And then there's, you know,
the first test positive and then the
second test, positive like fuck the brawl,
the press conference. Fuck. It's
like, there's so many things
I think that goes back to,
you know,
not being delusional and having the right
team around you and somebody that you
really listened to that you really
truly listened to, you know,
not just somebody that you just kind
of hard. Right. Yeah. I hear you, uh,
because it's easy to get that
way. It really is. I'm sure, uh,
like it have approached it a couple
of times. You know, you get that,
especially when you got that confidence
in the thing that made you great in the
first place. It can be like a
hindrance to youtube. And I think
a lot of it has been,
or at least a lot of my growth and the
past couple of months has been me getting
in my own head and understanding it
and, and kind of breaking it down. Uh.