The Joe Rogan experience or bowling
or not make a commitment. Highlight,
I think is one of the most
corrupt games. Oh yeah. Someone,
someone tried to tell me
explain, oh, it was Joey.
He was explaining to
me how highlight works,
that it's all about gambling and the only
reason why it works is that people are
betting on the games and so because
people are betting on the games,
they get these guys and these guys are
just fucking miss it on purpose and they
knew. Yeah. It's like it's
rigged. I might be wrong.
If you're a highlight play and you're
like, [inaudible] Joe Rogan, I love this,
this podcast again.
Hey,
I get my information from the Church
of what's happening here we go,
look at that damn glove. It's,
look how they play with that.
It looks like somebody with a one long
freaking nail. They're holding it right.
It's not like wrapped around their wrist.
They're holding it like a tennis racket.
How much more fun would it be if he
watched a baseball game with the picture?
Just had that thing. Boy, that looks
so stupid. Just came look so dumb.
What's the goal? That goal? I don't know.
They're throwing it off the wall and then
another guy catches it and it throw it
in, but they, somebody here to
get hit in the face pretty quick.
They're putting forth minimum effort. Even
when he falls down, it's like that guy,
he's fallen down like he's trying to
get a foul like, oh yeah, he does.
He looks like he flopped. Yay.
Flow soccer. The soccer flops. Oh,
he soccer flopped it. That's why suck.
I'll never make it in America. The flop.
He can't get. Yeah, you have 30
years of flopping. You can check us.
We can watch it on TV. We know
what you do. You know though,
I think it's catching on to
the NFL and the NBA floppy.
They're starting to flop a little bit
more because they see what happened.
Didn't somebody analyze who's free?
Throw to the analyze.
What do you mean?
There was someone that analyzed,
there was an ESPN analyst who analyzed,
um,
what's the guy's name of the big crazy
beard. Really good basketball player.
Oh fuck the clippers. Oh, go to, I
don't know what I'm pretended to know.
I literally don't know shit.
Go To uh,
Andrew Saul Schultz's things.
Kevin Duran, is that it?
Andrew Salt Schultz is go to Andrew.
Saul Schultz is a Twitter page,
so he had it up on his
Twitter and I watched it and
I've watched it analysis the
difference between him
when he's challenged and he
throws a free throw versus
unchallenged when he's on target
with the beard. James Harden. Okay.
We've been challenged,
meaning someone's trying to block him or
he has a free Oakland Shaka open shot.
When he has a free open shot,
he just jumps up in the air and
does his three is three pointer.
But when he's challenged,
he throws his legs up to hit the other
person so he could fall down on his ass.
And I'm like a leg kick, like a
dance move. Well he's not even,
it's not even a self defense move.
He's like making,
he's forcing contact with the
person so that you can fall down.
But it looks like, yeah, it's interesting.
So it looks like it got filed.
So here you'll see him, this
guy watch, watch, no one's
there, watch, watch, he jumps,
he jumped straight up in the air,
straight up, just straight up in the air.
And this guy,
several shots where he does this and then,
um, then they show when he's
contested and when he's contested,
he jumps up in the air and look,
he throws his body weight
forward and then it falls down.
So in the hopes that there'll be a foul,
yeah,
they're saying like if you
look at the way his body moves,
when someone's contesting him,
he moves in Leni his legs
towards them to make contact.
Do you think that's involuntary
or voluntary? Involuntary.
You see the problem is that pencil,
neck, Dork, fucking pushing that.
Now he's specifically known,
especially like in the last two or three
years for getting himself to the free
throw line. Right. At a way higher
clip than almost anybody in history.
So like that's what they're also saying.
Like you can't fault him for that because
he's using the rules of the game. Sure.
To play the game. Right.
So this guy is exempt.
Who is this guy who was examining this?
Do you know how I pelt?
He's got pell center guy,
so the head sports center guy is analyzing
this and he's realizing that the legs
are moving in a direction towards the
other player because the guys there,
which is might exactly be what he's doing.
It might be that or it might be that he
has a devil reaction when someone's in
front of him and he almost wants to
kick the guy away from him. Yeah.
I don't know.
Most Times fouled a three point attempt.
He has 95 60 more than
anybody in right now. So yeah,
I'm going to base on the son Scott Van
Pelt does that yet they've made it a rule
to cause you may be correct.
There's a big thing that happened over
the weekend and their game cause you have
to give the guy a space to land because
there are a couple of years ago there
were a couple of defensive players
that got in trouble for hurting people.
They're getting their ankles turned,
ruining their career,
which has been ruining this team's
chances to win a championship.
Lots of money involved. Yeah.
They made a, it's a flagrant foul,
like it's very bad to do that.
And the referees all of a sudden
didn't didn't call this on Sunday,
like the very first time all
year they stopped calling it.
That's why they're
talking about it really?
And they stopped calling it because
people were taking advantage of it.
Why they stopped calling it is the big
question that people were literally
talking about for 48 hours.
Like why are they doing this?
Bringing up the question of like, are the
officials really involved in the game?
And it's become a big just discussion
about another reason why I won't watch it.