Her low freak bitches saying
that marijuana is a dis,
like it's,
it's just a destructive fucking drug
that is almost as bad as heroin.
He said that's it.
Was it today or yesterday?
I think it was either today or
yesterday that he said, I saw it.
It's hilarious that this guy
is in charge of anything.
Only slightly less awful was his words
only slightly us off of the heroin.
Someone is without a doubt,
if that's what he's expressing.
Someones without a doubt influencing that.
Like there's,
there's more than just his opinion
here. This is not these, when these,
they have these meetings when they're
discussing policy or the discussing how
they proceed.
Like this isn't as simple as this one
wacky dude's opinion and they leave him
alone with his opinion. He has
ultimate power. There's no way.
There's a bunch of vested interests.
There's a bunch of people that have
tremendous amount of money at stake and
would lose money if marijuana was legal.
That is 100% why that guy's doing. Sure.
But I mean, he, he's, his personal
opinion towards weed has always been like,
he's like, he can't lie like that.
Like, that's just a fucking lie.
You don't have any data to show
that that's even remotely true.
Heroin kills fuck loads of people.
People, their bodies are ravaged by it.
Pot doesn't do a goddamn thing to you.
It might make you a little loony. Yeah.
Just, I mean, like, you know,
it's not even comparable. No.
And if you might be schizophrenia exams
where they looked at all the population
and they said, you know, marijuana
contributes to schizophrenia.
And they were like, well, no, actually,
no. If you look at the number,
it's always 1% and it feels 1% of smoking
pot or non smoking pot. It's still,
the schizophrenia numbers have always
been around 1%. Yeah. I mean, like,
it could be exacerbated by marijuana, I'm
sure. But it's not, it doesn't cause it.
Yeah. I think, um, I don't,
I'm not a brain scientist, nor
are you, are you, you know,
I had, I've, I've dealt with
schizophrenia. People, you
know them, right? Yeah. Yeah.
I've known a few. It's, um,
I think it probably varies like
any other kind of mental illness.
But what pisses me off though more than
even like the personal angle of like I'm
a pot smoker and this affects
me personally. I mean,
that does get my goat a little bit,
but what really pisses me off
is that a Trump is mr jobs.
Yeah.
This industry,
this $7 billion recreational
marijuana industry is employing,
uh, like a hundred, 150 people. Yeah. Uh,
part time and full time that are
along some rung of the ladder of like,
oh, well, you know, either they're
working for the growers or there, uh,
doing the packaging are there
helping with the shipping.
So this is like a huge job creator.
It's a huge money maker.
This is what Trump ran on. Trump's
like, I'm the jobs president.
I'm going to bring jobs back
if they go after this industry.
That's the exact opposite of bringing jobs
back. That's shutting jobs down. Yeah.
What's shutting jobs down though,
with the kind of people that we really
want around the first place? I mean,
they can,
they can sort of surmise that people
that are running pot shops are probably
pretty left wing, you know,
pretty, pretty quickly. Sure.
And so you're making almost, you're
making more money for your opposition,
whereas the pharmaceutical companies,
they, they, they're nonpartisan.
Don't forget the alcohol industry
too. That's true. Both of them.
The prison unions, prison guard
unions. That's what's really crazy.
You find out that prison guard unions
have worked to try to keep marijuana
illegal and you're like,
wow.
Like what you're really saying is we want
to extract money by putting people in
cages and says,
you're really saying that's what you get
when you do a private prison industry.
It, I mean, I've done videos about
this fucking private prison industry.
It's crazy. And you know,
I'm always surprised by just
how tap it, the responses.
People are like, Eh, yeah,
whatever. You know, prisoners
who gives a shit. It's like,
yeah, but what about the fact that plenty
of people don't belong to be there?
What about the fact that these people
who run these prison industries sponsor
legislation to put more people in
jail in a country that already has the
disproportionately highest
prison population of any
country on the planet while
claiming to be the fucking
land of the free. Yeah,
we put a fuck load of people
in jail. Tons. They're not,
I mean it's not just being used for
terrorism and they're using it for this
through their drug war as well.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, it's, um,
the drug war is going to have to ramp
up if this marijuana legalization keeps
kicking in, they're going
to have to figure out some
other way to arrest people.
They have to keep the same jobs.
I mean,
they have a lot of jobs they're
going to have to justify, I mean,
Jeff sessions could come to the
pot shops like where I live and,
uh, I guess there's pot
shops around here too and uh,
and they could fucking read them.
They could shut them down. Yeah.
They could legally. Yeah, because
it's still illegal under federal law.
Obama chose not to do that. He chose
to respect the will of the states,
but the Trump administration is at
least signaling that it's not going to
because of sessions.
You think because of the point.
I don't think it's just
because of sessions.
I think sessions is where he is partially
because they want to do this crackdown.
Hmm. That's interesting. You might be
right. We'll have to find out about that,
but the crackdown is not going to go well.
It's a terrible idea.
You let the genie out of the bottle,
you gave people their freedom.
That will be the,
that'll be the death of a,
of the power of the Trump administration.
If they actually go through
with something so stupid.
It would be stupid economically as
well. Oh yeah. Would it would show,
I mean you want to talk
about transparency.
It will show really clearly
who your loyalty is to that.
It's not to the will of the people
that it's to these companies that are
benefiting from keeping marijuana
illegal. Period. That's it.
And then we'd have to figure
out a marijuana coalition.
We've got to figure out a way,
like there are fucking 100 million of us.
I guarantee you in this country,
100 million people that smoke pot,
that's a lot of fucking people and that
number's going to grow a third of the
country. It's, yeah. And it's going to
grow. The more things are people like,
well,
I really believe
you fucking idiot.
You fucking wins.
There's a lot of
fucking people. I might've made that
number up. I fucking, uh, I mean,
I believe it.
I believe it's probably at least close
because even when I was living down south
and I was hanging out with
conservatives who love Trump,
they smoked a little weed. Yeah.
They're smoking weed, not a little weed.
They're smoking weed like crazy fun.
It's fun to get high.
It's nothing wrong with it.
The only thing that's wrong with it is
the fact that it's been buttoned down
into our brain,
deep,
deep in our memory through propaganda
that it's bad for you. That's it.
If you looked at the actual
effects it has on you,
like we were talking about schizophrenia
and blaming marijuana on schizophrenia,
but it still seems across the board it'd
be 1% it's the same thing with dummies
and lazy people. When dummies and
lazy people find out about pot,
it ruins the idea of it for
other people. Oh, well look,
it's associated with his loud mouth dummy.
His loud mouth,
fucking lazy person never gets
anything done. He's always broke.
So he's asking for money. That's a
pothead. Potheads don't get shit done.
Don't be a pothead.
And then you get that in your head
and you're just run with it. Well,
there's plenty of like,
we know there's plenty of potheads that
are really industrious and hardworking.
You know,
a lot of them,
you can't attribute something that was
always part of someone's personality and
say, well, marijuana cause that. Exactly.
It doesn't totally change
the nature of a person.
It's not that powerful of a
fucking drug. Nor does coffee. No,
nor does alcohol nor do cigarettes
for that matter. Exactly. Well,
alcohol can change some people.
That's true. It was a bad example.
Canada justice system is crumbling
as cannabis rates continue. So,
um, there've been, they'd been
busted all these fucking pot places.
I thought you guys had your social
justice warrior president and uh,
everybody was going to get to pick
their own gender pronouns and now you're
rating pot places.
Kaloga this 6,500 cases and provincial
court could be soon drop due to delays
including 38 for homicide or attempted
murderer. One terrible case last year,
a man named Kenneth Williamson was
convicted of raping a minor over a hundred
times, but because of lengthy delays
and taking his truck, his case to trial,
his conviction was overturned. Wait, was,
is that so they could
prosecute more marijuana? No,
this is just saying that they are there.
They're there.
They're system is in such crisis and this
marijuana case where they're arresting
all these people from marijuana,
it's insane because their justice system
is already in the crisis. So it says,
considering the justice system crisis,
cannabis should obviously be the lowest
priority for police and the courts.
But it's not,
not only your police launching more raids
against suspensory than ever before,
but ridiculous charges for small scale
cannabis crimes are continuing from coast
to coast.
So they,
they have a justice system that's so
broken that they can't even convict people
who raped miners a hundred times.
They can't take them to trial. I mean,
there is there,
but it's that broken.
But they're still trying to fucking
catch people for smoking weed and,
and just, uh, raiding
dispensaries and shit.
Like I had to get a waste of fucking time.
If I had to guess.
I would say it's some sort
of compartmentalism and
that like the drug people
aren't, they don't go after the other
crimes and they don't have to do with it,
you know, and then there's a
legal system that's backed up,
but to put more people
in the legal system,
just because you have to
somehow or another justify
the position that you're in.
A cop of a DEA cop, whatever they're
called up there, that's fucking crazy.
You got a broken system. You have,
uh, you're, you're preying on people.
You're locking people up. If
you, if you want to impress us,
then convict that fucking a rapist.
Don't, yeah, don't fucking, uh,
prosecute people who are smoking
weed for sure. And by the way,
what you're doing right
now seems like a crime.
You're locking people up in a cage for
a plant that everybody on the planet
knows is not bad for you.
So if you just decide that because of
some fucking bullshit thing that's written
on paper,
that you should be able to go against
all the science that's available today.
All the common sense and
the will of the people.
And you should be able to go into people's
houses, going to people's businesses,
arrest them, take all their money,
take all their pot. That's a crime.
That sounds like a crime.
It sounds like you're using your position
and you're using it to just mark one
up on the scoreboard. You know,
you, we got some convictions
today. Good solid ones.
A bunch of dopers caught us.
A bunch of dopers had to let
that crazed pedophile go,
but we got all the DoPay it dopers will
scourge of society to a hundred kids.
But you know what? He didn't, he didn't
fuck them over by giving him pot. Yeah.
Okay.
Wasn't smoking no weed.
It's those kids are going to
remember what he did to them.
It's not going to damage
their memory. Yeah, like that
Goddamn part. I remember it.
So you remember it explicitly.
Jesus Christ. It's just,
I can't believe that in this day
and age that shit is still going on.
It just seems like,
and Canada,
I thought with this Trudeau guy was
going to be more progressive than ever,
which Canadians are complaining
about it like crazy and you know,
I've had Jordan Peterson on the podcast
and he hates what's going on now with
this push towards being as open minded
as possible with all these accepting of
the gender pronouns and that you're
going to have to start putting people,
you're going to have to start processing
cases through the human rights council
because if you don't use a
person's proper gender pronoun,
it could literally be considered a crime.
Like I think all that stuff on
the left when it goes way far,
it gets really crazy, but it's
probably a good thing to balance out.
That's tough on the right
and people figure out some
sort of comfortable medium.
Yeah, he's not being that
at all. He's not. If you,
if the president is
allowing this to go on,
he's not being this progressive president.
He's just not,
if he's only going to be progressive
towards Trans Gender Pronouns and whatever
other ridiculous laws that
they're swamped with, this is,
this is just a terrible precedent to set.
Allowing them to lock people up for pot
in 2017 is a fucking criminal waste of
resources, a criminal waste
of manpower, a critic,
a criminal intrusion on the freedom of
those people that you're locking up a
criminal on the disruption that you're
putting into their lives and the money
that you're taking away from them
for, for trading economy as well. Yes.
And fucking your economy up and these
people were trading in something that is
very valuable to the community and to
the human beings that consume it. Yeah.
You know,
I'm a,
I consider myself a probably more
liberal than I am conservative,
but when I see the priorities
of liberals being identity,
politics, shit, gender pronouns and stuff,
and then so much of the real issues
like just get ignored like this. Yeah.
Uh,
that makes me hesitant to even say like,
I'm a liberal or I'm more left wing and
right wing or whatever because I'm just
like, you're, your priorities are totally
fucked. They're totally out of order. Uh,
you know,
apparently in Canada they're fighting
all these fucking politically correct
identity politics battles, but they
can't deal with the, the pod issue.
They're gonna their police raids against
pot dispensaries are actually up and
they're trying to charge people with
petty fucking weed smoking crimes.
And this is a thing that people always
go on about. Like it's because it's pot,
it seems like it's not a big issue.
It's like it's not,
we've got bigger fish to fry
when you look at Tj. Okay.
I don't know if you've been paying
attention to the stock market. Okay. Tj,
do you know what my war in Afghanistan,
Tj? Yeah. Okay. We've got problems.
Real problems.
It was fucking pot thing.
You got damn potheads if it's off of
your pot, oh, what do I do? Whatever.
But it's not that,
this is what people have to realize.
It's about personal freedom.
It's about a person telling you what you
can do and enforcing it to the point of
putting you in a fucking cage.
And that thing,
which had been an accepted part of
civilization 4,000 of years and is today
accepted. It's an accepted part of
civilization, civilization right now.
But there's just these people that don't
engage in it, that don't understand it,
and that feel like they have the right to
go and lock people up for it. You know,
when the Trump administration started
signaling that they were going to, uh,
take on weed or that they
were thinking about it,
at least that it was on the table,
like stupid at that point,
I was, I made a video where
I was, I was basically,
it was like making all the cases why
this is terrible. This is a bad idea. Uh,
you know, the, I made the
economics argument, I made
the personal freedom argument.
Um, I may, I get it.
I pointed out the tremendous amount of
revenue this is generating for the states
that have legalized it.
And a huge part of the
response was just like, yeah,
Oh yeah, of course he goes after Trump
when Trump goes after he's precious weed.
He cares. That's the only thing that
got them to care. It's like each chunky.
I made fucking so many cogent arguments
that hold water about the economic and
personal liberty ramifications
of something like this.
And all you want to focus on is my
personal usage of this fucking substance.
It's bullshit.
You Bet.
It's a good thing to talk about cause
it'll get you talking about it like right
now. Sure. It'll get
ya. It'll poke at you.
They know because they know that people
like you and I really do enjoy our
marijuana and when you try to take away
the pot, we really do get upset. Yeah.
I mean it was like kind of the like I
was kind of like on the give Trump a
chance bandwagon until they
started signaling this stuff.
So that's why really why I got shit.
It's a very,
very foolish thing to try to step in
in 2017 with all the signs and all the
information and the public opinion.
And to say that marijuana is
something that can get you locked up,
get you locked up, but it's almost
as bad as heroin. He's so stupid.
That's a silly man. That guy needs a pot
Brownie more than anything in this life.
He just needs a, uh, just a
quarter. Just give him a quarter.
Let him sit there and let him think about
his grandchildren and let them think
about fishing and let them think about
just napping in the sun and going to meet
the good Lord. A few years. You don't
have much time left motherfucker.
You want to ruin it for pod hands.
You're barely alive. Your hair's white.
Your posture is bad and
you're standing there lying.
You're lying on television about
heroin and pot being like really close.
That's a crazy person who doesn't know
what pot does. You're talking about pot.
You obviously have no idea what it's like.
It's like a person who's colorblind
describing some sort of a kaleidoscope.
You don't know what you're even
talking about. Like for a guy like him,
if you want to have a person who's
talking about individual experiences,
they should have had,
like if you're talking about someone
who's talking about the effects of a
chemical and whether or
not it should be legal,
they should have had some sort
of experience with that chemical.
They should know what it's doing.
They should understand it,
especially if it's safe.
Something like marijuana.
So if you had to talk about it and to
have these ridiculous, you, you can't,
you can't invest one evening
in a safe environment.
They'll do it in a laboratory
or a hospital somewhere,
pad up the rooms and give you
a pod cookie and then put,
put pink Floyd's the wall on just someone,
someone tell this fucking
guy what it really is.
Cause he's just talking out
of his ass. Yeah, I mean, uh,
I don't know if this is just apocryphal
or if they're, this is an actual story,
but I remember there being something
about him saying that he thought the,
the KKK, we're good guys until he found
out they smoked weed. That was, uh,
I think that was wrongly attributed
to him. And that not only that,
there has been evidence that he's
done many things for civil rights.
I had read that too,
but I think that's,
it just might be the case of people
being overzealous and trying to paint a
demean.
You could find things,
I'm sure that you've said
or that I've sat with you.
Take them completely out of context.
You could paint a very different opinion.
Definitely. It's fucking very hard
to form an opinion of someone,
like a legitimate opinion of someone
without actually knowing them.
But you can have an opinion.
It's not that hard when they call and
say that that pod is nearly as dangerous
as heroin because that you did that
person snapchat, you're just like,
this person is either delusional
or is willfully deceptive. Right.
And the important part about
it is it's not just a person.
It's a person with an extreme amount
of power. Yeah. It's a person,
a very dangerous position of enforcing
laws. And you go, okay, well,
will you think that that's crazy.
That's not true. That's not true.
It just drives me nuts because I
think it helps people. I really does.
I really do.
I really do think it's probably one
of the best elements in terms of,
uh, a happy, healthy society,
staying grounded and being
like a little more kind. I get,
I think it gives you a certain percentage
more of kindness. Yeah. I mean, uh,
I've definitely seen it
make people more empathetic,
a more tolerant towards one another.
I've seen people who have
anxiety that it helps.
I've seen people who have anxiety that
it exacerbates their anxiety to the
edibles. Do. Yeah, for sure.
Like with a story I told about my brother
at the beginning of show, but for the,
for the,
by and large,
I know a lot of people with like bad
anxiety who smoke weed and it makes them
feel better. It makes them feel more
comfortable in social situations. Um,
stuff like that too, bro. It makes
you fucking talk about weed. Yeah.
How come you guys keep talking about weed?
I get it. You like weed enough already,
Bro. I can read that now to
read it in the comments there.
Yeah.