Hello Freak bitches.
You're on a podcast called
the legion of skanks.
Could that be introduced in a presidential
debate? And then I have to go, yes.
That was my show.
Yes,
but you would do it just like that
and everybody would start laughing.
We're realizing that this just do
it like a politician or I'd be like,
I repudiated that show years ago.
I no longer associate with
big Jay Oakerson dude.
Speaking of which they put
wiener in the pokey today,
21 months in jail for sexting,
I believe as a 15 year old.
Well,
look,
I I that guy single handed
late probably changed America.
Yeah. I mean I really like, yeah,
I don't think she really did buy,
he changed it through Dick Pics,
which,
how else were you going to change
America in 2017 Anthony Wiener?
It gets hard time. Is that the
flows? That post is hilarious.
Whoever writes for the post, Damn.
They have some fucking great headlines.
Anthony Wiener gets hard time.
Oh, you know, it's horrible.
Is before all this happened,
he was fantastic.
That guy could have been the president.
He was, he had that politician. He thing,
I mean, he was he and he was like for
a young politician on the fast track,
but he, I mean, I really
do think Hilary Clinton,
I mean I just think it was such a close
race that any little thing probably
could have made the difference.
So you could blame any number of factors.
But I mean the FBI coming
out and reopening an
investigation on you like less
than two weeks before an election, that's
pretty tough to get over politically.
Like in any normal year, any candidate
would be buried. But after all that,
lock her up, lock her up. There's
no way you can survive that.
The FBI's looking into it,
all the people that don't want to look
into it any further than the surface,
they immediately go, oh, we fucking
God, it's over. And I'm, you know,
like I think there's also just in terms
of the politics and the way people work,
there was something about
Anthony Wiener wear, so it just,
it made the American public
think about him again.
And shrimp was bringing the women who
are accusing Bill Clinton of rape to the
debates. And I think the average person
just kind of went like, wait a minute. So,
so your husband is a sexual
Predator and your best friend,
her husband is also a sexual predator.
Like who the fuck are these people?
Who the fuck is that the story for?
Yeah.
Well that's one of the things that got
me about Fox News because Fox News has
always been the voice of conservative
America on television, right?
These staunch verse, The star staunch
Voice of conservative America,
but yet all this sex stuff comes out
like the bill O'Reilly tapes where he was
calling up is whoever the girl was and
saying crazy shit with a loofah sponge.
Remember all that? Yeah, I
read about it. It was crazy.
But they had recordings of it
and then it was, you know, the,
all the women that accused him of sexual
harassment and the sexual harassment
with other people and then other people
are sending Dick pics and like, Whoa,
you guys are freaks. And you know, it
was really crazy about it. Was that. Um,
so Roger Ailes,
who was the head of the network,
he went down first for sexual harassment
and then as soon as he was down like a
whole bunch of other people started
going down and then you really started
wondering like,
Oh shit.
Like was it just like a new guy isn't
letting us sexually harass anymore?
What's going on with this shark
off? Okay. Well I think it was just,
there was a culture that they could get
away with before the Internet where they
were the bosses and the women were the
underlings and they all felt, you know,
I'm sure there's probably a lot
of dynamics plan there, right?
There's a power situation. The man, the,
the guy who's the boss is in position.
And then there's also women that
are attracted to power figures.
And then there's also this conservative,
like really repressed environment,
which always leads to freak
shit. It always does. Yeah.
And have like people buttoned down.
They always lead to freak show.
They have to find a way out that
pressure's got to go. Yeah, you're right.
I mean, I really, I always
say to people, if you're in a,
if you're in New York City, if you go
to a bar in the financial district,
like right after work,
it's a really crazy seen,
something interesting like the
exact dynamic you're talking about.
Whereas these people who are all day
working in this crazy like this and then
like the ties are loosened and it's this
like drinking and they take their shoes
off at the bar. You're like, whoa.
People are getting slapped on the ass.
Like crazy shit is going on.
But you wouldn't think you're a banker.
You know the guy, the guy who runs your
retirement. Uh, okay. On, you know why?
Because like we were talking about before
with like before the podcast or it was
like these ancient reward systems.
There's an ancient reward system for
plundering. I really believe that.
I think that these guys feel like their
goddamn pirates, like their plundering.
Yeah. They're part of the financial
market and then they're doing shots.
We're going to fucking Jegan.
Yeah, yeah. Fucking take them down.
They grab each other.
We're going to fucking take them down.
We're going to fucking take him down.
And if you think about it,
I mean if you think about um,
the acquisition of property of goods
or anything like that throughout human
history, I mean the, the idea of like a,
just a theory of just acquisition
of property. His leg. Yeah.
Pretty relatively new.
And the way everything was acquired
for all of human history was through
conquest. Just through, you know, you
take it, you take other people's shit.
And Uganda think that like a hostile
takeover must feel incredibly like sacking
the city again. These guys, oh, that's
from Wall Street from uh, what's his name?
It wasn't Wall Street. What the fuck was
this called? A wall. A full Wall Street.
Yeah. Yeah. That was a great
scene. But people resonate.
That scene resonated with
people. I'm going to fucking
go. I'm not fucking going.
And everybody said it's like being
above the system kind of ease.
But this is tapping in just same
way football taps in [inaudible].
It's tapping into this ancient
reward system for plundering. Yeah.
When men get together and they fuck
up other men and take all their shit.
And then we kick ass.
Yeah.