Her low freak bitches and if
you listen to Jordan Peterson,
he knows so much about Marxism
that it's it, it shows you like,
oh this is a pattern of human thinking.
It starts off by people that were
really like well intentioned.
They're intellectuals, they're
very kind, they're sympathetic,
they're progressive and they
want everyone to be nice.
So one of the ways they do it is to be
really evil to people they think are not
nice.
And then you create this fucking war
cause they look at them as predators and
there it's, that's that sort
of like infantiles the date.
The problem is that people in the
other side don't look at it that way.
So you're starting this thing and you're
creating two short up defenses and
walls of offense. You,
you start, you push in,
you start Molotov cocktail in universities
that to given speeches by guys who
were Republicans,
you create a,
like that UC Berkeley that
went happened with Milo.
I just pulled them out of the fucking
building to save his life. Yeah.
He did $100,000 worth of damage to
the school for thinking. I thought,
I thought Berkeley was so
tolerant. How, what a surprise.
As long as you don't get along hearts
on fire, they make cars. Ireland.
Milo was there and so we got shadows. Yes.
Some kind of shy bias. Yeah, no, it's,
it's crazy. And if you listen to what
he's saying, he's saying some racist Shit,
right? Not nothing compared to the
reaction. And it's getting nothing.
He's mostly half of a troll. He's like
half of a comedian when he says things,
he's bitchy.
He's a bitchy gay guy.
They called him a Nazi and
he's a fucking gay Jew.
It is one of the funniest things ever.
They're calling this Guy Nazi and a
white supremacist slogan of his tour.
Loates intense, dangerous faggot
tour. But he, but he's gay. He's gay.
And he talks about his love of black
Dick. You know, he talks about how no,
he's up of writer and a troll,
but like a,
an intelligent troll and a
British guy who's got people on,
if you look at what the athletes yeah.
And they said it was because
he said a rude, racist shit.
Organize some sort of an attack on
Leslie Jones, but he didn't do it.
Like if you look at what he said, if, if,
how responsible is someone who
cracks a joke about someone,
like he said something about Leslie
Jones wouldn't be the first time I was,
I was, uh, in Saul turned
down by a black man. Like,
like something along those lines,
like bitchy but funny. And for that,
just for that,
for saying that because she was mad at
his review or something along those lines
that his followers started
sending her horrible come maybe.
But how much of that can you push
on to him? They can't control that.
You can't control it.
So I'm not,
what I'm saying is if you
look at what he actually said,
if that's grounds for a band, we're
dealing with some extreme censorship.
So you've got to figure out like, when is
he responsible? See did he say, hey guys,
go get him. No, he didn't. But you
know who did do that is Leslie Jones.
There was a tweet or Leslie Jones,
someone was attacking her and she's like,
go get them to that person. Like
[inaudible] which is like, look,
that's her prerogative too.
If you want to be a cut
and started attacking this
woman who's a very hilarious
comedian for no reason,
she,
I think she should be able to say fuck
you and do it publicly and say go get him
so fence.
So my,
my low never said that Milo
literally never said go get him,
but yet he was sort of held responsible
for things that other people said.
You can't,
there's so many crazy people out there.
The idea that you can control them and
then you could just like say like people
who like Brian Cowen,
you are responsible for those people.
You have to set a good example.
We're going to kick you off our platform.
That's essentially what this crazy,
it's weird, it's their prerogative.
But pull up 20 actually silence.
I think it's interesting
and yellow actually said,
you know that you're not going to change.
We always have to remember that if
you disagree with the other side,
the idea is to try to get them to agree
with you or try to come up with some
kind of a consensus. So you can move
ideas forward and move the world forward.
And what we have with this kind of
reaction to Milo is if you're going to do
$100,000 worth of damage in your protest,
well that's fine.
And Milo have to be escorted out and you
won't listen to them and you close your
mind. You're not moving anything forward
or making anything better though.
You're just creating a big old division.
And I guess you guys can
stay in your echo chamber.
They'll stay in their echo chamber and
nobody will listen to each other and we
won't learn anything. Well that's just a
product of being raised in this system,
this two party system and this ridiculous
idea that there's us and them and now
that they're in, there's this, you know,
all people have to fight back
and you have to punch Nazis.
So this crazy shit that people are saying.
But when you listen to what Milo actually
says, even if you disagree with them,
which I do all the time, like I disagree
with a lot of what he's saying, Hah,
there's Sam Harris put it best. He's
like, half of it is like a performance.
It's like he seems insincere a lot of the
times and he's very acutely aware that
is generating a response and the things
that he's saying that they're saying
like,
you know,
that they're saying that he's racist or
he's just as terrible white nationalists
or something like this is they're just
making stuff up so that they can start
attacking him more freely
because it's easier.
What he said is definitely controversial.
Controversial,
he said is some of it is definitely rude.
Some of it is preposterous.
Some of it doesn't make any sense.
Like he's,
he's pro circumcision because he doesn't
want Dick's to have extra skin hanging
off of him. He says he'll
fight with you about it. You
know, he's, he's, he's a, uh,
Catholic. I think he is. I'm like, okay,
that's fun. I believe that. He's like,
absolutely, Catholicism is the best
religion. It's the most amazing religion.
I'm super like, he's crazy. Okay.
So he started making front of Jones
and we wrote an article, first of all,
let's say one thing that he wrote an
article, uh, where he did a horrible,
like a mean critique of the
new Ghostbusters for women.
And he said essentially that
it was like a feminist film.
And he pointed out some really
important shit. He's like,
every guy in the movie is a fucking
idiot and every woman's saves the world.
And he's like, it's kind of
ridiculous. So He's, he says, um,
he writes this. So she was getting
hate mail from his response,
I guess from his thing, racial abuse,
abuse that she was getting. And he said,
everyone gets hate mail
for funds for fuck sake.
One tweet read another one called Jones,
barely literate.
Later she shared fake screenshots.
Oh,
he shared fake screenshots
that made it appear of Jones.
We're making profane
and offensive postings.
Twitter didn't say exactly why at Bandy
Annapolis only telling Breitbart writer
that he was permanently
banned for violation of the
company's rules prohibiting
participation in or exciting
targeted abuse of individuals.
So what makes that like,
okay.
I could see like if he was
post retweeting things that,
that were very rude.
I will have to see what those things were.
Probably proceed how rude they were.
Maybe they were silly. They were racist.
They were bad. They were
bad. They were crazy.
Or on the seat making it appear
that the Jones link there, Jamie,
scroll back down to see where it says it.
Made it appear of Jones were making
profane and offensive postings.
Click on that. Let's see what it looks
like. What it, what was actually said.
This was not me. Okay. Okay. Uncle Tom.
Fag Nero needs to get his racist ass out.
My mentions shit like this makes me think
we need to gas got Goddamn faggots sit
down. Okay, so it's not really hurts
fake. Yeah. Somebody made a fake.
That's kind of fucked up to do to Leslie
Jones. Terrible. Well, how do we know?
Okay, you got to assume that he
knew that that wasn't him. Right.
Posted one that that wasn't her
brother, but hold on, hold on. Hold on.
We got assumed that. Go
back to that again. Jamie,
you got to assume that he knew
that that wasn't really her. Right?
You don't think that he really thought
she wrote that? So if he retweets that,
if that's a fake account,
what's the diff? Okay,
so it's just a photo that
someone said or did he,
someone else did it and he tweeted
it. He retweeted it, I guess. Okay,
so let's see what the other ones are.
Although it says it looks
like it's verified as well
as dog. Did He retweet this?
If someone sent it to him and he
retweeted. Okay, here's one less dog.
You're Ghostbusters just in the first to
have an ape in it. Oh Shit. Super Racist.
That is, whoa. It's awful. So he
retweeted that. He retweeted that. Okay.
Yeah. That's not cool. That's pretty
fucking rude. That's again, what,
what else we got. That's, that's,
that's, that's just shitty man.
That makes me not like, just that
makes me want to put this on him.
He's definitely got some issues.
He's got some fucking issues.
We were good. We get it.
You get it. Well that's,
he's definitely got some issues like that.
That's not a cool thing to do.
But what he's doing,
he insights talk and because of that his,
his book is now number one on the Amazon,
the salads you trying to accomplish what's
the property sale and no one knows it
hasn't book isn't even out
yet. Yeah, it's really,
really interesting guy and a lot of ways.
He's very smart. I talked him off hair.
He's a very intelligent guy and he's
very cordial, very good to talk to.
I really enjoyed talking to him and I,
we joked around a lot when we did the
podcast together cause I grilled them
about certain things I think are
ridiculous and eventually it gives him,
starts laughing with you.
He's a very smart guy, but I
don't know what he's doing.
I don't know if this is a real as the
real him or if this is him doing a
performance or if it's combination of
both or if he's finding himself in the
midst of this hurricane of
negativity and popularity,
which would it be just
assuming that he's bulletproof,
that he can't be influenced by this
fucking crazy or deal that he's going
through. And occasionally do
shit that he shouldn't have done.
Like reposting some horrible
racist thing is young.
I mean he's maybe 30 something. Right?
How old is my life? You made a point.
That's a really good point.
You just said that made about if this is
like in transition, like so sure he is.
He's a growing just like all of us are.
And even like,
it depends on how you can
catch somebody in, in a,
in a moment where they can sound if you,
they already sound not like themselves.
So he's young. He's 23. He's
fucking smart, dude. I'm
telling you. I believe it.
I just feel like,
yeah,
I definitely disagree with retweeting
that racist picture of Lizzy Jones looking
like a gorilla. This one guy who said
something, he was at the, uh, when,
what was the theater in France that
they shot up during a performance?
He was in the band, I believe it's
Christ. Yeah. So remember when,
when those guys opened fire
the life contracts deaf,
famous, famous, famous, yeah. Death metal.
And he said something about Islam
right after that he was like,
he's in and he was emotional and people
that dive and it was his concert and he
saw some all kinds of stuff and he said
something that they picked up and he did
an interview cause they just did a
documentary on it and he said something
really interesting. They said,
you said something about Islam,
do you have any regret about that?
And it was pretty racist. And he said,
all right, well look, first of all, I
love people. We have a lot of Muslim fans.
Anything else said what happened there
was my emotions were so heightened and
there was a,
there was a span of time where I
was thinking in a very emotional,
uncharacteristic way that I usually am my,
I had,
I was hot off of something tragic and I
didn't even know how to make sense of it.
I don't want you to reread what I
said because that's not who I am.
But in that sliver of time, that's how
I was feeling and I lashed out in pain.
It's very honest way of putting it is,
and I thought that's,
that's why we have to be careful about
taking quotes and then applying that to a
person's entire Caribbean Myeloma.
This was a guy in the band after
he said something about Islam, but,
but it made me think about that.
We do this all the time where we say,
you said that one thing,
you said a sentence,
let's let's highlight that and let's
just say that's who the man is. You know?
You got to be careful. Sometimes you'll
be held accountable for what you do.
Eating good deal. We can't always
give everyone a pass, but I'll call.
He's just going through a rough
time. It's all good. It's drill.
You're going to be held accountable
to. That's true too. That's true too.
But we also have to recognize that like
at 33 years of age, especially, dude,
I was a moron when I was 33 and if I had
gotten drunk and I decided to retweet
some shit,
thank God Twitter wasn't around then I
want to say the stern of the ship that
young and if he's a smart yes it is. You
say stupid shit all the time. Hold on.
Just doing stupid shit.
I've never retweet anything racist.
All 33 you know you're not racist.
No, not a Rawls, but with them,
this is the pattern. Maybe you don't
get a free house. Here's the thing, man.
He's his whole thing is
courting controversy.
That's essentially what he's doing
by saying feminism is cancer.
He's organizing a fist fight.
He's calling them out and he's organizing
a verbal [inaudible] probably on
Adderall.
So he's talking a hundred miles an hour.
He's really articulate and he's gay and
he looks fabulous and he's got bleach
blonde hair and he wears clothes and
when he's killing it, like on stage,
he's a very good order.
So he's engaging them in these debates
that he's got carefully thought out,
responses, carefully thought out
sentences about what he's doing.
He definitely knows what he's doing.
He definitely knows.
How was your conversation with Henry
Rollins? Speaking of articulates,
getting a little pointy with this racism
thing. Look at Maria. Oh I love that.
He's a good looking guy. Handsome fellow.
Hell, a profound love of black Dick.
He talks about it all the time,
which is also one more way that they have
a hard time attacking him cause he's a
gay Jew that loves black Dick. Like he's
got the spectrum covered. He's like,
there's a triangle
invincibility that's around him.
Brian's up. These are good talking.
One time Brian's not.
You go off.
Oh Man, I am happy. I'm alright
man. You can't. This is,
this is what fascism is.
You can't enforce your view of the
world on people through violence because
that's what you're doing
when you're a fascist.
And that's what people need to understand.
Like you can't just use the word fascist
when it applies to right wing people.
If you're keeping people
from communicating,
you're keeping a gay Jew from talking
shit on your stage and you can't just
counter what he's saying with
someone who's better at talking shit.
That is better points.
So instead you want to throw a chair
through the window at fucking Starbucks.
Look, stop. You guys are fascist. I
know you don't stink your fascists.
Even if you think you're right the
way you're doing it, it's 100% wrong.
This isn't the guys on a Nazi.
He's not someone who's,
even if he had said a racist thing
in the past, he's not the first.
Every fucking comedian said racist shit.
Let's dog had herself had
a bunch of racist shit.
They pulled off her Twitter page.
We don't hate her for that.
She had a bunch of shit
about white people,
just generalizing about
white people in in general.
If you ever did that about black people,
you would get blackballed from
Hollywood for life, of course.
But we will allow a certain amount of
stupid shit to come out of people's mouths
if we think that you're not a bad
person. Yeah. And if you disagree,
if you disagree with somebody the
way you beat it, I'll say it again.
The way you beat a bad idea is with a
better I don't do is you don't start this
fucking meme of punch Nazis.
Like everybody keeps saying punch Nazis.
Like don't say that. You're talking
punched on there though. Girls.
You see that girl getting
maced in the face?
She the up make bitcoin great again hat
and they came up and maced Mesa in the
face cause it looked like a make America
great again when she fucked up where it
doesn't matter man.
They know I'm in a fucked up Peter in
the head with a sign and another guy may
stir in the face they're ruthless to they
weren't ruthless with is our boy Jake
shields. He was at the protest
that I didn't get maced.
He's lucky he didn't get mason the faith
that they ran the tray. You need more.
You need more than mace to fight
Jake shields. No problem with Macy's.
You can't see. And if people just jump
on you and you can't just look, Jacob,
probably Jack, 90% of them that come
anywhere near them. If you can't,
if you can't see and someone hits you
over the back of the head, but something,
yeah, these fucking people are
doing exactly what they would hate.
And when I see people, like there's
people that been calling out for a COO,
they're calling out for a military coup.
They're calling out for them.
I've seen more than one person say this,
like the military needs to step in and
take our country back. And I'm like,
Holy Shit,
this is a Patrick Swayze movies from the
80s they're shaking exactly the way a
fascist would or a tire and would they
just have a different target. Right.
That's what I always say to people.
It's amazing how many people
think exactly like their enemy.
Exactly like their enemy.
I want to kill all of them or whatever.
And yet they're just, the only difference
is they have a different target.
It's crazy when you have a
legitimate contest, right?
You had a legitimate popularity contest
and one guy wins and you're not happy
that the guy wins.
So you want to start riots like you might,
you might have fucked up and not voted,
or you might not have done such a
good job of picking a candidate or you
might've had the wrong campaign, but
you have to, except when someone wins.
Otherwise, there's no fucking
point in having this contest.
We have this contest every four
years and if you don't accept to one,
as long as it's not this, the cheating,
whatever the cheating happened,
it probably happened on both sides.
Whatever legal shit they got away with
whatever shenanigans and the PR they did
to him with the whole, uh, grab 'em by
the pussy thing and all that. I mean,
there's, there's a tax left and right
on both sides. He came out ahead.
People aren't happy.
I understand that people are unhappy,
but you can't think that you can start a
riot now because you didn't want him to
be in there. They had a stupid fucking
contest. He won stupid fucking contest.
The problem is you're having a stupid
fucking contest to see who runs the world.
And also it's important to have a little
compassion for the other side in this
terms.
Like I constantly hear Trump voters being
characterized as homophobes rednecks,
dumb hillbillies and all that
stuff cause they're in there,
they're in the mix and they're there.
They're in the mix in every,
on both sides of the categories.
Here's the thing,
it might also be worth taking a little
bit of a human approach and looking at
Trump voters and a maybe a lot of Trump
voters may be a lot of Trump voters who
are good people didn't like
Trump that much either.
But they liked Hillary way less.
Or maybe Hillary's talking the way Obama
has been for the past eight years and
their lives haven't changed for sure
they were and they were desperate to see
anything else work.
Be a little compassionate Wa on why
a lot of people voted for Trump.
Because remember this country voted a
black president and a lot of those voters
were white, uh, two times in a row.
Well in order for him to have one,
you have to have some people that voted
for Obama last term that voted for Trump
this to correct.
There's a lot of people that thought
it would be a better thing to have him
other than her. Yeah. So there
were not no racist and not, oh,
you know homophobes they were. That's
why I was always really careful about,
I was always critical of Trump.
I was very careful not to be critical of
Trump voters because you know there are
a lot of, but you're not being honest
because are dummies in there too.
Just like there's dummies in the
Hillary camp percent there on this.
That's one of those stereotypes exist
when you talk about the either the latte
sipping Hillary supporters who literally
know nothing about what the negative
things she's done. If you say
anything about, or you're a sexist,
I mean there's a lot of that going on too.
Those are real people.
Like the real ridiculous people on the
left and the right. They're all real,
you know? So the, the hillbillies at loved
Trump looped you'd I've seen it, man.
I saw a video where this guy got pulled
over with in an altercation with this
guy hitting.
This other guy had gotten some sort of
a traffic altercation and this guy comes
up to his window, he's calling them
the n word and he's saying, Trump, man,
I'm with Trump,
Trump's president now.
And it's that type of person
of course that like there,
there are people like that that want to
let you know that this is their guy now
because they're white and that
this is like a racist thing.
You think that their races winning,
you think there was KKK people that
voted for Hillary? Like a special group?
K K K for Hillary.
How many KKK people are there?
Like let's be honest, how
many just straight up racists
and how many KKK people?
2000 official Dick's.
There are a lot of these $200 I'm
sorry, 200,000 I thought I saw. Okay,
that sounds, I wouldn't doubt
if those a million in the south.
I think there's definitely probably a
million racists fish clan members joining
an organization's on knowing like
how many UFC fans are. There's a lot,
but if you had a joint organization to
be a UFC fan, they'd be far less of us.
You mean by an a paper view
hood and go to a fucking flame.
You gotta go to a bonfire.
5,000 what more than 40
different clan groups exist?
Many having multiple chapters
or cleverness. That's cute.
Including a few that boast of
presence in a large number of states.
There are over a hundred different
Klan chapters around the country with a
combined strength and members
and associates that may
total around 5,000 Oh my
God, they're a little bigger than
10th planet. It's a little bigger
coupler that is so crazy.
I don't even know if they're
smart enough to be anything.
I think that they are a lot of them.
So people are just sort of guys who
want to be part of a group and you know,
they,
they've been told something,
they don't do any research and
they're just dicks when they are.
A lot of just shitheads want
to be part of a hate group.
A lot of the problem with black versus
white as the same problem as left versus
right. Black versus white left versus
right. Share that fucking team thing, man.
They share that team thing and white
people want to think that they're on one
team and black people want to think
that they're on another team and we fuck
each other up doing that.
It's so stupid. Human, human,
human beings are very tribal.
I mean,
anthropologist tell you that all the
time that human beings are tribal.
It's about time.
Like this generation has cut that shit.
Okay.