It was a good fight for as long
as it landed on his last brother.
One of the cool things that we've gotten
is to be ability to hang out casually
with these fighters.
Like having just breakfast with Randy,
seeing him having with enough times with
you that I remember one time I was like
going into a buffet or
whatever or the hotel,
like free breakfast and like looking
around and just having him going, hey,
come sit with me. I'm like,
oh, okay. Just like, oh, you're
just such sought after it.
I'm just like,
I'm talking about nothing.
But some of my favorites were in Chicago.
Do going to the weigh ins and then like,
let's go to the show and then
just junk drive in with clay.
Guido am like, I'll drive
you just, it's his city,
it's his city. And he's like,
come with me. We're like, okay.
And you white knuckling,
holding onto the front seat
as he's swerving with a
brown paper bag drives like
he fights and I'm just
like, I accept that.
So either way cause it mattered and
he would just go and for it on these
highways that he knows and then I
believe the rain and it was just like,
I was just like so fun.
Yeah.
Another one that I remember
early on early on, John Jones,
he wasn't anything then. It's four
and oh, maybe something like that. Um,
meeting him, uh, talking about shit,
and I could talk about this now because
it's not no longer a banned substance in
the UFC, but like, uh, talking about
weed and was like, yo, let's smoke bro.
He wasn't anything, it wasn't anything.
And just going like, he was like,
who's got wait, am I, oh,
Rogan's got a piece in his hotel
room and texting you flip phone,
texting you back when it wasn't cool.
You don't have to have like hip to
have a flip phone where it was like,
that's all anybody had. That's
how long ago. And then just go on.
Like maybe it's that, maybe it was early,
uh, iPhone, but like just going, hey man,
are you up? And you're like, yeah, I'm
kind of and go to sleep. And was like,
Fuck John, I think he's doesn't want us up
there. And then be like, no, no, let's go.
He's got the weed. Let's go. Because
some fan gave it to us, right?
You had this fucking like
tin foil of weed and um,
and just knock on your door and you're
like, what? And you're like, uh,
you were retired. And it was like, um,
do you have that? We'd like to come on,
I want to go to sleep, man. John, when the
smoke and you're like, you looked at us,
who opened the door fully looked at me
and this young fighter and you were like,
come on in.
And we all smoked pot together and this
hotel room and fucking wherever it was,
I think Montreal, Ashley's Montreal.
Yeah. Yeah. And it just a fun time.
And then seeing this guy move on to
become the baddest motherfucker on the
planet. But we also had a
conversation with him about, I was,
I wanted him to go to a different camp.
That's right.
He was training in fucking youtube
videos in New York with his buddies in a
garage. You too. Good. I'm Mike, you
should be in a real cash. That's right.
We had that over weed in a
hotel room. He's like, you
really think so. I go, I know.
So I know. I go, you only have a
certain amount of time in this thing.
I go and your time should be
invested with a real coach.
Who's going to hone your skills. I go,
you, you can be an all time. Great man.
Wow. Yeah, I remember telling him that
and he's like, you really think so. I go,
I know. So I know. So you,
you really got to move on.
I forgot about that part
of how influential was that
in the fucking future of
mixed martial arts. So I hope it helped.
You know, he did. He went to Winkle,
John a hunk, uncle junk eventually.
I mean, he'd probably be what?
We might've done it anyway.
He might, who knows? But, uh,
I think it was a good conversation to have
with a young guy. You know, I was like,
listen man, you, you,
you, you have real talent.
Like you could really be something,
but you gotta be,
you gotta be coached by guys who are
going to find out your tendency technique
isn't worth, isn't going to go take
you that far. Well, I mean fucking,
he was so good. Who knows how far
he might've been a world champion,
even with the camp that he was in.
He's so good and his wrestling is so
powerful and he's so physically talented,
but it made a big difference for him to
go to Jackson's and be able to train on
a regular basis with world class fighters
being there on a daily basis with
Carlos condit who is, you know,
at the top of his game back then.
And I mean Keith Jardeen
and they just had a massive,
they had ruined tailors,
the,
they called it the ring of fire where
you would go five rounds of sparring with
to get ready for a fight with
a different high level. I mean,
highest level fighter.
So like Nate Marquardt like cool.
That was around one get out of here at
Giardia and you come in and now I just
finished a fucking route and they'd walk
quite now I got go with kicked Jardeen
cool. Round three charge didn't get out
Jon Jones who come in and it's like, what?
I mean the training you got
there. Correct. Johnson's
camp. We're like, well yeah.
I mean look,
there's a reason why so many extremely
high level fighters are coming out of
there. And then Rashad
Evans was there as well too.
And Rashad had a real problem with John
Coming there because Rashad was like,
hey, this guy's in my weight class, but
what are you going to do? I have one guy,
he's way class. Right. It's an
issue. Yeah. And then, you know,
Rishad and John became friends.
They did fight. Is that they would,
yes, they fought and John beat the shit
out of him. I don't even remember that.
They thought after they had a big falling
out because Rashad was upset that,
you know, John Wound up, John
Wound up getting a title shot, uh,
and beat shogun because were shod,
got injured.
Rashad was supposed to get the title shot,
John Steps in and they were friends at
the time and then somewhere along the
line then the trash talk started,
you know, I'll fight Rashad, fuck it.
And then it was like, man, I thought
we were friends and then, oh yeah,
that's back when it was like, you know,
you guys can fight as front and center,
but you don't have to like be at enemies.
Everybody fight.
It's a sport and it's a money thing.
And then when John beat him,
it was a real drubbing
and it was a five rounds.
It was a decision and uh,
it was a real clear cut,
unanimous decision. He did some crazy shit
to him, like step in elbow to the face.
I kind of do remember this one now,
and this was John when he was developing,
John Wasn't even John,
like the John that knocked out DC.
I remember him when he sang it in fights
that I didn't really ever see this
where the fighters, where he would talk
about after wins, talking about the holes,
the fuck ups he had more than the,
what he did right was most guys would
be braggadocious, but I love that I did,
but it was like he was upset at
things that went wrong. Yeah,
I guess I got to cover that up.
That could get exposed. You know,
John's a fucking smart data,
me as reckless and chaotic
as he is. And you know,
I've said this before that I don't know
what causes that kind of recklessness,
but there is a direct correlation
between traumatic brain injury,
brain damage, and impulsive behavior
and recklessness. It's a fact.
It's well researched.
It's well documented in neuroscience.
They know that this, this
is a, there's a connection.
I don't want to exonerate
him from his past behavior,
but we see that in football players,
we see that and BMX riders that go crazy
and fucking land on their head a bunch
of times. People, they get crazy. Wow.
They get wild and impulsive and it's just
a fact. It's just a part of the game.
You know, they, they,
those people that engage in any kind of
an activity where you bring gets rattled
on a regular basis,
you are way more likely to do ridiculous
things that don't make any sense. Yeah,
it does. It's what I said about John. Have
you talked to John about it? You know,
um,
and you know,
I know John was upset with me after one
of those things before we actually did a
podcast together. He was upset and
I said, listen, man, I have to be.