You're an asshole though. Thank you. I
appreciate it. You're a very nice guy.
You're just conservative. That's the
dirty little secret though. Yeah.
We're not supposed to do what
not supposed to talk about that,
but this is one of the things that
bothers me so much about you being so
misrepresented. When I read things
about you, there was a, the,
the article that we were just talking
about, the outright sage without the rage,
they called you and you're not
even remotely alt right. In fact,
you were the leading target of antisemitic
abuse for all of 2016 weren't you on
learning to the Anti Defamation
League, which is no LMI and so, yeah,
I mean I'm not only am I not all right,
I've spent the last four years like
legitimately battling the alt right,
talking about how evil,
I think their ideology is,
how evil I think white supremacy
is. I mean, first of all,
like people at the Yarmulke is typically
not the favorites of the outright.
And then beyond that,
I mean I think their
ideology is legitimately a
devastatingly awful twist on
what Western civilization is supposed
to be as amazing as a review of my new
book and my new book has several sections
and they're dedicated to how terrible
the outright is.
And then the interview they did with me
doesn't talk about outright stuff at all,
but they just assume I'm
on the conservative, right?
That must mean that I am
outright and it's like, no,
you stupid to say no problem with
no labels. They're disingenuous.
People are labeling people in a very
simple manner to try to categorize them as
the enemy and instead of
just addressing these points,
like I love watching your debates where
you do Q and A's with college students
and with people in the audience because
you can see you agree with you or
disagree with who you have
well formulated ideas.
This isn't just some bullshit
that you're spouting out.
You thought these things through.
I mean,
I've been doing this for legitimately
more than half of my life.
I'm 35 and I started when I was 17 and
I started writing a syndicated column at
that point and when you're 17 you think
a lot of dumb stuff and then sure you
get older and you educate yourself and
you spend a lot of time reading and a lot
of time studying.
Hopefully you have some cogent arguments
after 20 years of doing anything and
then, but it's the demonization
is pretty astonishing.
But we had an on Andrew Yang,
he's the only Democratic candidate who
has agreed to go on the Sunday special
that I do. We did a full hour
on ubi. It was perfectly nice.
It was perfectly coherent and and,
and conciliatory and yet people will
suggest that everything I do is about
destroying people on the other side
because of all the Ben Shapiro destroys
videos and all that kind of stuff.
There are certain groups of people
where that's their shtick there.
Like they're goons, right? They just go
after people online for attention. Yes,
this is a stick.
This is not you.
And this is what bothers me so much and
I know that you've said some things in
the past like particularly about Arabs
and like when you were a younger man that
you said, I shouldn't have said
that. Yeah, that's exactly right.
That's exactly right. Some of those
things were taken out of context.
Like that one particular tweet,
which is a bad tweet,
was a tweet that was
part of a tweet threaten,
which has specifically contrasting Israel
and the Hamas leadership and saying
that the Israeli government likes to build
and the Hamas leadership would prefer
that their citizens live in sewage and
bomb things. But that was a bad tweet.
Obviously my entire history on,
on Muslim relations is one I like.
I supported the ability of Ilhan to
where he job on the, on the floor.
I opposed. President Trump's
originally proposed Muslim ban, uh,
in the last three weeks
I've had on of Nawaz,
I've had on a contact
med I had on yesterday,
a reformed Muslim. Like
these are conversations that
have to be had, but to take,
this is one of the things
that bugs me so much. I've,
I've tweeted I think 140,000 times
I've written millions of words.
I'm sure you can find something. I don't
even remember having written it is bad.
I have a running list, by the way.
I try to be honest about this. I,
I'm one of the only people I know who has,
I have a running list it's called.
So here's a giant list of all the
dumb stuff I've ever done. Right?
And I actually go through all
this. You like, you can look it up.
This is not me saying this now.
I mean,
you can go and look up all the
things that I think I've done wrong,
and I'll apologize for some,
and I'll say somewhere dom,
and I'll say some I'm fine with,
and you're just taking out of context.
But I mean that, I hope that's
what honest people try to do,
but does, this is the problem. You're
not dealing with. Honest people would,
when people try to categorize
you as outright or they're,
they're trying to put you into this
category of Internet goon. There they in,
they did quote tweet.
There's taking some little tiny phrase
you said seven years ago and trying to
say, this is you, this is, you know, it's
so that's such a disingenuous thing to do.
I hate it.
And I hated across the aisle by the way,
like I was a defender of James Gunn.
I thought James Gunn shouldn't have
been fired from guardians of the galaxy.
Yeah. Over the old tweets about that.
They were just dumb jokes. Right?
That's exactly right.
Yeah.
And even if somebody tweeted
something bad like 10 years ago,
bringing it up now is not an attempt to
actually make the public space better.
And you're not actually
offended by that thing.
The person tweeted 10 years ago that you
didn't notice what it is that you want
to get rid of this person
or hurt this person.
So you're going to bring up something
from 10 years ago and then you're going to
try and club them into submission with it.
Because if you actually ask
them their opinion about it,
they might have a more nuanced
view on what they said.
Maybe they apologize and they,
maybe they think,
I don't even remember saying that. Right.
I mean, I, I felt the same way by the way.
I try to be consistent.
I really do about about this stuff.
I said the same thing about,
for example, Ralph Northam,
the governor of Virginia who is excoriated
for having this terrible racist photo
on his yearbook page back in
medical school in 1987 and
people were saying, well,
this is evidence he's racist
now. It's like, well no,
that's evidence that he was doing a
racist thing then that's not evidence that
he's racist now.
You sort of have to look over the broad
course of his career and he ended up
doing what everyone now does,
which is you just don't
apologize for anything.
You just try to pass it off as nothing.
The public space is actually getting
worse because let's say that you did
something bad in the past.
There are a few human responses to,
I did something I don't like in the past.
Human response number one is,
you know what? I apologize.
That was wrong these days.
That gets your face step done, right?
You say, I apologize, I was wrong.
It means what? Why did you do it in the
first place? Because you're a bad person.
Apologies are not accepted.
And then number two is you brazen it out.
You do the Trump. You know what?
I never did anything wrong, ever.
I've never perfect right?
And that,
and then you get your defenders to come
and surround you and then nothing ever
gets cleansed or opportunity. Number
three is you do what Barack Obama did,
which is you come out preemptively and
you try to remember all the bad stuff you
do and then you confess it in public in
dreams from my father. He says, right?
Well you know when I was back in high
school did a little blow. Everyone's like,
oh, okay, so you did cocaine when he
was in high school. That's, that's cool.
Whereas if it comes out during the
campaign, right, it's stone, right?
Then he's got that he's got a real
problem. The problem is that right now,
even if you preemptively come out
and say, I did something wrong. Like,
for example,
Liam Neeson talking about years ago when
he had a racist thought that he didn't
act on when he had a racist thought,
this is now we're going to try and ruin
your career for something that you admit
was bad that you did 30 years ago.
We're going to try and run you over that.
If you apologize for something
that you did 30 years ago,
which you would have preferred,
just got forgotten because it
was embarrassing and stupid,
then we say you're bad.
And so all you're left with is like the
most shameless people in the world who
are in the public space,
right? The incentive structure
is to be deeply shameless,
to just say, yeah, man, I own that.
And it was great when I said it,
or I didn't say it at all. And
you're just, you're just full of it.
I never said that stuff. Oh, who are
you gonna believe your eyes are me?
And it makes,
it makes for a really bad politics.
Well, it's just this, uh, the culture of,
of going after people for things and
finding any thing to categorize them as
someone who's a viable target. And this
is what I've seen. Thrust your way.
It's like there's nothing
wrong with being conservative.
There's something wrong with
wanting everyone to think
the way you think though.
This is the difference.
Like you,
why would I like that you do is you debate
your points, you state your positions,
you have a philosophy.
And what I don't like is when people try
to pretend that that philosophy is some
somewhat somehow hateful or somehow
regressive or some like your,
that you condemn people for their
thoughts. You, you just, you don't,
this is what I,
not what I see with you.
Well,
I appreciate that and I appreciate the
accuracy because I think that's true.
I mean, I've come out against
virtually every Twitter band,
including people who have personally
targeted me. I've come out against that.
I've come out against
virtually every yeah.
That because what do you,
what are your thoughts about this
idea of d platforming and you know,
this is something that we were just
discussing before the podcast, um,
where the CEO of Youtube and
it's Kara Swisher's from recode,
I think Kara Swisher.
They were talking about removing you
from Youtube and I thought it was the CEO
of Youtube. It was Eric, actually.
Kara who said I would if I could.
Yeah, she tests because her son apparently
listens to. That's kind of funny. Yeah.
If she's being funny saying
it, but it was, it would,
I thought it was the CEO of you
to, she was trying to
get much more disturbing.
I was trying to do the same thing that
they do with you or with Dave Rubin or
Jordan Peterson,
which is that anybody who
is sort of heterodox because
in that group I think I'm
the only registered Republican ever.
Anybody who's Heterodox is now
being explored, trained as a docs,
meaning just thinks differently from kind
of the down the line Democratic Party
platform. You're not like
down the line with Hillary.
Like Sam Harris is a democrat.
Sam Harris's Heterodox because he
disagrees that Islam is by necessity a
religion of peace, for example. Right?
Or he thinks that we have to look at
actual statistics in order to make
evidentiary based about
discrimination and disparity,
and this makes him an enemy of people
like as reclined@vox.com right.
Th this sort of stuff. They then say that
you are a feeder for white supremacy.
Right. They, they, they can't actually
get you on what you say. Yeah.
So it turns into, well, you know, some
members of your audience do things that,
that are really bad. It's like, well dude,
I have like millions of people
who are members of my audience.
I have 5 million Facebook followers.
I have 2 million on Twitter and
you're way bigger than I am.
I assume that some of those
people are going to be crazy.
I mean, yeah, I would assume.
Yeah. The idea that your respect,
well this is what youtube tried to do.
You know about the comment thing where
the youtube was going to try to make
people responsible for the
comments and their videos,
which what is a normal Jamie?
Like a normal video that we get.
How many comments does it get?
I don't know, like 10,000.
That's like an average one.
How the fuck
am I supposed to have some dude with
his itchy trigger finger standing by in
front of a keyboard, just waiting
for something offensive to pop up.
And this was in response to something
that happened with them where there was
pedophiles who are watching videos of
children doing things and they were
commenting stuff in the,
you know,
like the children's gymnastics
and stuff like that.
They're commenting and like communicating
with each other through the comments.
And it was sort of, um,
discovered that there was this,
this connection that they
were doing this and many,
many videos and youtube rightly
panic. They're like, Holy Shit,
we have to stop this.
So the response,
I guess was we just have to make
people responsible for their comments.
Someone said, oh yeah, good idea. I
didn't think through it at all. Right?
Certain people that
can't do that. Yes. It's
totally insane. And it's insane. And
in virtually every respect. And it's,
it's funny how it's only applied kind of
by the media on one side of the aisle.
So to take an example,
the congressional baseball shooting
happens a couple of years ago.
Guy Happens to be a Bernie Fan, is that
Bernie Sanders is fault, right? No,
that is not Bernie Sanders as
well, in a way. Right. Literally,
people stopped talking about it and
that was shooting of legislators,
like elected people. One nearly
died and that kind of went away.
We didn't talk about, you
know, Bernie's responsibility,
but there's a shooting in Christ church
and it's Jordan Peterson's fault. Yeah.
And Jordan Peterson has no relationship
with the shooter whatsoever.
It's my fault.
I have no relationship with the shooter
ended now to everything that that piece
of crap stands for.