The Joe Rogan experience.
That dad is a,
a really interesting breakdown that maybe
that is one of the big mistakes we're
making in our culture.
When people point to the problems
that we have in this country.
One of the problems we have is our
inability to connect with each other or to
recognize that a,
we're all sharing this space and time
together and instead wanting to uphold our
own religious or ideological ideas as
being the only one way to get going.
Yeah. The only one way to get through.
And one of the things that I've found,
these psychedelic experiences,
it really makes ideologies seem,
uh,
if not preposterous,
at the very least insignificant
in comparison to human
experiences. Absolutely.
The experience of, of comradery
and friendship and, and love it.
You realize like, oh, this
is what's important. This is
not enforcing your ideas are pushing them
on other people and forcing people to
behave the way you behave,
but instead love,
I'm thinking about religious ideas,
which caused so much division,
so much chaos, so much
hatred, so much fear, so much
suspicion in the world today.
Um,
is it really what we want to do as human
beings simply to accept a package of
ideas that were believed in by our
ancestors to accept them whole without
question as absolute fact,
which we regard as such a Thursday.
The fact that in some cases we're willing
to be deeply unpleasant to people who
hold different views or perhaps even
killed them. Uh, we've had this, you know,
this recent event in, in, in,
in Sri Lanka primarily a religiously
motivated terrorist event.
It happens,
it happens all over the world,
that people feel so convinced that the
inherited package of ideas that they had
nothing to do with creating and
that they have never questioned.
They're so convinced that
those ideas are right,
that in extreme cases they are actually
prepared to kill other human beings who
hold different ideas. They are,
they so insecure in their own,
in their own beliefs that,
that they're prepared to go to that
level of actually murdering another human
being halted.
They're so threatened by the other
beliefs that other human beings hold.
So it's an abnegation of our
responsibility as human beings.
We should be questioning things.
We should not be accepting
packages of ideas intact,
fully formed and using them to drive
the way we behave towards one another.
That was part of the human story, but
we need to move on from that. I mean,
it's a very dangerous
situation in a very complex,
modern world with billions of human beings
on the planet to have these kinds of
energy's being generated where
certain groups of people are saying,
we are absolutely right and you are
absolutely wrong. We are superior.
You are inferior. This is a very,
very dangerous path that we're,
that we are on and it needs to be changed.
Personally,
I know this is not a comment that
will go down well with many people,
but I am strongly opposed to nationalism.
I don't,
I don't see any virtue in nationalism.
It is an accident of birth,
which nation you are born in. It was
nothing that you did for your own merit.
You didn't earn that you born by
accident in, in a particular nation.
Why should we automatically feel the
other people who were born by accident in
that particular nation has
something special in common with us.
And that we together are a group who are
much more important than other groups
of people. I've been privileged to spend
my life traveling around the world,
living with communities all over,
over the world.
And one thing that really comes
across to me strongly, it's, it's,
it should be a cliche and yet it's not,
is that we are all one family,
that humans are intimately
interconnected all around the world.
That you can go to the remotest area
of the Amazon jungle and find the same
hopes, the same fears, the same dreams
that we have in industrialized cities,
shared by the hunter gatherers in
the, in, in the middle of the Amazon.
So our similarities as human beings and
what we share in common at the emotional
level and the level of love and at the
level of heart are far more important
than our differences that are defined
by the nation or the political group in
which we, in which we grew up in. And when
I, when I say I'm against nationalism,
I need also to make
clear that does not mean,
and I hope I'm not taken out of context
by others who are listening to this.
That does not mean I'm in favor of
world government. I detest governments.
That's another thing we need to grow out
off. We don't need governments anymore.
If we have them, they should have
a very minimal role in our society.
I think it's possible for the human race
to relate as one family without leaders
and governments who are exploiting
the worst aspects of our character,
the lowest common
denominator of our society.
Deliberately encouraging theaters
and hatreds and suspicion.
What responsible leaders should be doing
is encouraging love and unity and their
failure to do that.
In my view disqualifies them from the
leadership role entirely and that's why
I've often said I would not,
I would like to see a situation in which
no head of state can be appointed to
that position unless he or she has
first had 12 sessions of Iowasca.
That would be the condition.
Don't even bother applying for
the job if you haven't done this,
and we have to be there where you have it.
We have to be,
we want to see that you're
drinking every drop.
And we wanted an
experience Shumon presence,
who's really going to guide you
through the, through the journey.
And I suspect that that would be a
transformative experience for many of our
political class, and that they would start
to question why they do what they do,
why they exploit theories in order
to magnify their own position.
They'd start to question that and to
wonder about a different destiny for
humanity. But that's a dream, I guess
it's not going to happen, is very, very,
very well said.
Yeah.