Death grip. Yeah. Those guys, which brings
us to the last fight, man. Perfect. Yeah,
that's correct. Yeah. That Ben asked her
if I, dude, I watched that fight. Uh,
I've watched that finish like 10 times
trying to figure out what happened or
whether it was out or
whether he wasn't out.
I was pretty convinced that at one point
in time he went out and then Kamara
loose man changed my mind.
Come on.
Munch showed the that we watched the video
tape together. He's like, no, no, no.
He's giving a thumbs up. And I'm
like, Shit. Yeah. Okay. So I'm still,
cause the angles I've seen
haven't been the best.
I'm trying to see this thumbs up.
Was the thumb going up or with the thumb
in a thumbs up position going this way?
Right? Like on the, as the arm
drops was the coming of the, okay.
So when I give somebody a thumbs up,
like let's say somebody wanted a job,
you want this job, buddy,
good job. That's it.
That's what I want to do. You know? So
I mean, I don't know. Like, I mean, I,
so what I'm saying,
nobody's going to know whether he was
conscious or unconscious. What I saw,
I saw everything that would indicate
I'm seeing that unconscious fighter.
I see an arm go limp for
no reason whatsoever.
And so that's what I'm,
that's what I'm have to work with
because that's what, you know,
we don't know what someone's feeling
whenever we just see if they're doing
something that doesn't make sense and
you see an arm go limp at that time,
you're going to assume that the person's
unconscious. We assumed it. Yeah.
As the broadcast team,
we can hear you guys and that I'm
supposed to do certain things and like,
so here's the thing with that choke,
when I'm refereeing fights, you know,
there's sometimes where you know,
some positions or anxiety like uh,
you know,
you see two guys going after leg locks,
you see a noodle mess of legs
and you know, you got to,
you're going to have to help one guy out
and figure out who's tapping and make
sure you're on the right home. When I
see some chokes, a rear naked choke,
especially the guy in the back face up.
I took a sigh of relief.
My job just got so much
easier. This guy, you know,
it's not like he's going to
go out and then a second,
take some extreme amount of damage.
He may go out,
I'll have a second to make sure you're
not even a second or half a breath and
make sure he's okay
and then let it go out.
And he's not gonna take any other damage.
A bulldog choke.
We have anytime you have a choke where
somebody where there's pressure on the
neck and they're spinning, been in the
c spine backwards like that, that's a,
that's a rough situation for me.
So I see someone go limp and
I know that on top of it,
they're no longer putting tension on
their neck and their neck is just being
bent. I can't, I, you know,
I can't see that I should do something
different than that because that's the,
um, I like to talk to people about
this. I'd like to talk to people,
have opinions about fights,
especially people who are interested in
who they know what they're talking about.
Um,
because if I always have a situation,
if I always have been mindset that
I'm always doing the right thing,
I can't get better. So I'm going to have
to look at something and say, is there a,
you know,
a teachable moment there.
Is there a way I can learn from this
and is there a way I could do something
different? And No, I don't think,
I think with that same situation with the
arm going limp with type of a choke on
someone, I don't know of a defense that
requires the arm. You know what I mean? I,
I would think the arms should
be doing something else. I,
at this time, I don't, um,
I don't see that I should do
something different. You know,
I'm always interested in
always looking and always,
I love these types of conversations, but
right now I can't think of, you know,
and they sell you something. It was an
amazing fight. It was. Yeah, it was.
It wasn't, I mean, first of
all was the first time I seen,
I'd refereed been asking, I don't think
I'd refereed him before. And you know,
when you're in his PR, his pressure is
something special. It's not the normal.
And uh,
the way Robbie dealt with it and Robbie
had him and he hadn't been trouble.
You know, I was so close to stopping that
fight when they're on the ground. Yeah.
So many times. Yeah. Yeah.
With some bombs. Yeah.
The amount of respect I have for those
two athletes, man is like, so that's,
so that's the thing is,
you know,
we never want to see anything that
could make you have a feeling that it's
inconclusive, but I can't think
of what else I should have done.
But you know, I mean, especially for that,
that fight for those two guys, you know,
you always want it. Yeah. The people
would have a feeling of conclusion there.
Well, when we talked about on the phone,
when you brought up the, the damage,
the possible damage to the
neck with the bulldog choked,
he might be cutting off nerves and
you might be bending the spine in a,
in a kind of a fucked up way. I really
hadn't considered that when, uh,
when I was thinking of the choke
when he grabbed hold of him,
I was just thinking it was a blood choke.
But you're right.
Like the way you lean in on a
bulldog choke, you lean back. Yeah.
That's a lot of pressure on
the neck. I've, I've had,
uh, some chokes where there,
uh, I've, I've refereed a fight where
a guy did one of these moves. I would,
you had to move for it. Uh,
a technique where he's been
in the spine, back twister.
It wasn't a twister, um, that I
think guys have a name for it.
You probably know what the execution
or is. So that's what it was.
That's what it is. That kind of
explain it. Explaining to people the,
what that is is like if a guy is
a turn not to cut you off. Okay.
So for so long I've never really wanted
to talk about it because people weren't
doing it. This was years ago, I saw
it. But now if there's a name for it,
I guess it's okay. But you hadn't seen
a lot of people doing it before, right?
Well we,
uh,
we started doing it in 10th
planet a few years back. It's,
I think people have done it.
What it is basically folks,
it's like a guillotine from the back.
Um,
it's like taking a re you ever
like rear naked choke cooks,
but instead of choking guide this way,
which is how you would do it,
which is a wrap your form underneath his
neck and wrap the other arm behind his
head. Instead of doing that, you wrap
your arm all the way around the front,
like a guillotine hold,
but from the back and you
have ungodly leverage, right?
It's ungodly. How much pressure
you can put on someone's neck.
And our friend Scott Epstein, he, uh,
he used quite a few times. So we called
it the executioner. Is that it there? Oh,
I'm trying to find a picture of one.
I know this is the execution or
choke. This is a different, oh,
he calls it the executioner.
I looked that up and nothing came up.
I think I might have a have a heavy
here for you to something like this.
This is a little different. This
guy had arms in, this is different,
but it's similar. Yeah. It's
similar though. Similar.
Yeah. You could have arms in,
yeah. That's the same thing. Yeah.
This is it. That's 100%. So, um,
I dunno, we're going to show
people that. Right. Either way.
It's a real bad place to be in this
guy. Got It. Yeah. That's okay.
That's Scott Epstein. That's the north
shore south choke on it or is that, uh,
but what he would do if he wanted to do
an execution or is he would get his hips
underneath the guy and get back position.
This is just a really good,
uh, north south chose. So yeah.
So what I saw was the guy who
went north, south, and he, uh,
this was years ago at a king of
the cage and way out in Wisconsin,
and he had a, wow, this was a
long, long time ago. He had north,
south and he sat up once he had the guy,
he sat up and pulled the guy's body up
onto him and almost a sitting position
and then put hooks.
And then I've done it before where you
all rolled the guy to the side and I'm
just to walk it through and
figure out how it worked. Um,
he put hooks and I was sitting there,
I was like, okay, this is an illegal,
if I stop this fight, it's not, you
know, or this nun an illegal move,
but I don't want to
see how this plays out.
And the guy got one hook in and almost
the second hook was about to go in.
The guy tapped and when I pulled him off,
the guy couldn't move.
His neck was fucked up. Yeah.
He couldn't move. Uh, you know,
you got some sort of standard, I don't
know what's going on. He was, he was,
he couldn't move. He was terrified.
I was terrified. And, uh,
then it kind of, you know, uh, came
back and came back. Yeah. Jesus.
Yeah.
I know of several guys that have
gotten paralyzed because of a defense,
um, from a guillotine or trying to take
a god down when the ride. Yeah. You know,
when someone gets you to the team.
Yeah. I've heard of that. Yeah. So,
so that's why with some, uh, submissions,
you know, especially some of the jokes,
it's like, okay, a things
are slowing down and okay,
things are going a little bit easier for
me with that when things are not easy
at all. That's not something
that I want to, um, I want
to play with. I think if, uh,
you know, I'm kind of disappointed with
some, some of people have a platform,
I don't want to mention any names,
but some people have a platform
of kind of tossed it out.
It was something sensational and say,
Oh, look at this, there's, he'd wrong or,
right. I think that's a little
irresponsible when it's some, uh,
dangerous techniques like that.
Well,
I think you've really pointed that out
about the neck and a very important where,
and I think that's something that people
should really take into consideration.
When you see someone,
you've seen people, uh,
have you ever referred someone
who got caught in a twister? Yeah.
It's a horrible place to be. Yeah.
Dot. So it's a horrible place to be.
It's so your,
your neck is fucked up and there's so
much pressure and the fact that you're,
that you're left legs isolate and your,
your head's getting pulled to the,
it feels like it's going to break.
It's a fun place to be.
Even for the fact of the way it's
set up because it's not like it's,
it's not like a fast thing that catches
you off guard. It's a long road to it.
Yeah. So you know what's going on,
you know it's coming and you're like,
I'm doing this, but I know how
this is going to probably end.
And you're doing some little diff.
Yeah.
There's a chance on Joan Korean Zombie.
I think he got the first
ever one on Leonard Garcia.
I think that was the first to look
at that and so horrible, dude,
that is so that it's so bad.
That feels so terrible. Yeah.
And that's,
uh,
he then there's def con four when you
take a rear naked choke grip from the
twister position. Oh yeah.
Okay. Yeah, I've seen that.
Just you just rip and dude's heads
cleaned off. It's a horrible, you know,
those all those crazy like catch
wrestling, neck manipulation.
Right, right, right.
Those things to make my, my
neck hurt, just looking at
him. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So anyway. Yeah, that's,
that's why I think, you know,
you can't always say look at things
as good or bad, but you know,
some situations I've seen referees in
and that one I think is a difficult
situation. Not so I've seen other harder
situations, but you know what I mean,
like, yeah. It's an
unusual one. Yeah. I mean,
we've seen quite a few bulldog chokes
that, uh, put someone on conscious. Uh,
most recently, uh, Raquel Pennington
against Ashley. Evan Smith. Crazy,
crazy fight for cal Pennington. So
fucking tough. I mean that was just,
that was a crazy fight, man.
It was just war and chaos.
And then with like one second to go,
she chokes her out and then lets her go.
And she's um,
she's asleep from the bulldog choke and
Ashley Evan Smith steps up covered in
blood. I mean it's fucking
crazy. That was crazy.
But there's that one.
Um,
didn't Chris Lights out Lidell
catch Tki in a bulldog choke?
I think he did for us. If we're
going to Carlos Newton. That's the,
that's the title. Yeah. That's the the,
yeah, that one that looked really tight.
Yeah. Go forget that. Go to, yeah,
that's the one road a Carlos Newton
chokes out pat Miletich cause this was for
the title and he caught him in
a bulldog choking and it's like,
that was what that was.
I don't think we had a name for it.
I think we used to call it a
school yard headlock, but yeah.
Then somebody called it a
bulldog choke at that time.
I remember people were calling it
bulldog trail. Oh. Like they are,
it already had that. And I don't know
if it had there. Maybe they gave it to,
but yeah, it's a legit move.
Like it's a legit move. Like if,
especially if you're a bad ass grin
type dude with that kind of grip on
someone's neck in that
position. Yeah. Horrible. Yeah.
That was, um, that's why I
say that referees have the
hardest job because you're,
you're in that situation. You do have
to take those things into consideration.
What kind of damages is doing this guy's
neck? Is he out? His arm went limp. Okay.
When do I stop? I gotta get, I gotta
save him. Like, yeah, no, that,
that is the tough part about it. You
know, you were evaluating a is always,
there's different,
you know,
and you're evaluating a threat
to the person you're evaluating.
If there's a threat coming, you how
much, how well can they deal with it?
There's a lot of stuff going on there
and you know, we take it really serious.
I take it really serious. It's
a, to me it's, um, it's a,
I feel that I have a sacred trust.
I feel that it's one of these
positions that like, um,
our athletes are not stupid people.
A lot of them could be doing a lot of
things with their life and they've chosen
this path to a,
and they take time from their family.
They take time away from other careers
where they can be progressing and all to
meet their dreams and hopes. And I
need to balance that with their safety.
So it's something I think about a lot.
You know what I mean? I'm, I'm, uh,
even in the way, uh, I talked
to my friends, you know
what I mean? To always, uh,
you know, I, I'm always on, I'm
always working as a referee.
Anytime I'm out in the streets or with
friends, people are going to ask me,
what do I think about this fighter?
Who Do I think can be better? And I,
because of his job you're doing, you
don't longer have the luxury of having,
you know,
of talking about mixed martial arts in
the fun way about who's going to win and
how's this going to happen?
Because who knows?
I might referee the fight and everyone's
going to be on the Internet like hers
referee in the fight and
we're having beers yesterday.
And guess what he told me?
Right. So, yeah, it's just, you
know, so yeah. I take it serious. No,
you do it. I'm glad you have
that attitude. What does
this one right here? Oh yeah,
this is Carl is Carl is
right here. Yeah. Yeah.
In the transition he grabs the neck
and it's a crazy visual too because the
photograph, the fruits eat
right there, right there.
I mean that is crazy muscles and
Carlos's arm and shoulder and neck.
That caused student champion of the world
right there.
That moment in that crazy,
Carlos had some spectacular grappling,
real merrily on man while transition.
He was amazing. [inaudible] Jitsu.
His uh, his, his explosiveness is agility.
I mean, he was just, he was so athletic.
He was doing stuff that no one knows.
Yeah. He also had a really high level,
a submission game early
on when like in 96, 97,
a lot of people didn't have that kind of
a game in his submission game was tight.
The Matt Hughes one was crazy. I remember
that. Yeah. Yeah. That was crazy. That a,
catch him in a triangle choke where he
had him up and he's, yeah, that was,
he puts him to sleep. And
as they get up, Matt Hughes,
like you, here's car and her saying like,
stand up, you won. You won. He's like,
what happened? Yeah, yeah, they'll
double knockout. Yeah, I have that one.
I have one of the king of
the cage, a double knockout.
Those right here. This is,
look how God takes him strong used was,
he was so fucking strong
that builds them up there
and Carlos is trying to, so
he's, he's, he's squeezing,
squeezing. So Matt goes
unconscious, he's out cold,
he doesn't know what's going on and no
one knows what's going on and they get,
they,
so Carlos has head hit the ground when
he went down like that and then knocked
him out. Right, right, right. And then
Matt up from the choke and they're like,
you won. Yeah, it's great.
That was a crazy scene that, that
scene was a tough one. I was like,
what do you do there?
Yeah,
well that was like the thing about
this Robbie Lawler Pan African fight,
like Uconn was saying,
they got to run it back and I was like,
it wouldn't be a bad thing to run it back.
I mean, well, at the same time, you know,
we gotta be honest here,
like as far as running back,
how many of the fights is
that happened in the UFC?
Are there because it's exciting
what people want to see. Yeah, most,
right. So Brock Lesnar DC
is a perfect example, right?
So that's exciting as
people want to see it.
And some of the excitement has been
generated by throwing me under the bus,
but cool. Cool. Cool. The people
at another time, I'm love ticket.
I got [inaudible] you know? But
yeah, no. So yeah, I think, um,
you know, anytime that, you know,
the athletes get to do what they do and
people are going to watch it again and
people are going to be excited
about it, you know, I don't know.