They don't and you know, it's not
there either, you know. And in fact,
I've started to try and lobby doctors
to stop prescribing sleep and don't make
the mistake that that's me suggesting
prescribing sleeping pills,
that's a separate straight sleeping
pills are associated with significantly
higher risk of death and cancer. And,
and I'm happy to speak about that too,
was the one chapter in the
book that I think the um,
the legal team of my publisher took,
took a very long, long look at,
but I think doctors,
to come back to your point,
they on average only have about two
hours of sleep education in the medical
curriculum. So one third, two hours,
two hours, one third of their,
this podcast has been two hours.
Yeah, that's fucking crazy.
And so it's not frightening.
That's terrifying.
And I bet you probably have laid things
out better in this podcast than you
would get in those two hours of education.
I don't know about that,
but I think if I'll give you that credit,
if they could eat,
if they could increase that, you know,
I'm desperately appealing for the senior,
it's a third of their patient's life,
but they only get two hours of education.
But the other problem is the
medical industry itself. By the way,
you know that residents,
that data,
you know at residents working a 30
hour shift of 460% more likely to make
diagnostic errors in the intensive care
unit relative to when they're working 16
hours.
If you have elective surgery,
you should ask your surgeon how much
sleep they've had in the past 24 hours.
If they've had six hours of sleep or less,
you have a 170% increased risk
of a major surgical error,
such as sort of organ damage
or hemorrhaging relative
to that same surgeon if
they had been well rested.
And then the irony here by the way,
is that when a resident finishes,
a 30 hour shift,
gets back into their car to drive home,
there is a 168% increased risk that they
will get into a car accident because of
the under slip seat being ending up back
in the same emergency room where they
just came from. But now as a patient
too, from a car crash, you know, it's,
we need to radically rethink the
importance of sleep in education,
in, in business, in the
workplace and in medicine too.
Why do they do that to residents?
It's a fascinating story. Um,
so there's, there's a chapter
here in the book on this too.
It's a guy called William Holsted and
he set up the first resident surgical
program in the United States at Johns
Hopkins University and he was known for
being able to stay awake for these
heroic lengths of time, days on end.
It was incredible,
like superhuman strength tuns out
that in later years after he died,
there was a dirty secret that he
was actually a cocaine addict.
That son of a bitch. And here's
what happened. It wasn't his fault.
Ellian is Korea.
He was examining the anesthetic
capacities of cocaine.
So you know, if, well I'm
not going to save, you know,
you may have heard from, uh,
perhaps colleagues that when you
snort cocaine you get a numb face.
The reason is because it's, it blocks
nerves. Kay said from colleagues,
my colleagues have told me I've
actually never done cocaine.
I've know quite a few people who
have and they will, you know,
they'll have this sort of numbness.
It's the reason is because cocaine
is also a nerve blocking agent,
like lighter cane, lighter
cane. Exactly. Times about this.
Yesterday ironically on the podcast and
about doctors becoming drug addicts,
the initial doctor's has started doing
light of cane. Holsted was one of them.
He became an accidental cocaine
addict and then he's up for days.
He was up for days and um,
he structured a program where he expected
his residence to match him to go toe
to toe with them. Our, that huge remain.
It sounds like what a coke had would
do, come on and stay away. Unbelievable.
And I think the story was that he
actually knew that there was a problem.
He went to rehabilitation,
checked in under a different
surname and one part of the, um,
regiment for him coming off
cocaine was to prescribe morphine.
And at the end of the
rehabilitation program,
he came out with both the cocaine
addiction and heroin addiction.
And so now there's rumors,
you know,
that he would get his shirts
laundered in Paris, you know,
in France.
And you know,
they would come back and it wasn't
just the white starch, you know,
shirts that were in the box that we were
other whites substances too. But that's,
you know, you ask a great question, where
did that come from? Where's that history?
The legacy seems to date
back to William Holstead,
who is an accidental cocaine addict.
And there we have then maintained
that inhumane practice in medicine,
which is so critical to be
awake and aware and to be sharp.
You're cutting people open,
you're operating on people.
And think back to what we said
about being awake. You know,
you would never accept treatment
from a doctor who started, you know,
looking at your child who's sick with an
appendicitis at three m in the morning,
who then switched some whiskey and says,
yeah, I'm going to do the operation.
That's fine. You would, you
would go ballistic. Well,
why do we accept treatment
after 20 hours of being awake?
You're as impervious.
You would be if you were legally drunk.
So unfortunately we placed young
residents in this position of, you know,
acting and operating and decision making
under conditions of insufficient sleep.
One in five medical residents will
make a serious medical error due to
insufficient sleep.
One in 20 medical residents will kill
a patient because of a fatigue related
error. One in 20 that's
crazy right now, you know,
there are well over 20,000 medical
residents. For a hundred of them,
five were going to kill people, accidental
deaths. Think about that number.
That's insane. If we were to solve the
sleep epidemic in medicine, you know,
we could start saving lives and I don't
know what it is. Is it just a, you know,
an old boys' network where we
say, well we went through it. Yes.
So you've got to go through it. You know,
and there's, the data now is so prolific,
you know, I write it all about that and
try to make a build or an evidence based,
you know, emotionless cold
case for sleep in medicine,
asleep prescription for medicine
as it were. Or most people don't
realize their requirements
that residents have.
No. And, and they are, they
are literally, you know,
beyond human capacity thinking that,
you know,
Hubris and some degree of hours on the
job is going to be able to allow you to
sort of,
you know,
cut short what took three and a
half million years to sort of,
you know,
get in place,
which is an eight hour night of sleep
that's just thick headed. You know, it's,
and I think the medical profession that
may be at the stage where it's my mind
is made up, don't confuse me
with the facts. Wow. That,
that
this is blowing me away.
I just don't understand how the very
people that are working on the health of
patients and fixing them and repairing
injuries and taking care of diseases,
those are the people that are ignoring
one of the primary factors of disease and
errors and cognitive function.
It's impairment.
It's a travesty.
I have a friend who's an ophthalmologist
and he tells a story about during his
residency, he was uh, is, is back
in the 80s and you had a pager.
He was on the toilet with a tray of food
on his lap because he didn't have time
to eat and go to the bathroom.
So as eating food and he fell asleep and
then his pager went off and he's like,
fuck my life.
How many warnings,
how many warning bells do you need to
tell you that you're in a deleterious
state if you use with your trousers
around your ankles, with food or via face.
And yet you're in the deepest stages
of non rem sleep and he's a guy who was
working on people's eyes.
Yeah. It's crazy. Yeah. I mean,
I mean it's,
you know,
sleep is equally absent for the
patient in the hospital setting.
We know that somewhere between 50
to 70% of all ICU alarms are either
unnecessary or ignore bubble,
you know,
and the one place where you desperately
need the Swiss army knife of health,
that is a good night of sleep is the
one place where you get at least,
which is on a hospital ward.
We could,
we could exit people out of hospital
beds early at the data is already there.
For the neonatal intensive care unit,
they used to leave bright lights on 24
seven and that would prevent sort of the
signaling for sleep and
wake and sleep and wake.
And that cycle is critical if
you regularize sleep, sorry.
If you regularize the light in
the neonatal intensive care unit,
those infants ended up having high
levels of oxygen saturation because were
sleeping better,
their weight gain was dramatically
increased and they ended up exiting the
neonatal intensive care unit
five weeks earlier. Whoa.
Simple things. You know, why don't we
do something like this in medicine?
When you come in onto a hospital ward,
you get this on an international flight,
travel for free,
earplugs facemask even just that by
itself could help people to start,
get better sleep.
Next on the hospital admission form.
Tell me when you normally go to
sleep and when you normally wake up.
And to the best of our ability, we as
doctors will try to sort of, you know,
manage your health care around
your natural sleep tendencies.
If we could do that, you know,
sleep is, is the elixir of life.
It is the most widely available democratic
and powerful healthcare system I
could ever possibly imagine. Why aren't
we leveraging that and taking it?
That's one of the greatest hacks that
medicine could actually, you know,
inflect does stunning.
But how's this being received by doctors?
Are they reluctant to listen to you?
I mean, what, what, what is happening
with all this data and you're,
you're passionate cry for extra sleep
or more sleep or the proper sleep,
I should say. It's starting to happen.
I mean, when the book came out,
which was sort of the hub that
came out in back in October and,
and some people started to give push
backs to sort of in the medicine realm,
you know,
there was some concerns about continuity
of care that if you keep switching
residents out every 16 hours that you
wouldn't have continuous patient care.
And that was a problem. Um, well there
are other medical training systems.
For example, France or Sweden, New
Zealand, they do this all the time.
They do not allow their
residents to undergo anything
longer than either a 14 or
a 16 hour shift.
They train their residents in
the same amount of time or less.
And if you look at the rankings of their
medical health systems around the world,
they rank far higher
than the United States.
So you can't tell me that longer work
hours for residents, for example,
on necessary to train good doctors.
The evidence just doesn't support itself,
had some push back there.
But for the most part,
I think people are receptive once they
know the information. And I think I'm the,
I've been someone who's been to blame
here. I've known this evidence for,
you know, I've been doing sleep
research now for 20 or so years.
We are with sleep where we
were with smoking 50 years ago.
We had all of the evidence
about the deathly carcinogenic
cardiovascular disease
issues,
but the public had not been aware where
no one had adequately communicated.
The science of,
you know,
smoking to the public the same I
think is true for sleep right now.
That's part of the motivation
for why I wrote the book,
why I've been doing or trying
to do a lot of publicity.
I'm a very shy person and I don't
like being in the spotlight,
but I feel as though there is a mission
that whose voice has not been actually
gifted yet and I wanted to try and
help them be a sort of asleep diplomat.
I mean that's why I choose
the handle on social media,
trying to be there as
an ambassador for sleep.
And now once people start to understand
the science as we've spoken about for
two hours,
then people start to actually realize
it's not the third pillar of good health
alongside diet and exercise.
It's the foundation on which those two
are the things set. You know, for example,
if you're dieting but you're
not getting sufficient sleep,
70% of all the weight that you
lose will come from lean body,
mass muscle and not fat.
Your body becomes stingy in giving
up its fat when it's under slept.
So once you get this information out
there, things are starting to change.
I've started to have some discussions
with the World Health Organization.
They seem to be very interested now in
getting, getting to grips with sleep.
I love to speak to first
world governments though.
When was the last time you saw any
first world nation have a government
supported public health campaign
around sleep? I don't know any.
We've had them for, you know, drink
driving for risky behaviors, you know,
for drugs, for alcohol,
for healthy eating.
Sleep should be a part of that equation.
You know,
I want to lobby governments to start
to instigate this and it will save them
millions of dollars.
The Rand Corporation did an independent
survey two years ago on the demonstrable
cost of a lack of sleep too,
global economies.
What they found was that a lack
of sleep costs most nations,
about 2% of their GDP, the gross
domestic product here in America,
that number was $411 billion
caused by insufficient sleep,
solve the sleepless epidemic.
You could almost double the budget for
education and you could almost half the
deficit for healthcare.
Wow.