Yeah. You know, Jonah Hill is
training Jujitsu with mag a Henna,
Jonah fucking hill. He's skinny
and shit. He's getting scared.
He'll know much way, got skinny, and
then he felt like his head was too big.
He started gaining weight back. He's
skinny again. He's in great shape.
We realized that's all it was.
Yeah.
That happens to people sometimes because
you know when you get like 400 pounds,
your fucking head gets big. You're dude.
Yeah. Chuck that him. Wait a minute,
is that real head and not touch it?
Taste when you're 20 when you roll
with somebody, he'd go make his face.
Nice clean. Nice man.
Beautiful. Good for him, man.
Because he looks good. He
does a good, well, you know,
if his head's bigger in his body's too
skinny, just get to build your body up.
Let me get the sides of your head.
He's my boy. Josh. Swagger hills,
a very good actor. He's a really
nice guy. He's a great guy.
I met him one night at one day rather at
k rock back when people did radio. Oh,
there's Chen.