The Joe Rogan experience I heard cause
a lot of vitamins in it and some iron.
I can't produce anymore man.
None. They cut off my balls
do to do. I turned him in.
Yeah. What did, what caused you to
turn them in? What was the final straw?
Was this movement downtown La
embarrassed at your own gender? Yeah.
I went to the me too thing and I cut off
my balls and I left him there so I just,
I donated them if you like,
if people started calling for that,
if girls started calling for that,
guys would do it. Remove your nuts.
There's guys out there
that there's a certain,
there's a certain kind of guy that
would do so many people there.
If you called for guys to step out into
the middle of the town square and cut
their own balls off, at least a couple
of guys would show up. I can name two,
two centers we live in.
There's a couple of dudes I know
that would fucking do it exactly.
Just for like Twitter cred. Yeah,
just for some street. I just,
just for the retweets, some
love from feminists. What
this is how you are an ally.
Boys learn like my fed. Like we were
favorite like your favorite shirts.
Yeah. Females kickass or what is it? A
women kick ass or whatever else. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. That whole,
the idea of like, uh, of,
of virtue signaling overt,
overt support for something.
It's so seethrough when you're like,
I'm here for you girls.
It's so seethrough God,
it's such a crock of shit.
But you can feel that way without yelling
at all the time we pull you also like
broadcasting like that. Like what?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
What's the purpose? Yeah, that's what
I like. Why, why are you reaching out?
You're supporting, what do you
supporting? What is happening here?
It's another instance of the echo chamber
doing the whole supporting the thing
that I don't think people are really,
I talk about it on stage about the trend,
a trend,
the word trans phobic over
like I understand the meaning,
but I also think it's hyperbolized and
in essence of like there are these large
groups of people that are against Trans
people. I don't believe that whatsoever.
But there were definitely are.
I think there's small groups of
people that get a lot of attention.
I don't think there's massive look. The
KKK is significantly larger of a group.
Then whatever group you want to formulate
a trans folk of transphobic nature.
I know a lot of people don't
even know what that is. Right.
I haven't done any statistical research.
The company KKK members are in the United
States. There are tens of thousands.
Okay. How many people, what do people do?
I think a trans people religious that
don't believe in trends people or that
don't think that they should be able
to call themselves a woman. I think Mo,
I think most of those people don't care
enough to call themselves part of that
category. They just disagree. They go,
I don't really like it. I don't get it.
I think,
I think there's more of those than
there are people that are like adamantly
against trans rights.
I think we have to take any consideration
what we already said about God's
willing to cut their balls off that
there are guys like that. Sure.
There are some,
there are so many people in this country.
I guarantee you there's a lot of trans
phobic people, a lot. You listen man,
if you read the comments,
and I don't, and I didn't,
but someone told me that the
comments and the Eddie Izzard, uh,
Instagram posts that I made were horrific.
But don't you think that
is an internet fodder? See,
that's my thing is I think people like
to say shit on the Internet even if they
don't believe it, because they know
that gets attention. If they go, fuck,
this fucking dude looks like a chick
that I don't know what they said.
Maybe they were just making fun
of the way you look so you can,
you can assume what fucking people
right on the Internet about that issue.
They would just go, what's up with this?
Fuck. Oh, here. I'll give you an example.
I tweeted the other day about the
met gala, um, Harry styles. Uh,
I tweeted a, uh, he was wearing like a,
a lot of men were wearing like dresses
at the met gala. This was a whole thing.
And I tweeted,
um,
Tilda Swinton looked fire at the met gala
because he looked like Tilda Swinton.
Not because I'm saying like,
who's till the swimming?
She's a fucking actress who has short
hair, right? So, right. That was him.
And I said,
Tilda Swinton looked fire at the met gala.
Who is this gentleman pleaser?
He's a pop star. He's like part of,
what's it called? One direction.
He's part of one direction. What,
what is happening with that shirt?
That's what he wore to the back. Alice,
what'd you say, Jamie? It's a
blouse. Shirts versus blossoms.
Okay. Here's the thing.
If you go into one of those things and
you're going to stand in front of all
these jackasses with cameras
to take pictures of, why
not wear a fucking blouse?
That's what,
that's his point.
But I said Tilda Swinton looked fire
because when I saw the first image,
his face kind of looked like
Tilda Swinton. Okay? Of course,
I'm making the joke about the joke.
You're a comedian. Well, dude,
everyone was like, very funny
last night. Thank you. Thank you.
Everyone went after me. Everyone was like,
oh, of course you fucking, I mean, Hattie,
are you a Nazi? Well, they
say, here's my problem. They
go, um, he, I think he's gay,
right? Did He, is he gay,
Jamie? No, I think somebody
told me they were like alone.
They were like, you're, you're, you're may
you found in your sexuality. I was like,
I can't make fun of people
anymore for people. I said,
t he looked like Tilda fucking swim.
Why are you reading comments?
Because I'm not as famous as you stop
and think about the amount of people that
had their balls by,
no,
that would just walk into that town
square and cut their balls off to the ELA.
Now stop and think about those
people commenting. Yeah, I know.
And you're reading it and allowing
it to fuck with your head.
Sometimes I feed into it. A lot
of times I don't. When do you not?
When I'm confident in whatever I
posted. Hmm. That's interesting. Right?
When I like that joke,
I knew it was going to be misinterpreted.
Like I knew when I wrote that I go,
someone will misinterpret this. Who Care?
That's why I still posted it,
but I read some shit sometimes if I go,
I wonder if that was
dumb or if that was cool.