It's good that you think like this because
clearly you're a very confident guy
and you're obviously successful
and your mixed martial arts career.
But to have just a little bit
of that insecurity is fuel.
It's just like it keeps you sharp.
It keeps you aware. You know,
like to be confident is good. To
be delusional is terrible. Yeah.
100% of terrible.
Everybody knows that one guy that thinks
he can beat a guy that he's not ever
going to fucking be able to be.
You know?
I mean there's a lot of people
like give me that fight you,
hey wait, that's why
you don't see, you know,
you never see me say some outlandish shit.
Like oh I can't never be beat know or oh
I can go out there and you know our bar
Cain Velasquez or something like that.
I mean not meaning to pick on Rhonda,
but I know he was saying, yeah but
you know. But I think you know,
the Rhonda thing, it was, there was a
lot going on there man. Coaching wise,
there's a lot going on there.
What?
She just came along at a time when there
was no one like her when she was a real
Olympic caliber athlete and her
judo was at such a high level.
No one could fuck with him throwing people
around until someone could fuck with
her until she ran into
someone like Holly Holm.
And then then we really saw the holes
in the preparation, the distractions,
the fact that she had, you
know, movie deals going on.
They wanted her to do road house and
she's scripts and this and agent meetings
and all the bullshit man.
It's like a fucking Hollywood.
It was like a Hollywood script.
Like this is what happens to you and
this is how rocky when rocky went soft,
I mean this is literally what happens
and then all of a sudden you've got this
bad ass Holly Holm sitting there ready
to fucking head kick you into another
dimension. And that's what happened.
And like you said, I think,
I think most of it is just trying to
stay aware and I get the delusional about
it cause it's,
it is very easy to kind of slip into
that and fall into that and you know,
sometimes she will hit you.
And that's what happened in my,
in my second fight that I lost,
uh, to, to Leonardo Santos and,
and, and each fight I can
always see myself losing,
you know,
and people ask me that and they were like,
you talk about all this
visualization that you do.
Like sometimes I visualize myself
getting hurt too and fights.
Do you do that to see how you
recover? How do you, what do you do?
So it's not a new experience.
I Went Barboza fucking spinning heel kicks
me in the head like his, it's not, uh,
it's not,
it's always the punch that don't hurt you.
We were texted texting before that fight
and we were setting up this podcast.
You. I just listen. I just got to
concentrate on making sure I do.
Don't kick me in the head and
then after the fight like, Damn,
you fucking kicked me in the head.
You are definitely, definitely
preparing yourself for the possibility.