I know Robbie was angling
for a fight with Darren till,
but after Mazda all start steering until,
which was the nasty man.
People sleep a Mazda though. They do or
do not know why I don't understand it.
Go back and watch those backyard fights.
That guy's been going at it a long time.
Hey man,
any man that's [inaudible]
to both backyard but he
just had again this weekend.
Yeah, I know. That was crazy.
It's not about, it's about, um,
you know, you can't just
talk like nowadays this era,
you could just say whatever you feel
like you could say what you want because
he's social media. You want to get
fans on your side and this and that.
And he just happened to say it to
the wrong guy at the wrong time.
Like that. That's the situation.
And you did it backstage to massive.
Don't give a fuck. Like
know mutual. I think I,
I think it's mutual respect with me
and mass with all, like I respect him,
you know? I mean if we have to fight,
we have to fight one day, but you know,
like we feel the same when it's like if
you're going to talk shit online when I
see you keep the same energy.
Like when I saw Ben asks went backstage,
the only thing that stopped me from
pushing his head through that wall back
there,
it was the fact that I almost blacked
out blacktop when I was walking towards
him. Then I realize Dana was
right behind. So you were angry.
It wasn't that I was angry. It was the
fact that Bro, like if you're, you're,
you came at me online like you
had a problem with me. Like you,
she started talking mad shit to me.
Like you had a problem like saying things,
putting up memes and all this.
To me that means like you have a problem.
I don't know what I did to you,
but you've got a problem with me.
So when I see you now, like I want
you to still have that same energy.
Don't just act like we're cool. Like
what's up bro? Yo, you want to hug it out.
Don't act like that. Act like you
still have the problem. Same problem.
Well you think he's just trying to
mark it. I mean Ben not ever happens.
That's fun. Anger, that's attitude
towards that. But that's what I'm saying.
That's the thing.
Like people are kind of letting
them off for certain things now.
Now what happens if mass for dog
would have starts him like that? Yeah.
Backstage because he did talk shit to
what happened if that was him mass for it
all starts like that. What
happens? Yeah. You know,
so that was my thing is I,
when I saw him backstage,
I almost wanted to push his
head through the wall, you know,
but not realize Dana's behind me. Brian's
mind. What happens if it all now in uh,
in, in England because they don't like
that shit over there. I don't know why,
but I think he got away free
Scot free. Really? I think,
I know I haven't heard
anything and everything's
fine. He's in the back already.
That's hilarious. But that's the
case cause that's a salt. Yeah.
But I mean,
I guess you could say it's hard.
It's hard to say assault when you're
dealing with UFC fighter. Right.
It's so hard.
Like he played basketball off the cob.
Solutely it's hard to say this. It's
a tricky, tricky situation. Right,
but he struck him out in the parking lot.
Yeah,
I have to a baseball game but I think
data and then Dana put out a statement
saying that that can't happen anymore. We
got to do a better, something like that.
We should do a better job of having
security around two separate guys.
They didn't know.
My father didn't let me near.
Ben Asked when or a core cold dead. Yes.
There was one time, not before this fight,
but before previous fight where you
were backstage. It was actually,
was it a press conference?
It was press conference and
you were trying to talk to
Colby. Like what's up man,
I'll schedule it. Yeah. I was scheduled
to fight Santiago [inaudible] in balls.
That's right.
And we were doing a big press conference
and they happened to have like,
I didn't even know he
was there cause they hit,
they had them hidden away the whole time.
It wasn't until you are going to get on
the bus to go to the press conference.
He came downstairs like
we were all meeting in the
lobby and I saw him and right
away I told her, I said, I don't know
what it is. I just, I stopped my boy.
I just started your blood.
My blood just started bawling.
I started duct to a read. I
was, I read man, that's not
gonna work. That's not work.
You'll, you got moving, reuse.
Like we're getting him right now.
We're moving and read, put it, puts
him in a different car and every,
all the other fighters ride together.
And this is what I mean,
he's already isolated. That's
so fun. So we get there,
but we have to line up to walk out.
So he's lined up and he's just happened
to be in my vicinity and I just free,
I was trying and I was like,
yeah, I'm not going to say,
I'm not going to say I'm not gonna
say nothing. I just look at him. Yo,
I see you was talking all that
shit online now. Now we in person,
you can't talk. What's up with all
that shit you was talking online,
you thought she was tough.
What's up with that was that
tough guy now and he's just like,
I think he was reading his lines like
what he was going to say when he got out
there and Prescott, he uses like Wheaton
and he heard me and he's like, shit,
I don't want to say nothing. Shit. I
could get my eyes. What bright here.
I don't want to do that.
And I could say all those thoughts was
contemplating and Whitaker was standing
next to him and Whitaker does one
of these joint like look around,
fuck this dude talking to,
cause I had to watch the video over
and over where it could look bad.
Like he ain't talking to me
and then saw Kobe is like,
oh he's talking to Kolby.
So Winokur just kindly slid off
to the side and I'm getting,
I'm like, what's up with all that shit
you was talking. And then he's like quiet,
quiet.
And then he sees the security kind of
cause then they heard me and security kind
of walks. I didn't even know
there was a camera back there. Uh,
and then security walks up and security's
like, Yo, Yo, no, no, we don't need this.
We don't need this. And this was, uh,
what press con Kobi was about to fight.
This was after that Conor.
Khabib bus situation. Yes.
And so they're like, Yo, who don't need
this this week. We don't need this.
And now once this security,
he goes, he goes, stick,
stick to stick to a network. Television
Junior. Stick to this boy. You know,
I'm like network television.
What does that mean?
Because I guess he was fighting in
his first fight on now on paper view.
But this is the thing,
you were on Fox. Yeah.
But this is the thing is he had
never headline of car. To this day,
I don't think he's ever
headlined the card.