The Joe Rogan experience, they, you know,
our government and other governments
could debunk any information on Ufos,
anything because they,
you know,
there wasn't like the wide
communication that did exist now. Right.
So I think now they put in people who are
saying this crazy wild way out shit so
that people are, that are really trying
to expose truth on certain things.
They get looked at as whack jobs.
Like the rest of those
that are trying to say,
oh well flat earth or we're on a disk
or we're in a globe or Blah blah blah.
You know, ever been spying on you.
They'll throw all that together. Yeah.
It is buying on you. Yeah. If
they are, that is for sure. I,
they really are that it's, it's, you know,
since George Bush Jr was president,
they've been listening to our phone calls.
I mean that's a fact.
I mean,
that was one of the things they
enacted with the homeland security,
that they can record every
American's call and you know,
whatever conversation mentioned certain
key words as we were saying earlier,
they would,
you know,
they would get shuffled off to a certain
department and those guys were red
flagged and looked at and that still
happens today still to this day.
You don't need a warrant. They can just
listen. I mean, I'll tell you this, right?
There was a, I've been traveling
what, 20, 20 some odd years at,
at the point where, um, when I,
when I was coming back into the
United States for a long time,
I would not get randomly
checked or anything like that.
They just let us go by.
And I made a few posts somewhere,
you know,
with an abundant amount of cannabis,
right.
And right after that post,
each time I came back
into the United States,
they send me into secondary for a search.
And I started asking like, Hey, um,
I've been traveling for x
amount of years now. Every,
I've noticed that the last four times
that I've come back from another country,
you guys are randomly,
you know,
checking my bags now what's
the deal and my red flag,
what's going on with my passport?
Um, well, you know, we're,
I'm not really allowed to tell you this,
but I mean,
have you been with kind of postings
have you made on your social networks?
Really? Yeah. And I
said, okay, say no more.
And I already knew what it was
cause I had put like, you know, uh,
a post with like four or five,
six pounds in it,
but it's five pounds a we'd
even look like it's a lot.
It's like giant pillows he filled with.
Yeah. So, you know, right then and there,
I knew, you know, from that reaction that
he had that anybody with any sort of,
um, that's involved in entertainment,
music, athlete, you know,
whatever actor, actress, they're
watching all of our shit.
Oh, for sure. They're
listening and they're watching.
So especially someone like you has been
at the forefront of pushing cannabis
legalization and always talked
about it openly, flagrantly,
even when it was a schedule one
substance. So yeah. Everywhere, you know?
Okay.