The Joe Rogan experience.
Have you seen at a Chopin weird Al
Yankovic trapped at a drive through?
No, it's really good. No,
it's the same length as
our Kelly's trapped in the
closet and it's the same and
it's all about being trapped
at a Mcdonald's drive
through because the person in
front of miss taken too
long and it's like I can,
the fact that he did the whole side
is respect, respect, commitment.
I made it to, it's all cartoons
animated. Oh my God. That's hilarious.
Which one is, this is weird.
Al has been around for a
long time, man. Yeah. I mean,
I remember when Michael Jackson's beat
it came out and he had eat it. Eat it.
Yeah. I mean that was and said, I'm
mad. It was, I'm fat. Yeah. Yeah.
What year was that?
That's going to be in the A's.
It's gotta be late eighties early now.
Yeah, it is. How late it is. Real. Real.
How old is here? Weird. Al's
gotta be 85 years old take,
so 59 what? Yeah, 59 was he 12 back then?
His first song aired in 1976 yeah.
He was a big on Dr Demento
six. Yeah. That's insane. Huh.
So he was really young. Dr Demento,
Dr Demento, God, I run my head.
I remember listening to I
was a kid, but that's, uh,
they played all these weird
goofball, nerdy songs. Yeah.
And he was the king of it.
He has a huge following now.
He's like, he'll, he'll sell
out places. Weird al. Yeah.
That makes sense. Yeah.
We just got some big
giant body of work. Yeah. I like
his hair too. He's got the hair.
He's a super nice guy too. Yeah.
And smart. I've heard. Yeah. Yeah.
But everyone's smart. What else can
we say about these things? Yeah.
He's a good dancer too. Accepts
his gender. You don't also like,
he's not trifling. That's one that's
definitely not trifling. Yeah.
That's a word that's like,
there's certain words like that one.
You just seem so ridiculous.
If you tried to use it.