The Joe Rogan experience.
Yeah.
I start to wonder who is it
that's involved in this stuff.
I started at what it's where I'm at now.
Is All we even capable
of belonging to groups,
units,
tribes of free hundred million people or
60 million people with so many diverse
ideas. Is this a time to look
at federalism differently
to start breaking down?
Well, you know the, I exists
within this tribe of people,
but I collaborate with
all these other people.
I don't know how municipal action gets
done and how you run an army and build
roads if people are starting
to operate in smaller units.
But I am thinking that we need to have
a real sense of community and connection
and we got to let go of looking for ways
to object to and judge other people was
some sort of primary for way of
forming their own identity. No,
I completely agree.
And I think we're probably moving towards
some sort of understanding that a lot
of these boundaries and these clans of,
you know,
states and countries,
they were all established without our
consent before we're born and we're,
we're just, we're a part of a system
that we just were, we didn't agree to it.
We just all of a sudden found ourselves
in it and we're trying to make it fit us.
Yeah, that's right. And there's aspects
of it that are appealing, you know,
like sort of June in a World Cup,
I've really should feel English and
for now like I feel a genuine sense of
connection and investment,
but if I'm being asked to live
according to rules that don't affect me,
that affect except for,
you know,
that for affect me financially and
don't speak to I am as an individual,
then I'm like, Whoa, what is this? This,
this is for my benefit. Yeah. Yeah.
When the inclination to form teams and
to root for your team and a root against
other teams, it's a, it's so
deep seated in us. It's a,
and it can cause so many unnecessary
conflicts for no reason. It's just,
it's, it's so, it's so
escapable too. It's, it's some,
so if you can objectively analyze the
way human beings behave and interact with
each other and go, well, why do we
do this? Let's just stop doing that.
It's just if we disagree on things,
how much are these disagreements actually
affecting me on a daily basis. Dot.
That much. Can we just communicate?
Can someone say what they think?
And I say what I think and we just decide
like what makes sense and what doesn't
make sense based on our own
interpretations. Isn't that possible?
It seems like it's, that's the
direction we'd go ahead. And I did a,
as I know you've done a podcast with
Candice Owens who like on the subject of
individual, like when
she says stuff like, uh,
people should go over slavery
or it's as if it didn't happen.
I don't agree with that. I feel like
that has a massive social impact.
That is that those statistics
and not come incidents,
the number of people of certain
ethnicities in prisons and in poverty or
whatever. For me, that's
not just a coincidence,
but I said I couldn't agree with more
profoundly on according to social
criteria, some very, very
important issues. One in, in
a personal level, I fought.
She was absolutely delightful,
not so funny and sweet and she's
very young.
If you really stop to think that was
going only 28 which is amazing. Right?
Is that correct?
She's so much smarter than I was when I
was 28 she sent me a lot more confident
and not worse.
It's prettier to 28 or 29 same thing.
So when I was 29 I was a fucking moron.
Okay.
And no one would ever listen
to my opinions on anything
and on the world stage.
Yeah, we're listening to
her. I mean she's, she's
testifying in front of Congress.
I mean,
she's,
so I cut her a lot of slack with
some of the things that she's made,
like missteps on that.
I think sometimes when people say those
things like people should get over
slavery.
It's like,
it's almost like you're saying things
that you think other people want to hear
more than you're saying things
that are really rational.
So whether or not we should
get over slavery. Sure,
slavery was over more than a hundred years
ago, but the repercussions of slavery,
the echoes of slavery still exist and
they exist in all these different southern
states and cities and all these different
neighborhoods that had been a part of
systemic racism where they literally
forced black people to live in certain
areas and didn't even allow them to
buy homes outside of those areas.
They made laws and those laws are
in place in places like Baltimore.
And you know,
I had this guy,
Michael Wood on [inaudible] who was a
police officer and the city of Baltimore.
And one of the more profound things that
he said was that they found papers that
we're documenting crimes from the 1970s
in Baltimore and they were in this same
area,
the same crimes that he was facing in
the two thousands when he was a police
officer. So he was looking at this
going, what in the fuck? Like this is,
am I just a part of something that's
never going to be fixed and never going to
be changed.
And you know,
as he learned more about the city
and the city's laws and how these,
these systems were set up to keep people
in certain places and how the crime and
the violence and the drugs is all just
in this one concentrated area and it's
always been there and no one does anything
to change it. You realize like, wow,
this is a, this is a crazy echo of a
horrible past and that's what it is.
I had a couple of conversations that made
me recognize how powerful systems and
institutions are and their
ability to maintain themselves.
It regardless of any individual,
cause it seems like what happened there
with the man you were chatting to is
that he's an individual woke up, I'm
like, oh my God, hold on a second.
In some sort of weird grid.
And I spoke to his fellow called Ken Ross
who worked for the British diplomatic
service at the time of nine 11 and was
privy to confidential information about
how that was handled on a military and
geopolitical level and he said like he's
come away from that thinking,
well these institutions function and in
a totally corrupt way to pursue their
own objectives.
Disingenuity in dishonesty is just part
of the system and it was him that made
me think about Aneca ism in a
different saying that people,
the assumption that people if they were
not tightly governed with big government
and huge control would go around merger
in each Haverim raping each other simply
not true.
That's one of the means by which the
state continues to justify its existence.
People will behave better the closer
they are to self governing community self
governing committee and they sit like,
and I was interested in that because
he's talking from this is why sore on the
inside. This is how I saw it was running
like your cop friends there and like, uh,
another person I spoke to that had been
inside a system and then woken up within
it. Who was that? Yanis Varoufakis he,
when Greece had that mad revolution,
he was like one of the
leaders of the party.
Cerisa and for a minute
it was like Theresa said,
we ain't paying back all those debts.
You screwed us financially.
You screwed Greece.
So he was there at the EU meetings telling
like the German chancellery we're not
Perry Greece ain't going
to repay those debts.
And he just said that the way that the
system reassert itself was magnificent to
watch in a way.
And he said none of those individuals
have any power except the power that that
role gives them.
If you are the German finance minister,
you've got the power of the
German finance minister has,
you can't step outside it and
start going, right? Listen,
why don't we do this and
why don't we do that?
The system itself is beyond
individual decisions. You know, it's,
it's a self sustaining system.
It won't come up with ideas or
support ideas that freshen it.
And that's why I
continued to keep hearing.
And I'm sure you're having similar
conversations that if you are really
interested in changing the world,
you have to participate in systems that
are outside of it. Set up new ideas.
Don't worry about trying to smash
this one down with a hammer.
It will atrophy on its own as it
becomes less and less relevant.
I think also change yourself
and when you change yourself,
becomes evident to the people around you.
And if your change is beneficial
and attractive people,
they gravitate towards that idea that
you can improve yourself and you can,
you change your perspective on things.
Okay.