Gonads. Episode three.
I'm Molly Webster. Hello.
Hello. Are you still there? I'm still
here. And this is my mother Mary Webster.
Yeah. Um, but uh, but yeah, no, the
bedbugs are such a freaking pain.
You have to vacuum all of the baseboards.
You have to vacuum the floors,
you have to vacuum the door jams cause
they crawl up the walls when they're
trying to get away.
Oh Molly, that sounds awful.
So I recently called my mom for
I guess to catch up but also
bye.
I had a work question
[inaudible] that's been bugging me
cause on my mind, yeah.
So I asked her mom been working on this
story and it made me wonder what you
would have named me if I was a boy.
You would have been named Daniel
Dad always liked the name and yeah,
if we ever had a boy, dad said
he was going to name of Daniel.
I if that's you want, go for it. Yeah.
Cause he didn't want a junior. You wanted
it Daniel. He wanted a little Danny.
Instead he got a Judy, Chrissy,
Peggy and Molly. Your poor father,
Mike glucky father,
if you had come out, boy you
would have been Daniel. Yes. Wait,
all of us. Not Well No,
we wait Daniel for up
forever. You were just ready.
We didn't know when I'm breaking him
out. He was going to be up. Yeah,
I mean [inaudible]
[inaudible]
so this is just going to sound ridiculous,
but I called my mom because all these
stories that we've been doing in this
series, they do make you think about fate.
Like even if you think about the first
one where they're the primordial germ
cells, um,
and they are holding on to all sorts
of possibilities and futures and then
chromosome step in and no more infinity.
You're just like shunted
onto a path I guess.
I guess.
I guess asking my mom about Daniel was
just like a clumsy way of getting back to
what feels like a really pristine moment.
Like a moment where no decision
had been made where you exist.
Totally embalm, ish by
life and choice and fate
in less.
Maybe life isn't so
fateful. Case in point.
David, dark hour. Hello. Hi.
Actually, I'm just going to make,
I don't like correcting people,
but I'll just correct you.
My name is pronounced Sarah Kovar is
our covert covert yet cause it is a w
right? I'm not missed. It's a
w for the sake of my parents.
I pronounce it with the like a v.
Um, it's, it's essentially Polish.
That's good. And um, you
work at the University of
Minnesota? Yep. That's right.
Uh, what do you do there? Uh, genetics,
cell biology and development. That's,
that seems scary. It's broad. Anyways,
the reason I called Zack Kovar was because
I came across a series of experiments
that he did that just straight
up kicked me into gonads. Okay.
So to begin, this was,
um, back in the, uh,
early 1990s there Kovar was working in
a lab doing genetic stuff in worms and
flies and mice and things. And one day
Presto, we got lucky done, Dah, Dah, Dah.
He and his team discovered a
brand new gene. Yup, that's right.
They saw it in mice and gave it a name.
I unfortunately am responsible for this.
It's DMR. T One d m r t one
DMR t one. Yup. Demert one.
I keep trying to say d r m t it's
a little bit, it's a nightmare.
Very sorry for that.
And what was interesting was that this
gene was in mice but also in humans
[inaudible]
and in the male mouse it
was expressing itself in the
testis. You forgot to say it.
Testis testes. Testes, testicles,
testers. Is that a single? Yep. Okay.
So yes, we found this gene and
humans had it and the test is,
and the question we had was whether
it was doing something or not.
Like you've got genes in your eyes that
are making chemicals that are making
your eyes the color. They are this
gene DMR t one. What is it doing?
We wanted to know if it's involved in
maybe making sperm or maybe it just hangs
around. It doesn't matter. It doesn't
do anything, you know, we don't know.
And so they're like, let's mess
around with it and see what happens.
But
you can't do that
experiment in humans. No.
So instead they get some adult male mice,
perfectly normal fertile
males that are making sperm.
And we use some fancy
molecular genetic tricks.
And so basically it's kind of a
mean trick, but a, it's genetics.
They cut the gene out,
we did that and then they take a slice
of the testis and they look at it under
the microscope and it didn't look
like what we would have expected.
And what they expect to see is that these
are the cells that help make the sperm
in the testis. And normally
they're kind of tall and lean,
long and skinny,
but suddenly they're
different with DMR t one gone.
They had gotten smaller rounder
and their cover was like,
this was not something that was supposed
to happen. What is going on here?
What are these things?
And then he realized that the cells
are making estrogen and he was like
[inaudible]. Oh yeah.
I think what is happening is that the
cells in the testis turned into ovary
cells. Wait, wait and wait.
It's a male mouse. Yes. So you're
saying this male mouse now has
over resales in its testicles?
Yes. These are cells that are
changing their, their sex.
That's insane. Can I, can we just
have like a, a exclamatory moment?
Like where you were you like, whoa. Is
that pot that's possible. That happened.
What is it, you know,
what do you say for, for us anyway,
the greatest of all scientific
exclamations is, that's weird. Um,
so we had that weird moment
and just to take this weirdness
like a one step further,
a group of scientists did
similar experiment in adult
female mice where they did
like the same
fancy molecular genetic tricks.
Only this time they knocked out a female
gene in the ovary and when they went to
look at it,
the ovary is trying to kind of
reorganize itself into, um, the testis.
Wait,
[inaudible] you're saying in both cases
there's one gene that's flipping the sex
from male to female or back?
Yes. One gene. One gene.
How many genes do we have in our body?
I don't know, like tens of thousands.
Wow. And just one is doing this,
which is weird concept to think of
because we typically connect like sex or
gonads to chromosomes at least. I do like
an accent of why is a girl and a boy,
so how could a gene step
in and reverse that? Yeah.
Cause I thought chromosomes
were a, lots of genes.
There are these like massive
things. One gene is so tiny,
ginger tiny chromosomes are much bigger.
And I think the answer to that
is that when you get down to sex,
like what makes us one sex
or the other, it's not,
it doesn't work exactly like we thought.
Like take for example the x and y idea,
this like chromosomal narrative
we have of biological sex.
It's a specific way of thinking about
things from a certain moment in history
that we are potentially
starting to rethink. Huh.
I think it's helpful to see sort of the,
the history of how we
understand sex and in a,
in a longer timeframe. So
let me bring in this guy.
I'm David Page biology professor
at MIT. Where do we start?
Oh my gosh. Well we're
going to go. So let's see.
We could go off the rails in
any number of directions here,
all of which would be quite, quite
productive. But let's see. So, um,
let's go back to um, the 1890s.
Yeah, that definitely is 1890s.
So genetics was in its infancy,
Mendel peas, all that was [inaudible]
and people had been
pondering for millennial.
Where do boys and girls come from
now when it came to how you look? People
thought mom and dad clearly involved
because people had realized, you know,
the children ended up growing up looking
something like their mother and their
father.
Like maybe you have a Chin like your dad
and knows like your mom and the hair.
That's a little bit of a [inaudible].
There was a kind of blending of
mom and dad to make you you right.
But when it came to why
you were the sex you were,
that was a mystery because
there was no blending.
You ended up being like either
your mother or your father,
one or the other.
Therefore it must not have
anything to do with heredity.
It had to be imposed from
the outside in some way.
So people came up with all kinds of
ideas for what made you a boy or a girl
phase of the moon at that moment
of conception called dark moon.
Definitely a girl. The state of
the economy wouldn't be surprised.
Down economy girl, everything
that was bad was given to women.
Uh, there was what the mother
ate, mom's body, heat, stress,
all sorts of crazy things. And then, um,
in 1923, we started looking elsewhere,
but how do we inherit our
characteristics for an answer?
Chromosome chromosomes determine
our physical appearance and our sex.
In 1923,
a scientists looking down the barrel
of a microscope discovers to new
from the silence x and a
y all the sex chromosomes.
But I just want to hit pause here.
I came to find out actually from David
Page that the x and y chromosomes do not
look like an x and y. Wait, they don't
look like the letters. Oh No, no, no, no.
When they first discovered them,
they were blobs under the microscope.
They just look like
these misshapen clumps,
kidney being mark. The x look bigger.
The y looks smaller, but that's it.
That's so interesting because there's
something about the shape of the x and the
shape of the why, which read as gendered
letters that feel so yeah, cause right.
Why has a little stem on it,
which is sort of peanuts.
Like there's like a duality or something
in the x, which feels like, you know,
ovaries and breasts or
something. Like there is like a,
there is something about those letters.
So I was totally shocked when he was like,
there's no real reason they got those
letters. It was totally arbitrary.
Anyways, when they
found these chromosomes,
it was clear that if you
had x, x two x chromosomes,
you would develop as a
female anatomic female.
And if you had a y chromosome, your x,
y you would develop as an anatomic male.
Oh boy. That was the thinking.
So you see Roger on suse.
Yeah.
But then that idea it got
more complicated. Yeah. Yeah.
When did you intersect with this story?
The summer of 1970 pages at MIT.
First Year of medical school
and the DNA revolution. So
far tonight we've been
bringing you a news.
So the world around us was just beginning.
Now we have news of the
incredible world inside us.
He was involved in what he
described, like the precursor
to the human genome project,
what would become the human genome
project working with a group of senior
scientists who were envisioning maps of
the human genome [inaudible] we all know
within complete set of
instructions which made people,
and we began to look back
at some exceptional human
individuals who had not been
understood previously.
That saliva test women revealed that
Maria had a set of x and y chromosomes who
had an x and a y
chromosome. Like most men,
women usually have a pair of xs and they
were also looking at men who had been
an all together male
anatomy, penis, testes,
but whose chromosomes appeared to
beat those typical of a female xx.
And for Paige and other
scientists, they were like, oh,
there must be something more happening
here than just like the chromosome.
There must be something
deeper going on here.
So we might actually be on
the trail now of the secret.
So scientists across the world started
looking at these people's chromosomes,
and what we found was that the few x y
females were actually missing a little
bit of the y chromosome
with these x, y women.
A little bit of the y wasn't there,
and the bit of the why that the x y
females were missing was the same bit that
was present in the xx males,
meaning somehow a little bit of the y
chromosome had gotten onto one of the exes
of these x x males.
And so it was becoming very clear that
this must be the bit that matters.
And around 1990 other news this day,
scientists say they've
made a major discovery.
Scientists in Britain announced they'd
found this one gene on the y chromosome,
the genetic trigger on the y chromosome
that determines whether a baby will be a
boy or a girl.
What they found is that of the
200 odd genes on the y chromosome,
there was this one single
gene that acted as the switch,
the master switch, the
grand master switch,
which determines the child's sex.
So it's not x and Y as a whole.
It's one tiny piece.
[inaudible].
So back in the first episode,
there were those primordial germ cells
and they had to go on that super long
journey to get to the Gonad Cathedral.
And on the journey when
they got to the cathedral,
they were full of potential, right?
They could be anything can be male,
they could be female, they could be
whatever your version of anything is. Um,
and then when they get
[inaudible] get there,
there's a moment where like we said,
fate stepped in and just crushed,
like swept all their
possibility away and said,
you are one thing and this
is the thing you will be,
this gene is fate. Uh, this gene,
these scientists
discovered if it shows up,
then you shoot off down the path
that his sperm test is male.
And if it doesn't show up, you
shoot down the path of egg,
ovary female, and the scientists, uh,
gave this gene and name
s r y. [inaudible].
Sorry
man. Sorry.
So it sounds like we've gone from like
crazy ideas about what makes a boy or a
girl to chromosomes to
now like this little gene.
Yeah. But the,
the sorry gene that you just mentioned
is different than the gene that I just
heard about from a, I'm forgetting
his name. Zara Kovar is our Coover.
It's our covert, Yep. It's our
covert covert. Yes, it is. I think,
is it different that's the
same gene or is it DMR?
T one is a different
gene than s r y but this,
this is what's so crazy
about DMR. T y. Okay.
Primordial germ cells.
They're in the embryo.
They're waiting to become something
and then, sorry, shows up.
But it just comes on for about
a day and then it goes away.
But once it turns [inaudible]
Zan,
it then starts this like cascade
of Jean after Jean after Jean.
That all sort of say, you're
male, you're male, you're male.
And what all of these genes do is they
create chemicals that send out signals
that start forming and shaping
being the test is. And as soon
as the test is begins to develop
[inaudible] turns the fourth
gene, DMR t one zero clovers gene.
And it clearly is important for
finishing the job of making a testis.
But the thing is most of these other
genes that make the test is turn off the
DMR t one. It doesn't
go away at that point.
Yes,
stays active
forever in the wound when
the test is, is just growing.
And then when you're born and through,
you know, childhood, your teenage years,
adulthood, like until
you die, DMR t one is on.
And if you take it away,
likes are covert, did
the cell will actually change sex,
which leads you to believe that DMR t
one is actually preventing a cell from
switching sexes. That's right.
So I called blanche capable,
who is a geneticists
from our first episode.
And she explained that what all
this means is that that other path,
the path that you did not take
in the Gonad Cathedral, um,
it never went away. It's
actually still there.
You carry it with you always.
It's just that that Jean has
been shushing it. Yeah. Wait,
I'm repressing the other
pathway. My whole like, I
think we think so. Yeah. Really? Yeah.
There's like a parallel universe.
Male Molly. Yes. I think there is.
There's a parallel universe. Male Molly.
Wow. That's just cool. Wait,
when you say this gene has
been shushing the other Molly,
what does that even mean? Huh? Okay,
so you could think of it like this.
The code for that other
Molly who I'll call Daniel,
that code is still in my cells and dark
cover says that what this gene does is
it sort of,
one of the things this gene does is
sort of patrols and it makes sure that
Daniel genes don't turn on
basically what this gene's been doing.
It turns out as playing whack-a-mole,
I'm basically just going around and
being like, Daniel, no, off Daniel, no,
op and it does this maybe every day.
It's like an election that's always
being kind of challenged. Yes.
Or why cast the deciding
vote and male happened.
But there's recount every
now and then and a 50.
Marty one's not there to
say, nope, still male. Uh,
then you can go the other way.
So now I understand why you're so obsessed
with Daniel because it's not just as
an idea, he's like trying to get out
and it does go both ways. Like, like,
um, you know, there's SROI
and there's DMR t one,
but they have found these key genes in
ovaries that you can turn on and off and
have similar results. Why would or why
would our bodies be set up this way?
Like you think once the decision gets
made that you just make that decision and
be done with it,
why would there always be the
possibility of unmaking the decision?
That is a good question and I
will answer that after break.
But first I'm going to call my sisters
[inaudible]
[inaudible] uh,
uh, [inaudible] on
chase [inaudible]
this is Kayla Cabo calling
from Sunny Austin, Texas.
Radiolab presents gonads.
Gonads is supported in part by science
sandbox assignments foundation initiative
dedicated to engaging everyone
with the process of science.
Additional support for radio lab is
provided by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation.
Hey everyone. I'm Dr
Raj. I love getting to
talk with you on my show every single
day. But when the cameras stopped rolling,
the conversation isn't over for I decided
to start a podcast in order to dive
deeper into the issues and ideas
that I love sharing with you. Yes,
help unfiltered.
My wife Lisa will be joining me and
together we're taking wellness to the next
level and having a little fun along
the way. So download the Dr Oz podcast.
Subscribe where ever
you get your podcasts.
All right, back to gonads. I'm
Molly Webster. Everyone's say,
say their name or hello.
Okay, it's Chrissy [inaudible].
Peggy. Yeah. Hi. Hi. How are you?
I'm great. And these are my sisters,
Judy, Chrissy and Peggy. Okay.
So I'll tell you. So I'm going to tell
you guys the thing, it's not easy,
that big of a deal, but it's just
sort of funny. Oh, I know. Okay.
You're pregnant. I'm not
pregnant. I'm not. No, no.
I just want to tell you about some
reporting that I've been doing.
And then a funny thing that mom and
dad told me, that's all it is. Okay,
mom had an affair. No,
God that doesn't belong.
That's Chrissy. Yeah,
this is ridiculous. Um,
the third episode is basically
about how we all carry in us,
like the opposite self that
we never became. So, um,
so I called mom cause I was like,
what would mail Molly
have been like, like,
did you guys have like a name for Mayo,
Molly [inaudible]? And they were like,
oh, um, we would've called you Daniel.
No, that was what they were supposed
to call me. They were so desperate.
They used them.
Daniel, it turns out that we were
all supposed to be called Daniel
reveal. It's not either.
Daniel Webster is,
she does Molly.
Oh Man. Um, are you surprised that your
name would have been Daniel Webster?
That you would have been a Daniel? No.
No. I think we all knew that. Right?
Peggy? Did you know that?
I didn't know that.
I don't feel like my inner Daniel Webster
would have that much of a different
life than I have. So, but
I think you guys, honestly,
not to railroad this conversation,
but I think you guys lucked out because
I was the one that was raised with the
hopes that there was like
some gang no lingering in me.
Isn't Daniel Webster like
a famous dude in history?
Yes.
Oh, I took a picture of a statue of him
once and send it to dad because I was
supposed to be Daniel. Who is Daniel
Webster? He's a boring white dude.
Well of course he is. We knew that part.
He served as senator from Massachusetts
and was the under secretary of state
under three presidents.
Well, someone googled fast.
Yes.
I think he's just a reg. A regular
like old white lawyer dude. Yeah,
they're all racist
or ages or just douchebag.
All right, well great. That was funny.
Thank you. Got Her giggles in. It's all
been worth it. All right. That's all.
That's all I got.
We love you mom.
I love you guys. Goodbye.
Love you. Bye Bye. Sorry
Molly. You're amazing. Okay,
bye. Sorry about your bedbugs. Bye.
Okay. So to catch everybody up,
we have learned that we are all
carrying around with us another path.
We all have our own inner
Daniel Webster's, um,
and we're constantly shushing
it or them, whatever.
So my question for is our cover was like,
why would I carry this path with
me if I'm always trying? Like if,
if I'm just turning it off.
Um,
do you have any answer to that?
I wish I had the answer. So the,
we don't really have an answer. Um,
it could be as boring as, well,
it doesn't really matter because normally
no molecular geneticists comes in and
hacks out DMR t one or turns
on Fox l two or whatever. Um,
so why solve a problem that you haven't
created that that's quite possible but
boring?
The more interesting answer is that
this is an evolutionary holdover from,
from a common ancestor with fish.
[inaudible].
Okay. So this ancestor would
be our great grandparents,
16 million times removed, which
means 400 million years ago,
a fish swim out of the depths of the
ocean crawled onto land and took like
squelching steps forward and board
and board and board and board through
millions of years of luck and chance
and fate until finally getting to
you and me and boom. Hello? Hello.
Can you hear me? Yes. Can you
hear me? Yes, I sure can. Bob.
My name is Bob Warner.
I'm a research professor,
studies evolution and marine
biology at UC Santa Barbara.
What's your attraction
to the ocean? Uh, well,
the whole idea that there is
a different world under there.
Well, I'm just going to add
in brothers out of this.
So down in the waters around the Florida
keys there swims a remarkable fish who
had rats. It is a very
common, a coral reef fish.
This is Marshall Phillips Graduate Student
at North Carolina State University.
She like Bob's studies.
Blue heads. Yes. Anyways,
down in the keys are some
Primo spots, nice patches
that might have a group
of say a dozen blue heads.
And in that group there will be a
single large brightly colored male.
Just one of them. Yeah,
about the size of your hand with a blue
head and it's shiny blue, green body,
it white and black stripes right
behind its head that go black,
white,
black that we've very technically called
the Oreo and if he's got a big Oreo,
well
that's a sexy male
[inaudible]
and then the rest of the group is
essentially a Harem of lady fish and the
ladies in the group are little
and yellow, very pretty.
It kind of swim a little slower
watching out for things that the male is
flashing, darting all
around, much more aggressive.
And so this one male and this Herriman
females will basically spend their entire
lives on this one patch of ri where
they mate every day, each
female with that one male,
all it entails is the male and the
female will dart up in the water column
together and then at the same time he'll
release his sperm and she'll release
her eggs and then they dart right
back down and then a different female,
same male go up, egg sperm and
dark back down. And then again,
different female, same male,
they go up down and this is what
they do every day over and over.
Kind of sounds like a cult of that idea.
Sixties but say something
happens to this male.
I'll say a Predator comes
along and he chumps that mail.
So the Alpha male is
eaten up. Dead. Yup. Gone.
Now the question is what
happens to the ladies?
You'd think it would be chaos because
their whole system has been thrown out of
whack, but
within minutes to hours, life finds a way.
Somehow the ladies pick
who will be the next male.
The ladies have it pretty well
worked out. Who's the largest?
Do they all start like
eyeballing each other?
Like they don't line up or
anything? My bigger than, you know,
but somehow they, um,
figure it out until once they
establish who the largest female is,
she starts to change her behavior.
She gets a little more friendly
towards the other females.
She'll swim up to them, do
this little Wigley Dance,
Sorta waving her pictorial
fin at the ladies,
which isn't really something
they do as a female ever.
And then as time goes on,
her body starts to change.
She will get a little bit bigger.
Uh,
how do you just suddenly get bigger?
Testosterone or brain starts sending
signals to produce tons of testosterone.
Testosterone is, is taking
over and as she starts to grow,
a little bit of blue starts
to appear right at her nose.
Her scales start to change color then
sort of spread backwards right at her chin
and spread outwards
until her head is entirely
Baloo. And then [inaudible] these
dark stripes start to form. Those will
eventually become that black, white,
black Oreo.
And the other thing that starts to happen
is her ovaries start to disintegrate.
These are
the most valuable cells in the
body, and now suddenly they're being
destroyed and then they start to rebuild
themselves into testes that start
producing sperm really rapidly. Wow. It's,
it's not. It's absolutely incredible.
And then sex calls is back.
There's a new dominant male
at the top of the heap,
but at first he's not
very good at being a male.
Like he doesn't quite know when
to dart up and when to spawn.
It's just like a teenager who
doesn't know how to talk to girls,
but eventually he gets the hang of it
and can produce baby blue heads and the
cycle
school of life continues
as a good Attenborough. Thank you.
It's crazy that they just disintegrate
their insights and then rebuild.
But the funny thing is if you
ask Bob about this stuff, no.
It in fact about how these little lady
fish completely transformed. He's like,
Eh.
Yeah. I hate to admit that, but
uh, yeah, it's not that shocking.
The shocking thing is how many
fishes change sets?
It turns out it's a lot of fishes.
Nearly all the rass you blue had your
ferries, your flashers, parrot fishes.
They actually looked like parents. They
changed sex. Most of the big groupers,
the tiny gobies damsel fishes. Everyone
asks about clam fish finding an email.
Yes, they change sex, but they
do it a little differently.
They go from male to female up
with the clown fish matriarchy.
Bob Says we're dealing with like hundreds,
a whole lot of sex changing
fish easily. Wow. Hundreds. Yep.
Here's the really crazy thing.
It's not just fishes. Some
shrimps, worms, alligators.
If you include all of the animals in
which their sex goes a different way than
you would think lies. Lobsters,
bananas, lizards, birds, mussels,
snails, slugs, chickens, chickens.
Oh, ELL frogs. It's just amazing.
And wait till we get to turtles.
It's the whole zoo in
this conversation. I know.
So why would fish like, why would it tell
her? Why would any animal change sex?
Well, I think a sex change increases
your fitness. You have more young,
either eggs you produce or eggs that you
fertilized than you would as a c as a
single sex.
In other words, it just ensures that
you can pass on your genetic material.
Like if you're the fishes on the
reef and the male disappears,
you're stuck and there's no,
there's your DNA goes nowhere.
But if you can become a male socially,
you can make sure that your DNA goes
somewhere and then like all the other
fishes in your little
kingdom go somewhere. Okay,
so now let me ask you the
next obvious question.
You've told me that we
come from the fish. Yeah.
They've got this flexy sexy thing
and that we have at, to some degree,
Daniel Lurks within you and is being
actively suppressed every single day.
So can we be like the fish? Yeah,
it does make you think of that.
Does our covert says that ever since
he did those mouse experiments,
he gets this question a lot.
Yeah. Yeah.
There's some interest from a transgender
community and whether this could be
something, it'd be helpful,
but we can't do it.
We technically can't.
Is there a cover says it's unethical and
at this point probably even technically
impossible to take that gene
away. And even if we could,
removing a gene just won't physically
reorganize us in the way the fish do.
He says at most
you might be able to produce your own
natural sex hormones of the type that's
more aligned with your gender identity.
Oh, pretty crazy. You can even
get the body to do that. Um,
but the reason we can't actually do
the full on switch is because humans,
uh,
male and female humans have developed
internal reproductive plumbing that is so
different from each other.
It would be impossible at the drop of
a hat to switch was the then then this,
this makes me confused. Well,
is this to use blanche is a word from a
few episodes ago as this by potentiality
that still is there? Yeah.
Latent being suppressed.
Is that a legacy thing that is
just fading away or is there,
is it there for a reason? It's
there for a reason and the fish,
is it there for a reason in us?
Does it serve a purpose and therefore
it will be with us always or maybe even
get stronger. Yeah, no,
I asked blanche that.
I don't know. I don't know. I
don't have a good answer for that.
But it, do you think
anyone does or is this,
no, I don't think anyone does. I,
I think we're all trying to figure
out why it would be the case. Um,
and most people ask the same question
you ask why would this be true?
And I don't know why it would be true
even if we don't know why.
Just knowing that that other path
is there just below the surface,
you know,
almost like wanting to express itself
does make you think a different way about
how rigidly we define ourselves.
I think we like to bend people
as male or female and we, I,
we've always put people in two piles but
I think there's a tremendous amount of
middle ground even when you're
just talking about, you know,
things like the level of testosterone
you're making or the level of estrogen
you're making or um, the shape
of your genitalia or, uh,
many other features that we can,
we, we've been as male or female.
I think there is a lot of, um, there's a
lot of variation between the two piles.
[inaudible]
and maybe we haven't appreciated the
variation that exists naturally in our
population.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
[inaudible] this episode
is reported by me,
Molly Webster and produced by Matt
guilty with additional production help by
Rachel Cusick at Walter's
was our editor scoring,
mixing and original music by
Alex Overington and Matt kilty.
The gonads theme and the ballot
of Daniel Webster were written,
performed and produced by NATO
Connery and Alex Overington.
Special thanks for this episode.
Go to Erica Todd, Andrew Sinclair,
Robin Lovell Badge and Sarah
Richardson. Thank you. To compose her.
Eric Friedlaender for allowing us
to use his work frail as a breeze,
part two and musician Sam Pre-con
whose work a geometric from his album.
The republic is out on thrill. Jackie,
I think you should sign up for the radio
lab newsletter, you might think. Yeah,
newsletter. What's the big
deal? Everyone's got one,
but in our newsletter you're going to
get a bunch of staff picks telling you
about super cool things we discovered
while recording this series. Sign up at
radiolab.org/newsletter or text.
Don't add two seven zero one
dash zero one Radiolab presents.
Gonads is Rachel Cusick, Pat Walters
Jad album, Ron and me Molly webs.
See you next time. Hi, it's Annette Udall
calling from new castle, California.
Radiolab was created by Jad ABIM Rod
and is produced by Swann Wheeler.
Dylan Keefe is our director of
sound design and brand Matasar.
Pedea is our managing director. Our
staff includes assignment Adler,
Maggie Bartella, Mayo, Becca Bressler,
Rachel Acoustic, David gabbled,
Bethel hab ti, Tracy Hunt, Matt
Kielty, Robert Krulwich, Annie Mcewen,
Latif, Nasser, Melissa O'Donnell, Arion
Wack, Pat Walters, and Molly Webster.
Without from Shima or Lily
Carter Hodge and Lisa Hagar.
Our fact checker is Michelle
Harris. How'd I do dice.