Maybe all of us can sit on the couch.
I can or I can pull that chair over.
So we're going to start with
a story from our producer,
Pat Walters about a couple, oh my
word. It's the lady. I'm Janet.
This is the guy. So I don't
need you to introduce yourself.
That's usually the thing we do, but
we're not telling people who you are.
We're going to call him Kevin. Kevin,
yeah, yeah, yeah. That's, yeah,
that's my name. That's
suspicious at all. Yeah.
It's not as real name. No. Makes Sense.
Why we're not using his
real name in a second.
Okay. You know, this one starts a
few summers ago. It was July, 2006.
Jan and Kevin were at home and uh,
some people you don't know show
up and maybe out start with you
when they show up at the
door. So we were, it was a,
we were getting ready to go down
the shore. It was a Friday. So we,
so we're in the kitchen and
they come to the back door.
I thought the, I thought
that they were fundraising.
I thought they might've been farming
just by, you know, the, the blue shirt,
the blue shirt and then realized
that, uh, that they, they were,
they were law enforcement
[inaudible]
two women and a, I think two men more
came up from around the, you know,
the side of the house and they show us
their badges or are they cops or they
were homeland security.
They took me outside and they kept me
and they asked me to stay in the kitchen
and they had a, a woman with me.
I didn't know what was going on.
Nobody said anything.
What are they saying to you on
the porch? Meanwhile, when they,
when they showed up, like after to the
door, you said, you know why we're here.
I said, yeah, I do. I was expecting you
[inaudible]
and I showed him where everything was.
This story about Kevin and his wife,
Janet inspired us to do the entire hour
because one of the most basic things
that we do as people is we
judge, we judge one another,
could judge what's right, what's wrong,
but this story and the two that follow,
they will make you judge how you judge
or at least they had that effect on us.
We're calling our show
[inaudible]
blame him, Jab and Ron. I'm Robert
Krulwich and we'll go back to pat.
Before we do,
you should know that this show contains
some graphic difficult descriptions in a
few spots. If you're not in the
mood or if you have kids around,
you might want to sit this one out.
Okay. So what happened in that
first scene and what happens next?
Only makes sense. If we
go back a little first
about 15 years, it's just an ordinary day.
Kevin's going home from work and um,
I was driving home going about 65 70 in
the fast lane when suddenly there was a
thump in my chest.
Then he just a heat boating. After that.
He said suddenly he had this thickness
in my tongue and my throat than about
taste in his mouth. Then
my hearing, feed it out.
Any thoughts? It's back
when I finally did come to, uh,
he sees his car smashed into the
side of an apartment building.
I do recall the officers telling
you you've been in an accident,
you've been at an end.
He remembers one of them
insisted that he smelled alcohol.
And I was talking through clenched
teeth cause I had bit my tongue and uh,
and my cheeks. I was saying over
and over again, I had a seizure.
I had a seizure.
[inaudible] Kevin's got epilepsy.
He's had it since he was a teenager.
But two years before this all happened,
he'd had surgery to remove the part of
his brain that was causing the seizures
and it seemed to have
worked. He was doing great.
Essentially wasn't having seizures
anymore until suddenly you,
he was lost your license. I
lost my license for a year.
Things had kind of taken a nose dive.
Like here he is, he's 35 years old.
I'm living with my brother, I'm divorced.
And I have to call my daddy and ask him
now to drive me to and from work and you
think I need to do something, this
is not sustainable. No, no, don't,
don't need that.
So I walked into the office as the HR
person where he works for a list of all
the employees, give me a list of
everybody and where they're from.
So she pulled it up,
I go down the list and I get to Janet
Woodruff Littlefield only one that's
really close to me five minutes
away. So I walk to her cube,
knocked on the, on the wall and uh,
introduced myself like, Hey, my
name is Kevin. I also work here.
I've got this thing though. It's
Kinda awkward. I can't drive.
And I was wondering if you'd
give me a ride. And uh,
she said yes.
[inaudible]
I really passed by his street,
I mean, on the way to work.
So it was like right on history pretty
much. But I made it clear, you know,
I'll do it when I can. And as they
drove together, they started talking,
finding out little bit
more about each other.
Notice pretty quickly
we'd like to say music.
And that was unique because I sort of
liked music that was probably more in his
error. Kevin was seven
years older than Jan.
What kind of music are you
listening to? Jackson Brown,
mostly a lot of Jackson Brown.
James Taylor just call um,
funny rate. It's a little,
you know, Elton John
it down themselves.
Sing along to the lyrics.
You cannot sing with somebody day in
and day out and not have something
happened.
We wound up as the spring came,
you know, it's getting nice out.
So now it's like, well let's not go
home. Let's go out for a beer after work.
We're becoming good friends. We liked
each other. But for Kevin, yeah,
it was a little more serious than that.
I'm thinking about her starting to wake
up at night and one day in May as Jenna
is dropping him off, Kevin
turns to her and he says, Hey,
I really appreciate
what you've done for me.
Let me take you to dinner just as
friends, just as friends. Jen says.
Sure. So May 30th,
1992. Hi. Long pavilion,
nicest restaurant in town,
so your friends takes you
to a four star restaurant.
You're thinking right away he thinks
this is a date. We're going on a date,
come on. So now I'm panic stricken.
We have our dinner, we leave.
We had a wonderful time.
He drops me off and I handed her
the poem. What did the poem say?
You still have it? Yeah, I do.
Okay. This is a little slower.
Each time we sing on the way home,
I pray that traffic backs up so we can
sing together just a little longer and
the harmony can go on forever and each
time we reach my door I feel robbed
because we're always in mid song
or mid thought. If only I could.
He gets out and goes inside and
probably thinks, asked them.
I gave her that poem.
She's going to be so smitten
with me and you go home and what
want to throw up. I just
thought, Oh God, you know,
next day I just looked at him and
said, listen, we got to clarify.
This is clearly just going
to be a friendship. He was
seven years older than me.
He had these, uh, brain, uh, you
know, surgery. He has epilepsy,
he's divorced. He has two
children, parish in here.
You're catching the compassion here.
Try, I'm trying. And he's just like,
I'm not asking you to marry me. I'm
asking you to go out on a few dates.
Exactly. If you go out with me like
four times in the next six months,
I'm ahead of the game. He just handled
it and I don't think it was long at all.
I can't even remember. But it wasn't
long at all before we were like a couple
and Kevin, um, I'm dopey.
Dopey in love. Oh yeah. Yeah.
Doing romantic things for her all the
time. Flowers, poems and painting.
Illustration of the Jackson Brown cover.
And within a year we were engaged,
but all the while Kevin
is having seizures. Yeah.
Since the car accident more and more,
there was a point where
we were obviously dating,
she was helping to make his bed and um,
he said she pulled off the pillow case.
It's covered with blood and
one, two, three, four, five,
six of you can count the number
of seizures that I had in vitro,
my tongue and bled.
I knew nothing about epilepsy.
I had never seen anybody
have a seizure in my past.
Those would have been big red flags
that I would've just walked away.
But I just went with it
and they both went with it for a few
years until finally Kevin and Jan decide
this is enough. I wanted to be done with
it. I just needed to be done with it.
So they schedule a brain surgery.
Uh Huh.
Which sounds like a big
deal and obviously it is,
but they had every reason
to think that this wouldn't
change him. I honestly thought that he
was going to come out of it fine. Better
cause that's what happened the first time.
Kevin had actually gone through brain
surgery much like this one once before and
he'd come out pretty much the same
guy. He was still himself. In fact,
he made sure of it. I had a, I was
awake for the surgery and that's crazy.
It was. I had to be awake,
had to do with music.
[inaudible] Kevin is a musician
and the doctors told him,
they said that if I lost anything,
I was going to lose my
appreciation for music,
that it would be like music would
be white noise. I said, you know,
no. For me music was no
is part of my personality.
It was how I coped with my darkest
moments in dealing with epilepsy and
seizures. At 18 years
old, I'd have a seizure.
I take my harmonica and I'd find a place
with decent reverb somewhere and be
right where I needed to be. I
didn't want to lose that part of me.
So as the doctors were doing the brain
surgery, they had his head open, fast,
him to save. You remember what you're
saying? Um, and do the innocence,
some James Taylor and while he's saying
they would tickle different parts of his
brain and if they ever touched the part
that made him stop singing, they'd say,
okay, that's a part we can not take
out. Wow. Yeah. And in the end,
I think they ended up taking out like
four and a half centimeters. Like a girl,
you know, a little bit bigger than
a golf ball. Wow. But afterwards,
as he was recovering,
I had my keyboard in the room and I
tried playing right away, Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah Dah. And it worked.
The part of him that he really
cared about was still there.
Exactly. Yeah. He's the man I fell
in love with after the first surgery.
So I thought, well, you know, now that
you've got to do the second surgery,
he's already been there
on this road, we're fine.
And after that second
surgery, he did seem fine.
Janet didn't have her brother sneak
my, my keyboard up to the room. Yes.
Yeah. He was very, very adamant that he
wanted that keyboard. Played a little,
yeah,
just noodle. A couple of notes, played a
couple of things and it was like, okay,
I'm there, still me. I was ready to go.
So you go home and like
it seems to have worked.
Yeah. As far as seizures go, we thought,
okay, this is it. We're home free.
And uh, I was just happy
to have some normalcy.
But then in the winter, by
beginning in the middle of January,
Kevin noticed he wanted to eat my
physical appetite a lot more than usual.
Got like insane.
This is a guy who didn't eat breakfast.
He had minimal lunch and you'd have
a sensible dinner, maybe a snack.
That was it, but now I could
eat the couch. It just was odd.
It was not him normally, but
you know, you're like, okay.
She thought maybe it's just a
side effect from the medications,
but then the piano, you play
the piano for hours. Same songs.
They used to sing in the car
together. He has stuck on a piece.
He would play for hours. How
many hours? Eight. Eight,
nine and then there was sex. You
know, we were happy, healthy couple.
Kevin's nodding. Yeah. Yeah, it was
fine. But what was abnormal was it was,
it was anywhere. Clearly. It wasn't
like, oh, we're in the supermarket,
let's have sex here. I
mean, it wasn't like that,
but I mean it was like I could just walk
in the kitchen from banging out of work
and he'd be like, Oh, you, let's
go here. Which struck her as weird,
but then again we were thinking, you
know, let's try to have a family.
So the timing made things confusing
and more than that, it wasn't like any
of this stuff was out of character.
Exactly. In fact, it was all
stuff that she liked about him.
Yeah.
Except now it was all turned up to 11
all the things that were wonderful became
chores and that's pretty
much where things are at.
When those federal agents showed up
in July of 2006 I was just completely
blindsided. I said, you know why
we're here. I said, yeah, I do.
I was expecting you. Kevin
took the agents upstairs.
I took them right into here
where my computer was and
they arrested him for what
was on that computer. I gave it
up to him right away. Warning A,
this next passage contains some
graphic imagery. I mean, I, I had an,
I don't know if I had fully,
like I think I had just like let child
porn be this kind of vague thing that
meant as someone younger than 18,
but then I read some of the court
documents and they were like toddlers.
They were picked videos of two,
three, and four year olds. They're,
they're at these sites
had the most despicable,
disgusting things you can, you
can imagine infants on throw,
um, you know, preach preteen and you
know, pre-adolescent you know, in a,
in adolescence and you bought these
things and put them on your computer.
I, yeah, yeah. It, it,
it bothers me. It bothers me.
Like I said, initially it was, you know,
it was just your basic, your basic,
you know, Hetero Heteros,
heterosexual playboy, like penthouse,
like sites.
And then windows were just start to open
up and pretty soon he says he was going
everywhere. There was gay sex. They were,
I mean, there was, there was bondage,
there was a dedication.
Sex, there was animal sex,
Zino sex.
I went everywhere that a
button came up to push.
I, I still don't understand it. I
still, I still don't understand it.
He say it disturbed you and you feel
terrible, but I just like wonder, like,
how do you detail yourself?
Like, that wasn't me.
Like how do you explain it to yourself
too so that you can kind of, I dunno,
not feel like you're as bad
as the person who goes there
without a brain injury is, you know, like,
oh, I know. I
say that again. Ask that question. I
guess I'm just wondering, I don't know.
Like knowing that that's a thing that
you did and it sounds like obviously you
know, that that was bad. It was a
wrong thing. Terrible thing. Um,
but it was, it was you who did
it? Or was it not? I don't know.
You know what I mean? No, it,
it was, it was me who did it,
but it was me with a complete
lack of neurological control.
Yeah. I mean, I, I know, I know who I am.
I did idiotic things that I
couldn't stop myself from doing.
I didn't want to do it. There would be
nights where it would be four or five,
six hours of going to
the same site and and,
and downloading one or two
files and then deleting them,
going back a minute later, downloading
the same files, deleting them.
I would download those files a dozen times
and delete them a dozen times cause I
didn't want to be there,
knew I shouldn't be there and
couldn't help myself from going back.
I'm not an idiot. I mean I'm, I'm,
I'm a smart guy. I'm not an idiot,
but I know I had no control
and that's when he would argue
in court, can we plead guilty?
But at the sentencing hearing,
he asked the judge to be lenient,
arguing essentially that the person
who did all those things in some sense
wasn't him.
It was some other part of his brain that
he couldn't control that the hearing,
he called one witness,
Orrin Devinsky. I'm a neurologist and
epilepsy specialist at NYU Medical Center.
He's been treating Kevin for
decades, 2020 some odd years.
And he says as soon as he found out
what Kevin had been doing had a terrible
sense of of responsibility. This
is because of the brain surgery,
the surgery Orin recommended he have
any argued in court that this was not
Kevin's fault.
I remember looking at those agents right
in their face and saying to them and to
the judge, this could be anybody,
this could be those agents, judge,
this could be you, this could be me,
this could be anybody and we would
have no control over what we did it and
explained to the court
what the biology was.
[inaudible] the way the brain is organized
that there are parts of our brain
that are way deep down that
controls like based desires, hunger,
sex keeps us alive, but it's
teaming with the nastiest thoughts.
We all have these crazy thoughts
in our head now and most of us,
those thoughts are kept in check because
there are other parts of our brain that
sit on top and act like a
lid. But in Kevin's case,
the brain surgeon who did that surgery
removed part of that filter and suddenly
the courtroom
resolved. I mean it was just no lid on.
His sexual desires
is that scientist have known about it
condition for a long time.
They first saw in monkeys
in rhesus monkeys when the
monkeys would lose roughly
the same part of the
brain that Kevin lost.
They became very hypersexual males
that would only previously be sexually
involved with females.
Now we're 10 times more sexually active
with both males and females. David,
it feels to me, it feels
to me like there's a,
there would be a brighter
line before kids, you know,
I think there is a line for
quote unquote normal individuals,
but in a brain disorder case,
those lines get blurred and he told
the court that's what happened here was
black and white. Kevin was sick and his
behavior was out of his control. Well,
that's not what the facts
showed in this case.
This is Lee Barton who was the prosecutor.
We saw no evidence of impulsivity.
He says, if you're claiming
that he had no control,
that his brain made him do it,
then how come he had all this
child porn on his home computer?
I believe it was 52 videos and 125 images.
And yet on his work computer,
there were zero images,
zero videos of child pornography on
his work computer. And he worked a lot.
He held down a job. He
was working every day.
If you truly lacked impulse control,
I would think you would see child
pornography on both computers.
And so what he argued back was,
what was the lid on at
work and off at home?
Seems to me to be an easy out.
So the answer is that this is
common with neurologic disease.
They tend not to be 24, seven is
this take something like Tourette's?
Some people, when they're
engaged in playing sports,
they tend not to have ticks,
whereas when they're sitting
around bored or stressed,
they do tend to have ticks.
So you could say, well,
Therese clearly isn't a
neurological disorder, but no,
Tourette's is a neurologic disorder.
We understand some of the brain
things that go on in Tourette's.
The prosecution didn't buy it,
they just thought it was hogwash.
What was hogwash was
his level of certainty,
um,
depressed skis and asked the Kevin
be sent to prison for five years,
isn't paying for child porn.
He was supporting an industry
that does terrible things to kids.
Kevin hoped he'd avoid jail time
altogether and instead be placed on house
arrest.
That was for Janet. Um,
right after the arrest,
I have to imagine that you were
in shock a little like, yeah,
she'd gone to see a lawyer and
one of the questions he asked was,
is this marriage gonna survive
this? And I said, I don't know.
Ooh.
And at that point,
understanding, I didn't even know
the level of pictures. Yeah.
But she says the moment she heard Orin
say that this was a brain disorder with
the name got Kluver BC syndrome,
once I was able to get that for me.
Hmm.
It clicked. Like you couldn't blame it.
We have these experts saying
that it was a disease.
And I kept thinking they'll understand,
not to mention that after Kevin
was arrested and got an on bail or,
and gave him some medication and Janet
says it was like flipping a switch.
That's exactly what it was. It was like,
yeah, I got him back. Uh, I was able,
I was able to sit and watch a
movie with her, you know, normal.
Janet actually says in a lot of ways,
those few months between the
arrest and the sentencing hearing,
they'd been the best months of the
marriage. He now was just so much easier,
calmer. Uh, you could just talk.
The hearing took about three
hours and when it was over,
the judge took a recess, went into
her chambers. When she came back,
she delivered her decision.
She actually wouldn't
talk to me for the story,
but I have the transcript from
the hearing and if you remember,
the prosecutor of the, our 10 was asking
for five years, 63 months or in Kevin,
Janet, we're hoping for
meaning no jail time.
There's no way they're going to
put them in jail. This is clear cut
and here's what the judge does.
She says, I do agree with orange.
It is a neurological
disorder. No question do.
We can't be held fully responsible
for his behavior. She was getting it.
On the other hand,
she said the prosecution did have a
point that he was very much in control of
his impulses, at least some of the time.
And so the question for the judge was,
how does the legal system assign blame
when a person is sometimes themselves and
in control and sometimes
not? Well, this was a crime,
she said a crime which ultimately
leads to children being harmed.
And considering that you did have
moments where you were in control than in
those moments, you had a responsibility,
you could have done something,
you could have asked for help,
you could have told the people
around you what you were doing.
So even if you couldn't have stopped
yourself, they could have stopped you.
She made it very clear that we have
to do something here. His sentence,
26 months at a federal prison
and 25 months of house arrest.
Okay. And I, I believe, I believe
that she, she was, she was fair
and I, I believe she was compassionate.
And about a week before Christmas
in 2008 Janet drove him to prison.
How long was he in jail for? About
two years and she was even, no,
the judge said, you
know, he is responsible.
Does that change her attitude
toward him at all? No,
they totally stuck together. She
visited him pretty much every weekend.
The whole time
I knew the route and I had my own
little routine down in between visits.
She'd send up notes and I'll never forget,
he could send me mail and they had a
store where he could get some cards super
call murky and he would like alter them.
I remember the very first card I got,
it was this very, you know, beautiful.
Supposedly it's supposed to be beautiful,
but it was like, you know, if you need
anything, you know anything at all,
just let me know. And then he writes,
of course if it's pressing you might
want to ask someone else because Oh well
you can wait 24 months.
And I remember getting that and just
laughing and then that became our thing.
Like listen,
this is a horrible situation but
we're going to make the best of it.
Tell me a little bit about
like where things are at now.
I think things are,
are, are almost normal.
Uh, you know, I, I am still [inaudible]
Oh, probation, but he's home. Um,
he's working. Life is going on.
We have our normal routines.
Kevin still takes those medicines that
keep that other part of him in check.
I mean I have no libido at all,
but I know who I am. I know what I am,
um, um, disturbed by that portion
of my life. But um, yeah, I'm
trying, I'm trying to move on.
[inaudible]
pretty producer Pat Walters.
Thanks also to neurologist or Devinsky
for connecting us to Kevin and Janet.
Stay with us.
We'll be exploring these questions of
blame and responsibility even more deeply.
The next segment, even yell about
it a little. Yeah, come on up.
Hi, I'm nick and I'm from Minneapolis.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing
public understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
I am Robert Krulwich
today on radio lab blame.
In the story we just heard Lee were
wrestling with a very difficult question.
When somebody has a brain
injury and commits a crime,
just how much do we blame them and
how much do we blame the brain? Yeah,
and as it turns out, this question, hi.
Hi, this is Chad. Hi Chad. It's Neda.
That question is popping up more and
more in court cases. We're increasingly,
you will find defendants
like Kevin Arguing, okay,
you've convicted me of a crime,
but you should go easier on me because
I have these neurological problems.
So this is neat.
A fairy haughty professor of law and
philosophy and professor of genome
scientists and policy at Duke University.
She's been following this whole sort of
emerging field of neuro law for quite
awhile and back in 2006
it occurred to her, okay,
lots of people are interested in this
field, but nobody has any good data.
So I started counting cases to try to see,
to try to see how many times does
brain science come up in court. Now,
the only data that she'd get her
hands on were written opinions,
which turns out it
doesn't happen that often.
Like yours really only happens
in like 1% of court cases, but,
but in that 1% of cases she saw
a steady increase and you know,
relatively dramatic. You
have a couple of years,
2005 and six I had about a hundred
cases in (200) 078-9200 some cases.
And then 1112 year in the three hundreds
all told between 2005 and 2012 it's
about 1600 cases,
but 1600 cases that are kind of like the
Kevin Case where someone maybe argues,
look, it's not entirely my
fault. My brain made me do it.
Okay.
At least a little bit.
Yeah. And by the way,
that number was just in
the 1% she had access to.
So the other 99% of cases may
actually have a whole lot more.
Yeah, we'll wait a second. Is this a
new development? What do you mean? Like,
you know, in west side story,
there's this character that officer
crunky and he goes and the these juvenile
delinquents,
this is back in the 50s and they're
saying everything is someone else's fault.
Well,
they have bad parents and
they have poverty and they
have passion and they have
[inaudible]
youth and they plead all these,
their kindness sergeant croppy yet
gotta understand it's just our bring an
uptick that gets us outta hand.
Our mothers solid junkies,
our fathers all are [inaudible]
have you just added to the list tumor?
That's pretty much the same thing.
Well maybe, no,
there seems to be something
more compelling for both
judges and juries when,
when you are able to have actual brain
scans, you know, or EEG or whatever,
because now you can say, look
to officer crump key. Look,
I know this might sound like an excuse,
but check out this spot right here.
Here's the proof. I don't
have a normal brain, you know,
and I didn't choose not
to have a normal brain.
So how can it be
completely my fault? Well,
doesn't that sound a little bit like
a little too easy? Me? Maybe, I mean,
I guess it depends on the specific
case, but just in the abstract.
Let me give you the best version that
I've ever heard of this argument. Okay?
This is what, when what made me really
stop and take it comes from the uh,
from a psychologist Kevin Dutton.
He was interviewed on the scientific
American podcasts and he gave this
hypothetical.
Imagine if you've got a deaf person, okay,
and you've got a child in a
burning building and you've
got that child screaming
out, but the deaf person
can't hear the screams to,
you wouldn't necessarily blame.
You wouldn't hold that deaf
person culpable for that
child's death if the child
died. You agree so far?
Yes. By the same token,
if you are emotionally deaf, if you
can physically hear the screams,
but emotionally you just don't have that
kind of mural kick up the backside to
go in and save that child.
Isn't that the same thing?
And when you start thinking about that,
there's a whole kind of moral conundrum
that starts coming out of that because
damage to the ear is damaged
with physical strikes. Structure
Damage to the brain is also
damaged to a physical structure.
So here's the moral conundrum
I think he's referring to.
If we go along with this idea that we
can use brain abnormalities to defend
ourselves in court,
well that's going to lead us into
some pretty weird places as a society,
things may get very, very
complicated as we learned.
We got into a little tussle. All
right. Okay. Where's this guy?
Sorry. So you put this on, it
is a little chilly in here.
This is David Eagleman.
I'm a neuroscientist. He's
a regular on our show.
Is that what I'm supposed to say or
that really spirited regular? Yeah. No.
Here's one of the most interesting
parts. Here's his argument.
Think about a technologically
at the moment,
our best technologies in
neuroscience are very crude.
We can see when someone has a tumor or
damage from traumatic brain injury or
neurodegenerative disease, but it is
quite crude still the way he puts it.
Looking for those brain abnormalities
now is sort of like being up in space and
looking down at the earth. You can't
really see what's going on down there,
but you can see the big shapes and the
colors and every so often you notice
something that's not supposed
to be there. Like, Whoa,
what does that create over there?
If you see something that's big enough
to see you take a picture or you're back
in court, show it to the judge and
maybe she gives the guy a break,
but then say you're up there and
um, mission control, everything
looks normal up here.
You don't see anything.
Well then back into court,
the judge is going to take a look at
your apparently normal brain and say,
sorry, well that's your fault.
It's not a biological problem.
So we're just going to say you're
blameworthy. So that's where we are now.
We draw the line of what we can see and
what we can see is only the big stuff.
But he says, imagine forward,
we'll have new technologies,
we'll have x MRI instead FMRI.
And suddenly it's going to be like
Google maps where instead of being up in
space, you can,
you can zoom in and now
you can see everything.
We'll have new names for disorders
of the microcircuitry and so on.
We'll certainly never get
all the way to the end,
but one day we may be able to say like
see that little bit of mangled wiring
right over there. That is because
his mom didn't love him enough.
Maybe he got bullied like we will be
able to see all that stuff almost as well
as we can see brain tumors now because
there is nothing special about brain
tumors except for their visibility.
Really what he's saying,
when you get down to it,
his core belief is that
you are your biology,
which is on some level kind
of like whatever, Duh, but
he takes it much farther.
He says that almost everything
that you go through in your life,
all of your experiences, your culture,
your history, your neighborhood,
all of it is etched into the
tissue of your brain, right?
There's nothing separate. Nothing.
They cart famously suggested you've got
the body, you know the physical stuff,
and then you've got this extra bit,
the soul, the ghost in the machine.
[inaudible]
but sort of the, you know the inside word
on that neuroscience, is that eh? No,
no, no. It's all the same thing.
And now that we're beginning to
see that, he says, actually see it,
we are on a slippery slope because if you
start letting people off the hook when
you see a tumor,
well then you're going to have to
keep letting them off the hook.
When you see something smaller
or smaller or smaller, still
the point is it cannot be a just
legal system that in one decade says,
well you're blame worthy because for
the moment we can't see anything in your
brain. And then the next decades is,
oh, you have schmedlin his disease. Hey,
we can see it now. And
we didn't realize that.
So now you were lumping you over here
with the people with the brain tumors.
So then what does that mean? Like we
have to let everybody off the hook.
You know, blame worthiness is the wrong
question for illegal system to ask.
That's the point is that this whole
notion about blame worthiness and saying,
okay,
if we have a biological mitigator then
we'll bring that up in court and we'll
say, well,
it's not exactly his fault and if we
don't have a biological mitigator,
we'll say it is his fault.
The reason none of this makes sense
nowadays is because saying was it the
person's fault or was it something about
his biology doesn't make sense as a
question. They are
inseparable. Why I haven't,
I have a version of that question.
How about everybody should know that his
brain isn't completely normal in this
regard and now the question is proportion,
how much do you want to put on the brain
and how much do you want to put his,
what else is there behavior which comes
in was they ability to choose from the
brain is choosy part of his brain
as opposed to as an choosy pipe.
Well that's okay. I mean
you're forcing. I'm glad you,
I'm glad you're phrasing
it this way because that's
exactly the problem with our
intuitions. We have this intuition that
yeah, your brain might look like this.
You have these genes,
you have these experiences that makes her
biology like this. Oh, but in the end,
that doesn't matter because you've got
this other thing that's independent of
the biology. But we don't, you
arm your brain, your brain,
however, nevertheless helps you
decide things, brains help you choose.
So the question I'm asking you
that they're helping, who's the,
that you're helping the bear of the
brain, the owner of the brain, the, the,
the, and that's separate from
the brain. They'll show you, oh,
I need to keep doing this
to me. I know that I,
if I have a tootsie roll in
front of me in an m and, m,
I can choose the M and m. So I
assume my brain is doing something.
And the question I want to ask is like,
how much am I choosing and how much
am I really outside of choosing?
Because some something irregular
in my brain is choosing for me.
And that seems to me to be a
way to [inaudible]. So this,
but this is fascinating because the
way you're phrasing it suggests that
there's, um,
there's you and then there's your brain
and there's things in your brain that
might be telling you what
you don't want to do.
But it's all one system is the thing.
So when you're faced with the tootsie
roll versus the whatever else, m and m,
everything in your life leading up to
that moment from your genetic history,
written on invisibly small
strands of nucleic acids,
all the way up to every experience
you've ever had leads to that choice.
What would it even mean to make a choice?
Completely independent of your brain.
Okay. [inaudible]
what about like the 10 Commandments?
Those are like the, those were, those are,
okay. I'm just gonna jump in
for a second. At this point,
things kind of slid off the rails.
We ended up talking about
the 10 commandments,
debating the question of freewill
if free will exists at all.
It's a really small part of this system.
I'm going back and forth about whether
you can overcome your upbringing,
which obviously you can. Oh Gosh, no,
you can't share. You can, no, you can't.
I can go to the library and that's only
if you're that type of person. Anyhow,
after an hour, we finally got
back around to David's main point,
which is that the legal system
would be a hell of a lot better off.
He says if a, if we forgot
about blame altogether,
forget if it's someone's
fault. That's a dead end.
He would say the better way to do it,
he thinks is to focus on this
probability of future recidivism.
You mean like will they do it again?
That's right. That's exactly it. Well,
how would you ever know? So
here's how you crunch the numbers.
So this has already happened in the world
of sex offenders where there have been
a longterm studies following out. Here's
the way it already works. He says,
which he thinks is model. When a
sex offender comes up for parole,
someone at the corrections office will
grab their record and ask a bunch of
questions. What was the victim choice?
Was it somebody they knew or was it
somebody outside of their family?
Was it a minor, specific to male or
female? Was it somebody their age,
what was the crime type, all
these different questions.
Then the evaluator will take some
of the answers and give them points.
Three zero to one that
psychologist Amy Phoenix, she says,
researchers develop this point system
based on years of studies of criminal
behavior, massive amounts of data and
once you have all these points down,
then you can add up a total score and
that score is supposed to tell you is this
guy likely to do it again or not?
And here's the bottom line. Amy says,
if you were to ask a parole officer with
decades of experience to just use their
gut, no numbers, we call that
unguided clinical judgment.
If you were to ask them for their
unguided, but expert clinical judgment,
will Fred here recidivate or not? What's
your prediction? According to studies,
those experts are correct
about 50% of the time,
so you may as well flip a
coin. On the other hand,
she says if you have people just use
the point system, no gut involved,
the predictive accuracy
would be about 70% wow.
70% no humans involved. Yeah.
But here's the thing that
sort of gives me pause.
Like in order to get that accurate,
you kind of have to turn people
into data, you know? Yeah. To types.
I know it seems like, Oh, where's
the humanity in that? But,
but the question we have to
ask is, compared to what?
So the way it currently goes,
ugly people get much longer sentences
than attractive people in courts.
This is a well known bias from juries.
Is that somehow better than having a
scientifically informed legal system?
Hmm. I have no response
to that. Dammit. Well,
Robert will.
Yes.
It's okay that pretty people get better
sentences than ugly people because I'm,
I don't know,
I'm going out in the limits of what
happens when I can finish this in all go.
But because what we're describing
here is humans judging humans,
not tables judging humans, not data
judging humans, but humans judging humans.
So you went through that with certain
amount of humanness and maybe it's not
very rational and maybe sometimes
it's wrong headed or unfair,
but if you take the judgment away from
the humans and you give it to a table,
then you invite a different set of
problems, which is the chance for mercy,
which is a very big part of justice is
off the table because statistics don't
have mercy. They just have statistics.
Amen. I'm Oh, nicely
done. [inaudible] that.
But let me say a couple
of the question that,
that is a beautiful question.
And so the notion of we should be
merciful and so of course that's all true,
but the question is, are we good at it?
Are we good at knowing who is the
right person to be merciful with?
It ends up usually being the
attractive person, right?
And the person who's ugly and is missing
teeth were usually not as merciful for
I wish this morning. Let me just throw
in one more objection to this. Uh,
I mean obviously as a point, I guess so,
but this whole thing that he's advocating
for and he's not the only one of
throwing out blame, focusing
instead on what someone might do.
Is that a world you would want to
really live in? Need a fair honey,
that law professor, put it this
way. Imagine you do something small.
So if I, you know, forge a check,
minor offense and in the process
of arresting me and convicting me,
maybe the courts do a brain scan or they
do that number crunching things quickly
and they determine,
actually she has a predilection for far
more serious crimes than check forging.
I mean, she hasn't done any of those
things yet, but she could rob a bank,
she could commit a violent crime.
That's what the data shows.
If all you're worried
about is what she might do,
then you can keep me in prison forever.
Because what you've discovered is that
I pose a real and future danger to
society. I mean,
you could basically convict someone
of a crime that hasn't happened yet.
Exactly. And not only that,
if you think about this whole thing
from a slightly higher altitude,
according to Nita, when you
blame somebody for something,
there's a power to that act that
goes beyond that one individual.
There is value to society holding people
morally accountable for wrongdoing.
You're, you're upholding this code
that is important to all of us.
It's what we've lived by and clung
to for thousands of years. Yeah,
so you could argue that the
act of assigning blame is
sort of like reinforcing
the scaffolding of society. It
creates norms for people to follow.
That makes perfect sense to
me. Otherwise we would be,
well, it'd be like, I
don't know what we'd be
[inaudible]
so, hey, so you're coming out for the
10 commandments at the end of the day.
Wait, wait, hold on. No. Shut that.
Let's just say he went there
and he can't take it back.
Don't draft me onto that team.
This is truly a calling from Washington
d C Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and
by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org.
Ah, three two, one. Hey, I'm Jabu run,
I'm Robert Krulwich today on
radio lab blame. All right.
So tell me your name again. Bianca.
Bianca. Yeah. And I'm a colony name.
Thank you. Yeah. Okay, so this is taped.
It was sent to us by a radio
producer named Bianca Gavir.
It's a time she was in
college just starting out a
bike and across the country.
Yeah. We just got this grant to bicycle
around this summer and talk to you.
Yeah, it's called Davis
projects for peace. Oh Great.
And she was riding through this part of
Tennessee and ended up on this farm type
place where she met this guy. My name is
Hector black. I'm 86,
almost 86 and a half.
When you get as old as I am,
you add the halfs again like
you did when you were three.
And Hector ended up telling Bianca a
story that in many ways turns everything
we've learned in this hour on
its head. Um, so yeah, where's,
where would be the best
parts place to start? I mean,
I think the story starts when he decided
to move to Atlanta because that's where
Patricia was his daughter. Okay.
He had fought in the war as
a combat engineer, world war.
I was not a good soldier. Went to
Harvard, got a degree, met his wife Susie,
and then
did join the civil rights
work in the 60s, I think.
I think when Hector heard about
the civil rights movement,
he actually packed up his bags,
moved to the neighborhood
where Martin Luther King Live,
rented a house and said,
what can I do to help?
I felt that I wouldn't really understand
what was going on unless I lived there.
And that's when he meets Patricia girl
in the neighborhood who came over all the
time, just like a lot of kids.
But she stuck around longer than,
than anyone else. And at 11 years old,
she asked them, will you adopt me?
Why you explaining? Did
you adopt Patricia? What
happened? How'd you [inaudible]
was an alcoholic. Sometimes she
drank up the rent money and,
and the kids were out on the
street with their mom and dad. Mom,
there was no dad. And, uh, so we
took him in and she was very shy.
She had impetigo sores on her
legs in a nappy headed, no,
your mama never braided her hair. She
was just really a neglected child.
And so she just blossomed.
She got into reading, sewing, painting.
She'd make it all her own clothes.
She's making bridal gowns as
a second source of income.
And then she went off to college.
She came back and started teaching kids
to read. She even took in a few kids,
just like he had done, adopted
a couple of kids. Yeah. To,
she's a wonderful child.
So unfortunately the whole story changes
now in November of 2000 because that's
when Patricia
was murdered. I, even, Simpson is
the name of the man who killed her.
He'd broken into her house looking
for money and he strangled her.
And later the autopsy showed he sexually
assaulted her too. At first, you know,
a yellow kill, a bastard. No,
I saw it kind of a monster.
We do a thing like this and he said
for almost a year he could not stop
imagining what he had
done to these visions.
They'd come down and me out
of the blue just hit me.
Oh,
you do again?
Okay.
And you said no control. It
was like he had control over me
pushing my face in the mud
after I haven't had confessed
and this was right, the murder.
Hector said part of him did want
Ivan to get the death penalty.
Yeah, it was furious,
but then this other part of him
was like, no, this is a test.
This was a test of his principles,
of his beliefs and so he decided he
would not pursue the death penalty
it at the trial where he was sentenced,
you refused to look at Ivan.
Trisha's cousin got up first.
She was just in tears and just said how
much she hated him. I thought, oh Lord,
I hear on going to go say something.
It's probably going to hurt her
feelings and when it came his turn,
I had a written statement because I wasn't
sure how steady my voice was going to
be, but I was saying how
much we love Patricia,
how much he meant to us and how
wounded we were by what had happened.
And I said, I don't know if
I've forgiven you Evan Simpson,
but I don't hate you. I hate with all my
soul. Look what you did to my daughter.
And then you worked up the nerve to
turn around to face him to say the last
thing I had written to that is that
I wish for all of us who have been so
wounded by this crime,
I wish that we may find God's peace and
I wish that also for you Ivan Simpson.
And he says when he looked up,
tears are streaming down his cheeks.
Then you know if the first time I,
I looked into his eyes and
it was like a soul inhale
[inaudible]
I was just undescribable looking
in the end, I haven't ended up
getting life in prison without parole.
What happens next was so surprising
and troubling to us, frankly,
that we sent Bianca and our producer
Andy Mills to meet you back down to
Tennessee to talk to Hector again.
Okay, so it's the night after the trial.
Hector is laying in bed
in the material. I
couldn't sleep that night.
And you kept thinking about
that moment in the courtroom.
I've never, I've never had it
looked like that my whole life.
Never before or since.
Over and over and over and
finally he just gets up.
He grabs a pen and paper
and he starts writing.
Dear Ivan, Christopher Simpson,
I am writing because I wanted you to
know how I feel after the court hearing
Monday when I turned around while I was
reading my statement and looked at you,
it was a very powerful moment for me
when you raised your tear stain face to
look at me. Ever since this happened,
I've been trying to find something good
in all the horror and pain I have tried
to be a better person
and then he writes this line maybe as
a way to push himself to be that better
person, but he writes, I
forgive you for what you did
to our beloved daughter.
I don't know if this will be of any
comfort to you, but I wanted to tell you,
we will both have to live our lives
with the pain of this dude always there.
Patricia tried to make
the world a better place.
We should also try
[inaudible].
Did you think he would write you
back after that? I didn't know,
but about four weeks
later a letter shows up.
Yeah. This is it. Dear Mr
Hector, black and family.
I first want to say, God
bless you all in all things.
Second, I have to go
straight to the point.
I know God has forgiven
me. You have forgiven me,
but I can't forgive
myself. Not yet. Anyway.
I have so much anger at myself
right now. It's unbelievable.
This hardness I have against
my, I will always be remorseful.
I used to hear God speak
to me all the time,
but I guess after what I did,
he took away his touch from me.
Right. No, I miss his voice.
I don't know the level of
love Miss Patricia had,
but if it's anything
like your example of it,
it is great. God comfort
you all in everything.
Few free to us. Me, anything you like,
if I can, I will try to answer it.
[inaudible]
dear Ivan, I was very
glad to have your letter.
I think it is important that we be as
honest as possible with one another,
and so I have to tell you that it
is hard for me to write to you.
I wanted to know who he was. I would
really like to hear about your life,
about the people who loved
you, the people who hurt you,
because I wanted to knew what had happened
to him that could make it possible
for me to do with any length is
[inaudible].
Ivan writes, Dear Hector,
I was adopted when I was two
days old as Muslim schizophrenia.
This is Simpson. The one
I call mom now took me in.
He was raised by his grandmother's
sister. She's 82 now.
I used to have to stay over there
with my natural mom while Marie,
my mom. No had to work. Very
natural. Mom used to beat me.
Blurt out. I'm glad I got rid of
you. When he was a little boy,
maybe about 11 or so,
she took him and his younger brother and
his little sister to a swimming pool,
and you tried to drone all
three. One sister died.
He stood there. She drowned his
little sister in front of him,
just the most horrible
stuff. And so we asked him,
having heard all this from Ivan,
did he still blame Ivan or did he blame
his mom or society or something else?
Well, I do blame him. I
mean, he made the choices.
He made the choices.
There's no doubt about that.
But he says, knowing this
also made him wanna write back
[inaudible] dear Ivan, Ivan, about
his life. I grew up in New York City,
his family, two brothers. My
parents argued and fought a lot.
Basically it's whole life story.
I've always loved working with plants.
And after we left to find the
city and move back to the country,
and I wrote back, dear Hector,
I was raised in the church,
but after starting drugs and alcohol,
I changed to responded. Dear Ivan,
I don't think God has
abandoned you dear Hector.
You're the only one writing
to me. No, we exchanged many,
many letters
and at some point in this back and forth,
this almost incomprehensible
thing happens. Dear Hector,
their letters,
first of all, thank you for the pictures.
I never knew. Plum trees blossom.
Really just become casual.
My favorite bloom is the waterlily
blossom. They talk about flowers.
It's beautiful things. They'd I
even, thanks for your letters.
I've been closing a story someone said
to be because I thought you would enjoy
it. Do you Hector? Just the most
mundane details of their day.
Just sitting around this Saturday
evening been singing him as to myself.
Basically they became friends.
You knew Hector. You're right.
I do sense a bone developing unusual
because of the circumstances pitch.
Just not at all what I
expected to happen, you know,
and it's just so absolutely crazy.
Yeah,
you're actually,
gosh [inaudible]
it. We, we,
we started to send him Christmas packages
and we see this box on the floor and
I'd say to myself, are you crazy old man?
You're Sidney Christmas packages for
the man who murdered your daughter.
What the Hell is [inaudible]
with you? Just so cross.
So totally out of that goes out of
orbit or something and I guess I was,
because people don't do that.
Maybe I'm trying to exact meaning from it.
I don't know because I
struggled so hard with
why I
actually,
after years of writing letters,
Hector decided to ask that why question
and its most essential form what
happened that night.
This one, this one. I just want you to
know if you don't want to read this.
Oh yeah, we don't. We don't want to make
you read this if you, if you're not,
if you're not ready. I don't think it's,
this might be a good time to say that.
This next part is disturbing.
If you have kids or you're
just not in the mood,
now's a good time to duck
out for a few minutes.
Dear Hector, I wasn't going to tell
you. Oh what happened until you asked.
I'm also glad you're
relieving me of details. Also.
God bless you.
I went into the house around 7:30 PM
I'm used to breaking into place in the
past, so I figured the
house was total dark.
Soil broke out a whole
window and climbed in.
I took the VCR and TV and clock.
I figured that was enough.
Went and got $80 worth of
drugs or the heavy users.
So it went in about one hour.
So he made his way back to Trisha's house.
It was still dark. So I went back in,
he found his way into the bedroom,
so a computer in Stereo.
So I said I take it and that
should last for the night.
But I got trapped when I saw a car,
so I hid until I could get
back out the way I came.
So I saw a lady walk to the room.
I tried to be quiet so I could escape.
When she opened the door to a closet,
I was hiding. As she
stepped back, she fell.
I told her I was going to tie her up
so it would have time to get away.
She said, okay sir.
Her glasses fell off and
in no time she saw my face.
So I told her I was going to take
the car so I could load it up.
She gave me the keys, so I told her
after I found out her name, I said,
Patricia,
I know you're scared but I will be
out of here in about 15 minutes.
Then she said, you should get
help with your drug problem.
I told her I tried in the past, but
I restarted or glad. Yeah, that's,
that's Trish.
She had no compunctions about telling
people when they were in the room and then
I said, I'm sorry for this.
I'm going to leave your car in the
shopping center up the street next to the
Chinese restaurant because all I need
the car for was to transport the items I
had
and even though Trish was
tied up around her hands,
she went to the kitchen and warmed
up some chicken and rolls for Ivan.
Then I said, I'm sorry, and I left again.
I got rid of the things,
got about $200 well a hundred
dollars drugs and $100 cash.
Then I said, well, I just the
car at the end of the driveway.
Then I couldn't wait. I pulled over
and smoked some of the crack cocaine
and at this point he's really high and
he explained that when he gets this high,
he's sometimes here's a male voice in
his head and as he was walking away,
the voice said to him,
he said, well, go get you some sex.
I told him, leave me alone, but next thing
I know I'm walking back to her house.
No police had come.
He burst through the door, ran to
where Patricia was tied up and said,
did you have any money? Cash?
She said, look in my purse.
And then Ivan said that the voice in his
head became his own voice and he said
to her,
I want some sex. She said, sure,
you've been so nice. Why don't do that?
Yeah.
D said, only way you going
to do this if I'm dead.
[inaudible]
okay then and it happened.
He strangled her, sexually
assaulted her, then he ran away.
Sure. Around 2:00 AM I ran out of drugs.
You said that after he
finished getting high,
he started to wonder if
he had dreamt it all up.
So he made one last trip
back to Patricia's house.
So I looked up at the house, no police,
engaged to Lope and so now peeps through
the door, she was still laying there.
So I said Patricia, Patricia,
and then the voice in his head told
him to go back in one more time.
He sexually assaulted her.
I couldn't believe what happened.
So when to my mom has adopted
mother and I said, Mama,
it's something wrong. Moma,
something wrong. She said, child,
tell me what you're talking
about. I couldn't tell her
[inaudible]
I was really hoping they would kill me
in the electric chair because I could,
I shouldn't be able to live with
myself and God after what I had done.
I just don't know why I had to do it.
Was it because of the
items in the money? No.
Getting caught later on in life.
No control or power? No car?
No. Because she saw my face. No,
she didn't see me at no time.
Fingerprints left on something.
No, I just don't understand why I did it.
[inaudible]
well, I feel the pressure has left me
for telling you first what happened.
My mom doesn't even know.
I've been keeping all this
inside and it hurts. So
I'm truly sorrowful for what happened.
May God bless you all sincerely. Ivan
did it, did it help in any way to know?
Yes,
cause I mean I that
sounded exactly like Trish,
but she was, she was
to really the fearless,
I mean a machine. Mr Burrito, I
can't imagine what a horrible,
Oh God, I was just
amazed that
she could be so strong
just to be raised because when you love
somebody very much, you want to know
about their last hours
and uh,
he, he just, yeah,
he just wrote it in a way that I found
very kind.
I mean if you go kind is
a weird word to put there.
[inaudible]
but that's the word he chose.
Hello
kind
[inaudible]
after that letter, they still
right? Yeah, they still write,
they've been writing for 10 years now and
Hector has folders and stacks of these
papers in his basement. So only room
in his house that he keeps locked.
[inaudible]
pretty sure Bianca gave her
thanks also to our own Andy Mills.
Thanks to you for listening.