You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N Y Weiss,
c e n n p. R.
[inaudible].
Hey, I'm jabbing rod
and I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab in the couple of
days ago as in like seven we uh,
we were on stage at the Brooklyn Academy
of Music, the big opera house there.
It's a really beautiful theater and
it was full of more than 2000 people.
We were part of something
called Radio Love Fest.
Brilliant
radio.
OFS is a big public radio broadcasting
radio lovey thing that w NYC station here
puts on.
Basically it's a parade of all these
amazing public radio shows and podcasts.
We opened the festival and since
it was called radio love fest,
we figured we would use the opportunity
to basically talk about the community of
people around radio lab that we
love, the producers, the musicians,
we features amazing acts like so
percussion who you're hearing.
A lot of stuff happened and we
told a lot of stories today.
We're just on this podcast.
We're gonna [inaudible]
play two stories for you. These are
both stories about love and about heart.
The last one, which you'll hear is a,
is an exclusive interview
with Oliver Sacks.
Basically giving a kind of valedictory
interview. It's pretty wonderful.
But first we decided to do
literally a look at a heart.
This comes from our producer Molly
Webster. It was scored live by a,
so percussion, which is Eric
Chubb Beach, Josh Quillin,
Jason Trudy and Adams Lewinsky. Oh.
And some people in the audience in the
theater audience had a pretty strong
reaction to what you were about to hear.
And we're not so sure that that might
not also be the case if you're just
listening. So if you are driving
or you're operating machinery,
maybe this isn't the best piece to
listen to because it can get a little
intense, which we'll talk about a little
bit afterwards. Uh, in the meantime,
here's producer Molly Webster.
So this is a story about
a friend, summer ash. Uh,
we used to work together and I think
it's fair to say that summer has a
complicated relationship with her heart.
You know, my heart was not beating
for three hours is a really crazy thought.
Yeah, I was technically,
I don't know. So a couple of
things to know about summer.
She's like wicked smart.
She's an astrophysicist.
She uses a lot of big words,
propulsion, center of gravity and
moment of inertia, x and Y, Z axis.
Do you remember that original
like radial keratotomy like no,
I don't even know what that word is.
The other thing to know is
she's an engineer, right?
So she loves like take things apart.
You sort of like coke around rewire,
ratchet. You got a ratchet.
And so the thing to know is when she
found out she had to get heart surgery,
she made sure there was someone in the
operating room with a camera taking
pictures of my open chest cavity and the
valve and when things were cut and when
things were being sown in. Yeah,
I totally approached this
completely as a scientist.
I want to know what's
happening. I want to know why.
I want to know what you're doing. I want
to know what's going on around. Yeah.
And in any case, to sort
of back up and explain, um,
summer was just following up on like a
heart diagnosis that it had happened.
About 15 years earlier. And so she
had been diagnosed with a murmur,
which is basically just like
a funny sound in your heart.
And that's like a wash in between
the thump, thump, thump, thump.
And in summer's case she had
been told it's no big deal.
And so this was just a
followup appointment to make
sure nothing had changed.
And so she goes to the doctor, she,
they run a few tests and then they send
her on her way and a few weeks later she
gets an email saying don't panic,
but I think you should
see a heart surgeon.
So
it turns out the situation with
her heart had changed her aorta,
which is like the largest
artery coming out of her heart.
It was larger than it should have been.
So it's supposed to be about
two centimeters in diameter.
And in summers case it was five. Yeah.
What does that mean for your bodies?
So that's the thing. It's a seven
dometic. It's not actively harming you,
but it's a threat to your
life because if it ruptures,
it's your main blood
vessel. And if it goes,
you bleed out internally so
fast that no er can help you.
Her doctor says go find a heart
surgeon. And in the meantime,
no heavy lifting or contact sports in
summers. Like, well I live in New York,
like living in New York as
the contact sport. Yeah,
I was gonna say if people crash
into you all the time. Yeah.
Six months later, summer finds herself
on the operating table. They actually,
um, I think, I'm not sure the
exact order of operations,
but they cut open her sternum from the
bottom all the way up to the top and then
they just like, oh,
the rib cage so they can get at her heart.
They put some sort of fluid on it that
stops it from beating and they actually
sort of just inject that fluid into the
heart and that short circuits it so your
heart actually stops and then
they hook you up to a bypass,
a heart lung bypass machine.
And one of the things that does is it
drains the heart of all it's blood.
And so it's like flat, like a pancake.
And you can see pictures
of all of this on her blog.
You can even see pictures. It's true.
You can even see pictures of the a surgeon
cutting four inches out of her aorta
and replacing it with a synthetic tube
and the entire time summer's heart is
just lim in quiet.
Okay.
Eight hours later she wakes up.
Yeah.
What do you remember about your first
conversation with your doctors? Oh,
I don't remember my
first conversation much,
but I do vividly remember my first
thought part of my friends was,
fuck, this hurts.
Just mind altering pain.
Oh my God. Eight hours ago I
felt so much better than this.
Can we just go back to that now?
Like, no, I don't want this. You know,
everything pulls on your torso and so
when your sternum has been cut open and
then reconnected,
everything that pulls on that hurts
and you can't move anything or lift
anything.
It hurt to talk. It even hurt to breathe,
but literally from day
one they make you stand up
and start walking. Really.
I was like, she was like,
we're going to get you to sit and
shower. I was like, no, no, we're not.
What are you talking? What are
you smoking? And that's just to,
that's just to basically, you just got
to get the heart going again, you know,
just get it healing.
But here's the thing, when it came back,
it came back with a
vengeance. So to be fair,
her recovery went really well. About
two months in, she's in cardiac rehab,
the pain is fading. She's thinking
about sending her mother home.
Her mom had been staying with her for
awhile and then one day she's in cardiac
rehab on the elliptical machine.
And so I remember stopping and I had, um,
this white tee shirt that would
literally like just be fluttering
[inaudible]
with my heartbeat. Like it was
blowing in, in high wind or something.
And I was like, well that's interesting.
You mean that you could see it?
Oh yeah. Yeah. Even the physical therapist
there could see it. What do they do?
They do. You mean like you would look
down and you would see the thing,
your heart beating through your
chest wall, pushing your shirt? Yeah.
Off your chest. Well because I'm
a lady, there was a gap here.
So like that sort of, there's a space for
that vibration to happen, so to speak.
But then she goes home and
it was still happening,
like just sitting on her couch, not
even working out. She's like, Whoa,
my heart is strong. It
just felt so strong that I,
part of me was like, am I going crazy?
Like is it as strong as it seems
like it is? Because if it is,
surely this is making a noise. So one day,
a few months after surgery,
she goes to upstate New York,
she's visiting some family friends and
she's hanging out with their daughter
Julia.
She walked in and we
were standing in my room,
you're just chatting. And then
suddenly Julia's eyes get really wide.
And I was standing there just,
oh my gosh, I just to skirt it.
She could hear summer's heart out loud
two feet away from her in the room.
And I was like, okay,
this is happening. Uh,
so I guess in typical summer fashion,
she's Kinda like, let's engineer that.
If a friend of mine can hear it with
their ear and what could a studio pick up?
So she grabs her radio producer friend,
they go to a studio and he sticks a Mike
about six inches in front of her chest.
And this is what they recorded.
[inaudible]
this is not a stethoscope.
This is what it sounds like.
If you were standing at quiet
room next to summer, God,
that's strong. What does that feel like?
It just feels as if my entire rib cage,
my clavicle, my sternum,
my whole chest cavity
is acting like an amp.
And it's sort of transmitting
the vibrations of each
heartbeat in physically in
my body to feel each RP. Yeah.
Do you feel it right now? Yeah.
You can just feel that thump. Thump. Yep.
It feels like somebody has a rubber
mallet and is banging on the inside of my
store and it's very staccato.
She goes back to the doctor,
she's like, dude, my heart.
So he sort of just did some like
listening and some feeling [inaudible] you
know? And his reaction to was
like, yeah, that's strong.
So we run some tests and he's like,
listen, your blood pressure is fine.
All of your stats are fine. So I
guess I did a really good job. Yay.
Good for you. But, but okay. I guess I
have a strong heart. Yay. Strong heart.
But I don't want to feel this all the
time. The doctor was like, Whoa, Whoa,
whoa. I don't freak
out. This will go away.
It's probably just that there's
scar tissue on your sternum and it's
transmitting the vibration and is that
goes away. The sensation should fade.
He said sometimes six to nine months is
when maybe the Scar Tissue Heals more
thins out. So she's like, all right,
nine months. Oh, I can get to that.
That's no problem.
So she sorta just settled in and
treated it like a scientific curiosity,
like a party trick. If I went to, um,
a restaurant where they
had like tables for two,
but they weren't like
the sturdiest of tables.
If we had water glasses on them and
I, I sort of leaned on the table,
like the water glass would
look like Jurassic Park.
Like my heartbeat would be like
the footsteps of the Toyota Sys.
Yeah. So that was like my party's drag.
Do you had six months of elation
party trick and then, yeah.
And then it stopped being a
party trick it sounds like. Yeah.
What happened and I'm not really
sure like you know incident wise,
I think for me it was just time passing
cause that nine month mark just came
and went and it was still there and when
she asks her doctor, he has no idea why.
So 12 months still there,
15 months it's still there and she says
it just started getting really annoying
if it's distracting. The,
the funny thing was the more active I
was than the less aware of it I was.
But she says when she was at her office
trying to be still be still to either be
writing something, writing
emails, planning lectures,
that's when it would be like
really loud. That's when it would
become the most dominant thing. Like I,
I couldn't go to work because it just
kept drawing my focus and when it did it
would just fill her with anxiety.
It was sort of this like automatic
response, and I'll try and explain it,
but it's basically like
when you get scared,
it goes into your brain and then
the signal goes down into your body.
So you step on a snake and your brain
is like, oh my God, it's a snake run,
body run, and then your heart
pounds. In Summers case,
it was just the opposite. There was
no snake, but her heart was pounding.
So her brain would be like, Whoa,
why is my heart pounding? Oh my God,
is there a snake? There must be a snake
run body run in her heart would pound.
My brain keeps thinking something
must be wrong because we're having,
we're already doing this,
so something must be wrong,
so I guess something's
wrong. So let's freak out.
She was caught in this feedback loop
and then she was like rightly so,
edgy and primed that any emotion on top
of that, like even if it was happiness,
was just too much. Oh my gosh. Yeah.
Nights. It would keep me awake.
I would focus on it.
[inaudible]
I would get into hearing the
rhythm, feeling the rhythm
[inaudible]
yeah, sort of with the expectation of just
next one. Next one.
Next one. Next one.
Next one. Next one. Next one. Next one.
Next one. Next one. Next one.
Next one. [inaudible]
with every beat.
Our hearts are just literally tapping
out time and I mean researchers have
actually thought about this and there
was this idea that was proposed like a
right before the dawn of sort of modern
heart surgery that we each get 1 billion
beats in our lifetime and then that's it.
And most of us don't notice them going by,
but in summer's case
she can't not notice it.
Yeah, I'm aware of it
all. It's never not there.
It's never not noticeable that
maybe it's just like this constant
awareness of the future that summer is
endlessly meditating on.
My heart takes over and I can't do the
things that I want to do and not knowing
if that's going to last forever or if
it's going to end suddenly or if it's just
going to Peter out. The
not knowing gets to me.
So she stopped going out as much and
she stopped returning phone calls except
for like a few close group of friends.
Times were just being curled
up in bed and just crying.
It really wanted to yell
at my heart, shut up. Stop.
Which you really talk to your heart. Well,
I mean I would never had conversations
but I would be like shut the fuck up.
But it wouldn't.
And as time went on, like
the constant pounding,
it just became unbearable. She just
scribes it as like this alien creature.
It's like trying to just claw it's way out
the bottom of my neck.
[inaudible] fine.
But there was this one moment right in
the middle of [inaudible], middle of
all of this.
She had her two year checkup postsurgery
and for that they had to take a picture
of her heart. So I schedule my two year
appointment and to look at her heart,
they do an echocardiogram,
which is basically,
you know like the ultrasound like
that you get for the pregnant.
Oh it's like a wand.
Yeah. It's like a little,
a little wand and you get the jelly and
they basically go all over your upper,
you know, the area around your
heart and from all different angles.
So what ended up happening is I'm lying
on my left side and I'm facing the wall
and the technicians behind me and the
technician is sort of like reaching around
her,
waving the wand over her heart and the
monitor for the echocardiogram is behind
summer so she can't see it,
but she's wearing eyeglasses.
So you know how you can
sometimes like see a reflection,
a peripherally on your glasses of
something that's like behind you.
Like if you are in a somewhat
darker room, there was a window,
like you would totally see the reflection.
So the room's a little bit darkened.
Summer's lying there on her side and
she sees the reflection of the screen,
um, on my glasses and it catches your eye
because it's moving and then I realize
what it is that I'm,
I'm seeing a tiny reflection of her
heart beating and I have this like moment
[inaudible]
I have this moment where
I'm like, oh my gosh your,
I'm like talking to my
heart and in my head going,
well we had your working hard.
Like you're trying your hardest,
you're doing the best that you can. I'm,
I'm doing the best that I can.
You're in there and you're working and
you are working for me and we are on the
same team and I just totally like,
I just silently start crying.
No
like what do you think spurred that on?
Like what was it about seeing it or
there's just something about physically
seeing it but feeling it at the same time.
Like knowing that I'm seeing what's
happening inside me that somehow just like
clicked this understanding into place.
She said there was something
about seeing it in real time,
like feeling this thing in her chest,
just pulsing in rhythm with what was
happening on the screen and then suddenly
it just, it didn't seem
separate from her anymore.
And all of those worries about the
future and what was going to happen and
wasn't going to go away and every,
she's just stopped. She was just like,
no,
you are just beating and that
beating is me. It was sort of,
it was sort of like this moment of,
of recognition of its
purpose and its work and,
and sort of this,
so it's kind of like that whole idea of
when you feel like you see somebody not
just physically, like you see who
they are, you see what they are,
but you see who they are. Like I had
that, like I felt like I see you heart,
like I see what you're doing, I
see what your purpose is. I see.
I see you.
On the one hand, what she sees
like with her engineer's brain is,
oh I get you. You're just a pump.
And it's that same, you know,
realization that essentially
led to modern medicine. Right?
Like the minute we took the soul out of
the heart, we were willing to touch it,
to cut it open, a stitch it
up to start fixing things.
And now we have lifespans by some
estimates are 2.5 billion beats.
But on the other hand, like when
you hear someone's heartbeat,
your parents or your child's in
that beat is an entire lifetime.
It's a, it's a history of beats.
It's a series of beats yet to come.
And I don't know, thinking
about all that, I just,
I just sort of got walloped at
the end of this interview. Um,
when summer asked us if we wanted
to try and listen to her heart.
Can we try that? Just see
you. Do you want to, yeah,
let's just move the mic or
I'll stand up or something.
So she stood up from her chair and she
sort of put her chest right in front of
the mic and then we all
just got really quiet. Okay.
Oh my God. Oh my God.
Oh my God. Wow. It's this made,
it makes me really emotional.
Every time I hear it, it
makes my eyes, well it's here.
It's really amazing. I guess I still got
kitchen art. You Go. Yeah.
So give it up for Radiolab
producer Molly [inaudible]
[inaudible] and give it up the soap for,
yeah. When you said earlier that a lot
of people in the audience had a strong
reactions, usually we met, I mean I
don't know if you could tune this in,
but like
when we were doing that story I just
definitely seem like something's going on
out there. I couldn't tell cause we
were on stage, I couldn't, you know,
this is their 20 I
definitely was tuning in.
There's something going on in the
audience, something going on side stage,
but I didn't really know what it was.
We were in the middle of it walk off
stage and the first thing we hear is that
numerous people had fainted, even vomited
during that piece. We were like, what?
Seriously? I did not see a
coming. No, we were really,
really scared at first and I thought,
oh my God, am I, am I killing people?
What just happened. I'm like, like it
was just like, I was like, were they old?
Were they young? Like
what? Like why were young,
they were young and that
made me like, oh okay.
They feel like weirdly a
little bit better. Maybe
they can handle it. And yeah,
I just was, and then I, it was kind
of weirdly mortified. Terrified.
But after we figured out that no
one was hurt, we were like, we got,
we were like, we would,
we do start putting out and we started
making some calls cause we were like,
what was that? What did we make of that?
What is that good? I didn't know you.
So the show is over and we all go home.
This is days after this is days and you're
thinking, oh my God, we're going to,
yeah, cause I'm thinking we've got
a podcast, this damn thing, right?
We have to,
we have to understand this and say
something that's completely right.
So the first person we
called a was a psychiatrist,
Rachel Yehuda, Mount Sinai School of
Medicine, Department of Psychiatry.
I explained to her the basic situation
that that some people had fainted and
felt woozy. We weren't
quite sure how many,
five or six people out of 2100,
somewhere between five
and a 12. We don't have a,
a clear number just yet.
That's very interesting.
Do you have any sense of what might've
caused this? Just like a guess.
So my best guess about that would
be that they have activated their
parasympathetic nervous system in
response to hearing the heartbeat.
Yeah. Just to explain.
Our autonomic nervous system is divided
into a bunch of different parts.
You've got your
sympathetic nervous system,
which is sort of your
fight or flight, right?
Sweat turns on when you're scared and
then you got your parasympathetic nervous
system, which is sort of the opposite.
Rather than getting you ready to
fight or run, it makes you calm.
And Dr you Hooda says it in certain
people that parasympathetic response can
actually kind of go overboard and
there lud pressure can drop quickly too
quickly and they end up fainting.
Now, the most common, um,
stimulus for this to happen in,
in real life is failing
at the sight of blood.
Some people just do that and it's not
that common about two to 4% of the
population have this kind of a response.
And we don't exactly know why it happens.
There is some opinion that the idea
of fainting when you see blood,
is it an adaptive evolutionary response
that you know, maybe back in the day
when we were being chased by predators,
it would have been a good idea to faint
because maybe the animal
will think you're dead.
Then he'll skip you. He wants a live
meat and you're dead meat. Exactly.
He sees you laying there and he's like,
I don't want to eat that. What he bet.
Another theory is this isn't
also an evolutionary one,
is that if your blood pressure
drops like it does when you faint,
well that kind of protects you a little
bit because you'll have less blood in
your arms and legs. So if your arms
and legs get bitten by a lion, say,
then you're less likely to bleed out.
Mm. Let me see. So there's nothing,
there's nothing juicy to suck on if your
blood is on not in your wing or your
limb. Yeah. And basically, I mean,
who knows, these are just stories,
but going back to the two or 4% thing,
we got to thinking two to 4% of
our audience that night would be,
what do we decide Molly was
like 40 people, 44 to 88,
44 to 88, 2100.
So we put out some emails, uh,
looked at the incident reports and I
think now we have identified how many,
what do we get to for us, we've heard
of maybe 10 or 11 at this point,
10 or 11 net.
But I think that based on some of the
stories that are coming in that the number
might actually be much higher than
that cause it was, um, for example,
it just manifested itself physically in
a way that I could not have imagined a
would be the case. This
is Maria Checo who, uh,
actually works the street from us, uh,
for the company that makes Latino USA.
I was sitting in the front,
uh, against one of the walls,
but not right at the wall. She says,
uh, she was listening to the story.
Everything was fine at first, but
then she says, as the beat kept going,
she began to worry,
what if it never stops?
What if summer never
gets away from it? And,
and then the drumming got more
intense and it was just like, oh no,
oh no.
And it was definitely the sense of being
trapped that the thing that was giving
her life, which was absolutely necessary,
was also the thing that
was tormenting her.
And she says that she
was thinking about that.
She just kinda got short of breath.
And so I looked at my husband
and put my hands up like I like,
I gotta go. And he, he looked at
me, he was like, are you all right?
And I was like, I shook my
head like, no. And um, and I,
and then I had the talk
in my brain like, okay,
this is an intimate radio moment.
You are right in the front area.
If you get up six people have to
get up with you, what are you doing?
You're ruining this for everybody.
Just breathe and it'll be fine.
And then the deeper I tried to breathe,
the more anxious I sort of got like,
oh, and I had this fantasy of like
standing up and doing like a room
to wiggle it out of me.
But I was like, that's
just to suck it up. And
so Jeez, look at that.
I'm having trouble breathing
just thinking about it.
[inaudible] I don't want to put you
back there. No, no, no, no. I'm fine.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
But that's why my hunches at there
might be a lot more than 10 because uh,
maybe a lot of people just sort of
pushed through and didn't get up.
It still felt weird. In any case,
one of the most interesting things that
we bumped into is that Dr Yehuda told us
it's very possible that the
fainting and the wooziness. Okay.
He's some kind of an empathy response.
Really. In what sense?
Well,
if you hear somebody's heart beating and
you're aware that that's what you are
hearing,
it might arouse a tremendous connection
within you of hearing the very source of
their life. Yeah.
I became her. I did. I
just, I was there with her
can really be a lot to take in and
you feel a little faint or emotional.
I just identified so much with somebody
being trapped in their own body.
It's like she couldn't escape.
It was beating in my chest. Wow.
The drums I felt were beating in
my chest and in my crazy fantasy.
You know, maybe they were
breathing at the same rhythm.
One of the people that emailed that to
the live show said that he felt like his
heart was trying to match her beat
and he couldn't catch his breath.
I don't know. I haven't, I don't know.
It's never happened to me before. No.
Wow.
I asked her in the end if she'd ever
want to hear summer's heartbeat again and
she said, oh yeah. In fact,
she said she was going to listen to
the story as soon as it was podcasts,
which is now because now she's got all
these questions like was it the acoustics
of the space or the fact that she was
with so many people or maybe it was the
volume cause it was pretty loud and
will I feel the same when I hear it,
you know, with my headphones on or
you know, while I'm driving we'll,
I have that feeling.
So I had already decided that I was
definitely going to listen to it again.
We'll let you know what happens.
[inaudible]
sure. We got a break. Just want
to say this. So percussion.
Who provided all the music so far? Um,
they've just released an album called
music for wood and strings written by
Bryce deserter of the national.
This is what you're hearing. It's,
it's kind of an amazing piece.
[inaudible]
if you want to check it out, go to,
so percussion.com we'll also link to it
from a radiolab.org this is Charlie from
Brooklyn. Radiolab is supported in
part by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hey guys, this is Alison
calling from Luxembourg.
Radiolab is supported by rocket
mortgage by quicken loans.
Rocket mortgage brings the mortgage
process into the 21st century.
With this completely online process,
safely share your bank statements and
pay stubs with the touch of a button.
Ditch the paperwork and use your phone
or tablet to get approved for purchase or
refinance in minutes.
Get a custom mortgage solution
whenever and wherever you want.
Check out rocket mortgage
today@quickenloansdotcomslashradiolabequalhousinglenderlicensedinallfiftystatesandanlsconsumeraccess.org
number 30 30 hi
Robert Krulwich. Radiolab is
supported by Google and Squarespace.
Make your business official
with Google and Squarespace.
When you create a custom domain and
a beautiful business website with
Squarespace, you'll receive
a free year of business,
email and professional tools from Google.
It's the simplest way to
look professional online.
Visit squarespace.com/google
to start your free trial,
use the offer code document for
10% off on your first purchase.
Google and Squarespace. Make it
professional. Make it beautiful.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich Radiolab and we're
back now going to take you back live on
stage at the Brooklyn Academy of Music.
And this next store you'll hear
some references to some pictures,
which obviously you won't be able to see,
but we've got them for
you@radiolab.org um,
so we want to finish the night with a
salute to a guy who's been on our program
and part of our family pretty
much from the beginning.
I have known him for more than 35 years.
Early on when Radiolab started,
I asked him if he'd help us out
and send us a few story ideas.
He didn't send us a few. He sent us
bushels, tales of chemistry and medicine,
hallucinations, music
people,
so many extraordinary people that he
knew or found or help cause the guy just
doesn't run out. Dr. Oliver Sacks.
[inaudible] is a guy who
he notices everything.
He's deeply interested in.
Everything that happens
around him and to him.
And tonight we're bringing him back on
tape for what Alaska may be his final
offering for us. As many of you know,
Dr Sachs recently was diagnosed with liver
cancer and he wrote about this in the
New York Times. He said he plans
to spend the time that he has, uh,
left writing being with
friends, not doing interviews,
but he did agree to share his
thoughts exclusively with,
with us tonight for you gathered here.
Um, cause he's one of our family.
So as I've done for decades now,
I went over to his house in Manhattan
with my Mike and I said to him,
I just need to know like what, what
just happened a month and a half ago.
You were fine. And then what? Um,
at the beginning of the year I
was fine. On the 3rd of January,
I felt a little queer and I pass some
dark here and I thought I had a little
gallbladder attack and um,
didn't pay that much attention but
thought I better get things checked.
And um, the extra way,
which was expected only to
show a couple of gallstones,
showed hundreds of cysts in my liver.
Uh, although my doctor said
he didn't know what the, his,
what and I would need further
tests, I, I knew what they were.
I said, it's happened
and he was right.
The doctors eventually confirmed that
a cancer that had been found in his eye
nine years ago had spread
to his liver. Where you
frightened or relieved or console or what,
what? No, I,
I think my first feeling was
one of of overwhelming sadness.
Um, there are all sorts
of things I will see. Um,
and I won't do one or two people have
written to me in the know consoling me and
said, well, you know, we all die, but
fuck it. It's not like we all die.
It's like you have four months.
Has that has your pro, what is
your prognosis at this moment?
Cause I know you had an
well it's, it gets revised.
It depends on of course on how the
cancer responds to treatments and or how
quickly it spreads so far. Um,
the metasticies from my eye,
I only in my liver I'm told they love
liver actually I love liver as well and
one of the magical things I did was to
go and have live one on the sued often
the backers and thinking
that liver looks better than mine.
See this is what he's like instead of
being frightened by the thing is trying to
kill him.
He's thinking about loving liver and
liver lovers and looking for connections
and wondering and he doesn't stop. He,
he just notices that the case in point a
few months ago, his doctor said to him,
we're going to run a,
a line up your liver and in effect we're
going to try to shave off a starved
some of the cancer cells first on one
side then on the other to see if we can
give you a little more time. But they
warned him as the metasticies die.
They um, put out various unpleasant
chemicals that may exhaust you,
tax your system badly.
And um, at one point,
shortly after the procedures,
I started talking a
little strangely and um,
as I was talking I was also writing, um,
you'll be the first person to see this.
So he showed me a notebook and we're
showing it to you in just a moment and you
can see they're sort of writing
there on the left. It's all,
he's writing a book, actually a children's
book about the elementary table.
But as he was writing, if you,
if you look to the next page,
if you can see that it gets a little
bit wobbly, the letters and then,
and then there was some crossing
out there. Yes, I see. And then La,
the dramatically, the lighting
changes it actually there is,
there's a large slash
across it and then you,
it seems a little incoherent
at the bottomless. Okay.
And then it turns to pure scribble
that has delirium and crept up on me.
All this happened over the course of 10
minutes and I see what he's doing here.
He's figuring, okay, I'm
riding at a constant speed.
I know pretty much how fast I
right, and so I can time this out.
I can figure out exactly how long it took
me to slip into delirium and then out
of this delirium and he's doing this
very, very sick man. It's science.
The time to write it out
in a more medical way.
I think this would form
a lovely illustration.
You put in a timeline of
delirium just coming like that.
Why aren't you more frantic?
Unusual for any doctor
and as a man of science,
you don't seem to worry at all. When
things become incoherent or strange,
you're now showing it to me as
if like, Ooh, how interesting.
I was crazy here for a little bit.
The truth is Oliver is fascinated
by what goes on in the human mind.
No matter how strange it gets up there.
At one time when he was a young
resident in California driving his bike.
And by the way,
I should show you what he looked like
back then when he was driving his bike.
This I think is him in New
York, a kind of, you know,
in the 60s he was also a champion
weightlifter. They called him Dr Squat.
And in this picture that
you're showing you here,
that's him raising 600 pounds in
order to win a trophy. Like this is a,
he was a champ and,
and you can see more pictures like these
cause we have signed copies of Oliver's
new memoir out for sale in the lobby.
It's pretty good book too, by the way.
So in any case at this time,
and then 1960s in addition
to being all muscled out,
Oliver was a serious recreational
drug taker. And because he's Oliver,
he was extremely curious about his
highs and no matter how weird they were,
one time, for example, he took 20
pills that he shouldn't have. And then
to my surprise, um, uh,
there was a spider on the
wall which said hello.
It had a voice like Bertrand
Russell, the famous mathematician
and the term it asked me a while,
the technical question as to where the
Russell had exploded free egos paradox.
And um, we had this conversation,
you answered the spider a shoe I onto the
spine discussed fragrance paradox with
this minor, I didn't deed cause you,
you trust your perceptions. Okay.
Many years later when I mentioned this
to an entomologist fed at Cornell and the
philosophical spiders said yes,
he said, I know the species.
So thinking Oliver's way, taking
it all in, talking spiders,
whatever the generosity of his
curiosity becomes profoundly moving and
transformative when he's
treating his patients.
I want to tell one story here really
quickly too, to demonstrate what I mean.
I'll ever once had a patient
whom he called Mrs o c
she was an old woman.
She was 88 years old living in a nursing
home and one night she was awakened,
jarred awake by a loud,
I wish
it was assault
and she thought, well, somebody's left
the radio on. But when she looked,
the radio in the room was off,
her roommate sound asleep,
which was odd because
the song was really loud.
[inaudible] after that
there was another song.
Ah,
and then another song
who is at home
misses Mrs. She thought, well,
maybe my roommate can't hear
these songs because the songs are,
are coming through the fillings in my
teeth. I've heard that's possible. But no,
her doctors told her, this
is something in your head,
you need to see a neurologist,
which led her to Dr Sachs.
Yeah.
At when he met Mrs he,
she could barely hear him.
The song sung by the female
voice were coming and coming.
She was frightened and justifiably
worried that she was going crazy.
But Oliver said, no, no, no, I'm going
to do some tests. And when he was done,
he said he'd found a slight stroke or
condition that had triggered musical
epilepsy. These sudden
production of music in her brain.
Now a normal doctor might say,
okay, we've got the diagnosis,
and he thought that the songs would
probably fade and it will pass.
So they would be done. But Oliver
did not stop. He doesn't stop
[inaudible]
he kept talking to her.
She told him she was born in Ireland in
the 1890s her father died before she was
born. Her mother, when she was only five
often alone, she was sent to America to
live for the welder for beating maison.
And she had no conscious memory at
the first five years of her life,
no memory of her mother of Ireland.
She had always felt this as
a key in and painful sadness,
this lack or forgetting at the earliest,
those precious years of her life.
So we asked her about the songs, what
are they like and Mrs. She said, well, I,
I think they're lullabies. Can
you sing them for me? She did.
And then after checking with,
I'm not sure who al ever figured out
that these songs were happened to be
popular Irish ballads from the 1890s
when Mrs OSI was a little baby.
And that gave him an idea. Now
what he does next isn't science.
It isn't in any traditional way medicine.
He just told her a story
and it goes like this.
You know how nobody remembers anything
that happens to you when you're one or
two or three? Well, there was a
theory once, not honored much today,
but it's sad that those earliest
memories get locked away,
deepen our brains in a special
safe, and we can never open.
So let's suppose Mrs Ossi, you're
stroked by some crazy chance,
open the lock that none of us can break
and released those first memories in you
just for a little while so that
the voice you're listening to
there is a home
[inaudible] great. Then Mo,
maybe that isn't a radio voice. Let's
thing that it's your mother's voice.
That's your missing mother.
And so at the ripe old age of 88 you
finally get to be back in your mother's
arms. You get to be a baby again. And
Mrs OFI thought about that and said,
okay,
it sort of fits.
I'm an old woman with a stroke
in an old people's home,
but I feel I'm a child to Ireland. The
Gate, I feel my mother's arms. I see her,
I hear her voice singing,
the green it clean.
[inaudible].
Shortly thereafter, the songs
began to fade. The pauses widened.
Mrs Ossi had been so frightened by this
music in her head was now sorry to see
the songs go. But it was Oliver who
noticed how those songs had touched her,
who noticed that the songs might become
a comfort to her because that's what he
does. He listens closely, he
can hear another person's heart.
And this is really the profound puzzle
for me of Oliver because reading the new
autobiography,
you see that while he was so full of
heart as a doctor in his own life and in
the relationships that really mattered,
it turns out he didn't get a whole lot
of affection. He was, for a long time,
a lonely guy. I'd say he was very lonely.
And he's talking about that
now for the first time. Let me,
let me talk about love for a minute.
Um, in this book, you tell the story of,
of your very
first love a fellow by the
name of Richard Sell it.
Can you just tell me what
happened with him? Um, yeah. Um,
he was a road scholar at Oxford and I'm
a poet and handsome and beautiful beyond
belief and I sort of fell for him. Um,
although I didn't say
anything because I was, um,
uh, very haunted by my mother's
accusations. But did your mother,
um,
well to go a couple of years back then
my father had opened the conversation
that I was about to go to ops
for that and I've sort of father,
son conversation and he said, um,
you don't seem to have many
girlfriends. And I said, no,
wishing the conversation
would stop. He said, um,
something wrong with girls. And I
said, no, that they're fine taps,
you prefer boys. And I said,
well, yes I do. I said,
I've never done anything but I do.
And then you knew that then I knew
that then I had known it for six years,
probably since I was 12. Um, and I said,
don't tell mom she will
be able to take it.
But my father did tell my mother and
the night and the next morning she came
down with them.
I somehow wants to say a face
of Fonda and raged at me,
and among other things
said, you're an abomination.
I wish you would never been born.
And then she suddenly shut up
and said nothing for three days.
And um, uh,
the matter was never mentioned
again in her lifetime.
And then two years later I found myself
for the first time in my life falling in
love. And this was the gun guy, Richard
Oliver at the time was in college.
It was a very positive feeling where
I didn't know whether it was one,
which I did express,
but I did say so with my heart and my
mouth to each other. But what did you,
you remember what you said? Uh, I said,
I'm in love with you and we should
gripped me by the shoulders.
And he said, I know. He
said, but I'm not that way,
but I love you in my own way.
And I was glad I had said that.
I'm glad that it had been received
in such a warm, friendly way.
I thought we might be friends
for the rest of our lives,
but then one day he came into me,
he said he'd been bothered by finding
a lump in his groin and he was worried
could I have a look at it and I looked
at it and I felt it and it was hard and
tethered turned out to be a
particularly malignant form of lymphoid.
Timo was called a lympho sarcoma and
he never spoke to me again after that.
I don't know whether since I'd been the
first to recognize the ominous import,
I don't know whether he saw me as a
harbinger of death or messenger of death,
whatever.
But you were left with the,
with that silence. Yeah. Yeah.
A few years later I'll ever met
and man named Mel, he was a young,
he was a sailor like Oliver.
He was into weightlifting.
They became close friends and
they began living together.
I adored him and was in love with him
and loved physical contact with him
and they'd work out and they'd wrestle
and ride motorcycles kind of tightly and
they never talked about what might or
might not be happening between them.
But one day they were together and
Oliver was giving mil a back massage,
which mill often asked him to
do. And uh, I love doing that.
And Oliver says sometimes
he'd get a little, you know,
excited. And so long as I gave no
explicit indication it was okay,
but, but, but one day things went a
bit too far and I got sort of, um,
I went over the bridge instead
of just before the pink, um,
mental immediately sort of got
up and had a shower and said, I,
I can't stay with you anymore. And um,
I found that very cruel and upsetting
and heartbreaking and it made me feel,
I don't want to have anything to do
with people. I must have fallen in love.
I cannot share life's with anyone again.
And he didn't share his life with
anyone for a long, long time.
In fact,
he told me a story about something that
happened to him maybe eight years ago.
I,
I was just joining the faculty at Columbia
and I was having this one interview
and one point the interviewer
said to me, she said,
I have something rather private to
our school. We do like Ms Edgar,
your assistant to leave. And I said,
no, she's privy to all my affairs.
And I then set thinking she was
going to ask me about six. I said,
I haven't had any sex for 35 years. I bet.
In fact, when she was going
to ask me my social security,
okay,
and she burst into laughter. She
said, Oh, you poor thing. She said,
we must do something about it. Well,
the truth is Oliver didn't do anything
about it because he didn't think he
could. I mean, he chosen, Richard
lost, Richard Chosen Mail, lost mail.
It was the point he was
thinking. And then finally,
and who knows when or why these
things happened to people.
But a man came along who for
the first time chose Oliver.
I have made met
Billy is I meet a number of people because
I'd been sent a manuscript or proof
for book and I'm an
intimacy group between us.
I don't think I quite
realized how deep it was.
But then there was a
particular episode Christmas
of Oh nine when he came up and in s
serious way, he has a
serious careful when he said,
I I have conceived a deep love for you.
I have conceived the deep love for
you. Yeah. Um, that isn't sort of,
that's like a few extra
words I have concealed.
Okay. Was He scared to
say I love you or um, no,
she likes the English
language. I think it,
I think it couldn't have been put, um,
more cautiously and yet more strongly.
I think it was a beautiful
way of putting it.
And then I realized at that
moment with his saying that,
that I had conceived a deep love
for him and I am among other things,
I thought good has happened again,
two
and I'm in my 77th year. Um, and,
and what next and things, um,
basically have gone happily ever since.
[inaudible]
and surprisingly look Lesley. Um,
because then again I'm not dealing
with a, what I'm dealing with a hoop,
I'm dealing with an individual. I,
I'm not dealing with a um, uh,
well a condition defined
by medicine or law.
So Oliver's still doesn't know how much
time he has left. But for the moment,
as you can hear, his mind is
totally intact. He's still writing.
He has two books in addition to the
one you'll find in the lobby that he's
writing and the children's book,
bunch of New Yorkers stories in the
last few months and a New York Review of
book story. He's got energy to spare.
So I want to do one last
thing before we close.
And this comes from yet
another conversation I had
with him and it's a story I
know Oliver would hate because he's not
a capital I or religious kind of guy,
but he is somebody who
definitely embraces mystery.
And for a long time he's been
mystified by a color called Indigo,
indigo,
which Newton had inserted
between blue and violet.
And no, no two people seem to
agree as to what indigo was like.
And so I built up a sort
of chemical launchpad,
meaning he took a lot of
base of amphetamine from general arouse
or then some acid and a little cannabis.
And when I was sufficiently
stoned, I said,
I want to see indigo now
as if it were reply and does.
It's fallen by a giant paintbrush
that appeared a huge trembling,
pear shaped blob of what I instantly
realized was pure indigo on the white wall
in front of me.
It had had a wonderful luminosity
and in particular I am,
although I'm not a religious person,
I thought this is the color of heaven
and I live towards it
and the sort of ecstasy
and then suddenly disappeared and he
says he had one more moment like that.
This time, no drugs. He was in a
museum staring at an Egyptian artifact.
He sees this Ri and color
back again just for a beat.
I was given five tantalizing
seconds of, of, of radiant,
ineffable
ut, and then again it vanished.
And that was in 1965 and I
have never seen indigo since.
But who knows? You know,
someday I like to think Dr Sachs
may get to see that color again.