You are listening to radiolab
radio from W N Y s C.
Yup. Hi,
I'm Robert Krulwich and I'm Latif Nasser.
This is Radiolab and today we're going
to do something completely upside down
and inside out. Yes, it's,
it's a sport story sort of,
but like none you've ever heard.
And therefore we found a reporter
who is a sports reporter. Like none.
You've ever heard. Yeah, I've
been to a gym lately. Mike Peskov.
He's the host of the just podcasts
put up by slate, formerly of NPR,
still sometimes roots fan br. And now
he's here telling the story to us.
Yeah know. How did you even first
hear about this? Were you covering it?
Oh yeah. Yeah. So
this is morning edition from
NPR news. I'm her name on tape.
I was covering the 2012 Olympics
for NPR. Good morning. Hello.
And I declare open the Games of London,
the stories of the Olympics. Um,
you try to find your own stories that
are obscured, but if there's a big story,
you chase it. So in those Olympics.
So for you,
what were the most notable achievements
in the first week of the Games?
Well, it's history of the base con.
Microsoft's breaking the all time record.
Obviously over a hundred years,
nobody's won as many medals at the
Olympic Games and everyone knew that
bolt and his record set inquest
in a hundred would be you.
Oh, he's returned to tied with the
most empathetic way. Brilliant,
brilliant fun. [inaudible]
can this badminton story pops up
and everyone rushes to figure out what
the heck's going on with badminton.
[inaudible]
because the 2012 London
Olympics, badminton tournament,
just,
it took this somewhat obscure sport and
it morphed it into this bizarro thought
experiment about competition and
integrity and what it means to win.
Okay. But mostly I think that
the, although to be fair, Mike,
he jumped on this story
for very personal reasons.
As a New Yorker,
I say a lot of words and
they're mispronounced in the
NPR audience with jump on
them. But I always can say the Anand
badminton and get a lot of plots.
So I'm attracted to badminton. But
what's the wrong way to say badminton?
Most people say badminton bad. Ben,
like you're talking to some
hands where winter time I'm like,
you're chastising a playful
cat, right magnet. And I see.
And then also, um, you know, you,
you and I probably think of
badminton as this backyard fun,
silly game. But
[inaudible]
according to Mike, no,
this is anything but it has nothing to
do with the badminton you play in your
backyard.
It's much faster than you think it would
possibly look. You get these player,
I want a shot flying all over the
court, stretching, reaching, diving.
The skill of the competitors
is, you know, readily apparent.
This is pulsating badminton.
Shuttlecock is a funny thing and perhaps
not as impressive a thing as a tennis
ball, but it looks, you know, a lot
like tennis and there was a lot of
tension.
So to be a fresher and there's a lot
of grunting and it totally seems like
every bit of a legitimate
and highly skilled sports.
Wait, I'm going to start. Okay. So,
so Robert [inaudible] so
you haven't seen this yet,
but I would like to show
you something. Okay.
This is an ad.
Yeah. This, okay.
This is the game that is at the
center of this whole story. Oh Man.
These doubles group. I patient
a women's doubles. Badminton.
It is not a metal round. It's
in the group place stage.
There's a huge crowd here.
Like the place is packed. Yeah.
Please welcome a representative
of the People's Republic of China.
Why don't you show me you're young.
So these two teams come out. Uh,
you got China yellow when red
uniforms, the oceans. So here,
comm
versus Korea. Purple and white. Yeah.
And let's just skip ahead here.
Yeah. All right. So here we go. Game on.
This is the first surf [inaudible]
Korean serve. So the Korean
player flicks her wrist.
The shuttlecock goes over the net.
China return [inaudible] right
into the net. But that was it.
That was the whole thing. Oh,
that was just a, alright. Um,
so Korea and second serve
and Chinese return and same
thing. You know that again? Yeah.
So that
service has turned over and now the
Chinese are surfing China, Korea,
China.
It doesn't matter if you can, uh, yeah,
this is not exactly scintillating.
I just gotta tell you,
I think you're welcome.
Watch this next point.
So the Korean player serves it. Yeah,
it's sales over the net and then
it goes, goes, goes, goes, goes.
And the Chinese player clearly
is right there. She has it.
She then winds up just a
slight bit like you could see,
it's like she has this deep ingrained
muscle memory from years of doing this.
She winds up, she's about to
hit it and then she's stops.
And the Charlotte Cock just plunks under
the floor inbounds point to Korea and
then tellingly she looks, yeah,
back at the back corner of the
court where her coach's sitting. Uh,
they both are. Yeah, yeah. This is a
fix. They're fixing this. Well this is,
yes.
But there been plenty of occasions where
one side wants to lose and it ain't
hard to, and the more important thing is
that it ain't hard to get away with it.
Usually you wouldn't
even notice it. You know,
it's the difference between a
couple of serves over the line,
a couple balls into the net, but
in this case, as the match goes on,
you start to realize
that's a very lethargic Scott come back.
Korean players seem to be trying to
lose too. The cervic faults. Yes,
that's it's a rally of course everybody
we tried to lose like both sides.
Well it's actually a strategy because
the way the tournament is laid out,
both these teams are going to be
moving on to the metal rounds,
but whoever wins this game is going
to have to play another Chinese team,
a really strong team. I see.
And whoever loses is gonna
play a way easier Danish team.
So both teams are hoping to lose. Yeah.
And it is the rare instance where you
have both sides incentivized to lose that.
You get something that should
be scored by Spike Jones.
It's a little bit of a prisoner's
dilemma, right? Either side could lose,
but when both want to lose, it becomes
this surreal waiting game. Right.
You know who's going to crack first and
score a point and so you got the best
players in the world who just start
hitting the shuttlecock out of bounds,
see fault after fault,
faulting on purpose,
and we'll just take the
bull straight in the net.
You're hitting the shuttlecock
into the net. I'm sorry.
You know it's blindingly
obvious what's going on.
And you know that both tried to lose.
Sometimes they hit it below the
net and that is unforgivable.
They're hitting it straight into the
ground or by tripping over their own
shoelaces purposefully until what you
get is serve up all into the next point
after point of just hearable badminton.
And it just devolved into
this absurd repetitive,
crazy making lose the thought.
This is not to displace. Yes,
the lame, I mean this is
not, this is not sport this,
but it is kind of a sport because,
and this is why I really love it.
At a certain point,
these two teams have to start
competing with each other to lose what,
let me play you this point. So
China serves it. Korea hits it back,
but it's going way out of bounds
now. Now, in a normal world,
China would obviously let that fall
so that they could take the point,
but they lunge to save it, right?
And they're hitting it back.
No Korea, then they are like,
no, no, no. You know what?
We're pretty sure we
want it out of bounds.
They hit it in the opposite
direction, even further out of bounds.
So now China goes to save it once
again, but they don't get there in time.
So the point goes to China, which
China actually didn't want. Um, and,
and the Koreans wanted the whole time.
So what are you saying then as well?
It's like, it's like we
invented whole new sport,
which is the exact opposite of
badminton. It is, it is photo negative.
[inaudible]
then towards the end of the first,
that woman referee has
been pretty quick outcomes.
The referee since the birth.
Hello, Torsten speaking. Hi,
how Torsten Baron was the head Olympic
badminton referee who got that call.
And I also heard the spectators
Buzo. I went to watch it.
It looked pretty awful.
This was not [inaudible]
right. [inaudible] is
the planners together
and uh, told them that they were
not playing seriously and uh,
they were making a very serious mistake
and uh, they played stupid and said no,
we playing and we're trying our best
needed told me also
[inaudible] we were actually able to
get in touch with, what's her name?
You most of us three of the four players
in that match. Both Korean players
[inaudible] John can earn
and they're going the chemo.
And I knew that Kim Hannah and also one
of the Chinese players [inaudible] how
was [inaudible] and
[inaudible] [inaudible] told me they
were trying to lose in that match.
But what do we did in the
expected south career?
What the do the same thing has a male
sound, our whole, and as for the Koreans,
junk young urn said that they too were
trying to lose at least during certain
moments in the game.
But when the crowds hurted Abou
[inaudible] the run and the ref came out,
her partner, Kim Ha na said that. So
I was surprised and I'm embarrassed.
We're just much about loggers on scared.
We just wanting to get out of the court
as soon as possible. Got To [inaudible].
So Torsten walks off the court,
they window in court again.
And then the second serve after
Torsten walks out the court.
Nothing but net. So for
the next few points,
it does not get much better. No, it
didn't look like world class back.
Mm.
So the set comes to an end.
Korea wins the set and while the
players are waiting on [inaudible]
sidelines who comes to the
tournament referee, again,
Torsten comes back onto the court,
you walks up to the players and he pulls
out of his pocket almost subtly and
shows to the players this
black car, the black car,
which means discord, vacation.
This is absolutely extraordinary.
He has given both teams
a black card or has he
threatened them with a bat card?
I'm really not terribly short. The
players have returned to court.
It was now that they should
play or they would be in deep.
Sorry, maybe I shouldn't say the black,
the black card that says that the
car, the car was out and I was,
I told them in very clear words and
very seriously that in order to help
themselves, they better play now.
Can they then can they [inaudible]
the Korean player Junkie on
the [inaudible] said that
she turned to her party
and I told her there are them and we
are we so come give your, hit you. Okay,
let's just play and do our best.
The second set starts and pretty good.
[inaudible] China's
[inaudible] Lee told me,
so you see both sides changed a little
bit instead of just serving into the net,
things started to get better. Oh Raleigh.
They would get the rally going but
then as the points kept coming,
you started to notice like
they were playing very slowly.
Six still really off here. They were
not hitting the border very hard.
[inaudible] yeah, the Korean
team wouldn't admit this,
but once ya Lee said that both teams,
you then changed the basic fact
gabion and we're still trying to lose,
which I have to say is exactly what
it looks like when you watch it.
Because for the rest of the match, you
get a bunch of these points where like,
where just they'll lob, it's super
high, you know, as if to say, hey,
smash it down on us. Take your
point. Or they will, uh, you know,
hit it out of bounds and then
face palm just, you know,
practice their swing after they missed
one just to, to see, say, Oh, you know,
my mechanics are off. I just gotta
just practices a few more times. Um,
because it's like we've entered a whole
third iteration of this game where it's
like they're not just trying to lose,
they're trying to cover up the admin
cover up badminton. You're trying to lose,
but you're trying to look
like you're trying to win.
I don't think. No.
So finally, after 20 long,
the minutes of this, uh,
the Korean team loses
the match by winning it
tonight has left me with a
very nasty taste in the mouth.
Tonight is not sport. It
was a disgrace. Good night.
[inaudible] so all four players walked
off the court and Kim Ha na told him he
was not a pleasant winning at all and the
parents were in the audience that day.
And afterwards they
asked her what happened,
what happened and why,
why do you have to get the booze
from the audiences and et cetera.
And I was, I was sad
and feel, felt defeated.
So I didn't even want to talk to my
mom. So I remember I was just going,
went to the hotel and had, had
arrested [inaudible] killed,
know, and uh, the next morning at
eight o'clock or four pairs, in fact,
we're disqualified according to the
disciplinary regulations of, uh,
the badminton world federation,
which has a rule on the books that you
can be disqualified for failing to use
your best effort.
And the same evening
they, on the plane home,
they were just thrown out of the Olympics.
The scandal at the Olympics [inaudible]
this whole to do about the badminton
players. Everyone was talking about some
losers shuffle colts were going out.
[inaudible] the shuttle coke into the
net like a five year old in the backyard
picnic. It was downright
humiliating post. Just sad
that uh,
they were committing suicide in
that tournament can usually be job
[inaudible] it's a bad time. The
punishment hits me quite hard.
I was very sad and I felt helpless.
[inaudible]
[inaudible] I was perplexed
and didn't know what happened.
We just cried.
This doesn't sound like it's getting any
better. No, but there's still more, uh,
after the break. Okay.
Hi, this is Nila from Hamburg, Germany.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
I'm former US attorney Preet Bharara
and my new podcast is called stay tuned.
If you look at areas
where he is unconstrained,
his behavior is pretty consistently
awful. It's about the human side of power.
Those who do not study history
are doomed to repeat it.
And those who study policing.
No, we don't study history.
And it's about justice,
fairness and democracy.
I have never had anyone who committed the
crime of murder go back to prison ever
again. Presented by Wnyu Studios,
cafe and Pineapple Street media.
Stay tuned is available
wherever you listen to podcasts.
We're back. I'm Robert Krulwich and
I'm lots of Nasr. This is radio lab.
And when we left off,
the Korean and Chinese women's badminton
teams had just been disqualified,
kicked out of the Olympics. So what,
so then what happened to the [inaudible]
players? Like what happened them? Well,
all four of them did keep playing
badminton professionally after this, uh,
junk young earn from Korea even
went on to win a bronze in Rio.
But at the time this was a brutal
punishment for all of them.
Well, but you know, they, they did
something wrong. This wasn't right. Right.
I, you know, I don't even, I
questioned whether it's even unethical.
I think it's ethical in a way. What
they did, really, what the players did.
I do, I think it's an
ethical how so, okay.
So is the definition of
ethics in sports two two wins.
Sure. Without cheating. Yes.
Does that mean to win every
point? No, not necessarily.
You know, in baseball there's the
thing called the intentional walker.
In football,
a team will take a safety
instead of punting and letting
the other teams score a
touchdown.
So this a calculation where our point
here or there is not as important as the
hole and the hole is the game.
So, okay, let's move back.
Let's pan out a little more. I think
an individual game is often lost. Look,
we're not going to put
our good starter here.
We're going to manage the lineup because
the goal is to win the championship.
And the thing to remember about these
players is if what we want is players who
are hyper competitive and
actually want to win at all costs,
that's exactly why they were losing so
badly because they wanted to win the
overall championship at all costs.
And the badminton federation had a set
of rules that all bug guarantee that this
would happen.
Well. Yeah, I mean it's stupid to have
an event where people are trying to lose.
If that event is a sporting
event, especially at the apex of,
you know, the only time people care
about bad news it seems really good.
So this is chuck Klosterman,
we called him in because he writes a lot
about sports and also because he wrote
the ethicist column for The
New York Times magazine.
Now is this a, uh, some kind
of tragedy will, it's not,
I guess in less bad mittens really
important to you than it probably is
in this case.
I think the thing that people got really
upset about is this is this idea of the
Olympic ideal.
All the context to I promise that we
shall take part in the Olympic Games
athletes both
in the true spirit of sportsmanship for
the glory of the sport and the honor of
our teams
to transcend the in the way that as a
super athlete you're transcending your
humanity but then also as like this
representative of your country and I think
it did poke a lot of people like a lot
of people did seemingly get kind of upset
about Oh
yeah.
I mean for some reason it is disturbing
to see athletes failing on purpose that
just, it seems to Kinda
like tap into some,
I like morals somehow
tonight has left me with
a very nasty tasting.
Yes. Like, like,
like I don't know if not trying in a
sporting event is a moral question,
but it feels that way
when you see it happen.
Yes.
Here again,
one of the interesting thing about sports
is that we watch these adults playing
multimillion dollar games,
but they're the same games that like a
six year old or seven year old plays.
So when you have a seven year old kid,
you would say it doesn't
matter if you win or lose.
It doesn't matter what happens, just
play hard. You don't have to succeed.
It's the trying that matters.
So when you see people at the
eyes level not trying, there's,
it's almost,
it's sort of wrecks the entire idea of
why we play sports at all. You know why?
If you're at a playground in two kids
race across the playground to see who can
get to the swing faster or whatever,
like that's like a biological thing.
Maybe we are biologically
driven to compete,
so that's the baseline
expectation of what we have.
Have these bad been players
that they will try to compete.
It seems to me there's an opportunity
here for true athleticism and a kind of
topsy turvy little bit and reversed and
reversed it and see if you can do that
as well as you do the other way. I
mean sports only work one way though.
They don't work both
ways. I mean it would,
it would be be like going to
your wife and saying like, okay,
you say you really love me.
Prove it by hating me in a creative way.
Or to go to a great piano
player and say like,
if you're so awesome at playing piano,
Bang your fist against the keys
in a way that I will be, you know,
I will be sickened by it,
but every ticket out of the out of matters
of the heart and put it back on the
field,
what would be the most radical solution
that you could imagine if your desire
was to convincingly and astonishingly
athletically lose weight?
I suppose if they were both trying to do
it in the most convincing way it would
be, that was not really the case here.
I can say they never confronted it.
How do you lose on purpose if the other
side's also trying to lose on purpose?
And I'm trying to think, there
are some sports. So in football,
let's say in American football, let's
say both sides want it to lose. Well,
here's how the sport would go. You
can't make the other team score.
But you can score a safety on yourself.
So the quarterback would get the ball
and start running towards the zone end
zone,
and then there'd be a gel break by the
defense to tackle the quarterback before
he got [inaudible]. Baseball is hard.
You could hit the batter. That would be,
that would be an interesting game.
What about darts instead
of aiming at the dartboard,
just turning around and aiming it
your opponent. So that's like the,
that's like the baseball
strategy for the bodybuilding.
Think about the implications
[inaudible] where do I think I would win?
I see like a will Ferrell
movie out of this thinking.
We get to a point, our team,
all right, this is what we need.
You've got to go out there and go and
then there's a loser on the other.
It's also, and then I lose
[inaudible].
You can hear more of Mike Tesco on
his podcast and the just more of Chuck
Klosterman and his latest
book. But what if we're wrong?
Big thanks to all the players who talk
to us and to those who helped us get
those interviews and joy.
Lee Lee McCune, Kim uniquer,
Tika thanks to opponent and Charla who
came in and helped us puzzle this whole
match out. And in addition,
a special thanks to Gracie a Polly Gracie
was on the Indonesian badminton team
in those same Olympics and an hour
after the match, we featured, uh,
she face off against a
different Korean team. Uh,
all four players in that match were also
disqualified for not using their best
efforts to win. Uh, she
really helped us, uh,
understand what it was like
to be in that situation.
This story was produced by Matt Kielty
and Annie Mcewen and Latif Nasser.
I remember Krulwich and I'm of Vassar
and I guess that ends the game at this
point.
Go to the next minute. Hi, it's
Mike. I'm going to do this.
It's possible that even though this is
the fifth time I've said David Gabel
wrong,
but I'm going to do it once and I'm got
to do it with an intro of myself and
here goes, hi,
this is Mike Scott here to tell you that
Radiolab is produced by Jad Abumrad.
Dylan Keefe is our director of sound
design. Soren Wheeler is senior editor.
Jamie York is our senior producer.
Our staff includes Simon Adler,
Brenna Farrell, David Cabal, Matt Kielty,
Robert Krulwich, Annie Mcewen, Latif,
Nasser Malissa O'Donnell, Arianne wack,
and Molly Webster with help from
Tracy Hunt. Nightjar for Routt. Nope.
Nightjar Fatali, Phoebe Wang, Katie
Ferguson, Alexandra Lee, young w,
Harry Fortuna and proceed Verlyn.
Our fact checkers are Eva Dasher and
Michelle Harris. Thanks for listening
and this message,
here's an idea I have. There was an
old brittle, then it goes like this.
A king talks to his Tucson's
two princes and he says,
here's what we're going to do. Get
those horses out of the stable.
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to jump on your
horses and ride to the city gate,
which ever horse gets the city gate
last. Your going to inherit the fortune.
Maybe it's a crazy king. So the
two princes look at each other.
They both think and then they jump on the
horses and they ride fast as they can.
Why?
To to reign in their wishes at the very
last minute. Jump off of wishes and say,
Whoa, and then wait until the
other one. I don't know. Are they,
are they planning on just just,
just removing a section of the gate and
then just smashing it up against the
other horse? Yeah. No, that's terrible.
Like the answer, what is the answer?
They jumped on each other's horse.
They dropped on the other brother's
horse. Maybe. Let me just think about
other sports. Of course. He said whichever
horse gets her last, so how that.