Coach. I'm just going to go. Yeah, just
go do it. Ready? Yep. This is Radiolab.
I'm Jad Abumrad, and I'm Robert Krulwich
with you today. Our topic is Zeus.
We're doing a little sort
of chronological thing,
tracing the line from past to present,
starting back at those old
nasty concrete enclosures,
which I'm sure you love
to visit as a little boy.
Okay.
What do you mean? You know
you're a city boy, you, you,
you don't have much animals here. Oh,
there's nothing to do with New York.
What do you like?
Tennessee [inaudible] fine,
but when you talk about, you know,
enriching the lives of gorillas
as we did before the break.
It's a simple heartwarming story
cause gorillas and our out,
they have their vegetarians.
Rankling it gets a lot more complicated
when you switch to a Predator who likes
to pounce and chase and bite. Yes,
you're going to put those animals in a
cage and their whole being is organized
around killing things. Well,
what do you feed them? Mm,
I the question to a NPR
science reporter. Nell boys.
If we're talking like the big carnivores,
like the Tigers that would
normally be out in the wild.
Ripping other animals to shred.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. What are they?
They're eating mostly this,
uh, this is a little bag of,
um, uh, kibble. It's, it's
basically like a dog food. Yeah.
Check it out.
Well, this is for a meeting
animal. Oh, again, try one.
All right. Skinny.
Oh, that's like getting chalk.
This is what the predators
eat according to now. Really?
Why don't they just give them meat?
That's sort of what she wanted to know.
Testing the mini days
before heading to the zoo.
Testing them in the days
before heading to the zoo. No,
recently took a trip to the Toledo zoo.
Okay.
Oh, hi. I'm here to see Ann.
She wanted to know what it might look
like if a zoo actually gave the predators
what they want in this regard.
The Toledo zoo is pretty radical.
Once a year they have this event
they call the big feed, the big feed,
the big feed to be
opening. Thank, you know,
got there a day early just
to check things out. Okay.
So I duck behind the Rhino
House, go behind the scenes here.
I go in the back door.
And where I finally end up is this kind
of thing. Nondescript pillow kitchen.
This is the kitchen. We have a
freezer and refrigerator down here.
Don't think about a kitchen being at the
zoo, but there's a kitchen here. Yes,
yes, there. So I'm sorry, your name again?
Was Beverly scooting over screen
over? Yes. Beverly's going over.
And this kitchen is
actually the reason I came.
This is our freezer. You
can run about 10 below
the rat and we actually have
rats in about four sizes.
We have large jumbo monsters.
And then we have packs of
50 mice, packs of 25 mice.
And then these are the fuzzies.
These are probably about 10 days old.
The fuzzies and the pinkies are pretty
much newborn. Here's the basic idea.
You want to get closer to what the
animals actually eat in the wild.
So you want to give them some sort of
whole animals pull as in like all the
first eyeballs whiskers. So, um,
what are things different today?
Because the big fetus
tomorrow hooves hooves. Yeah,
the Tigers are getting some calves and
that's not something that we give out
like all the time. Calves. Can we look
at it? Yeah. So they take me into the
freezer and in the
corner, just so the one,
the floor is this box and it's got a
black garbage bag kind of thing in it,
which we opened up, you know, like
looking right up at me. I happens to be,
the head part is the baby
cab, but that's just the head,
the head. It was like a little
baby. We got it. Little eyelashes,
little ears. It's a baby
cow, you know? And I put,
oh baby cow. And then
I thought, oh my God,
tomorrow little children are going
gonna be watching this baby cow.
It'd be ripped apart by a giant wild cat.
They're wild animals. You know, they,
they live in a captive situation, but
they still have those wild instincts.
That's Beth stark. She's the one who
brought carcass feeding to the Toledo zoo.
The time we hear, oh,
carnivores are meat eaters,
but really they're not just meat
eaters, they're flesh eaters.
They eat other animals. And one of
the challenges there is is you know,
how do we,
how do we provide for the welfare of
the animals that while at the same time
providing for the needs of our visitors.
So it's about 10 o'clock in the
morning and the gates are open now.
So visitors are starting to
stream in about 15 minutes or so.
They're going to start the tiger feed.
The tiger feeding was the
first feeding of the day.
A big crowd was beginning to gather.
Right now the tigers aren't in the pen.
How many people? Oh, like maybe
150 people. A lot of little kids.
So we brought the boy down Ben pumps
since my wife told me about it,
so he made sure we got
her early to check us out.
The carcasses were already out.
The zookeeper comes out with her
microphone and like sort of gives a little
[inaudible] and Richmond
program description of
carcass feeding sures that we
meet, why they do it,
all the animals behavioral needs as
well as their psychological needs.
And nobody at this point is listening
to the interpretive discussion of this
because as she's doing this,
I think I heard a door,
they let the tigers into the pen.
Oh look, here come the Tigers.
Watch brand. Look, the
big ones coming down.
One of the tires just like streaks
across the pan and grabs the car.
It's like, you know,
it starts like immediately playing with
it and I have never seen in all my years
of Zulu going, I have never
seen a tiger move that fast.
Like at 1.1 of the Tigers was like
carrying one around by the ear.
You could see like the little cafes and
it was dragging it around and what were
people doing? Were they
cheering? Were they crying?
There was nobody there that
seemed to be disturbed. It really,
although here was a
conversation that I heard many,
many times the children
would say, what is that?
What is he eating? And the parent would
say, I put a baby cow hates a baby cow.
And the kid would say,
why is he doing it, honey?
The Tigers have to, well, that's
what he eats, the food that they eat,
and the child said, well,
I don't need cow. Yeah,
you do. And the parent would say,
what? Of course you eat cow at home,
hamburgers, hamburger. What do you
think a hamburger is out of cows?
And they would just be this
shocked look on the kid.
And I must've heard that conversation
like five times. It's food hunting.
No, it's food.
Wow. That's like a birds and the bees
kind of moment. Yeah, it really was.
People are just fascinated by it.
They appreciate being so close.
I see them back there. Right?
They'll say, Oh guy, that's really gross.
But then moving closer for a better view.
What Beth stark was telling me is that,
you know the whole time that they've been
doing this carcass feeding program and
they would interview people
afterwards and ask them questions.
We did survey people. How did
you feel? What did you think?
And found that more
than, and what she found,
98% of them is that the public is pretty
much uniformly very positive and what
they saw. Enthusiastic. One of the
questions we put on the survey is,
do you want to see more of this in
which animals would you like to see?
And so what did people
say just about everybody.
From what I can remember circled every
animal we put every just about every
animal, every animal, you know, like,
you know, do you wanna see dead rabbits?
Do you want to see dead rats?
Do you want to see dead calves?
Do you want to see dead deers?
And do you want them to see them fed to
polar bears, tigers, wolves, you know,
like a Chinese menu, you know, like, pick
your prey animal, pick your predator.
Do you want to see that? And they're
like, yes, yes. We want to see this.
The only complaints where people didn't
want rabbits fed at Easter and around
Easter, you know,
parents complaining or worrying that
their kid was thinking that the eastern
bunny was being eaten.
It just shows you how,
like what the animals eat at the zoo is
fraught with sort of human emotions and
ideas about right and wrong.
Here's another example. Okay?
So when I was at the tiger pen,
there was this woman who came
up and was very interested.
She didn't seem turned off by the idea
that they were eating a dead calf. Right?
Yeah. But then she got this very
strange look on her face and she said,
I hope that was dead. And I said,
well, does it does it manner? I mean,
because at some point it died, you know,
does it matter whether it died at the
hands of a human or the hands of a tiger?
And it was late in the
afternoon and I'm ready to go.
So I turn off my tape recorder
and just at that second,
even though she's just expressed sort
of relief that the calf was dead when it
was put in the tiger's pen,
she starts to tell this story that was
so diametrically opposed to what she had
just expressed that I just had to turn
my tape recorder back on and say like,
wait a minute. Wait, can you
start at the whole beginning?
So what was happening? What happened? Um,
a squirrel health through that
layers on the snow leopards cage.
She and her daughter had been
hanging out by the snow leopards pin.
There's this sort of net
kind of above the pen.
And there was this squirrel that had
been walking on the net and it fell down.
Cereal is here, lay down
into the snow lepers pants.
And her daughter described the
story to me where the snow leopard,
who'd just been like kind of
hanging out kind of board,
immediately began to stop.
The squirrel was pouncing and the
squirrel like started trying to get away.
Her mother said it was like
the standard dot. Oh yes.
Like the snow leopard was matching all
of the moves of the score on c pilot a
move for me. And like the
audience was kind of transfixed.
Excellent.
Her daughter like could not watt head
when she thought the Squirrel was coming
down. Yeah. Yeah. She took off.
Her daughter couldn't watch,
was hiding her face. And in the end the
squirrel escaped. The Squirrel got away.
He was smarter. And I said to
the girl, well, how did you feel?
Were you rooting for the Leopard or
the Squirrel? Which one? And she said,
laughing. I was rooting for the
snow leopard. Huh. And I said,
but you didn't want to see
it eat the squirrel and you,
you didn't want to see
that. And she said, well,
I still want to fit the snow leopard
because I didn't want to see it,
but I still wanted to see it
because it is cool but nature.
Right. Yeah, the wild.
I think that that the reason they felt
comfortable watching that and telling me
about it was because it seemed like a,
an episode that was not between
the animals in the human.
It was between the animals.
What about you? If you
were that little girl,
how would you watch that whole scene when
you watch it kind of gleefully or more
sheepishly.
You just watch. It's just
happening in front of you. I mean,
that has nothing to do with you.
It's funny, you know,
sh she never mentioned the possibility
of feeding live animals to um,
a predator. By the way, Nell Boys' is
a science reporter for NPR. Thank you.
Now, not those frozen
rat sickle things, but,
but something that scurry
then you can, yeah.
Live feeding is a line which
Americans use will not cross.
The only places that do feed out live
animals as far as we could find are in
China. Lucky for us.
Yeah. I live in Beijing.
That's where reporter Jocelyn Ford lifts
just over an hours bus ride outside of
Beijing. We ask Jocelyn to go visit
one of these live feeding parks.
That's what they're called. Live
feeding bark. You just get on a bus.
They'd drive you right into the lines
then, and they'll even sell you chicken.
The chickens are about $4 each and the
tour people sell them right there on the
bus riding the bus.
They don't have the lion's den
and one of the people on the bus,
one of the tourists decided often
don't care. I'm going to buy a chicken.
I'm going to feed the lion and
I can get the Allen County jail.
That side of the bus,
the guy who bought the chicken,
he would kick it up, rested again.
Here come the lion,
and soon we had four or five lions sitting
right under our window looking at us.
You're circling us. Dionysus
looks very intense. I tell you,
they had the most intense look
I have ever seen him anywhere.
I mean they have these very cold
amber eyes, angry, hungry eyes.
Whoa. He's looks like he's ready to pounce
and the guy with the chicken
just opened the window,
drop the chicken out
second that lion grab the chicken and just
[inaudible]. It helped me smell it.
Then I noticed that his
legs were still quivering.
Now it's working away at it
just sort of lipping it to bits
that say a pile of feathers.
Did it tell you what's your
house? You, what's on your base?
I asked a grandmother who was on the bus,
she was with something like a five year
old and I asked her if she thought this
was a healthy thing to have this hurt her,
her grandson watching this cruel event
and she said, hey, it'll
make him a braver guy
if you don't eat them
first they're going to use.
And she was just very matter
of fact about it, that
one woman said, we should
teach our kids to love animals.
But at the same time, if you know the
bigger animal eats the smaller animal,
that's the way the world works.
So you should understand this survival
of the fittest, just your Darwin,
Darwin [inaudible] and you should
also understand where you fit into it.
We'll get to the army. If you're weak and
you can't run fast escape or whatever,
you'll become somebody dinner.
And that's the lesson of life
I think. I think in the
United States that we've,
we're often so far removed from
the ugly part of the food we eat.
We just get squeamish when we see
it. Whereas especially the, the,
the rural people in China, you know,
they deal with life and death of
animals around them all the time.
And I think we're just closing our
eyes to it. I, having said that, I,
I mean personally I feel that it does
make for a more humane society when you do
feel sorry or compassionate
about the animals around you.
And there was no concern
at the safari park here.
Nothing of that sort. It was
all about funding. Dan's.
Okay. So at the end of the best ride,
they dropped you off. I got a little,
little circus-like place and they had
a little fake shooting gallery with all
sorts of repeating music.
And I went, I went and looked under
this dirty old tent over some,
some metal rods,
and there were rows of cages and tigers
pacing back and forth and yelling.
Have you ever heard of a tiger? Yowell?
Yeah. Yeah.
Wow. Yeah,
the cage, just the length of his body
turned around, but that's about it.
[inaudible] okay,
thanks to reporter Justin Ford.