Uh, hi, this is Jad. Hi. Yay.
To meet Jad. And I am Robert.
And today's story started when we bumped
into an article in the Philadelphia
Inquirer. Well, you're a little bit
weirded out as to why we are calling you.
Yes, I know. You know what I mean? I
just don't understand the whole thing.
That story really gets going with a phone
call to this woman, Elizabeth Mason.
I'm receptionist, last Swissport operator.
She works at a research lab in Boston.
And one day she's sitting in her desk
and she gets a call from a woman who says
that she has donated some eyes to them
and she wants to know what happened to
them. Call you going every day.
I just remember it was
just very unusual, right?
And to say I didn't
know what to do with it.
I just felt like I gotta find
somebody to help this woman.
Today we're going to tell
you the story of the,
of the woman on the other end of
that phone call. This is her story.
You might say their story. So for my
title, should I say, um, I'm Sarah Gray.
I'm the mom. I'm Ross
Gray, scree Thomas's dad.
And how did you guys meet while we're
waiting there and our bar in Glasgow.
Really? Yeah. It was on vacation with
a girlfriend and a and was it, uh,
was it a, was it, uh, what, what, what
happened without getting into too many?
I think we've got different ideas and
different recollection of what happened.
But,
well you started dating across the ocean
for a year and a half and then he moved
to America five days after you arrived.
They were married a few years after
that. They were pregnant with twins.
And when did you first
know that something was up?
It was at the 12 week screening.
They call it the first trimester
screening and they're checking for birth
defects. I think the most
common one is down syndrome.
But it was September 30th, 2009
they went in for the screening.
The ultrasound tech took a scan of the
two fetuses and shortly after the doc
came into the room and said that only
one of the twins would make it in one of
the twins that in unsafely and would
die within a few minutes or hours were
being born.
And he said he could see that because
one of the twins had around skull and the
other one had a bumpy skull. Huh.
But the bumpy skull showed him
that this goal wasn't correct.
It wasn't round enough. The brain
and skull weren't forming properly,
which is what anencephaly is. But
for shock, obviously. Yeah. Um,
I couldn't believe that. Yeah. It's
Kinda, it's difficult to process it,
I think. You think, yeah,
that can't be right.
They've just told us it's identical twins,
but one of them is completely different
from the other difficult fiction.
Ultimately making matters worse.
The doctors said that the unhealthy
twin was posing a threat to the healthy
twin, and if we were to be safe,
we would do a selective termination to
save the life of the healthy twin. Hmm.
So Sarah says they were
suddenly faced with this choice.
I actually docked to two priests on
the phone about it. Really? Yeah.
Her family's Catholic. She
was raised Catholic. I Dunno,
I guess I wanted to see what,
what their take was on this. Yeah.
This is probably not the direction we
want to go to for this my radio story,
but no man suddenly interested in,
basically what I was saying is would
you come and do a blessing over the
selection determination and what
they say? One priest said, no,
he just said he wouldn't do a
blessing over a selective termination.
And then the other priest said that
because of a Thomas Aquinas rule of like,
I think it was called
double account or something,
basically like the rule that if you,
if a train is coming and you like you
want to save the life of someone on the
train tracks and you shoot the
driver, that's the right thing to do.
After looking it up, it's actually called
the doctrine of double effect. And uh,
she's basically right. Maybe not the
part about the shooting the driver,
but the overall idea is that if you're
trying to do good and on the way to doing
good, you must inadvertently do some harm.
It's okay in certain circumstances, as
long as your intentions are good. Anyway,
the priest said,
because you're doing this with the
intent of saving the healthy twin that he
would be there and he would do a blessing.
Fast forward a few weeks we'd booked a
hotel and we'd packed her bags and the
night before was really terrible
for both of us cause I dunno,
we had seen him on the screen and we
sort of were attached to this little kid.
Next day they go in for the procedure,
we go into the room and
the doctor puts the um,
sonogram on me and start
getting ready and he said,
your placenta has moved since the last
time you were here and the location where
it is right now. Um, I don't think we
should do this. He said, if I nick it,
if I,
if I even just nick it a little bit like
you're going to bleed uncontrollably
and this is not safe to do.
You said they wouldn't
do it on his wife either.
What was that like to be on the,
on the table you've gone to leave?
Was it relief? Really?
Yeah, it was a relief.
I guess we've in the elevator we
just hugged. You were like, Oh,
I think the decision is taken at your
hands, you know, so it's not our fault.
But then your healthy twin
is more at risk maybe. Yes.
It was like a nail biter for the rest of
the six months. And according to Ross,
those six months were deeply strange
just by, in one of everything.
When you know those two babies coming,
then we knew we're going to be having
a funeral as well. So, you know,
I called the, um, what'd you call it?
The funeral director and told them,
you know, we're going to be
having a funeral. And like, well,
when was the death and all the guys not
even born yet, you know, but I know.
All right.
So they get to the day of
March 23rd 23rd 2010 10:30 AM
Thomas came out first and he's the sick
one that had anencephaly and then a
minute later column came out.
I know it wasn't sure if Thomas
was going to be born alive.
I sort of expected him to
die within a few minutes, but
it was, he was struggling
at first when he came at it,
they didn't think he was
going to last too long,
but then he kind of rally rally. Then
he was doing pretty good. And then
Lee, it was then Callum, the healthy twin,
who started to have some
trouble at the beginning.
And so he and Sarah went
off to the infant ICU.
And so Ross says in the delivery room,
no, it was just me and Thomas
for quite a while. I see.
We're just sitting together.
What was that like?
Right. It was,
it was like, you know, it was cute.
You know, he's a little slim Brian,
you baby. You know what I mean?
They cry, but he was like,
grab it onto my finger and oh no, it
didn't. The kind of things that babies do,
you know, there's nothing you can do,
but just kind of give him a cuddle,
you know, and try and try and stop
and cry crying and [inaudible]
I n I remember coming to the recovery
room and Ross had this little bundle in
his arms and I said, who is that? And
he said, Thomas. And I said, he's alive.
And I'm like, Oh, let me hold him. And
so I held him and yeah, he was cute.
Like he breastfed and we could
feed him with the bottle.
They ended up taking him home.
I didn't really planned on that.
Like we didn't have another car seat. Um,
we just didn't think of that.
And I remember thinking like,
what if he's going to beat the odds?
Like, do we need to arrange daycare?
And like, you know, we
hadn't thought of that.
It seems all right and we could
hang in here for awhile, you know.
But then soon after Thomas
started having seizures,
he started having trouble
breathing, stopped eating.
And at the time I remember thinking,
you know what, come on little guy,
like just eat some more. Like if you
eat some more than you'll be stronger.
And I was like, just eat. Just eat.
Yeah.
Well, so, uh, how, how, how
long did Thomas live in the end?
Six days. Six days.
He died in Ross's arms and he was
surrounded by all of the people that loved
him.
And then right then we called
the Washington regional
transplant community and
they sent a van over to our house and
they picked up his body and took him to d
c um, children's national medical center.
[inaudible]
okay. So this is where, uh, the story
really gets going? I guess so, yeah.
How did that idea of donating his
organs, skin come into your head?
Do you see an article in the paper,
the newspaper article or something?
Yeah,
my mom saw an article about a baby who
had an huffily who donated liver cells
and most major religions support
organ donation. Oh, okay.
So the van came, picked up,
Thomas. Uh, what happened next?
Nothing happened. Nothing stood up.
Follow up for a long time. You know,
I think there's some letter we got
left letter in the mail, I guess
sorta a form letter. It basically said
thank you for your generous donation.
Thomas's a cornea [inaudible] sent to
this place in Boston where they study a
potential cure for blindness and his
liver had been sent at this place in
Durham, North Carolina, where they
study a ways to treat uh, liver disease.
It seemed generic to me cause
I thought, I want to know like,
like who ordered it? Which researcher got
it and what study are they working on?
But you know,
they went on with their lives because
they had this new baby Callum Terez.
So they put it behind
them for the most part.
But then Sarah says they got to the one
year anniversary, one year anniversary.
Yeah, sure. We felt like a big
moment to me. Like that's when I can,
that's when it stops being in the
present and it can being in the past,
you know, just explaining it to people.
He's, I can say it was a year ago,
so they don't have to feel
stressed out when they talk to me.
And it felt like a big deal.
Like I think we were going to go to the
cemetery and put some flowers on his
grave and I wanted to tell my family
what were the results of his donation.
So she called the donor family services
person at the place that picked up
Thomas's body and she
basically asked them like,
is there any more information you can
give us about the specific study or the
researcher of something was
published and they didn't have any.
So I just thought, okay,
well I tried, you know,
but she couldn't quite let it go. What
do you mean she couldn't quite let it go,
you know, curiosity.
But also think she was
having on some level,
like a big conversation with the
universe. They both were like,
this terrible thing happened. How do
you explain it to yourself? I mean,
I think honestly it's shorter.
It sort of shook my faith in
God and how the universe works.
I thought that Karma worked or if I
was a basically a good person and I've
obeyed the rules, good things would
happen to me. Whatever the reason,
these thoughts about Thomas and where
he ended up, they were just there.
She had no real opportunity to act on it,
so they would just kind of
come in and out of her mind.
But then around the two year
anniversary, so this is now a year later,
I had a business trip to Boston and I
was exhibiting at a conference at Heinz
Convention Center and I googled
it and I saw that Skype bins,
eye research institute
was just a few miles away.
That's where Thomas' corneas
had been said, ah, lunch break.
That's exactly what I did. I
called Skype ins and I said,
you know,
I donated my son's eyes to this lab a
couple of years ago and I'm here in town.
Is there any chance I can come by
for a tour for like 10 minutes?
Then with the weird, been a weird
phone call. Yes. I mean, yes. Yeah,
that was like a wake her up or
that's Elizabeth Mason again.
It was just very unusual.
I think she was surprised.
I didn't know what to do with it. Had
you ever gotten a call like that before?
Never have gotten in the car and just
been working there for 25 years. She said,
hold on, let me connect you to
the right person. Don't hang up.
A lot of times when I say
something they hang up on me.
So I said please help line y started
searching for someone to speak with.
It's going to take me a while cause I've
got to figure out who that is but don't
hang up.
And they connected me with someone in
donor relations but it was financial donor
relations. Oh like like the honey.
Yeah, organ donor. But they,
cause they don't have any other
donor relations that you know,
like that was the person that gives the
tours and deals with the public so that
she got to talk to me
and she was [inaudible].
The woman was a little bit
flustered but super nice and said,
we know we've never done this
before. But yeah, come on down.
We'll give you a tour. I was so excited.
I took pictures of the outside
of the building and I felt,
I stood in the lobby and I put one of
the brochures in my purse and I just felt
like, I can't believe I'm here.
This is like being in [inaudible]
workshop or something.
Like I didn't think this was a
place you could actually visit.
She was taken around and eventually
she got taken to the lab where Thomas'
corneas went and there were refrigerators
with signs that said no food.
And then she introduced me to this guy
called Dr. James [inaudible] who's a
professor of Ophthalmology at Harvard
Med school and he was eating his lunch at
his desk and she explained who
I was and he said, you know,
thank you for the donation and
do you have any questions for me?
And of course she did. I wanted to
know how valuable the eyes were.
Like if they get thousands and thousands
or if they get one or two or like when
the delivery came. Was everyone
excited or was it no big deal?
Like was it sitting on a shelf collecting
dust or were people doing stuff with
it? He put down his lunch and um,
he said most of the i's that we get are
from people who are older just because
most people are older when they die,
an infant's eyes are worth
their weight in gold.
Wow.
I was like, God, I could barely speak.
I was like, um, could you tell me why?
He said,
because they regenerate the
regenerative properties and he said,
if you don't mind me asking,
how long ago did your son die?
And I said about two years
ago. And he said, well,
we're likely still using
your sons cells right now.
Okay.
Cause that's how long they last.
Wow. I know.
So at that point Sarah was like,
okay, since that worked out so well,
why not just go keep going with it and
visit all of the places where bits and
pieces of Thomas ended up. So, you
know, chase down his liver, his retina,
his cord blood. How many doctors might
that be? Do you have any idea? Like,
well there's the Boston one,
there's two in North Carolina.
She would ultimately discover
one in Richmond, Virginia,
one in Philly. What if?
What if? It turns out that
these people, you know,
didn't find anything. You
know, research is research.
You don't always have a head. That's true.
She's not hitting for validation
necessarily. Here. She might find it.
She might get further lost. Well,
yeah, but she's going to go.
She's going to go and she's not
going to stop. Cross your fingers.
It's coming up.
Hi, this is Shereen from sunrise, Florida.
Radiolab is supported in part by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
[inaudible].
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
Radiolab is supported by wordpress.com
wordpress.com offers e-commerce options
that range from effective buy button to
a complete online store as well as code
free site building,
so you don't need a professional designer
to get your website up and running if
you need help.
Wordpress has a customer support team
that is available 24 seven learn more and
get 15% off any new pen purchased at
wordpress.com/radiolab
okay.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by progressive,
progressive offers you tons
of ways to save on insurance,
starting with builtin and savings,
like discounts for being a safe driver.
You can also save for getting a quote
online and when you bundle home and auto,
you can even save more. In fact,
customers who switched to progressive
can save an average of $668 a year on car
insurance. Start a quote online and
start saving today. Visit progressive.com
watch just moments before the shooting
that meant 2016 and I'm to black man shot
by police.
Jim was a mental health worker who was
trying to return and autistic patient to
a group home
host of after effect,
a podcast from w n YC studios police.
We're trying to shoot the other guy, the
Latino autistic man. This is his story.
Listen and subscribe to after effect
wherever you get your podcasts.
Yes.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I am Robert
Krulwich. Uh, this is radio.
Where are we at this point? Okay.
Yeah. So Sarah, Greg, when we left her,
she was standing in a research office
in Boston and feeling good. Yeah,
she's gotten this rose of a success.
And so after that her and Ross had getting
a car and head down south to Durham,
North Carolina to track down a Thomas's
liver and a bit of his blood cord blood
because it turns out that in the delivery
room right after both twins were born,
nurses had withdrawn a little bit
of cord blood from both twins,
sent it off to Duke where researchers
were studying the disease that killed
Thomas and incessantly. She says they
walked in, we met the study coordinator,
this guy who worked on the human
genome project, uh, Grad students.
They met all these different researchers
who all seemed really excited about her
twins blood samples.
I think it was just weird that one of
them had anencephaly and one of them
didn't and they were
genetically identical.
So it's a good control study for them to
compare. After they all took the tour,
one of the researchers even told them
that they had compared Thomas' blood to
columns and they found there
were a thousand differences
in epigenetics between
both twins. They're called
epigenetic differences.
I think their genes are the same.
But the things that control the genes
were different. That's so interesting.
So they began identical,
but then somehow in utero thousand little
changes crept up between them. Yes.
Yeah.
It's possible that a few of those changes
might one day explain the disease.
In fact,
I even asked the Grad student who
worked on it most closely Dierdre crop,
I said, were you surprised by
what you saw? And she said,
for me to be surprised, that implies that
I knew what to expect. She said, well,
just at the beginning of this,
trying to learn about this.
So that's two roses, like this is a,
this is an amazing gift visit to sort
of kickbox. She's on a roll here.
So after visit two, they got in the car,
drove down the street to
this place called Cyto Net,
which is where Thomas has liver.
I ended up basically side on it,
will take a solid liver and they liquefy
it and then they inject the liquid
liver into a baby that's waiting on a
liver transplant as a bridge therapy.
Liquid liver, liver in a tube. Yeah. They
went in and got a tour. Refrigerators,
petri dishes, the whole thing.
The researchers then tell her that they
had a little issue with Thomas's liver.
His liver was bruised when they got it
so they couldn't inject it into a baby.
But then they told her that they were
able to use it in an experiment to
determine what was the best temperature
to freeze infant liver cells,
which is negative 150 degrees
Celsius as you already know,
common knowledge, half a rose there,
half a rose and she says at one point
as they were being walked around the
place,
we walked through the break room and
someone had taken a picture of Thomas that
we had handed out and they
took the photograph and they
taped it up in the break
room with a little sign that they wrote
on at St Thomas Gray was a donor here in
March 29th,
2010 and I was so excited to see that
because I thought they're just as curious
about us as we are about them.
Like I was wondering who,
what kind of person goes to work
and opens up a box with liver in it.
And they're probably wondering what kind
of person takes their loved one's liver
and puts it in a box
and mailed it over here.
So, uh, my name is
[inaudible] Ganguly. Uh,
I am a professor in the Department of
Genetics at University of Pennsylvania
School of medicine.
Now a Rupa Ganguly just
switched to her for a second.
She studies a kind of cancer of
the eye called Retinal Blastoma,
which happens almost
exclusively in children.
And at this point she doesn't know Sarah.
She has no concept of this
whole search that's happening.
She is just studying eyes. Where
are we by the way? Philly, Philly,
Philadelphia. No, she studies tumors,
but she also needs healthy
retinas in order to do her work.
Now you can imagine that getting
a normal retina is not a very,
uh, easy task because why would you
get a normal retina from a baby?
I must allude that if and
when an eyeball comes,
it is not a pleasant experience, right?
Because for a moment you
have to think the origin,
the sources of this eyeball,
and it's sad and every possible setting,
it's sad, sad and frustrating. She says,
because only when a normal child dies,
that's when I can get this retina.
So it's a horrible set up in my mind.
So she says often when the retinas
arrive, which happens maybe once a year,
and you pull them out of their
packaging, you right away you feel like,
like maybe you're trading
on other people's misery.
And I'm an, it's so bad when a child dies,
but I am asking for his
or her retina in a way.
I had this sense of guilt in my head. No,
Aruba had never spoken to a
parent of any of her samples.
So when she got that email and she was
sitting at a computer and she read the
email from the company that
provided or the sample saying,
the mother of this sample wants
to get in contact with you,
ah, I paused, I stopped and uh, uh,
doing what I was doing and I thought, um,
why does the mother want to talk to me?
That was my first question. So
I did not reply right away. But
after my conversation with the lab,
I took I think one day
to compose a letter.
And I sent it back to Sarah Gray and
they ended up eventually talking on the
phone. I told her, I think, uh,
at the very onset that Sarah,
you have to understand
that, um, I feel awful.
She said she felt kind of guilty
because she wished for this sample,
like almost by wishing for it,
she had made it happen. She said,
you should not feel bad about it.
If you didn't use my son's retina,
I would have buried it in the ground.
Like you're the only one that wanted it.
Bad things happen to children.
And so by being able to
help you with your work,
we added a layer to Thomas's life
that was, uh, I was amazed.
Eventually Sarah and
Ross visited Arup as lab.
She gave them a tour and she
sewed them Thomas' retina.
She still has samples of it
in her freezer. Tiny little,
I don't know, tiny little
vials, maybe a third.
The size of your pinkie filled with
frozen liquid liquified right now or in a,
it didn't look like much,
but it was amazing to think of how
many people were involved getting these
samples. They're like, we had to approve
it. We had to fill out this paperwork.
Then the doctor had to
come and remove the highs.
The NYSE had to be processed and
then I'd have to be shipped up there.
Then they have to do whatever
DNA process they do and just how,
I don't know, valuable, maybe
even priceless. The sample is,
Sarah says that throughout the whole
process of losing a child and then seeing
him reclaimed bit by bit by
all of these different people,
something she shifted in me.
[inaudible]
I used to think like the universe treated
people the way it should and now I
don't really believe that, but
um, I do believe that there are,
um,
really amazing kind people in the world
and science and medicine has something
to do with that.
[inaudible]
I started feeling that these were Thomas'
colleagues in his coworkers and that
he was a valuable partner in the important
research that was being done and felt
an even more fundamental shift.
Almost like I had felt like I was a
boat on an ocean that was like rocky and
choppy with waves. And I've
had this feeling that I am,
I'm not the boat on the ocean,
like the decisions that I make are
changing other people as opposed to just,
I'm a boat getting slack
with waves all the time.
Like the thank the Philadelphia Inquirer
for getting us going on this. Yeah.
Especially, yeah.
Big thanks to Michael Vitez for his
reporting and to dummy and Marchetti for
production support and to lots of
Nasr for all that help with research.
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. Thanks for listening.