Okay, I'll do that. Okay, let me
do one more time. Three, two, one.
This is Tim Howard and today on radiolab
we've been talking about black boxes
and the next story started with a radio
piece that I heard at the third coast
international audio festival. There
were a lot of incredible stories,
but there was this one called keep
them guessing that I just loved and I
couldn't get it out of my head.
So I sat jad and Robert Down in our
little black box of a studio on deep look.
Tim Howard, I'm not sure.
I like your tone. Okay.
And I connected them with the
guy who made the piece. Hello.
Okay.
I hear the sound of what sounds like
another room. Does he sound like me now?
Oh, his name is Jesse Cox.
Wow. You spent so close.
Can See your foot far away.
He's actually in Australia where everybody
is because they're upside down from
the rest of us. They are very,
very likely to fall into the sky.
You have as Australians worked
out, down to the tee, rub it.
I'm gripping on with my hands and the
table. That's what we speak. You'll get.
Just to start, I mean, maybe just
introduce us to your grandparents.
Who are they? Well, my, my
grandparents were mind readers.
Mm.
On the radio. Really? Yeah. You don't
have to explain that on what are they?
What are their names? First? Leslie,
Leslie Pennington and Sydney Pennington.
Piddington. He didn't and
they had a radio show. Yeah.
The show was called the pediatricians or
the amazing Penningtons and was on the
BBC radio in the 1950s now Jesse told
us that for most of his life he didn't
know this.
I guess the reason was that my grandfather
and my grandmother divorced well
before I was born, and then his grandpa,
he died when I was four or five.
Then his grandma remarried,
so nobody talked about it.
Crazily enough,
I knew that my grandparents had been
famous and my grandma was an actress,
that it really wasn't until I was a
teenager and a radio produce actually
discovered by accident that my
grandma was alive. I went, what?
They still have Pennington alive. The
reporter calls up his grandma's like, Hey,
can I interview you? And my grandma
was hesitant. She was like, Oh,
I'm not sure. I'll be very
good. I can try and remember,
and I came and interviewed her and when
it went to air, when it got broadcast,
we all drove up to his grandma's house
and listened to it around the radio that
they would have back in the 1950s and
heard the story and that's when Jesse
discovered that his grandparents,
Leslie and Sidney Pennington one time
had an audience of 20 million people.
Yeah.
Basically the population of Australia
was listening to my grandparents back in
the 1950s no way. I was like, yeah,
why? Why don't I know this is,
this is in my family and why?
Why don't I know it? But he says,
it was really when he sat down and
listened to the original broadcasts,
what's left to them?
Two hours of old BBC recordings that
survived today because my grandparents
pirated them from the
BBC back in 1950 he says,
it wasn't until he heard
those tapes that I went, wow,
tell us this story. Tell us what you
heard that made you go, wow. Well
[inaudible]
you hear these very dramatic theme song
and this old BBC voice comes into the
tape and says,
what do you mean? Maybe some
gentlemen, we present the fitting
and the music guys are
all very, very dramatic,
and then the narrator
sets the scene for you,
but eating too old by that Herman here
and the other one pick at least two.
They're right in the middle
of the west end of London.
It was done in front of a live audience
and then you hear my grandfather's
voice. Well, as Steven Grandpa had just
told you, live has been quite Insightly.
Exciting for us. He was
a stutterer out back.
We've had a lot more letters.
There were all these things that meant
it should never have worked on radio.
Anyhow, anyhow,
the night my grandfather was in the
studio on the stage and my grandma,
I'm sorry to say Leslie isn't here,
she was often somewhere dramatic as
in not in the studio somewhere exotic.
One time she was in a
dive in the diving bell.
She was underwater at the
bottom of a test tank.
One time she was in the
tower of London. Right.
You're there unless they end up town. Yes,
I am here and I remember pinning good
it here in the Piccadilly studio and
Leslie was in the Tower
of London. So, so your,
your grandpa's on stage and your grandma
you're saying is in a tower by phone or
no, she's in front of, she's
in front of a microphone now.
This is back in the time when microphones
were the size of small melons.
Very shortly there'd be a microphone
set up in the Tower of London.
Connected live. Yeah.
My grandfather then comes on the year
and sets up a series of telepathy tests
that they go into enact.
I know I down to work,
I will attempt to transmit that
to Leslie on a line of print.
I selected from a number of books
on the table here in the studio.
So there was a famous one called the book
test and this is where a member of the
audience would come up to the stage and
there'd be a pile of books and they'd
randomly pick up a book randomly
opened to a page and point to a line.
Would you read out the line
to the listening audience?
The lines elected is be abandon as the
electrician said that they would have no
color now,
completely random bit of tech selected
out of a stack of books after the texts
had been chosen and only then
I should now call in the tower of London.
They would connect to his grandma Leslie
in the Justin moment at the sound of
the Gong, I want your complete silence,
your sympathy and your cooperation.
Now concentrate on the line while
I attempt to transmit it to Leslie
and a Gong would sound and he'd kind
of very dramatically Farro his brow.
And the next thing you
heard was my grandmother.
It's sort of fry,
old gentle voice and she start to unpick
what was being transmitted to her.
It's something to do.
Okay.
And and Christian.
There's something about
light and electricians
[inaudible].
Remember that line again was
the abandon. I see electrician said
that they would have no column.
If you concentrate on the word
[inaudible]
like being Lyft, people being Lyft,
it's amazing to listen to over 60
years later listening to those tapes,
I'm still on the edge of my seat,
abandoned that
knocked light,
concentrate on the word like
light and right at the end,
I think the whole line is
abandoned as the electricians said,
they would not be current
via abandon as the electrician
said that they would have no color
[inaudible] almost every time it would
be 100% correct. Totally remarkable.
[inaudible]
it just was this feeling inside you
that you get going, hang on. What?
When Jessie heard those broadcasts,
his obvious question was
how did they do that? Well,
this is the question that I have wanted
to know for so long and there'll be
many, many theories. I mean,
they used to get letters in
from listeners all the time.
There's this box of press clippings
we found at the bottom of my grandma's
closet and we started going through
these press clippings and there were wild
theories, like little morse code
transmitters in their teeth.
Yeah, I mean,
one of the theories I quite liked with
[inaudible] who wrote in saying there was
a green man that ran between the shoulders
and he knew they sought authority
because he also had a green man, and
so that was precisely how they did it.
But you are totally convinced that this
was a carefully worked out trick of some
kind. Yes. That is the one
part of almost certainty.
I can say, oh, there has
to be some secret codes.
I'm tapping of the some something. Well,
you're not the first person to say that.
The people were constantly trying
to guess what the code was.
That's Jim Steinmeyer. I'm a an
author and a consultant and magicians.
He says that at the time,
some magicians in London thought that
his stammer was part of the code.
I do to not see.
I can just think is
Jesse for his part ended up going
through a ton of these theories as he
interviewed magicians and historians
read through magic books initially.
One of the theories that made sense to
him is that the code was in the silence
that basically my grandparents and my
grandma was so in sync that between each
time a sound or a word was uttered,
that inside their head start going through
the alphabet and they'd be so ensured
and so in sync that whatever letter that
matched up that that would be a code.
Wait, Jad
a, B, c,
Hi de Apathy. No sassy. I am wondering
a, B, c, d, e,
f. G. The next letter is
going to be Jay. Yeah,
of course. As soon as you do,
as soon as you start playing any
of these theories out on real time,
you realize how ridiculous they are and
if you listen to the second broadcast of
the two that survived,
you hear something that makes the whole
idea of a code seem kind of impossible.
Yeah.
That was a test I did on the airplane
broadcast in that broadcast is grandma.
She was in a, an Arrow
flying at a great height, did a great
speed toward something or other,
but we're not sure where
flying around Bristol and she was in
this plane at the same moment that he was
on stage. Exactly.
And on that time there were numbered
envelopes on everyone's seat.
And my grandfather said, okay,
everyone brought something and put
it in the envelope, seal it up.
Just write a poem off the top of
your head. 150 people do this.
And then sit turns to one of
the judges and says, okay,
pick two numbers from one to 150 and
then someone goes into the audience and
goes and picks those two envelopes,
brings them back to the stage,
gives them to the judges, and then
the judge picks one of the envelopes,
pulls out the poem, and then holds
it in front of my grandfather.
And so here you have a poem chosen
seemingly at random and Leslie,
the grandma is several thousand feet
in the air when they finally connect to
her.
Best personal comment. Hello.
Hello. The short way relay,
Leslie is still completely isolated.
She can't even hear a
word that they're saying.
She never had a pair of headphones so
she could never actually hear what was
going on in the studio.
She literally just spoken to a microphone
once the technician said, Leslie,
we're ready. We're ready for you.
It's thousands of people
below Sydney is there.
Furrowing his brow and the
poem he's trying to send
her is from Keith's one line
that goes hail to the blind
spirit bird that will never work.
[inaudible]
oh it's, it's two lines.
I've got it. I can get it
Heyo to the live spirit bird.
I'll never would I Ms. Young.
Would you read out the ones written
down on the piece of paper that you hold
hail to the blind spirit but
down? Never would. Thank you.
Crazy part. Is it in that trick, your
grandpa doesn't even talk to her.
There's complete silence between seed
and Leslie and if there's silence there
can be no coding. So you
know, it was kind of this,
this wonderful prices that I talked
to people and even as I came up with
theories,
you'd listened to the tape and then
realize that even the theories themselves
just seem so implausible.
Well, maybe it's the narrator.
Do you think it's a narrator
or that whatever it is,
the narrator says each
night, which is before your,
before the game is even on
somehow encoded into that,
that man's introduction is, is
is the answer. No, because the,
because the audience hasn't yet gone and
done its random act when he starts the
show. There was one thing that I
discovered from reading the magic books,
and this is this whole idea about passing
on a piece of information through a
third party. Now my grandfather
never speaks to my grandma,
but he says to the
technician in the studio,
can you please call Gilbert Sullivan in
the strata cruiser and ask my wife to
stand by. Then the technician
calls Gilbert and says, Gilbert,
can you please ask Leslie to stand by?
And then Gilbert Sullivan
says to my grandma, Leslie,
please stand by now.
That's is the only thing I can see where
there's some kind of communication,
but then we'll
communicate something like a random
sentence from a book or whatever. Exactly.
And that sent essentially where the theory
falls down because then what happens
next is that my grandma
basically successfully recites
a half written crossword,
which someone has put into an
envelope and pass up to my grandpa.
So like you go how? How standby
means. That means you know, six down.
I have no idea what that really,
I'm back to square one again. Oh,
I can't work it out. I've
got, you know the to this day,
you don't know to this day, I do
not know to this day. Where's the,
where's the ways we know? We can't know.
There's gotta be somebody who knows.
Can't believe we can go into this
interview. We have no way. We have no,
so it's the technician. It's
gotta be the technician.
You gotta get to the technician because
the technician is looking at her and
he's doing something pilot to do
is move their lips, their, that he,
there's something is happening with
that man's eyebrows. That's the code.
It's the eyebrows. I feel like
I'm just listening to this,
like what's been going on in
my head for about 10 12 years.
So then I ask Jesse like what happened
when he talked to his grandma?
Total dead end.
You mean like showing up around once we
discovered this story around the dinner
table, women visited. Hoed would always
be, but, but why don't you tell us?
Why can't you tell it's with family.
Surely you can tell us and she
would fob us often and just say,
you are the judge.
That is the line that I finished or that
is the line they finished with every
single broadcast.
Did they just say no,
only thanks very much everyone and
you're the judge. I will. I think
[inaudible] all right, I'm that,
but we'll know that just through
the predicament. Pick a did it.
She wouldn't even give me the satisfaction
of saying yes, it was a trick.
She won't even say that clearly
you are the favorite grandchild.
It was probably another another.
You have a cousin or a sibling who she
really adored at one day without your
knowing it, she whispered. No secret to
her, not about to her son. Your father,
what did, did, did she, did she
tell him? Did she tell your dad?
She told my dad something. What
did she tell him? I have no idea.
He will not even admit being
told something if she slipped
up. Is it Jessie's dad?
And I'm not even sure
that she did slip up.
Um,
I see. And I approved my dad
then. Why you can't say yes,
Leslie did tell me something.
I'm not going to tell you, but yes,
she did actually tell me something.
If my mum and trusted me with
something all those years ago,
then I will keep that trust. Why?
Because I believe in keeping
trust. My Dad won't tell my mum they've
been together for over 30 years.
You just have to continue. No nothing.
There is no book that's published.
There's no one that came out and said, ah,
I was the fellow who worked behind
the scenes with the Penningtons.
Let me tell you how it was done.
That's Jim Steinmeyer again,
they left people guessing
and, and walked away. Well,
the thing that got me is when I was
talking to magicians and they said we can
repeat everything that they did
really so they can actually do,
I mean like you know,
one of them is in a plane and
other ones in on the apparently,
but they still themselves don't know 100%
for sure. How my grandparents did it.
If we, if we could figure this
out or would you want you,
it sounds like you would want to know
the answer. I'm not so sure anymore.
Really. We all say we want to know and
we all go completely crazy and mad,
but I, I, I feel like this story
wouldn't have lasted for 60 years.
It wouldn't still captivate people today
if they told people if they hadn't kept
their line, you are the judge.
I kind of feel like that's almost the
greater magic than whatever magic they
would do.
I just feel like this is a black box
that we can shine a light into it and go,
okay, check that one off the list.
Now we can go to the other ones.
The cool thing. Now, if
we can't figure it out,
then you will be very happy with our
program. If we can figure it out,
we will call you and say,
do not listen to this show because
it will deeply disappointed.
Well, I mean the thing,
the thing I think for me that made me
come to peace with not finding out and not
knowing the answer was that a lot of the
interviews I did with my grandma were
from a few years ago and she
actually isn't very well,
she has dementia and she's been
sick the past couple of years.
And so she physically
can't tell it any more.
And Yeah, for me there is
something about, you know,
I visit my grandma now and
you go, she was amazing.
She not only did she make this
incredible program with my grandfather,
they had 20 million people listen
to them, which is just incredible.
When you think of the 1950s um,
they've managed to [inaudible]
well, what happened? Hey, no, no,
no. Jess come back. No,
we just went straight on
the hour or is exactly,
it's exactly x nine seconds ago. Yeah.
Mother a cell
phone. I'm just going to call
him. Yeah. Hello? Hello? Yeah. Hi.
I'm
your booking ran out just a minute ago.
Yes. We noticed that. It that uh, yeah,
yeah,
I think we'll probably need to use the
phone cause that booth now needs to be
used.
Sorry. So we call Jesse back and while
we didn't drag him back into the studio,
actually we couldn't. Um,
he did send us this tape.
Now you've held onto secret so many, so,
so many years. Why haven't
you wanted to reveal it to me?
I think the reason I haven't ever wanted
to reveal the secret is because it's a
wonderful mystery and I'd
like to think that, uh,
after I've died, people will still
say, how did they do it? Was it doing,
wasn't it?
It just tickles me to think
about a lot of secrets,
magic secrets.
They get passed down from generations
and they get really performed over and
over again. I guess that very much
becomes a part of that family.
Now as a performer myself, if I
wanted to bring back the pollutants,
would you feel like you could hand
down this magic trick to your,
to your grandson to
carry it on? Of course.
If I had a grandson who
wanted to carry it on,
I'd have enormous difficulty
telling him how to,
I don't think it would be possible because
there's an awful lot that I wouldn't
be able to tell him. What do you mean
you wouldn't get it to handle that man,
son? It's hard to explain.
Why wouldn't be able to,
it's just that I wouldn't be able to.
It's all I can say about that.
Our sincere thanks to Jesse Cox for so
graciously allowing us to air that story
and also thank you to ABC national radios,
three 60 documentaries who
produced the story with him? Uh,
it's called keep them guessing and we've
linked to the original story on our
website, radio lab.org.
So, well, you know,
I don't think it's actually time for us
to end this because I didn't tell you
this.
We were so interested in trying to
figure out how they did that trick.
[inaudible] that Soren and I,
because we just wanted to find out
like did somebody know how they did it?
So we called this guy.
Okay.
All right. Who ruined everything?
This is Penn Jillette who you
probably know from Penn and teller,
famous for doing magic tricks and
then telling you how are done now.
I don't really know what I was
expecting when we called him. I,
I guess I was thinking he
would know what they did,
but he wouldn't choose to
tell us. I didn't know.
But when we called them and we played
him the story, as soon as he heard it,
he said, oh, it's a book
test, right? It's a book test.
It's an envelope switch or
what? And there are, you know,
three or four ways to
do it. What did he say?
He said basically I can tell
you how they did it. Yeah.
Or how they might have done it, but
you are not going to like it there.
There go. The only Shukran in magic,
there's only one and that is
that the secret must be ugly.
You cannot have a beautiful secret, a
beautiful secrets, that kind of thing.
It's short and sweet like,
Yo, he folded the hat twice.
Or there's mirrors under that table. When
you hear it, it's like, oh, of course,
that's what they would do,
and you love finding it out.
Then you will whisper it to the
person next to you. So in magic,
what you want is an idea
that is not beautiful.
What do you call this as a magic trick?
That stays secret is one
that's so boring to tell.
You don't want to tell it and
you don't even want to hear it.
If I have to say he's lying about this
and there's gaffers tape over behind
there and there,
they're not actually telling you the
exact truth here and it gets so our,
you don't get an Aha.
One of the strongest feelings
you can get in the life.
What are the most rewarding
feelings is the feeling of an Aha.
I finally understand. If you
don't have a wonderful Aha,
people won't figure it out. So I've got,
I can tell you easily
how they did that trick,
but you will not get an Aha.
Basically you said that you answer to
this one is going to kill your joy. Yeah,
it's ugly. So did he, did he
tell you what they did? Yeah.
What'd he say? Well, I'll tell you,
I'll tell you in just a second.
You went into excruciating detail
about how he thinks they did it.
No a book tasks. We
actually do one in our show,
but the more important
thing, he was so right.
Once we heard the explanation and the
details and all we were were both like,
yeah, all right. Well,
yes, with a poison dart and love
how much I bugged your shit.
As you can hear.
He knew exactly what he was doing with
us and in a way he's asking us a deeper
and more of a philosophical
question. I've done this to you.
Will you turn around and do it to your
audience? Will all I've done to you,
you know, because you get to edit.
All I have done is put you in precisely
the position I live my life in.
You now have to make the exact same
decisions that I make and I will,
I will tell you, and this is just true,
that I would have played this particular
thing a differently with almost any
other show. You know, my move on the, uh,
on the chessboard with another
show would be to say, uh, you know,
I do have several ideas as to how this
could be done, but I think I'm, uh,
I'm going to be like the grandmother
and go to my grave with this. Hmm.
You know, and I would've just given
you that a soundbite. I just have
it set that we've pivoted
the entire piece called, so
it's like all eyes,
all eyes have been directed to the next
sentence. So that's a little difficult.
But I want to see how you solve
a problem that I solve every day.
But we have like a higher
call, like you're entertaining.
But we're entertaining with the caveat
that we're supposed to be like telling
the truth as best we understand it.
So we have a slightly different set of
gods and our Mount Olympus than you do
it. You don't really, you don't really,
because I am not suggesting that you lie.
You're just going to have
to tell your audience.
Would you think they need to
hear? And that's where he left it.
So in the days after the interview week,
we just got into this debate
about what we should do.
We obviously have an obligation to you.
You listening to tell you what we know.
Yes. The whole deal. Yeah.
We can't pretend that we don't know
something that we now do know, uh,
even if it would make a
much more beautiful story.
So this leaves us in a
conundrum. A, are we,
are we entertainers or are we
actually lists journalists?
So here's where we ultimately came down.
We have decided not to tell you
how the Penningtons did it. I mean,
we are going to tell you,
but we're not going to tell you here in
this podcast because we have now been
soiled by this truth. We
learned off the record and you,
if you want to be soiled,
sure. Come and soil yourself.
You can go to this URL,
radiolab.org/the ugly truth.
Don't click this
Don't no pasta fee. Click this
and we just leave it to you.
You can go there or you can not. All
I've said to you is that it's a trick.
Yeah, and you knew that the fact that
it wasn't the trick you wanted it to be?
No, he did turn sweet at one moment
we were talking about the grandma.
Grandma tells the grandson in the
conversation at the end, she is not sure.
She could explain to him how
it was. That's beautiful.
That is the most beautiful thing that
that happens in the whole thing because I
think she's telling the truth.
She may not know how the trick was
done and yet she was a party to it.
She's the one who he says, you know,
oftentimes when you're doing tricks,
somebody knows everything and the
other person is in the dark. Yeah.
One of the,
you mean like one of the partners
intentionally not knows what's happening?
Yeah, there are. There are tricks
in the Penn and teller show,
but I don't really know how they're
done. It might've happened here.
He may have, uh, decided that
he would be the knowing one.
She would be the innocent, and maybe
therefore, and this is just a hunch,
but just possibly everything she's
saying to her grandchild instead of being
a kind of dodge or a little bit
of a lie, maybe it was the whole.