Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad, I'm
Robert Krulwich, Radiolab.
And today today we are trying to figure
out how to make a deal with yourself
when most of you doesn't want to do
what the rest of you wants to do. Right.
And we've talked about these kinds of
deals when it comes to avoiding the
sirens, quitting smoking, figuring out
what to do with the balance of your life.
Now we're going to change things a bit.
Let's say instead of being an addict,
let's say you're just a writer. Yeah.
And you want to be inspired.
You want the words to come.
And this is very typical
situation. They're not coming. No,
no words to the question is
in that kind of situation,
what kind of deals could you make
with yourself to get the words out?
This is a, this is fanciful.
My friend Oliver Sacks,
the neurologist and the writer,
he made a deal, which frankly,
I find this kind of astonishing
[inaudible] bargain with creativity.
I will tell you all the,
I probably shouldn't, uh,
the first book I wrote, Migraine, um,
was very obstructed. And
then by obstructed he means
he just got stuck. Yes,
day after day he,
she tried to write something down and
it just didn't come and I was getting
desperate on the matter.
And finally on September the
first of 1968 I said to myself,
you have 10 days to write
this book. If it is not done,
then you commit suicide. Whoa.
And under the
imagined threat,
which seem to tell lie me in a way
because you're, you're what the,
the other half of you thought that
the first half of you meant it. Yes.
Did the first half of you
mean it? I don't know,
but there was a lot of, this
was that after months of,
of stewing and not doing anything,
I started work and what started as a,
as a fearful task soon became a
joyful task with this own momentum.
And suddenly he had this feeling
that there was something inside him.
Some engine inside me, a
wonderful associative engine,
which we've sourced together,
brings unexpected things
into our position.
It had kicked into gear and I'm just
kind of pulling things out of him and
putting them right there under the page.
I felt like who's being
dictated to me healing? Uh, I,
I was passive. I was the bridge,
I was the transmitter. Um,
and in fact, I finished
the book a day early.
That's a strange way to kick yourself
in the pants, I have to say. Yeah. Well,
um, for me a deadline sometimes is
felt homeless literally as such.
This is not an easy way to go to
work everyday. I wouldn't think.
I don't think corn can make bonk and
it's like that definitely not too often.
And it would have a cost. I'll
never of course did that only once,
but the story told got us thinking,
is there a bargain that you can make
with yourself, your creative self?
It somehow avoids this
terrible cost. Yeah.
That as long as this led me generally in
front too late a woman who just does it
differently.
I have this fascination with trying to
figure out how you can live a lifetime of
creativity without cutting your ear
off. You know what I mean? And who is,
who is that? Oh, I'm Liz Gilbert and well,
just something a little bit
not which Liz Gilbert rd.
I'm the Liz Gilbert who wrote
the book called the pray love.
I guess that's the way she described
myself because that's how my obituary will
read, eat, pray,
love in case you were born under a rock
or raised by wolves is one of the most
popular books ever,
ever, ever in the world.
It became even more popular when the
book became a movie and Guess who played
Liz?
Liz Gilbert is remarkable.
Roberts or courage in the way
America's sweetheart and the success
was great, but she says, you know,
it was also kind of frightening because
there she was back at home in front of
the same old blank page
with a new question.
How will you ever outdo
what you did last time?
Suddenly she's back where
Oliver was obstructive.
She didn't think that that success
was going to be there the last time.
So was the last time a flute, do I
even have another big book in me?
Dangerous Recipe for madness madness.
But then she thought back to a
conversation that she once had with hope.
Who? Tom. Wait,
Tom [inaudible].
Where this all began was that I was,
I was a journalist for she Q and I did
an interview with him and he spoke about
the creative process, I
think more articulately than
anybody I have ever heard.
Um,
and he was talking about how every song
has a distinctive identity that it comes
into the world with and it needs to be
taken in different ways. And he said,
you know, there are songs that,
that you have to sneak up on,
like you're hunting for where rare bird.
And there are songs that
come fully intact, like a
dream taken through a straw.
And there are songs that you find little
bits of like pieces of gum underneath
the desk and you scrape them off and
you put them together and you make
something out of it. And there are some,
cause he said that
needed to be bullied, um,
where he said he's been in the studio
working on a song and the whole album is
done and this one song won't give
itself over. And he said, you know,
everyone's gotten used to
seeing him do things like this.
He'll march up and down the studio talking
to the song saying the rest of their
families in the car, we're all going
on vacation. You coming along or not,
you got 10 minutes or else you're getting
left behind, you know, and he's like,
you got to shake it down. Some
Times lists as that interview was
maybe the first time she thought of
inspiration as as a, as an it.
And I remember feeling my own center
of gravity shift and thinking, wait,
you're allowed to talk to this thing
that the source of her ideas
was outsider than she could get
some distance from it,
maybe negotiate with it,
even fight with it instead of beating
yourself up all the time. Right. And this,
the story that I loved that he told me
about where his artistic anxiety ended
and his sort of new artistic liberation
began is when he's driving along the
freeway in Los Angeles and like
eight lanes of traffic one day.
And this little fragment of a
beautiful song comes into his head
[inaudible]
and he has no way to record
it. He's gotten no pencil,
he's got no tape recorder and he's
in eight lanes of stressful track.
So coma, it was blue,
and he immediately starts to feel all
the old pressure that he's felt his whole
life of, I'm not good enough. I, you
know all the artistic struggle, right?
I can't do it. I'm not good
enough. I'm going to lose it. I,
it'll haunt me forever. And
then he just backed off from it
and instead he established
that negotiating distance
between him and the melody.
And he looked up at the
sky and he said, excuse me,
can you not see that I'm driving if
you're serious about wanting to exist,
I spent eight hours a day in the studio.
You're welcome to come and visit
me while I'm sitting at the piano.
Otherwise leave me alone and
go bother Leonard Cohen. Oh,
that's very bold. It is. I
think that's what she wants.
She wants you to push back and she
wants you to set some terms and some
boundaries.
She doesn't want you to go to the
Leonard Cohen Concert two years later.
Very kind of you to come to this.
Now this idea that somehow the
creative act comes from outside you,
you get a visit from a somebody, this
isn't a new idea. This is a very old idea.
You know the Greeks would call it the muse
[inaudible]
the Romans called it
the ingenium the genius,
which was an interesting idea because
it's not the way we use genius today,
right?
Today we say that it person is a genius
and back then they would've said a
person had one. Um,
and again it's the separation so that
the creative person has this externalized
collaborator. So this is a
tinker belly kind of a thing.
It sprinkles you has little
wings. And I think it depends.
I think it depends on the process.
I mean it's got a lot of names
because it takes a lot of forms,
right? And,
and we're talking about all this as though
these are actually kind of believe it
cause I don't think it
would work otherwise.
But I kind of do believe that the world
is being constantly circled as though by
Gulf stream forces ideas and creativity
that want to be made manifest and
they're looking for portals
to come through and people,
and if you don't do it,
they'll go find someone else. You know?
And and so you have to convince it that
you're serious and you have to show it
respect and you have to talk to it
and let it know that you're there.
Like for the last few years there's been
a novel that has been sort of stirring
in me and I haven't had time to give it
the attention it wants me to give it.
But every day I talk to it and I have a
little conversation with it and I say,
listen, I'm in April, I will be
with you. I want you to stay.
Don't let me wake up and read in the New
York Times that someone else wrote you
and stay here with me.
I'm calming the Golden Retrievers. I mean
you have to keep passing it. Actually,
that's probably as good a metaphor for
me as any because I would relate to that
being half golden retriever myself
and, and liking dogs. That's great.
And when you say you talk to it
and its golden retriever form,
that's our producer pat Walters.
Like do you actually talk to it? Yeah
I do. I talk.
That's why I have to work alone in a
quiet room because I talk to it all the
time and I ask a questions. I say, what
do you, what is it that you want me?
What does you want me to be doing here?
Because you seem to be resistant to what
I'm trying to do here. Like show me,
give me a clue. Um, like
I uh, the title of eat,
Pray Love was the last thing
that came of that book. And,
and the book was about to be published
in it had any number of ridiculous stupid
titles that I'm going to tell you cause
they're so embarrassing and they're so
not what that book was meant to be titled.
And I ended up writing an email to all
my friends and saying the subject heading
was title search. And I said, my book
won't tell me its name and can I,
can all of you help me? And a friend
of mine wrote back and said, um,
if you're going to talk to it like that,
it's not going to tell you anything.
Um, right. So I really did that night.
I said it back and sweetheart,
listen, I respect you,
I love you. I honor you. I have
defended you these last few years.
I want to bring you into the world,
but you have to tell me your
name and the next day eat,
pray, love.
And you know it.
Because I know the difference between
something I thought of and something that
I was given. I can, I
can tell the difference.
She says sometimes it's the whole
scene. Sometimes it's just a word,
may be a phrase and then you have
the job to make it into something.
Wait it. But if I, if I say
to you two roads diverged,
well two roads diverge. Any yellow water.
So you can write that down. Two
roads diverged in the yellow one,
then you're done. Do you know
how that poem got written?
Two roads.
So he was working for, I may be
exaggerating this cause I tend to,
but I'm going to tell it
my way. How I heard it. Uh,
he was working for months
and months and months on,
on what was going to be the
greatest epic poem of his life.
It was the biggest challenge
that he was taking on.
He was going to be up there
with the masters with this,
I couldn't name the prison we were talking
about. Yes, this would be Mr. Frost.
And, um, and, and, and he worked on it
for, um, you know, forever and ever.
I mean, perspiration, perspiration,
perspiration. Right. And it was 20,
30 pages long and it was, I don't know
what the meter was, whatever it was.
It was the most ambitious
thing he'd ever done.
And it was arduous and it probably had
sweat all over it. Um, put it down,
went to sleep, woke up,
sat down and wrote two,
two roads. And all of a sudden in
one setting, this tiny, perfect,
immaculate thing was created that had
nothing to do with what he had just done.
He earned it.
I think the angels reward people who
are at their desk at six o'clock in the
morning working right. And
he earned it by showing his,
his intent to be a great poet.
And they said, okay, cool.
You showed your intent. That
thing you just wrote was crap.
I'm going to give you this
one. Here's your reward.
So then what evidence do you have
for this of justice? Except for that.
It's a great story.
And I liked the idea and I feel like
I really do feel like when they see me
working, they take pity on
me and they say, you look,
you're showing a real commitment to this.
You've been up at five o'clock every
morning for the last year working on this
novel. I'm just going to give you
the ending, you know, um, or I'm,
I'm going to spare you from that really
bad idea. You just having, you know,
I always think of it as like Henry Ford's
famous line about how creativity is
99% perspiration and 1% inspiration,
which is a very mechanical
way to divide it up.
But it also assumes that those
two things have equal weight,
that they're the same quality.
Right. I agree with 99% perspiration,
1% inspiration, but
it's 99% oyster 1% Pearl
[inaudible]
you can't even compare the,
the matter like it's a
bargain to get 1% inspiration.
You know, it's, it's a miracle.
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
I could get with the muses
sort of. What do you mean?
Well,
I think it's interesting that you can
hear it at one point she says that she
believes actually kind of believe
in, and another point she says,
it just makes a good story.
That's a great story.
And I like the idea so you can hear
her negotiating with the idea. Yeah.
Gosh, she's a little bit between the two
thoughts, which is interesting. I mean,
you know, you know,
a serious neuroscientists would tell you
that it's all in your unconscious and
it's all you. All the time. But
another way to think of it is, uh,
is to say that you got a gift and,
and therefore it's not
all about you would,
it's bad and it's still about you when
it's good, but it's not all about you.
It's just this business of all. Okay,
this is a form of well
organized and modesty.
It's a nice phrase. I'm just going
to, just going to go with that. Yay.
It's time for us in our
ferries to go to break.
No.