You are listening to radio lab radio
from W N y.
S. T. E. N. P. R. Hey, I'm Jad
Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich, Radiolab.
The podcasts podcast.
Will we should just say as a sort
of set the set the ground here,
set the ground, does that
table table, whatever, uh,
that we are on the cusp of delivering
five really fantastic shows right now.
So we're busy, busy, busy, very busy.
Which got us thinking about a
conversation that I had a few years ago,
which was conveniently, they're
waiting with Malcolm Gladwell,
the author of outliers and blink.
I was over at the 92nd street
y in New York City. Okay.
Just pull it to your mouth there.
The subject was how do you explain people
of really unusual, exceptional talent?
Like why are they so good here? What
is the nature of being exceptional?
Is this, you know, working hard or
need ability? Is it an accident?
And as we all know in America,
there's a real hunt on from a very early
age to find the gifted and talented
children.
And we have programs in our schools
all over the country trying to identify
exceptional kids. Malcolm Gladwell
hates gifted and talented program.
Yeah, it's ridiculous. Why do you decide,
so a gifted program says that we identify
a child and call that child gifted
because of their performance at the age
of whatever, nine or 10 or 11 years old.
Why do we care?
Particularly how well a child performs
at nine or 10 or 11 years old,
they're nine or 10 or 11 there are
good 25 years to making any kind of
substantial contribution to the world.
Why don't we wait? What's the hurry?
And also how do you
know? So like you know,
so one child learns to
read it for one child,
learns to read it, two and a half.
Right. So what, why does it matter?
Are the things that are being read
between two and a half and four of such
incalculable?
No, no, no. [inaudible] normal
parents response to, Oh,
if he's reading it two and a half,
think of the things he'll do.
And it's just an extrapolation
like reading is reading. Once
you can read, we're done. I mean,
it's not like there's an,
there's an infinite scale and so-and-so
reads better and better and better.
And I can say,
we can say today of Gladwell that he
reads so much better than Krulwich.
And that this is like what separates the
two of us. It's speeding. I mean like,
well there is also among your, you
use the phrase the Matthew effect.
What does that Matthew fact is?
I'm a phrase coined by Robert K Merton,
the great genius sociologist of Columbia.
He's the guy who says in the verse in
Matthew which says that I'm to him who has
much more will be given. Um, and he
uses this to describe the Matthew FAQ,
which is this notion that a
small initial advantage, um,
difference in a small initial difference
in the performance of any two people
will inevitably grow.
Because the person who is a little bit
ahead will get so many more advantages
that they will end up being
far ahead. So a good example,
there's all kinds of great Matthew
effects. So if you're born,
if you're a young boy
born in October, November,
or December,
who has designs on being a professional
soccer or hockey player, um,
the deck is stacked against you. There's
not much you can do. You, you, um,
you should probably give out
but not, but here's why we
don't. Why exactly. Well,
it's really an accident of birth thing.
The month you were born in Malcolm,
things might make a huge, huge
difference in their life here.
Here's his way of describing this.
I'm going to read here a
passage from his book outliers.
On page 23 of your book. You do a
play by play and every way to do this,
we're at the Memorial Cup
hockey championship and I
want to read what you wrote.
March 11 starts around one
side of the Tigers Net,
leaving the puck for his team. May
January 4th, he passes it to January 22,
flips it back to March 12th who shoots
point blank at the Tigers goalie.
April 27th,
April 27th blocks to shot reed mounted
by Vancouver's march 60 shoots medicine
half defenseman, February 9th and
February 14th dive to block the puck.
January 10th looks on
helplessly March 6th scores.
Question is why did you choose
this peculiar kind of nomenclature?
Because I wanted to make this point that
all an extraordinary number of hockey
players, um,
and are born in the first three
or four months of the year.
17 of the 25 players on the medicine
hat team were born in those first few
months. Why? Because, uh, uh,
the eligibility cutoff date for four age
class hockey in Canada in the world is
January 1st and we start recruiting
allstar squads in hockey and Canada when
peep kids are nine and 10 years old. But
of course when you're nine years old,
the best one is the oldest one, right?
So all you do is you choose the kids who
are born closest to the cutoff date and
then you give them special coaching and
put them on all star squads until nine
and extra games and extra practice
until eight and nine years later.
They really are the best. And by the way,
we see exactly the same effects in
school systems, right? The kid, the,
the, the relatively youngest
kids in the class, um,
a underperformed the
relatively oldest, um, uh,
kids and that underperformance
last into the college years,
the kid born, the youngest
kid born the last, you know,
three months of the youngest,
three months of their age cohort
in school or something like,
I forget the exact number,
nine or 10% less likely to go to
college than those born in the are the,
in the three oldest months and
we can fix it really easily.
You've got three classes in
an elementary school, right?
Typical elementary schools go up,
divide them up by birthday, right?
Doesn't that mean though
that that you have get,
you had to like a half dozen soccer
moms to work out the logistical problems
because you've now got four leads?
We used to have one and someone has to
be in the Seward park on Mondays and
Wednesdays, but who's going to be inserted
fucking Thursdays and Fridays. Okay.
So you would just for the sake of
efficiency, you'd know, I was very happy.
I was shocked. I was to know two thirds
of them. Know what I'm saying? No,
but your, this is exactly why
I brought this up with, um,
I had a conversation with this hockey
guy in Canada. Big Deal hockey.
Mocker I dunno whether they call them
markers. You can go and Matthews here,
but absolutely. And I say to him, look,
you're Canada, you want to be the
best hockey country in the world.
Why don't you have the three
parallel leaks? How hard is that?
Every single town in Canada has
like 25 different hockey teams.
Just divide them up. How hard is this?
He, he's like, oh, it's too difficult.
Well, let me make it, let me give
you a harder one because cause uh,
just another success puzzle from the
book. This is off to set up for you.
It's um, it's about the Janklow
family. So there's two gang close.
We're gonna talk about more and Mort,
but since those are names are socially,
we caught one daddy Janklow
and one Sonny Genco. Yeah.
So daddy goes to Brooklyn law school
class in 1919 sets up a practice in
Brooklyn, elegant fellow dresses in
a Homburg Bruce brother's clothes,
drives a big car and we was the queens,
married the right girl, worked hard,
hard, hard, hard sets of the
business, goes nowhere. The
Sun Baby Janklow when 30 years
later it gets a law degree,
marries nicely to works hard to
put together a cable franchise,
sells it to Cox Broadcasting, makes
a fortune, creates a literary agency.
Janklow and Nesbitt signs you
now he lives on Park Avenue.
He has an Anselm Kiefer painting on
his own airplane. So the question is,
is the son succeeds? The
father fails. Why is this
that definitely that part. The
book I'm really interested in, um,
generational effects, uh,
the worst year to be born in the
20th century is you can all kinds of
sociologists figure these things out.
It's between 1900 and 1907 or maybe at
1,919 10 that decade because you get out
of college and the, just as you're
getting going to depression hits, yeah,
you have nine years of depression.
And just as you're emerging out the
depression, trying to make a go of it,
you're shipped off to
war for six years. Right?
And so by the time you come back,
I want to start your business.
You're in your late forties
right? So it's really,
really hard for where is the best
year to be born in the 20th century.
If you live in, grew up in New York
City, actually I think anywhere,
but particularly in New York City is
1935 because it's perfect because you,
it's the smallest birth
year of the 20th century.
You always want to be part of a really
small birth cohort because no one's
competing with you. Right? Think about it.
So the difference between being a part
of the smallest postcard and the largest
one, the differences between
the smallest one is enormous.
It's like per capita twice as
many babies are born in, you know,
1920 is 1935 so if you're a nursing 35
there's this huge generation before you.
So what do they do for that
generation? They build big, huge,
shiny schools and hire tons of teachers.
Right? Then there's no more kids.
So you sail in and all of a sudden your
older brother had 35 kids in this class,
you have 18 your older brother competed
against a zillion people to get into
city college. You competed against no
one you wanted to join the debate team.
No one went out for the debate team.
You are captain of the base team.
Like I always, you know it's funny,
you always talk to people well in this
forum itch small cohorts and they always
think you're talking to
some guy accomplished old
guy, grew up in the Bronx,
white hair and he'll tell you about his
extraordinary high school experiences.
And so you know, I was captain of
the basketball team and you look at,
this guy is five foot two
and you say to yourself,
this is a man who belonged
to a small generation, right?
Nobody was going out for
basketball. So these guys,
they haven't made in the shade and
then they come into the workforce. No,
they go to a Harvard law school. Of course
they go to Harvard law school, right?
No one's applying to Harvard law school.
And they get out in the workforce,
do they get a job? Of course they do.
Everyone's desperate for work
because there's no one out there.
And then what's behind them? The
biggest generation of 20th century.
So they sail in the positions of authority
and they have in front of them this
enormous market to serve,
right? It's just genius.
You can even go more specifically,
this is great thing that happens.
Great in quotation marks in New
York City, in the depression,
which is that a whole bunch
of very, very, very able,
people can't get jobs
in the private sector.
There are no jobs in private sectors. So
what do they do? They become teachers,
right?
And you talked to this generation born
in 35 about their high school experience.
And I lost count and the number of people
of that generation who went to public
schools in New York who
told me, for example,
that their math teacher had a phd in math.
And so here's the generation who not
only could they be kept on the basketball
team, but their teachers were these
extraordinary people who you know, were,
um, by virtue of a lack of opportunity
ended up in the public school system.
So is that the difference then
between Janklow Dan and Genco son?
That is just the beginning of the
explanation. I mean, I never met Jankel.
I mean, you can only go so far with this,
but it helps you to sort of set
the stage to understand his shoe.
You've got these two very capable people,
one of whom achieved extraordinary
success and one didn't. And you,
I think you have to go beyond the
individual to make sense of them, right?
I mean,
so there is such a thing as getting an
accidental boost and I mean, you know,
nobody chooses when they're going to be
born. It's always mom and dad's fault,
but there's something even bigger and
even more important than good luck with
your birthday. And you illustrate this.
Malcolm cites the example of bill gates,
he so-called genius behind Microsoft.
When you say so-called, you'll see
here's the luckiest guy in the world.
And he's the first to tell
you that, um, he goes to, uh,
he shows up for eighth grade in
1968 or nine at a lakeside academy.
And for reasons no one can remember,
somebody on the parent's committee bought
a computer for the kids and a little
teletype hooked into the main
mainframe in downtown Seattle.
And Gates has essentially now what
that allows you is to do realtime
programming. Everyone, everyone's
programmed with cards back then, right?
Which is incredibly
laborious, time consuming.
And you don't really learn at a
program cause it just takes too long.
He can do real time programming the way
we program now on this little teletype.
And he does that starting in 1968
basically for his entire teenage life.
Um, and you mean that almost
literally. Yeah. You tell him,
he told me this one story about,
he then goes to these whole series
of things of finding other computers.
And at one point, Paul Allen is
Pat's paid at this school, um,
discovers that there's a mainframe that's
free at the University of Washington
Medical Center between,
it's free between two and six
in the morning on weeknights,
and he's now 15 years old.
And so he sets his alarm for one 30 in
the morning and he crawls out the window,
right?
Because someone's parents know at two
in the morning walks two miles to the
arrest of Washington programs from two
til six walks home and goes back to bed.
And his mom, upon discovering
this years later says,
I was wondering why it was so hard
to get bill up in the morning. Um,
so the question is, he's
clearly a brilliant guy.
No one's taking that away from him,
but he has this other thing which he,
by the way, what's really
remarkable about that,
but the story to me is
when he does that, he's 15.
So he's a teenage boy. And then all of
us here know about teenage boys, right?
Or what did he need to do? I want to do
what is the tangible I want to do? Well,
what does one of the things that
teenage boy wants to do? Sleep right?
Here's a kid, here's a teenage boy who
was willing to surrender his sleep,
you know, five nights a week to
program from two, six in the morning.
That is what's special about Bill Gates.
And it accumulates,
right? It gets, it's out.
It's three hours or four hours a day and
then five hours a day whenever you can
make it six hours a day. It's for
years and years and years until he,
a lot of hours. Yeah. Uh,
and Mozart I guess play the piano for
lawful hours and tiger woods just plays
out. People are all examples of
what's called the 10,000 hour rule,
which is this notion that, um,
Scott of brilliant kind of Ericsson a
psychologist has kind of formulated this
principle that if you look at any kind
of cognitively complex discipline,
it seems almost without exception,
that in order to be good,
you must practice at least 10,000
hours. What sort of surprised me?
You put the Beatles on this list. Why
are the Beatles? Because they go to, um,
Humberg, uh, before they
come to America as teenagers,
they go to Hamburg and they play a,
they're the house band in a strip
club and they play eight hour sets,
seven days a week for months at a
stretch. I mean, it's incredible. I mean,
you know,
paranthetically one cannot imagine a
more dismal experience than playing first
of all, playing in a strip club. Secondly,
playing at a strip club in Hamburg and
30 playing in a strip club in Hamburg in
the 50s. I mean, can you
imagine? It's just again,
so they learned in those hours and
hours and hours of playing every night.
They learned just to play and play and
play and play whatever. And somehow,
because I mean there is in
the book you're arguing,
I think that, I mean you
could say by the way,
that the rolling stones I don't
think went to Han Borg and uh,
there probably were other Liverpool bands
that did go to Hamburg and played in
the same strip clubs and you do not
know their names. I don't know how you,
it's a, isn't necessarily not
sufficient as sufficient on a, sorry,
I forget which way it goes, but whatever
way it goes, if that is that okay.
But now,
so what we got here then is you have
this talent plus the persistence versus
this Matthew effect that
is the Matthew effect.
You start out with these little accidental
differences and then coaches and
situations magnify them so they get
bigger and bigger. But with persistence,
what seems to be happening here is the
accidental differences that that may have
given you. Advantages get narrowed when
you add the practice and the practice.
Add the practice. Mozart at 13, you know,
copying other people's work. Practice,
practice, practice, practice,
Mozart 17 better. Mozart
2124. Oh my God. All right,
so, um, Lennon and
McCartney at 15, 16, 17.
But when they make their jumps,
they make leaps of a genius.
Nature leaves that are not available
to other people. Isaac Newton,
he goes home for vacation, thinks
about, oh, how am I gonna measure this?
He invented calculus.
So you are being accused of
being a genius denier. Yes.
Are you a genius denier or are
you simply a genius disliked her?
Um, well, so, uh, this career,
this thing called talent,
right? Great. Um, and it's this,
it's this, it's the, it's the,
it's the magic dust, right?
That gets sprinkled onto persistence.
It turns a lot of hard work into
something great. Um, and the question is,
how larger role does it play
and what does it consist of?
Municipal piece, I wrote
years ago for the New Yorker,
I remember writing about Wayne Gretzky
and reading a biography of Wayne Gretzky
and he's a keys as an educated
hockey player, great hockey player,
greatest hockey player of all time
as a kid when he's two years old,
his parents would sit up in front of
the television, he would watch, um,
uh, hockey games on, on Saturday nights.
And when the game he would
burst into tears, right?
And it was this little glimpse into his
future greatness because here he was at
two and he loved this, that he was,
he could imply hockey's too. I mean,
you can barely walk, but
he already is understood.
He loves this thing so much that for
it to end is an unconscionable burden.
Right. And it just, it's like the world
is ending and he's, he's just consulate.
So what is Wayne Gretzky's talent? Well,
part of it is his extraordinary,
you know, uh, vision,
his coordination, his,
whatever, his, this,
but a lot of it is this guy loves this
game so much that he would do nothing but
do it and think about it and engage
it and do all those things. Now,
if is this magic dust called
talent, is that all it is?
Maybe. I don't think fun is that,
I don't think that's a, that's um,
denying or hating genius. No,
I think that that definition
of genius is far more, um,
appealing to me. Then the
notion that it's this,
it's simply some sky high IQ or some,
well this is the genius, which just won't
quit and you can't eat, it won't quit.
You sort of like break the movie, but
the two guys on the mountain, I mean,
I'm recasting it sort of like what
I just broke back, break
back, you know, I go put you.
So it's the love of hockey.
Yeah.
That will not speak its name. That
they're not taking his name. Yes.
I suppose that's it. I'm not a, a good
analogy that would have occurred to me.
Maybe a what?
One of the things that I detect is that
it's not that you don't like geniuses is
that maybe you don't think we need
them and maybe ought to be for money.
Okay. Your watching.
Why are people so hostile to the notion
that what genius is is an extraordinary
love for a particular, um, thing.
Why is the love so we look,
we're, we're, you know,
we hear the ability, definition of genius,
the rare ability definition and we
think, oh, that's so plausible. Totally.
That's what it is. But then we hear the,
the extraordinary love definition of
genius and we say he's a genius denier.
Why? Why is,
why are we so hostile to the notion that
what separates the genius and the rest
of us is the genius loves what
he or she does more than we do.
But we have no problem at all.
But what separates the genius is
that they have some, you know,
well, because it misses the point. I mean,
there are YPO like Paul McCartney
and you hostile, the notion of love,
Robert, is that what that is?
No, I just want to make an
obvious point here that you know,
Harry Smith, no, that's a real person. Uh,
Harry x could love, uh, um,
my writing songs, but Paul McCarthy
for the way you say love though,
is so you really have, you,
have you thought about this to
others?
Yes.
Your Harry x could love, yeah,
that's better writing songs.
[inaudible] loves writing songs
so much that he can't stop,
but for lunch and dinner and
sometimes not even those,
but next door is, um,
is a Richard Rogers little
be tree. Ricky Rogers.
He loves writing songs too.
But for some reason Harry reits loves
writing Ricky whites and love writing and
how he writes a, a memorable song called
the babbling book. Those two in flow.
And Richard Wright's
Shannon chanted evening.
Well, no. So, um, your,
there's a difference there.
No, well, hold on, hold on.
No love doesn't get you. No, no,
no. The love, but the love does.
So think about this. Love is not the
complete explanation. Love is the way in,
because Wayne Gretzky
loves hockey so much.
He thinks about it all the
time and does more than that.
He engages the sport in a way that
no one else had ever engaged in.
So there's this wonderful, um, that,
remember in I running a fresco,
this is thing that he
famously did ones where he um,
scored a goal from behind the net and
he flips the puck over the net like,
and it kind of does a little
thing and goes in. Um,
and the reason no one had ever done that
before was not just that no one could
do it. Lots of good do it. It had
never occurred to anyone else before.
No one had engaged the
sport on that level.
So why is Gretzky engaging in that way?
Why is he thinking about it
that deeply and creatively?
Because he can't get hockey
out of his head. Right.
Whenever I encounter someone like that,
I cannot get past that sense.
They give off that they have.
They have,
they have found their calling that they
are in actively in love and almost in a
romantic way with this
thing that they do. Right.
Absent that you can't be
a genius. I'm sorry Ken,
are you convinced yet? Hi.
Still holding up for some really abstract
Nietzschean notion of,
no, I'm going to pull back
for a minute here. Oh,
we remodeled a little bit longer,
but I think they come to shove.
Oh Malcolm. That's what I say. I say go
Malcolm right there. Hello. You know,
I would say he might be shortchanging
the idea that there's a diversity of
ability out there. Innate talent. Yeah.
But I do agree with him though
that the idea of genius,
that old 19th century
stupid idea, uh, you know,
the eye does contain within it
are a really dangerous thought,
which is that our abilities are just
sort of God given. And so they're fixed.
So nobody but so, but his
argument would be, you know,
you need some talent and you need
certainly a little bit of good luck,
but what you really need is this
strange love of the thing you're doing.
And it's the love or the determination
to succeed. If what? Love equals,
it makes you just want to do it and then
do it, and then do it some more. Amen.
Yeah. We should thank the 92nd street
y and then get the hell out of here.
It's them and you to Malcolm
Gladwell and to you for listening.
I'm Jad Abumrad [inaudible] all
new episode in two weeks. See them.