You are listening to radio
lab radio from w n y.
S. E. Yup. Hey,
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm
Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
Today we have the story of just how hard
it can be to be who you actually are,
what it seems like the entire world
is doing its best to make you who you
actually aren't. I guess I could, I mean
this could be too many details, but um,
story starts for us. We
had reporter David Conrad.
So for me it was back in late 2014 I
was living in Philadelphia as a Grad
student and at the time David was applying
for jobs and one of the jobs he was
applying for was at a radio show that
was doing a series about international
women's issues. And so I,
I had this on my mind and I was taking
a bus to the university and I just
overheard somebody talking about
their recent trip to Venice.
And of course the classic tourist thing
to do when you go to Venice is to take a
ride on the canal boats, the
gondolas, you know, go down the canal.
Maybe someone sinks to the famous song.
Awesome.
It's very romantic on any case.
The person sitting on the bus next to
David was telling their friend that they
had taken a Gondola ride with this
first ever woman Gondola in Venice.
Yeah. And then we were like poking
around and we realized like how,
how did this become a, we know.
Who are you? I'm, I'm Kristen.
Kristen Clark, also a
journalist and radio producer.
[inaudible] and she and David are
partners and collaborators. I mean,
and this is what was interesting is like
we realize like how big a deal it is to
be a female gondolier this is like,
it's like a 900 year old tradition.
900 years. Yeah. All men. All men.
And it's always past father, son,
father, son, father, son, or like uncle
nephew down the line. So this is like a,
this has been
no ladies now, no ladies then no
ladies ever. No ladies isn't 900 years.
Yeah. Just think about that for a second.
Almost a thousand years of all men,
men, men, men, men, men. And then
one day you get a woman, right?
As a headline woman breaks through
900 year old glass ceiling.
I thought that sounds like a
good pitch and you're kidding.
It sounds like God kissed you on the
line. Yeah, exactly. It's under the,
it's under the like the perfect
empowerment story I guess. Yeah.
And so we're kind of just like googling
it and like it's all over the media.
It seems like every outlet from the
Guardian to The New York Times to the
Financial Times to the
Cedar Rapids Gazette.
[inaudible] made it all the way to cedar
rapids to newspapers in Germany and
China and Australia and they all,
all the articles laid
out the same basic story.
It was this Algerian woman from Germany
named Alex Hae showed up in Venice 20
years ago,
got around a gondoliers association that
never wanted to see a woman become a
gondolier and eventually became the
first ever female gondolier Venice,
the whole thing of course,
sparking this giant gender war.
But that was sort of it pretty much the
headline and the picture was the story.
Many of the articles didn't actually
have all that many quotes from Alex.
And so for me it sounded like a great
simple opportunity to go back and tell a
deeper story. Yeah.
Just like who is this person? Why?
Why would somebody be so hell bent on
getting into this club that just so
clearly does not want them.
Yeah. So we, we emailed Alex
just we're, we're
interested in your story.
We're wondering if you might be willing
to spend a few days with us this summer.
And I was hoping it
would just be like, yes,
I'm happy to meet with you for a couple
of hours and that would have been great.
But we got an email back right away
that said, if you come do the story,
you have to spend a week with me.
Yeah.
And then there are all these questions
about like who we were as journalists,
what our purpose was, and a bunch of
demands. You have to stay in the city.
You can't stay in like one of
the suburbs and Margherita,
even though it's cheaper, like
you have to be in the city.
I want you to hear these sounds at
this time. I have a vision for things.
It's a little odd. Yeah. And I
mean the message was definitely,
I want to tell a different story. Right.
Did you have any idea what
that meant? No, I didn't,
but we had that echo way. I
had that echo into my head.
So we flew to the Venice airport. Uh,
took a bus to city center really fast,
stepped off the bus and you could
smell the salt in the air from um,
from the grand canal and it was
kind of raining a little bit.
It was around midnight.
We're kind of getting our
bearings, grabbing our bags and we,
we look up and across the parking lot
there's Alex standing under a lamppost
just leaning against it with a cigarette
smoke kind of curling up into
the light of the street lamp,
short hair dark. It was
flipped back. Do you think
you were in a Fellini movie?
Really? I didn't know what to think.
This person was legit under a lamp.
Smoking
travel. So quick up close.
Alex look taller than I expected.
The strong belt, kind of a,
a face that was a little weathered,
like someone who works outside all day.
On the water finishing quite late.
So when you call it a just finished.
Perfect. How was your flight?
It was long. It was, you know,
we flew to Moscow first,
which is, since it was late,
we made a plan with Alex to meet up at
5:45 PM the next day on the steps of left
in each Shea Opera House.
Okay. Beautiful. For House. Yeah.
I was rushing all to find you.
So I left all the mess in the nucleus.
So anyway, the plan was to
go out on a Gondola ride,
which was one of Alex's
demands in that first email.
So we walked around the corner to where
they'd gone to Lewis Parked and oh my
God. The boat was just like shining.
So the Gonio was made for three
people's lawn, narrow jet black.
This was where the Nobel couples
sitting, Auntie cushions, golden trim,
and over there then what
was the seventh city?
Alex had had it about 12 years already.
Quite an old board when I got it.
And I had a name. This is called
pick us up, like I guess this.
And you choose it. Yes, yes.
Yeah, of course. All right, so
he wanted to come in. So
we climb into the boat.
Perfect angle there,
and Alex stands at the back holding
the or and we're down sitting in the,
in the lower seats. Kind of just like
pointing the microphone up. Alex,
I know you were just telling
us how annoying it is when
people snap pictures is
okay if I take photographs and
every once in a while, no. Okay.
You came here to study at first. No,
that's not what I said and it was pretty
much immediately clear that you came
here. I mean
that it was not going
to be an easy interview.
You came in a study when
you study. I know, I know,
but I was wondering the ruling, right.
You got to do a lot of practice. Yeah.
We had a notebook full of questions and
things that we had pulled from all these
articles we'd read. That
pretty quickly became useless.
That's what I was asking
you is, is you didn't come.
And whenever I asked about being the
first female gondolier and there were the
first woman in 900 years to
do this. Oh, it's a Lodestar.
Who that [inaudible] read that everywhere
and then let them in so little such an
over and over and over.
No, it was all set already.
Why would we need to repeat
things? We've already done.
This is very frequent journalism problem.
Like you become boring to the
person you're interviewing. Right?
You start flailing. Exactly.
And rework. We were like, uh,
you don't have anything. Why are we here?
How, what do you do? You know, we
just thought maybe we should just be
quiet. Probably.
We are about to make the Titus.
I haven't received 35
we moved away from the tourist centers
of the city and into these smaller
canals.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
As we'd go around these tight turns. Yeah.
Hello.
Alex would sing out to let the other
boats know that we were coming.
So here we have a cross and this is why
I showed out my direction in order to
avoid accidents because you
cannot hear the gun arriving,
you know, we'd go into
these beautiful archways
whoa.
Past Hidden Gardens.
You don't necessarily need eyes in order
to appreciate the Gondola tour in every
channel as a defense song. Any, some
Jones, you have a lot of birds singing.
Does it fly any faces?
So this is a beautiful entrance,
you know, to, to show you
at one point I'd gone to look cut
through this rectangle of light
shining from an open kitchen door.
[inaudible]
it was nice. I mean this side of Venice
was unexpected and really beautiful.
But the whole time we were
sitting on our notepads in, uh,
we were definitely quietly panicking.
Well, you know, there, you know,
I didn't know this at the time,
but I thought the some, you know, I was
like, hmm, maybe a little too young.
And I think
Alex was testing us
and maybe a little bit too, oh yeah,
we don't have enough experience.
Maybe that was my concern,
but I liked the A,
I liked the enthusiasm
and I liked the, uh,
uh, there was an honesty, which I liked.
Did you ever figure out
what you were being, um,
sussed out for or what was going on
there? No, for sure. Not on the boat,
but we,
we actually made plans to go out to
dinner that night and considering how the
boat ride went,
we thought at this point we should return
to square one and leave the recorder
at home. Um, and just try and
have a conversation anyway.
We sit down outside and very few people
are in the restaurant where we're the
only table outside. They had to open
when we all, when we got there too,
we should say we met um, Alex's
girlfriend, right? Yeah. And we're making,
I think we're just kind of making
small talk and yeah, it turns out,
turns out Alex's girlfriend
is a photographer and she
done this photo essay of
Alex
and the photos are really
striking. Like one of them,
Alex is just like drowning
under the water. Um,
there's one that's just like
Alex's back is to the camera.
This ripped and muscular
back. Yeah. Like arms splayed,
like looking out the window over the
city of Venice. Venice as lone defender.
Yeah, just like so bad ass and like
kind of like superhero style. Yeah.
So we were just chatting about the
photos and asking Alex girlfriend, like,
you know,
tell me a little bit more about what
inspired you to take these photos and you
know, like small talk friendly stuff.
And she kind of was like, you know,
it was just, it's so strange,
you know, we thought,
we thought it was so clear.
We like the photos were so like they
emphasized every masculine quality on
Alex's body. Um, we, you know,
in our artists statement,
you know, we used all of the male
forms in Italian, you know, like Louis,
which means he instead
of lay, which means she,
but everybody at the photo
exhibit was like, Oh,
must have been a Typo or you
made a mistake. And she was like,
which is funny because I'm Italian,
so I should know. And I was like,
oh, pronouns, pronouns
Louie. He, Alex, she used,
he, he, Alex is a, he is Alex Trans, like,
oh my gosh, Alex is a transgender man.
Wow. What did you, what does
that mean to you in that moment?
What I thought that meant, um,
was Alex was probably born in a
body that he didn't identify with.
Yeah. I mean mine was, I didn't
think transgender. I didn't think,
I thought Alex is a guy. Of course
Alex is a guy. Really? Yeah.
I wasn't surprised. Were you surprised?
I wasn't that super, I mean I wasn't,
I'm not saying that the, the
pronounce it is accurate.
I would say that like flipping
into he not a thing like,
like it was like Alex is,
Alex is a he, Alex is, he,
he is sitting at the table with us. Alex
and his girlfriend come very quickly.
It was like him.
I'm looking at him and then I start
thinking about the story that we had come
here to tell. Um,
that was about all of the women things
that she had done. Her, her, her,
her woman hero, heroine,
first female in 900 years,
international symbol of female power.
You start thinking about
that and it's like,
um,
those things are really
hard to square in your head.
This real person is also these stories.
And how did that happen?
What has it been like for 20 years to
be inside of that story when you're
actually a man
[inaudible]
after who knows how many articles
have been written about Alex?
This is the first time that he is
publicly telling his story as a man,
and so we should probably just stop for
a second and talk about pronouns because
this is really important
for many transgender people
in moments when Alex was
publicly understood as a woman and was
getting international press for it,
we've decided with Alex's permission to
only use his name or his title of First
Female Gondolier.
While some of the people interviewed
for this story were unaware that Alex is
transgender and do use female pronouns
or do refer to him as a woman. We,
when we're talking about him,
we will only use male pronouns.
So after that dinner, we
made plans for the next day
on his motorboat and he would just take
us to a quiet spot and we would talk,
what's the agreement on the
water on the water? Shut up.
Stop it. [inaudible]
hello? Okay. He speaks
a lot of false starts.
Oh, well, I don't know. Maybe
I can ask it. Has anybody,
has anyone ever asked you what
Gender Pronoun you prefer?
Nope. Never. Never had ever.
So after getting some of the
basics out of the way, you know,
Alex kind of started
at the beginning. Okay.
Well, you know, it's a long
story. I was born transgender.
This is in Germany. Alex tells us
he was born with a female body,
but at a pretty early age. Knew
himself to be a little boy.
I knew already before I went to school
with three years I was standing on the
toilet to pee inside Alex is that,
you know, for him, he, you know,
he had the sense even when he was three
that there should just be something on
his body that wasn't
there. Yeah, yeah. No,
I was praying for a penis every night. My,
my parents knew about it.
His parents were actually both
doctors [inaudible] but they,
they were not supportive.
[inaudible],
you know, I, I heard them, you know,
they were talking about
all the weird stuff I did,
how you'd ripped the arms off of his
barbies, cutting them like, you know,
it was a black pencil
and like destroying them.
And where the way Alex dressed himself
when there was a swimming lesson in the
school,
I was there only with little tents or
you'd call them the bet based suit for
four boys. And you know, I was of course,
very aggressive as a child, a lot of
fights. You know, I got quiet. Uh,
I was quite a violent as a kid.
So now I can off about this. But,
you know, it, it, it was a
drama at home. It was a drama,
the constant, uh,
try of my mother to, uh,
get this behavior out of me.
Alex has pretty early on.
His parents basically gave up on him.
They ignored me as much as they could,
which was, you know,
in a way it was saving me because
I could wear whatever I wanted.
I could do whatever I wanted.
And then when Alex was 10,
a little brother was born and
that was a huge shock.
That was a terrible shock because, um,
basically it confirmed that my
mother wanted desperately at boy,
but she didn't accept me as her son.
That's what it, Alex said. Basically,
you know, that was the
first time he saw what like,
like it should look like basically
when a parent loves their kid.
So, um, when he was 15
[inaudible]
he ran away from home.
I escaped one handbook.
And in handbook you have a huge, um,
district called some Poli where they
have all the prostitutes and you know,
all the bad sings. And
that's exactly where I went.
Some people kind of took him
under their wing, um, got a job,
kinda figured out how to take
care of himself. I got lucky,
but I know also very unlucky
these stories. But I got lucky.
Did he ever think about like
transitioning to a male body?
He says he thought about it at one
point, but in the 80s, when I was 15,
the opportunities you're fair to
become. A men were very, very, um,
poor in particular. If you wanted
to go down the road of surgery,
what I can remember for my family was
constant talks about how operations went
wrong, how they went
wrong and what went wrong.
And so for me to go into
hospital to do an operation,
this is not going to
happen. And of course,
many transgender people don't end
up having surgery. But anyway,
after Homburg at some point,
Alex fell into filmmaking and ended
up in San Francisco working in,
in the film industry. And so 1986,
he got involved in a production that
sent him abroad to go scope out locations
for a film that was going
to be shot in Venice.
Yeah.
So shows up in Venice in 1886, 29,
I think. Oh, she's older.
He's not a kid at this point.
Originally he's just
supposed to say a few days,
kind of just enough time to do
some research and scope things out.
But somewhere along the way,
he sees these guys rowing their
boats down the canal and uh,
for reasons he can't entirely explain,
he's just transferred,
fixed,
fascinated by this kind of bought.
And I was fascinated by the rowing style
that you'll go forward so you actually
see where you're going.
So it was just a fascinated and I
just wanted to try it out myself.
Eventually. Um, Alex ends up actually
meeting a gondolier and asks like,
do you think I could do this?
And I actually ended up down at the
Gondola station as an apprentice.
Um, did they ask you, did they
ask you why you wanted to study?
I remember the first day I was
introduced by the head boss of the group.
Okay. So this is Alex.
She's going to be all mascot because
they saw Alex as a woman and there had
never been a woman
gondolier most of them. So
for sure this was like a kind of a joke.
There was a very old man
who will do the latest set.
Now we have gone to Leah with tits
for the first seven months.
Alex says he basically just
picked up after the guys.
You were the bus boy for everybody.
So you needed to clean the boats and to
ship out the water like 10 20 times a
day. He says, it's really backbreaking,
grueling work for somebody that
everybody, everybody sees as a woman,
you think this would be like the
worst place on earth. But you know,
actually those first, those
first months in the city,
just kind of with the boys dirty
jokes. I thought this is great.
[inaudible]
Alex knew all the gondoliers nicknames,
walked and talked and acted like them
and cursed in the same way and he says he
felt like he was part of
this tradition of, you know,
learning from these old guys
who work mentors to him.
I was really like maybe the
best time of my, my life
[inaudible]
it was, it was like he was home
and then the, the travel began
[inaudible]
it started with the
journalist. Yeah. Is that
[inaudible] or those reporter Consuelo
Turin. We met in a noisy cafe,
so you know,
started in 99 to six with a translator
when consoler was a collaborator.
Often will have the names. Yeah.
She was a cub reporter in Venice working
for a very politically progressive
newspaper and she was out looking for
her big story and she runs into our,
how do they encounter each other?
[inaudible] Alex a Consuelo saw Alex at
one of the gondolier stations and she
was like, Whoa,
this obviously this has
struck her attention and
[inaudible] it looked to her like there
was this woman rowing among men and like
the seeming kind of
blend right in the night.
[inaudible] was attracted by this
vision, unusual vision for Dennis,
so she observed her [inaudible].
I camped out for like a whole morning
and basically just watched Alex's
behavior. Hey, ultra
Couto the [inaudible].
Alex didn't want to talk, told
him I can't talk about it.
Told her basically I'm just a
student. They're teaching me.
Don't make this into a thing like
get, I mean they see [inaudible].
Consuelo said, listen, I recognize
that you don't want to talk to me,
that you're apprehensive and that this
might be difficult for you to go with
that.
And I get that this might even damage
your reputation with the other gondoliers
but needed around the importance.
This is an important story.
The way to the [inaudible], you're
a pioneer. I can't ignore you.
And so Consuela said
there are two options.
I'm going to write the
story no matter what.
So you can either talk to me and
we can do the story together or
I can write what I think
that we'll see. Alpha, you know,
I said it can't go out now.
And she said it will, it will.
And why wasn't Consuelo
persuaded that she should wait?
Well there were journalists coming
from all over the place. You know,
I think the story was going to get out
there and somebody was going to write it
and Alex never sort of stopped and
was like, listen Consuelo or whoever,
let me just tell you the real story.
The way out of this is to
speak and yet he stays quiet.
Do you have a sense of why? I mean,
so just to kind of give like some like
data points that might be helpful and
understanding kind of where
we were. So we're talking 1997
just to give you like a corollary thing
where we were in our discourse around
LGBT issues was like Ellen degenerates,
I think that year, this is,
this is so hard. But I
came out on her show.
I think I've realized that I am,
I can't even say the word,
why can't I say the word?
And like shortly after it was canceled,
Caitlyn Jenner was just a few years ago.
Like we didn't even really have
a grip on what transgender was.
That wasn't a conversation
that we were having in public.
Can you imagine what it would be
like to be like guys, guys, guys,
don't worry though.
I'm actually a man that wouldn't have
gone over so well with the dudes at the
Gondola station. Yeah.
So what ended up happening after
Consuelo and Alex had this,
had the show down about the article.
Well, a couple of days later,
Alex was on the way to
the Gondola station.
I found it in the newspaper
Shop, the headline
[inaudible]
we're not done. No speed.
[inaudible] a woman is challenging
the gondoliers so I was like,
oh my God, it's going to be hell.
So it's in the newspaper stand.
Alex shows up at the gondolier station
and of course there's a big hello,
a big unfriendly hello? Yeah, just
like, oh, Hello Gondola Sierra.
So far as they got really, really
angry, they were like, well,
we do everything to teach you well and
you know, now you're challenging us.
Alex has a lot of the
gondoliers stop talking to him.
They wouldn't even let him wash
their boats and then you know.
Then of course there were
the ones who said, ah,
I told you in the beginning [inaudible]
she was just going to Blab to the press
and woman. Is that a good thing or
did it do to turn the whole thing?
You know what's like a little
stone becoming a huge, huge thing.
By the way, this is right.
This is coming right before Alex is
about to take the very first exam.
There's actually a series of exams
and it gets a little complicated,
but eventually anybody who wants to be a
gondolier has to take this rowing test.
And by all accounts, Alex was good.
Like we talked to the guy who was the
head of the Gondoliers Association at that
time I e. Oh, this Guy
Fulvio Scarfo was like, yeah,
Alex or me is a more
good, the other main Gando yeah.
And this is the head of the guild.
Yeah. And we also talked to this
legendary rower named Franco Crayon
[inaudible]. He was also like, she
put them into Voila. [inaudible]
Alex is better than most of the guys
we talked to was [inaudible]
answer that. They call it. Yeah.
So anyway, Alex takes the
test and I failed the exempt,
which wouldn't have been,
that by itself wouldn't have been such
a big deal cause a whole bunch of people
fail the first exam.
But the thing was there was a feeling
that like something deeply unfair was
happening. See, I don't know all that
[inaudible] according to Consuelo,
a lot of people started to think maybe
the fix was it to see what other boys
there who failed,
who were better than other boys who
did not fail Alex's suspiciously.
Pretty much all the people that passed
were sons of gondoliers or from gondolier
families because they have
had the right last name. So
then I got angry. I got a lawyer,
Alex thought this was going to bring
attention to how corrupt the licensed
practices, how corrupt
this association is.
I wanted that the exam is repeated for
everybody and this lawyer was negotiating
and the gondoliers association was like,
if we let everyone retake the test,
that will basically be admitting that
we favor certain families over other
families. That was exactly what I
want, but it's not what they wanted.
They said, we don't want the
bad press of this, but then,
and this is another moment according to
Alex where his story just gets hijacked.
My lawyer negotiated without my
permission according to Alex,
without telling him the lawyer together
with the gondoliers association dug up
this old law that says, because
Alex is a woman, I mean he's not.
He's a man, but they thought he was a
woman and this law says that as a woman,
he had the right to take the test. Again,
this time with women judges in the
boat, when she came back and said, okay,
here's what we're going to do. Do you
remember what you said? I was pissed.
I was very upset. That
was not what I wanted,
has nothing to do with man or woman.
Do you think she was your champion
because she identified with you? Yeah,
for sure. It was not my
story. It's her story,
but unfortunately for Alex,
as soon as the lawyer did
[inaudible],
it became everyone's story.
Oh yeah, because press
there. When was it? In
the next two months,
every paper in town was writing about
it, spend it by a Gumbo ears examination.
Mrs. Nixon. That got banned from
[inaudible]. Then the story went global.
Jeremiah catches a crowd in every
to become Danny's first woman.
Going to the sexist sink first
female, good [inaudible] fight,
a male to leash, failed
gondolier blamed chauvinist
and then things escalate into a full
blown gender battle. The are of course,
super pissed because of all
this press that they're getting.
We talked to a couple of
key like gondolier guys
Alixandra Hey, well no, no.
They have some thoughts and feelings
about it and she had to pass a test.
She didn't as an disaster,
Alex is at one point,
things got so bad that
one of them was saying,
I'm gonna wait for you on a small and
street and there's a knife and kill you or
I'm gonna. So I grabbed the guy
and I said, where's your knife?
I'm hit get it out. You know,
do it that it was one that
this all the many Oz's.
So on the one side,
Alex said he has gondoliers wanting to
knife him on the other. It was too close.
Then feminism kicked in and then Alex
said he had all these women rushing in to
save him. Wait, where do you want me to
like us? They thought he was ashamed.
We read in the paper that she had tried
to take the test and had failed and had
called foul saying that the donations
were Maine and the United sexist and
wouldn't let women become gondoliers.
This is gene capital two is active in
the community of Venetian women rowers at
the time. Women by the way,
like there aren't any, well,
so there weren't any women
gondoliers at that time,
but there's a whole community
of female rowers. Um,
they have teams and they race, subbing,
doing venation Ryan for over 20 years
and being a female rower and Venice,
um, who was very difficult. Eleanor,
this woman rower I was talking to.
Thus the week I was with
my a rowing partners,
it was like, I'm routinely when I'm out
on the water, like old men yell at me,
Hey, what's your doing? Returned
back home in the kitchen,
cooking or cleaning your
house. Why are you here?
You're just a Contorno.
You are just a side dish.
They both told me when it comes to racing,
there's a big discrepancy
in the prize money.
The men are getting like four times
as much prize money as the women.
We are now trying to uh,
convince the city of Venice who
gives prices that we are like men,
we are not less than them.
You hear all these women
who have been, you know,
incrementally busting their ass to try
to be taken seriously in the sport.
We are here, we can do this.
And when they saw this press about
Alex fighting the Gondoliers,
they reached out. I sent one of the
other considers down to speak to her,
you know, come to our club and come
and work with us and help us out.
Help us teach people. You've got your
back. But she wasn't interested. No,
of course not because Alex, there
are two problems. First of all,
you cannot compare the ganglia
rollers with racing rose.
There are two different styles
of rowing. And second of all,
the sense I got was that it was kind
of like, I don't want to roll with you.
You guys all wear matching white
skirts. Like not my thing. So, uh,
I remember there was a lot of resentment.
Sure. A woman, how can you be one of
us in this battle for the equality
me and then they're convinced
that I'm a feminist,
that I am one of them
and I'm not. And all of
this comes to a head.
Yeah.
In October of 2004
when Alex has to retake the test and this
time with champion women rowers in the
boat judging them, it
was a lot of pressure.
Everything about this test is supposed
to be a secret. The location of the test,
the path that Alex is going to row. I've
had no clue where we're going to go,
but suspiciously, as Alex
stepped into the boat,
he noticed that there was a huge crowd
lined up all the way down the canal under
the ears and their friends and
they're shouting and yelling.
She was screaming all kinds of the
roads and all kinds of go home.
CanNot imagine the heat. He'd female
rowers in the boat glaring at him.
There's press lined up along the entire
way, plus the tourist plus every,
everybody say it was full of
people. I felt like I'm in a ring.
[inaudible]
I try to block it all out
because I needed to do next. Sam,
the I wanted to do a good performance
and uh, I wasn't able
[inaudible]
it was hell, one of the worst,
worst days of my entire
life and we lead on,
I don't wish that that was real hell.
[inaudible]
hello, this is David from Berlin.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi,
it's Rachel Martin from NPR news up first
is the morning news podcast from NPR.
When news moves fast,
it's the quick morning update on what
happened and what you need to start your
day. The most important news
in about 10 minutes or so,
wake up with up first every day.
You can find it by 6:00 AM eastern
time on the NPR one app or wherever you
listen to your podcast. Hey,
I'm Jad Abumrad. I am Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab and we're turn now
to a story from Kristen Clark and David
Conrad. About Alex Hay,
transgender man who became somehow the
first female Gondola era in 923 years and
thus an international
feminist hero sensation.
And so we now find Alex being painted
by everybody in town in colors the he
doesn't particularly agree
with. And what's interesting
according to Kristen, is just how easy
it is to do that to someone. Okay.
So I'll tell you as we were doing
the interviewing and the reporting,
I'm like, I'm feeling like I have a good
grip on Alex's story. I'm feeling like,
Oh man,
I know what it feels like to be inside
of a narrative that feels really icky.
And so I feel like I'm kind of getting
it and I'm like understanding the full
Alex and like it's about all of these
other things that have nothing to do with
gender. So Alex's story isn't
about gender at all. And,
and for me that made sense
because I was like, in my life,
gender has been a box. Like, even
even when you're in the right,
even when you're in the right box,
gender is a box and it can feel shitty
to be in that box. And so I was like,
yeah, let's bust open those boxes
together. We're going to show you,
we're going to show people
who you are, Alex. But then
we would have these moments
where I would be like, hmm, wait
second,
like one night when we were in Venice,
we were like trying to park our
boat on the way to a restaurant and,
and like this guy is like trying to
parallel park his boat and Alex is kind of
sitting there like
chuckling at him and you,
you can hear like David
Chuckling in the background.
And so the two of them are
like, you know, joking about it.
And then Alex says like, he drives
like a woman, like an old lady.
And I was like, yeah, you know,
and kind of rolled my eyes at it.
But then later at the dinner he was
like, he was like, you know, though,
like I don't really think that like
a real woman could do this job.
And he was like, oh, like
macho about it. Yeah,
I remember you were shocked that
I was saying such a much a thing.
I remember that of course
a you are very right.
A woman can do everything,
but the,
this job is this going
to be very tough because
uh, it's a real, a cruel
community. Amens is very cool and rough.
But when you said that, but when
you said that I got, so I was like,
I'm so frustrated. Um,
and it was because I think I was attached
to the idea of like it being equal,
you know? I mean, I was, I was, I
was just like super confused. Like,
I don't know, I just,
I just want to know a thing that's
not, tell me what you want to know.
I don't, and I'll admit in the moment
I asked a kind of clumsy question.
Do you feel that it was just because
you seem to be almost like prodding me,
you know, having fun
and winging it, David.
And do you feel like you're fundamentally
on a different team from me?
Oh, okay. Uh,
I am on David's team,
but you can't see is it because
he's, you identify with me,
but that's is not a they, I can't help
that. How can I explain it to you?
Let's put it this way. When I'm
in a group of woman for example,
and they start to talk,
I feel uncomfortable.
The check things they have,
I call it a chicken check.
It's not really my cup of
tea. You know? I like it.
It can amuse me,
but the minute they think
that I am one of them,
it doesn't amuse me anymore and I
feel uncomfortable and I don't. I'm,
I'm a,
I'm a little alien there because they
think I am one of them and I'm not.
When I'm with the boys,
I'd feel comfortable.
If it is a nice group
of boys, which I liked,
then we have the same type
of humor on the, you know,
the same stupid jokes about woman
for Alex.
I think what was really striking is
that whatever it is that makes him feel
comfortable being seen as a man but
not as a woman, it runs very deep
for me. There is a difference
between men and women.
Not everybody or even every
transgender person would feel this way,
but the way that he sees it, if there
were no differences, there would be no,
no wish to do transition.
And there would be no two on
sexuality and six like that.
If it would be the same if it isn't
[inaudible].
So you were seeing him as like a
gender doesn't matter kind of icon.
And he was saying, actually
it does matter. Yeah,
we can I just ask a
simpler question. When,
when does he actually become the
first female gun to Lira? Well,
so Alex couldn't get one of these 400 or
so special gondoliers licenses because
he failed the test. Right.
In 2005, I opened up my own business.
He figured out that if he partners up
with businesses in town, like hotels,
he can actually refer them privately.
At the time, uh,
I was looking at all the Lords and I
found that it was possible to open up my
own business without
having a license. So I did.
And so for years he was just
kind of doing this quietly. Then
Alexandra, she said, not the Gumbo.
There she is [inaudible]
she works for a hotel.
Some of the gondoliers began to notice
that Alex was rowing passengers without a
license. And of course they didn't
like that she didn't bus it.
That's saying like, you can't do that.
She's not the part of our team that
is not have a driver's license.
You have to be a member
of this organization.
You have to have a specific license in
order to practice whether we can say she
is not a gondola driver.
I got some threats,
verbal threats and and damaging the
Gondola and since like that all kinds of
stupid little boy shit
[inaudible]
so when they understood they
cannot threaten me this way,
then the pressure at City Hall
to change the villa city basically said
like you can't row, you can't roll a
Gondola with tourists in it without,
without a license. And the law passed and
was signed and it became the real law.
Yeah.
And so one day Alex is out on his
boat and he just gets pulled over and
basically he's told you're
breaking this new law. And so
I wanted to defend myself.
So we went on trial in court.
It was Alex is one lawyer, City Hall
and the Gondoliers Association there,
Ford Lawyers for lawyers. I saw,
oh no, this last case any already,
but sit the whole,
no city hall fights back case goes
to the highest court in the land.
They lost again in front of a court, uh,
with me, a little stranger
from out of nowhere.
Now technically the decision just said
hotels can provide for their customers
the way that they need to.
So if they want to hire a chauffeur
who happens to row in a Gondola,
they can do that. But what that actually
meant was that now for the first time,
Alex could be considered a gondolier
[inaudible].
That was a huge deal message along the
canal to women and paddles against the
tying up times came in, woman
bakes on Vinnies, Gondola Cartel,
Chicago Tribune came in, there's
female gone to live, rock the boat.
Female women came in.
And so this is where we get all of
those articles we read before we came to
Venice, Venice, the story
went all over the world.
And at every single one I have a gun to
their bravo. The message was the same.
We have our first woman Gondolier,
uh,
Rashad.
Oh,
totally. And not held true
the,
so that was something, it was unstoppable.
I could not go in there and say,
excuse me, you know, I'm
not really, you know,
the identifying, no, it was gone. Okay.
It was done. Alex,
at this point in 2007,
doesn't have any other income except
for being able to market himself through
hotels and eventually
online and sold. Of course,
I need to have a website.
People are actively seeking out this
person who has broken the gender barrier
and become the first female gondolier
inventist so it would have been stupid to
try to go against those.
This was already written.
So Alex decides to make his email,
his Facebook page and his website,
all premed Gondola era or
the first female gondolier.
Um, I'm wondering if creating
a website with that name.
Did that feel like taking control
of that narrative or was that narrative
taking control of your decision on that
website? It's nothing to do with
what I've on. That's a label.
You know, I cannot change
a label who has, you know,
20 years of history shot up.
Alex told us he was talking
to his therapist one day
at this transgender center
they have near Venice and she
said, you are like in the cage.
This is like a cage for you. You can't
get really out of this. You know,
it's a, it's a difficult situation.
It's a very difficult situation. But, uh,
I'm tired.
[inaudible]
no, I thought the nasty
by the time we met Alex, he'd been living
almost 10 years like this, you know,
just kind of between these two stories
at night out to his close friends.
But by day giving these tours as
the first female gondolier in Venice
and every few months,
every new tourist season,
these headlines would just regenerate.
First female gondolier first female,
gondolier first female.
And when we left Venice,
that's kind of where we left him
kind of hanging in the middle of that.
And the impression that we got is maybe
that's just going to be how it always is
for him.
By the way, we didn't see each
other. So fast forward six months,
we get an email from Alex. He
says he's in San Francisco.
Uh, things have been happening in
your life. Yeah, he had some news.
Well, you know, I remember
when we were sitting,
when we were last talking in Venice
and we were sitting on the terrorists.
I remember that. Uh,
I was already in, I knew
there was something coming,
but I've, I wasn't sure what it was.
[inaudible]
it was a very difficult year.
I was kind of depressed,
which, you know, I'm not,
I'm not a depressed person
usually. And so I was hanging out.
Uh, I was not moving much.
I was hanging out on,
on my sofa and I was trying to think,
and I was a
more and more every day
I was unhappy about,
people are telling me that
I was a she and another he,
I don't know why I got completely
intolerant before I was like,
I don't care what they say to me. Uh,
I care that they're nice and now I
was last leg. I can't do this anymore.
I was so wrong.
[inaudible]
Alex was about to turn 50 at this point.
And it turns out that part of what was
happening was that he was beginning to go
through the early stages
of menopause. I was hot.
That was tired, sweat,
breaking out for nothing.
After fighting with the Gondoliers,
fighting with the feminists.
This was like a final insult. So, um,
I have this idea that homeless
might help with how I feel.
I started to take the, the testosterone
that was on the 7th of November,
which after six hours, uh, I get
the first smile on my face in, in,
in nearly a year. Like, you know, I felt,
felt good and the mood
swings, they stopped. Yeah.
So I'm now, I'm like, I,
I knew me because I was looking in
the mirror every day and I was like,
who is this monster? He decided to fly
to San Francisco, meet with a doctor. Uh,
some people wait like two years or
three years before they start to do a
surgery.
I wanted to do it now because for me
it was something like now or never.
Uh, so now, uh, I'm here in San Francisco.
I've had top surgery on the
24 days. That's about, yeah,
four days ago. And
I wanted to start this year with
a buddy, which is confirming me.
People see me as a first
woman. I'm going to the end.
That means something for many
people, it's not fair to them.
So you know, I need to, I
needed to say something.
I changed on the Facebook
side or changed the name.
Now it's a Alexei Gondola truce
and I did already a state.
Then on my, on my old website,
there is a statement, it says,
dear guests, colleagues and friends,
after holding myself
back for three decades,
it's time for me to depart from my
wrong body. I am not changing who I am.
I am becoming who I am.
And is he, uh, back in Venice now? Yeah.
Huh?
Do you have any sense of what that's
going to mean for his job or his life?
I have no idea. I have no clue.
I don't know how my voice is going
to be in a month. It should drop.
I have no idea how my face is.
Gonna look in my buddies. I'm
gonna look in the three
years, three years from now,
we all leave it as a surprise.
Hello? Hello.
Well idea. That's scary.
Okay.
Oh, hello. [inaudible]
[inaudible]
thanks to report Kristen
Clark and David Conrad also,
thanks to Alexis Unger and summer and
of course a huge thanks to Alex for
sharing a very difficult story with us.
Are you worried about what the responses
might be to it? Oh my God, David.
I love warrior. You
think this is boring me?
I've been to worst, I guess.
I remember like when we were
sitting out on the balcony,
you had said something like, I
don't want to do another battle,
but I don't want to do another
bubble. But if I have to,
I will because I,
I hope that it can at least
help one person out then
[inaudible]
yeah. Got It.
Yo, can you [inaudible]
[inaudible]
the story was produced by Annie Mcewen
and Molly Webster with help from Kristen
Clark and we got reporting and
translation help from Valentina powers,
Florence Percino and Ann Marie Soma. Kimi
go lucky me.
[inaudible]
he got dog. Oh,
we had original music from
Jeremy Blum and Alex Overington
[inaudible] out of [inaudible].
Ah,
oh,
okay. And on a very different
note, very belated note,
we would like take this moment
to say, um, good bye to our,
to our, our longtime reporter, producer,
Brenna Farrel. Not only goodbye,
but like thank you times 50
like that to the 50th power.
Yeah. Brenna has been
with us for many years,
and I think with the
station for over a decade,
I believe in done every single job.
That's that you can imagine. Uh,
and so Brenna,
we hear radio lab and the whole station
in are gonna miss you very, very much.
We already do. And still
go and do even more.
Like right now, a genomics
[inaudible]
string Giamo. She, John [inaudible]
I know. [inaudible]
[inaudible]
all right, I'm Jad Abumrad I remember
Krulwich. Thanks for listening.