Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich Radiolab. The podcast. Yes,
and today on the podcast we're going to
present a story that a whole thing is an
accident, really. The category podcast,
we were on tour a few months ago doing
this symmetry thing in San Francisco and
right as we were there,
we got an email from a woman who lives
there telling us this new nutty story.
Something odd had happened to her
and she wanted to share it with us,
so he met her in the lobby. I missed,
I didn't hit the record
button fast enough.
Could you just tell me your name again?
And My name is lysis Schonfeld and I'm
a research technician at the Gladstone
institute at the University
of California San Francisco.
Now Lysa is just getting started
with her scientific career,
finishing my undergraduate degree
about a year and a half ago,
and this story takes place as she was
about to take that next step after college
and apply to Grad schools. The Star
of our story other than of course,
Lizer herself, is a little
mischievous part of her brain. Well,
everyone's brain, your brain called
the Basal Ganglia, the Basal Ganglia,
which is a time she'd been studying
just so we understand basil and Ganglia,
so Bazell is not the a thing from
which Pesto is made. In your case,
what does Bazell mean about that? Okay,
let's go to go on to Ganglia. You know,
collections of neurons, big collections.
So basically Langley has a
fairly large part of your brain.
It's actually this big hunk deep in
the center and it's responsible for
controlling and coordinating movement.
When I move my neck back and forth,
am I using my Basal Ganglia? Yeah. When
I wink can by using my basal Ganglia.
When I make an expression in my
face, I'm using my Bazell testimony.
What about if I'm reading a, the
New Yorker, I don't think so.
Apologies to the New
Yorker and its employees,
but is this part of your brain is really
basic and at the lab where she was
working,
they had figured out this particular
Basal Ganglia trick using this really cool
technology called optogenetics. Maybe
trick isn't quite the right word.
What they'd done is they'd found
a way to take a mouse thread,
a little fiber optic cable through
its skull deep into its brain,
into its base with ganglion so
that when you shine a blue laser,
literally we just shine
lasers and a mouse brains.
They could actually turn it's basal
Ganglia or parts of it on or off.
When this is in a live mouse,
this isn't a live mouse.
So we have these really cool videos
showing a mouse running around having a
great mouse time. You turn the light on,
we can get them to free
in mid-stride. Yeah,
so you hit the laser and boom,
the mouse stop out just like this.
So use those lights. They're like puppet
ties the mouse. If you're this mouse,
no matter how hard you try, feet move,
as long as that light is on,
come on fool. You can't do it.
Lysa is holding the strings. Not Exactly.
It turns out she doesn't get to play with
the laser that much. I'm kind of like,
I'm the bottom of the totem pole,
so I do a lot of pipe heading.
It's like where you squirt
liquid from one tube to another.
I'm working at my pipe padding,
we're getting the thumb muscles. Oh,
I could beat anyone in that
wrestling competition right now.
So at a certain point she was like,
enough of this time for me to apply
to Grad school. I applied to five,
university of California,
San Diego, University of
Washington and Seattle U CSF,
Rockefeller University and Harvard.
Cause you're going big. Yeah, go bigger.
Go home. Right. So she hits
off to her first interview.
University of Washington went great.
I loved it. Okay. I went to Penn,
university of Pennsylvania,
went down to UCFC in San Diego.
It's a beautiful place, great scientists.
It's actually the largest neuroscience
community in the world. So far so good.
Did you ever go back to San
Francisco where we are now?
This is where things get strange. Yes.
So my last interview,
my very last interview was at UCF
and she says about a week before that
interview I got really sick. So I
think it was some kind of stomach flu,
but it was pretty severe nausea.
I wasn't really able to eat or do
anything and throwing up. Yeah,
I'll all sorts of, I don't know.
I had some bad dim some the weekend
before that could have been.
She goes to the doctor,
he gives her some pills to fight the
nausea and then the next day was my
interview. Friday was my
interview. So I went, you know,
there's a nice introduction. They
give you a breakfast. This point.
She's pretty familiar
with the whole routine.
Generally the way these interviews are
structured is that we talk a little bit
about my research and dopamine and
the Basal Ganglia and these mice,
they tell her about their work. I have
to think of a couple of woody questions.
I asked my questions.
What's a really question?
What are the science questions? What
are you saying? Nevermind. Anyhow,
she's raring to go and she heads into
meet her first Basal Ganglia Titian of the
day and he studies, um,
one of the things he studies is
dopamine in the Basal Ganglia.
He study stuff that's a little bit more
molecular than what I, what I know.
But we had a good conversation
about dopamine and at this
point in the day I was
feeling okay. Then I went
to my second interview,
which is this woman that I
was so excited to talk to.
Her name is Alison Dope and she's pretty
well known. Alison Dope. Alison Dope.
Wow. She studies dopamine,
she studies songbirds,
which is what lies I've really wanted to
study. So birds have basic English too.
So she's pretty fired up and kind of
in the beginning of that interview, my,
my face started to feel a
little bit strange and I was
wearing glasses that day.
So what I felt was happening was
that my glasses were, you know,
your glasses get loose and they kind
of start to slip down your nose and you
have to kind of tighten the muscles
around your ears to try and keep your
glasses on. So we were talking and
I just kept on feeling like, God,
why can't I stop tightening that?
It was Kinda got to the point where it
started to distract me, but I felt okay.
Then we went to lunch and this was a
lunch with all the current students and a
lot of the current faculty and
all the prospective students.
And at lunch I remember
on the walk to lunch,
my head just started spontaneously
turning to the right, like,
like I like I would be trying to sit
here and face you and I would just turn
over here and face Robert t. It was such
a funny thing. And you're like, no, no,
don't do that. Exactly what was happening?
I was trying to send signals to
my neck being like, all right,
sitting here having lunch
with an important professor.
Why don't you just face him, talk to him
and instead I'm just turning over here,
turning over here, turning over here.
Oh, you're turning a fairly wide art.
Yeah. You're turning away.
Yeah. Professor. Oh, I remember,
I remember at one point in lunch turning
my chair like this so I could see
a sign. A permanent
side. Long Glance. Yeah,
but you figured it's not that painful,
so it must just be a cramp or something.
I'm kind of thinking. Oh, okay.
So I slept funny last night.
I must've slept on a weird angle on
my pillow. Now I'm having a net cramp.
My glasses are loose. I just
gotta tighten the glasses,
everything under control. So, so then I,
after lunch was going to go to my third
interview was with Alison dopes husband
who also studies songbirds. So he's
familiar with the Basal Ganglia too.
They meet up to walk over
to his office together.
And so I explained to him on the walk
over, I think I'm having neck cramps.
Would it be possible maybe
to try and get a hot pad?
He's so sure I may track
one down, but on the walk,
not only now just my neck
start turning to the right,
but it's snapping itself back in
voluntarily. My head snapping back light.
Suddenly your eyes are pointing up at
the sky. And then as I'm talking to him,
I'm realizing that I can't
control my eyebrows from,
from raising pretty tightly. So I
look like you're doing right now.
Like I'm doing like deep
surprise, constant deeps.
I can't stop it. I look surprised at
everything I'm saying and I can't stop it.
So after the eyebrows start and
I can't pull them back down then,
then the mouth, then all this area
starts to go lower to face. Yes.
What is it doing? It turns into
this really twisted, painful,
grimacing smile. Would you mind?
I'll demo it. Okay. So I've got the neck,
it's like this crane back eyebrows
wrote like this total surprise,
like this crazy Frankenstein face
demeanor for graduate interview. No,
it's not going well and I'm
noticing that something is be,
I think at that point he thought I was
just really excited to be talking about
neuroscience and I'm just trying
to think, okay. Mouth, like try,
try and just calm down a little
bit. And it was pretty painful too.
I mean it was like, imagine like a
Charlie horse in your face. Oh yeah.
But she gets through the interview
and I actually do okay. You know,
he asked me tough questions about
science and I can answer him I think.
And I leave the interview and then I
met by the woman who's the head of the
admissions weekend and she took one
look at Lysa and she said, hi. You know,
I don't know if you should do the rest
of the interviews and with her as my
student host decides, alright, let me
just call my dad, just saying, Hey dad,
I'm in the middle of an interview and
someone kind of funny is happening with my
face. I can't control it.
And while I'm talking to him I lose
control of my mouth and my tongue so I
can't, I can kind of talk,
but it's, it's pretty bad.
Yeah. Is Your Dad a doctor? No. Imagine
your kid calling you being like,
I'm losing control of my face.
And as they're telling you that I started
to think something's really wrong.
And then my student host comes rushing
back in running and he looks at me and he
tries to put on a calm face and he says,
so now we need to go
to the emergency room.
So they throw into a taxi
and in the taxi it went from,
I can't control my mouth to a complete,
I mean a complete the all seat
of a torque. I did not look good.
As we're pulling up to the emergency room
is when my throat started tightening.
They rushed her inside and
they have me in a Gurney,
in a room in the back of
the Er, surrounded by six
people. Within two minutes,
doctors swarming all around her oxygen
mask. EKG leads all over my chest.
They do an ivy and then she's lying there
on the table and she's thinking like,
what's wrong with me? Why
can't I control my throat?
Why can't I control my body?
And I just, I couldn't.
I remember frantically sending messages
like, you got to cut this out now,
but she wasn't in control
and it turned out okay.
[inaudible]
the wild. She was going from
interview to interview to interview,
talking about how her lab had taken
these little Macy's and seize control of
their Basal Ganglia. The
composition that I took,
that nausea drug was actually affecting
the dopamine systems and my basal
Ganglia. In other words,
that drug had been doing to her pretty
much with what she'd been doing to those
mice. One to 2% of people
who take composition.
They can have what's
called an acute dystonia,
which is what happened to me
during all those interviews.
And the crazy thing is the guy that I
talked to first in the morning was the
molecular dopamine guy. You know, how
does dopamine get packed in the vesicles?
How does it get released?
And it wasn't until I started talking
with a more systems level people who
studied the behavioral output of the
Basal Ganglia that I started to have
behavioral deficits in my Basal Ganglia.
So your Basal Ganglia are testing the
San Francisco docs and they are failing
[inaudible] yeah, you can get into
San Francisco state. I just CSF CSF.
No, no. Oh Hm. Damn it. Basal Ganglia,
we should probably tell everybody
that lies is obviously doing okay.
Back in the Er when the doctors
finally figured out what was going on,
they just gave her some Benadryl of all
things and actually within 20 minutes I
was feeling a lot better.
She could breathe her face it
unclenched and we asked her,
how has this little adventure
changed you? Uh, she said, well,
I'm still working with those mice cause
when we talk to her Grad school hadn't
started yet. And now when I go
into that room with a little laser,
I go in now and I just
really, I empathize with them.
Come a little catch. This would just be
for a couple of minutes. You can do it.
Yeah. I'm thinking a lot about that.
[inaudible]
Eliza Schoenfeld is now a proud phd
candidate at the University of Washington
and a thank you to Brenna Farrell
for production help on this podcast.
And that is our podcast. And here it is.
I'm Robert Krulwich. I'm Jad Abumrad.
Thank you for listening.