G O K you there?
[inaudible]. Hello? Okay,
there you are. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
Yes sir. And so, okay,
we're going to continue with
one more episode from a,
from the series on erased what
you did for somebody else,
but here it was kind of for somebody
else but also for us at the same time.
Uh, it all was kind of
squishy to be honest.
So I've produced a four part series
along with, uh, focus features,
stitcher and limited house. Uh,
that was about the history of conversion
therapy in America. That's, uh,
people who are gay, who are being pushed
to or asked to or want to be straight.
Yes. And sometimes it's a
therapy type situation. Sciencey.
Sometimes it's a church type situation.
Here's the, here's a funny thing,
Robert. You would think it's kind of, uh,
you would think it doesn't happen
a lot, right? These days? Nothing,
certainly less, certainly
less than before. Well, uh,
there was a survey done recently
by, uh, by a group at UCLA,
uh, at the Williams institute in
conjunction with Gallup, Gallup polling.
They did a survey that looked at,
of the people in America
who identify as LGBTQ,
which is about 4.5%
roughly 13 million people.
How many of those people have gone
through something like conversion therapy?
And the number was completely
shocking to me. Ooh,
shockingly small. Shocking, well shocked.
Almost 700,000 people in the
1970s and eighties and so on.
Yeah, I mean, but also
recently, like recently,
this was a survey has done in 2012 and I
just want to give you a sense of scale.
Okay. 700,000 people,
that is the equivalent
of the city of Boston.
That's the number of
people we're talking about.
That's a lot of freaking
people. Now, to your question,
you would think it would
be mostly older folks? Yes.
From the days when it was an abomination
and dow no longer really from any
family? No. It was actually equally
prevalent in all age groups. I mean,
the survey found that just as
many young people, you know,
teens were being put through these
kinds of programs as people of older
generations. That is surprising.
The prevalence wasn't going down.
Um, you know, if anything
like just as LGBTQ, uh,
people are being embraced
in the wider culture,
there has been a kind of silent reentry
judgement in certain communities in
America.
And so that was part of the whole reason
to do this project is that there's this
thing happening that we're not really
looking at and it's got a whole history to
it. It's troubling, but also
kind of fascinating. So, uh,
I want to play the final episode in the
four part series and it deals with, um,
well it deals with one of the
central guys in that history.
This main character that
you found, this is a really
complex fellow. Yes. You turn
this thing on and you think,
no. Well, well he, oh hmm. And then,
I don't know, I don't know what your
face will look like at the end of this.
Yes. So, um, let's just say a few
things before we start this. Uh,
this whole project was done in conjunction
with the focus features film boy
erased, which is out now.
And that film was based on a wonderful
memoir by a guy named Garrett Conley.
And this story was the
story everybody told us.
We had to tell if we were going to do
a series about conversion therapy in
America, and it's about
a guy named Smith. Yes.
[inaudible]
news cameras started showing
bullhorns came out and all of
a sudden I heard John Smith,
we know you're in there.
[inaudible]
John Smith, we know you're
here. It was as though a torpedo
had just hit the side of our ship.
The ship that John Smith
captained before it was torpedoed.
What's the largest ex
gay ministry in America
called Love in action? 11 action
for almost 25 years from 1994 2008 if
you were an evangelical Christian who had
a gay son or daughter and you
wanted to convert them to straight,
you might've sent them to John for maybe
$7,000 he would run them through his
program and I want to, I want you
to tell him how affected he is.
The guy in boy erased the
torments Garrett County.
Tell him how you hate him for the things
that he's the way he, you sit down,
sit down, but I'm not angry and and
and yeah, no things that upset you.
Are you just letting me down here
and you die? Do I have to be angry?
I don't like my life to be painted as
a villain and that's kind of the way I
feel about this movie. It's like I
don't like it. It's uncomfortable.
I don't like the movie.
I don't like the book.
I don't like what people are saying. I
don't like hearing Garrett talk about it.
I don't like it. It's
uncomfortable. At the same time,
there is truth in that I was a foreigner
and a spokesperson and a national and
international leader that said, you must
eradicate homosexuality from your life.
That's just the price these days.
John Smit is living a very different life.
My life has been reinvented
several times. Majorly reinvented.
He now lives in Paris, Texas
with his husband Larry,
and he makes furniture
is this way. Yeah. Okay.
Producer shemale [inaudible]
and I paid him a visit. Well,
we're going into my workshop, which
is a off the corner of our house.
John and Larry live in a tiny one story
house bordering an enormous horse farm.
So what you see as we walked to
the garage, out of his house,
into the garage is rolling
hills in one direction. Epic,
Texas, flatlands and another
and a sky that is so big,
it kind of hurts your head to shop itself
as is it in here with the cars? It's,
it's a divided shop. The
cars are in the next space.
John also collects and restores
old cars. Oh Wow. Look at this.
I'm, I'm a person that uses
every scrap that I can.
I have a lot of used wood,
old wood like over there as a whole
bunch of these days. Uh, what he does,
instead of trying to
eradicate homosexuality,
John will spend his days taking, uh,
old copies of Reader's digest books and
carving them into the
letters of the alphabet.
This large band saw a really
cuts a nice refined edge.
There's no frayed edges
or a heel. Also, and I'm
going to router these out.
[inaudible]
carpentry work for local designers. I
know he'll make a calling. Paint it white.
Yeah.
When you're making something, what are
you thinking about it? Most of the time
I'm, I'm thinking about relationships.
I'm thinking about life,
people, history, future.
A lot of times it's processing painful
things, you know, difficult things.
How to think about John Smith
is a difficult question.
He is undeniably warm and funny and
honest and engaging at the same time.
Many people told us before
we came, don't forget,
this is a guy who ran a program, uh,
where people in the program
tried to commit suicide
and in some cases succeeded
and now that he's out himself and married
to man and vehemently opposed to the
whole idea of conversion therapy.
It does beg the question,
what do we do with that past?
How should we think about it?
Is He allowed to just move on?
Where'd you grow up? I was
raised in Omaha, Nebraska.
It was 1959 life was the
fifties life was good.
All the moms walked up and down the
street in their shirtwaist dresses and had
coffee with each other. I mean,
it was a stereotypical 1950s suburban
neighborhood experience and I remember
feeling, um, at five,
I remember sitting back in our backyard
on a summer morning school was out
sitting in to play sandbox
and feeling the warm sun.
And I remember just feeling, life's good.
[inaudible]
I was so at peace
it was this one moment of calm. He says,
where he didn't have to
worry about who he was
[inaudible]
now the story as it goes from here of
John becoming and then unbecoming the
Elvis of the ex gay movement is
complicated to say the least.
You could start the story
in the fourth grade.
I remember in fourth grade having
an emotional affair with Steve.
I wanted to carry his books. He had a
broken arm. I wanted to hold his hand.
Of course I was a gay boy,
but I didn't know how to work that
through or what does a little boy in that
situation say to himself.
I didn't have words.
Then there was fifth grade for the first
time in school gets a male teacher.
All my teachers were females and all
of a sudden we had this male teacher.
I remember just, I just fantasizing,
just looking at him being drawn to
him, being attracted to his maleness,
not knowing what to do with that.
Jumping forward a bit dated several girls
in high school ends up marrying a girl
named Chris. How old
were you at this point?
I was 1716 like him. She
had a tough family life,
alcoholic father. Parents are divorced,
felt like they just kind of got each
other and we created two children and then
you get to the first in a series of
violent shifts in John's midlife.
Many years later when he was like firmly
embedded in the ex gay movement and a
preaching against homosexuality,
he would give a sermon that sort
of talked about this moment.
I just want to share a little bit about
my personal story so you know who I am
and where I'm coming from.
He describes as being 23
newly married with kids,
homosexual and then
falling into this funk,
like suddenly being very uncertain
about his marriage, about the future.
At the time he was working at
a department store and, uh,
he meets a guy named Leonard.
He called me one night and we
wonder, you know, it's funny how,
how the enemy works in our
lives and you works in those,
those intimate times
of darkness of secrecy.
It's not in the light.
It's not above board.
It's always somewhere sinister that
he sneaks in. And one Friday night,
nine 30 at night, my wife was bowling.
I was taking care of the kids.
Leonard called me, Hey
John, I'm at the bar. Um,
why don't you come over and we can talk.
Well now he had strategically placed
himself at a bar right across the street
from where I lived. And, uh,
I found out later that he was already
surmising what I was looking for,
what I was curious about,
where I was headed in his mind.
I want to cross the street.
That evening ended up in a very
mutually seductive homosexual encounter.
Uh, I came home from that
four o'clock in the morning,
which is again something I never did. I
never, ever went out and stayed out. Um,
of course my wife wasn't stupid. She
knew that. Why was he out so late?
What was going on? So she began
to ask me questions, what went on,
and I immediately went to her and
I said, uh, Chris, I'm a, I'm gay.
Do you see how quick that identity
got stuck? I had one sexual encounter,
one outside of marital sex,
which was the only other experience I'd
ever had sexually. One sexual encounter.
And I'm signed, sealed, delivered.
I'm gay and I want a divorce.
Well, what do you think
when you hear that? Now?
My first thought was my verbiage and the
way I described that story and the way
I would describe it diff today
would be so violently different.
Those terms were inflammatory. I mean, I,
I filtered that story through
my theology at that time.
I walked away from that marriage,
abandoned my children in homosexual
adultery and dove into head long,
full force, the homosexual subculture.
I lived in a gay apartment building,
frequented gay businesses. Um,
anyone who wasn't familiar with
or didn't like my homosexuality,
I just crossed them off the list
in a later a TV interview.
John would say that during this period
he even became the guy so that a young
gay men who are new in town would
call to sort of get initiated.
I had taken people to the gay
bars for their first time.
I was instrumental in helping people
involve themselves in that lifestyle.
So for years I lived in that lifestyle,
four years of active pursuit and
all along thinking in my head,
I'm looking for monogamy, I'm
looking for a life partner.
I'm looking for that one person that can
satisfy all my needs and never let me
down.
What makes, uh,
John's backstory so interesting and also
difficult to wrap your head around or
these wildly different poles that he
travels between in one life? I mean,
he starts off living the sort of
50s American suburban Dream Wife.
Two kids swings into the gay
subculture as he calls it.
And then as he puts it,
what happened was he started
to get his heartbroken a lot.
The first guy that I
lived with, I mean I just,
I just really loved him as a
20 something year old can. Um,
he came home one day and he
says, I can't be with you.
I'm a size queen and you
don't measure up. Hmm,
okay. I basically told them, you're
not enough of a man down there for me.
That was a shocking, deeply,
deeply wounding moment.
He says he struggled with his confidence
and he got into a series of, of,
of very bad dysfunctional relationships
develop and began to feel like something
was wrong with him.
And,
and it was at that point with this four
year experience in the gay culture where
a girl I with at the time, he was
working for the railroad as a clerk.
She was an ever gelical Christian,
started talking with me about Jesus in
the Bible and she was very open about her
own struggles, very vulnerable with me.
And she invited me to church
and kept inviting me to church.
And eventually I went
[inaudible]
it was a Christian revival,
this church service,
this is the kind where people speak in
tongues. Talk about the devil a lot.
So I went and sure enough I was sitting
in the Pew and this guy was speaking and
I don't know what the heck he's talking
about because God was too busy speaking
to me personally and I was sitting
back in this pew and I'll never forget,
God said, John,
you don't have to live
this way any longer.
No.
What was it t that, I mean
t w this is always the hardest John.
Like what? Both stories, how's he,
how does it explain that moment now?
Because everything that follows
really flows from that moment
as honest as I can be about it because
I don't really understand it myself
either. But as much as I can process it,
it was built on the hope
of not the experience of,
he told me later that, you
know the conversion moment,
that God's voice in his
head that he can't explain,
but all the moments after suddenly having
this whole new belief system reframed
everything. First of all, he was reborn.
So literally everything before
that point was no longer important.
It was only about what comes after.
And also he now had this book,
which seemed to say that the
way he just was was a sin,
which you would think you
wouldn't want to hear.
But he said it was actually a relief to
hear that because he could now take all
of those really hard questions about
himself and who he was as a man,
and he can now put it into a box
called sin and say to Himself, oh,
that's why I was feeling so bad
because I was committing sin.
It was what I was doing. It's not
necessarily who I am. It was my behavior.
And that can change.
I believed that all this pain,
Jesus could heal and he
could bring meaning and sense
and comfort and peace into
my life.
And so in, uh, another violent shift,
John Smith becomes really only one of
two people I've ever heard of to come out
of the closet and then go back in. And
so this past starts to go into this
church regularly. I felt free.
I felt liberated telling them about your
clown ministry. Yeah, I was a clown.
I became a clown. You
were a clown. Yes. Um,
I was rainbow the clown and we, we love
how you say that. So matter of fact.
Yeah. Well we were, we were trained and
we went through clown school. Was it,
was it you was a, you were a
Christian clown? Yes, and my,
my clown stick was I would walk in
with an umbrella because I was high.
I was underneath the clouds
of life and the rain and my,
I had a trick umbrella
that when I would shake it,
you would fall and it put it down in the
rainbow would come out the promises of
God's future. It was my testimony,
kind of a story of how I came out from
under the rain clouds and found the sun.
No, I made all the wigs for the clowns
and I made the props and it was really a
significant two and a half years of my
life when I didn't have any outside.
Yeah. Pressures. He says it was a little
bit like that moment when he was four.
He was totally at peace,
super happy. But then
he starts getting lonely
and I needed a companion.
So I dated a couple of girls
and those things didn't succeed.
And finally I met Valene and we started
kind of dating and I felt like you said
initially things were going well and
he felt like, oh, maybe I can change,
maybe I have. But then as he
describes it, that funk returned,
uh,
like those old feelings. But
even more unspoken than that,
that's just a kind of panic would
come up. And I started feeling really,
really scared.
Um,
while I was in that place
today on family them I
heard a radio program.
Welcome everyone to this edition of
family talk, focus on the family,
James Dobson. James Dobson, by the way,
is maybe one of the most influential
evangelical voices of the last 50 years.
It's a hugely popular radio show today.
We're addressing the tough
subject of same sex attraction,
which affects millions of people and
their families and the guest on the guest
on the radio program as Barbara Johnson.
So when I learned that he was homosexual,
I thought this couldn't happen
to Christian families. I mean,
Barbara Johnson was a mom of a gay
son. And at the end of that program,
homosexual feelings can and do dissipate.
And they offered information sheets
on ex gay ministry. John's has,
they basically said for all of you who
are struggling with same sex feelings,
there is a program out
there. They can help you.
First time I'd ever heard gay anything
in the context of Christian anything.
So I said, focus on the family a
letter. And to make a long story short,
he ends up getting connected with the
guy who many people sort of believe to be
the father, the spiritual godfather
of the ex gay movement, very hard.
And I had just given up on the church.
We talked about him a bit in episode one.
Like John Frank Worthen was a
guy who had been in the closet,
come out of the closet, but then, uh,
at a low point heard a voice from God.
Yeah,
I heard God say, I want your back.
And you went back in the closet.
This was 1973.
I know,
right in the middle of a Jesus movement.
Frank starts going to church
and after service, one day
after church,
three young men came to visit me and
they were all gay and they said, uh,
I heard you made a
recommitment to Christ at,
you're leaving the gay lifestyle
and we would like to leave it too.
And so that kind of, you know, within
three days we a little group going
as frank Worthen tells it.
That's how the x game movement began
casually when they, after church,
while the members named
it love and action,
we did feel that it was God's answer to
the APA saying homosexuality is normal
and god is saying not really.
What he's referring to there is sort
of the beginning of the scientific
community washing their hands.
The whole idea of the gay cure,
which we talked about in the last
episode, they're not Christian.
They don't know what they're saying.
John says at the time that's,
that really spooked a lot of evangelicals.
This scientific communities were accepting
homosexuality and they were saying
that it's not a disorder anymore.
They were removing it from the DSM three
which is why we need to do what we're
doing. So it was very explicit
in your mindset? Oh yeah.
In any case, John and frank [inaudible]
and Frank's wife and Nita Worthen,
they started corresponding and I said
I was capable, I was trustworthy.
They could count on me. Can
you help me? What do you have?
And so Anita called me, she says,
we are hiring a house leader
for one of our houses.
We want to know if you want to apply
for it. So John goes out to San Rafael,
California and I volunteered for 11
action and so begins a very bizarre,
very dramatic 25 year odyssey to try
and stamp out homosexuality in Christian
men everywhere and especially in himself.
That's after the break on a race. We'll
continue on radio lab and just a model.
Hi, this is Jack from Peralta, New Mexico.
Radiolab is supported in part by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by on key. As we know,
pop culture is full of evil robots
program to take over the world vector is a
good robot,
giant roll forward for robot kind of real
life robot sidekick that lives in your
home. He can see and hear and
feel and navigate on his own.
He can tell you the weather, he
can answer questions, set a timer,
it gets smarter over time.
Vector will also update regularly with
new features and functionality show.
You can order a vector,
the good robot at [inaudible] dot
com slash Radiolab that's a n k
i.com/radiolab Andrew, Promo Code
Radio lab for a 10% discount.
Hey, I'm Chad up and rod. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is Radiolab. Yes,
and we're listening to episode four of
an erased on radio lab and let's get back
to the story of John Smith.
At this point in the story,
John is searching for a way to rid
himself of gay attractions and to make
himself attracted to his wife,
his second wife because he does
end up marrying a second time.
He goes to San Rafael,
California to volunteer for
a new ministry run by frank and Anita
Worthen that promises a solution.
They loved me. I was became an office
manager. I managed all kinds of stuff.
I became senior house manager.
Fast forward a couple of years,
frank worth and decides to go to the
Philippines on sort of a missionary trip
and John takes over the ministry
[inaudible]
so when he left,
clearly redecorated, moved everything
around, changed everything.
I'm an elected.
Yeah, I mean
the moment frank flew out, which
was a symbol of this is now mine,
and here's where John's story morphs
into something quite different,
something much bigger and maybe darker
than just one man's journey towards
accepting who he is. As John
tells it, the moment he showed up,
11 action caught a win.
Los Angeles, welcome to Larry King Live.
I went on the Larry King Live
program six months after I got there,
which is insane. You started
appearing on various talk shows.
Homosexuality from my
experience get stemmed out of
a need to know I was okay as
a man. And he very quickly
realized [inaudible]
his story was like rocket fuel.
I had a phenomenal, miraculous testimony.
This is him and a phone in here.
I mean,
I was one of those people who had a
dramatic transformation from where I was.
One day I'm sleeping with my gay partner
and the next day I'm 100% sold out to
God, committed, faithful.
So people saw my life as
the dark versus the light.
It was almost like Saint
Paul on the road to Damascus.
He says,
people would come up to them at Christian
conferences and say that they were
actually jealous of him. And once
he saw the power in his own story,
we became much more
extroverted as a ministry.
And perhaps as a result,
love and action started to gain converts
by the week to the point where they
could no longer fit in the small
church in San Rafael. And so
around 1994 they go off in search of
a bigger church. We'd go to Memphis
[inaudible]
in Memphis, Tennessee. So we go to
Memphis, big church, large community,
they hire staff. At this point,
John is flying high and love and action
was advertising the staggering success
rates. This is something that we
heard from Jared Conley. My mom says,
they said there was an 87% success rate
of conversion from gay to straight.
I internally underneath that all
while I couldn't verbalize it,
I had to admit somewhere in me
that we were not seeing success.
We were not winning. They were
successful. Why? They were in the program.
As soon as they'd leave, boom, they
had fallen. I knew it wasn't working,
but I couldn't admit that.
So the only way I could acknowledge that
would be to adopt something new that
might work better. So
when he got to Memphis,
he decided to go a totally different
route. He figured if people were quote,
relapsing, which they were,
let me draw inspiration
from other modalities, uh,
that also have to deal with the
problem of people relapsing.
And so he ended up visiting a
local drug and Rehab Center.
It's called second chance. It's a
drug and alcohol rehab for teenagers.
Wonderful success rates.
So we all talked about it as a
staff and we sat down and we said,
we really think they
have something valuable.
We adopted their philosophy.
They decided they would
define homosexuality.
Homosexuality is an addiction,
and maybe they could just treat
it with something like 12 step.
The 12 steps seemingly were the the best
way to rid people of drug and alcohol
abuse and had a track record. And
I'm thinking, well, maybe that'll,
if homosexuality is an addiction,
we need to remove the homosexual drug
long enough for these people to detox from
it.
So starting in 1994 and going through
his whole 14 year stint at the Memphis
clinic, John Basically implemented
a system where young men,
women would come in,
anything that they had that could
be remotely construed as homosexual,
which we called [inaudible] false
images. They're homosexual. Look,
they're homosexual books. They're
homosexual concepts, friends, people,
associations,
drug and alcohol recovery centers have
seen these things as contraband and it
has to be removed. They
can't come here with that.
They have to be separated from it.
So they can think without it because
it's their coping mechanisms.
It's their addiction.
After they were then separated from their
homosexual paraphernalia or what have
you, clients would then go through,
you know, endless rounds of
pseudoscientific talk therapy
and so it became this elaborate 12 step
program where we had to write down every
week three different sexual experiences
that we had in our lifetime and do a
moral inventory about each
one. This is Peterson Tescano.
We heard a bit from him in
episode one he did two stints,
11 actual sexual experience would be well
beyond just physically having sex with
someone, but a fantasy and
obsession over someone,
a romantic crush that you had an encounter
you may have had with an inanimate
object. They use this very,
this very like strange language to talk
about this stuff and some of it was
like, what are you talking about? And
they were like, you know, you know,
did you ever use shaving cream when you
masturbated over? Like I was like, no,
but now I'm thinking of
that. Thank you for that.
If you're writing about these really
intense sexual encounters and it becomes
like a butterfly with pins in
it that you're splayed out in,
you're analyzing it and dissecting
it and tearing it apart.
Peterson also told us
that there were times when this,
these kinds of techniques tipped
into just abject cruelty. Uh,
sometimes they would be asked to confess
some of these stories directly to
parents on friends and family at night.
He told us about a mock funeral that
was staged for a young man named Aaron
Opera. Lee Peterson
remembers candles. I'm not
sure if I remember that or
not, but maybe there were.
It's one of these pretty traumatic things
that I didn't really ever really want
to bring back to the light.
This is Aaron. We called them up. He
says he is okay talking about it now,
especially since it's a
scene in the boy erased film.
But essentially what
happened is that Aaron had,
I guess, relapsed or fallen or whatever
with someone outside of the program,
I guess is how they stated it. So
they asked him to lie on a table,
close his eyes. They brought in,
they had some pretty gaudy
flowers in their office. I mean,
John Smith is probably going
to laugh at me for saying that,
but I did not like the flower
arrangements. But anyway. Um,
but I do know that I was on a table, I,
that my eyes were shut and
then they wanted all the
people in the program to say
their goodbyes to me. Um, wow. Yeah.
When we asked John Smith about
this, like, come on, really?
This is what he said.
It was a directive by the professional
counselor that was our consulting
psychologist. They made this up and
they said, you should do this. He said,
the reason we're doing this is because
this man has had a pattern of destructive
behavior.
He says it was just something that was
suggested to them by an actual counselor.
He said, this is called gestalt
therapy. He says the guy suggested it,
they did it.
And it also just seemed like another one
of those things they could borrow from
drug and rehab clinics that apparently
do this sometimes if somebody's using
drugs and maybe my dye and needs to
be scared straight. I don't know.
When we were chastised for our rules,
which we were and I was and I have been,
I know, I understand that now,
but we were chastised for it and we
would internally say we are not doing
anything different than the
local successful drug rehab.
John says he knew that some of these
techniques were confrontational and maybe
even traumatic.
But at the time I believed at the time
that a temporary pain to rid your life of
the horror of homosexuality is worth it.
It gets me upset thinking
about it too. Just
how crazy some of us scout there.
This is Peterson disco again.
This is actually him in a film
made by a director, Morgan Fox,
who was nice enough to
let us use the footage.
One of my closest friends there
attempted suicide and, um,
I found his truck at the end of the
driveway with all these photographs of his
children. And he had, um, this note, yeah,
this, he had this note at just
about what a horrible person he was.
And he gave up,
you know, that he's such a bad person.
And he took all these pills and
went off to the fields to die.
Peterson told me he knows that at
least five students from Levin Action,
who at one point either in the program
or afterwards attempted suicide,
smit himself offered a story of going
with a colleague to a Christian conference
in California looking on the wall,
seeing a plaque with a
name of a former student.
This room dedicated in the memory
of David Bilberry bilberry king.
I said, Alan, what happened? He says,
he committed suicide five years ago.
I asked John about a letter
that he wrote in 2010 where he,
I know this is jumping forward just a bit,
but where he ultimately apologizes
for everything he's done.
And below that written
apology. A commenter said,
I don't accept your apology.
And then they listed a series
of names. Aiden Schaffer.
17 committed suicide dominant crouch
15 jumped to his death from a six story
building. Billy Lucas 15 hung
himself in his family's farm.
Asher brown 13 shot himself
with his father's gun.
Seth Walsh hanged himself from a tree
in his backyard. Didn't die immediately.
He was taken to a hospital or he's placed
on life support. Died nine days later,
Jeanine blend shit. 21 pills.
Terrelle Williams 17 hung himself
in his bedroom closet and on and on.
And on about 20 suicides. Now, not
all of them happened at Levin. Action.
What do you,
how do you hold that? How do you,
the only thing I could say to
that is in, in all honesty,
in some levels of this process,
I have to use some denial.
I have to, and I don't mean
denial, it didn't happen.
Denial of my feelings. Um,
there have been many times through life
experience where I have perceived if I
truly felt everything that
there is in there, I would die.
Okay.
And I also,
I also have to release people to
their own process and I cannot take
responsibility for their process.
I can't,
all I can do is acknowledge
and release the rest.
John, Dan told me something
that could sound defensive,
but actually I think is a truth
that needs to be acknowledged.
The idea that he, yeah.
With
selling it love and action or
perhaps that he bought into,
ultimately it goes way beyond him.
The sources of all that shame are
as much the families of those kids,
the peer groups, the schools where they
went to this. Certainly the churches,
the society at large that creates the
conditions for love and action to exist.
He says he cannot take
responsibility for all that.
And I think that's right.
This is an album that, um,
the guys in the program actually made for
me and it has pictures with statements
from each one of those clients.
While we were there, John showed us, uh,
a kind of yearbook of the love in
action class of 1993. These are,
these are students or,
yeah. Oh Wow. [inaudible]
okay.
First picture was a kid who's
maybe 18, Husky thick black hair.
This guy here, you know,
you've been an inspiration to me
from the first year I met you.
I've learned from you that you have to
face life and death and then go through
it. You're a good leader and a shepherd
and I'm so grateful to the Lord for you.
I love you.
And this is a guy that today is
married to his husband and uh,
and we are in contact regularly and,
and it's a very affirming
and positive relationship.
Okay.
This man I was in contact
with tall, thin, blonde hair,
but this is one of the, one of the
circumstances where this man, uh, uh,
he died of a drug overdose,
um, about two years ago.
They didn't believe it was
a suicide. Um, but he, uh,
he's no longer with us.
Yeah.
This Si. Um, here's one,
this guy, he says, Smitty.
They called me Smitty back then.
So much of my heart has gone into
preparing this keepsake for you.
Each time you look upon it,
may, you know my love for you.
He looks like early twenties, tall, thin.
Adam's apple kind of bushy black
hair. [inaudible] big smile.
I've had conversations with him. He, um,
he doesn't completely accept
necessarily where I am today.
Um, but he's very, uh, warm and friendly.
He doesn't accept where you are.
He doesn't completely embrace
someone being gay and being married.
So he's not openly gay is open.
Again, he talks about being gay,
but he's married to a
woman and he has a family.
I have not had communication with him. Uh,
I have had communication with him,
all American guy, freckles. Um,
but he actually continued working
for a very anti gay organization and,
uh, it got to the point where
I just was just in turmoil
when I would see things who would post
on Facebook or things he would say.
And so I really chose to kind
of not be affected by that.
Okay.
This is a guy, um, sandy
hair, radiant smile.
He was a guy who was HIV positive
when he came in the program. And, uh,
three years later he
died. Um, in California,
there were people that were in our program
or in our support group ministry in
California. The years I was there.
22 of those people died from HIV.
Are you in touch with all these people?
I have had communication with him, yes.
Him, yes. Yes. Actually,
in the last five years since he's
been high and dry of love and action,
John says he has made it his mission to
reach out to everyone he can to try and
engage with them, support them
if they want to be supported,
make amends if that's
what they want for him.
His sort of clean break
really began in 2005 June 6th,
2005 we moved in and
that was our first day.
They just upgraded their headquarters
a second time, hired more staff due.
We had just started a new group
of teenagers. Everybody was there.
We were excited. Eight 30 in the morning,
our office manager came running
in my office and said, John,
there are protesters outside.
I was hoping for
[inaudible].
Oh my gosh. What has happened?
How did they know?
This is when the torpedo struck.
A young kid in the program named Zach
had posted a message to my space saying
his parents had put him in this
straight camp. It was like a boot camp.
He wasn't sure he's going to make
it. News cameras started showing,
well her swat the demonstrates today,
say they basically are here today to
show their support for those who are
enrolled in the love and action
program. We're going to pan over.
Bullhorns came out and
all of a sudden I heard
John Smith, we know you're in John Smith.
We know you're here. Hey,
Ryan's after this door raising their
voices in front of loving actions,
new recovery treatments
in our, in Raleigh.
I mean they were there in
the morning and the night
from the protest. I started
entering into an absolute days,
just just a cloud. I don't even know.
The protest lasted for eight solid weeks.
International media started coming in.
There's so much attention that the state
of Tennessee actually started cracking
down performing inspections. John
Smith ends up counter suing the state.
I was so desperate to make this
work, and he says, now looking
back, what's amazing is how
long it took him to wake up.
How all throughout his mind would
contort itself to push away down.
I would drive through the protest
and I remember them saying, we love you.
We love you to me. He says, amazingly,
he interpreted that in
that moment as God's
speaking to him.
I know you're here and I knew you were
here and I didn't want you to hide.
I wanted to celebrate you being here
and I did it through these protestors.
That's the way I interpreted it.
Wow. This some mental gymnastics.
Yes it is.
So the honest truth is what brought John
into the light or what needed to happen
before he can be able to see the light
is that as organization collapsed,
the protestors created
division and his staff,
one of his managers tried to force
him out. He didn't know what to do.
Eventually he resigns
and so when I resigned,
I sat in my newly designed
Home Office and I said,
God, I have no idea what you have
in store for me. For the future.
Surprised me from that
point forward. He says,
it was like slowly sobering up after
you've been drunk for 25 years.
This time it wasn't a violent shift.
It was a series of tiny micro steps.
Like one day he's sitting in his computer
and decides to click on gay porn for
the first time in his life. Immediately
feel horrible, wracked with shame,
decides he's got to go tell his wife
who he was still married to at the time,
by the way. But then he thinks, no,
I'm not going to tell her we're short.
While after that he's at a
Christian conference and he
announces to the audience
that he, John Smith, the Elvis of the
ex gay movement was in fact not cured.
I vocally said, I'm a gay man.
I'm a gay man and I'm in a
mixed orientation. Marriage.
Mixed orientation by the way means a
marriage between a homosexual and a
heterosexual. So a term you sometimes
hear in this world. Um, but that process,
that slow, gradual awakening,
John says it is still happening.
Yes. And the whole creative
component in the car.
He told us even about the shoes he was
wearing it. Oh, that brought it up.
I have bright blue tennis shoes on
today. I bought those a month ago.
I, I love bright colors. I've
always loved bright colors.
I stood in the store for 20
minutes looking at gray or
turquoise blue shoes that
were identical and I made the
decision, the conscious decision,
and I feel very emotional about this,
crazy about blue tennis shoes, but I'm,
I hadn't to make the decision to buy
the blue tennis shoes because I love
turquoise blue and it's that, it's,
it's still, I'm still coming out.
I'm still having to open myself
up to the reality of who I am,
of who I was wired to be from
the moment I was born. It just,
there's this constant battle
within me to deny, to push away,
to surgically cut off a major of who I am.
And so even though I was a, I was
an ex gay leader and one of the,
one of the instruments of abuse,
I'm also per a person who was subjected
to ex gay ministry for 25 years.
And so I have the same kinds of
anger in the same kinds of wounds,
the same kind of pain and that
complicatedness about John Smith that
he is both the instrument of abuse and
also a subject himself of that same abuse.
It might color how you see
the final chapter in his
journey from straight to gay
to excavate to ex ex gay. But
it has to do with this guy
about, uh,
eight miles west of this place
community called Maxi, Texas.
Okay.
This is Larry McQueen, John's husband.
He works in the Engineering Department
of a company that manufacturers pipes for
oil rigs. Third Generation Pentecostal
comes from a very religious family.
And so before he and John
connected about five years ago,
he had never been with a man. He tried
dating women. It didn't work new.
He was attracted to men.
Push those thoughts away.
Up to that point. I
had lived my life along
and [inaudible].
In fact,
I had come to the point where I was
crying myself to sleep because I was so
lonely. And that's what
actually led me to say, look,
Larry, you know, you're 40
something years old, you're lonely.
I don't think God really wants
me to be this way any longer.
The first night that they were together,
which initially wasn't romantic,
it was,
they had gotten together as friends
to do some home improvement projects.
I don't know if I want to
talk about this. Well, no.
It's like, well, okay. So, so I walked,
we went out to dinner and
came back and we just,
we just really had a,
a comfortable time and Larry came to a,
an amazing awareness
at that point. He said,
you know what I'm feeling with you,
really confirms to me that I'm
gay. And he said, and by the way,
we're sleeping in separate beds. Next
morning, Larry walks into John's room,
lays down beside him on the
bed, puts his arm around him.
He just put his arms around
me and I was reading an email.
He had his arms around me and I just
started to sob uncontrollably. You know,
I had never in my life ever
cried with another human being
and for me it was like almost a physical
sensation inside me that as if there
were cogs that never were
quite aligned properly.
But that weekend I felt within my body,
these cogs coming into place and clicking
and I felt whole for the first time
I was Larry's first kiss?
Yes. Wow. At 52 years old
[inaudible]
a few months after that weekend, John
got a divorce from his second wife,
baleen.
John and Larry got married in 2014 and
these days they sing in their church
choir.
They're the only openly gay couple in
their church and they continue to nudge
the church very gently to take a
stand in support of gay marriage.
At the end of the day,
it's still difficult to know how to
reconcile John Smith's past with his
present, whether he's taking enough
responsibility for his actions or not.
We spoke to people who are all over the
map on that question. John would say,
however you feel the lesson from his life
is that very simply people can change.
Humans are teachable. The
human mind is infinite.
[inaudible]
Robert, I want to just offer
one side note to the story. Um,
in the time that we were
working on this series,
like something like four states,
uh, I may have that number wrong,
outlawed conversion therapy from minors.
And if you look to start more
broadly in the last few years,
there's been this wave of legislation
that's trying to stamp this out. Really?
Yeah. On what theory is
it's cruel. I mean that a,
especially when you're talking
about offering it to minors.
So I think something like 37
municipalities in the last few years have,
have outlawed conversion
therapy for minors.
And at the same time you have a lot of
debate about the sort of expanding idea
of religious freedom. Yeah.
That protection that's written
into the first amendment.
And a lot of these groups are arguing
successfully at times that they have the
constitutional right to
offer these programs.
So it's a really interesting
and confusing moment right now.
[inaudible]
this episode of Radiolab.
It's drawn from unraced,
the a untold history of
conversion therapy in America,
a series that I worked
on with focus features,
stitcher and liminality in conjunction
with a feature film boy erased.
Huge thanks to the production team.
She, Molly Ikat, Aaron, Alice Quinlan,
Michael Assessor, David Craig, Garrett,
calmly to anonymous content
for their support of unraced.
If you want to hear the entire
series, I hope you will.
You can find unraced in all
the usual podcast places.
Okay, well, I guess we should go.
Yes, let's go. We can whiz it. Gone.
We can leave it now. Bye.