And then go, Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich, Radiolab.
And today it's inheritance today. Yeah.
We're exploring questions of like, uh,
what can you pass down to your
kids in their kids? What can't you,
how much of you will echo into the
future and how much of you won't?
And I gotta say, I'm feeling pretty good
about this show so far because, well,
if, uh, if, if a mother,
a little IRAP mother licking her
baby can have such a profound effect,
basically change the expression of the
genes in the baby. Well that's you.
You think you can get deep down. Look,
in the end, what do I know? But, uh,
I take it that we have more control over
our destinies and our kids' destinies.
And we would have thought, well, let's
not get too excited too fast because, uh,
well we, we, we have a story
to tell. And this, this one,
this tale leaves me a little
queasy. Oh, there was a contact.
Hello? Hello. Yup, it's me. Oh, lamb.
This is Oola. Hi Libby. You get in.
I'm in public health,
the Karolinska Institute in Sweden
where he studies population data,
looking for patterns in cardiovascular
diseases, high blood pressure and such.
But the story he told us
begins around 25 years ago,
way up in northern Sweden
that Sam keen again,
he's the guy who told us about Auden's
work in our little community called over
colleagues. What does it look like?
Is it a big town, a little village?
It's a small forest area. Very beautiful.
But this was a really, really
tough history. Grow Up.
Very isolated and very cold.
Are you near the Arctic circle or north
of it? North of the Arctic Circle. Yeah.
My home village was 10 miles
north of popular. The goes, oh,
so you grew up in uh, over Kaylee's.
Yeah, we had a, an expression here.
Dig where you stand
and it just so happened is this
town is a perfect place today. Okay.
I'm here.
They are the kingdom archive
because there is more data,
more information about the people of
overkill going farther back into the past
and you can find almost anywhere else
on earth. Yeah. We a really data rich.
This is the Uber Colleagues
Church parish. Yes, it is.
Because he used to think the churches up
and over calyx kept incredibly detailed
records.
We actually sent our friend
Pike Malinowski to the
archives and Stockholm to
check it out. Says like Easter Register.
In those books you can meet everything
about the citizens of over calyx going
back hundreds of years. What's
his name? Even their names? Yes.
[inaudible] what year they were born?
1814 1881 she was born 1904 and this is
everything happening in the family is in
these books. Nielsen, who was an
idiot? He was an idiot. It's, sorry,
what? What does that mean? He was
an idiot, I guess. Yeah, he was,
you know retarded,
right? Yeah. He or landing
at score that he was this.
He was miserable to look at. It's
not very politically correct.
No.
In any case, these books tell you
when each of these folks died,
how they died from disease.
She's from a pneumonia accident.
She drowned. Oh my God.
A lot of diagnosis actually
influence cancer, heart disease,
brain disease.
Interestingly, the church has also
kept track of the farmers. Crows crops,
livestock, how much they
were growing each year,
which turned out to be kind
of an interesting thing
to look out because every
time the people in over calyx who were
farming trying to eco living out of the
soil, we have um, how
much they harvest it.
They would experience these wild
changes from harvest to harvest.
What you see in the records
is that one year potatoes,
crops that do great a hundred teachers.
Wow, that's a lot of potatoes.
A few years later there'd
be a harsh winter.
The crops failed and when the
crops failed, famines, yeah,
they basically start, I mean
when you look at the records,
you don't see huge spikes in mortality.
So it didn't starve to death.
They suddenly had to get by on a tiny
fraction of the food that they were used
to.
I didn't have grains. I
mean they didn't tell the of
and so they just had to hold
on for the entire winter.
But then a few years would
pass crops would bounce back.
Would we have a lot more grain
here and suddenly plenty of food.
I could eat twice, three
times as much, then oh no.
Total crop failure, famine. Again,
these changes would just
bounce back and forth. Famine,
feast,
Salmon East again,
and looking at these swings and Fortune
Oola realized what he had here was a
nice natural experiment
because with all this data,
he and his team could follow families
forward in time through the generations.
So if they saw somebody who was starving
as a kid in 1820 they couldn't see well
when those people had children and
grandchildren, did anything change?
Were there any consequences?
They wanted to see basically the effects
of starvation on multiple generations.
What did you discover?
Well, it,
it was some very interesting discovery.
That's a little odd actually.
Here's what [inaudible] says. He,
he found in the data,
if you were a boy in over [inaudible]
between the ages of nine and 12 years old,
so that's the window,
nine to 12 year old boy.
And then we have one of those terribly
rough winters and you're eating much less
than normal,
assuming that you can survive the ordeal
and you grow up and you have kids of
your own.
The data seems to say that your kids
will benefit from your suffering.
Yeah, yeah.
They'll do better if you
have a starving daddy.
It turns out that the baby actually
gets some sort of health benefit really.
And these effects in fact were so
strong that you could trace it to the
grandfather, the
grandfather, two generations.
It seemed to have been passed
down from multiple generations.
You mean if you had a
starving grandfather,
you would be a healthier
grant boy for the,
because you had a starving grandfather,
you got a health boost. If you
had a starving grandfather,
what, what sort of health boost? Well,
um, well they told us take heart disease,
vascular disease.
You said if you were a boy and you
starved between the ages of nine and 12,
and then you went on to become
a father, then a grandfather,
your grandkids were protected.
Meaning that they had less incidents of
heart disease, much less. How much less?
Well, it's um, one fourth then can we say
one fourth? Let me say this again.
If you're a starving boy between
nine to 12 years old now,
it doesn't matter a whole lot.
What happens to you after this?
Your grandchildren will have one quarter
of the risk of heart disease and if you
eating a whole lot between
nine and 12 one quarter.
Not only that, apparently those
grandkids were less prone to diabetes.
They lived longer lives. Something
like 30 years on average.
This was [inaudible] the Alere instead
of dying at 40 I'd live to 70 that kind
of 30 years. Yes, exactly.
I just don't, I wonder.
It's such a surprising result. I
wonder how much you believe in it.
Yeah, it sound saw that it's only
a, the mechanisms are not so clear,
but the results are very clear.
The results are obvious to you.
[inaudible] the results are quite obvious.
Just to be sure. We asked Francis
Champagne, which she thinks of this data.
I believe that. Well you do,
and I'm Michael Meaney as well.
I think the Swedish data are really,
really strong and very reliable.
Everybody we talked to seems to think
there's something really interesting going
on here, but what exactly. Maybe
you can explain this to me, Robert.
What exactly happens between nine to
12 that makes this big difference? Wow.
So here's the thing. How
old are your boys right now?
Three and eight months. Okay. So
here's what you're going to notice.
Your boys will first grow taller
and taller for the next few years,
and when they get to be
about nine, 10 years old,
they're gonna stop growing
just for a few years.
This is what's called
d slow growth period.
Just for those years. That's
nine 10, 11 just before puberty,
they won't grow much on the
outside, but on the inside,
that is the time when the
sperms, while developing
what's happening during this time is
that you're setting aside the stock of
cells that you're going to draw on
in the future to make sperm cells.
So they are sperms. So the thought
is when those little boys in over
KLX were really, really hungry,
their hunger started a chemical process
that reached all the way down to the
DNA. Inside the boys' spurn.
Something happens on the molecular
level. What exactly? Well,
uh, the DNA, the RNA
micro RNA is a histone.
Anyway, that's it that
you're just renaming
methylations phosphorylation
and so on that just judo,
that's all this is.
We don't know precisely how this happens,
but somehow the experience
of starvation marks the DNA.
Maybe like those methyl things we were
telling you about with the rats. Yeah.
Telling some genes to turn off
now or the genes to turn on.
And the incredible thing is
those marks stick around.
This sperm carries these marks to the
next generation and then the next one
after that, right.
[inaudible]
so somehow by some kind
of chemical mechanisms,
starving grandpa back when he was about
nine to 12 years old turned out to be a
good thing. So it's like, um,
[inaudible]
GRANDPA's struggle is sort of jumping
forward and giving me a leg up.
Well that's the good news.
But unfortunately there's um,
there is some bad news here. Yeah.
If your grandpa didn't starve,
instead he lived through great times.
He stuffed himself silly nine, 10,
11 years old. So he's a happy
grandpa. You the grandson, you then
would have high frequency.
So heart attacks as two
diabetes, it was, uh,
a fourfold risk.
Four, four, four, 400%
greater. Yeah. I got to say,
this is spooky. This is spooky
because it's like, it does get, yeah.
I mean it's like what if GRANDPA has a
bad day? Suddenly you're marked. Yeah.
Frankly, this makes being
nine, 10, 11, 12 like a,
a rather crucial and at a time and you're
not making the best decisions anyway.
Yeah. Cause GRANDPA's just
nine. I should add to that.
They have found very similar
effects for smoking. For instance,
if you start smoking when your, you
know, 10, 11, something like that,
you end up heading children
with more problems. I,
I initially felt very hopeful and excited
about this research because it seems
to suggest that a,
that a body one body can respond to an
environment and change and be flexible in
a way we didn't think was possible.
But this stuff you're telling
me about Sweden feels very, um,
grim in a certain way. Oh, you know,
sometimes that your grandfather's
suffering helps you, even if it helps.
It's horrifying. Claim
makes me claustrophobic.
You feel kind of hemmed in by what your
grandfather did? A little bit, I guess.
I guess the way I would I
would look at it is that, um,
you can change your environment a lot
more easily than you can change your
genes.
[inaudible]
I think it's, is, what's
weird here is that,
is that we started trying to make a
difference in our children and now we're
surprised attacked by our GRANDPA.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do though.
When a meal gets to be eight, I'm
cutting him off. He's not eating it all.
This may hurt you, my son, but
I'm doing it for my grandchildren.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
thanks to [inaudible] reporter Pike Mellon
off ski and Cardin Berquist young and
I'm a senior archivist at a the
national archive in Maria. Bye.