You are listening to
radio lab, radiolab from
W and y.
S. E. N. N. P. R.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Gilbert. This is radio lab,
the podcast pod cast zo today where
you're going to do something a little
different on the podcast.
We're going to present a story
that you and I ran into uh,
in Chicago and Chicago coast
audio cause he won an award,
this story and it's just
quite wonderful. Really cool.
This is about soccer and it happened
to remind us about a show that we're
putting together for the spring on
the topic of symmetry, chemistry,
symmetry submits, symmetry here,
partying, symmetry, all different kinds.
And by the way, but that's later. Yeah.
Oh well I'm sorry you were
about to say the cool part.
It turns out that we get to do this
show not only on the radio but in three
fabulous cities in the United States of
live. Yeah, we have shows in New York.
Unfortunately that one's sold out,
but we will be in La March 23rd and
Seattle March 30th and it's going to be
really fun and it'll be about symmetry,
which takes us back to our
subject soccer, which uh,
at least appears quite symmetrical. Yeah,
you got two teams and people on each
size, right? You got two coaches,
two sets of fans yield. However,
there are two people on that field,
the goalkeepers on either side who are
living in a very different psychological
universe from the rest of the
athletes. And that's the subject,
the loneliness of the goalkeeper. And
the reporter is hardly obscene coli.
Who is, um, well frizzle he was in his
earlier life, a goalkeeper himself.
He's a book author and regular presenter
on the BBC and he's talking to a guy
named Bob Wilson who's goalkeeper for a
very famous British soccer team arsenal
that's right in the sixties and
seventies that's the golden age.
And the piece begins with the following
question. What is it about goalkeepers?
All they agreed upon that they only
individual in what is a team game.
In other words,
the other 10 guys can make
numerous mistakes in a game.
Even the star striker,
he can miss five, six,
eight chances in a game and scored a
winning goal in the 89th minute of a match
and he goes home. The hero on the
reverse situation that is the goalkeeper,
this lonely individual,
the only one who's allowed to use his
hands with the purpose of negating the
game with the whole purpose of a game of
football is to score goals and the one
villain in the piece is the
bloke between the stakes,
the goalie and all the other 10 guys
around. You understand that as well.
They do sing. You're crazy.
You're putting yourself in this
position where for 89 minutes you do the
reverse.
You play brilliantly and in the 90th
minute you make a positional era.
All the ball moves swerves and dips
and it looks as if it's your fault.
I've got this image of goalkeepers
mostly because I was that goalkeeper that
lapse for that high ball only to see
the ball go into the back of the net and
that that moment. Can you
explain to me that moment
Bob,
when the rest of the team are walking
back to the halfway line as you're picking
the ball up of the net,
you're alone. I mean,
I can give you a very,
very good example of it playing in an
FAA Cup final and five days earlier we've
gone to White Hart Lane and we've become
champions of England until we've got an
opportunity to become an an as a second
club that center you to win the double.
So we go, we're playing Liverpool,
everything to play for in the 1971 cup
final and I've had the best season I've
ever had in my career and there's suddenly
Steve Highway cuts in from the left
wing. I've probably got it
wrong by a yard and a half.
Are we on the edge of the box?
But
he strikes the goal and it flew in the
back of the net one nil down the doubles
out the window and Bob Wilson is suddenly
the guy who is likely to cost arsenal
that does Dave highway next
it one mill politically.
And as I spun around on my pants on
the, on the floor, Frank McClintock,
a captain put his hands on his
hips and actually moused use
[inaudible].
It didn't cost us Charlie
George one is the devil.
I finished out being asked and was
player of the year in the double season.
Fantastic. But to my dying day, when
people meet me and they say, Oh,
what did you do with Steve Highway? Then
Hey, he's always comes up. Not The
million good safes on my to mate.
It's all those about, oh, you got
your Neopost wrong, didn't you?
Now here's a challenge
that I've never understood.
If you're a goalkeeper in a
team that isn't very good,
you're constantly vigilant. The bull's
always coming at you. If, however,
you're Bob Wilson playing behind 10 of
the best players in the world at that
time, for 89 minutes of a 90 minute game,
you don't have a great deal to
do. How do you stay focused?
See,
do you remember the bionic man when the
ball was at the other end of the field?
I imagined that the guy on the
ball, the opponent was Steve Austin,
so he could turn around any part of the
pitch, 60 yards away, 70 yards away,
110 yards away and strike
a ball towards my goal.
Fantastic. Say Bye to Michael
[inaudible] Cross. Here's the chance.
Oh my score doesn't brilliant.
Say by Basso tips in try age again.
Great Save for the crucial
money is for the post.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
I said challenge
[inaudible].
Here we go. Sunday morning,
south coast of England,
Brighton and in the background you can
hear some under sixteens 22 of them
chasing a ball around a patch.
Well actually technically
speaking it's 20 of them.
There's two goalkeepers either side on
their own with no one to talk to the game
to watch the backs of their colleagues
and their face of that opposition.
Almost poetic. Lets me getting
carried away with myself. Mom.
We'll cross the road. I'm here.
I meet a man called gem wall who is an
actor. That was a good, we tackle that.
Sorry. Slightly put off
by great. We tackle now,
Jim is acting in a Peter Flannery
play called the boy's own story,
which is all about a goalkeeper.
All right? So we've just kicked off
then we just kicked off, but we're,
we're about 10 minutes in
the Preston Panthers go down,
I'm afraid was that the goalkeeping
era was not goalkeeping era.
I'm a fully paid up member
of the goalkeepers union.
So I think even if had
gone through his hands,
I wouldn't have said it's
to keep his foot. Uh,
now it was a very good long range to
them where I'd show up and a very good
midfield pass. So don't lean to the cruel
rope and see that. Go keep her there.
Yeah. Is that all keeper
her or that Chemo there?
Keith and I keep as the quality looking
keeper with the yellow top or a gloves.
See their key.
But that's exactly what I
looked like when I was a boy.
I don't mean to be cruel.
How would those drive in those
slightly lardy slightly Lartey
I don't play and go, but I coached
the goalkeepers down there. Um,
but I have to say when, when I was a kid,
the idea of going and go
just baffled me. I thought,
why would you want to go there
and go? I've never known,
I've always been fascinated by
the kids who want to come and go.
But later on in my life,
when I became an actor,
I ended up doing a play
about a goalkeeper. So I've
got to meet goalkeepers. Uh,
I even did two days training down here
with Brighton and hove Albion and no, no,
no, no
sacco. Yeah, sorry. That's to nail to
the other team. Look at the cute guy.
He's looking skyward and he won't pick
the book. It will put the ball up.
It's gone actually through the next.
Nobody that should have been cleared.
The cross should never have commended
the goalkeeper got the blame for that.
Yeah. I think I'll keep scout a rough
deal. I mean, when we've been doing,
during the play, it was very simple
set. It was simply goalpost and net.
Okay. It's a full size and set in
the penalty area of John Mckenna,
the greatest goalkeeper
never to play for England.
So he's asking for the
bull talking, you know,
as far as goalkeepers are
supposed to do to keep this,
keep themselves mentally alert. And
the thing is he never gets the ball.
They hate him, the team hating and
they will never pass through it.
Good tackle Dave layoff.
Dave, come on Dave.
If you need me or I don't
know I apply. Dave. What?
I mean, I'd rather do without
me. I'm the last line of defense.
When I'm called into the game.
It means they failed and they
don't like that there. Your lights,
of course, they're glad to
have me here just in case.
Glad it's me throwing myself about glad
it's my head that goes in when the boots
are flying, but they do without
me. If they could wouldn't, yeah,
the object of their
game is to school goals.
The objective of mine is to stop
them. I made a spoil their game.
I can't win again. I can only lose it.
So how can I be one of them?
Not that I want to be one of them when
to them I'm just a necessary evil.
Go a kid, have it shot. Let one
go. No, no, no, don't tackle it.
I could have saved that.
Well, what Greg saved the
boat, tipped it up in the air,
but not enough to put it over the bar
and came down behind him and as he went
for it,
so he was charged by center Ford
Lofthouse into the net goal as well.
I was a young goalkeeper. I played the
St John's primary school in seminars,
poet and keeper, Marie Lachlan, young
keeper in the loosest sense of the word.
We played a local big teams, sort
of Manchester United of the area,
which was Amhurst school and
I think they beat a 17 nil.
The scoring of which goal broke
the young Marie, Lachlan Young.
I think it was probably
about five or six nil.
When I realized that there was probably
only about 10 minutes of the game gone,
the team had gone from being
encouraging to looking the other way.
How long did it take you
before you went back and goal?
I think about 32 years.
It may just be a coincidence that you
are a poet and a writer and a performer.
Do you think there is a commonality in
that experience of the creative for maybe
for people who think they're
a bit special, perhaps.
Perhaps it's things to be the ideal
place because as a striker you may can
always be partnered with another striker,
but there is only one goalkeeper and he
gets to wear a different strip than the
rest of the team and has his
own universe too to operate in
[inaudible]
that full nails, full nail,
that's not even half time we
have gotten taken apart here.
I wonder how much of his confidence
has gone or not. I better not.
I lucky lights, heads up character
both hours, other states by or
headed the ball back to the Polish,
go keep up. He goes, Jen,
pick it up. Extraordinary
and I think of how I used to feel
when I let a golden ridiculous,
that feeling of letting everybody down,
oh,
I save the Chive is let it go right
through his body and into the back of the
net that is in a pooling
gold BB in his face.
I used to go home after a match, a city,
and literally shed tears over a goal.
I'd lay him blaming myself for the one
that beat us over and over and over in my
head. Why didn't I go for the, why didn't
I see him coming in on the back stick?
Where was my cover? Yeah.
Where was my cover? Oh,
what's the fullback sitting
at home crying his eyes out.
[inaudible]
hello. Paul Robinson.
England goalkeeper was undone
when a back pass came towards him.
He aimed to kick at it, missed
the ball, went into the goal.
It wasn't his fault, the
ball bobbled. It was a go.
It was looked comic and looked like
Robinson sport. He knows it wasn't,
and yet it still destroyed him. Chief
sportswriter of the Times, Simon Barnes,
another writer, another man.
He spends his time alone hoping to
make a mark on the world and yes,
another former goalkeeper.
We're everywhere. Let's see,
I think I'm developing a theory here and
Simon's got a role call of loners and
Mavericks to support it.
Yes, the renascence goalkeepers,
it's a fine list and it begins with
Alabama [inaudible] author of the outsider
or go Coupa is by definition a tone Jay.
But Kennedy famously said that all that
I know most surely about morality in the
obligations of Man I know from sport.
Others include who you
Yglesias. Uh, Che Guevara.
Che Guevara was a, a goalkeeper out of
necessity because he loved football.
But uh, he had asthma so he would
couldn't cut it as an outfielder. The A,
the late Pope John Paul, the second was a,
also a goalkeeper and Laddie Amir
Nabokov who liked to be seen as sublimely
different from the crowd. And
this was well Vladimir Nabokov,
a goalkeeper and occasional novelists
wrote about the higher of his two aunts.
As with folded arms, I lent
against the left goalposts.
I enjoyed the luxury of closing my eyes
and thus I would listen to my heart
knocking and feel the blind drizzle
on my face and hear in the distance,
the broken sounds of the game.
And think of myself as other
fabulous exotic. Being in an English.
Football is disguise.
Composing my verse in a tongue.
Nobody understood about a remote country.
Nobody knew small wander. I was
not very popular with my teammates.
I think that's a beautiful
moment of serenity that only
a goalkeeper can know in
the middle of a game of football.
In the bustle of it all,
you have time to yourself,
time to reflect time which many
goalkeepers eventually used to destroy
themselves to suddenly to
destroy their sporting nerve.
Now that comment by Simon Che Guevara
pleading goal because of the severe
childhood asthma.
Now I've done a bit of research on that
list of Renee small school is and do you
know Albert Camou developed
TB as a youngster? Yes.
Vladimir Nabokov nearly died of pneumonia
as a child and then was traumatized by
having a flea revolutionary Russia,
Pope John Paul the second
mother died when he was nine.
Brother three years later makes you think
there is a sense in which, uh,
choosing to play goalkeeper does show.
I'm understanding that one is not as
other people and certainly a grief and
trauma can do that.
Particularly in children.
You may accept that your
position is to be, um,
not to the same as the rest.
And what I consider proof
from the BBC archives,
childhood goalkeeper and solar
violinist, emphasis on the word Solo.
Itzhak Perlman, four years old,
polio. I did football,
I was goalie because I worked with
crutches so I could stop bowls a little
easier than you know, I stuck
with my feet with my crutches.
The say that again. And
this time you gotten
terrific one say just
painted over the crossbar.
He just fit like a dog of a bow.
That and just deflected that one.
It was very hard for the top,
gone to that all the way and it
was a novelty side by side glove
that was a grand and shot in the grand say
when I see a great goal, it seems
to me an incomplete experience.
You should have a great shot
followed by a great save to be a,
a fully complete and rounded experience.
I don't expect people to
understand that. In fact,
I hope people don't understand it.
Being misunderstood is part of
the goalkeeper stocking tray.
You wouldn't be a goalkeeper unless
you wanted to be misunderstood.
How can I not be obsessed
with failure if I succeed?
What have I done? What
have I created? Nothing.
Even the poorest goals go into the
record books. Great saves or forgotten.
This could be a [inaudible]
eternal optimism.
You half the time does get somewhere near
the 18 year old box and Jim's thinking
it could be a goal for Nyla half time.
What's up? Yes, he's in tears.
Preston pump, this keepers in tears,
poor lot gloves are off.
He's crying. Poor boys crying.
It's under sixteens football on a
Sunday morning to go down to you.
Can you hear that?
I tell you what it is the great
goalkeepers when all else fails,
those guys in front of you,
those 10 guys need to look round
and say the goalie will savers.
Now that's the difference.
Once you acquire greatness,
true greatness and very few
goalkeepers really acquire that,
that aura about them and one
of the greatest love sprays.
Wait, say the bias. Great, brilliant.
That's great. I mean this
just about sums it up.
It doesn't matter that he kept hundreds
of clean sheets to get the cup and
championship successes.
Never mind that you saved the blushes of
countless dodgy defenders and there are
plenty of dodgy defenders. The
thing that defines Gary Sprague,
the loneliest of all
lonely keepers is the goal.
He scored against himself in
1967 and he's not even Scottish.
Gone Sell Gary Son,
we were playing live at the one day in
three minutes before half time costumer
cross. I caught the ball ketocal booze
on left wing, he shouted to throw at him.
Jessica was going to throw it to him
and they seen Ian Collagen run to him.
So I changed my mind. I've
done it millions of times,
just brought the ball back to my chest.
But on this occasion I miss my chest and
went all my Shorelan and right in front
of the cop and gestures walking off
the dgs says, we dedicated this racket.
The Getty guys are calling. It just
made this record. Keller sentence
[inaudible] too. Okay. Yes. The return
[inaudible] stony in the shop and
Robertson spelter it for goodness sake.
Preciado shopper and Carlson.
That's the second half of that to start.
And that's, um, the best pandas keeper.
Walking back to his goal alone, alone,
and four girls down. Do you know what
I wish you could say to you that
I didn't know how that felt.
I know how that feels. I remember
now why I stopped being a goalkeeper.
Okay.
[inaudible]
killed
his hands from the Elvis Presley.
Do you think he was a goalie?
He had to have been a goalie. No one
could have captured the tenderness,
the loss and the shame as well
as Al Shaman his music. Yeah.
He could have been forged between
those two goalposts. Oh wait.
I am now being told that
was not Elvis. Okay.
For getting thanks to producer
Adam Valor and, uh, the, uh,
the presenter of that
piece, Hardeep Singh coli,
and it was a lad Brooke radio production.
It was originally broadcast on
BBC radio four. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich. We hope
to see it, those live shows,
or at least at the next podcast.