Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is radio lab,
and today we've been investigating
the truth, the fact of the matter,
and this next segment to set it up.
I guess all I really want to say is it
sometimes getting to the fact of the
matter, a fact of the matter,
the way Arrow just did.
That can be tricky. Yeah.
You end up finding things that you didn't
expect that are way more complicated
than you expected. The story
begins with our producer,
Pat Walters started for him when he
was talking with an ex CIA agent.
So maybe you've taken me to,
was this the summer of 1981?
Okay. In the summer of 1981,
I was being transferred from a
one overseas post to another.
This is a mural [inaudible]
and I'm a retired CIA officer.
But in 1981 Merle was still at the CIA
and he was posted out in the sticks out
and in the Boonies, somewhere in
Southeast Asia. And, and, and why,
why were you [inaudible]? Yeah, I had,
I had a little disagreement with my, uh,
previous chief and I ended
up in, uh, in this remote,
a jungle backwater, I guess
is the best way to phrase it.
Can you say what country
you in? Um, I'd rather not.
Oh.
In any case, as much as Merle
did not want to be there,
it turned out that this little backwater
was ground zero for what was about to
become one of the strangest
stories of the Cold War.
Just to set the scene.
The story happens in Laos,
which is that kind of narrow country
between Vietnam and Thailand.
The time is a few years after the
Vietnam War, right after the war,
U s army left pulled out all of
our troops and once we were gone,
the communists basically
took over the region,
the communist being the Vietcong
and their allies and Laos,
the path at Lao group,
outdoor Lucia Chateau,
gee, it was may of 1975. All
of a sudden, the Vietcong,
the Pathet Lao had infiltrated and they
were all over our village and I knew
that the Americans had left.
This is an Yang. Robin and I
spoke with him and his niece.
Kalia translated for us.
[inaudible] lives in Minneapolis,
but in 1975 he lived in a tiny
village in the mountains of Laos.
[inaudible] is part of a tribe
called the Mon and inc says,
as soon as the Americans left,
Lao and Vietnamese soldiers
showed up in his village,
there was a hundred of them.
They came in cars and in a way you could
say they were out for revenge because
during Vietnam War,
thousands of Mong soldiers had fought on
our side and as soon as we were out of
the picture, that's when
the killing started. Thanks.
As it began with isolated attacks,
[inaudible] pod villagers started
getting killed in random fields.
[inaudible] they just find one of their
neighbors shot dead in his rice patty
one day or a woman would go
fetch water and never come back.
Yellow car show done a partial for long.
It was a village and I know
the name of the village.
I know the name of the
village chief, the pathic Lao,
which again is the communist army in
Laos had gotten suspicious that these
villagers may have been
hiding guns in the jungle,
like plotting to rebel against
the government. So one day,
but that law went over and you
thought, or the whole village,
that's when we knew that the laws of
humanity had been, had been terminated
and not long after that.
And in his family long with thousands
of other mung flood their villages when
the hiding in the jungle,
this is where things stood when
Merle got his assignment and um,
before he left DC and flew over to Asia,
I stopped in our headquarters and while
I was there I was briefed by our desk
officer who told him about what
was happening with communist raids,
the on fleeing.
But then the desk officer
said something kind of odd.
There had been these reports
from refugees, refugees,
like an about this yellow,
these yellow droplets
falling from the air.
[inaudible]
PBS went out to the camps and
interviewed some of the refugees,
Wendy and crab who, oh, area.
I said this yellow stuff that was falling
out of the sky was coming from planes.
We only saw the powders free prom.
Yet some refugees talked about powder,
some talked about liquid, you
know a yellow miss sometimes,
but they all said whatever
this was. When it landed,
it mean people buy a mentally ill and
they all talked about how after this stuff
fell from the sky, when did
powder reach the ground?
It's dark on everything
left behind is yellow spots.
Well now you know yellow drops
everywhere all over the landscape.
Ang remember the first time
you saw it? Oh, show it Amanda.
She was hiding in the woods somewhere
and somebody came running into him and
said, Ang, you have to come
and see this yellow stuff.
Just fell on a village up on the hill,
ran up the hill and sort of crashed
out of the forest and just stopped.
No,
right there at the edge of the
village, a glued Lucia toe.
I learned let p electronic too.
I saw my dad call and two dead pigs and
several dead chicken and all the people
who've been exposed, they, they
were all having stomach trouble.
Ink says people were doubled over
carving their stomach writhing in pain,
throwing up some, throwing up blood
[inaudible] things that
people began to suffer from.
Everything from diarrhea
to headaches, rashes.
There was a person, and I have the
photo right here in my keeping a,
her Capa Ma, who had been exposed in her
eyes, her eyes were destroyed entirely,
and many people inc says, didn't
recover. What I saw was people dying,
they wouldn't get better. They would die.
Hmm. Marel says the thought in CIA was
that this might be some kind of chemical
weapon, right? Did it have a name at
that point? Yellow rain, yellow rain.
By the time Marel got to Southeast Asia,
hundreds of these reports had come in.
Hundreds and several thousand people
had been reported killed by this stuff.
But you know, in those kinds of situations
and in Southeast Asia, generally,
you know there are tons of rumors,
but you have to be careful of what
you believe, what you don't believe,
and you have to rely on evidence,
which they just didn't have
no until all of a sudden
they did.
Just a few months after Maura got there
and they started getting these reports
that refugees and collected
samples off of leaves,
some refugees had shown up with
leaves covered in these yellow spots.
Here's a closeout where I see, look again,
this is Matt Mussels and he's at Harvard
chemists and chemical weapons expert.
The U S government asks to help
examine these samples. Yeah,
I went up and visited him in his office
in Cambridge. Here's some on leaves.
These are only leaves rug
back. These are all dried out.
Now this leaves are small, black, brittle,
which only makes the spot stand out even
more because there's this incredible
bright yellow. They're tiny. They're
there two or three millimeters across.
And that says,
when scientists put these leaves under a
microscope and looked inside the yellow
spots, they saw that the spots had a
very high content of toxin called t two
which is a poison. And while
T2 does grow in nature,
the concentrations that they found in
these spots was way too high to have
occurred naturally in which demonstrated
that this was, you know, in fact a, uh,
a new type of a chemical weapon.
Okay.
We now had physical evidence.
This is secretary of State
Alexander Haig, the fall of 1981,
which has been analyzed and found to
contain abnormally high levels of potent
mycotoxins and eating poisonous
substance in the United States.
Said today it has evidence that chemical
warfare has been waged in parts of
Southeast Asia. The U s obtained
a test sample of twigs and leaves.
Chemical analysis found high
levels of three toxic chemicals.
The news of this poisonous yellow rain
became an instant political crisis.
Refugees in camps along the Thai border
had been telling for years of a yellow
rain or rain that was followed in
limits by vomiting, bleeding, and death.
Because everybody knew the
Lao and Vietnamese armies
were not capable of making
this stuff. No Vietnam could
not even make their own rifles.
They were pretty backward in that sense,
which really left only one likely suspect
circumstantial evidence points to the
Russians. The Soviet Union may be engaging
in biological warfare. The Soviets,
of course denied. They were involved.
Soviets said it was a slanderous
accusation that the u s government did not
believe them. Show me your union.
Their allies are violating the Geneva
Protocol of 1925 and in the summer of 1982
in a speech to the UN,
President Reagan officially accused
the Soviet Union of supplying and using
chemical weapons in Southeast Asia.
There is conclusive evidence that the
Soviet government has provided toxins for
you should allow and camp
a chia. Three years later,
Congress passed legislation authorizing
the production of a chemical bomb called
the big guy, the 500 pound bomb,
and it's been to be carried on high
performance here and within two years in
factory in pen bluff, Arkansas,
again churning out thousands of bounds
designed to carry Sarah and gas. Really?
I don't know why
[inaudible]
this would be the first time the United
States had manufactured a chemical
weapon in nearly 20 years.
All this in effect because
of the yellow rain.
Ooh,
but before we jump ahead, in the,
in November of 1982 they were two
days of press briefings by the State
Department, and this is where
things really start to get weird.
The State Department had gotten
everybody together to explain it.
Some British scientists had looked at
the spots and in addition to the poison,
they found something else.
All the samples had a very high
content of pollen from flowers,
which initially didn't make any
sense like why would pollen be toxic?
But eventually the government officials
came to this kind of terrifying
conclusion that in fact, this was a very,
very clever communist mixture.
Somehow the Russians had found a way to
use pollen as a vector to transmit this
toxin. If it falls right on your skin,
it would intoxicate you poison you,
but if these drops should
fall on a leaf or a rock,
then the wind would read,
disperse these Poland Greens,
which we've just the right diameter
to penetrate to the dip the lungs,
thereby making it a more deadly weapon.
Matt remembers hearing that and thinking
that just seemed completely bonkers to
me. I knew a lot about chemical weapons.
And you'd never heard of
anything like that before? No.
So he sent some of these samples
around to other scientists.
He knew in one afternoon he's sitting
in his lab and he gets a call.
I remember the phone call is the
guy who called and Tom Sealy.
I'm a professor in the department of
Neurobiology and behavior at Cornell
University. Matt pick up the
phone. Tom said to him, Hey,
I analyzed the samples you
sent me, and then he said,
the State Department
explanation is not parsimonious,
meaning meaning this yellow stuff is
not a chemical weapon. Then he paused.
He said it's B, and then
he used a four letter word.
I think we can use that word
because that all right. Yeah.
You said it was beaten
[inaudible]
what these what we call
fecal spot of Honeybee
[inaudible]
that was their idea. Yeah. They
were like, look, here's the thing.
Every winter bees kind of
hibernate during the winter.
There are no flowers and there
is no Pauline, there's no nectar.
There's nothing for the bees to go out
and collect so that they stay inside
confined to their hives all winter
feeding their babies fattening up the new
worker bees for the next season.
And since they're very fastidious,
they do not defecate in their nests.
They don't poop all winter. Right.
So the become immensely constipated.
And then on the first warm days,
they all fly out on mass to like
a hundred feet off the ground.
[inaudible]
all at the same time. It is called the
cleansing flight in anybody who cultures,
bees. And if you get caught
beneath the situation, Tom says,
it feels like light raindrops hitting
your arms, hitting your forehead.
So this was their theory that the
yellow rain was not a chemical weapon,
it was just be droppings. They published
this and the government was like,
seriously,
even a bunch of prestigious scientists
came forward and said that it was an
absurd explanation. Kind of
crazy and embarrassing a,
let's not forget that
this rain was toxic and B,
honeybees and southeast
Asia don't even hibernate.
There is no winter in Southeast
Asia. It's the tropics.
So Southeast Asian bees
never get constipated and
they never do the big poop.
Those Eric, good objections. No,
Matt and Tom Counter by going to Thailand
12 and I flew out there and they go
into the jungle plants and beehives and
one day they're staring up at a high end
in the flesh. They see it happen.
The bees shoot up into the sky
and within a minute or two after that
we started to get rained
upon by the [inaudible]
B feces. So to tell the government,
sorry, we think it happens here too.
[inaudible] wait, that's only half of
it. I mean what about the toxic part?
The whole idea that these bees are
pooping poison. That is a hard one,
but while Matt and Tom were in Thailand,
some labs had started retesting those
original samples because you see the
poison had been detected by one particular
lab in Minnesota at the beginning,
but now that these yellow
spots were such a big deal,
other labs all over the world
began to retest them and
they couldn't find anything.
British never found trees.
The Swedes never found a trace. The Way
Matt sees it, the analyses were wrong.
He thinks that lab,
the lab in Minnesota that had been doing
this work inadvertently contaminated
the pollen because this lab did
lots of other work with Mycotoxins,
large quantities of these toxins.
The government obviously wanted to
be sure they did their own rules,
tests of the samples.
They didn't find anything.
They sent a team to Southeast Asia to
verify the bees do the poop shower thing
and they do.
And my friend, it's a good friend
pong tip who was part of that team,
told me that in the bar at the end of
this multiday excursion, off the record,
one of the gentlemen said, well,
I guess we owe the Soviets
and apology on this one,
which hasn't ever happened. In fact,
yellow rain is still,
that's morale again in the U S Army
Chemical Corps manual is, you know,
one of the, the possible weapons
that might be used. Oh really? Yeah,
it's still there. It's
still, it's still there.
I have a, I have a clarifying question
before I interpreted that. So,
so they found toxins initially and then
when they looked again at those samples
that talk to them were no longer
there. That's right. Okay. A lot. Like,
you know, I had the [inaudible]
at a certain point in our
conversation with Ang, the Hmong guy,
Robin and I talked to earlier with
his niece, Kalia translating for him.
We explained that the evidence they'd
been attacked by chemical weapons seem.
Yeah,
I interpreted that for uncle
a little shaky. Hi John [inaudible]. Uh,
[inaudible] ain't response was
if this was just be thesis,
how do you explain the kids dying, the,
the people and the animals dying? Uh,
where there is this yellow thing
where there are no bees, um,
whole whole villages die.
We asked Kalia to tell Ang what the
scientists had told us that the Hmong were
definitely dying. The moment
were under real attack.
They were being fired out from
airplanes and by soldiers. And,
but more importantly, even if they
weren't killed by those direct attacks,
they were on the run through the jungle
mountain nourished and drinking from
contaminated streams. Diseases like
dysentery and cholera were rampant.
And the way a lot of people see
it is that they may have missed,
attributed some of those mysterious deaths
to this cloud of bee poop that looked
like it could have been a chemical weapon.
Hi, John Gig with hydro
Noosa. The Ang says no more
[inaudible] not a chance
to what I've seen,
and there is no inkling in my mind
that those deaths were not caused by
starvation. Dysentery. It was chemicals
that with our killing my people.
So we wanted to know, and
this was an honest question,
did he see something that would
contradict the scientist story?
Did the source of the rain,
was there always a plane and then rain
plane and then rain or did sometimes the
rain happen without a plane?
[inaudible] [inaudible] we never saw what
they said was that it was always just
being dropped on them. And it will always,
always be in drop where there are heavy
concentrations of Hmong people. Hmm.
But that's what we knew. We don't know
whether there was a plane causing it.
It was just you just
see the dust or see the,
you have to understand that the planes
are shooting bullets and bombs every day,
all the time. And so,
so whether it was a bombing plane or
a yellow plane was incredibly hard to
distinguish. [inaudible]
everybody runs when you
hear the plane. So mom,
people don't watch bombs
coming down. You came out,
you sneak your head out and you
watch what happened in the aftermath.
You saw broken trees,
you saw yellow in the,
in the aftermath of what had been bombed.
[inaudible] Ma [inaudible] I saw with my
own eyes that [inaudible] on the leaves
eating two holes with my own eyes. I
saw Paul and that could kill the grass,
could kill leaves, could kill trees,
but he himself is not clear whether
it's the bee stuff or whether it's other
stuff, because there was so much
stuff coming down from the sky.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
you know that, that,
that were chemicals being that being
used against the mall in the mountains of
Laos,
whether this is the chemicals from the
bom or yellow rain chemicals were being
used, it feels to him like this is
a semantic debate and it feels like,
um, there's a sad lack
of justice that, that,
that the word of a man who survived
this thing must be pitted against a
professor from Harvard who's read these
accounts. Um, as far as I can tell,
your uncle didn't see the bee pollen fall.
Your uncle didn't see a plane.
All of this is hearsay.
[inaudible].
What's your [inaudible] [inaudible]
my uncle says, um, for the last 20
years he didn't know that anything,
anybody was interested in the death
among people that you bargain.
He agreed to do this interview because
you were interested in to know what
happened to them about what happened and
the world has has been on interest for
the last 20 years. He agreed
because you were interested.
She took a gay more attractive that the
story would be hurt and at the moment
that's who'd be documented and recognized.
That's why you agreed to the interview
that the moral heart is broken,
that our leaders have been silenced and
what we know has been questioned again
and again. It's not a
surprise to him or to me.
Okay.
I agreed to the interview for the same
reason the radio lab was interested in
the Hmong story that they were interested
in, documented the dust that happened.
There was so much that was not told.
Everybody knows that chemical warfare
was being used. How do you create bombs?
If not what chemicals? We
can play the semantics game.
We can but I'm not interest
in. My uncle is not interested.
We have lost too much heart in
too many people in the process.
What
I I think that, I think
the interview is done.
Okay
now. Um,
nope that wasn't the end of the interview.
They kept on talking Robert and bad
explained to Kalia that we know we're
reporters. We're just trying
to figure out what happened.
One thing I do want to make clear,
we informed the gangs in advance that
we wanted to talk about the controversy
surrounding yellow rain. We
were very clear about that.
We did not intend to ambush them,
but this interview troubled us.
We talked about it for months arguing
back and forth about what it meant to the
story, what it meant for
us personally and uh,
we decided at a certain point to bring
that conversation into the studio.
We're going to play you that conversation
as we originally podcast and then
we'll have some things
to say on the other end.
Okay.
That started by a talking about the
moment that you just heard on tape
that somehow that
moment was when the whole
story changed for me.
How exactly like I think that
there was something about
like the way that she was pointing away
from the thing that we had been looking
so hard at and saying, stop
looking at that. Look over here.
Yeah.
Like she like she didn't convince me at
all that this wasn't a chemical weapon,
but she convinced me that
we were missing something.
Yeah. What I'm hearing her say there,
not having been in this interview is
quit focusing on this yellow rain stuff
because when you do that, you're
shoving aside the much larger story,
namely that my people were being killed.
Right. So you're what she's saying.
So you're wrong.
That is absolutely into my mind. That
is not fair to us. How is it not fair?
It's not fair to ask us to not consider
the other stories and the other frames
of this story. The fact that the
most powerful man in the world,
Ronald Reagan used this story to order
the manufacturer of chemical weapons for
the first time in 20 years.
If the United States with the manufacturer
chemical weapons again and then use
them because the Russians supposedly
had, then people would have died.
Ugly deaths in the consequence of
that, and that is not unimportant.
That's hugely important, but
it's not important to her.
So should that not be
important to us, but I, yeah,
I mean she's saying
think that, I dunno. I,
I think that until she,
until she said the things that she
said at the end of that interview,
I don't think that I had
fully appreciated the,
the volume of pain that was involved
in that moment for them. Yeah. Yes.
I thought, I thought her
reaction was very balancing,
but her desire was not for balance.
Her desire was to monopolize
the story and that we can, sure.
We can say that though. Oh, if you
listen to the words, that's okay.
She said No.
I just think that they feel like their
trauma has never been fully acknowledged
and that they've attached it to this
because maybe they felt that they had to,
they've attached it to this idea that
yellow rain was a chemical weapon.
And if yellow rain suddenly isn't
a chemical weapon that doesn't just
unvalidated the yellow rain,
it negates their whole loss.
And I think she might
be right, but it's like,
I also think that the scientists are
right, it's not a chemical weapon.
And I also think you're right that,
to call it a chemical
weapon has big consequences.
So what do you do when three
truths are right at the same time?
This is where we stop.
So that was our original conversation
and when the podcast went out,
a lot of people were very upset by me
in particular. So I think I want to,
if I could add just a couple
of things here. First of all,
clearly it was wrong to say that Kalia
Yang was trying to monopolize our
conversation because after
all, we are the editors.
We choose what to put on the
air. And in this case we chose,
we were looking for evidence that
despite what the scientists thought,
that maybe there was a chemical weapon
here and we wanted to find an eye witness
to see if anybody saw a bomb
open and yellow rain come out.
That's what reporters do. We test
truths. And that is why I was persistent.
I had no idea what the youngs were going
to say. And when they got angry, I was,
I was embarrassed. And when I got angry
in my conversation with Jed and pat,
that was not right. And for that,
I apologize to Kalia and
Mr. Young in particular,
I have to ask questions and search
for truth. But in this case,
given how much Mr Yangs
had already suffered,
I should have done it with more respect.