You are listening to
radiolab radio from W N Y.
S. C e n n. P. R. [inaudible].
Kind of the everyday routine. Ooh,
ever dream of a life of
romantic adventure. Yeah.
Wanting to get away from
it all. Yeah. We offer you
escape
looking this way.
Escape is, I end the free
you from the ball walls up
today or a half hour of
high adventure [inaudible].
Okay,
so this is an old time radio show from
the 1940s late forties I forget that
called escape and always
starts the same way. You know
we offer you as state,
that phrase,
I love how they say it and here's what's
great about this show and why it seems
like a good way to start this show.
Our show is it immediately
after they say that phrase? Yes.
They then present you with a scenario
from which there seems to be no escape
[inaudible] hanging by your fingertips
on the sheer face of a nice cliff.
Like here's one suspended a thousand feet
above instant death with your strength
running out and with no chance for escape.
There's a million of them.
It's pretty, I brought a tiny chunk
on the ground off the coast of Borneo.
You were lost in the London Park.
You're a passenger for seven or eight
and you're the subject of an experiment.
After the age of aimless tear,
I can take the Blackman [inaudible].
Great. Oh wait, one more.
One more just for kicks.
You're like, clapped
in the remote valley of
the Andrew Walden by here rock recommended
around the new clothing and you is
the band, the blind
man to watch your eyes.
How could you not listen to that?
What is better than like a story where
the walls are closing and nonunion?
Don't know what you're gonna do. What
am I gonna do? What am I going to do?
And then suddenly, or Skype, it's
like the best story ever. That's true.
So you're ready. Okay.
This hour we offer you three bizarre
scenarios to stories of people and planets
writing yearning who, Hey,
will they make it? And if they do,
what are the scoping? Okay,
enough of that. I'm Jad, I'm Robert.
This is radio lab and uh, to start,
let's talk about escape artists
because why not, right? I mean,
this is an escape show. Exactly.
The most famous escape artists in
history is probably Harry Houdini.
And our first story is kind of a Houdini
story. It comes from our producer pat.
Yes. It's about a guy whose
nickname is little Houdini.
Right? Yeah. I heard this story from my
friend Ben. Hello. Like months ago. Oh,
your brother Ben, your journalism
friend. My journalism trend. Yeah.
I'm a reporter with the Tampa Bay
Times in Florida, but our story begins
at the Tourney Center
penitentiary and only Tennessee.
That's where we caught up with little
Houdini. He was between escapes.
It's a couple of guards. Walked
us into this huge cafeteria,
sat us down at this little tiny
table and brought out Chris,
Chris Gay. That's his
name. Yeah. Do y'all have,
do you interview my brother
and everything? Yeah, we
talked to then come. Okay.
Sorry. Yeah, I us,
the first thing I noticed was he was
even smaller than I expected him to be.
He's going to be a little,
you know, nickname, but uh,
he was a very little Houdini short
little maybe five. Five, yeah. One 41 30.
His prison uniform was,
was pretty baggy on him.
He was wearing a white ball cap and uh,
he's got a big smile
stretched across his face.
Skype. I think it's, it's actually
addicted, I think. Addicted. Yeah.
I think it is, but I think
what's addictive about it, it's,
it's a way to, uh, it's a way to
punch him in the stomach. Say, Hey,
this can be done. I can do
this. I might not have been new.
Y'All might have told me I can't
do nothing on my life. More people.
I've told me that I know I can do it.
How many times have you escaped?
Probably about 13,
13, 13. 13 out of jail. Yeah.
And unfortunate to Arthur
King. I made all 13.
I did a little research to see how that
compares to other Houdini's and there
are a few people who come close
as far as I was able to find out.
Nobody alive has that many escapes.
Can we say pretty safely that he's
the greatest jailbreaker alive.
I'll go ahead and call them that. Yeah.
So I got away from month pretty
much without even asking.
Chris began to list his escape. He
has escaped every way you can imagine.
Slip my hand, clip out.
What the dire does,
what out the band in
between the [inaudible].
All my clothes upset my
boxer shorts like handcuffs.
He said picking a handcuff keys. One
of the easiest things he's ever done.
Sure enough, he's used everything from
a pen spring to a safety pen. Yeah.
Even once the zipper thing
might Hank hippy out.
My zipper scrambled out windows, ran out
doors, climbed over walls under walls,
drilled through them. State suicide twice.
Trick the cops by drawing
up fake escape plans.
Food their dogs by covering his
clothes and pepper a pepper.
Another time he didn't have any
pepper, but he found some roadkill.
They didn't smell like a scout and he
rubs it all over his body to a racist
scent. Pretty good at hiding
it too. He's hitting the trees,
jumped down at trap door that
he cut the floor of his trailer.
Once he hit a grave, I'll have the
shallow grade beside a dead body.
Another time.
He ended up in a college campus someplace
outside Atlanta and he hit out on top
of an air duct for two days
until the coast is clear.
But one of the interesting things about
Chris is that even though he's been
doing this for 20 years, there's never
a record of him assaulting anyone. No,
I'll refuse to do it. Stole things.
Pretty much only things to help him run
are always refused to go in somebody's
house hours, refuse to
go in somebody's garage.
He says you got rules from sales
about how he breaks the law.
Almost like a coat. In fact,
the story that got Ben Interested in
Chris in the first place is kind of the
perfect example of this.
This was a few years ago in 2007 and
got a press release from the Florida
highway patrol. Be on the
lookout for, you know, Chris Gay,
and according to the press
release, here's what happened.
Chris had been locked up in Alabama
when he got a telephone call from his
family. He said, my mom was
a was guy. She had cancer,
so he faked suicide,
busted out of the prison transport van
that was bringing him to the hospital,
stole a truck, and just
started driving home.
Who's going to see his mom to pay his
last respects and expect her to live there
alone as he comes around the bend
in the road to where his mom lives.
He's driving a Walmart tractor trailer
and he's got like a dozen cops on his
tail. When I get Dan are run by,
I run off the road crashes truck
into a field near his mom's trailer.
Jumps out of the truck. Yes it was.
That was wrong. Told House. They start,
they've jumped out of
the cars and running.
Told them and just before
he makes it inside,
they chase him into the
woods and he disappears
without seeing his mom who would end
up dying before he could see her.
Few days later,
Chris turns up in Daytona beach driving
a tour bus that belonged to crystal.
Gale beat the country's thing ever. Yeah,
he's still crystal Gail's tour bus in
Tennessee and then drove it to Florida.
Yeah. So you get this press release
in and you think what? I thought, uh,
how do you miss with a story like this?
And so Ben writes a story
for the newspaper, Big News,
and pretty soon actually tour bus that
normally carries TV news people on it
took off. He's an escape artist
and something of a folk hero.
And soon crispy came
something of a folk song.
Literally the week Chris got caught at
Grammy Award winning bluegrass picker
named Tim O'Brien put out a song
called the Dalat of Christopher Daniel.
Daniel Gay,
pretty soon of famous Hollywood
director bought the rights to the movie.
They were originally trying to
get Johnny yet to do it. But
it's perfect. You're the
underdog making a run for it,
for what seemed to dance. I'm
going to be really good intentions.
And part of me thought, you know, I
mean this is awesome, but it's also,
I mean there's gotta be
more to this story. Absolutely.
Who's this guy really and
why does he keep running
destination? You want to
tell us where we're going.
Going to Buckeye bottom
road to talk to tare gay.
A Tory is Chris, his older brother.
He says he can tell us that whole
story about how they grew up.
Here we are.
Chris grew up in a small trailer out in
the middle of nowhere West Nashville.
There are junk cars off
in the woods. Uh, when you,
if I entirely hanging out with a
couple buddies drinking two beers,
I'll have any certain things you
want to know about or anything.
Or when we start talking about what
it was like when they were kids.
Now we lived in a little
bitty trailer down there.
He points off into the woods across the
street on this land. It was Kristin,
Tyree, mom and dad and a little
brother named Eddie who went by cotton.
And then there was Leanne lane gay,
the eldest among his older
sister cottons in jail.
So we weren't able to interview him,
but Leanne and Terry both told us that
growing up in that trailer was hard.
We grew up like mountain paving
walkie, no, no electricity,
no running water. Did their wash in the
river wasn't only as much food around.
I used to be a big field of plums.
A big plum thicket would go down and
woody, but you can't live on plums.
And a lot of days we would be hungry.
Leanne remembers they're lying in bed.
One on nine. She couldn't go to sleep
because her hunger pangs were so bad.
And Tare said, here, this'll help Ya.
And he ripped up and little dyeing a
notebook paper gave it to Leann. He said,
just chew it up real good and
swallow it and it'll help. Yeah.
And for Chris and his little brother
at cotton, those were the good days.
[inaudible]
because when my daddy and her separated,
mom and dad got a divorce and
the family split apart. Tardy.
Leanne went to live with mom,
Chris and his little brother Eddie,
who are 10 and 11 at that point moved
in with their dad and the dad, dad,
he really wasn't, you know, I don't
guess he just didn't know provider.
He wasn't around very much. Oh, I mean,
he was a deadbeat dad.
Yeah, he, he got where he, um,
he would get off work on Fridays and he
wouldn't come home for weeks at a time.
He'd tell him to go if they was
hungry to go steal from churches.
Sometimes they'd hike through the
woods into their grandfather's house.
Their Mom's dad, who Chris says hated
him and his little brother cotton.
We would go down there and he would,
he got where he started making us
fight each other. And we could,
if we first fought each other in the
winter, got some deep. It's, you know, he,
he was me. Maybe it was, that was their
life beating each other up for food.
He had go. He took his dogs on us.
So one night, one of them went and
found their dad's rifle, an old 22
and a tube sock full of rusty
bullets and went out behind the barn,
uh, lit a tire fire and,
uh, made a suicide pact.
[inaudible]
cotton was going to shoot Chris in
the forehead and then shoot himself.
And Chris closed his eyes and cotton
put the gun to Chris's forehead.
Chris heard him whimper and he opened
his eyes and concept, I can't do it.
And Chris said, well, let
me, let me, let me do it.
He took the gun and he put the barrel to
his brother's head and he couldn't pull
the trigger either.
And they were 10 and 11 at this
point. 10 and 11 man. And Ben says,
if you take a step back,
you can see that it's right about here
at this point that Kristen has brothers
start to steal, like really
steal. And I started that,
likes it on bicycles and
then he went to a little,
I guess four wheelers and
motorcycles is all stuff with wheels.
Yeah.
Chris remembers going with
cotton to sit on a bluff. Yeah,
it was on interstate 40.
We would go a wash trucks of ice and
they would dream about getting an a in a
semi and driving [inaudible]. Then
they went to a, I guess forwarders,
motorcycles and cars.
And it gradually got bigger and bigger
and bigger to one day. When Chris was 17,
he stole a a
semi, didn't even really know
how to drive it. But, um,
I kind of decided the keys was in it,
so I started it up from there.
There's really no looking back.
Can I pause you right
there before you continue?
Let me just name some modes of
transportation and you tell me yes or no.
What you've stolen a semi bulldozer. Yes.
Skid steer, skid steer, tractor back coat,
anything that's that flies. I actually
got in a helicopter once and uh,
we got in there, started flipping
switches and we finally got it.
We got the blight would rotate,
but it was a little low low thing
and got scared and got out of it.
Point is this is his life for more than
two decades. Even things that move,
getting caught in, escaping,
stealing things that move,
getting caught and escaping until
eventually he became bat guy on TV.
Dany who had police on
the run and six states.
But then when they,
something happened that seemed like
it might break this loop forever.
He met a girl. Yes.
Yes. Her name was missy.
She was waiting tables at
a little campsite diner.
He thought she was cute and Missy, he's
a smooth talker. I'll give him that.
She liked the way he taught,
taken right off the bat.
And a few months later I got pregnant
with my daughter and me and him moved in
together and for a while
life was really [inaudible].
We still had a little money in the
bank and I was working good for Gregory
instruction, had a good paying job,
running it up bulldozer. And uh,
I was actually going to school
in Lebanon to get my CDL license.
We had a nice trailer and
it had a refrigerator.
Did you like it? Yeah, I really, I
really liked [inaudible]. Matter of fact,
I was talking to my daughter last night.
It came real close with my daughter.
She remembers it like it was
yesterday. He got her a dog.
She named him blackjack first
puppy. She ever got that right.
There was the best moments in
days of a diapers, days a month,
I think for mine in his life I ever,
but then things got complicated.
The one day when Chris and missy
were driving in the car together,
we were going right through in the
middle of Nashville and, uh, Chris says,
look, I gotta tell you something.
I stole something cause I stole
the bobcat tractor from my
construction job and to make ends meet
as soon as she heard that missy
whipped her head around. And um,
I like hitting with a big Mac right in
the middle of Nashville and I just wanted
a big man. Yes, Auntie ed.
There was only funny for a little while,
a couple of days later somebody
told on me, I've got arrested.
He stayed in jail for about
two years and then escaped.
I don't know how exactly,
but before long he still again
and ended up back in jail again.
And um, and missy had stayed
by his side again. She,
she was determined he'd come home
from these escapes saying, Oh,
just tell you to being locked up.
He did being away from you guys
won't be a boy for my kids.
And I didn't want to be away from
me. [inaudible] got locked up.
Missy would write him letters.
I would send him money cause I work the
whole time I was pregnant with my uh,
13 year old. What kind
of work were you doing?
Worked on a sand and line
standard rocking chairs.
Chris meanwhile was thinking about his
next escape and when he came charging
through the front door,
thinking of roadkill,
telling missy the again he had
escaped. I stayed with him again.
But this time you guys started asking
for check stubs on a weekly basis and add
an hours up that he had been
gone from time he left the house,
which I would knock down riding time there
in from you were keeping tabs on him?
Yes I was.
She even went so far as to take $5,000
out of the bank account that they shared
by a trailer for them to live in
one that wouldn't move. You know,
I was trying try and more or
less to make him do. Right.
And it seemed like it was working.
But then one night Chris came in after
work and sat down in the living room with
missy and their daughter to watch
some TV next. I know we heard loud,
beaten at the door. Well, you know,
I jump up and he jumps up and
um, uh, next thing I know he was,
you know, moving that kitchen table
and sliding it out. Next thing I know,
he raises the rug up off the floor and
he jumps down in there and he says,
cover it back up. So I cover it back up,
put the table back and answer the door.
And uh, they came in and they
walked all around the house and uh,
and they laughed.
He bought this house to keep him still
and he'd cut a trap door in it. Yep.
He just stayed up on his father the
whole time they were walking over top of
him. Wow. Yeah. I guess it
was more or less I was young,
I knowed but I was also in denial.
But eventually something happened that
kind of forced her to admit just how bad
things had gotten with
Chris day before Halloween.
[inaudible] owner daddy had went down to
Walmart and she had picked out a little
which outfit, but she was old enough
and they don't, you know, she was for,
you know, trickle trading for a
four year old. That was a big thing.
The next morning it's Halloween. Her
daddy looked at her and said, what baby?
I'm going to work. Um, I'll
say this afternoon, you know,
I'll get home,
we'll get you out outfit on you and we'll
go trick or treating up in Nashville.
And that afternoon,
Danielle was sitting on the back step and
then was just sitting there in a white
tee shirt. And I asked her, I said,
Daniel, what are you doing? How about no,
my daddy get home mama? He says,
we're going to go Nashville and we're
going to go trick or treating. I said,
okay, he'll be back in a little bit.
And she sat there and she sat there
and he never came home that night.
You, um, I don't really hear, like,
I don't hear a lot of bitterness
from, you know, is that accurate?
Yes. Why? What?
As far as me being upset with
Chris or Hating Chris? Yes ma'am.
Is that what you're asking me? Yes ma'am.
How could you not forgive Chris? 18 years.
That's how long I've known that boy and
I have seen firsthand where he lived,
how he lived.
I'm a fighter and I go to
church, my kids go to church.
I learned to forgive people
and Chris was, had a hard life.
He needs help. Help
that our can't give him
[inaudible]
you saw it for a while that you could
give him that help and yes it is.
[inaudible]
I should have been
there for my kids. Yeah,
they took a lot of time on
making this up. Yeah, no, Mike,
you know what are done
[inaudible]
so what do you make of
this story, Pat? Well,
somewhere along the way
for Ben and I, this,
this story really became
about the symbol question.
Can a person like Chris, you
know, grew up the way he did?
Can a person like that change
or do you just never escape
a childhood like that?
People live with a how
they grew up. Yes. Miss.
She says if two kids and a wife
that he loves, if we keep stopping,
I don't know what Cam, but when we
asked Chris, he said, it's in my mind.
I'd only change it on our own. They're
going to change. I'm working to change.
Really? Of course he has
said that before. Truthfully,
what's different this
time? What? What? You know?
I'm going places I don't have to
take, I've taken every one of them.
I'm taking her anger. I'm
taking how to be a better daddy.
I'm taking everything about, if I were
not a pro this month, I'm going to,
I asked him, can I go ahead and
complete another non-math problem? Wait,
is he saying he's going to ask
them to keep him in jail? Yeah.
It's 20 years of running. He's asking
the parole board not to let him go,
which made me think, I don't know.
Maybe. And Ben, what do you think?
I don't think there's any way
that Chris changes. I
think he's, you know,
unfortunately doomed to stay
in the cycle, which sucks.
You know? I'm sort of ashamed
that I have opinion. Why?
I mean, why do you think
you feel that way? I,
I mean my dad was pretty
similar to Chris in many ways.
Really. My father abandoned
me, uh, when I was,
when I was a young boy. And, um,
and I got reacquainted with him when
I was a teenager. At that point.
He was, um, a very sad alcoholic,
uh,
who often made big mistakes and
I played high school football.
And near the end of the, of
the year, my senior year,
they put out this highlight tape.
So I took that highlight tape to
his trailer in Slick Oklahoma.
And after shooting a lot of Tequila,
we sat down on the couch together and
I put the tape in and we were watching,
you know, watching me
play football. And, um,
not long into it. My Dad
starts sobbing, just bawling,
tears running down his face. And I
look over at him and, uh, and he says,
I wish I could have been there. And
I wanted nothing more in that
moment and today than to ask him,
why weren't you? And, um,
I think in some way
I get that opportunity in this
job to ask my dad that question.
Ben Says, his dad never
answered that question.
And after that day where they watched
that football tape, nothing changed.
Ben got Older, you graduated
from college, got married,
had kids and his dad never
showed up for any of it.
So he says when he's talking to a guy
like Chris, in some ways I, I, you know,
I'm sitting across the
table from my own father,
which doesn't give him a lot of hope.
The only ounce of encouragement that I
have honestly is if we find out that,
that Chris has indeed when given
the chance to get out of jail,
said, no thank you. Maybe that
gives me an ounce of hope.
And a couple of weeks ago,
Ben got a letter from Chris.
Can you just say, can
you read it for me? Yeah.
Uh, he says, dear Mr. Montgomery,
thank you for your letter.
I'm doing well.
I went up for parole and yes, I did ask
them to let me go through the program.
The final decision was to parole
me upon completion of the program,
listening to radio lab, radio,W , n, y, s,
e, n, p, r,
double e, every day routine. Woo. Ever
dream of a life of
romantic adventure. Yeah.
Wanting to get away from it all. Yeah.
We offer you escape.
Is this this way?
Escape the sign the
[inaudible] walls up today,
or a half hour of high
adventure. [inaudible]
okay,
so this is an old time radio show from
the 1940s late forties I forget that.
Called escape and always
starts the same way. You know,
we offer, you escape that
phrase,
I love how they say it and here's what's
great about this show and why it seems
like a good way to start
this show. Our show is it.