Talking about escape stories about people
being trapped and them getting out,
getting free.
And in our last segment week met a guy
for whom will the escape itself became a
trap. But now we're going to take our
escape Motif to a much bigger scale.
Yet we're calling this, by the way,
we are the limit because in this one
we're going to the outer limits of the
human imagination began for us when
we spoke with this writer. Yes,
I hear you. Boom. Here and Dole Nick is
his name and he told us a story about,
so this is Isaac Newton's
story for the most part.
And it's a story that involves the
Earth, the heavens, God, humanity.
And you might as well
throw on the apple. Um,
the one thing everybody knows about Newton
is that an apple fell from a tree and
bonked him on the head, which
isn't true. I was told, right,
that isn't an apocryphal,
it's probably not true. But,
but it's a story that Newton himself
told. Oh really? Cause Newton,
according to Ed all his life had this
notion that he was different from other
people. Uh, not only different
from but, but better. Uh,
he had a pipeline to God.
God was whispering secrets,
the secrets of creation into his ear. Uh,
no one else had been blessed in this way.
Other people's role in life was
simply to, uh, to bog him down.
Not what I would call the modest
guy. No, but identity rate,
what our story begins around
1665, Newton is at Cambridge.
She's a student in Cambridge,
is hit by the plague.
They send everybody home because although
nobody understands how the disease
works, they know that if people are
crowded together, they tend to, uh,
to all get it. So, so everybody
go your separate ways.
This was a kind of an enforced
summer vacation, right?
And He's like 19 or 20 at
this point. 2122. Okay.
Newton goes home to his
mother's farm. Mom's like, cool,
now you can help me on the farm. But
he says, no, because he has a plan.
He'd brought some books home,
a bunch of of textbooks and he locks
himself in his room and sets himself not
only to having mastered all the
science that had ever been done,
but two plunging on ahead
of everyone else on his own,
motivated by this religious faith that
everything in the universe was set up by
a god who wanted someone
to crack the code.
Newton believes he's the one in the
same as he doing in his room. I mean,
was he just sitting there and like
with a thousand giant textbooks,
all that's known is that he did this.
He just went into his room and
came out with what we're about.
So he came out with, with the how
gravity works, how light works,
how rainbows work, how the tides
work. And then having done all summer,
he did all this. What did you do on
your summer vacation jet? I know Mike,
my summer I, um, I learned how
to fold sheets like Marines do,
which I thought was pretty good too.
So after having one flash
of insight after another,
Newton now sets his mind to one
of the great problems of all time,
which for our purposes we will
call the problem of the moon.
And just to set this up,
what everybody before [inaudible]
Galileo thought is there were a bunch of
ordinary things here on earth like rocks
and they behave in the ordinary way
that we know, you know, pick
up a rock, let go it faults,
and there are a bunch of much more
different mysterious, elegant,
perfect things in the sky like
the moon, which doesn't fall,
it just flutes there.
So one could conclude that the moon
has its own separate set of laws.
There are one set of laws that work here
on earth and another set that work in
the heavens.
And there's no reason it should be the
same set of laws any more than New York's
laws should be the same as as Paris's
laws. Can it make sense? Actually?
Heavenly things float earthly things fall.
But then here's where the problem begins.
Newton and a bunch of people at that time
had gotten a hold of this new fangled
thing called telescope.
And one of the things they saw was
that the moon wasn't this mysterious,
a heavenly body that they seem,
it was a big rock, irregular,
lumpy potato wish rock.
Oh. People were like, Huh,
but Newton being of course
Newton. But now wait a second.
If the job of a is to fall, and
if the moon is just another rock,
why doesn't it fall down? Exactly. So
what's it doing sitting up
there night after night?
Whoa.
And it's at this point that Newton
sitting in his room or wherever he was,
we can imagine, makes a crazy mental leap.
He thought back to a little thought
experiment that Galileo had come up with,
which initially might not make much
sense the connection, but it pays off.
And here's the setup.
You've got someone standing in a big
field with a gun that he's about to shoot
it,
and next to that person with his gun is
a person holding in his hand a bullet.
So you've got a person holding a gun and
a person holding just the bullet side
by side and the bullet in the hand and
the bullet in the gun are exactly the
same height above the ground and
now somebody says, ready, aim, fire.
And at the instant he says
fire the man with the gun,
shoots that bullet horizontally.
And at that same instant,
the man next to him holding the bullet
in his hand opens his hand and the bullet
trucks. So there's one bullet
zipping along, mn falling.
And then there's another
one that just falls, right?
We shoot the bullet out of the horizontal
gun and we dropped the bullet from
right decks to the guy
at the same time. Yes,
both bullets will hit the ground
eventually, but when they do,
they'll be far apart. And Galileo's riddle
was, which of those bullets hits the
ground first? Well,
I mean everybody would know that the
one that would hit the gun first and the
one that you just dropped because the
other one has to go all that. This is,
this is, this is a hard drill. And the
answer is why is it such a hard riddle?
Because I would think that the bullet
you drop is just gonna hit first.
The gun's got to go all the
way. No, those two bullets
both hit the ground at the exact
same instant. Really that's,
that's an experimental fact.
The bullet from the gun and the bullet
from things lands at the same time. Yes.
This bullet that shot horizontally,
it doesn't go like Wiley
Coyote running off a cliff.
It doesn't go straight through it.
Straight, straight, and then fall.
It's curving as it goes.
And the thing that causes it to curve
as it goes of course, is gravity.
It's the same gravity that is pulling
the bullet that you drop. Same gravity,
same pole, same speed.
So counterintuitively,
when you drop a bullet and it falls
for this long, when you fire the gun,
it'll also fall for that long,
even though ends up a mile away.
See that was Galloway was riddle and
that's as far as Galileo took it. Yeah.
Newton looked at that and
he said something smart.
First thing he said is, okay,
this field,
let's not pretend that this is some
perfectly flat field that goes on forever.
No, we're on the earth
and the earth is round.
And what roundness means is that the
ground curves away below horizontal.
So really what's happening is it has the
bullet is shooting across the field and
falling to the earth.
The Earth at the same time is very
gradually curving away from it.
Now of course, most guns, you know,
they don't shoot the bullet very
far and at that short distance,
the field is still pretty much flat.
But here's what Newton thought.
What if you could find just the right
gun that could shoot that bullet,
not just across the field but
across like thousands of miles.
And what if as it falls,
that bullet curves down towards the earth
in just the same way as the earth is
curving away from it. In this
scenario, the bullet that we've shot,
we'll keep falling and
falling and falling,
but the earth keeps falling and falling
and falling away from the bullet.
So the bullet falls forever.
The earth curves forever.
The picture never changes.
So the bullet then does what the pulpit,
he's in orbit
[inaudible]
hundreds of years before
Sputnik and other satellites.
Newton has invented the satellite.
And on top of that he said when we see
rocks like the moon that are not falling,
the reason we think they're not falling
is because we misunderstand really just
as the gun launched a bullet on
earth and it goes in never falls.
God who was presumably a terrifically
strong picture launched the moon around
the earth at just such a rate that that
would continue in its circle around us
forever. This is a perpetual dance.
The partners are bound together but they
never come close and they never break
up either. It's this endless round,
round round
from which there is no the scheme.
What this does,
what Newton did is take the
moon out of the domain of, of,
of poets and, and, and,
uh, musicians, the,
the golden or in this kind of thing and
last Sobek to the same that we use here
on earth. In other words, what he
showed is that in a very real way,
there's no separation between
the US and the heavens.
The same set of laws
does govern everything.
It's one universe and
I've explained it all.
[inaudible]
once you figured out
the laws of gravitation,
then you can send
spacecraft to Mars, Jupiter,
Saturn, anywhere out there.
If you're a radio lab
listener from way back,
you might recognize that voice
that's an [inaudible]. Hi.
One of the first stories we did actually
I interviewed her about working on the
famous uh, golden record.
You remember this? Sure.
So the idea at the time was to put
this record on the voyager capsule,
send it in the space,
and on the record would be all of these
sounds that represented, you know,
us kiss a mother's first word.
It's your newborn baby. Come on. Now.
In any case,
Ann was the one who was in charge of
choosing all the sounds to put onto that
record. She and Carl Sagan work together
on that project. And here's the thing,
we stopped our story as
the rockets took off,
but obviously that was just the beginning
of the story and the voyager capsules
right now
or about to make the kind of escape
that Newton could have only dreamed of.
Okay. It's the record thing. And, uh,
our producer loom levy has been, sorry,
I just turned my headphones up way too
loud. I've been following this story. Ah,
AH, oh yeah, yeah. Just turn it down.
Yeah. Okay. So it can pick it up.
Where we, uh, left. Okay.
So like in the point of the mission
wasn't really to deliver this record,
it was to go out and look at all the
planets in the outer solar system.
So starting in 1977, these two
little spaceships, two spacecraft,
voyager one and two went racing
away from Earth snapping pictures.
And so every time before [inaudible]
would reach another planet, you know,
all of the voyager people would get
together, go into the imaging room
and see the pictures come
from the outer solar system.
Do you remember seeing them? I remember
as a child saying life magazine,
you know, I was seven when
[inaudible] was launched. So this is
[inaudible] professor at Boston
University. As a grown up,
she became part of the voyager team. All
the pictures that, you know, as a kid,
you look at the books and to see what,
how Knapton look how Jupiter look.
No, just a complete revelations.
Sat to the image of Saturn technique,
color like pink and look, reddish,
turquoise, color yellow. And
those rings just spectacular.
They could see active volcanoes on
one of the moons of Jupiter. Finally,
that vision of Neptune,
this like blue jewel,
really blue, it's all came from voyager.
We had no idea how they
look like before wager.
Neptune was the last big cool planet
and it was the last thing they were
supposed to photograph.
After that the cameras were going
to be shut off till save energy,
but Kelsey and convinced them to turn
voyager back to earth and take a final
picture. So on Valentine's Day, 1990, uh,
one of the ships slowly rotated
so it was facing back to earth
and
it snapped a picture. One
last picture. Describe it.
So it's mostly empty.
Um, it's, it's pretty dark.
You can see sort of streaks
of light coming from the sun
and then you honestly wouldn't notice
it if it wasn't pointed out to you.
But down in one corner, kind
of a suspended in a Sunbeam,
there is a very small dot.
Blew a pale blue dot that
with us in Carl sagans words,
everyone you ever knew, everyone
you ever loved, every superstar,
every corrupt politician, just
everyone in all of history,
everything is some total op Rod.
Think of the rivers of blind
so that one indistinguishable group
could have momentary domination over a
fraction of that pixel.
It was one of those really rare
it images every single day.
I hear from people who take that Pale
blue.so deeply to heart and was it,
it was a complete reframing after
that because I was with tone-deaf,
but here's the thing.
The ships kept going, going, going, going,
drifting through the darkness,
going, going, going,
even though they weren't taking pictures
anymore that they were using like their
other senses, little instruments that
detect like how many particles are around,
what the temperature is.
So they were hurdling through this
empty space really fast, measuring,
sending that data back and scientists
like that off where they're listening and
waiting for what was not clear,
but they knew at some point these
capsules would get to the edge,
the edge of what? The solar system,
the solar system has an edge.
I thought it was just a big spiral.
Has an edge. It's, it's like a bubble.
C The Sun has a wind.
If we start has a wing, but
the sun has its own wind,
it blows out through the
solar system. It's very fast.
It can be between 400 to 800
kilometers per second anyway.
It blows out from the sun
past all the planets and uh,
it keeps everything else out. Oh, so
it's like blowing up a balloon. Yeah,
exactly. The wind gives it a shape, right?
So these little things are cruising
out towards this edge, wherever it is.
Scientists don't quite know
where it is or what it is.
The guys in the control room are like
pinging the ships. Like, Hey, what's,
what's up? What do you see in the
ships are like nothing. How about now?
Not much, no. Nothing. And how long
before they actually see something?
14 years. Oh Man.
It's like driving through Kansas
but like a million times worse. But
there comes a day I end of 2004 where
they stopped listening for a little while
because the antenna,
NASA only has so many antennas and
they have to use them to listen to
everything. So for a little while
the voyager teams like, okay,
you guys over there can use the
antennas. We're going to lunch. Yeah.
I mean it's not like anything's
happened. Nothing's happening anyway.
It's been 14 goddamn years.
Yeah guys, it's cool.
And they come back a few hours
later, start listening again and
it's happened. Very southern.
Everything is totally changed. Really.
All of a sudden, boom.
The speed of the wind dropped from
around three 80 kilometers per second
to 100 instantly. Like
just all in one sentence.
And then everything out
there started to get messy.
Top on [inaudible] much more top on land.
And before particles are also, um,
behaving a very different way.
And the fields are very, um, we are
the fields, the magnetic field.
So just like the sun has a wind,
the sun has a magnetic field as well.
The field starts at the sun and then
curves out in this kind of graceful arc
through the solar system in the how the
subtle tates create what people call
[inaudible] cart.
You know how like a skirt will
flair a few spin around real fast.
[inaudible] that's apparently kind
of what this field looks like.
But way out there, it seemed like
the skirt had started to fray,
maybe tear a little threads,
had broken off and seem to be
floating around on their own.
Not connected to anything. So
what does this all mean? I mean,
if the fields are breaking down and the
wind is dying down and you said the wind
is what actually creates the
space of the solar system,
does this mean we're out to know?
I kind of thought that was what was
happening, but no, it's not out.
And it's not quite in,
it's in the edge of the
bubble. It's in the air. Yeah.
But it's not like, I'm not like a
little thin edge. It's a, it's a thick,
thick edge. So the edge isn't just a
little line that you cross. It's a place.
Yeah.
And while we listened the two voyager
ships moved through this edge for several
years.
Then something very
interesting happen, um,
is that the wind on virtual one
stopped like completely stopped. Yeah.
So now we're out. No, no.
I mean this is what people thought,
but there are other measurements like
temperature and number of particles.
The magnetic field doesn't tell
us that we are out of the bubble.
Nature surprised us again.
So now we think there's a place
at the edge of our solar system.
Why didn't they edge the edge of the edge?
That's utterly still no
wind at all. A pause.
People are Connie stagnation layer and
there is a big discussion why this layer
exist and how thick it is
and by how thick it is,
she means when will it end?
Because once we get past this.
So has anything ever crossed
the boundary before? No.
This would be the first man
made object to live any star.
And a voyager has like right
there smelling, touching
that boundary. You know,
you only do those things first.
Once like your first kiss,
your first tasted alcohol,
your first time driving a car,
the first time you see the ocean
[inaudible]
these things open up a whole new world.
First time out of the solar system.
Aw.
So when is it going to freaking happen?
It might have happened while we were
talking. Yeah. We're thinking from now.
Any moment now. Next couple of
months or three years from now,
four years from now. It's close.
Everyday opened my Google alert for
voyager and I look and see did it happen
today? [inaudible] if it happens before
the show goes out, I'm really pissed.
Yeah. Every day. That's the first thing
you do in the morning. Oh, alright.
Like the third thing.