You are listening to radio lab radio lab
from [inaudible], w.N y.
S. E. N. N. P. R.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm
Robert Krulwich, Radiolab,
the podcast chest. So today on radio lab
we've got a shorty for you, but it's
like it's a good, it's a good thing. Yup.
We're going to introduce
you to two different,
I am a v S Ramachandran at the
University of California San Diego.
I direct the center for
brain and cognition there.
Okay. My name is Dr Carol Berman. I'm at
NYU Medical Center. I'm a psychiatrist.
So there's,
there are two folks and they're going
to tell you two different stories
that really, it's the same story, just
two different versions of it in a way.
That's right. That's right.
Can we start with Carol Berman?
So my patient,
who is this 37 year old patient comes
back to her house and sits next to this
man who's wearing a red
plaid shirt, trucking boots.
And this woman looks at this man,
doesn't quite know what to make of them.
I think the gene she recognized and the
boots and she takes a look at him and
says, who are you? And he says
to her, well, who are you?
Come over here. Give me a kiss.
So she leans in little
tentatively gives him a kiss,
but it feels wrong. Everything
about this situation feels wrong.
She was thinking this was some
strange man who is sitting here in a,
you know her husband's clothing.
This did not look like her husband to
her and she was wondering what he was
doing in her apartment.
Okay, so that is one story.
And now we want you to
hear a second story.
This one comes from Dr v S Rameshchandra.
I saw a patient not long ago, was in
coma, two weeks, came out of the coma,
a student on our campus, intelligent,
quite articulate, a little bit slow down,
but overall quite intact. But here's the
problem. When he looks at his mother,
he says, doctor, who is this woman?
This woman looks exactly like my mother,
but she's an impostor and
imposter. She is an impostor.
She some other woman
pretending to be my mother. No.
Is this person coming into his in his
actual is his mother and of course this is
very alarming to the parents. Sometimes
it's still spills over to the father.
Okay.
It's usually somebody very close to you
and he has nothing else wrong with him.
He just doesn't think that his
mother is really his mother. Yeah.
This person looked like her husband,
but there was something off like what?
There was something about him.
Some essence like the feeling you have
was towards someone when you see them,
right. The feeling or the
essence of the person,
the soul of the person isn't in there.
[inaudible]
so it turns out that these two people
are suffering from the same delusion,
delusion, pronounced like cop grass',
very rare cop named [inaudible],
g r a.
S are these kinds of cup grass delusions
appear sometimes with brain injuries
where certain kinds of dementia
or sometimes just out of the blue,
but the result is almost always
that you feel like your
left ones have been replaced
by imposters.
No,
still no one knows the underlying cause
and there are lots of different ways to
explain it. We explain it psychologically,
there might be some negative aspects
of the person that you don't want to
recognize. Like maybe
my patient, you know,
saw some negative things in her husband
that she didn't want to recognize.
So when the negative aspects came in,
he had to be a completely different
person for her too because she couldn't,
you know what I mean? On some level
you think it's a kind of denial, right?
So it'd be like Robert, if,
if there was something about you that I
just couldn't handle and every time that
thing appeared, whatever it is,
the only way I could deal with it
psychologically was to make a break and to
say, oh, well that's not the Robert I
know. Therefore it isn't Robert at all.
It's some fraud. Yeah, it's a fake.
But if you think there's
some psychological basis
when you try and treat that
psychological cause or whatever it
is we do. But we don't get too far.
We tried this stuff,
but when a person starts breaking
from reality and become psychotic,
you could take a fingerprints,
you could show them everything about
the person and you can't get any place.
I think what's happening is
something quite specific.
You can explain this in terms of
the known circuitry in the brain,
the visual centers of the brain funneling
information to the fusiform gyrus.
But you recognize your mother
or a dog or a table, a chair,
because this a stranger is a Jo. Is
that my mom? Is a dog, is that Fifi?
Then the message goes to the Migdal of
its cages, the emotional significance,
emotional and relevance of what you're
looking at for you. So wait, so,
so to cap,
to make that into a normal English mom
is a face I recognized as mom any set of
feelings that I associate
with my correct. Absolutely.
Now what happens is in this
patient, because of the head injury,
that wire is cut. So then no mommy
feeling no mommy feelings. So you say, my,
my God, this is my mom. She looks
like my mum, but what I'm doing,
I know feelings. There's something really
weird here. She must be an impostor.
Now, that's a very farfetched delusion.
Why doesn't she just say
she doesn't feel like mom,
but of course she's my mom and
why doesn't he do that to be sure?
Sometimes that happens, but
most often he says, not my mom,
because our thought processes are
much more dependent on our gut level,
emotional feelings. Then we
realized, so absent a feeling,
a familiar feeling of mom,
some part of my brain says,
that's your mother, and some
part of me says, no, it can't be.
And the deal that the brain works out
is a deal that creates this fiction.
It's an imposter because that solves the
problem and the equation that says it
can't be. It was from your emotions
wins. But now here's the twist.
Now if she goes to the next room, speaks
to them on the phone, he says, mom,
where are you? How are you? It's
wonderful to talk to you, Huh?
All the emotions come flooding
back and he is not delusional,
right? Why would that be? And are
literally, she comes to the room, he says,
who are you? You look just like my
mother, but you're not my mother.
So seeing the face seems to set
off this problem. The reason is,
does a separate wire going from the
auditory regions in the brain to the
Amygdala emotional centers?
That wire was not cut.
So what you hear can be very
familiar, but if you see it,
then you got a problem. When people ask
me, how come? What if she just Keke?
What if she comes and talks
to him? Right? What was the,
why doesn't the hearing kick in
and say, look, she is your mother.
The answer is she our brains.
There's a hierarchy of of priorities.
You're highly visual creatures.
We pay much more attention division,
give much more weight to vision,
dental hearing and to voice. Huh?
So you say this is an imposter.
She sounds a little bit like
my mother. I don't know why,
but she's obviously an impostor rather
than she doesn't look like my mother,
but has my mother's voice.
You tell me if you don't feel
comfortable talking about this,
but I understand that you have personal
experience with cap grass dilutions.
Yeah. Actually my husband,
he started not recognizing other people
first and then at some points I didn't
even think I was his wife.
I'm very stressed out with this whole
situation because my husband was a
charming, intelligent,
wonderful person in all ways.
And his dementia has been getting worse
and worse. Yeah, you're a psychiatrist.
So does, does your understanding of how
that might work in the brain change your
experience of it in some way? Well, no,
it can't really change your
feeling because you know,
when I get home and I'd like to, and I
get home, I kiss my husband and say hi,
how are you today? And I hope he's
recognized. I May and if he doesn't,
you know, I feel terrible. I
couldn't, after a hard day's work,
I want to be able to hug him
and kiss him and you know,
have a nice friendly
environment when I get back.
But you never know what you're
going to get when you get back home.
[inaudible].
Carol Berman is the author of a recent
book called Personality Disorders and V s
Rameshchandra, and is the
author also of a new book,
the man with the phantom twin adventures
in the neuroscience of the human brain.