Hey everyone. I'm Jad Abumrad.
This is radiolab, the podcast.
Every so often on a radio lab,
we set aside the science and we set
aside the big ideas and we just play some
music or I should say every so often on
the podcast we have that opportunity.
So I wanted to do that again today.
Also to invite you guys who,
who like radio lab to check out
this other series that I am hosting,
a couple of different shows we're putting
together on the wordless music concert
series, which is a really,
really innovative concert
series here in New York.
It's curated by a guy named Ronan
vone. Basically what he does,
it's very simple. He
takes classical musicians,
puts them on the same bill as
rock musicians because it is his,
uh,
opinion and I agree with this that the
music's do have something to say to each
other. So I'll be hosting a couple of
those shows. I hope you can listen,
but here is an excerpt
of one of my favorite,
favorite all time favorite bands
that performed as part of the series.
Stars of the lid is probably the
inventor of a certain kind of,
well, I don't know if
they're the inventor, maybe
Brian Enou is the inventor,
but they perfected a certain
kind of pop, ambient,
serene,
dreamy kind of narcoleptic thing
that is particularly their own.
And they performed recently at a,
the good shepherd faith church as part
of the word, this music concert series.
They played two selections from their
latest release and their refinement of the
decline. So I want to play this for you.
Now the people that are
going to hear are, uh,
Brian McBride and Adam Bryan bomb.
They are the founding members of star,
the lead, and they're going to
be joined by Ella Bruce on Viola.
Kate O'Brien on violin
and Juliet Kent on Cello.
Here they are stars of the lid at the
Good Shepherd Faith Church in Manhattan.
Uh, this next piece, uh, is
called requiem for dying mothers.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible] uh,
[inaudible] uh,
[inaudible] [inaudible]
two pieces by the bands,
stars of the lid that was
recorded recently at the
Good Shepherd Faith Church in
Manhattan as part of the wordless
music concerts series to perform,
as you heard were the founding
members, Brian McBride and Adam.
Brian Balm along with
Ella Baroo Shun Viola Kate O'Brien
on violin and Julia Kent on Cello.
There was also, by the way,
a visual artist Luke
Savitsky showing tape loops,
sort of like super eight tape film loops
that he layer one on top of the other.
To create these sort of like textual,
uh, visual escapes to match the music.
You can sort of vaguely conjure
that in your mind and aid case.
You can hear the complete wordless
music concert at Wny C. Dot. Org.
You can also visit our website for
anything you've ever heard and radio lab.
That's radiolab.org I'm Jad
Abumrad. Thanks for listening.
Thanks for listening to the radio lab
podcast from wny c New York public radio,
the station radio lab calls home.