This is Radiolab.
I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert Krulwich
and today we are talking about the
placebo effect and the
power of suggestion.
We're looking at a lot of new research.
I don't know. It was new research we've,
we've done well. It is new research,
but the problem has been
with us for centuries,
even at the very beginning of the
age of reason. Let me take you back.
18th Century. The enlightenment was in
full swing. There was change in the air.
Voltaire was denouncing the
church. Ben Franklin was flying.
Kite live was Yang, was
inventing chemistry.
It was the beginning of
modern times. Modern Science,
you might say reason inquiry. People
were reexamining the big questions.
How does the world work? What possibly
could hold everything together
and this was new.
Well, you have to understand that
in earlier historical moments,
the unification of the universe was
not a problem because it was God that
unified everything and everything was
a manifestation of God. That's it.
Colin talking about God,
he's a, he's starring you.
But if God isn't the glue that
holds the universe together,
then what does hold the world
together? Enter End Twan.
Mesmer and who? Antwan Mesmeric.
Have you ever said a,
you mesmerize me my dolling feel
to that said the word Mesmer.
I'm as mesmerization comes from Anton
Mesmer was a real historical figure.
So he's part of our narrative. Yeah,
I'll get out on my way home
to tell the rest of the story.
So in 1778 he moves to
Paris and he has a theory,
he believed that the world was filled
with a kind of fluid that moved through
all living things and he gave it his
own kind of sexy name, animal magnetism,
or as they say in the French
magnetism and he married it, right?
And as this force flowed
through all of life,
occasionally it would get stuck like
in a traffic jam, it would bunch up.
Right? And that is also the bunching
up can also be a cause of a problem.
That's what he thought. Being
sick was blocking the flow.
I restrictions in the flow of
animal magnetism in the organism.
I mean not that dissimilar to the way
that we understand traditional Chinese
medicine.
She with the needles and
the, and the acupuncture.
A Mesmer thought this life
was when it got stuck,
could be released with a little help
from needles. You don't know. This is a,
there's a lot more theatrical.
He created a kind of salon.
I actually think of it as um,
a prototype for the,
the idea of a happening in the 60s
that's the way I like to think of it.
You know,
it's sort of like everybody kind of
came in and there was this like music,
there was like dim light
and he would walk around in
his lovely purple suit and,
and he had to let her pull.
Yeah, I think he was a,
a lilac was a belief that
actually lifts the shade that
report it and then he would go
over to a particular client.
Usually it was a women,
most of his clients were women and he
would madame sit across from them and
their knees would touch
your magnetism or it is,
how do say all pushy and
then to unblock this flow,
he would stare into her eyes stare. Right?
[inaudible] if he, if he jammed
you, how would you know? Oh okay,
cause you would have a healing
crisis. What was that? Simple?
They would scream, they would vibrate,
had actually a padded room where the
ladies could go and loosen their corsets
and fling themselves about and bang
their heads against the wall and whatever
they needed to do in order to kind
of release the damned up energy.
It was apparently quite dramatic.
Oh my, the looks of it.
They were real seizures and people
said they felt better afterwards.
So word spread and SUNY had disciples
and then more disciples and it had
a lot of popularity. Yes it did.
So he did what any businessman would
do. He franchised it, he branched out.
And I mean this, literally,
he magnetized trees, trees,
trees, Mesmer, or,
or sometimes his assistants would
take to magnetized iron rods,
touch them to a tree in the forest,
and that would transfer
the magnetism to the tree.
The tree would then have the kind of
therapeutic powers that a mesmerist would
have, how convenient. That's in
Harrington, a Harvard historian.
And this was quite efficient because
then you could sort of have the trees do
part of the work for you.
So imagine if you will.
Lots and lots of people gathered around
a tree touching each other and the tree
and allowing the flow
to move through them.
Then they would all have fits together.
And the problem was the doctors of the
time who used to have all these people as
their patients were now
losing patients and money.
So they protested to the king.
King established a commission.
And actually one of the members of
that commission was Benjamin Franklin,
who at the time was the
ambassador to France.
And there were other important scientists.
[inaudible] was one of them. Is that
the guillotine? We know from the right,
so we're talking here about a major,
major league panel. These were big guys,
big names,
and they devised a series of experiments
to test for a magnetic field.
They weren't concerned whether
or not animal magnetism work.
They were concerned whether or not
animal magnetism existed because they
figured, you know, it can work
even though it may not exist.
And one of the most dramatic tests that
they devised is sometimes identified as
the first placebo
controlled trial in history.
[inaudible]
they were actually down on
Benjamin Franklin's estate.
This was just south of Paris and
Franklin himself conducted an experiment
and it involved front of a young
boy. Is that on too tightly?
No. Yeah, that was with 12, 13
years old. Can you see anything? No.
Any light at all? No. And uh,
he was told that is the deal.
Young boy, a lot of these five oak trees,
one of the trees on the estate has
been eyes by an actual mesmerist.
We'll take you to one tree at a time.
Your job is to tell us which
one has been magnetized.
They said one of the trees when magnetised
and where you blindfold you and you,
you tell us when you
know you're up by them.
Magnetic trees cause patients insisted
that they could feel the energy.
And by the way, I believe them,
I'm totally persuaded that the
real experiences were happening.
They brought the boy to one
tree, this is tree number one.
He began to kind of shake and
they brought him to another.
We started before tree number two.
They began to sweat and by the time they
brought him to the third and they look
forward. Here we are before tree number
II sort of collapsing convulsions,
which is all that dramatic
except okay tree number one,
tree number two and number
three and number four. Yup.
Had never been magnetized.
So this was seen as pretty definitive
evidence that there was no mandate
magnetic force here.
But they also didn't think that
the boy was sort of faking it.
So what they concluded was that
there is no magnetic force,
but that all the effects which they don't
deny the reality of were caused by the
imagination.
That was Harvard just starting in.
And Harrington and Rutgers historian,
Ed Cohen, my final stuff in this hour
comes from reporter Gregory Warner,
who recently visited a tent
revival in upstate New York,
little Adirondacks, lakeside community,
very rural to see a faith healing.
Okay, so, so I get there and I'm a little
bit late, I'm a little bit nervous,
there's a lot of mosquitoes.
People are restless,
they're sitting in their chairs,
the tent flaps are still up,
the sun is kind of setting. And Steve,
Steve Booza is going on about some
verses of scripture and people are really
bored. And he says, don't worry,
we're going to get to the healing.
Pretty soon the readings
important too, you know,
that kind of thing like a teacher,
like so then he says, okay,
now it's time for some healing.
The flaps go down and suddenly the space
changes because what was before this
kind of people milling in and out
becomes this very focused title chamber.
And in the beginning of the
Ministry of any kind combined, okay,
this preacher who, who is
this guy? That's Steve Booza,
he owns a construction company
in Syracuse. All the [inaudible]
physical healings. Financers,
so he's looking out into the crowd and
then the volunteer comes up. Hi. Hi.
Strawberry Blonde hair. Pink
Cardigan. Okay. Oh my new,
my backbone shit and yeah, Ninja backbone
straight and tell me what your honor,
how old is she? She's in high
school in an s shape. B diagnosis,
her scoliosis. That's cool though.
Don't let this scare scary.
Now I'm not trying to scare her.
Scoliosis of the spine
is 100% of the time.
Demonic. Okay, that's not
even physical. That's a demon.
I'm standing next to Steve. If it's
going to be straightened right now,
can be your hands full.
He spins her around.
I break any generational curse off of
my sister right now. In Jesus name,
you'll spirit of scoliosis.
I break your power and then all of a
sudden you spirit me now in Jesus name
backbone,
be straightened and Jesus just kind of
shoved her forward straight and right now
in Jesus name and Jesus. Then try it now.
Move around. Do what
you couldn't do before.
Stand back and give yourself plenty
of room movement. Moving more
faith.
I really don't want to say that she
was healed or that she wasn't healed
because she was just crying for some of
this. This isn't a hundred percent bad,
but I did meet a woman who something,
I think something did happen with
the other woman that I met had.
Okay, so there was nothing wrong
with it. From my phone sticks out.
She comes up,
I'm older woman in her 50s or 60s and
she just holds her hands up and I know I
clean offices sometimes
do have carpal tunnel problems.
Carpal tunnel. Explain what that is.
I mean as far as I know, it's
like an inflammation of the,
of the ligaments and it's
really, really painful.
It's a repetitive stress injury. I
want to show you something though.
Sandra sand right here. Sideways
cover. You could everybody see he,
what he does is he basically tells her
to to grip together her little pen,
pinkie and her phone and make
a ring like an okay symbol.
I'm going to take my
smallest finger, my pancake.
Then he sticks his finger in in the rain.
Try to see if I can pull my pinky
through. Your hand. He says,
I'm going to try to break it and you try
to stop me and I want you to fight me.
Now I want to, I want to see how much
strength you have. After you're ready,
he just pops it right open. You
got no strength. Throw it all day.
She can't hold her grip. That means
she got trouble in her carpal tunnel,
which is right here. Give me
those hands. Give me no chance.
She gives me her hand. He takes
it and both of his carpal tunnel.
I command you in Jesus
name for all swelling and
inflammation and rubbing right
now his thumbs,
I command all the ligaments and tendons
circled back to the normally last.
Statistically that's supposed
to be a narrow command.
All pain to be going out to this carpal
tunnel region like command healing like
one to this entire arm and his carpal
tunnel and all strengths that come back
there and Jesus then don't
do it again. He said, okay,
let's do the same
demonstration right again.
He hasn't bring her pinky against her
thumb. Now make that, make that grip.
I'm going to take my big finger
and I'm going to fight you.
And when he puts his finger in this and
watch what's going to happen and fold
your ready, he doesn't break her grip
and you can hear, he just drags
her right across the stage.
Okay?
The silly it worked. It maybe
did Lee's temporarily. Um,
she went back to her seat. They gave
her a blanket. She was really trembling.
I went over to talk to her.
Can you describe what
the experience was like?
But then when he did that thing,
Christian belief is that
Christ died for our sins.
We actual phrases, which they always
repeat is Jesus Christ. I'm healed.
By his stripes, we were healed by
the stripes of Jesus. You work.
He killed me when he died on
the crush. What does that mean?
It means that you were healed.
Meaning he died in the cross for
our sins and also for our ailments.
So we've already been hit.
We've already been healed.
We just have to access it and realize
it by our connection and relationship to
God. Okay, so, so what
happened to Linda afterwards?
The carpal tunnel came back
almost immediately. And um,
I met with her in a coffee shop.
But this is my belief from reading
the word of God. The Devil,
Satan comes in, tries
to talk you out of that.
He like he'll say you
didn't really get healed.
You know those things come into your
mind. And I believe that's just Satan.
So you have to have strong faith to
stand against that pain is Satan's way of
testing her belief? I think
that's what she thinks.
I talk to Satan and I tell them, yeah,
like the pain is part of the test.
God says you are liar and if the
pain is there, you wants me to pos,
she's not healed. She's seeing this,
this bigger struggle,
this bigger battle where pain is
just one more kind of obstacle.
Not that there aren't
times that I, I doubt I do,
but I have to be pet and I
have to say, I'm sorry God,
I doubt it because I know
you feel me so many times.
There's so many different things.
So I know it's for real. It's not,
you know, fake. I'm not part cause I know
that. I think that's a crucial point.
I mean if we think of it
as a medical encounter,
it's about pain in the body.
But if we think of it as a spiritual
encounter, the way she sees it,
it's really a battle against doubt.
Reporter Gregory Warner. Thanks
to him and to you for listening.
We've got to go now. Yup. Don't
forget to visit our website,
radiolab.org for more information
on anything you've heard. Also,
you can sign up for our
podcast@wnyc.org or on iTunes and
always we'd love to hear what you think.
Completely. Radio lab at w and
Y C. Dot. Org is the address.
I'm Jad Abumrad and we're signing up.