You're listening to radiolab from
public radio,W , N, Y, s, t, e,
n, n, P, R
for Steve Strogatz mathematician
who we sometimes have on the show.
It all started with a pendulum.
He was sitting in math class. Our
teacher handed us a little toy pendulum.
Basically just a little device with a
ball on the end of the string that was
retractable. That is,
you could change the length of
the string like an old telescope,
you know on that the pirate stretches
out of spyglass. Click, click, click.
You could make it longer in discreet
clicks and then the teacher gave us a
stopwatch and said,
I want you to time how long it takes for
this pendulum to swing back and forth
10 times. Okay, so I do the experiment,
10 swings, I record how, how many
seconds it took. Then he says,
now make the pendulum a little bit longer.
One click longer, click do it again
and as you might expect since
now the string is longer,
it takes a bit more time to make the
10 swings and I write down the number,
click do it again, click do it again.
And I do this five or six times due to
fleet plotting the the results on graph
paper,
which is what the experiment was really
supposed to teach us how to use graph
paper. So he's clicking,
measuring, making little dot.
Click measure.click measure dot
soon the thing is filled with dots.
That is when he noticed something,
this spooky thing was happening,
which is that the dots were
falling on an arc on a curve.
They weren't on a straight line.
They fell on a particular curve.
And I noticed that this curve was a curve
I had seen before because I had just
learned about it in Algebra
class and it's called a parabola.
And this really gave me the creeps.
I had this sort of feeling of the hairs
on the back of my neck standing up
because it was as if this inanimate
thing, this pendulum, new Algebra
and my 13 year old mind couldn't
understand that. How could,
how could this thing swinging back and
forth know something about parabolas or
how could that be built in then? And
even creepier thought occurred to him.
Wait a second. This parabola on my paper,
which is the same one as the math book
is also out in the world. It's the,
the shape that water makes
coming out of a water fountain.
It's also the shape of, you know,
when you shoot a rocket into
this guy and it slowly descends.
It's that it was in that moment that I
suddenly understood what people mean when
they say there is a law of nature.
Uh,
do you remember what it was that meet
your heroes stand on and was it that you
had peaked in and discovered
a secret or did you just sent,
we found the right answer it much closer
to the first thing you said that there
was this sort of veil over reality.
A hidden universe that you
couldn't see unless you knew math.
It really felt like being led into some
sort of secret society and that wasn't
so much the point. I mean, it's not like
I cared about being in this priesthood.
It was, it's a very
intimate, personal thing.
This feeling of wonder of a sense of
living in an comprehensible and beautiful
universe
[inaudible]
go partly comprehensible. That's the
beauty of it. I mean, if you're a lobster,
you don't have this thought, right?
And lobster doesn't get to
think about the laws of nature.
And so I've often thought to myself
that it's a blessing that we live in a
certain window of intelligence, that
if we were infinitely smart, godlike,
we'd have such powerful brains, we could
see every implication of everything.
So math wouldn't be fun for
an a being that's too smart.
And of course for the lobster
that's not smart enough,
math is no fun for them either.
It's in this intermediate window where
math and science become something to
rejoice in.
Today's program is about kind of
search search for order for patterns,
hidden truth in truth,
and it's about the scientists who go out
looking for those things and sometimes
find them, oh, what's
that? And sometimes don't,
I felt humiliated. I felt stupid.
Question is what makes these people
tick? And we're calling this show,
why do I love the fly
that's eating my brain?
That'll make sense later. I'm Jad
Abumrad. Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab.
Okay, you ready? Yeah. Off we go.
I think there's always been a desire
to somehow categorize and classify the
world around us.
I remember it and when you were in,
I don't know when it would be
like in eighth grade when they,
when the teacher comes in in general
science and he pulls down the periodic
table of elements or that. Yeah, sure.
I mean that was one of the first
times where I was like, yeah,
I don't want to be a
scientist. It's not for me.
But for kids who love this kind of thing,
take Oliver sacks for example. Yeah.
Chad, you should come in.
I should come in. Yeah.
So a couple of years ago we had went to
talk to Oliver sacks about something.
Well,
it's actually mostly you that was going
to talk to them and I was just tagging
along for the hell of it. Yup. And for
some reason we ended up in his bathroom.
I tend to read it for this and that,
maybe to look in a book or something.
He seems to have facts and figures in his
as well. There's a lot of us in there.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
And that's when we noticed you have
a periodic chart in the bathroom,
but he had a periodic Cuba, the
elements on the wall in the bathroom.
Here we are. Wow. How funny. Periodic
table in the bathroom. But then he said,
well, you know, if you
go out into the couch,
you'll see type of cushion cushions
employed with the periodic table.
And then he took us to his bedroom.
Although I don't usually take people
into my bedroom. Oh, he'll come where?
He showed us his periodic
table, comforter.
I tend to sleep here right under tungsten.
But the cool part was when he took us to
the living room where you had this, uh,
describe what isn't before us here. And
I'm like an Walter, it's like a little,
a little dictionary Stan on top of,
which was a beautiful mahogany
box, a fine wooden box,
like the size of a backgammon set,
core periodic table of the
elements is a very fine wooden box.
And if you care to open it all
right? It's, it's, it's uh,
it's made of some sort of fine wood
if it comes from Russia. All right.
Is there a trick to opening this? Oh,
[inaudible] okay. We've all seen the
periodic table of being Alona chart,
but I don't know the phrase box
there. There were the shovel elements.
These are all these and we have
here like 90, some odd little, uh,
little tubes, little solid UDL TV files.
Almost all the elements.
We'll have arsenic this myth
[inaudible] manganese, Merck can
nitrogenic molybdenum goal. Since I am,
for example,
having my 77th birthday tomorrow
and element 72 is half Niamh.
There is a little half a
million, a little rocks.
Here's what they're, what they
sound like. If he's grabbing me,
I have coming to me,
I hope it lives today and in got of
half Hafnum which will be very much more
satisfying.
What would you do with an in gap that
you can't do with the two little pebbles?
Uh, I'll be able to hold it in my hand.
I first love of chemistry had to do
with the, the said she wants a year.
We, one of the liquid elements
me, I loved the colors around me.
Lee Brown fluid, Ethan Luster, Pale
Golden. That can be very, very beautiful.
The, the physical properties is a gas
trapped in a little vial. Yes. I wasn't,
the one wouldn't want to
drop that. Why not? I will,
it's just not good to [inaudible] can
I just jump in here for a second? Sure.
Um, cause I, I, I really need to jump.
But the thing that's really crazy about
that box and this you don't get from,
uh, from looking at a period of chart
on a wall, is that all those elements,
Boolean Bull, carbon, nitrogen,
that's like the world.
I mean everything that we can see
and perceive. This table right here,
the depth in my mouth, sky
though ocean, the mountains,
it's all need of some
combination of elements.
That box and the box itself
gives it all in deep,
deep order.
I had noticed myself,
I can't help noticing that the elements
are organized in a very special sort of
way. For example, excuse me for
I have managed to not notice.
I find it a little odd that
you could organize them at all.
I don't even know how to begin the
process of figuring out they're related in
well, well then then you are sort of um,
recapitulating what you know, what
everyone felt in the, in the early days,
of course in the really early days people
thought they were just four elements.
The ancient notion of elements
took the form of earth,
fire and water.
Basically the thought that the whole
world could be composed of these four
ingredients in different ways.
But then in the 18th century,
we're skipping ahead a bit.
Chemists began to break things down into
smaller pieces like wind became gases
like oxygen and hydrogen and nitrogen.
And Earth got divided up into things
like sulfur, phosphorus ion, by the way,
do this kind of investigating.
Do you have to boil and pull and tongue
and fry and steam and do things like
that? All of the above.
So to fast forward,
after enough of this boiling and tugging
and frying and steaming [inaudible]
chemists got all the way down to
the root of it, which was the Adam.
That's really
what an element is. It's a particular
kind of Adam. The problem was though,
when chemists began to
start measuring these atoms,
they found that they were all
different sizes and types.
Like one would be heavy,
another would be light.
Third one would be really friendly,
likes to link up with other atoms where
as the fourth would be a loner and they
would come in combinations like heavy,
friendly, heavy, Shy, light, friendly,
light shine. What was the
pattern? That was the question.
Could they fit all of these differences
and similarities into one big,
you mentioned his name. You have to me
here, show you a picture of the um, um,
here's where we get to Oliver's hero.
The Siberian big a mist I skew is cold.
That would be Dimitri Mandalay, the great
men delay of whom we will talk about.
Oliver has a black and white picture
of him on his kitchen cabinets.
Man is not going to win any,
any beauty content? No. He uh,
he looks like a mixture
between a Rasputin and um,
uh, who do, I mean, what do you
mean? He has a big nose, a shaggy,
slightly unkempt white beard and
mustache that goes all over the place.
Piercing eyes, thick eyebrows and looks
like he's in a hunchback position.
Generally, if you met him on the sidewalk,
you'd probably want to
walk around him. Yeah.
He didn't believe in wasting
time going to a barber.
Let me just ask you as the degree of
your passion, when you look at this man,
do you think he's a beautiful looking
guy or do you see what I see? Um,
I think mentally I've had a
beautiful mind. All right. Okay.
In 1860, uh, along dating 16th,
there were trains going all over Russia
and [inaudible] could afford to take
trains. He was often on enormous
journeys and to wile away the tide.
Since he couldn't do chemical
experiments or whatever,
he would take playing cards with
the name of various elements,
their chemical and physical
properties, and he would play
what he called chemical solitaire,
sorting them for likeness or sorting.
I'm fed, I, I don't know the details,
but you know what we can imagine, right?
Sure. Let's just say he's Day
sitting there on the train.
He's looking out the window to get these
trees made of carbon carbon like a lake
made of hydrogen and oxygen, oxygen,
oxygen behind that amount
should be made of silica,
any shuffling the properties and
the atomic weights in his mind.
Wondering how do these things go to
Karen? What's the pattern? Any shuffling,
I'm shuffling, shuffling,
shuffling traffic,
and he did this for years until one night.
This we think is true.
In February of 1869 he has said
to have had a dream and his dream.
All the atoms have all the
elements of all the world.
If that wants a smaller points,
dense warrants, the heavy warrants,
the friendly ones to shine.
Once they all begin to dance
in his mind and then snapped
into a grid,
he awoke with a vision
of the periodic table.
Oh
dreams, which he then wrote
on the back of an envelope.
[inaudible] is the thing about what he
wrote on the back of that envelope is
that it starts out so
simply left to right.
The Adam's just getting heavier and
heavier Nav. You feel heavy on it,
but every so often, and this is
what he intuited in his dream,
is it while they're getting heavy,
are there other traits like whether
they're shy or magnetic or whatever those
traits, o repeat, UDL
decree changed Berger, Uri,
and every time they do start a new route,
it brought with these repeat again out
of this simple repeating structure.
Mentally, if you get a table that
you can read in a million ways,
there are so many ways to read this table.
I'm going to call this the PDL dictate
that if you use your imagination,
you can see yourself in there.
I was a rather shy kid with a,
uh, difficulty forming relationships. Um,
and I sometimes compared myself to the
inert gases in nerd cancers are very
isolated.
They react with nothing because I felt
that they too had difficulties forming
relationships. But um, I did, uh,
he has now left the chair and has moved
to the library as taking on an a hugely
thick, actually a dangerously thick book.
This is the handbook of
physics and chemistry.
As you'll see it says 5,000 pages.
I had a smaller version as a boy
and I'm from brooding in this book.
It seemed to me just possible
that one of the inert gases,
xenon might be seduced into combination
by the most active element of all,
which was flew in this lonely, lonely
gas might find a partner somehow. Yeah.
Did they ever get together? In fact,
it came to me with great joy when I found
out her in the 1960s that a actually a
Canadian chemist hadn't fact
made, a flew out of xenon
elemental love. And speaking of love,
he then took us, let's come
here to the living room.
And he showed us a small
painting in the painting.
There was this dramatic
figure of a bearded scowling
character on the side of a
mountain holding two stone
tablets over his head.
And the sky was filled with lightning.
And who was it? It was Dimitri Mandalay.
F when I heard of how mental AAF had, um,
discovered the periodic table,
I imagined men to laugh as a sort of
Moses going up to a chemical Sinai and
coming down with the
tablets of the periodic law.
And when I mentioned this fantasy
to Peter Celkon, my friend,
uh, an artist, he did this, imagine it,
of picture of the young Mendillo f peaks
of a chemical Sinai behind him holding
aloft the tablets of the periodic table,
which raises maybe the
deepest question of all,
did Mendeley a think this up and impose
it upon the world or was this pattern
always there? In which case mentally
you've just removed the veil and said,
oh, very, you are,
is the periodic table a
discovery or an invention?
Is it a human construct or is it a
revelation of the cosmic or divine order?
Is it so to speak?
[inaudible]
Radiolab. We'll continue in a moment.
Message one radio lab is funded in
part by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation.
The corporation for public broadcasting
and the National Science Foundation
radio lab is produced by W NYC and
distributed by national public radio.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by Squarespace.
The simplest way to create
a website this new year.
Make your next move with Squarespace,
whether that's starting a business
or launching a passion project,
no matter what your goals are.
Squarespace's award winning templates
can help you present your ideas to the
world.
Beautifully use offer code Radiolab
for 10% off your first purchase of a
Squarespace domain or website,
squarespace.com make your next move.
Make your next website.
Mitogen
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
yeah. Hey,
I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is Radiolab.
How do we continue with our ongoing
appreciation of the Great Dimitri Mandalay
[inaudible]
wow.
And, and,
and let's also get back to the question
that Oliver sacks asked about Dmitri
Mendeleev before the break,
which is when a scientist looks out
at the world and sees a pattern,
is that the scientist mind projected
onto the chaos of the world?
So is the discovery in the scientist
or is it out there in the world,
right? Meaning it just
exists independent of us,
doesn't care if we find
it or not. Exactly.
Is it a human construct or is it a level
Asian of the cosmic or divine order?
That's the question. And it
can lead to some fairly well,
sad and riveting. Do you
mind waiting for you? Ooh, this
story comes to us from Alan Lightman,
a theoretical physicist working out
in cal tech. Once upon a time, Alan,
when he was a scientist, he
was working on a problem,
a problem that had to deal
with on astronomic object
called a globular cluster,
which is a collection of
about a million stars.
So he's got a Glob of
stars orbiting each other.
And the question he's asked
is how do they hang together?
Tell me a little bit about the
gravity that links them. And he,
he thought he'd made a
discovery that was brand new.
So I was in the process of writing up
the paper. I'd done the calculations,
I was writing the paper and I was
in the library as one often does,
putting in the footnotes
and the references.
And one of the things that you do in
the references is you cite other people
have done similar things and ideally
you should do this before you start the
problem.
So I was flipping through some of the
most current journals and I saw a title
that looked alarmingly like the title
that my article would have been.
I got this terrible Pang,
a bang society that went through me.
Uh,
so open up the journal
and these two guys from Japan had
solved the same problem that I had and I
pulled out my notebook of results and
started comparing my results against their
results. And the numbers agreed
to like three decimal places.
So what they found was exactly
what you had found. Well,
they would have to find exactly what
I'd found because this is the world of
science and the world of science
has this terrible precision.
I was crestfallen.
I was a so disappointed.
I felt humiliated.
I felt stupid.
Uh,
and then another sensation went through
me and that was a feeling of amazement
that these two guys on the other side
of the planet with no communication with
me sitting at their desks,
worked on the same problem and
had gotten the same results,
the exact same results. You know,
all of the philosophers like Bishop
Barkley who said, it's all in our mind,
they're all wrong. Any scientist,
anywhere in the universe solving this
problem would have gotten that answer.
There. Willy is something outside of
our bodies and independent of our minds,
and this is both a wonderful
thing and a terrible thing.
It's a wonderful thing because
there's a beauty to it.
There's a feeling of power and
control. But the tragedy of this,
which I felt at the same time,
is that what is the relevance
of me as an individual person?
If anybody else could have
solved the same problem,
then why was I needed? What
is the meaning of my life?
How do I leave my
individuality on the world?
Certainly not through science.
[inaudible]
so here's what happened.
Alan gave up the practice of bench
science and became a novelist.
Einstein's dreams when the Pulitzer
Prize, great book. That's his work.
It couldn't have happened without him.
And that is a profound difference
between the sciences and the arts.
Jeff, if the Ode to joy had
not been in Beethoven's head,
you don't think they would
have come around? Yeah,
that's right. I,
the tempest is not going to have been
written by anybody but Shakespeare.
The brief and wondrous life
of Oscar Way oh by Juno Diaz,
which is the novel I just finished,
is going to have been written
by him. So it's good by
science. But let's, um,
let's argue the other side for
just a second. Okay. There's, oops.
Okay, I'm back. Um,
there's an idea floating around that gives
the scientists a little bit more. Um,
I dunno, you'll probably like it.
It comes from another physicist.
Can you just introduce yourself?
Casey, forget you're talking
today. I'm Paul Davis.
I'm director of the beyond center for
fundamental concepts in science at Arizona
State University.
So Paul Davies starts with a basic
question which humans have been asking
forever. Why are we here?
If you think about it,
it's totally crazily improbable that we
are here asking these questions that,
I don't know,
13.7 billion years ago
[inaudible]
the universe is born and a
shower particles that somehow
cool in just the right
way to form atoms,
which somehow gather in just the
right way to form stars and galaxies,
a planet with sunrises and sunsets and
just the right atmosphere to give rise to
a creature that can look at the
sunrises and sunsets and say,
wow,
if the fundamental laws of physics or the
initial conditions on the universe but
then is slightly different, then there
would be no life and no observers,
no one to say. Wow. And the question is,
is that a significant fact
or just an incidental fact?
A lot of scientists would say,
well, it's a fluke that we're here,
that we have a mind that
we ask these questions
and I think it's a big deal.
We've been made privy to the
fundamental nature of the universe.
The rules on which the universe runs.
It's basic laws. If we've just accident,
why aren't we just here looking at the
universe surviving but having no clue and
the only way I can make sense of it is
to suppose that there is some sort of
link between the laws of the universe
and the emergence of of life and
consciousness that the existence of
observers like ourselves is part of the
explanatory story.
In other words, says Paul,
the fact that we're here understanding
at least trying to know the universe
works on some scientific level. He
thinks that's part of the grand scheme,
that somehow the universe,
the atoms in the universe
need to be understood.
Well, the universe has engineered,
it's its own self awareness that that
the universe has thinking beings within
it. You can think about it.
I'm going to compare the thinking beings.
Like on the one hand maybe you had Cezanne
painting a portrait and on the other
you had Einstein doing an equation.
It sounds like if understanding
is the key that as you just said,
that this theory would
put the scientists ahead.
Well it does and I, you know,
I'm always wary about saying
that FFA are infuriating. My uh,
out out Scotty for example,
um, uh, that's not to diminish
the value of art and poetry,
but this thing we call silence
is a, is a near miracle.
I'm not using miracle
in the religious sense,
but the fact we can do
it I think is stupendous.
We're incredibly privileged and I
think there is some, uh, bigger,
I want to say agenda, but you have
to be very careful with these words,
but certainly a scheme and that we
judged that a scheme to be ingenious and
beautiful for reasons we know not
[inaudible] seems to me that the earth
would have a beautiful day and there was
no one around who could
reflect on all that beauty.
Then what is it? It's
there, but unappreciated.
It's not quite there enough.
You know, in the Bible,
God creates a bit of
the universe every day.
But at the end of each day, almost
as a necessary function, God says,
and it was good. He gives himself
a grade, she gets way off a grade.
So maybe this is just the Adam's way
of inspiring itself because what is a
scientist? It's just a bunch of atoms.
Yeah. You know, it's a nice idea.
But actually in the end I
don't buy it, you know? No,
cause he's saying that the purpose of
the universe is to create thinking beings
like us to examine it. And the best
examiners of them all are the physicists.
Well guess what? Here's a physicist.
He is the very thing that he sort of,
it's a little miss piggy. I, yeah.
And I don't think anything that we've
learned in science in past couple of
hundred years would lead us to believe
we are at the center of anything.
I think most scientists in the
world would agree with you. And,
and one more thing just on the
level of aesthetics of beauty.
Isn't it more beautiful to think
that all of this is an accident?
I hate that idea.
Why hate you think that that all of this
beauty coming into being by accident is
better than in having some purpose?
Yes. Because if it has a purpose,
it means it's supposed to be here.
And if it's supposed to be here,
then it's just somehow
little less. Um, amazing.
Do you know what I mean? Yeah.
I just think you're wrong. Okay.
Okay. Thanks. Let's keep it moving. Yeah.
Appreciating is the key according
to Paul Davis will in science,
that is sometimes harder than it sounds
because what if you're out there in the
world, you're on the cusp
of a major discovery.
It's right there in front of your face,
but you happen to be looking
the other way. For example,
take the story. So I'm very
excited to hear about your journey,
but first tell me who you are.
Okay. Uh, I'm Erica Lloyd.
I'm an editor and freelance writer.
Testing looks like the mic is on and
Erica recently took a trip with a bunch of
scientists. Everything
is working very far away.
Quite a ways
where exactly similar between Greenland
and Siberia and all you're seeing every
day is just lots and lots of ice.
What's that? What's that like?
Ice Is really beautiful.
July 5th among the deck.
We're looking in the Arctic
Ocean. I mean it's just
one guy called. It is
cold Campfire Chili. Here it's,
it's hovering around zero degrees.
I mean sometimes when the sun
is up and it's just sparked,
glean like diamonds,
look out. It's this mermaid thing.
You get how isolated you are.
Close to warmer clothes,
mittens. Maybe you can
introduce yourself. Rob resewn.
I'm a scientist at the woods
hole oceanographic institution.
He's sort of the main
guy of this expedition.
We have extra shoes like should
I wear one? You're welcome to.
So he raised the money. Millions of
dollars of government funding. Go for him.
Career wise, this is very
important. This is it.
When I was coming out of graduate school,
I was trying to think how was I going
to make my mark in the scientific world.
And you know, the more
mature a field gets,
the harder it is to do
something important.
And sometimes in graduate school
it can feel like you're, you know,
nine on bones as a scientist.
And I'm the Gaggle Ridge has
been a little bit of a, you know,
in a sense it's, it's one
of the final [inaudible]
frontiers. Wow. That's a shit petty. Nice.
So we're going to the Gecko Ridge
[inaudible]
well, it's one of the great,
unexplored places on the planet.
Basically it's an Arctic mountain range,
two or 300 miles from the north
pole at the bottom of the ocean.
It's like two and a half
or three miles deep.
Making matters worse in terms of
getting there at the top of the ocean is
covered in ice. Really,
really thick this ice.
But the thought is if you could somehow
get there, get underneath the ice,
get all the way down to
the bottom of the ocean,
you'll find volcanoes and you
know where you have volcanoes,
you might have hotsprings
where you have hot springs,
you might have life.
Just imagine blacks
really toxic, billowing out
of a chimney on the sea floor,
hot enough to melt lead Jesus.
All manner of bizarre biological
organisms making a little oasis around it.
And what kind of creatures were they
expecting to see? Weird kinds of,
I mean everyone wanted to
see a three eyed two words.
Yeah, really? Yeah. Is this a thing
as a three I tuber? No, not yet.
But the point is,
is that every time that they've seen these
hot springs in different parts of the
planet, they've found
completely new things.
Something like 600 previously unheard
of species like really strange looking
Schramm with eyes that had moved to their
backs and they have found tube worms.
Huh? Big Ones that look
sort of like plumes,
the really cool looking and they're
big. They have these little flower caps.
In any case,
this spot that they're going to for
various geological reasons that I don't
really understand. It might be
the most interesting one of all,
but no one's ever seen it,
huh? Huh? It's too early
in the morning. 3:28 AM
[inaudible] minutes ago. As soon as that,
but of course it took a few days to
get to the first site is probably our
colored location. This is a
place where there was evidence of
these fat,
so we thought, well, that's where
we're going to start, Erica,
how are they actually going to get
through the ice to go down? Well,
rob reef song thinking, how am I ever
going to get to the cackle ridge?
I had a newborn, a child,
this is I guess 1996 I was giving her
a bath and of course the whole layer of
bath bubbles. I mean you couldn't
see the bottom of the bath tub.
Then what are the toys that she
had was a sesame street submarine,
the cookie monster, and Elmo is the
captains and all this kind of stuff.
And we were playing around with it.
So we dove the submarine
under the layer of bubbles.
Oh wait a minute. The submarines
underneath the bubbles.
If we could develop robots,
robots that could go under the
Arctic ice cap to the sea floor,
that would be a way to
move beyond, you know,
nine on bones and navy
bring down some big game.
So finally, finally they're going
to put this thing in the water.
The verge of history. Man, I go down
and gone all the way here, Rico,
but the hell say we'd already gone.
I'm in this shack that's
sitting on the deck,
a nice small heated
enclosure and it's tiny.
There's a a couple of Grad
students and you know, I'm,
I'm hanging in there and just to
kind of squeeze into a corner.
Everybody's got these big exposure
suits on in case you fall into the water
pretty quickly. It starts smelling
like body odor and peanuts. You know,
it's not there. People are doing laundry?
No, they're not washing their fleets.
Oh, the stress level. How's your stress?
And then they, they dropped
the robot in [inaudible]
letting the baby go. No.
It's like sending your child to
preschool for the first time.
Okay. He is funny. And [inaudible]
so they're watching it go down deeper,
deeper, deeper, deeper, deeper, deeper,
deeper, deeper, deeper, deeper.
What's going down, down, down.
And they can watch on the
computer monitor on the screen.
What you're seeing is streams of
data. So it just, just stayed. I know.
Pictures, right? X, Y,Z , depth
time, love of blah, blah, blah.
Good. Let me get this down. Coming up,
the dropping is taking hours, hours,
writing about the meter
every five seconds.
Oh, so 12 meters per minute.
It goes now to 187 meters
are now at 220 meters.
373 meters or at what?
Cool. A hundred meters.
Right now it's exciting
to read the problem.
The problem is that nobody should need
music. I've got my iPod, you know,
they start playing
music. Let's do of course
[inaudible] and rolling.
[inaudible]
[inaudible]. Okay, awesome. Yep. Six
41 OBL and right. Six 41 six 31 meters.
Yes. So that's the new record. That's the
depth record for an ATV in the Arctic.
One or somebody go somebody to go
for breakfast, I'll go and just,
and that I'm not going anywhere.
I want to thousand yen.
So it's past the 1000 meter mark and
it's moved on and makes his first mission
goal a thousand meters.
Everything's looking great.
It's moving onto its next
goal, 2,500 meters. And then
Beta boards, it's mentioned what? Oh,
vehicle boarded the software died.
Separate bug software, bug software.
What's the matter with you? Can't you
test the software before we come up here?
So you're pissed off at this point? No,
I wasn't because I knew how hard it was
[inaudible] but I was so stressed out,
so stressed out. I had facial
tick tightness of my chest,
labored breathing, eating my fingernails
to my knuckles, you know, 10 years of,
of effort, millions of dollars,
his entire scientific career.
All of that is on the line. You know,
people kept asking me, of course,
you know, Eric, I, you know,
had aired a microphone there.
How do you feel trying to kind of get me
to take this kind of introspective look
on it? And I even try, I
like sat there, you know,
one night after things had kind of died
down and went on the front with the
stars and said, okay, you
know, feel the moment, dude.
I can't feel the moment.
We haven't had coms from the
AUV for two and a half hours.
I've gotta get back down there.
You only have so many days on station
to do what you've been planning 10 years
to do. And Front to a board. Yeah.
You're burning the clock. You know
Dick Dick, Dick, and you feel it, Dick
Dick. You feel that tick, tick, tick.
You can feel the Fuze tick,
tick, tick, tick, tick.
We're not finding vents here,
Dick. The clock is ticking.
Let's move on to this next site.
Well, we went through five times zones
to get there. Took a week, took a week.
Yeah. So you're back just chugging through
the yes. For a week. Yep. Yep, Yep.
Tick, tick, tick. And then, yeah.
Whoa. That's a guess. We're
hitting some ice here.
Everything's rocking everywhere.
Really, really big ice flow
moved in and ran us out of town.
Meaning you were stuck. Yeah. And
a big traffic jam of ice chunks.
Exactly. There's absolutely nothing
we can do. Tick, tick, tick.
We're just waiting in the eyes, you
know, and just be fired, like, ugh.
Or it didn't come up here
to wait, let's keep working.
Let's make something happen.
So the CTD team drops in their equipment
because that's what they do. You know,
if you're just sitting around
in your, dropped you [inaudible]
you think so they were just
stuck there and they're like, ah,
let's throw it over the side,
see what happens. Right.
And he found signals. Yeah.
Much stronger signals than they'd found
anywhere else. Oh, see they got lucky.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
it's like interesting stuff everywhere
is what it is kind of looking like.
And this time, did the robot
have a camera? Yeah. Ooh.
They got all this video
footage. Wonderful. Wonderful.
High definition video.
Superb. You know, and we could watch
from the ship. We're seeing it, you know,
in the control van in real time. Is it
gonna be two berms is going to be clams.
Is it going to be muscles? Is it going
to be snails? This is Phil [inaudible],
one of the engineers. Oh, over the
next rock. Now there is going to be,
there is going to be the next smoker,
there's going to be the next Cali field
with clams and mussels and who knows
what we're going to see.
And we go over this crater,
the big rim, and then drop
back down on the other side.
And we found these fight fields,
a whole hilltop fields just covered
in this. This is so eerie. It was,
it was, I haven't seen anything
like that before. Yellow, yellow
fluffing stuff.
And it was really beautiful
yellow fluffy stuff. Yeah.
It was just everywhere floating
around or were on the sea floor.
We were seeing ski slopes,
like cotton candy or something that
might be growing in your yogurt. Whoa.
What's that? Like? There'd be like a
waterfall on it or I know one fall. Wow.
Like it would just be coming
down rock. So scarps and wow,
kind of beautiful but but year.
And it was
really,
really frustrating what
there was a certain faction
on the ship that was really
disappointed and they were really angry
with me but telling me that I failed
them really. Absolutely. In
what way? That, you know,
the combination of the AUV [inaudible]
and our technology and my leadership
hadn't resulted in finding [inaudible]
worms. That's what we all wanted to see.
Everyone wanted to see a three eyed
to warm something really kind of
spectacularly new and creepy and weird.
And instead the new stuff
that we found was, you know,
this yellow fluffy stuff to the
fluff was just like whatever.
Well they was exciting
cause it meant well, okay,
hey what's going to eat this stuff?
We're on the right trail, right?
It's gotta be something eating this
stuff. Nothing seemed to be eating no.
Three I two worms
[inaudible]
and of course all of that is built on
the supposition that there are three eyed
two worms there to find, you
know, the world is the world.
The Arctic Ocean is the Arctic Ocean.
It doesn't care what we want to see,
what's there. Is there,
whoa.
So here's the interesting thing. Robbery.
If sones comes back all that way thinking
basically this trip that I've planned
for the last 10 years was a
bust. No vents, no two berms,
nothing cool and amazing, just
this fluff, whatever it is.
But then they get back and they look at
it more closely and they realize, okay,
this stuff is microbes but not
your run of the mill micro.
These are some of the oldest
known living organisms on earth.
We were the first to see it.
And what's funny is that like you didn't
even know that until you got back.
Thank you. Almost missed it. Yeah. Right.
Are you going to be doing this again?
Well, any more trips? Well that uh,
that's a good question. I mean, uh,
I'm broke now. Uh, the money's all gone
field programs over, I am a, you know,
a free falling a little bit,
but the three eyed worm
is still out there and
it's still there for the taking mythic
three, I'd worm the Unicorn of the Arctic
[inaudible]
thanks to rob brief zones. And
Erica Lloyd and also before them,
Katelyn walkin foots and the
Brooklyn Tech Cheer Squad.
Radiolab. We'll continue in a moment.
This is Christine Stone from Maplewood,
New Jersey.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hello, I'm Jad Abumrad.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab and we're talking about
how scientists think about the world
and appreciate, yeah, except appreciation.
This is something that scientists
do differently from the rest of us.
And I think this next story
is an act of appreciation.
So different from the rest of us
that it makes me want to Barf gag.
Bring it once upon a time in a rainforest
in Costa Rica and Central America,
there was a little buck fly. It's
a butterfly. Butterflies are here.
He flies that live in moist,
uh, tropical areas on route to,
they're not like New York
City flies. No, no, no.
What a butterfly does is when a bot
fly is pregnant and our butterfly was a
pregnant female,
but she has her baby flies up
into the air carrying a baby,
she sees in night hearing this feeder
grabs actually grab on to the mosquito
mid-flight and drops her baby on to the
mosquito. Why the mosquito? Well,
because the mosquito is going to do
something very important for the baby.
But the mosquito of course is a mosquito.
So it's looking to paint somebody right
when the mosquito lands in a nice warm
help potato potatoey math so she can have
the Bob by baby is programmed to fall off
into the mosquito bite and Mokolo. Wow,
that's impressive. Completely. Yeah.
And then mosquito probably has no
idea of any of this. No idea at all.
You got all that. Got It. Okay,
so now I want to introduce you
to a particular palpitating
mammal that happened
to be in Costa Rica on our very day.
I guess I was about 24 it was
a 1973 his name is Jerry Coyne,
37 years, I guess 35 years. But I
remember it like it was yesterday.
This isn't an unexperienced that you
forget easily working at Harvard as a Grad
student at the time. Yeah, I was,
I was doing a laboratory experiment
on flies ironically. And, uh,
there was a program for Harvard graduate
students to go to the tropics for two
months during the summer so they could
get some experience in the field and
learn something about the
diversity of tropical nature.
So now we've got Jerry coin, Costa
Rica walking through a forest,
doing some researchers and some research
and through the air you hear the
distance sound of a mosquito getting
closer and closer and closer to the Gerry,
right on the head, not too far from
the crowd. And uh, and I scratch
[inaudible],
you know, it didn't go away when it
got to be about the size of a pea.
I consulted one of my fellow students,
this friend of his happened
to be an entomologist.
She climbed up onto a bunk bed
and she looked in my head, pulled the
hair's bag, and she said, oh my God,
there's something moving in there.
That's when I freaked out completely.
I started running around the field
station and going, Oh my God, Oh my God.
I mean just physically running
in circles is mosquito bite.
It was a little hose or something
protruding through the top of the mosquito
bite and it was sort of wiggling around
breathing tube, like a little straw.
I was really completely freaked out.
I mean, I had a a worm in my body.
Nobody knew how to extract it. Why
couldn't you just grab onto the,
to the periscope part in Paul because
like all marvels of evolution,
the butt fly Maggot has devices to keep
you from pulling it out because it makes
his living in your body.
So it has a pair of hooks on the anal
and the other end that are dug into your
flesh. So if you try
to pull the thing out,
it just digs in and you'll break it into,
that is the thing you want to avoid
because it can cause a serious infection.
Now you don't want to do
that and you know you don't.
But what you could do however is you
could try what they called the meat cure.
Put a slab of meat over
the wound, strap it to you.
I would have to have
strapped, for example,
a stake to my head which
is not practicable and then
the worm thinks that you
know the worms breathing tube, which
is went through the mosquito bite,
it gets cut off and it's deprived of air.
So it thinks that the steak is part of
your flesh and it burrows up through the
steak and when it comes
out almost all the way,
you can just remove this steak with a
worm in it. But what a clever idea. Yeah.
The idea of toiling in the tropical heat
every day with a t-bone strapped to my
head was not something
that I wanted to do.
Meantime, it's some, it's causing
problems. This thing is a terrible
itch and from time to time it would like
move or switch and you'd feel this sort
of sharp pain, your score or you can
feel it grinding up against there.
And when I went swimming or took a shower,
we'd get sort of freaked out because it's
air hole would be cut off and then it
would really go nuts, you
know, make a lot of pain. So,
so I tried to avoid getting my
head under water. Meanwhile,
that lump was getting bigger and
bigger until it sort of got noticeable.
Wait, how does it, what does it eating
in order to get bigger and bigger? Well,
it's a
um, yes. Um, sitting my muscles
and tissue and my scalp.
It's eating your flesh
then. Yeah, it is. Oh,
that's turning human flesh into fly flesh.
This fly. It's eating Jerry.
So it's more and more.
Well it is Jerry. It is and that's
the part that made me like it.
So
Jerry and the part of Jerry that is now
the butterfly leave Costa Rica and it's
time to head back to Cambridge,
Massachusetts at Harvard University
where Jerry's the Grad student and uh,
you know, he has to check things out.
So I went to the health
clinic and you know,
in about 10 minutes there was 20 doctors
around me that nobody had ever seen
anything like this at Harvard.
They were all curious and poking and
prodding and looking at it and doing an
arm. But of course none of
them knew what to do about it.
Can I just decided screw
it, you know, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna let it come out and
make the best of it. I, you know,
enjoy it as much as I could
and, and marvel at it. I mean,
when you really think about it,
it is amazing that an animal can take
human flesh and turn it using its own
genes into a fly. I mean, and
you have to, marvel is so weird.
Have you actually, I mean, I
didn't even think this misbehavior,
it might seem weird to the
lay person, but to biologist,
it's sort of absolutely normal to, you
know, be very curious about something.
You know, I make my living on
flies, I've worked with fruit flies,
I'm a geneticist and, and here's
the fly making. It's living on me.
And I was getting more and more curious.
I wanted to see what it looked like when
it came out. I didn't want to kill it.
What about girls? I mean, assuming
you're dating. So like, yeah,
can just like a total turnoff. Say Hi,
this is me and my maggot. Well, I was,
you know, I was dating a
nurse at the time and this is,
this is the good thing
about it. The nurse was, uh,
actually quite fascinated with this.
Huh? I thought it was disgusting.
Cheryl Rogerson was Jerry's friend.
She inspected the fly. Did
you give it a name? No.
No. Jerry May have felt that way
about it, but uh, no I didn't.
This was more of a scientific
experience. This is something you were,
it was okay with you. Well,
I don't remember being informed that
there were any other options. I thought,
I thought this is just what had to happen.
So a couple of weeks pass and the
butterfly is just getting, yeah,
bigger and bigger and bigger. It goes from
Jelly bean size to something like
the size of an egg. An Egg. Yeah.
It was pretty big. Like a quail egg. Well,
he's covering it now with a baseball cap,
which is maybe one reason why they decided
to go to Fenway park one particular
evening. That is correct.
[inaudible]
yeah, there's the Psych Yankees game.
I wasn't gonna miss that. And uh, every
once in a while I would rub my head,
I mean, throughout this whole gestation
of this thing, just to check on it.
And during the game when
I wrote from my head,
I felt something coming out of the
lump. Jerry kept saying, oh my gosh,
oh my gosh, it's coming out. I can feel
it. So was this a little distracting?
Uh, yeah.
A foul ball came up where
you were sitting in it
damn.
And one of those wooden seats at Fenway
and we've narrowly escaped getting hit
because we really weren't paying
much attention to the game at all.
[inaudible]
but it took a long time. I mean, it
started at the game and then it went on,
started the game and, and
continued on until the evening
back to Jerry's apartment.
And he kept reaching up and checking to
feel the lump and we were just hanging
out and
Morris gave in that and he
said he reached up and said,
it's gone.
We've gotta find it.
I turned on the light and there was
on the pillow and it was horrifying.
What did it look like? Is it
a weekly little wormy thing?
It's sort of bulbous on one end and
then it tapers down to a little tail.
It's white fat, white Grub,
warm inch and a half long,
and it has little black tea.
[inaudible]
no, I thought, oh my goodness.
That's what was in my head.
Had I known that I might've
been more freaked out.
When you are greeting your baby there,
did you have a feeling of pride or just,
well, no extreme curiosity. Um,
the one thing that was extremely
striking to me was that it's,
it's exit was completely
painless. Um, you know,
it's painful when it's in
there, but when it comes out,
it does so very painlessly and that's
another evolutionary phenomenon.
Of course it's the, if the worm
was did it painfully and exited,
then the horse or the monkey or whoever
it's infecting would just slap it and
kill it. So what did you do when you
had the baby there on the pillow then?
I decided I was going to try to rear
into an adult fly, you know, um,
aside what you do. So I,
I had prepared a jar of sterile sand.
I took the worm and I drafted into the
sand and put the top on with air holes
and hope that, um, it would, pew
paid, but unfortunately it died.
Did you get sad? I was
extremely sad, you know,
in the temperate zone in Boston about
flight is not gonna make it and just can't
live. And so it was doomed from the start,
but I wanted to see it
complete its life cycle.
And unfortunately it
didn't quite make it so
I did the best they
could with what I knew.
You know, I, I think it's as an added
some richness to my life. It really did.
People still get completely horrified
when I tell them this story,
even though to me is, you know, it's sort
of a nice store.
Jerry [inaudible] works at the University
of Chicago and his forthcoming book is
called why evolution is true and
we have time for one more story.
A couple of years ago, I sat down
with one of the great bug scientist,
insect scientist in the
world. His name is Tom Eisner.
He teaches up at Cornell and has taught
more scientists to love insects than
anyone in the world probably.
And I guess I wondered if you spent
your whole life having feelings and very
sophisticated feelings about
tiny, almost alien lifeforms.
How does that happen?
We spoke at the 92nd
street y in Manhattan.
It's an insects. Can you remember when
it began? According to my parents,
when I first stood on my
feet, great. Right here.
The Button was box MD, Beatles,
caterpillars, ants, termites,
cockroaches. I've picked them up.
I learned quickly not to put
them all in my mouth. Uh, I kept,
I'm in my room. My Room was Zune.
You were born in Berlin,
correct? From a Jewish family.
You were, what, about three years
old when you left or thereabouts?
Three years old went to Spain.
So you went from the Nazis
in Berlin to Spain? Yes.
And the Spanish civil war fled for France.
My parents decided we should really
start somewhere else and we went to South
America. And that was an
entomological paradigm.
Every living organism
has some sort of coder.
You can build these up in your memory.
And I used to take a whiff of that
in second classify in my mind's eye,
according to what place smells
like Caterpillar and Beatles.
And do you ever dream
of insect? Yes. Yeah.
I tend to dream that I am in
insect. What does that mean?
That your dream that you are in, in Sec?
I mean you were scurrying and walking
upside down on the ceilings or leave even
escaping. Sweating's um,
the weirdest situation that I ever got
into in a dream was like dream that it
was an insect.
And I was telling another insect that
occasionally dreamed that I'm a human.
That's your dream.
Insects were somehow my great love.
It was very much a loner. And, uh,
if I didn't have a room full
of insects live, I was unhappy.
Tom, I wanted to ask you,
and at this moment, uh, Oliver
sacks who was on the stage with us,
he asked Tom this question
whether you feel that insects
respond to your, you know, whether,
whether you feel them sort of
polling and whether they, um,
they know that you're gentle
and reliable. And for them,
you know, it's, it's a, it's
a good question. I don't,
I don't presume to read responses
on the part of the insects,
but the older I get,
the more difficult I find it to experiment
with them and they were ways that
killed them. Um, bombardier
beetles can live four one,
two up to three years in your lab.
You become very attached to them.
You give them names and when
they die, it's an event.
So you must somehow have moments where
you feel that things are going on in that
tiny little brain that they have
secrets hidden up their sleeves that uh,
they might reveal. If you
find a common language,
I find that I can love nature no matter
how distant the individual organisms are
from me,
but I reach out and hope that
I can shorten the distance
and create some feeling
of coexistence.
[inaudible] a
[inaudible]
Tom Eisner's book is called
for the love of insects.
It's really what it's called. Yeah.
Well, we should go check our website,
radiolab.org for more information,
and you can always send us an
email@radiolabatwnyc.org Radiolab is
one word. Yes, it is. [inaudible] boom,
rod. I'm Robert Krulwich.