Are Listening to radio lab radio lab
from
W. N. Y. S. E. N. N. P. R. Hey, I'm Jad
Abumrad and I'm Robert Krulwich. Yep.
This is radio lab and a today. Just
to start things off for this podcast.
All right. Let's just say
that you love an author,
but somehow the text isn't enough. Okay?
It doesn't get you close enough
to the author. So what do you do?
You know what you do,
but take off your shoes.
You take off your stocks as you stand
on the plan and the book and your whole
body. Let me, yeah, let me give
you a different flavor that,
hello? How about you take the tex,
give it to this guy he puts into a
computer and you turn it into data?
What do you mean? Who is that I,
this is a, My name is Ian Lancashire.
I'm a professor of English
at the University of Toronto.
Now, Ian, as he said,
is an English professor, but
he's also a computer guy, right.
Founded a computing center
with the help of IBM Canada.
And the reason he combines those two is
because he's interested in the secrets
behind the authors word and that desire.
He says to take a text,
spin it the data as a way to get
into that author's head. Well,
that goes back to long way. It goes back
to the fathers of the Christian Church.
It's the Bible. In the early Middle Ages,
some monks decided to make what's
called a concordance of the Bible.
And what that means is they were going
to take every single word in the Bible
and there are 960,243 of them, at
least in the King James version,
and they're going to list
them all alphabetically,
notate each time every single word was
used and the context, oh, Yay. Yes.
Imagine it. You begin
with the first, first.
In the beginning
you create a heading for the first word
n, and then for the second word, Duh.
And then for the third beginning,
every time you come across those words,
you have to write a context.
In genesis one verse one the
current one in the beginning,
genesis one per sixth
Kearns two and God said,
let there be for a minute in the myths,
all handwritten and at the end you n
well you end up with a a lot of pieces of
paper. So many that it, it took
those first monks, you know,
who decided to do this an entire
lifetime to complete it. Nowadays,
you know, with computers you
can be done in under 15 seconds.
So that all just basically sets the stage
for the story that I'm about to tell
you, it's the 1980s Ian is an
English professor, Toronto.
He's got a lab full of kids computers
and he's using them to analyze his
favorite authors, Samuel Taylor
Coleridge, TSL, IA, James Choice, Cadman,
Chaucer, Shakespeare, and he's starting
up some interesting stuff sort of,
for example, in his poetry,
Melton didn't use the word
because who knows why. Yeah.
But at a certain,
Ian decided to look at more modern
authors and so I turned to Agatha Christie
[inaudible] at the time he was doing this.
We're now in the nineties Agatha Christie
happened to be the most published
author ever. She sold a
billion books, a billion,
like be billion. She was
number one failing God after,
after the Bible. I think.
So what I did is I collected two of her
earliest novels written in the early
twenties fed those 200 Peter
and I did the third [inaudible].
Eventually you would add in 14 additional
books that cover 50 years of Agatha
Christie's writing. What does
the computer doing exactly?
Measuring the individual
concordance, word frequency,
vocabulary of the works and all the
while it's spitting out these reports.
And I saw the totals at the bottom.
So all this is first of all,
a woman written needling
detective Knowles,
which is just amazing in and of itself.
Something the computer found that her
use of language was relatively consistent
and normal, uh, for the
first 72 of those books.
But something happened on book
number 73 something drastic.
What suddenly her use of
words, like words like thing,
anything, something, nothing.
What Ian Calls indefinite words.
These these words increased six times,
but also when the computer added up
the vocabulary size of that book,
that is how many different words
are there in the first 50,000 words.
If a text it found in this book
there were 20% fewer different words.
That is astounding. That's one
fifth of our vocabulary lost.
It gradually dawned on him that what he
might be seeing was the very beginning
stages of an author
mm
losing herself. She had
developed Alzheimer's
[inaudible].
I delayed publishing my
results for two years.
I had to to have the results analyzed
by computational linguist and a
statistician and in her lifetime
was she ever actually diagnosed?
Absolutely not. There was no diagnosis.
He said that some of her biographers
suspected that something was up in her
later years. One point parently
she cut off all of her hair.
She was not doing very well in
interviews as far as we know.
She was never taken to a
doctor, never got diagnosed.
I think her family closed
around her and protected her
[inaudible].
I realized that I was seeing
something about the human mind.
I was seeing the author in the text in
a way that people hadn't seen the author
and the texts before.
Um,
raised the question for me. And I
think this can apply to anyone. I mean,
we all write a bazillion emails a day.
I've got a decades worth on my computer.
Does that stuff cold clues about what
will be like early warning signs?
I think it's possible. It does, yes.
And it's well worth doing research
about how a loss of vocabulary can be
determined, let's say in man's email
over five or six years. Indications are,
he says that those clues
are there. Not only that,
they may actually be there practically
from the beginning. Oh, Yup.
Yup. Very famous example is
the so-called none study. Okay.
The nun study actually began in 1990
and what's this is Dr Kelvin Lim.
He works at the University of Minnesota
and is the current director of the
so-called none study and this study
more than any other that we know really
makes the point about the predictive
power of the words we choose.
Study began with a guy named David
Snowden who wanted to look at aging over
time. So he chose nuns because he wanted
a group that was healthy. For example,
they don't smoke, they don't drink,
they all have similar lifestyles,
obviously haven't had children.
So he approached this one
particular order in Connecticut,
all the school sisters of Notre Dame and
he signed up just short of 700 nuns and
the only stipulation being you had
to be at least 75 years of age.
And so we're now 20 years in the study.
So that means the youngest of the
sisters is about 90 yeah, I think I am.
I am the youngest. And you
are 94 years old? Yes sir.
Not 95 not 95
this is sister Alberta Sheridan.
I like the way you said that.
Do you happen to know who the oldest
remaining sister in the study is?
Wait a minute now. The
one who was very today,
John was 101 I think she was the oldest
one in the study. Wow. In our province.
Yes. The study began,
uh, innocently enough.
She says the researchers would
show up to the convent every year,
give the nuns a bunch of tests.
But like mostly from memory,
we just questioning back and forth.
Right. And then over the years,
as the nuns passed away, which
many of them have at this point,
they've all gone check of the
original 678 sisters. At this point,
we have approximately 40 sisters still
alive and participating in the study.
And I'm the only one left
here in the Wilton province.
And as an unsurpassed away,
the researchers had arranged it so that
they would get a small piece of their
brains, which they could examine
for plaques and tangles. Oh,
this morning we buried assister here.
I told you at the funeral was delayed a
bit because she had to be taken to the
hospital to have a portion of her
brain removed to further this study.
Oh, [inaudible]. Okay.
So here's why I bring this
study up because of an
accident that happened pretty
early on, the changed everything in the
study, David Snowden, the main dude,
was in the, uh, convent archives
and he was talking to the archivist.
Yorkville says to him, Hey, you know,
all of these nuns that you're studying,
who right now are over the of
75 I actually have the essays
that they wrote right when they got here.
And they did this roughly at about
age 18, like 60 years before.
Oh, yes. Oh yeah. Right. I
have a copy of it at home.
Thank you so much.
We actually asked to report
or Naomi Sterban to visit
sister Alberta at her home
in Connecticut today and having her
read her essay that is now 76 years old.
Yeah, go ahead.
[inaudible]
oh,
two days after the birth
of the Christ child,
I was brought as a belated Christmas gift
to Mr and Mrs. Albert Joseph Sheridan
of Providence, Rhode Island. A week later,
the sparkling waters of
baptism were poured over me.
Nicklin read all the silly stuff
that when I first entered. Why not?
It sounds kind of Saccharin. I
was only a teenager when I wrote,
but here's the thing. When the
researchers found the essays, like
when you just heard it was a gold
mine, there was a major, major find.
So the analyze the essays looking
primarily at two specific features of the
language that was contained in these
narratives that Serge, AICPA, Houma,
he does the analysis for the
current and unsteady particular,
they looked at the notion of grammatical
complexity and a idea density.
What is idea density? What does
that mean? Density is, um, a,
um,
measure that looks at how many basic units
of meaning are contained in any given
utterance divided by the total
number of words in that utterance.
In other words,
the date of my birth is December 27th.
Like if you'd listen to sister
Alberta's autobiography,
when I was 11 years of age, my
dear mother was called to God.
It's the number of little discrete ideas
she's able to cram into one sentence.
This was to be a turning point in my life
as I had always had the odd desire to
become a sister.
Here's a classic example of the difference
between low and high idea density.
Here's low
from sister Helen. I was born in a Claire,
Wisconsin on May 24th,
1913 and was baptized in same
James Church. Okay, that's low.
Now here's high from sister Emma.
It was about a half hour before midnight
between February 28th and 29th of the
leap year in 1,912 when I began to live
and to die as the third child of my
mother whose maiden name is Hilda
Hoffman and my father auto Schmidt.
I got to say I'm liking
the first one, Jed,
probably you as a journalist seen the
first one as straight to the point.
Yeah, it's good writing. The second one
seems kind of embellished a little bit.
Yeah, but here's the punchline of all.
Well, this turns out that the people
who when they were 18 wrote in that
journalistically very precise,
low idea density sort of way.
Those people 60 years later, we're vastly,
vastly more likely to develop dementia.
In fact, based on those essays alone,
the researchers could predict with about
85% accuracy what the nuns brains would
look like when they died and were
able to look at the brains. I mean,
would the brains have plaques and tangles
that you associate with Alzheimer's or
would they not? What I
mean that's just crazy
why it's backwards reasoning. But
we'll see you, we'll see. I'm, I'm,
I'm just suddenly, I'm suspicious. Here's
a man who, from what you just said,
has found the ones who got sick and
working backwards found certain incidences
of this, that or the other. And this, ah,
this is a cause that produces
this effect. No, no, no, no, no.
There is no cause and effect here.
These studies are demonstrating
associations, right?
They're not demonstrating causality.
It's a very important distinction.
This is just the correlation.
Okay. But you know,
that may be one of 190 correlations that
produce people who get Alzheimer's in
the end. Yeah. I mean, yeah, I mean,
but let me argue your case actually
from a different angle. Like,
would this kind of linguistic
analysis actually be relevant in the,
in the age of Twitter where everything
is short and clip people Twitter only
Twitter, they might also write um,
small, short tens essays for their yeah.
But no, you know, man,
I guess you are right.
It's like it's mostly about
the thoughts in your head,
not so much why you write well.
So what about Agatha Christie?
Was there a conclusion about
Agatha? Yeah, there was,
I get the Christian writing.
Elephants can remember.
This brings us back to
Ian Lancaster and uh,
that 73rd book of Agatha
Christie's that he analyzed,
found that her vocabulary dipped
well before he did the analysis.
He picked up that book and gave it a read.
And like most people who
read it didn't like it.
Initially I thought it was very
poorly written, badly plotted,
full of errors of time
of dating, terrible read.
Then I realized when I looked at
the title, elephants can remember,
he realized that maybe
Agatha Christie sensed
what was happening to her.
She was responding to that truism
that elephants never forget the a,
the chief character is an,
an aging female novelist named Ariadne
who is a foil for I get the herself and
she Ariadne is suffering from
memory loss in the story.
She tries to help a
detective self this crime,
but she has trouble cause she keeps
forgetting. And uh, the last, uh,
the last sentence in that novel
in fact, is Agatha Sang, well,
maybe it's okay now.
Do you remember
she was trying to defend herself,
defend her sense that she was forgetting
she was losing her vocabulary.
She was losing her language.
I began to see that Kristi was heroic,
still writing despite this handicap and
her willingness do that at an age of 81
82 struck me as is heroic in a way.
Well, I understand that
the amuse wouldn't quit,
but the tools all left the room. Yeah,
I think we should leave the room. Okay.