Hey Robert. Yes.
Woken from a long desperate slumber.
Robert Krulwich opens his left eye
then his right alerted to the presence.
Hey Robert. Oh, right here. Okay.
That's you. I have a thing I want,
I would like to share with you and then,
um, by extension the people out there.
What would you like to share?
Something you've been mulling. Yeah,
so I recently completed a,
a sort of a mini series,
a in conjunction with a film that's now
out in the world called boy erased for a
project that we called unraced.
If people can hear it like yeah,
put it out for episodes. It's out there
in the world, in the wild on iTunes,
Spotify, all the places and uh, uh,
I want to play one of the
four today cause I think it's,
it's just I think [inaudible]
I think in all honesty, I should probably
say I've heard them as it happens.
Yes. Here's the things that
sort of like that sort of,
I found sort of just about the third
one at this. That's our first one.
Here's a really important
moment in American history,
I guess you'd have to say in American
cultural history. Yeah. And uh,
it almost feels like a single individual
walks into one room and says something
startling to a group of very important
people because of an accidental moment
that he just happened to be over here
talking a scholarly conversation.
So by a crazy quilt of
serendipity, enormous changes.
Now,
now this may be oversimplifying it and
I'm sure there's a lot else going on.
Deeper and shallow. We're rhythms,
but the changes come almost by accident
because someone misses a train.
Yeah, yeah. That's a, that's a pretty
good, you go, there you go. Okay. Uh,
so can we play it? Yeah, let's play it.
This is unraced a new podcast that
reveals the hidden history of conversion
therapy in America. I'm Jad
Abumrad. This is episode three.
Let's start this episode by talking
about one of the great successes in
psychology.
If you are living with
a mental health problem,
it can be hard to know which way to
turn or what to do to feel better.
It's called CBT cognitive
behavioral therapy.
You hear about it sometimes in the news,
uh, around, uh, treatments for PTSD.
Like suppose a soldier is
triggered by a loud sound. Well,
what the therapists will sometimes
do is take that same sound,
play it for the person over and over,
but under less and less
stressful circumstances
until gradually over time the
sound gets less stressful.
CVT focuses on goals and focuses mostly
on the present day and things that are
affecting you and your life.
Now these kind of techniques can
help people with gambling addiction,
stop gambling. People
who smoke, stop smoking.
It is a hugely important
wave in psychotherapy.
It's often called the second wave.
Freud was the first. This is the second.
What follows is a story about one of
the Grand Poobah because of this second
wave in a grand awakening that he had,
it kind of blew up the world
too.
Okay. Maybe that's overstating
it, but no, no, no. I don't know.
Start, start from all you know
about Jerry. So Jerry is a god. So
case in point, this guy,
this is David Tesler,
we bumped into him digging through
some archives at the association for
behavior. And cognitive therapy,
central office. My colleague Shima Oli,
I and him were hunting around
for some tapes while they were,
you sort of offhandedly mentioned
that like yeah, Jerry. Oh, he's,
he's trained practically
everybody in the field.
We, we have this thing called, um,
there's this river tree and it basically
plots the several different people from
whom almost every single
contemporary psychologist came from.
Cherry is one of the six because how
many people own their careers to him?
You might call him one of the six cardinal
bishops of contemporary psychology.
Hi. And My name is Sigmund Freud. Yeah.
Yes. Gerald G. E R A.
L D middle initial C,
last name Davidson d a V.
I s o n Professor of psychology at
the University of Southern California.
[inaudible]. Jerry grew up in the 1940s,
Orthodox Jewish household playing stick
ball in the streets of Boston at a time
when the streets were pretty empty because
of the war that was a good little boy
and didn't get into trouble. And um,
since he was kind of a quiet kid,
wasn't a particularly cheerful
child, I would say analytical,
watchful. Anyhow,
Jerry eventually finds himself
one day working in a ham factory.
Pardon me?
Yeah. And a ham. They say like
Hammon like ham and eggs. Wow, okay.
Kind of a weird place for a Jewish
kid to be. But there he was.
So I had a job in the
graveyard shift at the start,
like at midnight and go until 8:00 AM
one day he is at the ham factory or maybe
on his way to the ham factory board.
What was there to do? So I always,
I was reading,
somehow I settled on Freud's introductory
lectures at Clark University,
well that he gave and
the early 20th century.
So he's reading Freud and the ham factory
reading Freud's lectures and something
about it hooks him, but also
horrifies it. This book made
a profound impact on me.
I stopped at [inaudible], we moved to
[inaudible]. [inaudible] [inaudible]
okay, so this is Freud that
you're hearing right now. Uh,
don't know what the hell he's saying.
Apparently this is the only
recording of him that exists.
Well, um, concert.
He's talking about unconscious
and kind of make that word out.
And Jerry says, uh,
the whole idea that you can like peel
back the layers of a human psyche.
It was absolutely
almost voyeuristically fascinating.
The same time he says, I felt like
some of the things Freud was saying,
which is kind of weird. How can
foist say, if you dream of a
[inaudible]
train going into a tunnel
you're really dreaming of
having sex with your mother.
Anyhow,
something about the book both intrigued
and enraged him enough that he goes to
Stanford and then Stonybrook and to make
a long story short ends up standing at
exactly the right place where many streams
converge to create the first real up
ending of Freud, the behavioral therapy
revolution.
Previously it had been all about
dreams and the subconscious.
Now it was scientific that was
about experiments. And you know,
the basic question,
how do you sit with a suffering
human being and help them?
How do you make someone happier,
less anxious, less suppressed?
Do you remember the first
patients you started seeing?
Yeah, the so called [inaudible],
you know the Avis y. A. V. I. S.
It's another acronym called young, young.
I went the ace stand
for able or attractive,
but they gave this
patient, it's the patient.
We're living it up for
you. Oh, it is. Okay.
It is a term psychotherapies
that described the
[inaudible] young, attractive,
verbal, intelligent and successful.
That's it. You got it. So you know,
early on he says he saw a
lot of people who were um,
your classic art variety neurotics,
which is not a very complimentary term,
but he says that is what
they used to call them.
But the whole reason we're telling you
this story is that in that initial batch
of patients, Jerry says,
he began to see like fairly
frequently these young men walk in.
They were mostly young men who complained
that they were sexually attracted to
other men and they really wish
they weren't. That's right.
He says he can't remember
how many exactly walked in.
Maybe somewhere between four and a dozen.
I'm trying to think of there
were, they all came and,
and I supervise some cases in
the training clinic at Brook.
They all came because they weren't
happy and they wanted to change.
They wanted you to turn them
from gay to straight. Yeah. Yeah.
And not wanting to, you know,
impose my heterosexual values on them.
Some would say my heterosexist values
on them. I would check it out with them.
Can you tell me a little bit about what
living situation is like your
social life and whatnot and brands?
Nancy got an apartment off
campus I live with by myself
and in fact the film myself last
year where I really played myself,
I wasn't acting,
but we did have a graduate student play
the role of a troubled homosexual young
man who wanted to change.
You'll see in that film a
pretty reasonable rendition.
Have you ever previously been to
any therapists? No. In a thought.
I'm going to you. Yeah.
Gary says that the film that he made,
which you're hearing is sort
of a composite of all the
cases that he saw of this
kind. And what you see in
the film is hymns in a suit.
Sitting in one chair a couple of feet
away from him as a young man with big
seventies hair,
not the same age kind of having trouble.
And the guy explains that. He did.
He did. He's having trouble concentrating.
Yeah. I, uh, I'm having a
trouble getting down to work.
It turned out that he was recently
frightened by an intensification of his
lungs, standing attraction to men.
Gary says initially he had no
idea what to do with these cases.
They were anxious, very
depressed. These were folks who,
the kind of people who could,
you know, commit suicide.
He says he felt like you just had
to help. That's what I was taught.
That's what I was taught.
And so in the film,
can't get into it. You don't, after
maybe, I don't know, 15 minutes.
Well, I'd like to outline for
you. Wait, I can procedure.
Okay.
Now before we actually get
into that procedure, uh,
just a little bit of
context isn't necessarily,
oh, I know that inside now
I am sick. I'm not sick.
Just sexually I'm sick in a lot of ways.
It's time. Jerry was not the
only therapist in the situation.
There were a lot of therapists all
around the country trying to quote,
help their gay patients
say, [inaudible] isn't back health.
Anything that we can do to prevent
future generation wrong suffering.
This reflection must be
the overall approach. Certainly
did not start with me.
There were other people who were doing
what was called behavior therapy with
gaze. Most of it was a version.
Terrible change comes from
poverty. The ordinance so strong,
which was applying electric shocks
when they saw pictures of same sex,
you know, people,
um, or making them nauseated
with objections. You vomit again
and again, all over everything.
Jerry, your members,
one of the leading aversion therapists
coming to Stoneybrook where he was
training at the time to give a lecture
and the Guy Shows 16 films of how it was
done.
[inaudible] the screen,
the film showed researchers
hooking up gay men,
two electrodes to their fingers or their
forearms. Show them pictures of men.
Naked Man.
Okay, did you get your shot?
And then they would shock them, hurting
them and flicking physical pain.
They then show them another slide
of a naked gay man. Do it again.
[inaudible] Hey,
this bothered me. Uh, just
personally, this hat does this.
It bought the idea of an, of
intentionally inflicting physical pain.
On other people. I just worried
about it. It was cringeworthy.
Interestingly, Jerry doesn't fall.
The researchers who administered those
shocks picture that they were like
dentists before novacane
in a pulling a tooth.
I am old enough to remember what going
to the dentist was like to get a filling
or getting a tooth pulled, uh,
before there was novacane find
the right analogy though. I mean,
if your tooth hurts, you
need to have it pulled out.
You don't need to have homosexuality
pulled out if you may not think so.
But if, if you're gay and the 1960
ultra Americans, I repelled by
the mere notion of homosexuality,
your being haunted and
discriminated against.
The CBS News survey shows that two out
of three Americans look upon homosexuals.
We've discussed discomfort or fear
being told that you're an evil
person and you're disgusting.
These people need help.
And so what Feldman was trying to do
Belvin was leading a version therapist.
He was the guy that showed that film.
He was doing the best that he could
given what was available knowledge.
You didn't, they were just
trying to help the patient.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah. That's why
I don't demonize him
in any case,
as Jerry is sitting there in the back
of the room watching this guy film and
show this film of people being tortured.
Okay?
He says he just kept thinking cheese.
Do we have to do it this way? But
people were saying, well, but it works.
And that's what the literature was
telling us. But I was thinking, well,
are there other ways to do it?
And so what Jerry decided to do was take
the basic idea of aversion therapy and
flip it.
So what am I supposed to do now?
And I'm supposed to argue. Well, um,
I'd like you to follow me if you
can. I don't want to say now,
and this is what you see in the film.
He basically tells the patient, um,
here's what I want you to do.
Grab a copy of Playboy magazine.
Okay? A, you can probably get hold of a
copy of playboy. Don't too much trouble.
The new standards. Yeah,
go to the newsstand, get a copy.
Playboy was what I thought of as a
source of material of attractive women.
Then he says, when you get back home,
get yourself aroused or
whatever you're accustomed to,
think about a man thinking about his body,
you start masturbating with you, a
homosexual image. Now there comes a point,
you know, the inevitable point
at that point of inevitability,
switch over to the female picture.
Have you had your climax? Okay.
And, uh, you know,
misca idea was instead of shocking
people in to hating their gay thoughts,
he would gently encourage them to take
their positive gay thoughts and map them
onto a different [inaudible]
body. I fact,
I think the technical term
was orgasmic reorientation.
And in the video, apparently
it seems to work in the video.
A Jerry checks in with him about
10 times and the guy tells him,
at first it was really hard for him to
finish the deed while looking at female
pictures. But then it got
easier and easier until finally,
after about 10 of these sessions,
I really feel like I'm really getting
into it now. Uh, but happened was,
um, every time I masturbated,
I found now that I could go straight
through without any trouble, you know,
with uh, do you like, do
you like what's happening?
I think the thing I like most
is I now see some direction,
I feel myself moving towards something
as opposed to not knowing which way I was
going to go. And I
think that's a good too.
Okay. Setting aside for a moment,
the question of whether this
therapy actually worked. Uh,
I think you can guess the answer to that
and it is not the point of the story.
What happens next is that this therapy
takes on an entirely surprising and
consequential life of its own.
And that's after the break.
I'm Jen. I'm Rod unraced on radio
lab. Yes. Continue in just a moment.
This is Katie from big sky, Montana.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org.
Hey, this is pat Walters. I'm an
editor and producer here at the show.
And I have a quick announcement to make.
We have an email newsletter. Now
you may be thinking, so what?
Everybody has an email newsletter,
but the thing that I like about ours
is Radiolab is put together by this
eclectic bunch of Weirdos who I
feel super lucky to work with.
And every week we put out this newsletter
that is filled with stuff that they
have noticed out in the world and found
interesting or surprising or weird in
some way and want to tell you
about movies, TV shows, books,
magazine articles, photo
essays, strange music,
things that they've heard on the Internet.
And it's a cool way to get a peek
behind the scenes into the brains of the
people who put the show together every
week. So please sign up. It's free,
it'll take you 30 seconds.
Just go to radiolab.org/newsletter or
send a text message that says r l news as
in radio lab newsletter two
seven zero one zero one again,
that's r l news two seven
zero one oh one thank you.
Hello Radio lab listeners. Are you hungry
for an extra helping of science? Oh,
of course you are.
Have we got a podcast for you from wny c
studios and the team behind the popular
youtube series sideshow.
It's sideshow Tangency,
a new podcast where four friends,
Sarah Riley, Sam Schultz, Stephan Chin,
and me. Hank Green tried to
outsmart and outwit each other,
but usually we just get excited and
talk about all the awesome science we're
learning about. We also compete for
who has found the coolest, weirdest,
funniest scientific research
on our weekly topic,
which could be eggs or mucus or flight
or the science of snow, ice and dragons.
But one more thing. We also
go on a lot of tangents,
like if we've got something fun and kind
of related to say about death metal or
cartoons or the smell of space.
It's size. Show tangents,
subscribe wherever you get your podcasts.
Um, dad, I have him. Ron. Hi, I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is radio lab. Yeah.
And were listening to a story, a from
a theory that I produced called erased.
And let's get back now to the story of
Dr. Jerry Davidson and the gay cure.
It is in 1966 67 Jerry has pioneered this
new kind of conversion therapy called
orgasmic reorientation.
He's made a video about it.
Shortly after making this video,
Jerry found himself reading the very
magazine implicated in his therapy,
naturally reading it just for the
articles as they say, as they say.
And I was reading the playboy forum,
that's the section in the magazine
where readers write letters,
talk about stuff, voice
concerns. And in the forum,
this would have been around 1966 or 67.
Um, there were people writing in
trouble by their homosexuality.
Here's when we found, when
I was in the hospital,
the doctor told me they were very few
cures for cases like mine and I should try
to adjust my condition. Well being
a card carrying behavior therapist,
I wrote a letter
[inaudible] playboy, crazy,
isn't it? And I said,
actually there are new procedures
for helping gay men become less gay.
It comes from behavior therapy and I
don't know what else are about. Well they,
they, they printed it.
What ensued in the playboy forum
over the course of many issues,
many years in fact was a
vigorous back and forth.
Jerry's letter prompts a series of other
letters, some positive, some negative,
uh, one in particular, which calls out
a version therapy as this cruel thing,
which then causes one of the
world's leading aversion therapists.
The guy by the name of David Bartalow to
jump in and defend himself. He writes,
our procedures are not torturous,
are the inquisition rather methods
derived from experimental laboratories and
carefully applied to consenting human
beings to relieve some suffering.
That letter prompts a famous
gay activist, Frank Caminie,
to jump in with his own
response. He writes,
I find the August playboy
forum letter if David H.
Barlow offensive and illustrative not
only of the failures of psychology and
psychiatry and their
approach to homosexuality,
but also of the dangers of human
engineering. Here's the weird fact,
Kim and his letter was titled, Gay
is good, and just a few years later,
post stone.
Well, Yay. Good.
That phrase, Yay is proud.
The slogan of the entire
gay rights movement,
and this was maybe the first
time that that phrase was used
in the pages of playboy.
Everyone raves about how
interactive the Internet is.
People forget how Interactive
Playboy magazine was.
Okay, so this is a little
bit of a digression,
but I think it's one so worth
taking. That's James Peterson.
I was senior staff writer slash
senior editor for Playboy magazine.
He worked at playboy from 1973 to 2003
he's sort of the institutional memory of
the old playboy last man
standing kind of there. Right.
James reminded me actually, truth is,
I never even knew this to begin with,
a that Hugh Hefner's intent with playboy
wasn't just to show naked ladies.
He had a whole philosophy did he
actually spelled out in great detail?
I call it the term paper
that changed America
[inaudible] when, uh,
Hefner was an undergraduate,
the first Kinsey report on male sexuality,
it came out less. The research
had been cops in [inaudible],
10 of the people have go off at random
and it was a bolt from the blue.
It's changed Hefner's life. It came out,
I think 1948 and it described
the range of male sexuality
without judgment.
Kinsey described males on a range of one
to five from strictly heterosexual to
strictly homosexual,
but in the middle where something like
35% of American men had had a homosexual
experience in their
adolescence or early adulthood.
So the straight jacket was released
[inaudible]
and what struck Hefner,
this to me is the value of a of Kenzie.
The indicated for the first time,
statistically the great disparity was
this dissonance that existed between our
beliefs and the, uh,
the actual actions of society between
sex laws versus what people were actually
do. This is one good reason for
questioning some of the old morality.
And so, uh, when Hefner started playboy
along with the magazine and, uh,
the playmates and along
with all of the, uh,
televised parties from the playboy
mansion, we're glad you're here too.
Along with all that James says, he
wrote this constant stream of essays,
monthly installments, one
essay a month for two years,
like really long essays
on capitalism, religion,
essays on the history of sex.
Collectively it became known
as the playboy philosophy. Uh,
the philosophy really I think,
uh, is an anti puritanism
and James says behind
the scenes, through the
playboy foundation, we were funding
court cases in advanced gay rights,
abortion rights, birth control rights.
And James says the playboy forum
was part of that whole initiative.
Right after he finished that two
years sort of chain of essays,
Hefner then created that space
in the front of the magazine
for uh, people who had nowhere else to go
turn.
And it was in that space where you had
some of the first open discussions of
homosexuality in America ever.
And I said, you know, it's, you look back,
the sexual revolution
happened on the news stand
testing. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Okay. Back to Jerry's story
recording of a workshop by General
and see Davison. October six,
1972, New York Hilton,
a playboy letter, episode aside,
Jerry continued to push his
playboy therapy and in fact,
he says among therapists,
technique kind of started
to blow up and a, in 72,
he ends up getting invited
to give a workshop.
I want to you really convention present
to you some ideas and data and whatnot.
From our point of view as we have
been working with homosexuals,
we're going to skip over the actual
specifics of that workshop. Well,
I think it's clear that we have solved
all the problems that field has because
what's more consequential? Thank you.
This was enjoyable for me is
what happens after the panel.
Jerry is a hanging out waiting for
the room to clear. And this young, uh,
young man walks up to him chubby. He
was a little Chubby, bought my age.
Jerry was 33 at the time. Very
pleasant, very friendly, lot of smiles.
I don't recall if he had any, a beard.
He came up to me and introduced himself
as a graduate student at Rutgers and he
said, you know, I heard your talk.
I thought it was interesting. Uh,
I'm actually giving a talk
myself the next day. Uh,
you mind if I hand out some
flyers for it? And I said,
I don't mind at all. Of course,
the decision was made to attack what
we call the gatekeepers of American
attitudes.
This is Charles Silverstein.
He was that young therapist to training
with the flyer. Unbeknownst to Jerry,
he was gay and was part of a growing
movement of activists that were targeting
people like Jerry [inaudible] on this
thing that the behaviors had a different
point of view, unlike the Friday
and Weirdos. They were scientists,
I would say [inaudible] them up and he
says the public trusted the behavior
therapists. They had a lot
of sway over public opinion.
So if they could convince Jerry and his
colleagues that homosexuality was not
something that needs to be cured,
maybe the public would go along.
But the question was, how do you
do that? How do you make the case
[inaudible]
this was around the time
when gay activists would
start zapping meetings where
they'd basically go to a conference
where therapists are meeting storm, uh,
an event, grab the mic and
we want to deal with people.
[inaudible]
Charlie's sense was that this Gonzo
approach was not going to convince the
people that needed convincing like Jerry.
And so when he approached
Jerry after that,
did a workshop, very polite and friendly,
simply handed him a flyer, said,
hey man, a few folks are doing
a thing. Come by. Tracy has,
he just had a sense whose heart was
in the right place. And so he thought,
maybe I'll take a different approach
with this guy. And I looked,
I remember looking at
the Flyer and seeing, oh,
it's those radical gay activists,
all of these troublemakers. I mean,
I've been called in my career,
been called a Nazi and a fascist.
And so I remember looking at the
flyer saying to myself, well,
there's no way I'm going to go to this.
So he shoved the flyer in his pocket.
Yeah, I wasn't interested in it.
Went off to the next panel [inaudible]
some stuff the following day,
final day of the conference,
Sunday morning checked out of the hotel
and I was on my way to leave for Penn
station to go back out to Stonybrook.
And he says, on his way out,
he kept bumping into colleagues
who were like, Hey, great workshop,
love your playboy therapy thing. And
so he'd stop and he'd chat. And um,
at one point I looked at my
watch and you realized, dammit,
I could not make it down to Penn
station, is going to miss the train.
And I thought, oh, the next
train doesn't leave. You know,
three hours later suddenly had some
time to kill and for whatever reason the
thought pops into his head, oh,
the kid from Rutgers with a flyer,
maybe I'll go that I pulled
out the, the flyer he gave me,
I hadn't thrown it away
and I found the room and I went
to the room and it was a madhouse.
So the room was electric in the
sense that it was absolutely packed.
Charlie and two other gay
therapists were on stage.
There were maybe a few hundred
people in the audience,
although it may seem incredible to you
if they had never heard a gay person
speak as convention,
I mean they'd maybe seen gay
people interrupt the convention,
but never take part. So in my
Hollywood imagination of this moment,
people are shouting, they're
waving. No, no, no, no, no.
Charlie says this time he worked very
hard to keep it professional, respectful.
Okay, so it's so it's,
it's cordial but fierce.
I was at the top of my form when
it came time for him to speak.
Charlie says he took aim at that idea.
He'd heard people like Jerry
repeat over and over again.
I only work with people who
want to change. So what's
the, what's the big deal?
That idea? Here's what he said that
day we asked him to read the remarks.
It's a discussion of male homosexual
to suggest that a person comes voluntarily
to change for sexual orientation is
to ignore the powerful
environmental stress oppression,
if you will,
that has been telling him for years
that he should change to grow up in the
family where the word homosexual was
whispered to play in the playground and he
had the words Faggot and queer.
Did you go to church and hear of sin and
then to college and here of illness and
finally to the Counseling Center that
promises to cure is hardly to create an
environment of freedom
and voluntary choice.
What brings them into the
counseling center is guilt.
Shame and the loneliness
that comes from their secret.
If you really wish to
help them freely choose,
I suggest you first desensitize
them to their guilt after that.
Listen truth, but not before.
I don't know anymore than
you what would happen,
but I think that choice would be
more voluntary and free than it is at
precedent. Yes, those are my words.
Do you remember how those were to
you all? It affected me very deeply.
Affected me very deeply.
Jerry says he went to Penn station.
Was Charlie's speech into the
counseling sentence? It is guilt.
Shame echoing in his mind.
Five 25 lead modeling like seven Tang
says he got on the train back to stony
brook sat there staring out the
window at the scenery thinking,
thank you. Sorry.
I was running through the whole talk
action in my head and to feel comfortable
with this sexual violence after
the event with him and he says,
by the time he got to Stoneybrook,
he felt something changed in him.
I went to school the following day.
I know I began to talk to people about
what I had just heard at the convention
and how it's gotten me to thinking.
He says he was teaching a series of
undergraduate classes at that time and he
would get up in front of those
classes and for the first time think,
what if some of these
students are in the closet
talking to people, mulling
things over, talking to students.
I began to think what I've been
doing was absolutely wrong.
Meanwhile,
his film on the playboy therapy was
still making the rounds still gaining
convert.
Oh yeah. People love the film.
Okay.
The film had been out for a year already
and by the time the film began to be
shown,
I was already wishing that it wasn't
being shown that I had no control over it.
1973 a couple of months
after that convention,
Jerry gets nominated as the president
of the a B t the gigantic organization
that had thrown the
conference. He just attended.
He becomes one of the youngest presidents
ever and the following year he was due
to give the presidential address.
This is where things come to a head.
The conference that year
was held in Chicago.
It came at a time of
great fervor and foment.
He says in the days and months
leading up to the conference,
people on the radical left were calling
us fascist and Nattiez and they were
publishing circulars where their home
addresses someone publish your home
address. Absolutely. We had to, I was
president of the Association at the time.
I remember we all had walkie-talkies
and we hired plain clothes people in
Chicago police because we were
that afraid of, um, violence.
Set the scene when you give the speech.
How big is the room? Big, big run.
Big Ballroom. Couple hundred people.
Thousand. These are all therapists? Yeah.
And how are you feeling before the
speech? Very nervous. Terrifying.
But he says before the talk,
he'd actually met Charlie at a diner
and told them about the speech he was to
make. I remember him saying, do you
know that your reputation may suffer?
Because you have to
remember that in those days,
if you said something positive about
homosexual, people would suspect you.
People may think that you're gay. Oh,
he must be gay. That's what he's saying.
He warned me. He warned me.
[inaudible]
colleagues and my friends.
I want to make plain,
if not perfectly clear that I am speaking
only for myself on an ethical issue
that impinges importantly
on our therapy enterprise.
Jerry began the talk by
telling the audience,
I wish today to voice some concerns I
have been wrestling with for over three
years.
That he's troubled surrounding the way
behavior therapists and for that matter,
all other therapists have
approaching homosexuality
that he,
like a lot of the therapists in the
audience have been approached by clients,
gay men mostly who want their
help, our up to be made straight.
People who relate to us that they are
troubled by their homosexual behavior or
feelings with any asks.
Uh, Silverstein's question,
what does it actually mean to help these
people as Silverstein put it at the a B
t
convention two years ago in a
discussion of male homosexuality.
And let me court again to suggest that
a person comes voluntarily to change his
sexual orientation is to,
is to ignore the powerful environmental
stress oppression, if you will,
oppression. If you will,
that has been telling him for years that
he should change to grow up in a family
where the word homosexual was wisdom
play and he quoted you in that speech.
Yeah. What was Ellie? I was quite pleased.
Continuing the quote from Silverstein.
What brings them into the
counseling center is guilt,
shame and the loneliness that comes
from their secret. In other words,
Silverstein suggests that we miss go
back in the causal network and ask
ourselves as determinists what are they
determinants of the client asserting to
you that he or she wants to change.
Jerry then delivers the simple point,
which is that the problem that
these people are asking us to solve
[inaudible]
it's a problem we created
that we labeled as a problem
and so even if we could
effect certain changes,
there is still the more important
question of whether we should,
I believe we should not
to us now or to many of us.
Now that may sound like
kind of as simple, easy,
obvious thing to say,
but that was an extraordinary
statement. You see,
everybody else was arguing
that the attempts to change
sexual orientation ended
in failure. That was not what he did.
He did something quite different.
He said in that speech,
it makes no difference how
successful the treatment is.
It is immoral.
Charlie says he was the
first person to say that
to ever say that trying to change sexual
orientation was an immoral thing to do.
[inaudible]
and that's not a trivial thing.
I mean you could see this moment
in a way as one of them
early tremors in a tectonic shift
in not just therapy but all of science
[inaudible]
like science to that point. It
concerns itself with objectivity.
That was all that mattered.
We stand apart from the world and
we examine it as it is objectively,
but that
from this moment forward would start
to be questioned all over the place.
Even in places like mental illness,
you know, you look at history,
you see that some diseases come and
go. Why would that be what people would
begin to argue that even mental illnesses
or social constructs created by the
society, by the people who study
them. What Jerry was doing here.
Um,
he was shifting the
language. He was saying,
forget objectivity, forget
bullshit. Empiricism.
Let's talk about ethics.
Let's talk about morality.
We shouldn't do this. Not because
it doesn't work, which it doesn't,
but because it's wrong.
I hope and I recommend that we continue
to devote the necessary energy to the
important challenges. Thank you.
You right about that moment.
Like as you were talking about how
like the air felt in that moment. You,
you right. Friends commented afterwards.
That one gets that kind of silence when
everyone in a room full of a thousand
people stops
breathing at the same time.
Yeah, yeah, exactly right.
I remember that. I just remember that,
you know, like what are they going to do?
What I say this?
And it turned out that what they
were doing was holding their breath.
[inaudible] they do eventually [inaudible]
but afterwards Jerry says,
ah, at the reception, uh,
he walked in and it was like parting the
Red seas. Nobody wanted to talk to him.
They're all looking at me
and I remember one person,
I will not name him, he came
over to me and shook my hand.
Then he bent over and gave
me a kiss on the cheek. Well,
it didn't you like that? Oh,
like he's making a point to say you must
be gay because he said those things.
Yeah. Yeah. And I said, I said screw you.
So it took awhile to
get the peeps onboard,
but they did start to come around
and get on the right side of history.
And it's not a straight line by any means,
but there is a line that you can draw
between Charlie's words coming out of
Jerry's mouth and the epically
huge decision that these
psychiatric community as
a whole would make to remove homosexuality
as a mental illness from the DSM.
That big Bible of mental illnesses.
Jerry speech happened right at that
beginning point when science was just
starting to wash its hands of
the whole idea of a gay cure.
And what's interesting, I find
just as one final thought,
you could read this entire story
as a, as a sort of prelude,
psychotherapists were
basically ready to say that
homosexuality was not an illness by about
1986 that is precisely the time when
the Christian community walked
in and grabbed the baton,
the scientific communities were accepting
homosexuality and they were saying
that it's not a disorder anymore.
They were removing it from the DSM three
which is why we need to do what we're
doing because Christians
have to fight the battle.
Christians have to fight this battle of
homosexual sin because the professional
counseling community won't do it anymore.
So it was very explicit in
your mindset. Oh yeah. To that.
That story is a story that we eat here
in the next episode of Honor Arrays,
which I think we might also
play on radio lab. Well,
I hope so because all of a sudden
instead of talking to data and instead of
talking to jeans or instead
of talking to chemicals,
now you're talking to either God or
your parents or your teachers or your
society or depressors
that are all around you,
and it gets really,
really lonely and really,
really tough. Yeah.
This episode of radio lab
was drawn from unraced,
the untold history of
conversion therapy in America.
It's a series I worked
on with folks, features,
stitcher and limited house in conjunction
with a feature film boy erased.
Special thanks. Go out to Shimo,
the [inaudible], uh, cat, Aaron,
Michael Assessor, Allis Quinland,
David Craig, Garret Conley,
and all the folks that anonymous
content for their support of unraced.
If you want to hear the whole
series, which I hope you, you will a,
you can find unraced and all the
usual podcast places. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I want to put Krulwich. Thanks for
listening and happy Thanksgiving. Yeah.