You are listening to radio lab radio lab
from W. N y.
S. T. E. N. N. P. R. Yay. I'm Jad
Abumrad. This is radio lab, the podcast.
It's just me today. Robert
is, uh, traveling. So, um,
but I do have a short
little story for you.
The actually actually
it's two stories, uh,
that I've been thinking
about for quite awhile. Um,
it's about the mysteries of creativity,
any piece of music and a neurological
condition that unite to people across
space and time.
[inaudible].
Okay. The first story begins in
the early 1980s in Vancouver,
British Columbia with a woman named
Anne Adams who was a brilliant cell
biologist and was highly articulate.
That's her husband Robert Adams,
extremely capable with language.
She did cancer research.
He actually developed a cell line.
Really I believe still exists. Wow.
So she was very sharp as a
scientist. She was a natural,
but then rather suddenly at the age of 46
and kind of does a one 80 something
happened in 86 which changed the course of
her life. It all started
when their third son, Alex,
gets into a really bad car accident.
And we were told that he would probably
never ever walk again and decided she's
going to take some time off to
help them recover. And he does.
He does learn to walk again. But while
at home she just decides to quit,
quit science and become a painter. Yeah.
And made up her mind then and there that
she was gonna take up art full time.
Had she ever painted before? Well,
she did a fair amount of it
when she was in high school,
which was a very long time ago.
So the whole thing struck him
as kind of out of the blue,
but he rolled with it and uh,
within a short period of time she had
converted a room in their house into a
studio and she was painting
houses and buildings,
little churches simple at first,
but then after that brightly
colored versions of what
you see when you look down
the barrel of a microscope, you know,
cells, bacteria after that, strawberries,
a series of paintings involving these
blazing red strawberries, for instance,
a water faucet. And out of what would
becoming a scream of strawberries.
There was things called Strawberry
Universe where the strawberries had rings
around them like Saturn and so on.
I think there was something like
35 or 36 strawberry painting. Wow.
But then she would switch to something
else even after their son had fully
recovered,
even threw away his crutches and went
back to school and kept on painting.
And she would work all
day long, 10 hours a day,
making these paintings as it got
bigger and bigger and more abstract.
And there were times he
says when he was like, wow,
because for someone who hadn't
painted since high school,
she was suddenly so prolific
[inaudible]
and it's entirely possible that
something was happening to her.
Even then way below the surface. I mean,
on the surface she was just
painting and it was working.
People were buying the painting,
she was having solo shows,
she was becoming a successful
artist. But then in 1994,
she decided, I don't know what
gave her this idea of big,
I never knew what gave her
any of her ideas, but um,
she decided she was going to
do a painting of, well, this
[inaudible]
Bolero Bolero. Yes. Yeah.
We'll arrow rabbit says he's
not quite sure how it happened,
but at some point that year and heard
this famous piece by Maurice Ravel became
obsessed, couldn't stop listening to it,
then playing it on the piano, the play.
Then deconstructing it,
mapping every pitch and the melody
and the bass to a color. Here's a, uh,
here's one page which isn't very
long. This is from her notes.
She's got a silver, a flat copper, B leaf,
green, B flat, metallic green.
Eventually the painting was quite a
large work, two panels side by side,
very electric colors, a blizzard
of symbols and triangles,
little tooth type things
with marks on them.
That all mean something and
rectangles marching back and forth.
Across the first panel,
there was a triangle in the bottom of
each one of the rectangle and the height
of the rectangle represented the loudness.
It's an incredibly obsessive translation
of the music into visual language and
just like the melody in Bolero, the
symbols repeat and repeat and repeat,
obsessively getting bigger and bigger
and bigger until at the very end of the
second panel,
things unraveled. By the way,
her title for the painting
was unraveling Bolero.
And here's where things start to get
a little spooky and did this at a time
when, um, she knew nothing about rebel.
She called her piece unraveling Bolero,
having no idea that that's exactly what
would happen to ravel right after he
wrote Bolero
[inaudible]
which brings us to story number two.
Well, okay. Should we jump in? Yeah,
please.
This is RB Orenstein professor of music
at the Aaron Copeland School of Music at
Queens College.
He's written about Revelle perform
rebel talk to anyone who ever knew rebel
[inaudible]. He kind of
is a much, shall I say,
kind of a living presence
inside my head too. Okay.
Maurice Ravel is composer obviously
one of the greats born at 1875.
Papa was an engineer.
Mother was from an old busk
family as in she was Spanish. Yes.
Which is why, uh, some of his music
Lake Valera does sound a bit Spanish.
In any case, mom encouraged
them to study music.
He goes off to Paris in
the 1890s meets Claude WC,
and together they sort of
invent this style of music,
which we now call impressionism,
which was this kind of free floating,
almost dreamlike,
sensuous, a lot of colors.
The Flower, yes.
[inaudible]
but then like an ravel
makes a kind of shift.
1928 when he was 53 about the same age
Anne was when she did the painting.
Oh l is having an absolutely phenomenal
year. Just toured the United States,
performed for thousands.
You set the zenith of his creativity
and he's back in France at a beach house
wearing a pink bathing suit.
The story goes right before
he steps out onto the beach.
This melody swoops into his
head. He runs over to the piano,
takes his index finger,
and he goes, Duh, Duh de de
[inaudible]. There it was. It just
came to him fully formed. Well, he,
I don't know if he played the whole
melody, but he at least started it off.
But here's the shift. When he sat
down to flush the whole thing out,
instead of developing the melody, making
it super flowery, like his other stuff,
you said, no, I'm not gonna do that.
I'm going to take this melody and
repeat it again and again and again,
and then again, some more and then
some more. The theme never changes.
One note,
the only thing that does change is the
orchestration which grows around the
melody.
Terry slowly, bit by
bit gets bigger, bigger,
more company meant more
instruments play the melody,
the melody itself
for 340 bars never varied.
Yes.
When he says where the performers,
they're ready to see a psychiatrist.
By the time they're done playing this
piece and reveal at the first performance
in Paris, some woman
screamed out these crazy,
which turned out to be,
well not exactly true,
but in the neighborhood six
years after he wrote Bolero,
this is 1933 Revelle
begins to forget words.
He'd always been forgetful. So
no one really noticed at first.
But then one day at dinner he grabs the
knife by the wrong side and he doesn't
realize it.
And he continues to try to eat holding
the shop side of the knife and tried to
cut with the handle. Then
he visits a friend, leaves,
not two hours go by, knock on
the door. It's ravel again.
He didn't remember that he'd been
there before just two hours earlier.
Eventually by 1935 he could
not ride anymore or speak.
His language had evaporated.
RB says there are documents where you
can see Revelle desperately trying to
relearn the alpha.
A a a a
over and over again.
Wow. B B
with a kind of a shaking
hand, very small. It's very,
very painful to see
[inaudible]
whatever it was that was
wrong was getting worse.
Here's the weird
symmetry, just like ravel,
six years after finishing herbal
Arrow by 2000 I would say,
and also begins to forget words. She
would try to say things and couldn't.
She would try to find words and couldn't.
So how are you today? Fine.
Eventually an ends up at the University
of California, San Francisco,
and this was in 2002 when they
gave her a bunch of tests.
Can you tell me your,
your full name, please.
Am Teresa Adams.
There's a video of one
of these tests in it.
You can see Anne sitting at a table
in a black sweater, gray hair glasses.
Very composed. Can you
tell me your address?
Like someone who's used to knowing the
answers to questions people ask her.
Four
23 which town?
Um,
which town? Vancouver. Great.
By the time Anne had come to see us, uh,
her communication abilities
were markedly diminished.
That's Dr. Bruce Miller.
He's a neurologist.
He runs the memory and
Aging Center at UCF.
Example, we asked her a to describe. Okay.
Otherwise you used to take a look
at this picture, a very complex,
rich picture with take your
time children with a kite,
with a sailboat on the ocean. And
please tell me what you see. Any,
if you can please try to
speak in sentences and would
it be able to say single
words with no grammar. She'd go sailboat,
tree boy,
water people, kite tight
flag.
And uh, that four or five words would
come out over about a minutes time.
She was very frustrated.
Both Ann Adams and Merissa val were
unraveling in the exact same way,
at the exact same speed to the
same soundtrack you might say,
but just roughly 60 years apart.
We think he and Anne down to the very
molecular process had the exact same
disease and he thinks Bolero the music
and then the painting in both their cases
was the first symptom of that disease.
This takes a couple of steps to
explain, so bear with me, but to start,
the disease is called
frontotemporal dementia.
That's Jonah Lehrer author regular on
our show and it begins when spindly cells
in your frontal cortex.
This part kind of right above your
forehead start to wither and until your
frontal cortex is puck mark
with sometimes visible holes.
We know this about an from
tests and brain scans.
We suspected about rebel
because according to Arby,
just before he died on December 28th,
1937 the French surgeon opened up his
skull and saw that one of the lobes of the
two lobes of the brain had sunk
because it was disintegrating.
Now in both their cases,
the part of the brain,
the part of their cortex
that got hit was on the left,
which is the part that does a lot of
things, memory, recalling, memories,
finding memories. And most importantly
for our story, it governs language.
What happens is as the frontal
cortex starts to fall apart,
you lose the ability to access language.
Now here's the thing
about losing language.
Our brains quickly debriefs are basically
a series of circuits that are all
tightly connected with progressive.
And when a dominant circuit
like language turns on,
it's basically wired to turn a bunch
of other circuits off, basically go,
shh, six years, other parts of the brain,
we have this constant dance where one
circuit or many circuits turn on and then
they're obligatory. Les
Turning off other circuits.
So language acts as a kind of break. Um,
other things that brain could be doing,
like daydreaming, thinking
in images and pictures,
but when the language is no
longer there to hold things back,
often what can happen is that those
other parts like say the visual parts can
just rush forward and suddenly
the mind is, is flooded
with images that all of a sudden
people have these rich, rich,
intense sensations. The world is so
beautiful and they need to express it.
This is very common.
We see a number of patients who become
visually obsessed from every possible
walk of life investment bankers who have
never been interested in art before and
never even walked into an art museum and
all of a sudden they decide at the age
of 55 to move into a
loft, become an artist.
One of the first glimmers of their
illness is this insatiable need to create.
That's right. How many of these
cases have you seen 50 60. Wow.
Manifest itself in as many different
kinds of art as there are people,
but at the end of the day, what
all of these people have in common?
Is it this explosion of
creativity in their heads? Well,
it's not a free flowing,
loosey-goosey kind of creativity.
It's quite mechanical.
The repetition obsession,
they get stuck in a kind of loop taking
one thing and just doing it again and
again like an Adams painting or
like Bolero.
This drive to repeat happens very early
on the course of this illness till he
says what can seem like a simple creative
choice to repeat a melody may actually
be driven by a condition that you
won't even know you have for six years.
We think that this had something to do
with the very unusual rhythmic repetitive
sorts of music that ravel produced.
And why the repetition?
Where does it come from? Um,
I think this is the release of a of a,
Bruce says, we don't really know,
but he offered up a theory
which I find fascinating,
which may get to the root of
creative obsession of any kind.
He says there might be several parts
of the brain that are held back by the
language circuit and one of them is
this very ancient part of our brains
[inaudible]
Basal Ganglia. The part
of the brain we move with,
you can call our reptile brain. This
is the part of us that uh, governs,
you know, basic behaviors
like eating, running
motor programs that uh, we,
uh, do repetitively every day.
That's all it does. It sends command
saying move, move, eat, eat, run, run.
Birds and snakes get by with basically
just this part of the brain keeps them
alive. Now normally he thinks the
language part of us inhibits these habits,
these repetitive motor programs that
when the language part is not there to do
the shushing, these motor
commands filter up to.
So imagine you're one of these people,
your mind is suddenly
flooded with pictures,
maybe sounds and it's also flooded with
these kinetic repetitive instructions,
move, move, move, do it again. And
in the early stages of the illness,
you still have enough brain
to make sense of it all.
There's still a lot of cortex that is
still available to act upon this desire to
repeat.
And so you get art that is
obsessive and repetitive. Yes,
but also beautiful and abstract,
like unraveling Bolero.
But then as the disease progresses and
more of that front human part fades away,
the repetition becomes much
simpler and not creative at all.
In the latter stages
of a disease. He says,
you'll often see patients [inaudible]
pouring water into a cup
a hundred times in a day,
a squishing ants over and over again.
The complexity of the behaviors are
diminishing as as we're losing these parts
of the brain that make us so human.
Sort of what you see in answer
work or painting startled, simple,
explode into abstraction
and then get simple again.
But what's unusual compared to the
other patients is that she kept painting
almost all the way to the end until
literally it was not possible for her to,
to hold and direct a, uh, a brush or a
pen. That's her husband, Robert Again,
and became progressively paralyzed
on the right side of her body.
She lost the ability to, to
paint
2005 early and that, that,
that was sad towards the end.
He says he would go into her studio
and I would see her there in front of a
blank canvas and she
wouldn't be doing anything.
She would just be looking at it.
And I'd come back a couple of hours
later and she still wouldn't have done
anything. She had lost
the ability to do the art,
but she hadn't lost the drive.
And that to me is one of the
beautiful parts of Ann's story.
But the drive to create can be as primal
as the drive to eat that even after she
couldn't move, could barely
swallow. She still sat there trying.
She had gone down hill so
far by that time that, uh,
that, uh, she was hardly recognizable as,
as herself at some point in the
disease. And you can see this in that,
that early tape painting
was all she had left.
I don't have the memories of this
painting had become literally all she was.
Can you tell me what your job is
or are you, are you still working?
Uh, I do art.
She died in 2007. Yes. In January of 2007
thanks to Robert Adams, Bruce Miller
at the University of California,
San Francisco and Arby Orenstein
at Queens College. I'm Jad Abumrad.
Robert will be back with me
next podcast. See you then.