You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N Y.
S? Yup.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich Radiolab and today
we're going to hit the phones. Hello. Hi.
Can I speak to mark starting with
this guy, Mark Morrison. Hey mark,
this is jad calling from radio lab.
Hey Jack. Good to hear Ya.
Got Ahold of him at his
home in Olympia, Washington
that hanging out on the front porch
cause the kids are running around so you
might hear some traffic.
Okay, Gotcha. Um, alright,
maybe we should just jump in and
you should just tell me this story.
Okay. So, um, I was deejaying
a wedding, um, out in Lacey,
which is the next town over. It was a hot,
like late spring kind of
feeling like summer kind of day.
And uh, we were in uh, a little,
a rented facility that had like windows
on all sides and all of a sudden the
power starts flickering and
it starts raining really hard.
Okay. Then trees are falling over,
the wind is gusting and it,
the sky turned tonight and this
is like three 30 in the afternoon.
So mark takes off, goes back home.
My inlaws are visiting in town to
hang out with a new baby and um,
we open up the curtain,
turned off all the lights and we're just
kind of marveling at the insane power
of this storm that's happening.
My wife is sitting on the couch,
my two year old is watching Charlie Brown
or something on the iPad and then all
of a sudden there's just a loud snap,
like the sound of a whip cracking or like,
like a two by four being snapped in half
and about a foot and a half to two feet
in front of my face right next
to my mother in law and the baby,
there's a little
fear of white, white light,
just a little or the size of like maybe
an orange or a grapefruit kind of blurry
edges around it floating in mid air.
As bright as like the sun and like
the bright, it lit up the entire room.
Wow.
All screened.
Everybody in the room, in the unit then,
and mark says this son Orb just sort
of hovered in front of his face,
kind of going, Wong, Wong, Wong,
Wong for maybe a second
when all of a sudden poof, it was gone.
Yeah.
That's some x files that right there.
Yeah. None of us had any
idea what the heck happened.
Well, did you go around the room
being like, did you guys see that?
Did you see that?
Yeah. Everybody thought everybody side.
I'm by mother-in-law thought that I had
liked taken some kind of like fireworks
and thrown it up in the [inaudible].
Like what? What did you
do? Like I didn't do anything.
So what I did was I started trying
to Google it and there's, you know,
I mean, imagine trying to Google that
and you're not gonna find anything.
What w what did you type into? Google?
A sphere of light floating in, indoors.
Um, I didn't get very far. Yeah.
But, um, I just, I just wanted
to get to the bottom of it.
And so what mark did is he sat down on
a computer and he typed up this email
basically saying like, what
the Hell is this thing?
And then he sent that email into the void,
which would be us, yes to our
email inbox and a, you know,
it sat around for awhile because we
tend to get these kinds of questions
a lot. Are there more stars
in the universe or grains
of sand on earth? A lot.
A lot. Is it clean and neat?
The sticker off the apple.
Why do some birds walk and others hop?
How do fish here? Why are horses special?
We get things a leg. What's
up with traffic jams?
Random questions like
Gilliam is a finite resource.
Why are we wasting it on
balloons out of coop questions.
Why is different animals poops
differently? A lot of poop.
What happens when you flush a toilet on
the equator and they just sort of pile
up? We sort of put them in this bucket
and then feel guilty about not answering
them. And over the years they keep coming.
So the bucket gets fuller
and fuller and fuller.
So finally today we decided, okay,
let's just dump the bucket out
and so we're going to try and answer some
of these questions today. Bunch of us.
Hello, beginning with the question about
the orb. Can I speak to Martin please?
You're talking to him. Try
and answer Mark's question.
I called up a guy named Martin Newman,
professor of electrical and computer
engineering at University of Florida.
Thank you. Is this still
a good time to chat?
Uh, it was about the only time because
I'm going to go to dinner in about 10
minutes.
All right, excellent. Uh,
so we'll just jump right in.
All right. How long
were you going to talk?
Well, W so I, uh, told Martin the story,
thunderstorm, boom, glowing or boof,
glowing orb gone. Yeah. So maybe I'll
just put the most basic question to you.
Like what is that?
Well, that observation is not uncommon
and it's called generally called ball.
Lightning
ball lightning. Yeah, that's what it's
called in. According to Martin Ball,
lightning is timeless.
Some Greeks described exactly the same
thing in the 19th century and 18th
century. They used to commonly come down
the chimney, come out the fireplace.
Oh Wow. But now it says Martin, we
are living in an electronic world.
And so these balls of lightning
sometime to come out of a wall socket
sometimes out of a telephone. Huh.
Or they happen in airplanes.
They happen in submarines.
Whoa. That actually, that's been reported.
Yeah.
Lightning strikes outside an airplane
and a ball comes through the and floats
down the whole plane.
What if I'm in that plane? I'm thinking
you're going to hope you have your diaper
on, right. Where are your, depends.
Anytime you've got electrical stuff
going on you can make a ball of fire like
that.
So do we know anything about
what causes what it is exactly?
Is it just another form of lightening
that somehow manages to ball itself up and
hang around?
Well, probably
Martin is actually one of the few people
who has studied ball lightening in the
lab. He actually got funded by DARPA
to try and figure out how it works.
Wasn't quite able to.
He says what's likely happening is
that when a bolt of lightning strikes,
it might hit something.
Soil, water, tree,
whatever it is, some substance.
Yeah. It's lit up and somehow
forms itself into a sphere,
like a balloon or a bubble or something.
Like if you imagine lightning
hits some dust shocks,
the dust changes its chemistry so
that it forms some kind of spiritual
scaffolding and then the lightning
sticks to the scaffolding or something.
Yeah.
Maybe that's what's happening.
But you can't prove it. I mean,
there's some theory which
indicates that that might happen,
but if you go into the laboratory and
you try to make it, you can't make it,
so can't prove it. And uh,
if you got a book on ball lightning
or do you get my book and look at the
chapter on ball lightning,
you'll see probably a list of 50 different
theories that people have come up
with. Oh.
From all the way to black
holes and continuity's and
time space and things that
are just, you know, completely
almost out of this world.
So they remain in ministry. But, uh,
well observed history.
Did you know that people don't have any
good maps for how light and get started
in a cloud?
Really? I didn't know that.
We don't know what, how lightning can
can get started. It shouldn't be able to.
It shouldn't really be based on what
the math says. There's not enough
the measurements that have been
made of a conditions in clouds.
Huh. So you're saying
all those things that aren't understood,
almost nothing is understood.
Yeah.
We're floundering around.
Do you,
do you find yourself thinking about
ball lightening and then suddenly just
tiptoeing into an existential crisis?
How little we know of the world?
Hello? Sorry. Make my living
is trying to uncover a little,
little more bits by little more
bits, but yeah, there's lots of,
is it not about everything?
[inaudible] wow.
Next up producer Tracy
hunt goes on a field trip.
Do some very hallowed ground man. I
think I finally reached the library,
the New York Public Library,
the New York public life within
it's white marble walls, the store,
the son of man, which
in its glory days. Okay.
Right here in the grand hall is like
Beautiful Chandelier's all over the place.
These gorgeous Collins was filled
with seven floors of style,
millions of books in every field
of human endeavor, row upon row,
upon row of shelves, smiles up shelves,
close to 50 centuries of
human thinking and experience.
And every year millions of visitors like
Tracy would walk through these hallowed
halls each has a question with
questions fueled by curiosity,
the desire for truth, for
knowledge, for wisdom,
people trying to unravel the
mysteries of the universe.
[inaudible]
I came here to ask them a question
about catnip cabinet. Yes.
Katnik Whoa, wait, why?
Why can't I sit back up?
So we actually got like 500
questions from our listeners,
so I thought it might be good idea
to take some of them to the library.
Hey Resin. So I met up with this
woman. Nice to meet you. I'm Tracy.
Nice to meet you, Rosa. And she walked
me into this office. There's about like,
I don't know, 12 people
sitting at their desk.
Why don't you just introduce yourselves?
Okay, sure. So my name is Rosalie.
I manage asking YPL and I've been in
this department for about five years.
I would ask and why P L it's nine one
seven ask and YPL I'm putting the phone
number out there and if you call
them and you ask them a question,
it's their job to answer it. Yes.
So we are like a call center.
So our typical day starts with questions.
And like in a typical day, how many phone
calls do you get? Typical Day? About
150 to 200.
And residents telling me that most of
the questions they get it a little,
whether it be like this
weekend I'm very boring. Hey,
my library card expired or I want to
renew this book. But you know, also they,
they get some weird ones.
We take them all. Yeah. Um,
so I got a list right here and in the
past they've gotten things like what kind
of apple did he eat? Is it proper to
go alone to reno to get a divorce?
And the statistics on the
lifespan of the abandoned woman.
Do candles have to be licensed in India?
What is the natural enemy of the duck?
Can I get a book telling me how to be
a mistress of ceremonies at a musical
orgy? What does it mean when you dream
you're being chased by an elephant?
And do they answer all those?
They'll try to, you know,
I was maybe a little dismissive
for a few of them. I mean,
all the questions of course
are very important. We
welcome all questions please.
This by the way, is Bernard
Bernard and Mar Savine.
He has been working for asking YPL since
about 2001 and so the question though,
he did answer my catnip question,
which is do large feline species like
tigers and lions have the same reaction to
catnip as domestic cats?
Yes. I'll Catholic catnip,
apparently tigers, at
least that I'm, you know,
I had all these questions so I actually
had them pick one that they thought was
super interesting. Yeah. Which
one did you pick two to answer?
Let me get the exact wording
out of, so yeah, so here we go.
Could you play a meaningful game of
Frisbee on the surface of Mars? Yeah,
and I really liked that.
That was a good one.
And I think the word that makes it
like just really shine is meaningful.
So the first thing he does, you'll
want to get me kind of doing some,
some searching, you know, again, back of
the envelope kind of stuff here in he,
I guess I was a little disappointed that
we didn't invest that. Any like books,
I'm just looking up a
frisbee aerodynamics.
You literally just turn it just
computer inside of googling.
How's a Frisbee behave here on
earth? The spin of the Frisbee,
of course lift, drag. So he looks
all that stuff up. Let's see.
Then he looks at like aerodynamics
on Mars. On Mars, it's very thin,
the air there. So because
it airs within on Mars,
you wouldn't get that spinning lifting
thing that you always get frisbees.
It might not have the same
sort of hovering effect that
a first bee does here on
earth. It probably would be
more like just throwing a ball.
It would just go from 10 feet away, 15
feet away. I don't think that that's,
that counts as a meaningful
game of Frisbee. You still
throw it back and forth.
But the meaningful to me,
the question is like you're
playing Frisbee on Mars.
I mean that's just, that's just
inherently meaningful, you know,
growing up I remember seeing uh,
alright, sorry.
You know where you broadcast of a, you
know like the astronauts on the moon.
Oh yes. In why you are looking at,
you might recognize what I
have in my head is the uh,
playing golf
and no further continued example return.
It just still happen to have it next time
I brought him over to my birthday and
I have a [inaudible]
American. I dropped the damn
and I'm sure that they were
not playing like, you know,
PGA golf
but I've got to try it. Old Sam shot here,
all the [inaudible]
they were just, you
know, amateur duffers but
no,
they were golfing on the moon.
Nah, one more.
Oh and miles and miles.
I mean to me that's pretty great.
Pretty, that's pretty impressive. So the,
the, the, the
uh,
kind of makes the whole endeavor
meaningful I think in it.
And its way
[inaudible]
thanks to producer producers.
I actually did ask them
my dragons question. Oh,
well then her next up, Tracy Hunt
and dragons. Hi, this is
Christina. Hi Tracy. Hi.
Hey, are you coming back? This
question is from Christina. Hard quiz.
I am a native of Nevato
out in northern California.
Um, and I was born and raised
here. So yeah, love this place.
And you, and what was your question too?
Is if you remember what it was roughly?
Yeah,
so I came across this article about
these creatures called ohms that I guess
we're being, you know, washed out
of these caves in eastern Europe.
What did they call,
um,
the o l m these sort of like
blind cave dwelling amphibians.
They're totally white. Their skin is
translucent, very like other worldly.
And the article touched on
the idea that, you know,
folklore thought that these little
creatures were actually like dragon babies
being pushed out of, of these caves where,
where these huge dragons live.
So I started digging into it a little
bit and of course you can only find so
much on the Internet,
but there was this idea of dragons being
a sort of like a universal [inaudible]
yeah, a cross, you know,
different disparate cultures.
And Christina started to wonder why it
seemed that so many cultures all over the
world all had myths about dragons.
Is it about like humans that will
cause them to believe in these like
huge airy, fire-breathing animals?
Is that true that cultures all over
the world have dragons? Well, sorry,
now you have the northern European
dragon that we're all familiar with
[inaudible] then there's the Chinese
dragon, which is a little different.
It doesn't have wings,
doesn't breathe fire.
Then there's other dragon looking
sort of things. The Nana Boli
[inaudible] Soto people
in Southern Africa.
There's the Amaru associated
with the Incan Empire. Yeah,
I think there's no doubt that we have
dye abuelas awesome creatures like
dragons, uh, in almost
every culture in the world.
So this is Adrian Mayer.
I'm a research scholar in the classics
department at Stanford and I'm most
interested in is what sorts of
things found in nature might have led
pre-scientific people to believe that
dragons or monsters or other fantastic
creatures really existed. At least in
the past or even maybe in the present.
Adrian actually wrote a book called the
first fossil that lays out this theory
that a lot of these stories were actually
based on people finding old, you know,
fossils and bones,
fossil bones or teeth or claws
or footprints in bedded in stone.
So they see a set of old bones that
they couldn't explain with any modern
creatures.
So the creature they go to is
this dragon shaped thing. Yes,
but I do want to point out though that
we can never know for certain which comes
first,
the observations of mysterious traces
of of unknown animals or the stories of
dragons. We don't know which comes first.
She says it could be that the story about
the dragon was already there and then
when they found some bones,
they just sort of applied those
bones to the dragon myth. What if,
if the dragon came before the
bones, where did it come from? Well,
there's another theory.
Some scholars have said they're
like monsters of the [inaudible].
They arise from ancient memories of very
real predators that were faced by our
ancestors.
Basically dragons are composited that
these creatures that used to eat us and in
Honduras and kill us like crocodiles,
Saber Tooth Tigers and lions, cave bears,
gigantic serpents, snakes,
pythons, condo raptors.
So you can take like this
scaly skin of the crocodile,
the claws of the saber tooth
tiger and its saber teeth.
The wings of these raptors
put them all together.
So this is all the old
terrorist rolled into one
boom together. Yeah,
they tapped into all those fears that
are ready are in ready inside of this
theory. I'm going to go for that
one. Yeah, I like that. That works.
Then that feels like an
answer. Well, you know, like,
like they're very powerful. I
mean that can be very scary.
They can be very destructive.
But what's kind of magical in,
in game of Thrones is that the intimate
scenes also melt your heart and bring
you closer to these creatures that should
be, you know, burning your face off.
Okay. So I, I,
I should admit that I actually just use
this whole dragon thing to talk to this
lady at gay from game of Thrones.
[inaudible] her name is Paula Fairfield
and she makes all the dragon noises for
game of Thrones. Oh, she
makes the dragons. Right.
Well, what did you ask her?
I guess what did you want to
know? Well, I wanted to know,
I wanted to know like
how does she make these
sounds? And it was really
interesting cause you know,
we're talking a little bit about, uh,
you know how dragons are
composite creatures and she
basically uses composites
to make these noises. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
I absolutely take some laces from birds.
Ricci shrieky bird sounds, insects,
different kinds of reptilian
recordings and stuff.
And gays are always scary animals.
Well, depends on what dragon that she,
you know, which of the dragons
that she's trying to actually, um,
create a performance.
I have sounds,
I might choose simply by
certain personality traits
that I might want to push
forward. Um, so in the case of Drogon
[inaudible]
so, um, on the show there's Dinero
[inaudible] Dragon Queen and she has
three dragons and one of them is named
Drogon.
She named that dragon
after cal Drogo, her,
her hot late husband. Um,
so drogue on his like her lover. Yeah.
He kind of has like a very
affectionate central relationship.
Okay.
He's whistling at her all the time.
He's looking at her butt and going,
Ooh Baby,
does it happen?
And so in order to kind of push forward
this sort of like drag in sexual
attention, I guess she uses the sounds of
too dry and tortoise is, you know,
mating. Oh, toured tortoise as well.
It sound like, well, um, you
know, I'm, I'll just play it.
Hello.
Whoa, whoa.
But the grown of the male actually
became with some work and,
and you know, adjustments and
stuff became, I'm the source,
the basis for dro guns per with her,
with the narrows. How
far did she come to me?
We need to [inaudible]
my people need me.
And the funny thing about the per what
Drogon was watching people watch it and
giggling when they heard it,
but not really knowing why.
And to me it's because it had that
essence that that kind of sensual sexual
essence, that person. Yeah. No, I
use from all all kinds of things.
And you know,
I also used for dragon fly wings
to make that kind of funny,
flatter of the thorns that's as moving
like especially on the end of his tail
this year as he moved through,
there was like a Chitter and
that was like dragon fly wings.
Dragon fly wings. Yeah. Really.
I was wondering if you ever had a question
about dragons that you would like to
have answered.
Yeah, no, it's,
it's curious because I think the thing
that differentiates the dragons from
creatures and makes them slightly
either worldly is the fire thing.
Where did the idea for that kind of
long, that's a good question. Yeah.
Where did that come from?
Well, there are many theories
about that. Actually,
I take that question back to Adrian Mayer.
The one that I like is connected to the
devastating weapon called Greek fire,
which was this unquenchable fire
can't be put out by water. In fact,
it burns in water. And
so it was a naval weapon.
And I believe that scholars have found
that some of the nozzles for lasting
Greek fire were shaped like dragons so
that the boat looked like it had a dragon
on board breathing fire out the
enemy ship. Oh, that's so cool.
The stories of they had
dragons that breathe fire, uh,
would make it back to uh, to northern
Europe. That's the best theory I've heard.
Oh, that's interesting.
So it's like if the drag,
it is a composite of all the things,
creatures that have scared us now we're
part of that composite technology now be
it is built, becomes part of
the creature that frightens us.
[inaudible] thanks Tracy. You're welcome.
Who is, what is, uh,
what is uh, uh, [inaudible]
who is,
uh, uh, anything coming to mind? What is a
Oh oh six something.
It's a fedora. I should have known
that. He shouldn't have known that.
All right, we're going to take a break.
This is Marnie Campbell from the beautiful
banks of Lake Washington in Seattle,
Washington. Radiolab is supported in
part by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
jad Robert Radiolab man, we
are back with more questions.
Next one comes from
producer Rachel Cusick.
So this question comes from Liam
hamburger from Denver, Colorado.
No [inaudible].
I was browsing meanings on my Instagram
feed and there was meme where the
picture was of a husband and
wife trying to go to sleep.
The wife was looking weird.
She was like looking irritated and the
husband was looking like this kind of
confused on the opposite side
of bed and a capsule utter.
He's probably thinking of
other girls and then him,
I wonder if I bought milk
from the same cow twice.
What'd he say? When do what?
Yeah, so he said, I wonder if I've ever
bought milk from the same cow twice.
So if I go to the store, I buy a
gallon of milk and then I go back.
Maybe a week later I get
another gallon of milk.
What are the odds that the same cow is
in both of those gallons of milk? I see.
[inaudible]
I would say the answer
is almost certainly. Yes,
100%
that's our Benjamin. He's a math
professor. Yep. At Harvey Mudd College
in Claremont. And I'm
also a mathemagician.
And how is he so sure that it's 100%
well, according to Art Benjamin,
it all comes down to a [inaudible]
ability. Statistics and dare I say,
hey, how cute. So take a farm
like Dale's here. Oh, here we go.
My name is Dale Mattoon,
pine hollow dairy.
Dale has about a thousand
cows and 20 at a time.
These cows walk into a
milking parlor, they line up,
it looks like a [inaudible]
all day and all night long.
And they get hooked up with these
black rubber hoses area here.
And every once in a while is the guy
putting the machine on a cow and he hits
the button,
it turns on a vacuum and any pumps the
milk out of their utters into this big
hose along the bottom of the floor.
You through the hose down into this line
and it's meeting up with all the milk
from all the other cows
and then it goes from that room into
another room or it gets cool down the milk
out. Put your hand on this
pipe. Oh my gosh, it's cold.
There's condensation on it. Very
cool. Once it's cooled down,
it goes into this rocket ship looking
thing outside called a milk silo where all
the milk from Dale's farm is
just hanging out together.
Silo gets filled up and up
and up and up until it's full.
We're sending out over 8,000 gallons
of milk today on a trek. The trailer,
his truck comes along,
picks up that milk and it stops at
another farm and another farm and another
farm until that truck is full,
right full goes to the processing plant
and once you're at the processing plant,
all that milk is just mixed around
even more with milk from all the cows.
[inaudible] Maria and
I still have my,
my back of the envelope that
had the calculation here.
Here's where the math comes in.
There are about 90,000 drops
of milk and a gallon and uh,
oh, I don't know,
100,000 cows who are contributing
to a particular processing plants.
When you were in the odds of a drop of
milk from any one cow getting into any
particular gallon,
probably the case,
every gallon of milk contains
most of those cows contributing.
And here's the thing. In one drop of milk,
you could probably have a bunch of
different milk molecules from a bunch of
different cows.
And so one glass of milk might have, yeah,
thousands,
maybe hundreds of thousands of
different how molecules in my glasses.
Oh Wow. Crazy. Oh my God.
So going back to Liam's
original question, uh,
arts argument is that when
you're drinking a glass of milk,
there's like so many different bits
of milk from so many different cows,
then it's probably the case that after
just two glasses of milk, you're,
you're almost certain to have, um, a cow
that was represented in both of them.
So you're bound to run into at least
a little bit of one of those hundred
thousand cows. Again,
the point being that every
glass of milk has, you know,
has thousands and thousands
of different cows contributing
a little bit of 10,000 cows and every
glass, every glass. I love that.
I don't know that I do. No, it's great.
It's like you're enjoying the collective
efforts of this entire almost. No,
no.
I think it should be the product of one
or two cows and you can picture in your
head and maybe pat on the nose. Thank
you. You could say, yeah, I dunno.
I would both of you I
feel like weirds me out.
But I also think it's kind of cool
at the same time. Well, you know,
become a thing of it. What happens if
you drink a glass of milk in New York,
get on a plane, fly to Atlanta,
then have another glass of milk.
Are you getting the same 10,000 in
each class or are they different?
10,000 yeah,
so I tried calling around a little bit
to answer that question and it seems like
no one really wants to
pay to ship milk that far.
And so basically a different processing
plant might mean a whole different group
of cows.
If you really want to figure out exactly
which plant your milk is coming from,
you can go to where is
my milk from.com. Yeah,
and you input the little code on the top
of your carton and see how often that
number comes up. Again, each
processing plant has its own code
and yet there's so many stores.
Thank you, Rachel. Thank you. Um,
and just a big thanks to dairy farmer
Dale Mattoon over at pine hollow dairy.
Are you a big milk drinker? Oh yeah.
How often do you drink milk? Oh,
well I have it on my cereal in the Martin.
I have a glass or two for lunch
and a glass or two for dinner.
Probably two glasses each. Each
meal. If I don't drink milk,
I don't feel good. Like if I go away on
vacation. And a lot of times you go to
[inaudible]. No, now
[inaudible] [inaudible]
all right. This next one came from
a couple, a married couple. Hello,
is this Marie? Yup, this is Matt kilty
calling from Radiolab. How are you?
I'm good. Thanks. I have you on
speaker phone and that goes right here.
Oh, Hey Zach, how's it
going? So Zack Murray,
it was years ago actually,
they send us an email about what I think
is like one of the most confounding,
perplexing, mysterious devices that you
can find inside anybody's home. Okay.
So the microwave, I guess, I guess
what I'm wondering is how one,
why were you microwaving
peppers? Uh, and too you,
do you remember the moment this happened?
Oh, I know what it is. I know
that's what happened. So,
okay, so quick scene set. Uh, Portland,
Maine, a kitchen around dinner time,
I think we're like cooking a tomato sauce.
Zack was on bell pepper duty.
Try and take a shortcut,
take them in a microwave to make them
a little warm or soft or something.
And I said, oh that don't put those
in the microwave. They'll spark.
And Zach was just like, hmm,
you're crazy. Hogwash. Believe you
at all. And uh, reads like none of them
know. I remember seeing it as a kid.
You said there was a couple times her
mom put some peppers in a microwave and
they sparked
yes. My first thought was that,
and I never even was wrong.
[inaudible] bet your memory was wrong.
Like there must've been a piece of metal
in the microwave and you just don't
remember that.
And that's what was sparking up.
Cause festivals wouldn't do that.
And this is going back and forth in
yes and no and sparks and nothing until
I think it was like have to, we have
the ability to find this out and uh,
prove this wrong.
So that was like five
years ago in the past.
So we decided that we would actually do
our own experiment in the present to get
to the bottom of this. Do Green
peppers spark in the microwave
Maserati first things first. I
actually went and bought a microwave.
Has It gone off guy on craigslist?
I, yeah, so, uh, 50 bucks,
50 bucks, 50 bucks. Alright. Alright
baby. And carried it like uh,
hey eight blocks back to work.
Also bought a bunch of crosiers because
we were going to do more than just a
peppers test. And for reasons
I'd rather not get into. Uh,
decided not to start with the peppers.
Baby carrots. Carrots. Yeah.
Produce producer and Macewan.
Then we're going to kitchen.
Really? Yeah. Couldn't tell carrots.
Okay. And as the Great Runco
says of infomercial fame,
I don't know who the great Ron
go is. Great. Round. Go set it.
Alright, two minutes. Let's
see what happens. [inaudible]
and all of a sudden
this little yellow spark to shout out
from one of our slices of carrots.
That was crazy. As a little spark. Oh
yeah. There you see another one? Yeah,
I just saw a little flash.
Wow. Cause little tiny spark
carrots. Hmm. Okay.
Next Kale
[inaudible] this is where it gets a
little crazy because the Kale, oh, there.
Same thing. Boom, boom, boom.
Sparks smoke. It's a smell.
[inaudible] Jesus. Delicious.
Also. That is smoke.
Um, we're going to try
to base Maddie said it.
Woo. We started driving out
of a crowd in the studio.
Why was the electricity coming out of
the blueberry next I'm to get this.
Repeat those scripts.
[inaudible] and he means any time cook.
Whoa. All right. What's up
next? Okay. Jumbo francs.
Can I got Turkey? Frank
did set it. Spread it.
Oh my God. Okay. Pepper. Yes. Set it.
Okay. Both red and green bell peppers.
Green is crazy. Hey pepper. Yes,
it's green diced tomatoes. Heres
decorative gourd down again
and also a flaming lips city. There we go.
Who needs fireworks when you've got
a CD in the business? KZ shots up.
I wish that. Yeah, cause I don't
want it. Yeah. Is it gonna?
It looks like he was on fire. He's
this smoking in here. Yeah. Oh,
that smells really bad. I had to
take a break. Everybody. Oh God.
Yeah. We want to keep the door open.
What did you say to Maria after the
peppers sparked in the microwave?
I think I was, I don't know.
I was probably speechless.
I said I was a, yeah, I believe
that you're right. And Murray,
did you say anything in return? Oh
wait, something to the effect of,
I told you so.
So pepper, sparky, the
microwave. That was settled,
but then there was the debate about,
he doesn't believe my understanding
of how microwave's work. Why?
Maybe it's just that pepper has
a lot of moisture in it. Yeah.
Zach, maybe it's, you put
the pepper in the microwave.
All that water gets really high.
The skin acts as like Tinder and that
light's on fire quickly. But Marie,
we always have peppers in our house
and I think that the green wine taste a
little bit. MCKAYLA,
the, it's like maybe these peppers is,
have like some little bit of metal
in there that's sparking. Yeah.
And your next step to find
the appropriate scientist.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I'm definitely gonna
try and put this case to bed. Yeah,
just give us one moment. So ended
up tracking down this woman.
It's a Carolina Carolyn, is it
Kyle is Caroline. Caroline. Okay.
Her name is Caroline Ross.
I'm a professor in the
Department of material science
and engineering in MIT and
experienced microwave. I've done it
with them with roast potatoes. Oh,
you've seen sparks? Yeah, I've seen
sparks for most potatoes. Huh. All right.
So yeah, maybe we should just slate.
So I asked her in the case
of the peppers or you know,
the red potatoes or the grapes, like
all the different food that we tried,
like what happens in a microwave?
It makes the food just go late,
right? So let's say I got some pieces
of pepper put 'em in the microwave,
I press start like what,
what happens next? Okay.
So there was a gadget in the microwave
oven that produces the microwave's,
it's called a magnet farm. And, um,
it's, uh, an interesting thing in itself.
Okay. Quick side note.
It's basically like this hunk of
metal that makes the microwave.
But Kaitlin told me
this really cool thing,
which is they actually used to be
used, uh, in World War II for radar.
That was in the forties. And then in 1945,
there was an engineer at Raytheon who
was working on these devices and he found
that some candy bar he had in his
pocket got hot. I was like, oh,
this cooks food.
And so eventually a magnetron got thrown
inside of a metal box and thus was born
the microwave. So it's an
interesting thing in itself, but, uh,
it produces a beam of microwaves and
they bounce around inside the microwave
oven. Moving at the speed of light.
What are the, are the pounding
into the pepper or maybe not.
I don't really like shooting into the
painting absorbed, yeah. Being absorbed.
And these microwaves, um,
they are the right kind of frequency to
cause the molecules in food to oscillate
back and forth. Ah, you've
put a pepper in there.
So the purpose got a lot of water in
it. It's got all the things as well.
Um,
and those molecules start absorbing the
microwave's and dancing back and forth
and hitting each other and heating up.
And then that bit gets even hotter and
even hotter and eventually it could burst
into flames.
But that is not what we're seeing with
our pepper or any of the food in the
microwave. It's not, no, because, uh,
as Caroline explained to me a flame
is very different than a spark.
So one thing to keep in mind is that,
um, the pepper is fairly conductive.
It's got all this water in it.
We know that water can conduct
electricity and the water isn't pure.
It has a lot of salts dissolved in
it, minerals, things like that. Okay.
In that sense it's a little bit like
a piece of metal metal as we know,
absorbs microwave energy rather
well as we all know. Yes.
So,
um,
okay. So let's say you get these pieces
of pepper in the microwave and they're,
you know, carefully keeping up.
Okay. Now the thing is the microwave,
like the wave itself,
it has an electric field which oscillates
back and forth rather high frequency.
So when these make waves shoot
into these pieces of pepper,
what happens is this electricity starts
swishing back and forth through the bits
of pepper.
So there's a cone flowing and it's more
microwaves are absorbed in these bits of
pepper.
You can get quite big cones current
so big that they start to create this
electric field around the food and that
electric field builds up and up and up
and eventually it's big enough
to cause the air to glow
around the food because now there's
actually electricity coursing through the
air like a fluorescent light bulb can.
And says at this point you can start to
see these glowing balls of gas floating.
It's actually the air turning into plasma.
Now back in the center of the microwave
are are little bits of pepper where
there's still this electrical current
swishing back and forth through those bits
of pepper. And if you have sharp corners
like the actual corner of a pepper,
even on the skin, like these
tiny microscopic little points,
you're like trisomy in the pepper,
the electricity in the air can get
concentrated at those sharp corners like a
lightning rod. And at those
corners, electricity bill,
Bill ill until
[inaudible] you got some
mini lightening bolt.
And then Katelyn said everything in
the microwave, just sort of [inaudible]
palms down until the electric field
builds up again and it does it all over.
Letting loose these mini lightning
bolts. So it's a very dynamic,
you've got things being ionized,
you've got things recombining,
you've got charged flowing, you've got
light being emitted, things get hot,
there's a big current flowing all for
that tiny fraction of a second lot of
quantum physics in there.
And then we hear a little Ding and
then we're done and then we're done.
But I just had one last job to do. How
are you two doing? Okay, good. Okay.
All right. So I think called up second.
Marie told him everything I learned
about their sparking pepper.
And then even though both of them
didn't have the exact theory,
lake sac was right. Water's important.
Part of Murray was, you know,
kind of onto something with
this metal thing. Yeah.
It feels like it's almost like a little
bit of like a, um, a marriage of sorts,
pardon the pun, uh, between
both of your ideas that, uh,
kind of is what is happening
inside this black box.
Alright. So, yeah. Okay.
That's the way we were.
We have some of the elements
there. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um, so that's a, that's
about it. Okay, excellent.
Oh,
there was one thing that I
actually thought was kinda
interesting and all these
questions we were getting in there
was like this tiny little pattern of,
of married couples sending us
in, uh, arguments that they can,
there is, there was one
couple that was like, uh,
they were arguing about the nutritional
value of microwaving a potato. Um,
there was another couple that sent in
a very long email about how they'd been
debating about how we perceive color. Um,
you've actually had a similar
dispute. Yeah. Oh, over color
was the couch. Oh yeah.
They have some sort of like drab
tone that I thought was rain.
And you thought it was brown, Gray. I
agree that, yeah, I think that, yeah,
we had that couch for like
between different houses
and different combinations
for probably like five or six
years and maybe seven years,
10 years and a lot of
licensed. And I was, yeah,
I always thought it was gray and still do.
But apparently you and your
sister thought it was green.
You're like lived together for
years and just never realized.
You're seeing something completely
differently. Like what do you mean?
Our green couch. I have no idea.
We don't have a green couch
producer, Matt guilty.
[inaudible]
all right, so that's just a few
of the questions you asked us,
which we tried to answer, but that's
just the first part of our effort.
We have another whole sequence of
questions and answers coming up.
So if your question hasn't been
answered yet, um, hang tight,
never know the next batch. Put in your
question and it's coming very, very soon.