Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. Hi, I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is Radiolab and today, oh,
I dunno what we're talking about.
We're in a doubtful state of mind.
Constant doubt. That's the topic.
Yes. Like in the last chapter,
we met a person who had a real a doubt
pile up. He lost his faith in God.
He lost his girl.
This may be an extreme
example of something that
we all go through every day,
right? Yeah.
I mean you wake up and then you have to
get something done and then some little
voice inside you says, you know,
you can't do this. Sure about this,
but still you gotta act cause you're an
adult. So what do you do in that case?
How do you act without the
feeling of certainty? Hello? Hi,
Mr Sanny. Yes. Okay. And we met someone
who thinks about this all the time.
This is an area that I'm
pretty well versed in.
Would this be your stock in
trade? This would be very much so.
Her name is Annie Duke.
I'm a decision strategist.
But you might know her better
as a bad ass poker player.
Well in 2004 I won a bracelet
which is a a world championship.
I also won the tournament of champions
that year. That was the cheers one a lot.
Now when we call up Annie,
we had this idea about poker that
I think a lot of people have,
which is that it's like this game
about tills like reading your opponent,
watching the way their nose quivers so
that you can tell when they're bluffing
or when they've got a good hand. Nope.
Taos are actually a very
small part of the game fact.
She says they often backfire.
I remember the first tournament
I played after it was on TV,
I had a hand that was kind of a close
decision and this guy moved all of his
chips into the pot and God,
he was just confident like I could see
like he was really confident in his hand,
so I threw my hand away.
But then in a subsequent game she sees
the same guy doing exactly the same
thing. He pushes all his chips in
looking super confident. I was like, wow,
he must have like a crazy
hand, like two aces.
And he turns his hand over face
up and he's super confident in it.
And it was a really bad hand. It was
just the hand that he thought was good.
So the problem for me was that
I read him totally correctly,
but what I didn't understand
was that he didn't,
let's call him inexperienced, he didn't
know what a good hand or a bad hand was.
But then you get players who are a
little bit more experienced and sometimes
they would do what's called a reverse
towel. Is it like a double fake? Right?
They'd basically pretend
to be overconfident.
So she think they're dumb and I'm in
the Biz. They call that hollywooding.
So she says, unless you've
played someone a million times,
it's really hard to know how to read
them and what's worse. The good players,
they do nothing. Doing nothing is the
best choice, which you try to disappear.
You pick a spot on the table, stare at it.
What do you do in the case where
there aren't any signals to read?
And the only thing you really
know is that you know nothing.
Well actually what you sort of figure
out is that you don't need to know.
The real breakthrough moment for me
was when I stopped trying to figure out
anything with certainty. And here
any laid out a way of thinking,
I just leave caming doubt that
we find completely fascinating.
And that has paid off for her to the
tune of about $4 million. Huh. Well,
you know, I think that, do you
mind if we just back up? Okay.
Like how did you get to be
Annie Duke? Um, well I was,
I was born Annie letterer
and then I married someone
with the last name Duke and
thought that's much easier to be Annie
Duke. Well, I went to Columbia Undergrad,
double major in English literature
and Psychology, psychology.
Then I went to U Penn, studied
cognitive psychology there.
I had a national science foundation
fellowship. And then right at the end, um,
just really had this realization that
I didn't really want to be an academic
holy hell. Like what am
I going to do now? Okay,
well I need some money. I'll play
some poker while I'm figuring it out.
And as you played a lot of
poker to that point, no,
but I'd watch my brother play a lot.
Well she, she would come out and
she would sit behind and watch.
That's Annie's brother.
This is Howard Howard letter
sounds exactly like his sister,
but with a deeper voice.
He started mentoring me a little bit. Um,
and I started making money right away.
She was very competitive.
I think your mother tearing out her hair
at this point or was she agreed at that
point? My parents had just given up
hope. My brother when he was 18, he,
my grandfather,
grandfather had the family,
a $2,000 check for the two of
us to help with college. And um,
my brother gambled it away
and a little poke around in the back room.
Well that might've been the very early
phase. I was a terrible poker player.
It has since become a very
decorated, open player.
And he's also been in the news recently
because an online poker company,
he was associated with cold, full tilt.
So we've gotten into some
legal difficulties. But
back when he was starting,
so I started,
he says he would play in these tiny
little games 36 hours straight,
which was not atypical for me back then
and it was all very seat of the pants.
But I, but I, I arrived in
this wonderful situation,
fortunate he happened
to be learning the game,
which you would later teach to
his sister at a time, you know,
1983 1984 when the game
was changing radically.
[inaudible]
poker poker was this Texas
gambler thing happening in Vegas.
Like the Cliche we just
talked about, you know,
that you play with your gut with the Texas
Dolly and Amarillo slim and who knows
what's going on over there. But
then like in so many other things,
the geeks took over.
Okay,
well, you know, there were these
games, I was playing it and I was,
people will peg the change to different
times, different places. But for Howard,
it began in New York. Yup. When he
joined this regular game, but huge game.
These are Wall Street traders,
world champion, bridge
players, brilliant people.
They get together after Wall Street,
closed play for about eight hours.
Then go to a bar and carefully deconstruct
the eight hours they just played,
you know, hey, what were you thinking in
that? Why did you do that? Why you you,
you weren't really bluffing,
but you made this big bet w
and out of those conversations
came the style of play that you now find
everywhere. Yeah. Hold on. Okay, let,
listen. If you Google the phrase
right now, hold them odds chart,
you're going to be able to give him,
hold him, hold him, hold him odds chart.
We ended up talking to our
friend Mike about all this.
My name is Mike [inaudible].
I cover sports for NPR and he's also
spent a fair amount of time in underground
poker clubs. By the way,
it's always a misnomer cause in New York
City they're always on the ninth floor
of an office building or something
like that. Anyway, he showed us these,
these charts. Yeah. Okay, and what my
God, look at this thing. What is it?
It's like my nightmare. It's like a
spreadsheet with tons and tons of numbers.
Well first I'll say this, but Mike
says, don't be afraid. These charts,
this is how you achieve
zen in an uncertain world.
Okay, let's say, let me give you a
situation. Let me give you a situation.
You're playing the game of hold'em
and there's only one card to come.
The river card that is the
last card and hold them.
And you figure in fact just
explained in Texas hold'em,
each player gets two secret cards that
they can see and the dealer puts down a
bunch of a community cards one
by one that everyone can see.
And the game is who can combine their
secret cards with the community cards to
make the best hand. Exactly.
Now say one of your secret cards
is a heart. And on the board,
the community cards include
three, three hearts. Okay,
I've got one in my hand that's for
dealers about the deal. Another card.
And if the last card is a heart,
well damn, I would have a flush.
So I want to know what are the
odds of me getting that last heart.
Every decent poker player will know
how to calculate this automatically.
And for the non decent ones,
Weldon, there's the chart.
You know there are 13 of
every suit in the deck.
You know there are 13 hearts in the
deck and there are three hearts on the
board. One of my hand.
That means that you can figure that
there are 30 minus three minus one nine
cards in the deck out of the 46 that we
don't know about that can complete my
flush. Now look at this
chart I'm looking at nine.
Number nine is all the way to
the right nine flush draw night.
So when you do the odds that you wind up
having a about a 20% chance of victory
of getting that last heart. Yeah.
Uh,
okay. So what do you do in this
circumstance? Am I one more time?
What am I in my odds? Your odds
are 20% you bet. Do you go for it?
Do you stay in, be bold or
do you fold? I personally,
I fall totally at fault. Of course you
fall. I walk away. Get out of there.
I quit the game. Live to fight another
day. Exactly. No, no, no, no, no, no,
no. Not necessarily.
Every poker. And he says there are times
when 2020 5% sure means bet. Bet. Bet.
I know that sounds counterintuitive.
So let me explain what I mean.
And this is the none of it right here.
Let's say that someone bats $100
and there's already $200 in the pot.
Okay? That means that for
you continue with your hand,
you have to put in $100.
So if you win the pot,
you'll win $300 and if you lose the pot,
you'll lose $100 right?
In order to break even,
you could lose the pot three times
because you'd lose $100 three times.
So that would be negative 300 and you
could win the pot once. That makes sense,
right? Cause you're going to get
300 and then you would break even.
So you could lose $100 on
Monday, $100 on Tuesday.
You lose another a hundred on when they,
but if you win the 300 back on
Thursday, yeah, you're good.
You just need to win one
out of every four times,
so that means that you have to
win the pot 25% of the time.
Those are your pot odds.
Pot odds are what dictates good bets.
The amount that's in the pot determines
how certain you have to be that your
hand is good,
which is a really cool concept I think
because if you're pot odds are 25% and
all you really need to be is 25%
sure that you have a good hand,
which you are in the hearts case.
Sometimes you have to be 40% sure.
Sometimes you have to be 30% sure you
know if there's $70 in the pot and you
only have to call 10 you know now
you're in the 15% range in terms of how
certain you have to be. That
your hand is good. In that case,
you can bet this hand that you really
not sure about knowing that while you
might lose this time, if I do that
a million times in my poker life,
the law of high numbers indicates that
I'm going to be very much a winner in the
long run. It might be the very long run,
but you should be ahead in
the long run because it's not.
It's not about winning
the hand all the time.
It's about winning the
hand enough at the time.
That is what she got watching her brother.
I'm sure that I'm just quoting him and
that's warm comfort. I mean that's,
that's weird. So the man,
the probabilities or what you
carry it care about most. Yeah,
because that sort of embracing
of uncertainty [inaudible]
some really wonderful
things for you.
If you're in a situation where you only
have to have the best hand 25% of the
time. If you're playing well, you're going
to have a bad hand a lot of the time.
It's okay.
It's actually a relevant and that's
really the big bonus of this way of
thinking.
You begin to learn how to avoid that
very human tendency to feel shamed.
There is when you lose, you
just float right above it.
If you're making good decisions,
then you're making good decisions.
You have to be somewhat outcome blind, but
sometimes that's not so
easy. Yeah. [inaudible]
there is no event on the planet like it.
2004 the world series of poker,
biggest tournament in all of poker.
What a tournament this is,
they handle emotionally.
Three people at the table
and he Duke. This guy,
Phil Hellmuth is a big player
and and his brother Howard,
they've played together for so
long. It never for 2 million,
never been in this type of
position. The 2 million is an alive,
they get their cards and hey,
Duke was sixes. I had two.
Six is pretty good hand and she'll open
with 70,000 big fat opening bet over to
Phil. Phil thinks no,
they'll help me with immediately
gets out of the way again.
He folds over to our letter room and
here's where things get interesting.
Instead of folding like that Guy
Phil, my brother moved in on me.
Howard goes all in against his sister.
Decision now to Andy with the pocket
sixes. Any things? Should I stay in?
Should I bail? Well, mathematically,
two six is actually rates to be
the best hand there. So brother,
it's on. Yeah. However,
when they turn over their
cards and remember she has
two sixes actually he's got
a seven and it turned out he had two
seven. Yup. That's what he wants.
A four to one favorite. And
Annie knows she's in trouble,
her brother in a commanding position
and he was 82% to win the hand.
They both knew that if they
play this hand a hundred times,
he's gonna win about 82 of them.
The only thing that can save her is if
the dealer now turns over a sixth is 18%
chance and here comes the flop.
Dealer turns, blueprints, the cards
and he gets her six at a full house.
Oh God.
And she immediately feels horrendous
for her brother and I won the hand.
And that's the end of the
line for a Howard Lederer,
Annie Duke Knox or big
brother out in the video.
You see her getting up from the
table? She hugs her brother.
Oh, this is very difficult
for Annie. I want to,
you see her emotions and you must
have mixed about that failure.
Look, I was 82% when that pot.
That was incredibly, I'm like,
yeah, and she my sister too.
I taught her how to do that.
Yeah, no, I wanted to win that
hand. That's, that's for sure. I,
I was upset when my mom watched that.
She called me up and she was
like in tears and she was like,
how could you knock your brother out
of the tournament? And I was like,
I now I know your favorite
is now. Here's the thing.
If you, if your superior
cards do not win the day,
you know we have vocabulary to deal
with that. It's called a bad beat.
A bad beat.
A bad beat is when you had the cards
that should've won and you got beat. Wow.
There's a term that should
catch on right there. If,
say in stock investing you
were to say, look, you,
you invested for all the right reasons,
but the stock went down because someone
you'd never heard of shorted it.
That was a bad beat. Do you know
what, I wonder what, like, you know,
this whole, uh, rigorous
probabilistic way of thinking,
is that something that you just acquire
once you know the math or do you have to
first be of a certain cast of mind
in order to Kinda get into it? Well,
that's, I'm not sure it would work for me.
You have to be from a pretty unusual
family techno to get constellation that
I'll tell you what our
family's like. So, um,
my brother and my brother in law
both knew my boyfriend before we,
me and my boyfriend started
dating. OK. And they,
when they found out we
were going on a date,
they made a market for what
the probability was that
we would actually end up
together together. That he
was willing to give me $27.
If they get married, I
have to give him a hundred.
I was offering 73 to 27 what is
wrong with you? And I was like,
are you insane? We haven't gone
on a date together. Exactly.
They've never gone on a date yet.
I made one of the best bets ever.
I assume you'd be happy to lose
that then. I'm going to be,
I'm going to be thrilled. But, but
that's how gamblers think. I mean,
it's not a bad way or
taints anything, it's just,
that's the way that we memorialize the
fact that we had a fundamental difference
of opinion
that works. You know,
if you're bidding on your sister's
marital status I suppose, but if,
if it's, uh, if it's bigger stakes,
like going back to the beginning of the
program where we were concerned with the
presence or on presence of God,
that's not a mathematical thing.
Oh, well I'm not so
sure that's true, Sarah.
And what'd you like to say
something? They're there. You know,
there was a guy named Pascal, I don't
know if you've ever heard of them.
They have who thought that
you could do exactly that.
So he was one of the first
thinkers of probability.
So all this stuff we've
been talking about,
but he at some point was also struggling
with the question of God and he
couldn't decide for sure.
He always thought there was a chance
that he did exist, a chance he didn't.
So he didn't know what to do. So
he came up with an idea. He said,
if I decided to believe him, him
[inaudible] all right. In that scenario,
if he exists eternal
forever, happy, happy.
If you believe in him and he
happens to be there, then you win.
You win the pot big time
forever. Like infinite. Now,
if I decide to not believe in
God, that's my other option.
[inaudible] and now I'm a not believer.
If he does exist and you don't believe
very, very, very infinite, bad,
eternal damnation forever, you
go to hell, then you go to hell.
So there's a huge infinite payoff to
believing in God and there's an infinite
downside to not believing in God the
pot eyes. So no matter how I speak, yes,
because no matter how unlikely
it is that God actually exists,
this is like Annie having an infinite
amount of money on the table.
No matter how bad her cards are, how
unlikely is she thinks she'll win?
You gotta Bet. You have to bet the pot.
Odds are saying that you must
believe in God is what you're is.
That's what Pascal said. Pascal said,
if you do the math the way Andy
does the math, believe in God.
What are the pot odds on God? But
that's ridiculous, by the way. You know?
That's ridiculous. [inaudible]
why? Because you've Kels,
faith is lesser his.
His belief in God because he got to it
through math is somehow lesser than,
I don't know, say Saint Augustine or
someone you were spending less because,
because we're talking here about
grace and love and being connected,
and it's, it is.
It is a daredevily heart of
your hearts full of emotion.
That's what rules here,
and that's what guide you.
It is not calculating the odds.
The od Sir looking pretty
a divine right now.