[inaudible].
You're listening to radiolab
from New York public radio,
public radio,W Y,
y c
[inaudible]
testing, testing. This is radio lab.
I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert Krulwich.
And since this hour we'll be talking
about brains and bodies and how they
communicate.
We thought we'd begin the program with a
guy with that we'd go to quite often he
knows about this sort of thing.
Oliver Sacks. Oliver is a neurologist.
Should I get closer to
very famous author? Yeah.
Took us to his study to show us
something that just fascinates him.
Um, I've become fascinated. I'm instantly,
I hope you have to be careful
with your watch or your computers.
[inaudible]
um, he showed us a silver ball.
I should just describe here I am looking
at a silver bowl about the size of a
small, small ping pong ball, which
he handed to you, right? Yep.
Would you care to lift that, that
little steel ball this little,
and as soon as he did, I am
interesting.
The ball went flying through the
air, taking your hand with it,
smack into the nearest bit of metal
in the vicinity, which was a plate.
Little tear left very
fast and it hurt. Wow.
That'd be cool. I've got a cat. Okay.
I don't put it too near your watch.
And also you have to
put it down very gently.
Otherwise it may fly with great
violence onto this nickel slam.
What is that and what are we
talking about it? Okay. Um,
well this is a little rare earth
metal magnet of great strength.
[inaudible]
these magnets orient themselves almost
violently to the earth's magnetic field.
If you have a couple of these things,
say in your pockets and you go
for a walk, as you turn a corner,
you will feel them really at
themselves in your pockets.
I like like little animals.
So your, your pockets would tell you
whether you were going north, south,
east or west.
Good. So whenever you have
the way with magnets and
how you hear very weird man, how
would you propose to use this?
In what situation that you have imagined?
Would it be a happy advantage? Well.
Um, I, I myself, I'm always
getting lost. I have,
I have no sense of direction.
I would function [inaudible]
come downtown to meet me.
You would know because of the pressure
on your thighs from these little balls
that you were carrying out, whether you
were going downtown or not downtown.
You see, and I may need things
like this. I am very bad at all.
Anting myself in space. He's
trying to do with the birds too, right?
Bird because birds have magnets in their
brains are or something like magnets
which lets them fly south
so they know where it is.
They fly it when they're
migrating, right? Yeah.
He's trying to start a
conversation like a bird,
but because he's choosing his thighs,
he wants his thighs to talk to his
brain. I've often wondered as an aside,
uh, the extent to which one, um,
one could develop a new sense.
That's what this hour of radio lab is
about. Human beings, not just Oliver,
all kinds of folks who are attempting
to add census and mostly to subtract.
Since we'll have stories about both
adding and losing sentences in more
generally, you look at how
brains and bodies communicate,
often fail to communicate
because believe it or not,
it's not an easy relationship
between your brain and your body.
There's a lot of confusion, deception,
even. That's what new research shows.
And we'll get into all of that. So
let's get into it. Alright. Okay.
Ready? Yeah, we're first, well,
let's begin with on urology.
Um, well listen, my cell phone is
ringing, so let me pause until it stops.
So that's Robert Sapolsky. He's a
professor of biology at Stanford.
I've never figured out how to do voice
messaging or whatever it is even has done
in this century. Prisoners of I machine.
Yes. Oh, okay. We're in business here.
Okay, so to begin now,
I said to Robert Sapolsky just to get
my head around this. Let's imagine it.
I decided to visit my best friend
in the world, Tommy, Tommy. I walk
over to his house. I have a key.
So I opened the front door, Tommy,
I walk into his apartment
and then I see him
sprawled on the floor, dead
[inaudible]
and in a horrible,
tragic, instant like that,
I wonder what would be
going on in my brain.
And I asked this because his answer is
supposed to the answer. It was so weird.
According to some Polsky, what happens
happens in the following order.
First Light bounces off Tommy's
corpse and Andrew's my eye. Okay?
It goes up some nerve from your
eyes and into one part of the brain,
which turfs it onto the next part. And
then the inflammation keeps moving.
A couple of steps down. It gets into
what's called your visual Cortex,
which turns the dots into
lines and lines into shapes.
And that's just like a local train.
You're taking eventually that local
train carrying the image of timing kg and
chug deeper into my brain, to my
cortex. And after a few more stops,
I will finally know, I will
consciously know the Tommy is dead.
But now here's the surprise.
Information can move through the brain
in different ways at the same time.
And there is a second route, it turns,
there's a second pathway into my body,
into my nervous system, which bypasses
all of that visual cortex stuff
like a bullet train and goes straight
to this area called the Amygdala.
And what the Amygdala does is instantly
it tells the heart to pound your heart
speeds up the stomach to clinch
stomach muscles, clench tears to flow,
and you're still a couple of seconds
away from like even consciously making
sense of what you're seeing.
And by then already your
stomach is heading towards
your throat or your throat's
in your mouth or whatever the cliche is.
So as I'm standing there in Tommy's
apartment looking at this figure on the
ground before I even know
what I'm looking at before,
I am consciously aware that Tommy is dead.
My body already knows that's
exactly the punchline.
Your body knows that before
you consciously know it. Right?
Which is an astonishing idea. It is
astonishing, but it's not a new idea.
Yeah.
This goes back to what was originally
viewed as this totally asinine theory in
psychology back around
1,901 of the, you know,
grand old poop laws of psychology,
William James, Dean James,
and he's trying to answer the
question where feelings came from.
That's Jonah Leora science writer.
He really likes William James.
He's written a lot about him and
he says, a hundred years ago,
William James poses a thought experiment.
He gives the example of a bear.
He says, imagine you're
walking through the woods.
All of a sudden I'm behind a tree.
Yeah,
the bear attacks. Any wonder William
James did. Okay, so the bear attacks,
you're going to feel scared.
But what exactly is that
feeling of fear made of?
Which seems like a strange
question to ask. Yeah, but, but he,
he was trying to be empirical about it.
He was trying to be a good psychologist.
And his answer was that the feeling
is the perception of your body,
meaning step one, you see the bear, you
see a bear with his teeth and his claws.
Step two, your body
response, a fast heartbeat,
the adrenaline cursing in your
bloodstream. And it's only in step three.
When the brain sees the body respond,
does it, then it trigger the feeling,
a fear,
and the feeling of fear comes from the
perception of those changes in your body.
If you took away the heartbeat,
if you took away the body,
there'd be nothing left
to feel. Needless to say,
when William James proposed this idea,
people absolutely crazy, he was nuts,
completely nuts. They said,
you know, if you're right,
then someone who's paralyzed from the
neck down and who doesn't get signals from
their body,
well that person would see the bear in
the woods and they wouldn't get scared,
which is ridiculous. Completely
ridiculous. So the critics said,
William James is wrong, dead wrong,
and that's the end of it. Yeah, the
end of it. Hello.
We happened to bump into a
neurologist, Antonio Damasio,
director of the brain and creativity
institute at the University of Southern
California. Wow. What a nice place.
So we're sitting near with demasio.
We happened to be talking about
William James and his critics,
which we always do always
do on, you know, lunch.
We don't go into a luncheonette for
lunch and before we order a tuna fish
sandwich, we always mentioned
William James in his critics.
This is something we do. So I
said to the, I said, Demasio,
you know the critics call James Wrong
because he said people who were paralyzed
couldn't feel anything and he
says you, it's funny you should
mention this because there's been a
series of studies thinking about James One
more time and it's very interesting
because the first study that was made in
this area,
it was made by a paraplegic psychologist
who thought that he felt less emotional
than he was before and he talked to
others and others reported the same.
The studies reported that people who had
once been able bodied and then became
paralyzed, felt less, less
happy than able bodied people,
less sad, been able body people just less.
Our B is rooted in a body state.
If I would be able to remove from your
brain the representation of your body,
you would not know that you are you
and would I not be sorry at my friend's
death? You definitely would
not be started at anything.
What is in fact the essence
of being joyful or sad.
If you don't hook those
notions on a changed body,
he's right. You know? I mean, if you
think about the last time you were sad,
like really sad, how would you describe
that feeling to yourself? Right.
In fairness when I guess I would,
I would say I felt dragged
out and heavy. Yeah.
That feeling is completely
rooted in your flesh. Well,
brain has nothing to do with that
thought. Made me say it and then my body,
hold on. Hello?
Oh, hi. Yeah. Hold on one second.
Is Your wife here?
Hello? Robert? Yeah. I can't believe you
still there. What are you doing there?
What do you mean? Am I doing here?
You're supposed to be home an hour ago
in the studio. We were
on the, I don't care.
What do you mean you're
supposed to be home an hour ago.
I reminded you this morning. I
reminded you last night. I was pissed.
Not Important to you. This is not
such a big deal. I'll be back in.
Actually this just an example
we've been talking about. No.
Robert's having a fight
with his wife, Tamar,
and while he's fighting inside his body,
his stomach is clenching his hardest.
Palpitating. Hers is doing the same,
but their brains are picking up
these signals. I'm thinking anger.
They feel angry.
As important as your WIC screwed
it up. How did I screw it up?
How did I screw up your job
though? At a certain point,
Robert will probably realize he
has screwed up and just get home.
He'll apologize if I get home
in 20 minutes. I'm really sorry.
I know this is horrible. I said,
yeah, yeah, it's just a second.
I'm really sorry. Okay. He'd be like, no.
When it comes to brains and
bodies and men and women.
The interesting thing is that when a man
and woman fight these systems in their
body, the heart, the stomach clenching,
while these systems do turn on at the
same speed and it takes like two seconds
according to Robert Spolsky where there's
an interesting gender difference is
how long it takes to turn off
the system and ladies, sorry,
in advance and in general it turns
off more slowly in women than in men,
which may explain something that
happens to couples all the time.
Okay, good. I'm really sorry this isn't
right. I know. Oh, I'm really sorry.
Like here we are.
Maybe like maybe later we'll go
do something or I'm really sorry.
Robert Stomach is relaxing.
This is really stupid. I know.
His heart is slowly very stupid.
He thinks the fight might be over.
Okay.
You know, this is something
you do all the time.
When we were having a dinner right
after we got engaged and we went to the
restaurant and I was waiting for
you and I've made the reservation
for like 45 minutes. You didn't
even call it just you didn't.
Did you hear what just happened there?
It's this way of even James stuff
coming back to haunt us a century later.
Topolski says sometimes the
body actually tricks. The brain.
Tame knows the fight is over
mentally, but her body's still tense.
Her heart is still racing and
her brain thinks, Whoa, wait,
if my heart is still racing and I
consciously know that this issue has been
resolved,
it must be because I'm still pissed off
about that thing that happened in the
Carter Administration.
Minimize every day. Maybe it goes for you.
Brain fills a vacuum. We have
a list. You have a list there?
I do. I have a long list. I didn't know
how often you do this sort of thing.
I do it like one. I can tell them
this year the babies are calls.
I'm going to be out of town and says,
should I make dinner for Robert?
Because quickly you can't make
dinner for yourself and the kids. No,
I do make dinner. I haven't made much
of anything. Potatoes. Last week,
Wednesday I made the big potatoes.
That's just applying heat.
I want to thank my wife,
Tamer Lewin for what I think was a pretty
startling lead that really, I mean,
performance switch.
I don't know how she did that because
it's so unlike the rest of our marriage.
You know this story by the way,
came from Robert Sapolsky and
he tells it about his wife too,
but they're not reporters. They're
scientists, so they do it differently.
My wife's in the same business as me,
so the very words we will
say to each other is, honey,
don't forget what the half life is
on the autonomic nervous system.
Then suddenly it's all over with.
That's such a rare exchange
between two people. You know? I
know. We're just sentiment. By the way.
Robert Spolski's latest book is called
Monkey Love, which is where that
anecdote came from. Ed.
Speaking of brains and bodies [inaudible]
let's put the science on pause for a
moment and take a brief detour because
often what gets you into these ideas,
like take this kid, for example,
Christopher seals go to the Blake
high school isn't the science.
It's more basic than that.
It seems something disgusting
and not being able to look away.
You really just can't believe
that if something feels like this,
it actually came out of a real person.
You just don't get the feeling.
When we bumped into Christopher, he was
gingerly holding a pair of human lungs,
but it is a real person,
but you just can't really associate
with a real person because it's there in
front of you and it doesn't look like
real person in case. That sense of, whoa.
That's why we originally went to the
Walter Reed Army Medical Center in
Washington d c but here's
what happened. Our tour guide.
Okay, Steven S. T. E. V. E.
N. Solomon, s. O. L. O. M. O.
He showed us the particular
photo that got us thinking
a famous photo in our archives.
It's called field day.
It's a civil war photo
hanging in a sign gallery.
It's a picture of legs.
Kyle have amputated legs, a
huge heap of severed legs,
some feet thrown sort of
haphazardly into a pile.
Wow. It's oddly beautiful in
a way, gruesome, gruesome,
but the next thought immediately after
was what was happening at that moment.
Right to one side of the picture frame
must've been an operating table and on
the table,
soldier inhaling chloroform and at the
foot of the table must've been a doctor
signing away,
a circular amputation involved cutting
straight through the skin to the bone.
A flap amputation required the tissue
to be cut in two flaps of skin that were
used to create a stump and in fact
your typical army surgeon was basically
graded on how quickly they could do an
amputation. That was one of the first,
they really had doctors being
aggressive in terms of taking off limbs.
Like I said, that photo got us thinking,
so we went back to Jonah Lehrer who has
written how about a very ghostly side
effect that pops up during the civil
war as a direct result of all of that,
taking off of limbs, this,
this one astonishing syndrome that these
men who have had their limbs taken off,
they describe very,
very often this a very common thing that
they still feel their phantom limbs.
They say they feel it. Yeah. They
say, doctor, I, I still feel it. Move.
They can feel it hurt. Get through that.
Sometimes get hot sometimes very cold.
Imagine you're a civil war
doctor and you hear this. He,
you don't even know what germs
are yet. But one guy, Dr Silas,
where Mitchell decides he's
going to get to the bottom of it,
the first thing he did was he wrote
some clinical reports only. Yeah.
About 5% of the men who have suffered
amputation never have any feeling of the
part as being still present, um,
and circulated them or in the hospital
while the remainders seemed to retain a
sense of its existence.
So vivid as to be more definite and
intrusive than it is of the truly living
fellow member.
The stump is liable to the most horrible
[inaudible] and to a certain curious
spasmodic paralysis.
[inaudible]
no one could make sense of this.
Even our Guy William James,
even he looks into it,
he did a very authoritative study where
he sent out questionnaires to all these
amputee victims and wanting to
know about their lost limbs.
He has all of these civil war
amputees, all these questions,
does your phantom limb hurt? Can you
move it? If you really concentrate?
And what he found was that
there were no patterns,
no stereotypical loss limb every,
every experience was different.
In other words, phantom
limbs are like real limbs.
They're yours.
Well, on this topic of Phantom limbs,
there is a guy who has figured at least
something out about this phenomenon.
Dr v S Ramachandra. I am a v S
Ramachandra. Remember him? I remember him.
He's a well known neurologist.
He works in California at the
University of California, San Diego.
And one day he says,
a patient showed up in his office and
it seems that the guy had had his arm
amputated. It was his left arm.
And then ever since this man had an
uncanny feeling that he still had an arm
where his real arm used to be. Yes,
it's important to emphasize
this is not a delusion.
He doesn't think he has an arm. He
knows he doesn't. He's not crazy,
but he vividly feels it's presence.
And the rough part was
that this arm eat hurt.
This sometimes happens to
people with phantom limbs.
He would have days where his phantom
arm would seize up in pain. Doctor,
it hurts really badly. Goes into
this painful clenching spasm.
The nails dig into my palm.
So he has a phantom hand at the
end of his phantom limb. Yes,
and he will say things like,
it's going into a cramp with the nails
digging into the phantom palm and it's
excruciatingly painful, but there
are no nails. There is no no problem.
And weirdest of all, the patient
couldn't do anything about it.
He try to unclench his phantom nails
from his phantom palm to make the pain
stop, but he couldn't. He said,
I cannot move the fountain.
The fandom I'm wouldn't obey.
I cannot volitionally move it.
And I started thinking to myself,
what does he mean when he says he cannot
move his phantom limb like an oxymoron?
There is no arm there.
Drew Ramachandran was
confused what's going on. He,
he checked with the patient and
discovered that 11 years earlier,
before the amputation,
he'd had an injury to his spine and after
that his real left arm was paralyzed.
He could not move it. He tried his
brain would issue the commands.
His brain will say move the arm.
But he was getting visual feedback and
indeed feedback from his muscles saying,
nope, move the arm. No move.
No. And this went on for months,
move. No,
so maybe the doctor Rameshchandra maybe
this patient got so frustrated trying to
move his real arm that at some
point, after a few months or a year,
the paralysis [inaudible]
learnt by the brain
snapping into the circuitry of the
brain. Well, I call it learned,
learned paralysis. So even
when they cut the patients,
I'm off a year after the accident,
he still didn't get any relief
because the problem wasn't in his arm.
It was learned paralysis.
It was in his head. Now,
and that is when
Ramachandra thought, well,
maybe the solution here is to trick this
man's brain to unparalyzed to get his
cells to think, well
actually we can move on,
but how do you trick a brain? How would
you do that? How would you do that?
How would you do that? How would you
do that? Indeed, he thought for a bit.
Then I hit on this way of using a
mirror prompt inside a cardboard box.
What a mirror mirror prompt
inside a cardboard box.
A mirror pro parked inside
a box popped up. Oh,
it was kind of a home
depot solution. Really.
Ramachandran took a
long and skinny mirror.
The kind you'd hang on
a closet door, right?
Any propped it up using a cardboard
box and then turned it sideways.
Place the side right in front of the
patient like right on his nose because he
couldn't see himself. No,
couldn't see anything in the mirror
yet unless he hooked his neck around.
Took a p. Oh, otherwise he's just
looking at the side. Ramesh Arjun says,
I want you to imagine
this with me. Jeff says,
I want you to take your
good on your real arm. Okay?
And stick it out in front of
the mirror. So do that. Okay,
now make it do what the phantom arm
does. Pick your good arm. Make it stiff.
Curl your hand into a fist. Dig Your
fingernails into your palm deeply.
Make it hurt. You're doing that. It's
kind of hurting. Now when I tell you,
Cook your head so that you can look
into the mirror and on your left,
just where your the fandom ought to be.
Let's pretend that that's your
phantom arm. It's cramped.
It's curled exactly as you'd imagine
it. So now look in the mirror, okay?
And there's your arm. You see it there
and nearer your phantom arm. Got It.
Now very slowly keeping
your eye on the mirror.
Now I want you to
[inaudible] curl your hand.
Patient says, okay, he
opens his real hand, my God,
and of course it looks like his phantom
is opening. That's not surprising.
He's got do the mirror there,
but he says, my God, doctor,
you're not going to believe this.
The movements of all comeback,
all these movements in
my fingers, in my elbow,
in my wrist from 11 years ago,
come flooding into my mind.
So it was his pretend nails
are now ungripping from his pretend
palm in the whole problem of the pretend
pain goes away, goes away. That's what
he said. For how long? By the way, total.
The middle was in place. But when Dr
Rameshchandra took away the mirrors,
the pain came back.
I said, fine, say, let me, you
know, and then I said, look,
why don't you practice with a mirror for
the few weeks, every day for an hour.
Then maybe if you do it repeatedly,
you can unlearn the learn to pain.
So this guy goes home, I told him, you
give him a mirror to take home. Correct.
And if it was $22 take it with you. So
he texted with him, he was delighted.
And then after about another week,
he phones and he sounds all agitated on
the phone. And I said, what's going on?
So doctor, you're not going to believe
this. It's gone. I said, what's going on?
I thought maybe the mirror was gone.
He said, no, no, not the mirror.
The Phantom has gone, gone. Go on.
God. That's what I said. Gone. Gone.
What do you mean fandom
was going? He it? Well,
this phantom arm I been having for the
last 11 years, it's disappeared. Well,
my, my, my initial reaction was alarm.
I said, my God, does this bother you?
That it cause it, no. You know,
this has happened three days ago and
in the last three days you remember the
excruciating elbow pain and wrist
pain. I've got several times a day,
but I don't have them anymore
because I don't have an arm.
But my fingers
they have not disappeared and they're
still up here dangling near my shoulder.
They're still painful. You mean just
disconnected? Disembodied fingerless yeah.
Finger looks dangling from the
shoulder. What? W what does that mean?
This guy's saying that he seems to have
fingertips hanging on his shoulder.
He said you a mirror doesn't work anymore,
so can you redesign it and
push it properly near my
nose so I can look at that
reflection and maybe get,
get rid of the fingers.
So he now wants to get Dr
Ramachandra to prop up the mirror,
point them at these phantom fingertips
and have the mirror erase the fingertip.
You thought I was a magician
and I got, you know,
eliminate his different
body parts and sequence.
And this is amputation by mirror? Yeah.
As I tell my medical
colleagues jokingly, I say,
this is the first example in the history
of medicine of a successful amputation
of a phantom limb. Yeah, so
don't leave me hanging here.
Did the phantom fingers eventually
dissolve? No. Vv we still haven't.
Have they been able to devise a technique
to get them and it turns out that the
pain there subsided a bit, so he's not
that worried about us getting rid of him.
So somewhere in California there's
still a guy walking around with a sense,
fingers on his shoulder. Yeah. Are still
dangling. Another shoulder, which is,
well, not only weird,
it suggests that there's an awful lot
to know about how brains and bodies
interact. Many things to learn,
but for a work at day doc who has to deal
with whatever comes through the door.
Dr Rameshchandra and had what I would
call a pretty good day at the office. Yes,
exactly.
Yes.
Ramachandran is a neuroscientist at the
University of California in San Diego,
author of many books, including a
brief tour of human consciousness,
which is where you can find
out all about the mirror.
Right next up. Let's scale it up a bit.
We're going to go from lost limbs
to a guy who's lost everything.
His entire sense of his body.
I'm Jad Abumrad Robert Krulwich
and I will continue in a moment.
[inaudible] you are listening to radio
from New York public radio,
you and
C h. N. P. R. Hello,
this is Stefania [inaudible]
originally from Caracas, Venezuela,
and currently living in Corvallis, Oregon.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation and housing,
public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by Squarespace.
The simplest way to create
a website this new year.
Make your next move with Squarespace.
Whether that's starting a business
or launching a passion project,
no matter what your goals are.
Squarespace's award winning templates
can help you present your ideas to the
world.
Beautifully use offer code Radiolab
for 10% off your first purchase of a
Squarespace domain or website,
squarespace.com make your next move.
Make your next website.
Sometimes what seems so clearly like
the right decision ends up being one you
regret and really great expectations
for how it's like basketball.
I was going to pee. Hi Radiolab
listeners. I'm Anna sale, host of death,
sex and money from W NYC studios.
And this week we have stories of
people with big dreams and big debt,
student loan debt, 10 grand, 80,000 7,500,
$300,000. Listen to the latest death, sex,
and money wherever you get your podcast.
This is Radiolab. I'm Jad
Abumrad red, I'm Robert Krulwich.
And in this hour on radio lab, we're
talking about the relationship,
sometimes the uneasy relationship
between the brain and the body.
I think most people will who have
brains and that would include,
I think most of the listeners here, uh,
think the relationship between brain and
body is more like the relationship of a
commander to a command D, right?
The brain makes the orders
and the body response.
But I think the more accurate way is
to think of this as a conversation
between the brain and the body. How do
you mean? Well because any movement,
even a very basic one, let's
just say a wagging my tongue.
Okay? Very simple really, but it
still involves three steps. First,
the brain has to issue the command
tongue, face and tongue station. This
is mission control, commence wagon.
Second, the command must be
executed [inaudible] third.
Now this is the crucial step.
The tongue. In this case,
we ports back to the brain.
All we have a wagging. I
repeat, we have wagons.
Yeah. By completing the loop,
you control the foot. Come in full
mission control. This is here,
me here coordinates over
to Roger that Michigan,
yeah, this happens, this conversation
you're hanging right now.
[inaudible] or Alpha. It happens
constantly all over your body.
Your brain is issuing
commands. Come in, let me,
parts of your body are
receiving the command and
reporting right leg standing by
and this conversation adds up to
something really quite important.
It ends up to his sense of yourself.
It's an unconscious sense which
really allows you to move normally.
That's Oliver sacks again,
the neurologist we talked to
at the start of the program,
you have of course a sense of
smell and of touch and of taste.
He says this sixth sense also has a
name sometimes called proprioception.
Proprioception.
Proprioception is the unconscious sense
by which the position of one's limbs,
the posture of one's body
is automatically monitored.
Now imagine he says what would happen
if all of a sudden this sixth sense,
this conversation that you are
always having with your body,
suppose it went away when we
all have this in a slight way.
For example,
if you go to the dentist and sometimes
half of your mouth or your tongue is
numbed, the tongue may feel very large.
You may grab the Dental Mirror to reassure
yourself that all is okay and there's
does and it doesn't reassure you.
You can still wag your tongue.
Your brain is still sending
messages to the tone control.
The tongue isn't sending
messages back anymore
so you can you anything.
You know that feeling?
Yeah, of course. Now. Could you imagine
that instead of just losing your tongue,
your tongue not responding, suppose
your whole body doesn't respond.
Okay.
What would that be like? I mean,
we have words like deaf or blind.
We don't have a word for
being ineffective, deaf and
blind to one's own body.
And yet there are people who have a
condition that rare and that horrible.
No proprioception. We
talked to such a person,
Ian Waterman and convinced him and his
doctor and very good friend Jonathan Cole
to crowd themselves into a very little
recording studio and fully of the other,
the BBC. Fantastic. Southampton
in England. Hello America.
And we ask them to talk to us.
Hello? Oh, you got a sexy voice.
Ah, and you hear us? Can you
hear me? Your other? Hi, we can.
I can thank you guys for coming
and doing this with us. Yeah.
Will you just ask us some questions and
we'll answer them as best we can far
away. All right, well let me just
start it then. Now can you remember,
I'm sure you can.
What happened that led to this
total change in your life?
So it began with what
I thought was, um, uh,
a batch of the flu or a very
heavy, heavy cold. And uh,
I was at the shop, probably worked
and felt tired and lethargic.
The guy that owned the, the shop look,
you know, you look on, well go home,
take it easy. I took the day off,
went home and I've always been pretty
energetic and I hate being stuck in doors
and whatever. And I thought, well,
the fresh year will do me some good.
It's got to the shed and pulled the motor
mower out, pulled the what out with,
what's the, what do you call it? The
mower. The lawnmower out of the shed.
I thought it's going to be one of those
cultural moments where you guys call it
something else. No, not
quite. And pulled the uh,
lawnmower out of the shed and primed
it up and started it and it started
chugging away and as I engage the gear
off it went and I
couldn't keep up with it.
It was a fairly slowly and punters sort
of lonely and I just stood there bemused
thinking, how come I just can't keep
up with the money and didn't really,
uh, attend too much more than, you know,
I'm just tired and
sluggish and lethargic and,
and went back to my bedroom and laid
down and did some seriously thing.
And the following morning I went to get
up and out of bed and collapsed against
the radio twice. Fell, slid, fell,
tumbled out of the bed and
fell against the radiator.
[inaudible]
it's very difficult to do, to describe
as I lay there and I was laying flat.
I had a rippling sensation in
my tummy around the ankles,
a a tingling sensation for
once we've had a chairman,
I felt disembodied
[inaudible]
I remember waking up with a hand on my
face and not realizing that it was mine.
Simple movement, simple movements.
The simplest of movements.
Pick up a cup to eat, to eat.
The biscuits are suddenly very
hard by couldn't control anything.
Totally. I mean, from the neck down.
I had no control over over my limbs
and for the next 12 years he went from
hospital to hospital.
Doctors couldn't help him because he'd
never seen anything quite this drastic
until they finally did meet
a doctor, Jonathan Cole,
who began to help him figure
out what might be going on.
So let me ask Jonathan for a second.
What is wrong with the
n he had at the Italian,
he had his eldest last class of peripheral
nerve cells to do with sensation.
It lost touch, but also his
movements and position sense had got,
is this unusual? I mean in your
experience? I mean depends who we talk to,
but I normally say that we know of about
six in the world really who are like
this.
No one really in the world knew what
proprioception did and what the effects of
the loss of proprioception
would be until it
and when they first met, Dr.
Cole said to him, he said,
how do you manage? How do you
cope with this? Unbelievably,
he was the first doctor to ask that
question in told him that on own over
the 12 years he had figured out how to
walk again and how to grasp a cup again
and explained that he did
this by carefully breaking
down and then reassembling
every single move he made started.
Um, this way. Um,
I was laying in bed one day in hospital
and I wanted to sit up and it just
wouldn't happen. And then
laying there in frustration,
I just thought the whole process through
and I broke it down into quite simple
small movements and I lay flat.
I checked where absolutely
everything was before I started.
And I then started with the head and
folded and tucked my chin onto my chest as
if to start the first part of the Co that
I moved my arms slightly forward and I
started to tighten some muscles
in my tummy and around my back.
And then I started to curl myself
to sit in an upright position.
And when I got there, I was damn
down, euphoric and we fell out.
The bed has studied movement in a weight
that will in history has ever studied
before though ballet Dodes said,
do professor of neurology
has ever had to study,
move with the way he had as every day
because every day, every
move that Ian makes,
he has to consciously direct it
as though Ian, we're two people,
a puppeteer and a puppet.
His mind is directing and his body is
obeying and the strings of Ian's puppet
instantly or his eyes are control.
All my movement with my sight at,
because he doesn't have this feedback
information coming from his limbs back to
his brain pro for septic
feedback cause that's missing.
Unless he looks directly at the limb,
he wants to move, he can't move it.
If I look away from from my hand,
I lose all connection with it.
Or what happens if, if it's dark or
if the lights are out, we know it's,
he can't afford darkness.
If the lights go out accidentally us
call caught a dangerous place to be our
shoal over. He has not turned out the
lights in the night in the last decades.
Wow. To stay in the world.
In motion. He must focus,
always focus. He's like, he spent a
long time just training with paper clip.
Yeah. I use them now occasionally. And I
still don't like the little devils. Um,
you know, I mean, well wait, when you,
when you're manipulating the paper clip,
what are you actually trying to figure
out how to put it on the way these and,
but he's, uh, I lost my fellow
say if you could repeat that. Oh,
okay. We should do Jess
cause the headphones back
on yet. Hang on. I'll do it.
Great job. By the way, is he, is
he able to put on, I mean, is this,
you can tell me what's going on,
but is he able to grab the headphones
you're fucking on so he can grab the
headphones and put them on?
But because I'm putting the
headphones over the top of my head,
I can't see exactly where the headphones
are in relation to the rest of me. Um,
otherwise I would finally get this a
lot quicker. Jonathan just puts them on.
Right. And, uh, he likes to feel,
so what I was asking was what were you
doing with the paper clip? All tone.
I was given paper clips as
a, as an exercise to, to,
to get my fingers to
move again and to, to,
to throttle them together and
then to unclip them. Uh, very,
very frustrating therapy but
one has to admit that it is,
it is a good one and it takes an awful
lot of find extras movement to get paper
clips together and apart again,
put the idea of breaking down every
move you make into sub moves and sub sub
moves and then relearning
everything. It's exhausting. Very,
very mentally tiring because it
takes such total concentration.
What if you were walking down
the street and suddenly a
thought like a daydream pops up?
John Jonathan has a very good
memory of that and maybe a,
that'd be good to compliment. Jonathan.
Ian and I were walking through Oxford
having done some groundbreaking
experiments or whatever and he had
suddenly stumbled and I'd never seen him,
stubble ever before.
And he was looking at pretty girl and
he's thoughts had drifted from walking and
from the concrete ahead of him to what
he'd like to do to this girl while she,
she was, uh, about 18,
she had nut brown hair,
lovely legs and miniskirt and it was a
navy blue dress with white polka dots as
a family program.
But walks anyway to think
about walking the floor,
some merely the around the erotic
sort of charge cost you beer.
That sort of charged, but any distraction
really took me away from my focus,
which is,
where is my left foot in relation to my
right for and where am I balanced at the
moment and how am I actually
going through this process?
At what stage am I in this movement?
And to suddenly be attracted
by that by a waft of perfume.
And a pretty girl took all
that concentration away.
It can be taken away by
the song of a bird or,
or the sound of music drifting from
somewhere. Uh, just on that day,
it was a pretty girl
today. If you saw Ian on the street,
you wouldn't be able to tell
that he has this handicap.
He has figured out how to live a very
deliberate and in a way kind of a normal
life. He drives a car, he works,
he drives that car. Yeah. My latest car,
which is a very nice Mercedes. Um,
I do drive the same speed
as everybody else in all.
[inaudible] I can react as
quickly as anybody else.
It's an automatic car
and it has hand controls.
That's the only favor to my
disability really. But, um,
I tend to do with my drive and what I do
with in the way that I manage my life,
which is I plan ahead.
I just want to [inaudible]
my last question. Really.
It's free and I guess is,
is a, have you solved this
problem as best you can? I mean,
do you feel like you're
one person or do you feel,
uh, cut in half like a
mind directing a body?
Like like maybe two people
or don't think about
it in the way that you've just just
related that, um, I just think about,
I want to get up,
I want a cup of tea and this is the
process I have to apply to do that. Yup.
That's what, that's what we all do.
I don't think stories
like this involve heroes.
They involve people who try their best
under certain circumstances and have
tested in a way that many of us
are not. We can learn from that
Delta hand and you play
it as you as best you can.
[inaudible]
Scott speaking,
thanks to Ian Waterman and
to neurologist Jonathan Cole.
Dr. Cole wrote a very nice,
lovely book about Ian Called
Pride and daily marathon.
He spoke to us together from the
BBC studios in South Hampton.
That was from,
Gosh, I really should read the book.
You know. Hey, look, look at the chair.
The chair is fine. Lunch
cultish room doesn't get
[inaudible]. It's a dog.
You are listening to radio lab. Then
you're from New York public radio,
public radio,W
and Y. C. O. N. N. P. R.
Hey, this is Chelsea from Atlanta,
Georgia, where the CICADAS are singing.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing
public understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
this is Radiolab. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich and today on
our program we're looking at uh,
brains and bodies and how sometimes
brains and bodies can get wildly out of
sync. And let me offer one
more flavor on this theme,
which has to do with something that
neuropsychologist Paul brox calls body
Schema.
Body schemer is the brains sort of
working model of the body in order for the
brain to keep track of where
you are, where everything is,
it creates an inner representation of you.
This is what he thinks a model very much
in the virtual reality sense of where
it thinks you are in space
and where it thinks you are.
The point is that we,
although we think as a very
solid distinction between
where our bodies and and
the world begins, in fact,
the brain has to work quite hard to
produce this kind of consistency of
experience. And clearly it can go wrong.
This brings us to pilots.
Okay. My name is Dan Folger.
I spent 32 years in the Air Force,
25 that an active flying
and this incidence occurred
in July of 1952 at Luke air
force base in Arizona.
Our story begins on a normal
training day. It was really hot
in the cockpit flying down at
low level, below 3000 feet.
It was over a hundred degrees.
And Colonel Dan Full Jim was on
his fifth run, flying in formation,
doing a trading maneuver. He'd
done it a million times before,
but this time something
happened. He pulled the plane up.
Hard rolled out. Yeah.
The next thing I knew I was,
eh,
seem to be sitting up on the back of the
airplane looking down into the cockpit.
Suddenly he was outside
the plane, not inside
to see what was going on.
I could see the ground.
I could see it with
another airplane. And um,
and when he looked in the cockpit
where he was supposed to be,
he could see a pilot. I was watching
myself not knowing it was me.
What's going on here?
[inaudible]
I'm just going to watch
this for a little while.
So he just sat there on the wing of his
own plane watching himself fly the plane
and just all of a sudden
that curtain snap.
So
it's not a dream. I'm actually,
that's me in a cockpit and I'm flying
the airplane again. But we began to,
to realize it, Luke, that uh,
in the eight weeks of training
period that I was there,
we lost nine pilots. Hey died. Yeah. Wow.
And most of them for running into the
ground are running into each other in the
air and that sort of thing.
And that's an awful lot of polished
solutions just in training.
Okay. Fast forward many
years army engineers are
studying this problem and they
figured out some stuff about it, not much.
And then along comes this Guy Jim winter
or Jim Winter, he is his name ma'am.
At the Federal Aviation Administration.
Your medical research program
and he had a radical notion,
if we're going to really understand this,
I mean really get to the bottom of this.
We have to induce this
experience on purpose,
make them go blank.
Make them create the conditions that
exist in a fighter jet on the ground,
in a controlled environment
so they can study this.
His idea was let's put
pilots in a centrifuge,
this big a centrifuge and go to
these things at the astronauts use.
Got a 50 foot arm that
round and round and around and
on the end of that 50 foot arm,
this cockpit,
a cockpit pretend cockpit mocked up to
be exactly like what a fighter aircraft
might be like with all the uh,
controls. They screens the throttle.
That's where the pilot sits and
gets spun around real fast. I see.
So when we put out a call for volunteers,
I'm Tim says Deck Commander Says Tech.
I met Dr Winter. He was one of the ones
that, uh, got involved in his research,
heroically volunteered to the centrifuge
and to deliberately knock
himself out. Scared pilots.
Don't do scared.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible].
This is a recording from the experiment.
The task was to chase
this little airplane.
So I'd sit there and you'd follow it.
And first couple maneuvers would be,
you know, three gs g forces as the
is when you're on a rollercoaster,
five gs that force that pins
you back in your seat. Seven gs,
except really on a rollercoaster,
you're only ever going to experience
about two gs. And then nine gs.
Nothing like these guys
at the high g forces
the skin on your face sags,
your eyelids sag so low that you
can't see out from under them.
You end up tilt your head back to look
out from under your own eyelids that are
shaking down in front of
your face. Meanwhile, yours,
you're tensing all your leg
muscles in your abdominal muscles,
in your arm muscles as hard as you
can. You learn to use
your body to fight it.
And what you do is you tend to every
muscle from your toes here, calves
side out, push it all the way
up, all the way up. Okay. And uh,
do you take a breath? Right?
And you start to say the word Hook
and you hold it for three seconds
and then you finish it off by finishing
the k of the hook. So these pilots,
they sound like they're wrestling
or fighting or shuffle hook.
They're grunting and groaning and hook.
Hello,
making all these hook noises.
Select that
the most you have ever pulled was 12.4 gs.
Just to give you a sense of what
that might feel like for a pilot,
like Tim says, doc who weighs about 200
pounds. Once he makes a 12.4 g turn,
his body goes from 200 pounds
to two almost 2,500 pounds.
That's like over the weight
of a car because of the
pressure pushing down on it.
Yeah, exactly. More
crucially says when Ray,
those g forces pull blood blood violently
from the brain is pushed from the head
down toward the feet and it pools and
the abdomen and the lower extremities and
when it pools down there,
it can't get back up to the brain
and that's when the problem starts.
This doesn't sound very
good. No, he Dr Winter,
he documented a particular sequence that
happens when blood is pulled from the
brain. The first thing you
lose his vision. Usually
the first thing to go there,
your eyes and you have what's called
gray out or loss of peripheral vision and
you start getting tunnel vision and then
you go through blackout where you can
see nothing.
You lose your sight and then if you
take the acceleration forces a little
higher,
you're lose consciousness.
When I woke up,
I remember just sitting there and
I'm in this little white space.
I actually had no idea who I was, who
am I, where I was or what I was doing?
Why am I doing?
I'm sitting in this little white ball
and I'm looking around and what is this
all about? I hear this beeping.
There's this white light
beeping and then at that moment
I realize that I'm in a little room and
that I'm supposed to do something in
that. One of the things I'm
supposed to do is press that button.
Should I press the button and
at that moment I realized,
holy macro on a pilot, I'm in an
airplane and I'm not flying it,
but I grabbed the controls
and then just giant.
I'm Tim Sestak, Holly macro. I'm
Tim Sestak. I'm Tim Stash Jack.
I'm a pilot. I'm flying in.
The centrifuge all came back
to me at once and I was okay.
Okay. Commando says tech, Dr.
Bennett, how are you feeling again?
I'm like, okay, go home time.
Over the course of 15 years when he tested
about 500 pilots in the center view,
she recorded their experiences,
measured everything he could think of,
and he found a few things.
First at the average blackout lasted
somewhere between 12 and 24 seconds,
24 second. Yeah, and wild blacked
out. This is the interesting thing.
Pilots experienced these
strange little visions.
Visions are given an example
of the individual that,
that lost consciousness had convulsive
movements where he was moving his arms
forward and back for about
two or three seconds.
When he came to we ask him what
had happened. He said, uh, yeah,
it was a nice warm day and I
was out at the lake fishing.
Okay.
All of a sudden I could feel like a,
I had a about a five pound bass on my
line and he was tugging and each time he
tugged,
I haven't pulled back and then all of
a sudden I was back in the centrifuge.
I don't know what happened.
These little dream, let's winter.
He thinks this is the brain
confused. It's cut off.
Meaning think it from
the brain's perspective.
It's lost the body and yet the body is
convulsing trying to get blood back up to
the brain. The brain has no
idea why it's convulsing.
It just sees arms flailing
about. It thinks, well,
my arms are jerking back and
forth. I must be best fishing.
The things that are happening around you
frequently get incorporated into those
short streamlets. Here's one of his own.
Turns out he has tested himself
in the centrifuge many times.
A little dream up that I had. I was
going down the aisle of a grocery store
floating, if you will. I don't
know that I was on a magic carpet,
but I sure wasn't having to walk and I
was just really motivated to try to pick
up some ice cream. As I was going down
the aisle and I was moving down through,
then I could see the freezer.
I knew the ice cream was over there and
I just could not move my hand over to
get it.
The next thing I realized was I was
trying to turn off the buzzer in the
centrifuge with my hand
and I could hear it.
I could not move it and just momentarily
I got the ability to have motor control
return and I could turn it off.
I don't know where I am. God
don't know where the hell I am.
I thought I was at the
grocery store by the way.
The other thing is I,
I couldn't control my arm to get
the get the found off either.
That's interesting.
This recording,
you're listening to this from a day when
Dr wintery blacked out five times in a
row.
I don't remember anything
on that one. Okay.
And after that fifth run, which you're
about to hear, something weird happened.
Let you take a break. Just a
few seconds. Can't you breath?
I don't know about that one. I
don't remember starting Allen
last ride coming up. God, I don't
know if you can take one more.
I have thing cause I not ready yet.
Sarah at the I'm hesitating cause
I'm not quite ready yet. Okay.
Just let me know whenever you get ready.
[inaudible]
well I didn't realize like you love
flow through you Brian, my brother.
Okay, I'm ready for that one. I did
good Bob checklist that a
station gas station is ready.
Operator operator is ready. Medical
medical is ready. Following,
have you please. Hey, sort of
final already has been activated.
Are you ready guy? Yeah, I'm
going up this time. Right? You,
I remember going up on this one. Yes.
Ron. Greg
[inaudible]. [inaudible]
yeah, I think that was enough.
At the end of that last
run, doctor winner,
he got off the centrifuge woozy
and stumbled down the hall.
I was really confused when, uh,
when I got off the centrifuge and I
was walking down the hall back to my
laboratory and all of a sudden
I began to realize that, uh,
I was above and behind myself and I
could see somebody who was myself walking
down the hall and I said,
Oh man, that's unusual.
Pilots are generally not
new age kind of guys,
but at least 40 of them in wintery
study did report what he just described
having an out of body experience.
We are still an even smaller
sub sub group reported
the classic tunnel with
light, light type thing.
All Dr Whinnery can say is
it that last sub sub group,
they were the ones who
were out the longest.
They had the most intense blackouts.
He's not ready to draw any conclusions,
but he does suspect that the dream lists
divisions of seeing yourself from above
even the tunnel and white lights,
it's all part of the same situation.
The brain is just confused
at having lost the body.
[inaudible] [inaudible] uh,
and peppermint and Kara older produced
that piece for us. Thank you to them.
And thanks also to our pilots.
Dan Full Jim Tim says stack
and of course Jim Winter.
That's all the time we have.
For more information on anything you
heard this hour, visit our website,
radiolab.org and while you are there,
send us an email, our email address.
You know, uh, no. Come on. I
have never really learned it.
radiolab.org or something like that.
No, that's our website address.
If you would like to email us and we do
like to get email, the address is radio
lab@wnyc.org I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm
Robert Quote. Thanks for listening.