Alright. Hey guys, sorry. Hey, we're
here now. Hey, Peter. Simon, Simon,
how are you man? I'm doing
well. And Yourself? Good.
Okay. Uh, who's who? Um, Peter is
a DJ. Peter Rosenberg from hot 97.
Simon Adler is the journalist.
Our Pal Andrew Moran from the New Yorker
is also in the room and Robert and
ironman.
Good. Well, uh, we have all gathered
here today to talk about, uh,
the wonderful world of
professional wrestling,
my favorite world.
So yes,
we're going to talk about professional
wrestling for the first half of the show.
And we realize there's probably a lot
of you out there listening right now who
are like,
seriously guys, there are people
like, oh wait, you're 35 years old.
Do you love wrestling? It's, you know,
I get this a lot if I'm tweeting about
it a lot, I get tweets that go, you know,
it's fake, right? It's like,
we'll do I write you that when you
tweet about your favorite movie,
it's entertainment. The awesome
thing about wrestling is,
is that there are these random
things that are a little bit real.
And sometimes those moments
of realness can just be like
Paul [inaudible].
They can change everything.
Oh,
now if you're like me and
you grew up in the 80s, a,
you might remember wrestling is like, you
know how Kogan versus Andre the giant,
these epic matchups,
they were kind of great but also sort
of ridiculous and cartoonish. Well,
according to Peter Rosenberg,
there was a moment where wrestling started
to sort of tinker with reality and a
much more nuanced and a
fascinating way. In fact,
you could argue that pro wrestling
became a reinstate the creation of the
Baroque movement of the 16th century.
But the postmodern twist you get,
I know people who would.
Okay, you're going to meet him. I'm Chad.
I'm Robert. This is Radiolab. And uh,
according to Peter, this whole
thing's where we're going to start.
This whole thing goes back to this
moment called the Montreal screw job.
The Montreux screw job was above anything
else that had ever happened or that
will ever probably ever happen
again because it was odor,
reality transpiring right
there in the ring. I mean,
it was when real life
just came and tore a hole
in the fiction.
That guy you just heard
is David Shoemaker.
I write about professional wrestling for
Grantland and the guy you're about to
hear is journalists, Simon Adler. He
will take the story from here. Okay,
so the moment in question really
centers around this one guy named Brett
[inaudible] red. They hit man heart.
Brett Hart is seen by many to be the
greatest entering performer of all time.
He was one of the good guys.
That's the room, the
[inaudible] business.
They call him a baby face. Is
that what you call the good guys?
The good guy in wrestling.
He's a baby face.
He was my favorite wrestler as a kid.
I didn't understand why at the time,
but now I do. It's because he did so
well and in that era, the mid to late
eighties when I fell in love with him.
So many guys were just big and
hawking and a little bit clumsy.
But Brett did the kind of work that
you could show to someone who's,
who's never watched wrestling.
I think they could see the art in it
and I think they could see how it's,
it's like ballet or a million other arts
forms. What he means.
And you can kind of see this when you
watch old Brett Hart matches on youtube.
He's a gliding through the air, bouncing
off the mat, off the ropes here,
tell stories brilliantly within
the way he, uh, executes a map.
The wrestling is scripted, but there's
a lot of improv going on there.
The set beads,
he knew how to take those moments
and in that Improv make you think,
oh shoot, he's about to lose. And then
[inaudible]
he was a natural born wrestler,
you know, his father was a, was a
legendary wrestler, his brother,
Owen legendary wrestler.
He comes from, um,
this Canadian wrestling royalty
kid. Growing up, I had the
ability to watch the, uh,
or had the fortune of watch these varied
wrestling styles and techniques and
stuff.
That's Brett Hart in an
interview in 2000 on fresh air.
And he says that some of his earliest
memories as a kid were these massive dudes
showing up to his house and hanging
out in his basement with his dad.
You know, even then my dad
was, you know, I'll say 60,
who's teaching them how to be wrestlers,
pull on these old wooly tights. And
then he would wrestle with these guys.
And he would literally,
um, put them in wrestling,
holds these submission wrestling
holds, which is his obsession. And uh,
he would torture these big huge football
players for hours and they would scream
literally these high pitched
screams. It was terrifying.
I'd be upstairs in the room
above it and as I got older,
I would go down and actually venture
into the room and sit on the bench and
watch. And uh,
he would sometimes these wrestlers would
run out when my dad finally let them
go. They'd actually run
out, tear out of the,
out the doorway and out the outside,
sometimes in the snow and run out the,
in their bare feet. And you,
and even seeing them again,
I mean there's a legendary, so many
legendary stories about the Hart family,
but you, you know, my
favorite among many is, uh,
the bear that lived in their backyard
during the summers because at the time,
wrestling a bear was a thing that would
actually happen from time to time. No,
really. And, uh, Brett tells a
story in his, his book, um, about,
you know, just sitting there and
letting the bear lick his toes. I mean,
like this is, this is a life that they,
that he lived and he was, he was so in,
it was so ingrained in him.
Um,
so in the early eighties,
Brett was working for his
dad's company up in Canada.
And while that's going on in Canada,
there's this guy, Vince McMahon,
back in the u s who is building kind
this wrestling empire. It basically,
he's buying up all of these small
promoters from across the country and
eventually goes up into Canada and
buys out breads, dad's company.
I bought it in 1984. They paid him a
certain amount of money to stop running.
Like, just to kind of go out of
business. And then they took on, uh,
some of his better wrestlers at the time,
which was myself and I had
a couple of brother-in-laws.
And shortly thereafter,
Jared,
the WWF comes under fire,
how Kogan and other world wrestling
federation stars have taken the offensive
against accusation that many have
been steroid abuser, like man
red to widespread steroid abused in
the world wrestling federation. So
there's this big steroid crisis.
Vince has to deal with all of this
litigation and he kind of needs to rebrand
his organization. He needs a new good
guy, a new champion, a new baby face.
And he looks to Brett for that
for a couple of reasons.
According to David Shoemaker.
One is that he's a traditionalist, sort
of a throwback to an earlier time too.
He's not that big. So when you see
him, you don't think steroids guys,
definitely, yeah. Roid rage. And
so he saw all that in Brett Hart.
So during the 90s, Vince
makes Brett a really big star.
Hey Scott,
face of the company, I mean he was
on the Simpsons. He was a really,
really big star. You know,
there are people who criticize Brett
for saying he wasn't that fun or he took
himself too seriously, but
he was a serious worker.
He took wrestling very
seriously for myself,
really fighting hard to actually
survive and come out of it.
Actually to come out of the
wrestling profession someday as a,
as a success rather than
a wrestling tragedy,
which is what so many of them turn out.
Okay. So fast forward to
1995, 1996 at the time,
a major rivalry was starting between the
WWF that is Vince McMahon's company and
the WCW, um, which was
ted Turner's company,
Ted Turner and Gillian Air.
And one of his big tactics is I'm
just going to start buying all of the
wrestlers from the WWF, from
Vince McMahon's organization.
So he's offering them more money.
He's offering them longer contracts,
and he was just like flooding it with
money to steal all the stars from WWF.
And then in late 1996, Brett got an offer.
Turner really went in for the
kill from WCW. That was huge.
Two point $8 million.
I mean you have to show us the
common sense, you know, first of all,
you've got to do what's right
for your family, but I mean,
how much money do you need?
Sometimes I find myself torn between
trying to do the right thing for my family
and at the same time show my loyalties.
That's a clip of Brett talking in a
documentary that was being filmed at the
time called wrestling with
shadows, which is fantastic.
The filmmaker Paul Jay was nice enough
to let us play some clips. In any case,
Brett gets this offer and he's
got kind of terrible decision
to make because Vince
gave him a lot. You know,
he really gave him his life and initially
Brett decides there's no way I'm going
to leave. You know?
I think my relationship was with Vince
McMahon was always sort of like a father
and I sort of saw myself. If I left,
it would have been a little
bit like leaving my dad,
especially when the shifts are down.
He really did see Vince
as a father figure.
So Brett goes to Vince and
basically says, convince me to stay.
They went back and forth.
There was conversation about
him signing a longterm deal,
a 20 year deal with WWF. Not for as
much money, but for guaranteed security.
Vince said, I can't
afford to pay you that.
Just talk to Vince
in the documentary. Brett and his wife,
they're sitting at a kitchen table.
Let me see. He goes, nobody wants bread.
Heart more than Minspeck, man,
you can't afford to compete with Turner.
He was Turner's hell bent on
trying to put him out of business.
I got to think about everything.
Just see what makes sense.
Call Eric, maybe. How
can we cut this off now
for a little while? Okay.
Ultimately it became clear that Brett
would have to go take the money.
I can't help but feel really
heartbroken and disappointed that um,
that I left this company.
Yeah.
So this really gets to the heart of it.
Once Brett decides he's going to leave,
they have to figure out how, how
are they going to make his exit?
This is really the pivotal
question behind all of this.
Yeah. You know that it's a
very, very delicate situation.
That's Vince. So,
and this was sort of his problem to solve
because he worked for Vince McMahon,
you know, you could say I was his right
hand man because I was writing the show.
He was part of the team that scripted,
who would win, who would lose,
how it would happen, you know? I mean,
I was literally putting this show on
paper, you know, once a week. Wait,
why is this a hard question? I mean,
can he just pick up and leave? Well,
because he's the champion. He
has the belt, the physical belt,
the giant golden like belt buckle thing,
and that belt is the symbol of
the company and everybody in it,
everybody working behind the scenes,
everybody who was trying
to support their family,
that belt was a
representation of all that.
That the worst thing that could happen
is your champion walking away with the
belt, drilling up to the new company,
holding up the championship
from the old company
where they could just
defile it if they wanted to.
That was not an option for Vince
McMahon. This isn't a perfect comparison,
but the closest thing I've come up to
in my mind is it would be like Lebron
James quitting his contract with Nike
and then showing up in an Adidas and
taking a piss into a pair of
Nike's. So you know Vince,
at the end of the day, he just
had to get that belt off of bread.
So their initial thought, their first
plan was probably the simplest option.
There was a match coming up, this big
event of pay per view event in Montreal.
Brett being the champion of the company,
he should just lose to the number two
guy in the company, Shawn Michaels.
Vince loved Sean. I mean really
thought Sean was a mega star,
which was right about clearly
Sean was next in line.
So they pitched this idea to Brett
and Brett was like, I can't do that.
For one he thinks Shawn's an idiot.
It's got this premadonna personality.
I mean he thinks he's better than everyone
else and is something very arrogant
and I'm noxious about him
because he was, he was a showman.
He would hump the ring just like
do ridiculous things. And like
Brett. Shaun was the triumph
of style over substance. Also,
you're asking Brett to wrap up his career
in the WWE with a loss in Montreal in
Canada where he is a national hero.
I described the events. I just
assume blow my brains out.
It would be the same once you're asking
me to do from a character standpoint,
that's what I would be doing.
Breadth to hit hitman hardwood.
Blow his brains out.
Yeah.
Oh, the whole thing's been hard. Yeah.
Okay.
Day of the match.
Still nothing has been decided as
to how the match is going to end.
Brett is backstage and eventually he
goes to Vince to have a conversation.
Right.
I gotta just talk the documentary crews
filming all of this and at this point
Vince says, no, I don't want any
cameras in here. Get those out of here.
And so Brett actually ends up wearing a
wire to document the conversation that's
about to happen.
I never ever wanted to leave here
with any kind of bad feeling,
but this week has been a bad week for
me. I feel kind of betrayed a little bit.
Well, I go to a little bit and again,
all we're talking about really is Turner,
Gosh, what's coming between
you and me and that's all.
I can't tell you how appreciative I will
always be for everything you've done.
I didn't want to leave with any problems.
I actually didn't want to leave it all
and then it's the point where there was
no other choice but to go the way
this whole thing has been depicted.
It's really hard for me as a hero
here to come up short this weekend.
What would you want to do
today then? I'm open to new.
I think what I'd like to
do is get through today.
I think tomorrow is you
just go in and do my,
so Brett suggest that this
ends in a disqualification.
Usually what that means is something
called a Shmata Moz or whatever you want.
Typically in a Schmaltz,
the ring is just flooded with a bunch of
wrestlers and chaos into is the referee
usually is thrown out of the ring
and it ends in some sort of draw.
Bret would then appear on Monday night
raw the next day and turn over the belt.
That is what he planned on doing too.
That way he could turn over
the belt but not lose. Exactly.
And eventually Vince says, okay, fine.
Nah, I ain't got, I'm opening to, like I
said before on the term wind up
and now Milton Bradley,
they're like chronic karate
fighters by 1997 survivors. Sherry.
Okay, here we go. So
survivor's series, 1997
[inaudible]
oh, the drama.
So around 9:20 PM 20,000
people in the stands,
countless television screens across
the country. Shawn Michaels comes
and he,
he comes out singing his own
theme themes. I think I'm cute.
I know I'm sexy. It's singing karaoke
style. It's prerecorded of him singing.
That's an approach. Yeah, he's
got his hair in a ponytail.
He's wearing his trademark
black spandex pants,
but hearts all over them like he is the
manifestation of everything that Brett
despises.
And then outcomes. Bret
Harte waving a Canadian flag
and he walks into the ring to gets
in, takes off the championship belt,
hands it to the ref and before
the match even officially begin.
Okay.
Shawn flies at Brett and
just starts [inaudible].
Yep.
Sean and Brett. They're
going at each other
with assertive
like real ferocity pretty
quick. They're outside the ring.
Right.
Kicks up. Shawn chucks him over the
security railing into the crowd.
It didn't, no.
Then there's this moment where Brett
picks Sean up so that Sean's legs are
straight up in the air and then
right. Just slams him on his back
in all of this.
Yeah. Everything I know about it
is like they're following the,
the narrative arc, but
like they know, okay,
we're going to fight her out outside
the ring for a while and, and then x, y,
z will happen and so eventually
Brett throws Shawn back
into the room and then
you get to a point in the match,
which feels very early in the match
where Brett climbs onto the turnbuckle,
which is the corner post of the
room. He gets up on top of that,
catapults himself off the turnbuckle
through the air towards Sean.
Mike, Super dramatic. He's kind of
floating in the air there for a moment
and then in front of a hip man.
What Sean does right before bread
is about to come and hit him,
he pulls the referee in
between Brett and Sean,
a human shield of sorts. Brett
hits the referee, the referee
hit Sean and all three men are lying
on the map. Is that a disqualification?
It might be if they could get on
Paula, oh, here we are. Right?
This could, this can
be the moment, but no,
before the referee can
get up. Sean gets up,
walks over to Brett and then Shawn
Puts Brett in the sharp shooter,
which is Brett's signature finishing move.
Basically Sean pretzels up bread's legs
and sits up and within seconds the bell
rings,
Sean Slides out of the rain, grabs the
belt, runs to the back, takes off things,
work a certain way in wrestling matches,
right? Like no one gets the first pin,
the second match starts and no one puts
someone in submission hold and they
instantly submit,
especially not bred heart and ages did
not appear like the time the match was
supposed to end. The
crowd is kind of shocked.
It's strangely quiet
and there's this one moment where the
camera zooms in on Brett's face while he's
lying,
chest down on the mat looking up
and there is just this bizarre,
amazing look on his face.
Confusion is an emotion that almost
never exists in pro wrestling.
Yeah,
there's the cartoon confusion of like
everything's crazy and your arms are going
like wild. Your eyeballs
pop out of your head,
but real confusion is one of the
most compelling emotions of all.
That's what you see on his
face in its most pure form.
[inaudible]
genuine confusion.
and then anger. Brett gets
up, puts his arms on the rope,
looks down
seasoned and sick man and
spits right in Vince's face.
He then proceeds
to get out of the ring and basically
destroyed everything in sight.
He goes over to the announcer's
table, starts ripping it apart,
he destroys the monitors, throws
the headphones out into the crowd.
He goes pretty nuts
and in maybe the moment that truly
made you go, what is happening?
Brett gets back into the ring.
He takes his hand in the air and draws
with his finger in the air as big as he
can.
W C W which is where he was going to be
leaving to go work w c w and keeps doing
that walking across the range
of signaling w c w to the crowd.
[inaudible]
after the match, Brett heads back into
the locker room looking for Vince.
It is good. It
tells the cameras to shut off
and then to make a long story short,
he clocks Vince in the
face, knocks him out.
Now the WWF has a real
problem on their hands.
Vince has a black guy and the fourth wall
has just been torn down and they need
to figure out how or if they're
going to build it back up. And um,
the next day, this again was the
head writer at the time, Vince Russo,
we had a television taping
right after the, you know, you,
you have roar on Monday, you know,
you, you do your paper view on Sunday,
you have roar on Monday. So
they all huddled in a room
to discuss their options.
And Vince says that everybody in that
room dif first knee jerk reaction is,
well, we're going to sweep this under
the rug and not even talk about it.
I mean that,
that was almost just assumed because
you have to understand there's this old
principle in wrestling called [inaudible]
Kayfabe. And basically what this is,
is this law of the wrestling God passed
down since time eternal that says,
you don't talk about
the fact that it's fake.
Everyone knows that it's
scripted and that it's fake.
But you damn well better
not mention that ever. Why?
Because everybody has a better time
when everyone is under the spell. Of it.
Uh, and I was like, wait a minute,
Vince is walking around with a black eye.
The boys has a black guy and one of
the boys punched them in the face.
Russo is saying, I understand
Kayfabe but we have to address this.
We can't not acknowledge this and
that doesn't have to be a problem.
That can be an opportunity for us.
I mean it like, I hate to say this,
but like it doesn't get
any better than this.
Rousseau says this
discussion got very heated.
It was passion filled and in the end
nobody really knew what Vince McMahon was
going to do.
Why the time red hearts step center
stays for his match up with Shawn and
eventually Vince McMahon decides
I'm going to break with Kayfabe.
Now keep in mind he's always been
the owner of the organization,
but very few people actually knew that
too. Most fans of professional wrestling,
he was just an announcer that
night on his own TV show.
He comes out not as Vince
McMahon, the ringside announcer,
but as Vince McMahon,
the owner of the company.
Yeah, right in the chase seven
days ago. With the survivor series,
did you or did you not screw Brett Hart?
Some would say I screwed Bret Harte.
Bret Hart would definitely
tell you I screwed them.
I'll look at it from a
different standpoint.
I look at it from the standpoint of
the referee did not screw Brett Hart.
Sean Michael Certainly
did not screw Brett Hart,
nor that Vince McMahon screw
bad heart. I truly believe that
Brad Hart Screwed Bret Hart and you can
look in the mirror and know that I'm
sure in some parts of the country right
now there's a collective groan that you
orchestrated in the situation
and the fact that uh,
there are people are not going to
understand what you mean by Brett heart
screwed Bret Hart. So
what do you mean by that?
There's a time honored tradition in
the wrestling business when someone is
leaving,
they show the right amount of respect
to the WWF superstars in this case who
helped make you that superstar you show
the proper respect to the organization
that helped you become who you are today.
It's a time honored tradition and Brett
Hart didn't want to honor that tradition
and the less that was
Brett's decision, Brett,
rude breath.
And everything changed from that point on.
And according to Peter,
after the Montreal screw
job and after this speech,
the writers of the WWF started blurring
the lines on a different level.
Vince McMahon, the chairman of
the WWE, ladies and gentlemen,
he became
Mr [inaudible],
Mr McMann, the character, the
number one villain in the company.
Yeah,
there were no more ridiculous,
you know, stupid, unbelievable,
childish, ignorant,
immature, Terrick, dors.
Every character we had was basically
an extension of themselves.
So,
you know, stone cold,
Steve Austin was Steve
Austin 1000 times magnified.
Okay?
The Rock was rocky.
My via 100 times magnified.
And as a result,
that was the beginning of the biggest
boom in the history of the wrestling
business
as far as business goes. This was
huge for the WWF and Vince McMahon.
They came roaring back in the ratings war.
They destroyed Ted Turner
in the WCW. They won.
And if you ask Vince
Russo, why this approach,
this new aesthetic was so
successful, he said simply the truth.
That was great TV, plain and simple.
The fans just want something true.
Just tell the fans what happened.
But Peter says two things.
One, it's way more complicated than
that. It's not just about the truth.
You still have these writers who are
scripting the show and wrestlers who are
getting that script and following it
so it's not like it's now a true world.
I think it's something more like there
are these tiny injections of truth into
this world in really unexpected moments.
What that does is it puts everyone on
high alert all the time for those moments
and when everyone is on high alert
for those moments all the time,
every moment has the potential to be true,
has the potential to have a little
bit of that injection into it.
And when you are watching
for those injections,
it completely changes how you
are engaging with the art form,
with the entertainment. And that
creates an entirely new type of fan,
what they call a smart fan,
a smart Marcus smart as they're known
people who will love the wrestling
business but really love the behind the
scenes of the business. No. What now?
What was the smart mark? Smart Mark.
Here's where you can get a little lingo.
Crazy. [inaudible] the lingo part of
wrestling is a huge, huge part of it.
And uh,
mark is someone who doesn't know that
wrestling is fake or using another piece
of jargon here that it is a work. Yes.
A work is anything that's not real.
Okay. As opposed to a shoot,
which is something that's real,
like the Montreal screw job.
Yes. Our shoots by definition,
something that's not supposed
to happen in the ring.
A shoot should never happen. But yeah.
Then there's something called, of course,
a work shoot
[inaudible]
and that's something that
does happen. What does that,
where you script it to seem like it's
totally unscripted and it may even be real
life that they're injecting
into it, but it was planned,
was still all discussed that
this is what would happen.
And so watching wrestling becomes this
game of hunting for the truth according
to David Shoemaker and not just
any truth, but the authentic truth,
the true truths, the truth, truth.
Even if you know that it's fake,
there's some point where the guys are
really going at it in the ring that you're
just like, wow, maybe it's
real. Just that right there.
And that's what makes
wrestling so powerful.
It's the never ending search for
the reality, uh, within the unreal.
The fact that we get so blend
these things together. I mean,
another example that's just fantastic
is, um, in the early two thousands,
there was edge,
Matt hardy and a girl named Lita Lita
and Matt Hardy were legitimately in love
dating for years. Edge and Matt
Hardy were legitimately best friends
and then you
make your life miserable edge ended up
with Lita took his best friend's girl.
You bet your life miserable too. Something
that unfortunately happens in life.
Sometimes guy kills
and it was turned into a storyline.
Man had fought over women
since the beginning of time
and we got to see an epic
battle over one right now.
I find it incredible that you
could go out into the room
and pretend to beat the
hell out of someone.
You want to beat the hell out.
[inaudible] to know that
you have to go out there,
work really hard against someone you
legitimately hate and also absolutely have
to protect. How can we not find
that? Fascinating. That's awesome.
That's incredible. It's like watching
Fleetwood Mac go on tour. Exactly.
That's what I was going to say next.
That's Andrew Moranz the way from the
New Yorker and play all their songs cause
all their songs. They all
had these love quadrangles.
They all were married and left
each other and wrote songs about,
I'm so pissed off at you because you
left me for the guy who's standing right
there.
And then they'd go out on tour and Lindsey
Buckingham is standing right next to
CV annex playing the song that
he wrote about you betrayed me.
I hate you so much. It's crazy. It right
after night. Super Fascinating. Yeah.
I just think there's a part of the human
brain that wants to be confused between
those boundaries that wants to be
slipping in between. What's real,
what's fake to feel that confusion.
I feel like that's why Jimmy Fallon was
so successful on Saturday night live,
not because he was the
greatest sketch comedian,
but because he broke a lot and you,
you can't do that in wrestling
because those moments are the best.
You have to save them.
And when people acknowledge a moment
and you can tell they look around at the
crowd and they're
acknowledging like this is,
or someone says one line that everyone
kind of knows. It's like, Whoa,
that's kind of real. Those moments are
special and you, you have to save them.
Hold on one sec guys. Sorry. Hey,
what's up? He's on the way. All right.
I'm I'll, I'll be leaving shortly.
Peace. Sorry guys. I'll show way it's,
come on guys. One real quick
question. What have you, of course,
what happened to Peter, Brent,
Brent Hart after this? It's a,
did he go off to WCW and
have a big career? Well,
that's Sorta the interesting thing
is that after the Montreal screw job,
a few weeks later,
Brett showed up on WCW television and
it never really worked out for Brett.
In 1999,
just two years into his contract
with WCW during a match,
he got kicked in the head and
suffered a severe concussion
and it, it, it was the
beginning of the end
that same year.
Well, Ladies and gentlemen, uh,
something has gone terribly wrong.
Brett's brother Owen Hartman who
was wrestling for the WWF, um,
during one of his entrances to the match.
He was entering from the ceiling and
something with the stunt went terribly
wrong and he fell 50
feet into the ring and,
and he died. Anyway,
this is not a part of the
show. This is real life.
Oh one mark is being
attended to right now by,
oh, I went through right
away. I said I could never,
I don't think I can ever go back.
Brett Hart spoke with Terry Gross
about a year after this incident.
You think of all these sort of contrived
storylines that they have in wrestling,
you know, this guy's going to come in and
he's going to do that. And he's gonna,
he's gonna say this about you.
Are they gonna I just thought I heard
anything that you could possibly imagine
is so pathetically meaningless when you
relate to the, the real life horror.
What happened with my brother, he would
retire shortly after saying that.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
so thank you to um, to Simon. Uh, what
did we decide his wrestling name was?
Simon Simon, the growling
gruyere. Adler. Adler.
Cause he's from Wisconsin. So you have
to be like a fierce cheese cheese.
And thank you.
Also a very special thanks to fresh
air for letting US air their Brett Hart
interview and thank you also to Paul J
for allowing us to play some clips from
his documentary and
wrestling with shadows.