Alright. Sorry, Robert,
I have you to turn to,
I'm gathering my thoughts as I'm speaking.
Yeah. Okay. All right. Robert? Yes.
Season two, finale of more.
Perfect. Yes. Long overdue,
but much anticipated maybe. Yeah.
Maybe among those who care among the
[inaudible] care, it growing, number one,
one can help you having a modest
day to day. It's, you know, it's uh,
it's Tuesday. It's Tuesday. It's modesty.
Tuesday. Yes. Modesty. Tuesday. Okay.
So I want to bring you a
story from the more perfect,
the final story of season two because
this story fulfills a promise I made to
myself at the very beginning
of more. Perfect. Oh my God.
This question of yours is that old and
that deep. It's only two years old.
Just two girls show. But when people
hear what the question is, they will,
eyeballs will be rubbed. No,
no, no. All right. Go ahead.
Tell them it's modesty. Tuesday.
What was it two years ago that stuck you
at a question you have never been able
to let go of question and
everybody will let go.
One of the first questions I bumped into
and learning about the Supreme Court
[inaudible]
was why does everybody keep talking about
this thing called the commerce clause?
Commerce cloud commerce commerce clause.
The commerce clause. Yes.
That had a dazzle for you. No,
I just wanted to know what the
hell is it? Well, it's article one,
section eight, clause three of the
constitution, 16 words to commas.
Congress shall have the power to regulate
commerce with foreign nations and
among the several states
and with the Indian tribe,
the power to regulate
commerce with foreign nations.
And among the several states
and with the Indian tribes,
there are no more sexier words
in the English language. Yes.
Better words for Wuhan were never written.
That's Jamie Floyd and Ari Savitsky will
meet them properly in just a second.
Okay. So turns out that question of like,
what is it is pretty easy to answer to
these 16 words in the constitution that
say, uh,
Congress has the power to regulate
commerce from one state to another.
Like as soon as it goes between
states across state borders,
the feds can regulate it.
I think that they're with the SAI would
begin and end and that would be the only
way. So, well, yes, but here's the thing
within that Shell of Boring
is I'm politely silent.
Here is an amazing story of a kind of
cosmic power that develops from very
humble beginnings to something
truly extraordinary and
maybe troubling depending
on who you are. A cosmic power.
You mean this phrase from the constitution
has had consequences that surprised
you? Oh boy. Oh boy.
Here's how I've been thinking about
it in the more perfect story. For me,
the experience I had learning about the
commerce clause was a little bit like
watching the x men movies. Initially
I was like, my name is Mike NATO.
Why is magneto the head of the bad
guys do join my brother Hood and fight?
Why would they follow him? He
has the most boring power. Your,
I mean he can control metal. Okay,
well like those mystique can
shift into any shape she wants.
Dorm can control lightning.
Initially, his [inaudible]
power seem like you have the worst one.
So we start with the commerce clause
and we ask the riddle of magneto.
I am trying to cross the bridge
and getting, I'm getting there.
All I'm saying is that like initially I
didn't understand the true deep nature
of his power, but then
you see these scenes where he's like
being attacked by a thousand policemen and
he just kind of makes their bullets
freeze in midair or he picks up a whole
bridge with lights pointing at it
and then it hits you all.
Oh, he has the best
[inaudible]
because the whole world is made of metal
he can control the world
[inaudible]
if we built the world a
different way, maybe not yet
in this world, let's just say
I'm Frankenstein's monster,
periodic table, baby periodic table baby.
So that's for me what it was like
to learn about the commerce clause.
What initially seems stupid and boring
becomes extraordinarily powerful.
Once you understand that the
world in which it is situated,
does that mean you're
about to take us on a,
on a journey which begins with something
that feels utterly trivial and ends up
with being something
enormously powerful? Wow.
Has a question to which I
simply must answer. Yes.
The question. We laid it all out
there. I am doing well then we can get,
we can get on with it then.
Yeah. I won't tell you the
story of the commerce clause.
Everything we fight about in
America is in these 16 words,
the honorable, the chief justice,
and the associate justices of the
Supreme Court of the United States.
Oh, Yay. Yay. Yeah.
Before the honorable,
the supreme court in the United
States rent money to draw an Aaron
[inaudible] card.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].
All right. I'm gonna. I'm
gonna Start you good? Yup.
To even explain why something
like the commerce clause exists,
just pull out a dollar bill. Go
ahead and pull it out. Right.
If it's issued by a central bank, are
you looking at a dollar bill? Right now?
I'm looking at dollar bill says Federal
Reserve Note, United States of America.
That is James Chen, professor of
law at Michigan State University.
Now the thing about a dollar bill,
the awesome obvious thing is that you
can take that dollar bill and buy some
sour patch kids or whatever a dollar buys
these days anywhere in America. Right,
but in the late 18th century, in fact,
all the way through to the 20th century,
it wasn't like that. No, no, no, no,
no. All the states had their own banks
and their own bills, different sizes,
colors. For example,
there was a moment when South Carolina
has this pretty little green South
Carolina Bill, same time Rhode Island
has this giant pink square thing,
and if you are a South Carolinian in Rhode
Island trying to buy some carrots and
potatoes, let's say, let's say that,
and you've got to make payments somehow.
What do you do? Well, you hand them
your South Carolina Bill. Well,
the Rhode Islanders would
look at that and say, well,
I don't know if this is who's
to trust this bank. Right?
And so they would discount the note based
on the distance from their own home.
They would discount the
note based on how it looks,
how professionally drawn up it was.
They might look at that $10 and say,
that's only worth eight. To me,
that's a horrible [inaudible]
way to do business.
That sucks for the person
who holding the note. Right?
And so what the government
decided to do is to say, hey,
we're just gonna use one bill, just
one bill. It's gonna be so much easier.
This is one of the ways government is
going to pull all these different states
together.
They were gonna regulate the currency
and not just the currency itself.
They were going to regulate the flow
of that currency. And this is
where the commerce clause comes in.
[inaudible]
this is Jamie Floyd, journalist,
sometimes legal analyst,
host of all things considered here
at WM YC. It's early in the republic.
Now we're at 1820s no, just
to hit pause for one second.
So the commerce clause was a preexisting
thing. Oh yeah. Okay. Oh yeah.
It's in the US Constitution.
But it's never been really
like thought about or where,
where is it in the minds of people
a date? Do you know where? Nowhere.
Pretty much where it is right now.
It's nowhere in the minds of people.
[inaudible]
she says 1824 to steamboat operators get
into a thing. It's a business dispute.
They're each going back and forth
between New York and New Jersey.
They each thing,
they should be the only one allowed to
do that and it makes its way, as we say,
all the way to the u s supreme court
and who's sitting up there? Well,
a big bad dude named John Marshall.
Marshall is the sort of
Rambo of the court.
He looks at those 16 words,
Congress shall have the power to regulate
commerce with foreign nations and
among the several states.
He looks at those 16 words and a couple
of commas and a period and he decides
pretty much for the first time that
those words give Congress the power to
regulate commerce
between and among states.
This boat is going from one
state to the other. The only way
to resolve that is for the federal
government to come in and control it.
Again,
the idea is that this is the only way
for the country to function as a unified
thing.
And John Marshall, when he writes
his decision, he says it, look,
we have a United States of America.
We don't have a divided states of America
or independent states of America or
New Jersey and New York
existing separately.
We decided to organize as a United States.
And so what John Marshall
says is because of that,
there has to be a power to regulate trade
between those states and amongst those
states when there are disputes,
otherwise it's all gonna fall apart.
It was at that point that the
commerce clause began to glow,
but very faintly for
the next hundred years,
the government would experiment with
the commerce clause in cases involving
trade with the native
American tribes or navigation.
But if you want to talk
about power, like real, raw,
weird power, that power got unleashed, uh,
at a very specific moment
around 1941 in a wheat field.
Well, what happened in
the wheat field? Okay,
well let me introduce you to someone
[inaudible]
my father was a farmer.
I'd like to say all of these life
took pride in the fact that he never,
he never worked for another
man. Uh, he would tell me that.
Can you introduce yourself? Well,
my name is the same as my father.
It's Roscoe Curtis, Phil Brun.
I'm a junior Roscoe film burn
as he was known at the time.
He was a fifth generation
farmer in Montgomery, Ohio. Our,
our farm was just right
next to Dayton, Ohio.
Roscoe is about a 40 year
old man at this point. Ken,
we're talking about 1941
42 good looking, sturdy,
fiercely independent.
I never worked for another man in my life.
Apparently that was his motto. He would
tell me that many times over the years.
If you had to put like captain
America with a pitchfork,
this is him.
So Roscoe's got this farm more
than a hundred cows on it.
He would milk cows until both of
these arms went practically numb. Wow.
Cat chickens, 3000 chickens. And
we had them a very big garden.
He would plant things, you know,
like string beans, Lima beans, peas,
sweet corn, potatoes, carrots, radishes.
Couple of different kinds of fruit
trees, apples, cherry trees, peach trees,
pears, strawberries and raspberries.
Oh. And of course they had crops.
We would grow corn and couple of
different kinds of hay, oats and course
wheat, wheat. Okay. Set up out of
the way. Here's what happened. Um,
it's 1941, Roscoe senior.
My dad was out in the field
I think on his tractor
that day. He was plowing
the weed or something and
there permanently must've been a, some guy
from the Department of
Agriculture locally,
I guess going around to various
farmers in our community,
a wanting the farmers
to answer several pages.
I think of questions. And this
particular day, this government, uh,
a gentleman came out in the
law field. He looked around
and he said, Rosco, by my calculations,
you've got 22 acres of wheat on
this farm. You're over your quota.
He was 11.1 acres over
what was permitted roughly.
And so the guy tells him,
you have to pay a fine,
really big fine.
My Dad looked over and he was just as
sober as that judge in a courtroom on a
murder case.
And what happened next would change
the country forever in ways that we are
still literally living with. But let
me just sort of fill in the gaps here,
tell you what you need to
know about why they're,
why they were even having this
conversation. And to help me with that.
My name is Ari Syvitski
and I'm an attorney.
Let me bring in a friend of the
show, man of the law. You know,
an important thing to
understand is that, you know,
when our story starts with Roscoe Filburn
agriculture is a huge
percentage of the economy.
The Great Depression is happening
up on the central panic,
gripped the world and the dust bowl,
the great dust storms of the mid 1930s
has happened to [inaudible] America's
great plains.
And so you have a lot of people who
rely on selling crops and buying crops.
And so wheat prices too matter of life
and death for millions of Americans,
this nation is paying far
Ectron and a come out.
So look,
so 1938 congress enacts what's called
the Agricultural Adjustment Act to reboot
the economy.
So the 1938 Agricultural Adjustment
Act got the federal government into the
business of regulating wheat.
Basically what the government did was
they said to the farmers of America,
we are going to give
you essentially a loan.
We're gonna guarantee you a
certain minimum price for wheat.
We're going to give you x number of
dollars per Bushel or whatever it is,
and that will help lift you out
of poverty. In exchange for that,
you have to promise us to
only grow a certain amount.
This is the big fear was
that if they grew too much,
there'd be this flood of supply on
the wheat market, prices would crash.
And that will be bad
for everyone. You know,
wheat is sort of a collective
action problem, right?
Everyone's going sell as
much weed as they can,
but that means prices go
down and everyone makes less.
So what the government decided to do
in addition to giving out loans is that
they placed a cap on how much wheat
a person could grow. So quota,
straight up quota.
That way you ensure that the supply of
wheat is steady and you ensure that,
uh, that the prices don't crash.
And the whole reason the government
could do this regulate the entire wheat
market was by hinge Egon
on the commerce clause.
Those 16 words that basically said that
when something like wheat is bought and
sold and moved from one place to another,
one state to another cross state lines,
well that's interstate commerce and that's
something that Congress can regulate.
So my father having this brings us back
to Roscoe Filburn would that inspector
on his farm inspector says, look,
Roscoe, you've grown too much wheat.
My Dad looked over and he was just as
sober as that judge in a courtroom on a
murder case. And what do you think?
He says back, he says, wait a minute,
I'm going to tell you what, just
exactly how I feel about that. No,
that's how I feel. No, you
government, I don't know.
He might've been a family guy. Yeah. He
says, I don't get it. I'm not, I'm not,
I have nothing to do with
interstate commerce. And
this is the key.
[inaudible]
he explains to the inspector that yes,
according to the government quota,
I'm only supposed to grow about 11 acres
of wheat and I am growing 23 but that
extra 12
hello.
I'm not selling it to anybody.
He doesn't sell the week.
He doesn't trade the wheat.
What's he doing with his wheat?
He uses all the wheat to feed his
animals who use feeding it to the farm
animals. The weight. He fed the
some of the wheat to the stares. I,
I was just keeping it
on the farm. Well, yes.
So it's in a completely internal
operation. I do. I sound biased here.
I'm going to feel like the poor guy gets
kind of dragged into a national case in
case he tells the inspector I'm not,
I have nothing to do
with interstate commerce.
Just grown a little extra wheat
to feed my cows. I'm on my farm,
I'm doing my business.
Big, big brother. Leave me alone. But
big brother does not leave him alone.
The inspector says we're the government.
That's the law. Please uphold it.
Pay the fine 50 cents
for every excess Bushel.
I think it is. He had 239 excess
bushels of wheat for which he was,
you know, fine about 117
bucks in today's dollars.
It's about two grand, two grand.
[inaudible]
my, my father,
apparently he wasn't real crazy about
that and I guess he didn't like that too
much. If I'd have been 20 or 25 years old,
I would have probably advised
my father not to do what he did.
But I guess he sued the
federal government. Huh?
His argument was like, look,
I'm just trying to feed my cows. Come on.
I guess it went to on our
court in Dayton, Ohio.
That was the first stop.
And I believe that he was
one round one to Roscoe.
The Ohio court agreed.
There's no commerce of
any kind nine going on.
You're unlike the original
case with the boat. Right.
I believe I even remember him, uh,
my sister telling me that the,
he came home and he was just, uh,
delighted that he did win. But then,
okay,
the government appeals the case and of
course the one had got to the Supreme
Court of the United States.
Okay.
He, he, he lost
[inaudible].
He lost in a decision that I think it's
fair to say still drives conservatives
and Libertarians bonkers and I am neither
one of those things, but I get it.
What the Supreme Court said is it Roscoe
Filburn growing that extra wheat and
not selling,
it still counts as interstate commerce
because half of that extra week causes
him to not buy it on the market.
He needs less wheat from the market and
if all the farmers of America did that,
then that'd be really bad for the market.
The idea is that if you need
more wheat than the quota,
you go on the market and buy it.
Even though you can grow it yourself,
you got to buy it because if everyone
can produce their quota and then whatever
extra they need, I mean pretty
soon the regulation breaks down,
which means that the
government intervention in
the wheat market will fail.
You will have defeated our
attempt to regulate this market.
Therefore we have to regulate.
Even the things you don't do.
[inaudible].
See that is so weird. It's such
a mind. Frankly. It's like, well,
he's not doing anything. Well, we'll
just literally non behavior. This is,
this is Obamacare. It's very
much like the healthcare case.
It's getting heated over healthcare.
Today's issue, the individual mandate,
just to explain, that's a reference
to Barack Obama's healthcare plan.
There's hotly debated a couple of
years ago, still hotly debated.
One of the key ideas of that plan is
that in order for healthcare to be
affordable for everyone independent,
everyone should have to buy it,
so we're going to require people to buy
insurance or else you pay a penalty,
which made a lot of people
mad because they're like, hey,
the government's forcing me to
buy something. I don't want.
My decision not to get healthcare is not
participation in interstate commerce.
It's not even economic activity.
I'm sitting here on my
couch not buying healthcare.
I'm just sitting here from the individual
perspective. That makes perfect sense.
But in the aggregate, if you pan out
and justice Kagan said this in court,
it's not so simple
and the aggregate of all these uninsured
people are increasing the normal family
premium congresses by $1,000 a year.
Those people are in commerce.
They're making decisions that are
uh, affecting the price that
everybody pays for this service.
Obamacare makes sense to me in
some, in some spiritual way,
but getting back to Roscoe, we're
regulating the things you're not doing.
No farmers and islands.
This is the case in which Congress
receives a tremendous amount of power from
the U S Supreme Court.
Essentially this case,
it says that Congress can
regulate almost anything
and that is the single most
significant precedent in the area.
The Big Bang
[inaudible].
Did anyone sort of raise their hand in
the middle of this and be like, Whoa,
if you can regulate the non
behavior of this American farmer,
then that's not even a slippery slope.
That's like a cliff that goes right down
to like there's no slope to that. Yeah.
A New York Times editorial
from November 13, 1942 said,
if the farmer who grows feed for
consumption on his own farm competes with
commerce, would not the housewife who
makes herself address do so equally.
The net of the ruling in short seems to
be that Congress can regulate every form
of economic activity if it so decides
would not the housewife who makes herself
address do so ego. Yeah. It's like,
yeah, if you make something like, shoot,
my wife and I with our kids made these
little like a miniature stuffed animals
for them to play with the other day.
Are we then in violation
of some on my desk?
Seems crazy to make the kids do it and
now you've violated some child labor
laws. Even
so like what happened to your
essentially Robert is the, um,
the definition of commerce, uh,
changed in as in a sneaky
but really powerful way.
Cause now it wasn't just like
the buying and selling of stuff.
It was the not buying and
selling of stuff. Yeah.
It was your negative commercial activity.
That is all the things you don't do as
a much bigger territory than the things
you do do. Yeah.
It's a massive extension of power and
that expansion would continue over the
next few decades and it would move from
just wheat to something much deeper to
like beyond markets into the,
into matters of the heart.
You mean like people hating on each other
or people trusting people being great.
People all will become clear
after the break. After the break.
Excuse me while I get myself
up this sizzling drink and
settled down in my black
leather couch. Ooh. Yeah.
All right. Season two,
finale of more perfect here on radio lab.
We'll continue in a moment.
This is Nicole from
Corning, New York.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org.
Hey Simon Adler here. Uh,
I'm one of the producers here at Radiolab
and I wanted to take a quick second to
tell you about something that, uh, that
I think is pretty interesting that,
that we make here, uh, besides
the show. So we have a newsletter,
which I know everyone
does, but hear me out.
Unlike a lot of other
newsletters out there, uh,
we don't waste your time by just blabbing
about what our next release will be or
begging you for money. Uh, actually
we, we do a little bit of that. Uh,
but what we also do is each
time a new episode drops,
we send you a list of staff picks,
essentially a collection of things to
folks here who make this show have come
across recently and are excited about, uh,
they range from books and music to TV
shows, youtube clips, art exhibits,
blogs. It's sort of a repository for
the stuff that's got us interested.
But for whatever reason, uh, we're not
sure how to turn into a radio story.
So if that sounds interesting to you
at all, I hope you'll sign up for it.
Our newsletter, it's free and you can
sign up in about just 30 seconds at
radiolab.org/newsletter or even easier.
Just text our l news as in radio lab
news to seven zero one zero one that's RL
news to seven zero one
zero one and thanks.
Hi, this is John Roderick
from the rock band,
the long winters and I'm Ken Jennings
from the syndicated quiz show jeopardy.
We have a podcast called omnibus.
It's a time capsule of our era and we
put a new entry in the ground every
Tuesday and Thursday.
Listen on Apple podcasts or wherever
you get your podcasts and subscribe to
never miss a single episode.
I'm Jad Abumrad I am Robert
Krulwich. This is well,
we're featuring the final episode
of more perfect season two, uh,
here on radio lab.
A strange and Heartfield salute to the
commerce clause of the U s constitution.
Yes. And uh, previously we had
the big bang in the wheat field,
but that was still about markets and
commerce and all that, right? Yeah,
there was a moment about two decades
after the wheat case where you might say
the commerce clause got weaponized. Hm.
Hello? Hey, can you hear me? Yes.
This is Jad from a Radiolab and more
perfect in New York and Jack. Jack j. A d.
J. A. J. A d. Okay.
Well Andrew is here and he's recording
to really understand what I mean,
you have to meet this guy. Can you
reduce yourself? Tell me who you are.
Your name? Yes, there's Ollie
McClung jr. And how old are you?
and where are you speaking to us from
right now? I'm in Birmingham, Alabama.
You were born in Birmingham? Yes. Gotcha.
Aside from some time at college in
Florida and a stint in the coast,
coastguard Ali Jr has lived
in Birmingham his entire life.
And the reason we call them
up is that for 75 years,
his family ran a famous
barbecue joint named Dolly's.
So this is your dad's business
from what I understand, right? Yes.
My grandfather actually had founded
it. Oh really? When was that? 1926.
So this was passed to your dad
who passed it to you? Yes. Okay.
We were in business
together until he died.
Ollie's BBQ was located on Birmingham
south side of the building.
We were in at the time, you're
talking about 1949 til 68.
It was concrete block,
a big sign outside said world's best
barbecue. Pretty good for today.
Apparently during lunch the
line would stretch out the door.
Ali's was famous for its slow cooked
pork and chicken and for its a spicy
vinegar barbecue sauce, a on
the pad baking chocolate pies.
We always did a lot of pies,
but Ollie's was also famous or would
become famous for something else entirely.
Oh, uh, locales. The Times, uh,
in the way things were, uh, at that time
course throughout south and Birmingham,
uh, we had, uh,
carry out business as well as
sit down business and, and uh,
those of our black
customers came in and, uh,
ordered from the carry out counter and
took their food out and, um, you know,
truth fact history, uh,
they would take it on, uh,
with them to eat as opposed
to sitting down and eating.
What he's saying is that Ollie's barbecue
was segregated. If you were white,
you could eat inside. If you were black,
you couldn't remain. That was
the way it work. [inaudible]
okay. So what does this have to
do with the commerce clause? Okay,
so the federal government at the time,
this would be the Kennedy Administration.
Then LBJ, they wanted to come
down and places like Ollie's BBQ,
but their hands were sort of tied. I mean,
we have this thing called the
14th amendment, which says,
no state shall deprive any person of life,
liberty or property
without depressive of law.
Nor shall any state denied equal
protection of the laws to any person.
James Chin again? No. Those words he says,
which were ratified right after the civil
war were written to basically outlaw
things like segregation.
Of course, it didn't work.
We'd have another 80
plus years of Jim Crow.
And the reason for that is that the
Supreme Court shortly after the 14th
amendment was passed kind of new
debt. Well, not kind of. They did.
And one of the ways they
did was by insisting that we
read the 14th amendment as
being targeted only at states.
If you look at that sentence,
the second sentence of the
14th amendment says, no state,
no state shall deprive any
person of life, liberty,
or property without
depressant. The problem is,
is when a restaurant owner like Ollie
McClung denies service to black patrons,
it's not Alabama doing the
damage just to private business.
It's not as if Alabama ordered the McClung
family to discriminate against black
patrons. They just did it.
So the 14th amendment can only get to
states here it has no reach because if
there's no state action, there is nothing
to regulate at the state level. So
[inaudible]
with the feds decided to
do in a fascinating bit of
legal gymnastics is they
decided to use
[inaudible] the commerce clause.
Congress passes the most sweeping civil
rights bill ever to be written into the
law, giving all Americans the
right to be served in facilities,
which you wrote them in the public.
July 2nd, 1964,
congress passes a sweeping civil rights
bill that was hinged on those 16 words.
And I will explain to you how,
because it's kind of
fascinating in just a second,
but first just to get us to that point.
So 1964 civil rights act is passed.
Did you desegregate right away? No. No.
Well we were, we were not
happy with it. Obviously,
I want to read to you something that
you said in 1964. I believe these are,
this is sort of your account
or something that happened in,
in your restaurant day after
the Civil Rights Act was passed.
A black man comes into the restaurant
asking to be served and uh,
and you turn them away.
45 minutes later it comes back with
a young girl for other black people.
They sit down at the counter,
they want to know why you,
why Ali's wouldn't serve them.
And they were taking notes and you're
quoted as saying they seem like
dictators. Yeah. In fact, they were,
they, uh, they were folks that came,
uh, and went around several places, uh,
just to test the law basically.
Yeah. And you were a,
and you were turning those folks
away. Yes. You kicked them out.
[inaudible] and why don't we
just, because that's way, uh,
we had always done this way
until the law got adjudicated.
Uh, we weren't going to
unilaterally, uh, change, but they,
you know, from their perspective,
they're there because the
laws have been changed.
Yeah. Yes.
[inaudible]
Holly says right after the
Civil Rights Act was passed,
sort of an emergency meeting was called of
the a Birmingham Restaurant
Association and he and his dad went
when we, uh, discussed with the, um,
with them and with the executive of it,
that this was going to be
such a potentially, uh,
harmful to the restaurant businesses.
Like you wouldn't lose all your customers.
Is that what you
were worried about? I mean
that that was a possibility
and, uh, somebody out to do something. Uh,
and so we kind of ended up being
the ones to do something, uh,
if I file the suit.
So they filed a suit basically
saying to the federal government,
you have no right to barge into our
small independent local business.
That was,
they can't really tell us what to do
because we're not an interstate business.
And that's all that the federal government
regulates. And up until that point,
that was all they had regulated.
The case went to the u s district court
for the northern district of Alabama.
Uh, at the lower court level, the
three judge, special panel, uh,
we had a unanimous decision in our favor.
The Alabama court agreed that there was
no interstate commerce happening here
and that Ali's did not
have to desegregate.
They could sell their ribs
to whoever they wanted.
And we were optimistic about that.
The government then appeals
and the case, as they say,
it goes all the way to the supreme court.
[inaudible]
all right.
Let me now explain to you how the
government made this argument because they
made it. Yeah,
the court chief justice bad please. Carte
October 5th, 1964
second case
solicitor General Archibald Cox
gets up there and lays it out.
Why the government should be allowed to
use the commerce clause of all things to
desegregate all these barbecue
that believes operate a
restaurant in Birmingham, Alabama,
specializing in barbecue meat.
He says this is a business that
sells and buys a lot of meat.
It's a 12 month period
prior to July one 1964 yeah,
pleas prices about $70,000 worth me.
$69,683 to be exact. And where
do you think all that meat cake
is? That purchase from the Carmel
Company at is Birmingham, Alabama.
All the beat sold that.
That came from other states so that
it moved and then it's big. Huh?
In other words, you think you're
a local business but you're not.
Meat is sourced from places other than
Alabama. And what about your ketchup?
Hypothetically, do you grow your
tomatoes in Alabama? No. Salt. Salt,
not mine in Alabama. So, even though
we bought it from a local vendor,
that local vendor probably bought it
from somebody who bought it from somebody
that got it from out of state.
They were reaching beyond what
had ever been done before.
Basically government was basically
telling the McClung is the same thing they
told Roscoe Philbin
you are not an island. Well,
and that was only the government's first
argument. They had another argument
that was a second than still bar directly.
That was even more
radical betray and racial discrimination
in restaurants at interstate commerce,
which is caused by the
artificial narrowing of the
consumer resulting from the
explosion of big girl patient.
So here's the argument, okay.
If you deny black people access
to restaurants and hotels,
you are effectively shutting
down interstate travel by them.
In parts of the country where
this practice is commonplace,
the entire deep south,
you're limiting their ability to
cross state lines and and travel.
The central argument says James Chen
is that when you discriminate against
someone,
well as you create downstream negative,
uh, commercial effects, like,
like you create a chilling effect
because the person you're discriminating
against is then less likely to travel
across state lines and spend money.
So in effect, you are depressing
their future interstate commerce.
If you ask black people with this
experience from this time period,
they will universally say we never
left home unless every tire was triple
checked.
Every belt was triple checked in the car
because we did not want to have the car
breakdown in a hostile southern
town and get lynched. Right?
Right.
It is an entire system of travel
and commerce that's at stake here.
Essentially, the argument was
discrimination is bad for business.
It's expensive.
And ultimately in a unanimous
decision, the Supreme Court,
same court,
that a hundred years earlier had
basically gutted the 14th amendment.
The Supreme Court agreed
that a discrimination in
restaurants post significant
burdens on the quote interstate flow of
food and upon the movement of products
generally.
Do you remember that decision coming
down? Oh, certainly. Where were you?
Pause at work. Can you tell me a
little bit about how you and your dad
processed that decision?
We simply served anyone who
came in after that no problem.
And they were, uh, the very next
day there was a group of local, uh,
civil rights leaders who came in and
ate lunch a new, some of them. Ah,
I haven't seen them in the
news, that sort of thing.
They were not our regular customers for
then, nor after, frankly, but, uh, they
celebrated or whatever you
want to say, uh, test it.
I don't know what their motive was,
but they came in and ate lunch.
They got served just like anybody
else. They came in and it was fine.
Sure. The law was, was
decided. So that was it.
Was it tense? No,
other than the waitress who was waiting
on was, she was a little antsy about it.
And was it this waitress,
was she a black woman?
Yes. No, I forget who it
was now, but she was like,
most of our employees have been
there a very long time and, uh,
had never served other black folks, uh,
in a sit down situation. And,
and of course it was a little bit, uh,
I won't say upsetting but different.
She was a little hesitant at first. I,
you know, told her, you know, Cisco
right-hand serve him and she did.
And we did. And that was not a problem
after the ruling.
It's not as if a lot of black customers
suddenly started coming into Ollie's
BBQ. They didn't really
increase their blood.
Here's how a guy named Nathan
Turner Jr put it in 2014, uh,
he was interviewed for an NPR
piece. He grew up nearby. Ollie's,
just the fact that all is pushed it that
far to take it to the supreme court.
It left a bad taste, pun intended,
in the mouths of a lot of
black people in Birmingham.
Now, now 53 years later. How do you
think about that Supreme Court decision?
Well, yeah, if you're
asking me about segregation,
that's one thing you asked me about
Supreme Court and the decision and the
commerce clause. I still
disagree with, uh, uh,
let me put it real, real succinctly. Uh,
I think what you had in that
decision was it rather than,
and I think my civics is
correct, but I don't know,
rather than three quarters of the, uh,
Congress and three fifths of the states,
I believe it is having two or maybe two
thirds of Congress, whichever it is,
having to vote to repeal an
amendment to the constitution.
Uh, you had basically nine appointees
who repeal the 10th amendment to the
Constitution,
but 10th amendment basically says that
the powers not given to the feds are
reserved for the states
and for the people.
And that's about as
succinct as I can say it.
Do you understand how this is going
to sound to a lot of our listeners,
I mean that you are making a state's
rights argument as a not so veiled way to
continue to discriminate
that really in the end,
this is not about states' rights.
I think that's going to how it's
going to sound to a lot of people.
Well, it may very well, but it's
not the case. Was there segregation?
Yes. Uh, where we going to voluntarily,
uh, in that, probably not.
Would we go back and reinstate
if we could? No, absolutely not.
But the issue that you're
talking about with the uh,
commerce clause and the constitutional
issue is still just what I said.
So you still believe 53 years later
that the supreme court got it wrong,
that they should have never used the
commerce clause to make you desegregate
Ollie's? Yep.
That is correct. But
don't hear me say that.
I don't want to go back and have
segregation again. That's separate
[inaudible] issue. But is it separate
I guess is my question. You know, uh,
like I grant you, if you
think of it in the abstract,
a federal government being
able to regulate commerce
across all boundaries is an
enormous power and in it, and
it could be a scary Paris,
I grant you that at the same time you
have a civil rights act that it speaks to
a different amendment in
the constitution, right?
And that you and your father
were not willing to follow.
So how is the government going to get
you to pay attention and to get in line?
They've got to use the commerce
clause. So on some level isn't,
it isn't the power present because the
other principles that would otherwise
regulate your behavior
just aren't working.
Well, that's, that's the
point. And you choose which,
which is the priority basically.
I don't understand that. You W W
which is the priority [inaudible]
how well, which is the priority
of, uh, those amendments.
Uh,
and so for you,
the 10th amendment that grants states
rights for everything not enumerated,
outweighs the dignity of
black people. No, no, no,
no. We'll put, so say it to
me differently then. Well,
the 10th amendment left
that to the states,
the fourth amendment. Yes.
I think you meant to say the 14th
amendment gives people rights,
everyone rights. But here's the
thing about rights and Scott,
kind of like the first law of
thermodynamics, there's only a,
and people don't realize this a lot of
times there are only so many rights and
then only a finite number
of rights. If you take some,
give something to someone, they come
from someone else or somewhere else.
Now it's very well to say that
the end of segregation was a higher
right and more important right then the
misuse of the commerce clause
or whatever you want to say.
But u s but there's still a balance
and just which one you think is most
important. Um, today's
parlance, we call it zero sum
[inaudible]
Ollie's basic point. We talked
about this for another hour,
was it in achieving desegregation
that way, and by the way,
civil rights act of 64
dramatically altered the south.
It desegregated huge parts of the
south. But by doing it that way,
he says with the commerce clause,
something was, he calls it
a zero sum, I wouldn't call it that.
I don't think most people
would call it that.
Treating people with dignity
inequality is a net win period.
[inaudible]
but it is legitimately strange
that the government had to take such a
roundabout ass backward way to fix this,
to fix this grave injustice.
What, what,
what you would think would be the obvious
that you would go right to those civil
rights parts of the constitution.
But it wasn't. It was the commerce.
That's weird. Is it? Yeah.
We have the 14th amendment and yet we
go to the commerce clause for something.
Yeah. That is so clearly stated
in one of the amendments.
So why it will lawyers are very tricky.
This is Jamie Floyd again, by the way.
And the lawyers in those cases that want,
they wanted to win,
they wanted to win more than they wanted
to make a social statement about equal
justice, equal rights. The 14th
amendment. I mean those things mattered,
but most of all they wanted to win.
They wanted to shut down discrimination
at those lunch counters and if Congress
could shut them down or require them to
open their doors to all Americans using
those 16 words, I'm okay with that.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I mean obviously the,
if the ends do justify the means
in that case, but it does make you,
if you sort of put that case and the
wheat case in your mind as a kind of split
screen. Yeah. It's,
it's a little strange because I do
think, okay, we have id. I mean,
hopefully we're Americans with
principles that matter. You know,
that we believe in equality.
We believe in racial justice,
but really we just believe in money
and we can do all the other stuff by
bootstrapping it to commerce. But
somehow as, as pure principles,
they what don't have
well,
it's deeply troubling that we have to use
commerce to achieve our higher values.
That is weird to me. That is
fundamentally weird to me.
And it's kind of cynical.
Well yeah, I mean I, you are right.
We are at least in large part
about commerce in this country,
but if that's who we are,
then we should embrace it
and use it to our advantage.
And if we can use it to our advantage,
perhaps it does take us
to our higher principles.
Oh that's an interesting way of
looking at it. Yeah. It's not all bad.
[inaudible]
one of Jamie's points,
which I hadn't actually thought
of was that legislating morality,
legislating what is good and
what is bad doesn't always
go well.
Cause we very often don't agree.
I mean obviously there have been times
where people kept slaves and thought that
was just fine.
That was right.
[inaudible]
and for a hundred years you had
the 14th amendment in place,
but it couldn't solve Ollie's
BBQ. And here was a way
[inaudible]
for the government without going
at the moral questions head on,
government could reach its hand all
the way into the barbecue joints in the
hotels and the restaurants in the houses.
And now the cake shops of America reach
its hand all the way down into the
local.
And it was because of this increasingly
expansive idea of commerce that was now
no longer the buying and selling of
things or the not buying and selling and
things. It was now any
behavior they could create,
a kind of butterfly effect
that might one day,
many steps downstream have a future effect
on the bike.
So in that sense, Ollie
McClung was writing his case.
That was a massive shift.
It shifted totally the federal
government's role beyond business.
Even if you think it's good,
then that's fine and it's for the better.
But just ask to be realized that it was
a massive shift from the way that the
country had been, uh, up before that time,
after the McClung case.
James Chen says service government use
of the commerce clause pretty much went
wild. Yeah, there was just no real limit.
They began to wave those 16 words,
sort of like a magic wand to pass laws
on everything from fair labor standards
to marijuana is a schedule one drugs gun
control act of 1968 guns sped justice
for victims of trafficking,
sex trafficking,
19,000 African lions in the
wild, dangerous species,
1992 professional and Amateur
Sports Sports Protection Act,
which forbids state authorized
sports, gambling, all kinds of things.
And in fact,
the only question was whether the
government even had to make the argument
itself, whether the governor
even has to defend itself.
James Chen says there were times
when the government would pass a law,
it'd get taken to court and the government
would basically not show up and they
would still with, that's where we were.
So we were arguing whether the
government even has to argue.
So you can see the McClung case as
sort of a second big bang, but then
you get to the mid nineties at this point,
1994 you have a democratic president.
Bill Clinton Democratic majorities in
both houses of Congress and together they
pass the violence against women.
Act today is the first day of Spring and
I think it's appropriate that we begin
a new season of hope in the fight
against domestic violence. [inaudible]
I'd like you all for being
here. This is an important day.
The act was sort of a sweeping rethink
of the federal government's role in
trying to prevent violence against
women. It beefed up investigations, uh,
of violent crimes against
women prosecutions.
It allowed women to sue their alleged
attackers in federal court. [inaudible]
take responsibility.
Domestic violence is now the number one
health risk for women between the ages
of 15 and 44 in our country.
And the law was hinged
on the commerce clause.
Same essential argument is in
the BBQ case that same fall.
My name is Christy Brown. Carla. I am 19
years old and I have lived in Fairfax,
Virginia, most of my life.
A woman named Christy Brown.
Kala starts her freshman year at
Virginia Tech and just weeks in,
in mid September, 1994 I was raped by
two football players in my own dorm.
I had met them for the first time, just
15 minutes before they assaulted me.
These two football players she alleged
had raped her repeatedly on a single
night. In 1984 I was raped three times.
She went to the local campus
authorities. She told her story,
college held their own hearings,
didn't go to the police.
They suspended one of the two students.
He appealed the other
one and when he returned,
Krissy Bronco dropped out of school.
Oh,
Christy Brown.
Kala ultimately decides to sue her alleged
attackers and the school under this
new law. The violence against
Women Act and the case
ultimately makes it to the Supreme Court.
We'll hear argument now.
Number 99 five Kristi Brown,
Kala versus Antonio Morrison
when Christie's case got to
the Supreme Court, her lawyer,
MR chief justice and may it please the
court made the same argument about women
that the government had made in the
Ollie's BBQ case about black people.
One of the most discrimination,
or in this case outright violence has a
huge downstream effect on the economy.
A bipartisan Congress
concluded that gender based
violence substantially affects
the national economy,
gender based violence,
and the fear of that discriminatory
violence deters women's travel interstate
restricts women's choice of jobs
and ability to perform those jobs,
reduces national productivity and
increases medical and other costs.
And again,
the court was given tons of evidence
about the economic effects sample congress
heard from women whose batterers
kept their partners from working.
They're shown data that every year this
costs the country billions of dollars.
And that economic downstream effect
was not hard to prove in this case,
she dropped out. Well, especially if you
aggregate it right, it's not just her,
it's everyone else who similarly situated.
But in this case, as I understand it,
this law doesn't apply to any,
any argument what's happening at a
very different time in the country,
very different mood and in front of an
increasingly conservative supreme court
that just wasn't buying it anymore.
Petitioner Bruise oncologists complaint
alleges that she was the
victim of a brutal assault.
This is chief justice Rehnquist
reading the majority opinion.
If the allegations are true,
no civilized system of justice could fail
to provide her a remedy for Morrison's
conduct,
but gender motivated crimes of violence
are not in any sense of the phrase
economic activity.
[inaudible].
In other words,
we're very sorry for what may have
happened to Christine Bronc Kala,
but this is not commerce.
This is violence.
The suggestion was, at
least in the Ali's case,
there was something
being bought sold here.
They felt like the length
of commerce was [inaudible]
too thin.
We accordingly reject the argument
that Congress may regulate noneconomic
violent criminal conduct based solely
on that conduct's remote effect on
interstate commerce.
Chief Justice Rehnquist got his majority
to start to chip away at the commerce
power. Just a tiny, teeny,
teeny weeny little bit and Jamie Floyd
says that attempt to roll it back
continues its rolling
back. It is rolling back.
It's still pretty powerful.
Don't get us wrong,
but where we're left at the end of the day
is in a really confusing place.
Ollie McClung excluding black
people from his dining room.
Yeah, it's a commercial act. We
consider it reprehensible, but I,
I would like to think that raping
Christine would be at least as bad.
Totally. I mean, do you see it?
This is what this kind of like
absurd abstraction gets us to and in
a coherent ideal world can't be right.
[inaudible]
I dunno when you, when the, when the,
the reasoning behind something gets a
little rocky than the soul of things gets,
gets called into question.
What are you doing? Good.
Yeah. For me, that's what happens
when you make everything about money.
Things get a little bit
rotten at their four.
All right, so I'm gonna I just, before
I, uh, before I read the credits,
Robert, thank you for being a
party to the [inaudible] adventure.
[inaudible] always my flight. All right,
so this episode was produced
by Saraj Karrie. Uh,
more perfect is produced by me, Chad
Avalon, Ron and, and amazing teams.
Susie Lectin Berg, Jennie Lawton,
Julia Longoria, Kelley Prime,
Alex Overington and Karrie with
Ellie, Miss Doll, Christian Pfarius,
Linda Hirschman, Dave
Gable and Michelle Harris.
We had production help from Derek
John and Louis Mitchell supreme court.
Audio is from [inaudible],
a free law project and collaboration
with legal information institute at
Cornell.
Leadership support for more perfect
is provided by the Joyce Foundation.
Additional funding was provided by the
Charles Evans Hughes Memorial Foundation
dying to say goodbye. Time to say goodbye.
I'm Jad Abumrad I'm Robert Krulwich.
Thanks for listening.