If you are listening to radiolab, Radiolab
from [inaudible], W N, y.
S. E. N, n. P. R.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is radio lab, the podcast.
And today since we are right about to
have the New York City Marathon Zip
through our neighborhoods senior in
New York, we have a puzzle. Yeah,
it's a puzzle. It's a
puzzle. It's a, it's a, yes,
it is a puzzle and it comes from,
uh, NPRs East Africa correspondent,
Gregory Warner. I've prepared for this
story by taking a jog through Nairobi.
Well, all right, so where
do we start with this, Greg?
I think we should start in 1968 I mean,
there's a lot of places we could start,
but let's start there. Let's try it.
So 1968 summer Olympics in Mexico City,
Mexico City, thankfully [inaudible]
piece on the Olympic opening day,
it's 7,900 feet, one of the
highest elevated Olympics.
And that's difficult for runners
because there's less oxygen.
And one of the big races that everybody's
looking forward to is the 1500 meter
between the 23 year old American. Yeah.
Favorite Jim Ryan.
Ryan of America number 300 he's the world
record holder and this guy named Kip
Chuggy, Kane, Kane, Kenya, number
five six five kip Kane's got flip cam.
They bill him as an untrained
Andy tribesmen from Kenya.
He's actually a policeman from
a long line of cattle wrestlers.
Marvin Woodruff was the winner. And
here's what you need to know about Kipp.
He's running three different races
at this Olympics, 1500 meters,
not only the 1500 but also the
5,000 meter and the 10,000 meters.
If you include the qualifying measures,
he'll be running six Olympic
events in eight days. Wow.
Six races in eight days, which would
never be done today was hardly done then.
So first step, have about
the later 10,000 meter race.
He's in the lead two laps away
from finishing. When he collapses,
it falls off the track. He gets
rushed to the Kenyan doctors,
a German guy who diagnosed him
with a gallbladder infection,
Mitch turns out is incredibly painful,
actually hurts the most
when you take deep breaths,
like when you're running
and if you don't treat it,
your gallbladder could burst. So basically
who the doctor sends, kept bed says
there's no way you can run, but Kipp,
he runs the next race anyway,
ends up getting silver. Wow.
He sent to bed by the German doctor
again who literally says, okay,
this time you have to stay in bed. If
you run any more races, you could die
back to the drag for one of the most
memorable events are they old games?
The 1500 meters,
three days later. It's the big
matchup against Jim Ryan and Kipp.
Apparently he just leaped out of bed
an hour before the race and he said
something like, if I die, I'm
going to die in the track.
It's really complicated. So
kip Kaino starts, they're off
and running, three and three
quarter labs for the stadium.
He starts out dead last.
Okay. I know running my ass and then
moving up to the middle of the pack. Now
how? By the end of the
first lap, he's in third
drop out, the Germany's back
at and Kipp Kaino third,
third lap. He takes the lead.
Here comes gift k. Now having
up with this teammates,
he goes ahead, but that's
okay. For Jim Ryan.
Jim Ryan's known to have the
greatest kick in the sport. Okay,
kick right at the end of the race.
Every runner gives this extra boost
and Ryan's got the best kick in the
business. Good. Brian is beginning,
so he's thinking there's no way that
kip Kaino at altitude suffering a
gallbladder infection can hold out
against my kick. Very rough in the,
in the final lap. It looks like he's
right. Starts shooting up the field,
gaining on Kipp Kaino
who is clearly in pain,
sort of reminiscing, reading his teeth.
Hey y'all. Good job. Lurching.
Did the finish line and even though
he's in an ungodly amount of pain,
even though pain is shooting
through his entire body,
amazingly
he does not slow down.
Jim Ryan never catches
[inaudible]
when he hung on around
that last turn, it was all,
I was hysterical. This is John Manners.
I'm a semi retired journalists who for
many years had a specialty in covering
the exploits of Kenyan runners,
African runners in general.
He was watching that race in a bar
about 50 miles north of New York,
but as a kid, manners actually
lived in the part of Kenya.
The KIP Keto is from my people,
and so when Kaino won gold,
it sparked a question for manners that
he would spend the next 40 years thinking
about. I wanted to find
a reason why my people,
as I chose to regard them were
great because on that day in 1968
ushered in an era of
east African dominance
in the sport. It's 10 year your,
it's kind your, it's can be applied.
It is almost hard to believe,
but Kenyans have done it again. One, two,
yeah.
It was a once again as the eighth
successive gold medal in Olympic history,
so 1968 was the beginning of the
Kenyan dominance and running. Yeah, but
in the United States we think of
Kenyans as being good runners,
but really it's this one tiny,
small geographic swath within Kenya
where all the runners come from.
That's David Epstein. He's a senior
editor at sports illustrated.
He wrote a book called the sports gene,
and the swath that he's talking
about is in western Kenya.
It's a mountainous region spread out
about the size of Massachusetts and the
people who live there are a particular
tribe of Kenyans called the Caligiuri,
pretty small group of people.
His tribe accounts for about
0.06% of the world's population.
But from this one tiny tribe has come
this unbelievable fount of talent that I
think is unparalleled
in any other sport ever.
[inaudible]
there's all kinds of, statistics sort
of becomes laughable. Uh, you know,
there've been five American high school
runners who have broken four minutes in
the mile. The first was actually Jim
Ryan, but there's one high school,
any 10 in Kenya that had four
sub four minors at the same time.
There's 17 American men in history who
have run under two 10 in the marathon.
That's about four minutes
and 58 seconds per mile pace.
17 American men in history.
There were 32 [inaudible] who did it in
October of 2011 so you start to look at
these statistics and it,
and it appears to be the
greatest concentration of
elite athletic talent ever
in any sport, anywhere in the world.
And that's the question. I mean,
how does that happen? That was
John Manners question 40 years ago.
Something has to account for this
extraordinary set of numbers, but what
[inaudible],
and there have been any
number of scientists and
sports gurus and athletes have
gone to this place to figure out
what's happening. What's the,
what's the secret here? You know, and
this, and there's all kinds of theories.
Like it's something about the tree
that they use to make the spoon,
which they used to mix the corn
meal. What would the tree do? Well,
this was this Swedish scientist
who came in and looked at Lugalia,
which is a corn meal. It's
the basic staple food of,
of Kenyans because he wanted to mix it
with the water from the spring in the pot
that Calonge in use thinking that
something chemical was happening that was
making these, these guys, you know,
run super fast that, I mean, you know,
it's kind of silly but, but
a lot of people here, Tom,
tell me it's the bananas,
but people have also suggested
some more reasonable theories.
Well John Manners.
People talk a lot about altitude and the
ability to process oxygen and what have
you.
Other people have said it's cause the
calendar didn't have a high starchy diet
or because they run to school. This
is a very prominent phenomenon.
We know that the runners that come from
the calendar and tribe to become great
runners, they're much more
likely to have run to,
to and from school long distances
like 10 k to and from school.
But there are millions of kids in Kenya
who run to and from school or who live
in altitude.
The problem with all of these is that
these are not specific to the Collagen.
Yeah. So then you get the
socioeconomic arguments.
The salary of a runner is
a, is attractive, you know,
10 or $20,000 a year seems like
a fortune worth striving for,
but the country's not so poor that it
can't send competitors to the athletic
competitions. This is Malcolm Gladwell's
argument actually. Very close. Yeah.
There's a, there's a social pressure
to it. This is how you get out. Yeah.
And there's so many role. I mean every
village has some kind of champion. Yeah.
The problem with that argument,
I mean there's actually no problem
with the argument. It makes sense,
but it doesn't say how the calendar and
got so good in the first place that they
created these role models. I mean,
where did the role models come from?
So the idea you're left with is maybe
there's something genetically different
about them that makes them better than us.
[inaudible]
this is obviously a
dangerous idea. And in fact,
when David Epstein was writing his
book about sports and athletics,
almost backed out of writing the book
because I realized I was going to have to
address ethnic differences
and gender differences. I,
I really did almost back out of it.
There were scientists who confessed
to me that they were withholding data,
that they had studies that
show to genetic advantage,
but they wouldn't show him because they
were afraid that they'd lose tenure.
But he says you have to
acknowledge the obvious.
One aspect of innate biology that
clearly helps Calonge and a that's been
studied by scientists
is their bodybuilding.
So the calendar and what's called
a, a lot of people they're from,
they have ancestry in very low latitude.
I was criss crossing the equator
when I was visiting their track,
their training camps, and when you have
your ancestry in a hot and dry climate,
you have have a certain body type
for cooling and we know this,
we've known this for over a century.
It's called Alan's rule. That organisms,
not just humans,
all organisms that evolved and hot and
dry climates have a certain body type,
namely very long and thin limbs so that
there's a lot of surface area through
which he can dissipate their limbs,
get thinner the farther away they
get from their center of gravity.
So they have extremely thin
ankles and extremely thin calves,
which is particularly important because
your leg is like a pendulum and the more
weight you have farther away
from your center of gravity,
the more difficult it is to swing. This
has been tested in the lab too, right?
So you take a runner and put eight
pounds of weight around their waist,
it increases the energy they have
to use to run at a given pace.
But if you take that same eight pounds
and put it in the form of two four pound
weights around their ankles, it's
like over 25% the increase in energy,
they need to run at the same
pace. So if you have fed ankles,
find a different sport, right?
You're not going to win the New York
marathon if you have a thick ankles.
And so it gets you to this place
where you think, well, I dunno,
maybe halogen from these area, maybe
they have this built in advantage. Hmm,
it's physics. I don't know. Somehow like
I to Sorta just peg it all on physics
smells like an argument that I really
don't like. Oh, nobody likes it.
I don't think it's a
question of like or dislike.
I think it's just not the reason I
watched the Olympics. I mean, you know,
going back to Kipp Kaino. Yeah.
Why? Huh? Who
overcame a gallbladder infection to
break the Olympic world record in 1968 he
didn't win because he had thin ankles.
He won because of something which is
the reason we watch sports. You know,
it's dead essence that will power
or triumph over adversity. Right?
The triumph of the human
over everything. Yes.
And this is where I ran
across a completely new,
fascinating and somewhat terrifying way
of explaining why the [inaudible] are so
good and it's an idea that eventually
led me to go to calendar and country
myself.
That's perfect way of beginning a little
cow hoot to get to 10 which is in the
mountains. The air is cool.
There's a lot of cows,
lot of people and it around
5:36 AM all you hear is the,
the pitter patter of feet
and then all these people just pass
you all of a sudden and then you know,
you wait for a few more seconds to two
people pass you again because everybody's
running. I even started morning
jogging when I was there.
I'm not really a morning jogger, but
it just kind of got into the flow.
Anyway, while I was there, I met this guy,
his name's brother Cole McConnell
Colombo. I'm Irish of course,
came to Kenya in 1976
famous running coach.
He works with a lot of Kenyan runners.
So I met him in an Irish pub in Eldoret,
which is, um, there's only one
when I asked him this question,
what is it that bakes the calendar so
good. This is what he told me. When you,
when you're train an
athlete, um, to a high level,
you need to remember that they
live on the edge of injury.
They live on the edge of overtraining.
They leave on the age of paint,
paint, paint, television,
CSF. They look to some degree.
Everybody has a runner, talks about
this insidious protean nature of pain,
how it finds all the places you become
breathless and in your lungs have
needles.
The best runners have to learn to mentally
override these distress signals to
run. Despite the page. He actually
calls it expanding your pain barrier,
but Columbo, Connell
says for the calendar,
pain is something else entirely. You
know your ability to withstand pain,
that that in a sense into
[inaudible] tradition made you a man.
Quite literally the central event of
their young lives will come up when they
are going to be initiated into the
tribe. That's John Manners. Again,
remember he spent part of his childhood
in calendaring territory and he says
when he was a boy, say 12 years old,
he would notice his friends had
scars on their arms and legs,
marks of having burned their
arms and legs with the hot coals.
He soon learned they were practicing for
this initiation moment. And you know,
you're facing it for 10 years at least
because as a calender and teenager,
boy or girl, you have to go through
an experience which is so painful.
It's a kind of theatrical orgy of pain.
And here's what happens.
First you have to crawl naked
through stinging nettles, um,
which is like formic acid, you know,
and African stinging nettles are much,
much skinnier than the western
stinging nettle. But then your, your,
your fingers are squeezed together.
Then you get beaten on that bony part
of your ankle where it really hurts.
But that's just warm up because then
one morning
calms the circumcision.
Now we have some idea of
how circumcision works.
Maybe some of us are circumcised. So
you perform it on a baby and it's,
it's one kind of experience. I've gone
through that myself. I've seen it done.
I've had to hold the legs
also my nephew, it's hard,
but the calendar can circumcise
somewhere right after puberty.
So around age 13 to 17 mm
oh, they're four skin is,
is not only cut, but it's tied
into a bow. The more than that,
the tied into the boating thing.
Got To stop there. I kind of froze.
I don't really know how to describe
it past there. I believe that
of the,
either the top or the bottom
of the foreskin is pierced
and then the head of the
penis has pushed through the opening.
Uh, and the thing is
it's not just the cut.
Actually when he undergoes the operation,
he is obliged be absolutely
stoical still unflinching.
So in some versions of this ceremony,
mud is caked on the face and
then the mud is allowed to dry.
If a crack appears in the mud,
your cheek may twitch your,
your forehead may crinkle.
And if that happens,
a little crack will appear in the mud.
And all the people around will know to
immediately start beating you with large
sticks. So worst part though
is not just the beating,
it's that after that moment,
if you don't make it through this
ceremony, you get labeled a cabby.
Tet a coward. You're a pariah in
society. You're not part of society.
In the olden days,
you didn't have access to the economic
opportunities to afford what's called the
bride price, which is what you, what
you need to get a wife. However,
if you show yourself to be a true warrior,
if you make it through this
experience, then then hey,
you get the rights of reproduction.
You may even have two or three wives.
So manners wondered then
he's just speculating here.
But maybe if you have 2000 years of this
sexual selection of ensuring that the
stoical tough guy types get to have
babies, the sensitive types don't.
Maybe it's not just that the
calendar are built for speed,
it's not just that they
have the body type.
Maybe they have some sort
of innate ability mentally
to persevere through pain.
Huh.
And is that a cultural ability or would
he say that all that selection has
filtered into their DNA in some way?
Well, so manners this, he isn't sure,
and there's certainly no gene for
stoicism that that's been discovered.
And any athletic success has to
be ascribed to a host of factors.
But W can I play one cut?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's here.
So, um, all right. So I was in Eaton,
I was thinking about that question and
I met this kid named Ellie kip cocaine.
He's 19 years old. So self-described
bookwork from the very beginning.
I never wanted to go through
the traditional form of
circumcision cause I knew
the ordeal as in it was so,
and actually what he said was please
circumcise me in the hospital.
I want to do the cowardly way.
But his relative said no, you,
you chain the entire family
and if you don't do it, yeah
you're not a fool man.
That's how they put it.
So he felt like he had to just do
it cause I still had this beatings.
You're supposed to stay for night.
I was inside the Coldwater then, uh,
early in the morning, around seven in the
morning. It's a conversation they use,
I sharp stick. I hope you
understand that. A sharp stick.
So it's just,
and he said the whole initiation ritual
actually went on for a couple of weeks.
It was more than just the cut.
And during the whole time he was kept in
a hut on the outskirts of the village.
Is faced with powdered white
like a ghost, and he was told,
whenever you leave this hut,
you are not allowed to work.
You're not allowed to walk. So
you're supposed to run very fast.
So you only [inaudible]
having the opinion.
And before the circumcision, Ellie
was never a runner. Afterwards,
when he was done with initiation and
he was back in high school, I said, Oh,
let me give it a try so I could
run and I feel pain. I feel pain,
I'm feeling pain and I wanted
to stop [inaudible] let me try.
Let me just tell you.
They didn't tell him I one one one 21
one time and two minutes later I was at
school. Ellie joined his track team,
started running to school and during his
lunchtimes and after 24 two weeks and
three weeks,
I became an expert and I was known
as the school cliff after how long?
After two weeks salon to Salon.
Two weeks. That's how we began.
That's a crazy stories. That
really true. Yeah, that's true.
So probably my ability of running
was a bit higher than dressed.
Turns out Ellie's mom was an
accomplished athlete. Okay,
so you're saying you had
some physical ability to run,
but you just didn't really do it before?
I never realized that I could run.
So we didn't talk at all about women,
but calendars and girls also
go through an initiation,
right of their own female genital
mutilation, the same type of ritual,
not the same ceremony, but a similar
type of stoical testing ceremony.
And to me this made no sense.
This is John Manners again.
Obviously the women are not the
warriors, they don't need to be brave.
Why is it important for them to
show courage during this operation?
And when I asked this question of my
calendar and friends many years ago,
they were kind of astonished at the
question as though the answer should have
been self evident.
And the answer they gave me was a
woman who chose cowardice during this
operation might bear cowardly sons.
So some Collagen might say that Ellie
actually got two things from his mom.
One was his physical prowess,
his speed on the track.
The other was a mental ability
to persevere through pain.
People usually say it's
called a blessing in college.
[inaudible] blessing is what
you get. Probably a father,
probably a grandmother. So you wish
he blesses you with that activity.
That's what you used to
see the blessing. That's,
that's pretty interesting,
right? It's interesting,
although we're using inheriting
words are blessing words.
What we're really talking about is the
pressure of a culture that is simply
choosing to deeply,
psychically reward certain behaviors and
create expectations for those behaviors
and create success around those
behaviors. Those are all cultural,
not biological things, but they, they
are the equivalent. I think it's both.
Uh,
and I don't know what proportion each
contributes to the ultimate result.
I, it's, I have no way of judging,
but whatever the mechanism
and whatever it is,
it'll probably stay a mystery of all the
explanations out there for why this one
group of people is so good at running.
This is the first one that's
made me want to run. Hmm.
Once I met Ellie and talk
to these runners in Kenya,
you know, this is a embarrassing
story because I don't run very fast,
but I got to the gym and I was
on the treadmill and I was like,
I'm taking it up to seven you
know, seven miles an hour,
like 7.1 actually I went and you
know that's not like very fast,
but that would usually be my end run like
at the last five minutes I'm I do with
them. But it went, but I did the whole
25 minutes at 7.1 and I thought, how did,
why did I ever think that
this was undoable before?
Why was I staying at like 6.8 if we're
trying to figure out what makes these
runners so great? And our first
answer is a totally scientifically,
factually true,
but somehow demoralizing absolute.
That puts one set of people over
there and the rest of us over here,
we all have our body type
that we're born with.
But then if the second explanation
of this Calonge in advantage,
maybe just as inaccessible
to the rest of us,
but still it feels like a more
egalitarian version of advantage,
even if we're talking about a very
specific culture. Yeah. I think the,
if you run with this extreme pain for a
month after having been circumcised and
somehow that gave you a certain culturally
troubling but also real relationship
to pain, that feels like
a fair advantage to me.
Not that I would wish
it on anyone. Actually.
Even Ellie does not wish it
on his kids when he has kids.
The system is changing from
the traditional format to
the new format right now.
I mean, he's part of a new
generation of Collagen.
He says for his contemporaries,
the painfree hospital circumcision
is becoming slowly less of a stigma.
And I can't imagine my son going through
the same procedure as their father.
So my son, one of my sons went to go
through the same procedure as I did,
but um, didn't, I mean, don't
you want your son to be,
to have the benefits of what
you, the benefits only a boot.
The perseverance part of it and they
believe [inaudible] can get through many
ways. He tells himself he's going to be
able to pass on those Calonge and values
without resorting to the ancient rituals.
I will teach him how to persevere
and he thinks his kids will still be able
to be champion runners if that's what
they want to be.
[inaudible]
thanks to Gregory Warner, NPRs
East Africa correspondent. Also,
we should say thanks to FIA Beneen
for production help on this piece.
Thank you for you and thank you guys
for listening. I'm Chad. I'm Robert.
We'll see you next time.