Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is Radiolab and we're
talking about bliss. So far.
I'm going to say we're not doing so
great. I mean we had a fleeting moment,
a dream that crumbled snowflakes
that evaporated in your hand,
but in the next story we're going
to shoot for bliss that lasts.
Hello, this is Mike Young. Mike, speak
up. Andy comes to us from our producer,
Andy Mills. Can you hear me? I can
hear Ya. All right, so set this up.
Who is this guy? His name is Mike Young.
I called them up because of something
that happened to him a little over 50
years ago. Let's see.
This was 1962 is something that he still
thinks about all these years later.
I was in my early twenties
22 something like that.
21 he was an undergraduate
at a theological school
in Boston and one day he
received a very different
kind of religious education,
a very different kind, good ds though.
He event occurred on Good Friday
[inaudible]
and it happened at the Boston
University Marsh Chapel.
He was sitting, not up in the main chapel,
but down in the little basement chapel.
And he was sitting with about
19 of his fellow classmates.
The Meditation Service was being piped
down to us from the chapel above.
They have speakers in the front of
this little chapel in the basement,
had organ music and an excellent choir.
And the voice of the preacher
sentenced those is this kind of
famous guy named Howard Thurman.
And we relaxed. We're all good
and interesting ideas
began going off in my head,
well beside us in the way that we take.
Sometimes it was hard to pay attention
to what was going on in the room,
the things that resist and defy.
And we slid jet a right into the, uh,
silicide been experienced.
What we did, he said silicide
yes. Was in magic. Mushrooms.
Shrooms. What? You're gonna
have to explain that one.
This was actually something called
the Marsh Chapel experiment,
the Marsh Chapel experiment.
And it was run by this guy.
His name was Walter Pinky.
Very briefly summarize that.
And he was a graduate student at
Harvard at this time and he was studying
religious experience. Me.
Oh. This has also been
called the cosmic experience.
The transcendental experience
or the mystical experience.
What exactly was he looking at? You know,
like, um, Christians, Muslims, Jews,
mystics. Like what kind of things
do they all have in common?
So he did a bunch of research
and interviews and he came
up with a basic catalog
of the ingredients in
a religious experience.
And one day he's at Harvard
and he bumps into turn on
Carolinian and drop out
that guy, Timothy Leary,
he was actually a teacher at Harvard
at the time and he was famously giving
psychedelic drugs to Undergrad
by teaching people out of his very head.
The a point is that in order to use
your head have to go out of your mind.
And when Panky got a chance to talk
to these students who had tripped,
he noticed pretty quick that they used
really similar language to the people
that he'd been studying.
And he started to wonder,
if you put people into the right
situation and you give them this drug,
could you induce, actually
induce a religious experience.
So on that day in 1962,
Pankey put 20 theological school students
into this church basement, you know,
during this Good Friday service,
10 of them got a placebo and then 10
of them got a hefty dose of Psilocybin,
things in the room morphing. Um,
which brings us back to
Mike Young. You would move
of your head and there'd be an after
image from the lights at one point.
The visual effect was especially powerful.
And he had this one moment that
has just stuck with him ever since.
I was in the middle of a technicolor's
C and there were bars of color and I was
floating through them and they
were floating through me, uh,
and it was just glorious. And
the bars of color then resolved,
uh, into, uh, a feel.
I was at the center and there was a
different color going out from me in every
possible direction.
[inaudible]
at first, this was quite nice. Uh,
and then I realized that I had just
swim out one of those color bars
I had to.
And each of those different color
bars would be a whole different life
experience. And I could
choose any one of those, uh,
life experience color bars that I wanted,
but I had to choose one
and I couldn't choose one.
It was very painful. It felt like my
insides were being ripped out of me
and I died.
And at that moment that I died, uh,
I heard Howard Thurman say,
I shall die,
but that is all that I shall do for death.
And I stopped dying.
Wow. That's, wow.
What are we supposed to make of that?
Right. It is. It is strange. Yes. In fact,
this is actually right around the time
that this huge cultural backlash against
this drug, by the end of 1962,
you've got Harvard making the decision
that these experiments are not going to
be done at their university
anymore. 63, that evil man,
they fire Timothy leary. Timothy
Leary, he's out of there.
1970 congress outlaws, psychedelics, 1971
nearly every country in the world,
including the United States,
bans them from research is their signatory
to an international law banning the
use sale,
cultivation and possession of dangerous
drugs that have no useful place in
medicine.
I mean on some level,
like I get that because like what
could you learn from a bunch of people
tripping like scientific.
I mean I think that there actually is
something that we can learn from this.
What? Well,
if you look at Mike Young on the
day that he walked into that chapel,
I was still a theological school
student. He was, you know,
he's experiencing doubts
without any real confidence.
That ministry was something
I was going to stay in.
But after this experiment at the chapel,
he went home to his wife
and when I walked in,
my wife was very much aware that something
rather unusual had occurred to this
guy she was married to. Did she
just, you carry yourself differently?
You should never been that explicit
about it. She just said she knew that,
that I had had some kind of
a major experience at first.
He just kind of wrote the whole
thing off. But as time passed,
he couldn't stop thinking about the
death and the rebirth experience.
And to make a long story
short, if you fast forward,
I'm a unitarian universalist minister, um,
as a result of partly a result
of that drug experience.
I want to share with you this
morning, a little extra. Jesus.
The New Testament. That's him. Yeah.
Story of the Good Samaritan. And he has,
I've been preaching for 45 years here.
Here's the thing that I
think is really strange.
All of the people who
took the drug that day,
those 10 who got the
psilocybin and not the placebo,
all but one that came.
Ministers really? So nine out
of 10 went into the mystery.
Nine out of 10. What about the
others? The Placebo Group? Yeah. None.
None. Gordon to Mike. Absolutely
none. Wow. That is interesting.
That was the first thing. I was
like, wow, that's, that's crazy.
But at the same time, you know,
it's really small sample set.
Who knows why anyone becomes a minister?
I'm sure it wasn't just the drugs.
You know, maybe they didn't even play
that big of a role for everyone else,
but this did make me, you know,
like more curious like what exactly is
happening to people when they take this
drug? Yeah,
and I was surprised to find out that
like right now there are actually a few
laboratories who are starting
to experiment with these
drugs. Again, we thought,
well why not? This is Roland,
Roland Griffis psychopharmacologist. I
studied the effects of drugs on behavior.
He's at Johns Hopkins and
Hopkins for 40 years now.
He's really well known for
studying nicotine and Ritalin,
but he tells me that back in 2000 he
was reading about the old psilocybin
studies from the 60s and this is right
around the time when the Drug Enforcement
Administration and the FDA were starting
to loosen their rules on experimenting
with psychedelics. So he
applies and he gets approval.
Study about short had not been approved
for 30 years and I can tell you that
I've never had a protocol that was
as rigorously and carefully reviewed
and scrutinized from every angle since
no one had studied this drug for like
three decades. He started with
some really basic questions.
How does this affect behavior
after people have taken this drug?
Like did they feel confused or
afraid? Is it habit forming?
And how he did his test was he has this
lab room at Johns Hopkins that he's,
he's made like really nice and cozy.
It's a, it's a aesthetic living room,
like environments.
There's a couch in the stereo system
and then one at a time the volunteers
brought in and given a hefty dose of
psilocybin blindfolded and then they're
asked to lay down and direct
their attention inward
[inaudible]
we were bringing people in two months
after sessions and asking them so well,
you know, what was the session like?
And they filled out some questionnaires
and the thing that I really wasn't
prepared for was how salient and important
these experiences we're said to be on
follow up. You know, they were saying,
well, it was really important, you know,
and I would say, well, how important?
And they would say, oh, well,
it was a most important experience
in my life. And I'd go, what?
[inaudible]?
And they would say, yeah, you
know, it's like, um, you know,
like when my daughter was born,
that changed my world forever.
I recently lost my father and,
um, and I'll never forget that.
And they'll say, you know,
it's kind of like that.
And that's a totally
improbable. So we didn't,
we didn't have any metric
that could even assess that.
And what made things even weirder
for Rollin is that when he gave these
volunteers a questionnaire,
about 75% of people are saying it's in
the top five most personally meaningful
and spiritually significant
experiences, but their life,
a vast majority. We're talking about it
like it's a spiritual experience. Huh?
So rollin,
he went back to look at Pankey's
studies from the 1960s about the basic
ingredients that make
up a religious aspect.
Let me look. The characteristics
of very summary list first,
the characteristics of awe and wonder.
Everyone would report that they felt like
they were in the presence of something
great and enormous
characteristic is the of time
and space. People describe time
slowing down or space getting
the third characteristic have to do with
mood. Very deeply felt positive. Mood
fourth, and I'm skipping over a few
you want to do this is a
sense of cosmic oneness,
this feeling of intense connection
to everything around you.
The part of everything that is the whole
universe and even every blade of grass
and grain of sand and so forth.
These are words that people
use in describing anyway,
so based on this one guys,
research and keep in mind,
you know a lot of people have
different opinions about this.
Roland believes that you can actually
take this little drug and from majority of
people you can induce
a religious experience,
but it's I you don't you, I don't know.
Soon as you call it bat then I'm
starting to think, hm, don't know.
This is a real, a real, I
mean I don't know you guys,
but for someone who has to
take this very seriously,
because to say that you can pop a
pill and then in some shortcut fashion
suddenly get this experience that hit
her too had been very rare and had been
assigned the values of grace
to say that is to say any enormous
thing. Well it sounds like,
it sounds like you're not, I'm
guessing how you're taking it, Robert,
as to say that a d values, the thing I do,
values kind of does the
opposite for me. Well really,
I mean when I hear the stories from,
from like all the people in these
studies, it reminds me like I've,
I've had these like very meaningful
experiences that I didn't think would last
on the pill. Did you have them
or no, not, not a pill. No drugs.
So what happened? What, what
are you talking about? Well,
it goes back to like
when I was a Christian,
I used to be an evangelical Christian
and when I was about 15 I was at a church
camp and me and some of my best friends
were all gathered around a campfire.
It was hot in the stars
for all bright and shiny.
I remember they were playing
this song that I really liked.
And you know that feeling that you get
when when you in a crowd of people are
all singing like really loud some
song that you all really love.
Sure. And as we're all singing this song,
I remember my friend who wasn't raised
in the faith like me leaning over to me
and saying that like he wanted to
accept Jesus and be a Christian.
And he asked, well, what am I supposed
to do? And I remember that being like,
great, great. It's not
even the word for it.
Like in this one moment I got caught up
in something that just felt so enormous.
It's hard for me to
explain how it felt like.
It's hard to describe how I
felt like we were all one.
Like there was something
powerful that was,
that was like both over
us but also inside of us.
And so much has changed since then
that sometimes I look back and I think,
did that happen?
Like did I hallucinate like some dude
on drugs because that friend who,
uh, reached over to me, he's dead now.
That faith that I was
a part of, I left it.
Okay.
Like all I have is this weird feeling
okay.
That I can remember. That's good.
And even though you're not
a Christian anymore, you,
you still have that feeling. Oh yeah.
But what is it about the
idea that, that feeling,
that campfire feeling can be triggered
by a pill and that maybe that's what was
happening to those folks in Rollins study?
What is it about that idea
that helps you? For me,
like I see something concrete,
you know, like I see,
I see. I see something that's
harder to write off. How so? Well,
if I can go back into reporter mode,
I will introduce you to one more guy who
I think is going to help you understand
what I'm talking about. Hello.
This is Charlie. Charlie Busan.
He's a longtime smoker. No, let's
start it at 17. Smoked for 40 years.
Pack a day. Breakfast, coffee,
talking on the phone. Wait,
why are we talking about smoking? Well,
Roland's new studies doing right now,
his pilot program that he's
just started a few years ago.
[inaudible] is trying to see if there's
something in the transformation that you
have in, in the psilocybin experience
that can help smokers quit smoking.
What really stick with me. They
gave me a pill, a a blue capsule,
and he closed his eyes. And like Mike,
he says he had a hallucination
that changed him.
The thing that I found so amazing,
the one thing that was more amazing than
anything else was when I was on this
mountain. This is the
mountain in his head. Yes.
When I had traveled to
the very top, uh, I was,
uh, looking out over this greatness,
this vista of everything he says
he was just this microscopic thing.
He was, he was so small and it was so big.
But my experience at this one place was
so exalted because he was struck by this
feeling,
this deep feeling that
we were the same thing.
[inaudible]
we were the same.
This right here is another
hallmark of these experiences.
You're somehow confronted with this
radical shift in scale and things that
formerly felt like too big for
you to deal with. They suddenly,
they suddenly look different. We had
one person involved in her cigarette
smoking study who had had a dose of
Psilocybin, and in the
course of that session,
the idea of smoking came up
to him and he said, you know,
it was like a fly had landed on his
arm and he just took his finger and he
flicked it off and he said he
was done with it. Done, done.
[inaudible] and that's exactly
how it was for Charlie.
The morning afterwards he says he just
didn't want cigarettes anymore and they
just weren't an issue anymore. Huh.
And how long has he been off of it?
Three years. Wow. Now this
is just a tiny pilot program.
I don't think that we should
make too much out of it yet,
but the insight I feel
like is like, because,
because like Charlie has this
real experience, like it's not,
it's not a question of like
something invisible like faith,
but it's like a tangible reality for me.
It's like the closest thing I can come
to having some kind of real evidence that
what happened to me was real
with a campfire. Right. To me,
the mystery is you've done this occasional
thing with an artificial stimulus,
had a extraordinary but temporary
feeling and then mysteriously it isn't
temporary. It just goes on and on. Yeah.
Do we have any idea why it persists?
Well, Roland has a very educated hunch.
I asked him about this and he's looking
right now at getting in there and doing
research with some new SMRI machines,
but his hunch is that the
silicide man drug experience,
it somehow rewires the,
we're talking about rewiring a personality
at a fundamental machine programming
level.
Like he calls this experience a
rearranging experience. Huh? You know,
maybe, maybe one day science.
We'll figure out what's happening
in the brain of a person.
That's experiencing something like this.
But one of the things about this that
troubles me like as a reporter and then
even like personally is that
going back to Walter Panky,
like remember his list of ingredients
from earlier, his final characteristic.
Yeah.
The final characteristic that
I'd like to mention here,
the final ingredient was
the characteristic of
alleged enough ability,
which means that the people who have
such an experience claim that it can't be
described in words that is
nonverbal, basically indescribable.
And that's one of the main things that
I'm going to take away from all this.
I mean, talking to Roland
and Mike and Charlie is,
is just how hard it is to talk about the
thing that I've just spent the last 20
minutes
trying to talk about. I
understood something some
life, uh,
suddenly eternal truth.
These words really don't
match the thing. I was at the,
I was feeling divine source of,
um, of um,
self awareness that I'd,
sorry, aide said trick
of words. I guess it's a
got
larger thanks to producer Andy
Mills. Thanks to you guys for.