You're listening to radio [inaudible].
This is radiolab and I am Robert Krulwich
and let's begin today with something
deceptively familiar. Fireflies are
something that we have all of those kids,
right? Catching them in the backyard,
putting them in in a jar and watching
them glow so we don't tend to think of
them as anything. All that mysterious.
Well, they do one thing very nicely,
which is flash on and off.
That's how fireflies do flash,
but what interests Steve Strogatz,
a mathematician at Cornell University is
that there are places in the world and
not here, but in in Southeast
Asia, in Malaysia or Thailand,
where fireflies don't just flash
randomly like we're used to.
They somehow flashed together.
There are enormous congregations of
fireflies along riverbanks. How many,
it could be tens of thousands of tree
after tree extending for literally miles
along the rivers,
all flashing in sync like a Christmas
tree rows and rows of Christmas trees all
wired together going off and it's one of
the most hypnotic and and spellbinding
spectacles in nature because you have to
keep in mind, it is absolutely silent.
We picture it. There's
a riverbank in Thailand,
in the remote part of the jungle. You're
in a canoe slipping down the river.
There's no sound of anything,
maybe the occasional, you know,
exotic jungle bird or something and
you're looking and you just see route
with thousands of lights on
and then off, all in sync.
[inaudible]
imagine all the cheese as far as you
can see are all brilliantly lit and then
totally dark, brilliantly
lit, total darkness,
all of them in sync. Yeah, and no
Wessler had ever seen this site.
There was folklore,
there's stories about it,
but nobody had gone in and photographed
and captured samples. Well,
not until 1965 and this was
done by John Bark. John Bark,
the you guy, one of the great
researchers on his other records.
I'm 92 buck and his wife Elizabeth mass
went to Thailand and captured bags full
of mail. Firefly catched them,
shaking them for anxious,
fight-flight shouldn't rain down and
brought them back to their hotel room and
we turned off the lights.
We turned them loose and saw that the
fireflies flittered around on the walls
and ceiling flew back and forth flashing
random Elizabeth layer on the floor of
the room. I was just tired.
John stayed away and he was the one who
saw within a few minutes little groups
do o's and trios formed and after a while
fourth one would join in a closer and
closer together and then
finally they were synchronized.
The whole room was blinking in perfect
harmony. He was excited. The next they
told me outlet.
20 years later John Buck is still asking
this question, oh, what is going on?
Because no one knows. There
are literally 10 theories.
What seems to be clear says Steve is
there is no one firefly that makes it all
happen. It just happens on its own order,
materializes out of nothing.
And that hasn't puzzled how can order
come out of out of disorder and this is
what the creation has loved to talk about
and it's because they don't understand
and neither do we this, this is
the big, big mystery of science.
I think bigger than black holes are
bigger than superstrings. I mean,
science has had hundreds of years of
success since the time of Galileo and
Newton from reductionism, from
looking at the smallest parts,
whether they're jeans or
Adam's, whatever. That's great.
We need to understand the
individuals, but that's not enough.
Obviously we're not just talking about
fireflies anymore. Today on radio lab,
we will do as Steve Urges and step away
from the individual to find mystery,
beauty and order in the
group, not fireflies.
They are groups of city dwellers, groups
of Internet, surfers, stock traders,
even the group of neurons
that are inside your head.
This is a science called
emergence. So let's begin.
In the beginning, God created [inaudible],
heaven and earth. That's the King
James Bible. That's how it starts.
The ultimate expression of the boss,
God telling everything
else what to be, how to be.
It's a top down kind board.
What about midway through the
Bible contains another passage,
more of a bottom up
thing from King Solomon,
the wisest of the kings where
he says, look to the ants,
consider her ways and be wise. Nice.
So we start in California, they're good.
The office of an ant expert.
Hi, I'm Deborah Gordon,
professor of biology at Stanford.
Deborah Gordon has been studying
ants for over two decades.
It's because such mindless individuals
collectively can do so much that I'm
interested in is, you might say
she's the reigning aunt queen,
but as long as you bring up the raining
part. When we went there, I thought,
well, let's what's, she
has a lot of answers,
but I wanted to see what the boss and
so she led us to our lab and going into
the secret and place
where we found to our disappointment that
she keeps the ants and big Tupperware
container.
This is the foraging area of a colony
that's stuck living in the lab instead of
out in the desert where it would probably
rather be in a big plastic box with
plastic around it and build bits
of sand on it. That's right.
And so I'm going to take off the top.
Maybe we can see the queen better,
but I'm like this. I never seen it
before. When I'm looking for the clean,
when I'm,
am I looking for the ant in the center
of the biggest crunch of other hand?
Well, usually there are a
lot of other ants around her.
She doesn't look much
different, but she's bigger.
Does the ants know that she's special?
I think the ants know that she's the queen
and does it. What does that well, the
Queen and the way we think about quicks.
Yeah. I mean they do they know that as
mommy or not even? I don't think so. No.
Uh,
I don't think they know anybody. Has
Anybody. And remember she's not in charge.
He's not telling anybody what to do.
Wait a second, wait a second. Yeah.
This is different than
I had actually imagined.
I thought that Queens gave commit,
like, you know, an Alice in wonderland,
what bare hand kind of thing.
Ah, she says no, she's just a big hand
that lays the eggs. That's it. That's it.
Every year there's a meeting flight
and all of the colonies send out their
virgin queens who have wings and males
who also have wings and they all go to
one place and they gather and they mate
and the newly made it queens fly off and
start new colonies. That's how it
starts. Queen scatter make babies,
but that's all they do. They're
just the colonies, ovaries.
They don't sit on a throne and decree
anything nor are their generals or even
bosses. The colony somehow
gets by without any of that,
which is especially hard to believe when
you watch these ants who tell us what's
happening here. This is, that's
an anchoring, a dead ant.
I remember there was this one little EDBD
and carrying a big fat dead and on her
back and look at this.
She seems to be gradually,
although with some difficulty
moving towards my elbow.
Then she dropped it. Then
she picked it up again.
Then she dropped it maybe then up again.
Now she's training in the other direction.
All the while carrying this heavy corpse.
She may like it back and forth like
that for hours sometimes can lead some
objects we'll get in there that they
can't all carry and they can spend months
tagging it one way and
taking it the other way.
Month tugging back and forth on either
side of one seed. It wasn't a seed,
it was a little twig. One of them is
thinking this way and I was thinking,
oh this way, like this way, this
way. And that's all that's going on.
Well I don't know what they're
thinking. Right. I know,
I know one of them is pulling one way and
because the stick feels like something
that needs to be pulled and the other
also feels the stick needs to be pulled
and they just pull. It
must be frustrating.
Watching these mindless exchanges
is, it can be very frustrating.
I don't have very much
empathy for ads there. So, um,
the more you watch the ads,
the more weird it seems,
the way they never get discouraged.
They don't care if they do something well.
Um, it's very alien. I
think she hates them.
Not really. Cause here's the thing,
you can make an argument that
so the most successful
species on the planet,
they thrive in places that are
too hot for us, too dry for us,
even too cold for us. They outnumber
us by a factor, many thousand
in pure evolutionary math
terms. They're winning,
which intrigues her and also forces
her to think about them differently.
I think about what the colony is doing
and then I tried to think how it would
work. If you do it like that,
she says answer actually amazing,
but you have to ignore the
individual individually.
They're totally incompetent and
keep your focus big as colonies.
They do great things. It's
kind of a constant whiplash.
You Zoom in stupid to ansible, a
twig back and forth for months.
You zoom out smart. I'm
impressed that it works at all.
It's somewhere between the
zooming in and zooming out.
Bizarre intelligence appears
almost like a phantom.
I think the most intelligent thing I've
ever seen harvester ants do is to build
a little turret around
the opening of the nest,
just as the summer months tunes
are gathering. And then when it,
it rains and floods, it's raised
up so that the water doesn't go in.
So when I see the first few ants coming
out with their little twigs and I look
up in the sky and I see a few clouds in
the distance and I realized that there's
some link between the change in the
barometric pressure or something and it
really is a very tidy,
um, and effective little
construction. And what else do aunts
do? Let me just count them for you.
Shall I? [inaudible] farm.
They have livestock ants make
garden, ants organize wars,
generals and soldiers and things
take slaves. There's young,
it's tunnel involved. Incredibly good
and sophisticated climate controls.
You can start from two opposite directions
and meet precisely midway answer
engineer, hence orchestrate massive public
work projects that put FDRs new deal.
I'm talking about Tennessee Valley
Authority from your home state.
That's nothing compared
to what ants could.
Hello, which raises the question
at the center of this program,
which is how do so many very stupid
creatures with no boss add up to be so
smart.
The scientist who first really tackled
this idea with some success in the mid
1950s was e o Wilson from Harvard
University cause he made one of the great
discoveries in all of the
science of communication.
Certainly we know that creatures
make noises to each other,
sometimes touch each other,
but he figured out pheromones.
Pheromones are the key to
understand that communication of the
vast majority of animals species.
We didn't know it then. It's a neat story.
He told me that a few years back up
at 92nd street y in New York City.
One day I shut out,
I was culturing fire ranch then in
the laboratory at Harvard and I said,
I'm going to get to the bottom of this.
And the way I did it was to, uh,
dissect these tiny, tiny ass. Very
difficult to do. But I just selected them.
And under magnification I can
see that it's sticking out,
sting and dragging the Stinger.
Something's coming out of that sting,
kind of like a fountain pen or somethings
through. Bit like that. Yeah. Yeah.
So, uh, I proceed to,
um, believe me, folks,
this was the way science goes. I
mean, it really is simple minded.
It's only later when you're doing
the technical paper, you know,
when you're producing the mathematical
models and that it looks tough.
It's really, this is the way
you're thinking when you're
doing shots. So I said,
I'm going to find out what
the organs are inside this.
And so what I did was
to do anatomy and then,
uh, you know,
just the sect that I knew approximately
what the different glands were in
showing you snipped off the part where
the glands, where you suited or well,
you just distract open. Oh, you opened
it. Right. You know, and, and, uh, and,
and just the way you would any animal
alerts exceedingly difficult when it's
about the size of a great assault.
That's the tough part. But anyway,
I took out the various
organs one after the other,
and I made a preparation and
I made an artificial trail,
smeared out one organ after
another. No effect. Oh,
so they're ants over here and
you're drawing lines. Oh, gut stuff.
I guess basically what it is,
Yo Justin or different origins.
I've watched each one in churn and then
smeared it out and finally I came to a
little finger shaped organ,
which we didn't know.
The function of it is just the tiny
little thing tucked down there and I
mirrored that out and
incredible. It wasn't,
I didn't have to tell
them to follow that trail.
They exploded out of the nest
running along that thing.
I started playing around with this. It
was so effective for demonstrations.
I would write my name.
That's probably a column of 102 hundred
three a hundred answers would come
pouring out back and forth and they'd
actually write my name and I am
so that was the first clues smell.
[inaudible] ants may not
take orders from above,
but they can exchange information. See
this one with the abdomen bend under?
Yeah. That one is somehow reacted to us.
Oh really strange smells that we're
making back a debit. Go into lab.
As we watched the colony, one
of the aunts even stopped.
What it was doing to smell us when
they waved their antennae in the air.
They're looking around because their
antennae or their periscopes sounds simple
enough. Ants follow scent
trails sorta like dogs.
But if you stare at them long enough,
you will see that when these
ants get together, lots of them.
The simple sniffing talents they have
add up to solve pretty amazing problems.
Here's a forage or coming back. What's
it in her mouth? It's a seed like this.
Suppose there are a bunch of forage or
ans in one part of town and something
good to eat and another part of
town, like if there's a picnic,
how does the colony get
more ants to your picnic?
They're blind and virtually
brainless. So how do they do it?
That's the question. How
do they do it? Hello,
I'm ABCDF t with that question in mind.
We visited up Princeton biologists
in Kusan. This one here? Yeah.
What is this note?
You pops open his laptop to show
us a beautiful map he's made.
So here on the on the screen you can see
the individual paths coded by color and
ant map.
It's as if you gave a few hundred ants
a paintbrush and then let them wander
over on canvas on the
computer has software which
tracks the motion of each of
these individuals. The resulting
picture is vintage Jackson Pollock,
lots and lots and lots of
layers of squiggly lines so
you can put the food down
in here. For example,
I've got droplets of sugar water here
that the ants love for the feed on the end
points to a splotch it white
in the upper right hand corner,
then flips in the next image. Jumping
forward in time and what what?
What I've actually shown with this
is that the ants have begun forming a
chemical trail and you can actually
show how they've laid a trail to this,
this, this good food source.
This is the type of image that makes
you want to stare at static on your TV
screen and look for patterns.
It's downright eerie. One Minute,
the screen is a mass chaos of squiggles
overlapping no patterns at all.
The next is this by magic,
the squiggles of snapped together to form
a vein leading directly to the sugar.
It happens every time. And what's weirder
says Ian is every time it happens,
it happens by accident error. Really.
I mean this is really what we're talking
about is these ants probably just made
a mistake. Error is
architecture. Imagine 500 answer,
exploring a space number 411 finds the
sugar completely by accident except it's
not an accident because the ant has left
a scent trail and there their 500 other
and so surely one other will come
along and make the same mistake.
Suddenly you've got two chemical trails
on top of each other, doubly hot,
attracting a third, which makes the
trail AAA hot, attracting five more,
which makes it octopussy hot and soon
what you've got as a blazing pheromone
highway of bumper to bumper and
[inaudible]
not unlike mid town during rush hour.
Cool. [inaudible]
when I first saw the ants, uh, in person,
one of the first thoughts I had was
this looks like a small little city.
Steven Johnson noticed this connection
and wrote about it in a book called
emergence, the connected lives of
ants, brains, cities and software.
A lot of what the ants do is positive
feedback loops where they lay down a kind
of fair amount of chemical signal to
recruit other ants to do something that
they're working on and those ants
lay down more of the same signal can.
So very quickly you can get a whole bunch
of ants working on a single problem.
That's the similar effect that you get
in a way that city neighborhoods warrant
accidents that always happen.
That is how ants find food and he
says how cities find their shape.
It gets to what I sent
was called the swirl
that comes with this
gun.
When you're walking down the sidewalk
going from point x to point why you're
gone from subway back to your house
and you pass by completely accidentally
point Z, which is a new
boutique or new restaurant,
something that catches
your eye and you swerve.
You see this thing you've never
seen before and you're like, hey,
I want to check that out.
The whole business in a sense of sidewalks
and thriving urban centers revolves
around the idea that somebody's coming
to see boutique a is going to be swerving
into Boutique B or Boutique c just because
they're near each other and because
they're kind of window shopping.
What a neat idea. Yeah. Right?
You wake up thinking, well,
here's what I'm going to do in a city.
I'm going to walk my daughter to school.
I'm going to go to the news stand and
buy a paper, and then on your way,
something that you didn't expect
something new catches your eye,
but goannas I will always want that in
Sally. That's the Bagonia she wants,
right, so you swerve, which
begins as an accident,
but all these kind of local unplanned
decisions all add up into this larger
macro unit that does have
a distinct personality and
that crucially can last for
hundreds of years,
which does make you wonder because
the personalities of cities,
we know about that. How come there are
distinct neighborhoods for rich people?
There are neighborhoods in
some cities for artists, slums.
Consider a 28th street in [inaudible]
today in the flower market
we have hydrangeas and uh,
some flowers from Florida. How many
flowers? Doors are on this block?
If I had to guess, I'd
probably say about 25.
There are flower stores all around. It's
like a Walmart for flowers in a week.
Okay. How did this begin?
Let's propose that someone for some
reason came here and set up a flower shop,
which picked up a few customers.
So then a second flower merchant
and she's getting the traffic.
Maybe if I open a store like
a heady is on the block,
maybe I'll be able to pull
some people away from him,
had him swerve into my store.
Location, location, location,
and let's say that gets more traffic.
You gotta be with the traffic,
so then you get third
store. Matt works too.
You could sell pencils that look
like ducks and nothing else.
And if you're writing them all
time square, you know what?
You'll probably make money. That's
the key. Traffic is everything.
Once a neighborhood becomes the place
for duck shaped pencils or the place for
flowers, what began as an accident
then becomes a neighborhood. So much.
So if I blindfolded a flower salesman
and dropped him onto a hundred blocks,
would he know which one was 28th
street? Oh absolutely. Yeah. Shit. Yeah,
of course. Why I just, I now
my street man, I this smell,
the flower highest says you smell the
highest as soon as you walk in there.
I mean of course I would sound at
the hen shrugs reef was screaming,
yelling at me, please.
It's okay. Cause I'm mystical concept.
I really do think of it when you think
about a neighborhood in a great city,
whether it's in New York and the West
village or Paris in the Latin quarter of
America, right? You know, ask the question
like who created this neighborhood,
right? Who created things we
love about this neighborhood?
Who creates that kind of life force?
And the answer is everybody
and nobody at the same time.
[inaudible]
so that brings us again to the
central mystery of this hour.
We're studying here the
science of emergence,
which asks where does the
organization come from?
How do you get a neighborhood,
a district or a city?
How do you get the complexity of an ant
colony if there's no leader and everyone
in town is stupid? Steve,
Steve Johnson proposes that a city is
the emergent quality of the swerve to
series of accidents, you know
is always going to happen.
You multiply the swerves
and you get a neighborhood.
Deborah Gordon is arguing that if you
look very closely at the aunts and you
watch them smelling and
you multiply their smells,
then you get to the complexity of any
ad colony but buried in the system.
Both of them say is a rule, a sense of
direction, but how do you see that rule?
That's the wrong thing. Question,
and that's what's so uncomfortable.
The instructions aren't anywhere.
The instructions come out of the way
that the colony lives and behaves.
It is hard. If you had
one aunt on its own,
you couldn't take it apart and find the
substance that would make it behave in a
certain way. But you see how hard
that is? Yes, I want to know.
So when you asked her where
we're gonna find the rule. Yeah.
So when that added any
individually as you see it,
when all the ants get together,
but where is it? Well,
where is the thought in your
brain? Is it in a neuron?
Does each neuron have a
little piece of the thought?
If you took your neuron out
and lay it on the table,
could you see the little tiny bit of
the thought that's in that neuron? No,
it's not in the neuron. It's in the way
the neurons interact with each other.
[inaudible]
think about a syrup painting.
That one where they're all on the banks
of the Cen River. Yep. You're the one,
if you look at it up close,
all you see is dots, right?
You pulled back and the picture emerges
with all the ladies in their parents'
sols. But the question with these systems,
the big question is whether there is
a syrup to make the dots to paint the
picture, or if somehow the painting
just materializes on its own.
Uh, well, you know that I have an
opinion about this. It's not a,
it's not a sciencey opinion. Ah,
I think it's not just fascinating that
there are these hidden patterns and
hidden rules.
I think it's just gonna
change the whole tone.
I think it's kind of
holy and I don't have,
there's no scientific evidence because
there's no science behind this.
It's just an instinct.
I think when you look at the way ants
work or the way it's SRAP painting emerges
before your eyes, you're
looking at an author.
When you say that, all the air just
gets let out of the balloon. For me,
it's like the magic is gone.
Really? Can I think so?
Let's see what you're left
with then everything that
you see when you wake up in
the morning as beautiful and you all
agree that it's beautiful is empty of
purpose.
Is that okay with you? Yeah.
In a way it makes it even more
mysterious to be alive in any case,
author or not.
There's really good reason why
these systems would not centralize,
put all their eggs into one basket,
one supreme being, because if they did,
they'd be vulnerable. Case in point,
this story from producer
Laura Star Chesky.
I'll walk you over toward
the beehives, not about ants.
So we're sort of in their flight zone,
but don't worry bees and we'll
just see if we have any luck here.
She met up recently with a
beekeeper named John Clayton.
It's always hit and miss trying
to find a queen, that's for sure.
She's right there. Get off me. Thank you.
One of the things that beekeepers really
like to do is raise their own queens.
All you need to do is take a frame out
of an existing hive that has egg cells on
it and a bunch of worker bees and put it
in its very own box and they'll realize
that they don't have a queen and they'll
pull an egg or pull larva and start
feeding it.
The Royal Jelly make the peanut shape
Queen Cell and 16 days later you got a
brand new queen. Well, one time I uh,
I made a brand new.
Kwame was my first queen.
I was probably 17 years old at the time
and I had it out on my back porch and I
knew to come. Day three,
she goes out to mate.
So I'm sitting there and here it sure
enough comes to queen out the entrance and
she flies off and she takes off and,
and I'm watching and I'm watching the
whole mating process take place and it
takes place in flight. She made a in
flight with about 10 drones and uh,
the drones die after mating.
They come crashing to the ground dying
and the queen goes back to the hive.
And while she started coming back to the
hive and then I realized I had a piece
of sticky fly tape hanging up on the
back porch and she flew right into it and
there's my queen all stuck to the
flight tape like this, you know,
I said there's my first queen and I
killed the poor thing cause there was
nothing I could do to save it, you
know, it was just a horrible story.
So it's one of those things, it's
you learn from experience, you know.
But it was a sad moment
because they a a special thing.
Ouch. Just got a chap there.
Thanks to producer Laura Starecheski
and beekeeper, John Clayton
coming up the science of how a trillion
leaderless neurons in your head come
together in musical fashion to sing the
song of the thought you are thinking
right now, which if you're a caffeine
addict like me, just might be
the [inaudible].
I'm Janica, I'm Ron Robert Krulwich
and I will continue to [inaudible].