Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
Radiolab is supported by Squarespace
launching their new campaign.
Make your next move, make your next
move and set new goals for this year.
Lock down your next move idea with a
unique domain and create a website to
launch today by using offer code Radiolab
for 10% off your first purchase of a
Squarespace domain or website.
Make your next move with
Squarespace more@squarespace.com
hey, this is Emily Valani and
I'm calling from Austin, Texas.
Radiolab is supported
by dash digital cash,
a revolutionary form of money that allows
anyone anywhere to make instant secure
payments. Dash is digital
cash. For more information,
visit [inaudible] dot org slash radio lab.
Hello, I'm Jad album rod and I'm
Robert Krulwich. This is radio lab.
We're still talking about numbers and
now we're going to switch though it'd be
it'd be fatigued, some of us, if you
think about them a little differently,
if you learn to embrace them
and give them a bit of a hug,
wonderful things can happen. I'm
going to introduce you to a m. Well,
a nosy man named Mark Nigrini.
I'm an associate professor.
At the school of business at the College
of New Jersey has a really heavy New
Jersey accent, but what he really likes
to do, what kind of accident was that?
It was kind of a, I originally
grew up in Cape Town, South Africa.
South African. Yes. He likes to
play detective and the clues,
he looks for numbers. I,
I can't walk past the number
without just wondering about it.
What went into that number?
How did it get there?
For example, after I finished
filling up at a gas station,
sometimes I would just walk around and
look at the dollar amounts on the pump.
So he peaks in at the pump right
next door and it's rather amazing.
You can almost tell who's been
there before. If you see a number,
like a dollar 40 then you know,
oh teenager with no money. Why?
Wait, explain that. Cause that's
all the kid can afford. Quite dry.
Sometimes I'll see $10 and
40 cents and I'll say, ah,
you meant to do $10 but
you are a bit slow today.
So you'd go to the gas pumps and they
tell you all the [inaudible] little short
stories. Yes.
And his favorite story that numbers tell
actually starts back in 1938 so imagine
an office in Schenectady, New York
at the GE research laboratories.
And in that office is a man
and he's sitting at his desk,
Mr. Frank Benford and Mr. Frank Benford
is a physicist and he's doing some
difficult calculations. I
was hunched over a book,
probably actually the one of the
most boring books you could imagine.
This is a book of logarithmic tables,
what our luck and with nicotine.
So locked tables were a very convenient
way of doing multiplication in the early
part of the last century. So remember
this is before there were calculators.
So if you want it to multiply something
like a 145 times 3,564 you could just go
to this book and look it up.
So each starts with numbers.
You might want to multiply by one
new a hundred on the first page.
That 101 hundred and two up to 200 and
300 and the back of the book is like nine
hundreds the further you go,
the higher and higher the numbers
you use to multiply that trade.
So our Benford fellow,
he's sitting there doing miscalculations
and he's looking at the numbers
flipping to the bone.
He's staring at the pages and notices
something kind of weird. United State.
The first few pages were more
worn than the last few pages,
meaning more smudgy and darker and oily
as if he was using the front of the book
more than the last few pages. And
he wondered why is this happening?
Strange, not aware of favoring one
part of the book over the other.
Am I doing something a little?
Huh? Or maybe it's something
and that's when it hit him.
He thought maybe in this world
the are more numbers with loafers,
digits and with heifers, digits.
What more numbers that
start with one or two.
The numbers that start with seven,
eight or nine yet just because
his book is more, that's where,
that's what started him
thinking. So here's what he did.
He compiled some tens of thousands
of statistics that Steve Strogatz
mathematician at Cornell University,
just anything he could think of that
was numerical molecular weights of
different chemicals, baseball
statistics, census data,
revenues of all the companies listed on
the main stock exchanges in America and
everywhere he looked at all these
different category it seemed, yes,
there were more numbers beginning with
one in twos, that eights and nines wait,
really? Oh yeah, this has been
checked out again and again and again.
And it's true, it's eyes of rivers,
earthquakes and things like that.
Populations or a number of deaths
in a war, areas of counties,
stream flow data. What if you were to say,
get all the people in New York together
and look at their bank accounts,
bank account balances,
follow Benford's lonely perfectly meaning
that if you just look in at the amount
of money that people have,
matter of fact the in all the Mankins
you'll find they begin with one more often
than they begin with two perfectly. Yes.
So actually they begin
with one 30.1% of the time.
They'll begin with a to 17.6% of the time,
they'll begin with a three 12.5% of
the time. That's a big endurance.
Why was three DB, I'm sorry,
I keep going and the poor nine would
only occur as a first digit 4.6% of the
time,
which actually would make
the one approximately six
times as likely as the mine
and is quite amazing. That is more than
quite amazing. That's deeply suspicious.
I mean this is crazy what I'm telling
you and I can't give you good intuition
why it's true.
But Steve and mark and mini mini mini
map petitions would tell you despite what
you may think, there is a preference,
a deep preference in the world.
It seems for number sequences that
start with ones and then twos and then
threes. Um, I'm Robert
[inaudible] [inaudible] so what,
okay,
well this is not just a mathematical
curiosity jad no, no, no.
There is something you can do
with this information. What? Well,
when Mark Nigrini first
ran across Benford's law,
he thought, [inaudible],
maybe I can use this law,
the bus
for payroll fraud tax
return for you thought, hey,
we can use this to catch a thief. That's
right, huh? Hello, welcome to green.
He figured, if you look at a
bunch of numbers that they bank,
state minister expense report and so on,
and you see that the numbers
in the business do not
match the natural pattern of
Benford's loss,
or the numbers don't begin with one's
more than the and movie with Twos,
one with threes and so on. Then you
could say, hey, this is not natural.
This may not be true. This may be
fraud.
So he started giving lectures on the
idea that Binford is a way to catch
thieves. The only problem was they
didn't quite believe Benford's law,
which means the rest of my
talk isn't gonna go anywhere.
It is now my great
pleasure to introduce you,
one of the most fabulous people
I've ever had the name to say,
Darrow d Durrell [inaudible].
That will be the relativity. I definitely,
totally [inaudible] lead or it's
an illiterate to literative heaven.
It's like Palindromic yeah.
Itch Darrell Darell. Oh
Wow. And um, but I should say
Darryl is, uh, what did he call it?
He calls it, I'm a forensic
accountant. Forensic Accountant.
[inaudible] it means his job is to examine
numbers and figures to see if someone
is stealing. It's an
investigative process.
And while at first he was
unsure about Benford's law,
but skeptical.
One day I happened to talk to one of my
neighbors who was a retired statistics
professor and he should, oh.
Benford I have my students
do that proof every year.
He actually wrote out the proof
for me and it just, it's immutable,
which are your mathematical law.
And now it's one of his [inaudible]
favorite tools of his trade. We
have a case right now underway,
relatively small company, family
shareholders. There are four of them.
One of them feels like she has been,
uh, misrepresented as a shareholder.
Meaning she thinks these other three guys
may be stealing. [inaudible] yes. Ah,
yes. And I know you can't tell
us what this business is doing,
but is it a [inaudible]
say a regulated vision?
It's a vision that each of you purchase
on a regular basis through your local
governmental authority. [inaudible]
trash collection or lane. Sure.
Anyway, it's one woman thought
that she was being cheated,
so she's got an attorney involved.
The attorney requested data,
so we have seven years of income
tax returns and that's all he had.
Just tax returns [inaudible] yes, so
he edited them all into the computer,
aggregates them, run Benford's
and clicked on the graph.
We instantly saw NGO for
a couple of the years,
coincident with when the dispute began.
The way they've reported their taxes
violates Benford's very suspicious.
Yes. Blew out the Benford's pattern.
You mean like there are too
many nines on the tax returns?
Meaning if you look at the
tax returns at this company,
you will see a pattern that
isn't natural. Exactly.
Not enough ones and too many
sevens, eights, and nines,
but now you have to convince detectives
and then lawyers and then judges that
this is real evidence of wrongdoing,
but they've not heard of this thing.
Benford's she don't know about it.
As a practical tool has probably
been around maybe 10 years,
maybe 15 at the outset.
I'm at a conference now with about 700
[inaudible] all of you here,
I've spoken four times and each
time I've asked about Binford,
who's heard of it? Who's familiar
with Benford's law? Maybe,
maybe 5% of the people.
Can you just look at penny a
couple observations? To me,
it doesn't make sense to
exclude the community when
your same result and they're
asking,
do judges allow Ben for the in as evidence
suggest that someone's committed a
crime there?
Case Law out there that actually cite
the use of Benford's law and Daryl tells
them, oh yeah, yes, you can use this
evidence in court. Yes, federal,
state and local from the
experiences we've had.
And then he tells them stories like the
case of the CEO stealing money to buy
automobile firearms, artwork,
jewelry run Benford's you, she, you,
you're still in federal prison or
the case of the dentist and his wife,
she began having an affair with a guy
who turned out to be a mess dealer.
The dentist suspected her of having dipped
into the till run Benford's and boom,
busted.
She eventually pled or the guy with a $40
million Ponzi scheme run Benford's and
well almost boom. I mean, benefits
was an element in all these cases.
It wasn't the clincher,
but still it is a very compelling argument
and 10 years from now it'll be the
equivalent of a fingerprint.
[inaudible]
that's it. Huh? You still haven't
addressed the central mystery here.
Why in the world would there
be more ones than knives?
Shouldn't they be equally, uh,
equally coincidence? Yes. Well,
the answer is actually very
complicated and deeply mathematical.
The simple answer is, is
there an answer to that? Yes,
there is an answer and it has to do,
do you understand the answer? No.
I mean, I understand that it has
to do with logarithms and the,
and the business of doubling
and the culture of numbers.
But if you were to sit me down and say,
explain it to me carefully and, well,
I mean, no, it's just too numeric
for me to explain it to you.
Okay. Alright.
But I will now take a little sidestep to
a group of people who would be able to
explain it to us if
they were in this room.
But we didn't find them in this room.
We found them in, in other rooms.
We're rarely in the same
room that they are. Yeah.
So let's go with our reporter Ben Calhoun
and meet a crowd of mathematicians.
Ben. Yup. You'd decided to,
I don't know what some kind of a busman's
holiday you wanted to go to a math
conference. I did badly.
And what happened? Well,
I went to CUNY, which is the
City University of New York,
and it was a math conference called it.
It was on Combinator tutorial and
additive number theory. Oh, a good time.
Had by all, yeah. Goes by the,
a optimistic acronym camp.
So I had heard that if
I went to this room,
there was going to be a bunch of
mathematicians from all over the place,
petition from Sweden attending, and
they would be able to tell me condoms,
college, what their name was,
but they would have this other way
of identifying themselves. Right.
They had this number. My
number is two three two yeah,
three, three two minus three
actually. Oh, nice. Yeah,
I'm really excited about it. What, what,
what? What is the, what does it mean?
I'm okay too. I'm a three. Well, it's
an air dish number with an ear dish.
Air Dish is a guy. Oh,
so your air dish number is how many
steps away you are from this Guy Paul air
dish. So you're going to tell me his
story. Yup. Hey, you ready? Okay,
let me turn off my cell phone
so we don't ruin the best take.
That's Paul Hoffman. He
wrote a book about Paul dish.
So we start out in Budapest,
Hungary in 1913 it's spring two math
teachers have a son named Paul and he had
two sisters.
They were three and five in the had
scarlet fever and they died the day he was
born. I mean,
imagine that his mother loses her
two daughters and gains a son.
Oh my God. Yeah.
She was so terrified after that that
Paul would get a fatal disease and die,
that she didn't let him leave the house
pretty much for the first 10 years of
his life. She didn't let
him play with other kids.
Really didn't let him go to school,
didn't let him go outside. Also,
when he was one and a half,
his dad was captured and put in a Soviet
prisoner of war camp for six years of
his life.
So here's this kid at home
without other children around.
His mother is out teaching mathematics.
All the books in the house were math and
he taught himself basically to read by
looking at these math books.
And he also said to me that numbers
became my best friends. So I mean,
here's a kid who's, you know, whole
life has mathematics from the beginning,
but let's fast forward.
Paul Arish gets his phd in his early
twenties this is in the early 1930s
[inaudible]. Paul [inaudible] is
Jewish, which means he knows the,
he's got to get out of Hungary, that
he managed to get to the United States,
but he has to leave his family behind.
When the Nazis moved into Budapest,
four of his mother's five
siblings were killed.
His father died as they were occurred
in Jews and trying to move them into the
ghetto, and they only had his mother left,
but she was in Hungary.
And in 1941 Paul dish was
at Princeton University.
He was just 27 years old,
completely cut off from his family.
He was lonely and he was homesick.
I mean, this guy had no
conventional friendships.
He had no sexual relationships.
His only contact with the girl
was the people he worked with.
I mean,
that's what's remarkable to me is other
people who had been through this kind of
life experience might've ended up
in a mental institution or worse,
but he didn't.
He turned this sort of inwardness into
making mathematics a joyous and social
occasion. He started connecting
with people. I don't get this.
Like what do you mean?
Well, he started traveling.
He would hear about somebody who was
working on something interesting and he
would find a way to get there,
show up at their door and he had
this phrase that he would say,
my brain is open and he was there to work
with them on whatever it was that they
were working on and he just kept moving
mid a circuit of 25 different countries.
Eventually he gave up almost all of his
possessions and he became essentially
homeless. He had no home, he had no home.
So everywhere he went people had to
put him up. And as a house guest,
the man was an acquired taste. He
didn't know how to do basic things.
He couldn't cook, he couldn't
even boil water for tea.
He could barely change his clothes.
Your dish didn't know how to tie his own
shoes until he was 11 he had some kind
of skin condition, so they only wore
silk, silk clothes. You had to wash.
I mean he went through life this
way and there was the schedule.
He did mathematics 20 to 22 hours a day.
He Bang pots and pans around
in the kitchen at 4:00 AM
because he wanted you to
come downstairs and do more math.
So why would anybody want
a visit from this guy?
This sounds like a walking
nightmare. You Cook for him.
I stay with him and wash his
clothes regardless of his shoes.
Regardless of all of it. You
wanted him to come see you. Why?
Because he was just that good.
This was like God coming to visit
you. He knew your strengths,
he knew how you thought and it
was fascinating to watch him.
I mean there were times like I went
with him to a math conference and he was
there in his hotel room and at one point
there were like 10 or 12 in the room.
Some are sprawled on his bed,
some are sitting on the floor and he'd
be working with one for a few minutes and
then he would turn to another and then
he'd go back to a third and he was
working simultaneously with all
these people in different problems.
Paul Air Dish wrote more
papers and collaborated with
more people than any other
mathematician who's ever lived.
He did mathematics with anybody,
even if the person was a dim bald.
[inaudible] well did mathematics.
Now let me just, what's
this people can do?
This is a Paul air dish
on his 80th birthday.
That's the only one dovish by an old man.
You can save so easy cue
of Zane curable disease,
a fly surrounded by a lot
of the mathematicians who
loved him and put him up in
their house. We want to express our deep,
warm feeling to you and I want wanted
to raise your distance for you.
He was a saint,
a singer, a saint.
That's Joel Spencer. He's a mathematician.
He was also friends with Paul Paula dish.
Now that he is is gone.
I think of him sometimes in a
religious context because he,
he gave this faith to those of
us that are doing mathematics,
which after all is if you
look at it from the outside,
it's a little bit of a strange activity.
While you put this enormous effort
into finding these these statements,
mathematicians will spend years of their
lives trying to prove these things that
you know from the outside look
totally obscure and pointless.
And yet it was clear working with him
that what we were doing was we were trying
to find truth with a capital t truth
that transcends our physical universe.
I think that's the reason why we like
to talk about our connection to Paul
because our feeling of mathematics,
that feeling for what we want mathematics
to be Paul Erdish was the embodiment.
Somewhere along the way,
mathematicians started keeping track of
their connection to Paul air dish and
that's what air dish numbers actually are.
If you published a paper with Paul
[inaudible], your air dish number is one.
If you published a paper with someone
else and they published a paper with Paul
Ordish, then your Erdish
numbers two and so on and so on.
So this is like all the people that Paul
ear additions some way has touched all
the people who are connected
to him through their ideas.
There are about 500 people
with [inaudible] number
one and about 8,000 people
with their, just number two. This
is professor Jerry Grossman at the
University of Oakland in Michigan.
And what he did was he took each ring
of erudition numbers and he charted it
out.
Heritage number three has
about 34,000 people in it, uh,
84,000 with their addition number
four, then they start decreasing
44,000 that's a lot of people.
So if you go ring upon ring upon ring
and you and you do the whole deal,
like how many people did this
man in the end influence,
I think it's about 200,000 mathematicians.
200,000
[inaudible]
200,000 picture that for a second.
It's like a solar system with more than
200,000 mathematicians all orbiting
around Paul Air Dish
[inaudible]
and your air dish number is
one it yes,
Dennis Eichorn is a number two
and your dish number is two.
I wrote a paper with, uh, my
advisor and the other students,
and she had written a paper
with a mathematician who
had written a paper with my
oldest number is three. Your
erudition number is one.
And everybody with heritage number
one knows that they've got that post.
Everybody in this room knows their
numbers. I would be very surprised if Kara
[inaudible],
Ben Calhoun's erudition number is oh
0.5778 dash minus one radical six coming
up, a story from our friend Steve
Strogatz, the mathematician from Cornell,
who tells about a friendship.
He has a very precious
friendship with his math teacher.
So it's all about mathematician, but
this is a very unusual friendship.
And Chad Abu [inaudible], I'm
Robert Krulwich sticking around.