You are listening to radio lab, radio lab
from w. N y.
S.
E. N. N. P. R. Alright, so for this
podcast I want to talk about my kid. Uh,
his name is a meal. This is
him right here. Oh by the way,
I do plan to make this interesting to
people who don't have kids cause I was
just one of those people two months ago.
So bear with me. But uh, OK. A meal,
he's two months old,
he still in the Munchkin phase and he's
just starting to tune in the world.
So there are these moments like yesterday
for example, where he gets real quiet
and he just stares at me.
It's kind of amazing actually,
but it also kind of presents
an interesting question
which I want to explore
right here. In fact, you can't avoid it.
You're just staring at this
thing and you're like [inaudible]
what is this little creature experiencing?
Like here is a little human being
that is brand new in the world.
What does the world look like to a
tiny baby? What does it smell like?
What does it sound like?
And I have to find somebody who could
help me or at least begin to answer these
questions. Okay. Hello. Hi
Jad. Hi. Is this Charles? Yes,
that's right. Good to talk to you.
Charles. Before we get started,
can I just have you introduce yourself
so I can get your name right? Okay. Hi,
my name is Charles Fernie Ho on a writer
and developmental psychologist from
Dharma University. And back when
Charles had his first child at Dina,
he decided to tackle that
question of what is it like,
what's going on for this little
person as a dad, you know, as a,
as an Austrac new dad,
but also as a scientist.
So he wrote a book called a thousand
days of wonder. Scientists Chronicle,
if his daughter's developing mind,
amazing book where he basically goes
through what we do and don't know about
what's happening in the minds. A
little babies when they're brand new.
So I put the scenario to him.
Okay, meal's brand new. Oh,
when I'm sitting there holding him
and we're staring at each other,
what exactly is he seeing?
One difference that does relate to
their visual system is that they're,
the lens of their eye is absolutely
crystal clear. Whereas your Lens,
my Lens is because they're of a certain
age, they've become slightly yellowed,
so they filter out some of the blue
frequencies of the light that we see,
so we paint the picture out.
What would that be like for them?
I mean this is my, my stab at
imagining what this would be like.
If you can imagine being in
a Greek village in the summer
[inaudible]
that name Sun is directly overhead
and it's one of those villages where
everything is white. You need
the houses are all painted white,
you're wearing sunglasses and you
suddenly take off those sunglasses.
It's not bright. Yeah.
I think light is a big as probably
the biggest shock to newborn babies,
but it's interesting to consider did
that blinding Hayes of whiteness might
actually be how the world
really is. We just don't see it
in any case. Then I asked him about sound.
Do babies hear things differently than
adults the same way they see things
differently? And he said, yeah, we
think so. We think they hear Echo.
Yeah. The echoes are actually there.
Yeah. Yeah.
But our brains filter them out.
But it takes some time for
them to learn to do that. Um,
I mean the science behind it,
it's quite complicated and like,
I don't think I could
explain it now, but, um,
it's to do with the relative
times of arrival that the,
that the sound makes on the, uh, the two
years. But the brain basically has to,
has to learn to make this adjustment.
They can't do it straight away.
And so a newborn baby's hearing, we
guess, we don't know for sure, again,
because we can't know what it's like,
but we guessed that babies hear
things in a very echoey way,
but it gets even stranger.
Tell me about the, uh,
the experiment with the
babies and the brain cap.
Yeah. I described the study
that was done with, um,
babies where they were taking EEG
measurements and these are the kind of
measurements that you get when you put
a net of 16 or so electrodes over the
scalp.
And these electrodes pick up the very
small electrical changes that go on as
your brain works and
it's a perfectly safe,
harmless procedure which you can
do with very young babies. Well,
usually when you do these studies,
you can see the way c see the way in which
particular parts of the brain respond
to different kinds of stimulus.
In an adult brain he says if
you show someone a picture,
you will see a little bit of electricity
towards the back of their brain.
If on the other hand you heard a sound,
then the bit of your brain sort of
slightly further forward from that,
the auditory cortex would fire
and you wouldn't see any in the
visual cortex because different parts
of the brain have different jobs.
But what happened with these babies is
that things got very strange like the
researchers with show them a bunch of
pictures like boop, here's a circle, boop,
here's a cross. And often things
would work as they were supposed to.
They would see like a little spark in
the back of the baby's brain where vision
is processed. Sometimes they wouldn't.
Sometimes when they showed them, most say
a cross division part would be silent,
but they'd see a spark in the auditory
cortex, the hearing part of the brain.
So the picture would trigger
a sound in their head.
We don't know what it triggered in
their head for them subjectively,
but we do know that a part of the brain
that shouldn't have fired did fine.
They were hitting me w
w what you're saying,
but not quite allowing to pass through
your list. It they were hearing
the picture but we don't,
we don't know what they heard but it's
a good basis for saying that when a
newborn brain is developing
these different wirings
that lead information into
different parts of the brain,
it's still taking shape.
It might be, he says it inside a
meal's brain right now at two months.
All of his senses are
in a big synesthetic,
not so that when he hears my voice,
maybe he sees flashes of color or maybe
when he looks at the wall he hears tones
or maybe when light comes in through
the window he tastes it like salt or
something. I don't know. I mean
that's the thing. We can't,
and I mean there's really strong
philosophical grounds for being skeptical
there. I mean, actually I can't
know that anybody is conscious.
Wait,
what does that mean? I can't
know that you're conscious but,
but I'm talking to you.
Sure you are. But you know,
you could be a really smart Zombie.
You could be a robot. You know,
I can't see you. You're
5,000 miles away. I mean,
it may be that I'm the only person in
the University of his conscious. Huh.
We tend to, you know, the vast
majority of us tend to say, well,
he looks like me and he talks like me
and he thinks like me and he perceives
like me, so he's going to be like
me. But it is a leap of faith.
Then I told him about the,
uh, the stair, how, you know,
just in the last little bit,
and Emil has started to really stare
at us and we stare back and it's,
that's not a leap of faith.
That's for real. And he, um,
you told me something really depressing
in those first couple of months.
The visual system is controlled by the
subcortical regions and they're kind of
the old bits of the brain. The cortex
is the relatively new evolution.
You're only speaking the relatively new
part of the brain that surrounds the
whole thing and there's a switch
between one kind of control system,
the sub-cortical system
and the cortical systems,
but as the handover happens, and this
is happening at about two months,
it's probably there's, it'd be interesting
to know if he's doing this now.
As the handover happens,
there is a kind of struggle for power
and the subcortical regions which were
controlling vision can have,
don't immediately want to cede power to
the cortical regions so the baby loses
control,
temporarily loses control of where he or
she is looking because of this struggle
for power,
really the scientists called a sticky
fixation and it's where a baby will just
keep staring at you. It's as if
the baby can't take his eyes off.
Yes, this is what's happening now you're
telling me this is a brain glitch.
She's quite a well-documented phenomenon
and it's bad news for the parents who
think that their babies get gazing.
Gazing at them. Adore and Ah,
cause actually they just kind of,
they don't know where to look.
They can't control where they're looking.
They don't know how to look away
basically. Ah, depressing. [inaudible]
this might actually be one of those
cases where ignorance really is bliss
because the truth is you have to, you
have to make that leap of faith, or at
least you have to believe whatever it is.
You have to believe so that when he
looks at you and you look back at him,
you smile.
Because eventually that will teach
this little dude how the world works,
that humans operate on relationships,
which are these feedback loops,
which, okay, at this moment
in time for him or not real,
they will be soon.
[inaudible] radio lab is funded
in part by the Sloan Foundation,
the National Science Foundation and the
corporation for public broadcasting.
Please go to our website,
radiolab.org and you can check out more
information there about Charles Ferny
Ho's book, a thousand days of wonder.
It's a really [inaudible] great.