Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad, I'm
Robert Krulwich, Radiolab,
the podcast remixed.
So here's the thing,
we make this show and we worry
about each and every word ever.
Each sound, every breath, the
really what we're hoping for
is it the stuff ends up in your head and
just become some set of thoughts that
we could have never imagined.
So with that in mind,
a couple months ago we teamed up with
the site called Indaba music. Yup.
To host a radio lab remix
contest. But we did was,
we put out a bunch of our stories but as
multi-track versions so that the voice,
the interviews, the music, everything
is separated out on its own track.
People could take what we've done
and do anything they want with us,
anything. And they did.
And our job was to pick
a bunch of winners.
Here we are with the
results of the first ever,
not necessarily annual Radiolab
remix contests. Yes. Five months straight.
You flipped through
magazines while sitting on
136 submissions, every
style that you can imagine.
And we're going to play a couple for you
right now. Some of the winners right?
So let's just jump in with
the grand prize winner.
So one of the pieces that we offered a
as remixed material was this one in the
afterlife, you relive
all your experiences,
but this time with the events we shuffled
into a new order is from our afterlife
show. And it was a story called sum,
which was written by David Eagleman
read for us by actor Jeffrey Tambor.
And the idea of the story was to imagine
a version of the afterlife where all
the moments of your life would be clumped
together by category for five months
straight. You flip through
magazines while sitting on a toilet.
You take all your painted ones,
all 27 intense hours of it. Boom.
The story itself isn't, it's okay. It's
kind of a, it's a a remix in a way.
Yeah,
it's a really funny story and point it
at times and a lot of people chose to
remix this story, including our grand
prize winner. My Name is David Minnick.
That's him. Is that all you want?
We'll hear more from David Mannequin.
Just a second. First,
let's hear his remix.
This is some written by David
Eagleman. Read by Jeffrey Tambor,
originally produced by Radiolab and
remixed by David Minnick. Alright, try it.
Take two
in the afterlife. Here we
live. All your experiences
with the events. Lori
shuffled into a new border.
You see all the moments that share a
quality. Our group together. For instance,
board staring out the bus window, sitting
in an airport. Two years of boredom,
staring out the bus window, sitting
in an airport, two years porch,
in this airport, two years porch,
staring out the bus window.
Sitting in this two years.
[inaudible]
two years or every other Sydney airport,
two years, every other
bus. Monroe City Airport.
Two years [inaudible]
18 months waiting in line.
18 months waiting. 18 months,
18 months, waiting in line waiting.
[inaudible] wait, wait, wait. Do you mind?
Thank you. He loves waiting
in line. Waiting in line,
waiting in line, waiting
and waiting and waiting.
15 months
looking for lost items,
looking for lost and private.
15 months looking for lost
items, looking for lost items,
looking for lost items. Looking
for lost by the 15 months.
Eight items, lost items,
looking for items, looking
for lost items. Seven months,
having sex, having sex,
having sex, having sex, having sex,
having Sarah, having sex, having
sex, having sex, having sex,
having sex, having sex.
And yet it's because you can't take
a shower until it's time to take it.
The marathon, shower,
hundred day shower, shower, Gel,
shower, shower,
shower.
Okay. I would like to do a whole show
like that. I've never been to it myself.
If we did a wholesale
like that. Really? Oh,
cause you know why it's two Broadway
for you. I'm realizing this. For me,
this was like, it was the
best. It was like, it was um,
it was Broadway in a
way that made me hurt.
But it was also like, it was
also just a feat of composing.
If I could wake up in the morning and say,
I think I'm going to
go to the bathroom now.
I think I'm going to go to the
bathroom now. Oh, I'd kill myself.
That if you feel wonderful for me. Hello.
Hey, hey. Is this David? Yes it is.
How are you? Hi David. This is Jad.
Hi Jen. We you like your thing a lot.
That was really something. Thank
you so much Ella. Truthfully,
we kind of disagreed. Robert loved
it. I was amazed at what you've done,
but it was a little too Broadway
from me. That's not my fault.
You got to talk to Jeffrey tambor
about that. Oh No, I'm not, I'm not,
I don't like showtunes either. But
uh, his voice was already musical.
David explained to us that each line of
tambourines reed would guide him to a
new melody and a new style
cause he's, he's an actor,
he's a really good actor and so his
voice actually follows a pitch pad five
months
straight.
You flip through magazines while sitting
on a toilet with different magazines
about sitting on a toilet
for five months. Right.
You flip through magazine glass.
A lot of them actually
suggested the type of music,
like driving the street
in front of your house,
driving the street in front of
your house was already in rhythm.
Driving the stream in front of that one.
I could actually hear the first time
driving the street in front of your house.
If you listen to the melody enough times
and then you start putting chords to
it, it inevitably suggest
some sort of style of music.
Last five weeks driving
cost, five weeks driving,
last five weeks go by because lost lost
two weeks. Wondering what's
happened when you die in two weeks.
Wondering what's happened. Two
weeks wondering what's happening.
Really die six days clipping your
nails, six days clipping your nails,
six days clapping your nails.
I just wanted the, the whole idea of the,
of the story to be
manifested in, in music.
So you've actually feel the long lengths
of time when it's two years of doing
this, a little less when it's 18
months, staring into the refrigerator,
15 hours writing your signature, et
Cetera, and to get shorter and shorter,
seven hours
vomiting.
And then when he describes,
um, that you imagine your life,
all the events in your life
being in different order,
like real life actually is on earth. Uh,
I just wanted to cut from one
thing to another, to another,
to another and random orders sort
of the way life actually works.
This part of the afterlife,
you imagine something
analogous to your earthly life.
Reading books and the thought cars
crashed explicitly watching commercials.
A life where episodes are split into
tiny showers, swallowable pieces,
swallowing swollen moments
do not endure. You sleep.
One experiences the joy of jumping
from one event to the next,
like a child sitting in thought hopping
from spot to spot in this cut on the
earnings here working they was born.
For instance, flipping your nails,
staring out the bus window,
waiting for a green light tower,
having sex reading books popping from
spot to spot or it's crest count of money
swallowing, swallowing your eyes, hurting,
paying two lasers staring into the
refrigerator without opening your eyes.
Shower.
Well, I'll tell him
about a 60 hours hours,
60 straight hours. Oh No, no,
no, no. I've got three kids.
I can't say up that 60 hours
over a period of a few weeks.
My actual job was a piano teacher and a
church organist and I teach a couple of
music theory courses at a
two year college. That's
what I actually get paid for.
I don't get paid for
this time. It's just fun.
How often do you do this kind of thing?
I've entered probably about
30 contests since 2009 really?
What sorts of contexts? Um, well there's,
there's the snoop dog contest and
I turned it into a pirate song.
Pirate Shanti. I just had him
singing over pirate music changes
rhythm to make it a sea shanty
suitcase. It's what they say is if they
knew me, oh my head, like a two feet.
My n***a key kid, that's my
little buddy. Toss him holes up.
It gets them cutting.
Cutting. What's it like?
Mine's just kinda tight
a long way from Huston.
They to like let, so David Minnick
was our grand prize winner.
He gets $500 ticket to the live show
and a backup from Robert. I didn't,
I didn't know. I didn't know I was doing
backdrop. Just, I just put that in.
But now it's on tape.
You got to do it. Okay.
And let me just say one thing
before we do any more winters,
and this is in reference to
the whole Broadway thing.
If we're going to be representative of
the kinds of things that we got in most
of the submissions, like I would say
about a hundred of them sounded like this.
Wait,
listening to radio radio from
Jay
four on the floor at tech. No.
Which I gotta admit, you know,
not being a Broadway guy. I sort of
liked this stuff. You like this stuff?
Yeah. I mean lower the lights, but the
smoke machine on. I'm all about that one.
I actually, this and this stuff like
this when I'm writing. Really? Yeah.
It's just like the sound of energy.
I am so sorry for you because not
only do you lack any Broadway,
but you believe in techno. I just
think it's a tasted little loop.
It's a great loop. How do I know you?
Please, please.
Okay. We'll be right back and we will
have the runners up. Some of them.
Pretty fabulous critic
taken the crown and uh,
one of our remixers actually ended
up being Paul Miller, Aka DJ Spooky.
He threw together a break beat, uh, based
on some material from our limits show.
And uh, here it is. Do Loving me.
Sports and Andre.
Hi, this is Whitney
from Richmond, Virginia.
Radiolab is supported by GFI
creators of Viper Antivirus.
Ipe is designed to protect personal
computers from our threats including
viruses, bioware, Trojans,
warms and Edwards without slowing
down the computer or special offer.
Did it try viper.com. Click
the mic and enter code Radiolab
and this message.
Hello. This is Hannah and this
is my and we're from San Jose,
California.
Stitcher is having a contact for one
of it to users to fly to Seattle the
weekend of August 25th to see
radio labs live show in the dark,
the winter of stickers. Fly Away contest.
We'll receive round trip airfare for
two and overnight. Stay in a hotel,
breakfast seats and a meet and greet
before the show stitcher users can only
enter the contest by listening to radio
lab on the stitcher app and clicking on
the contest of banner to register.
The stitcher mobile app is available in
app stores and@stitcher.com that's it.
Goodbye.
Okay, so we're back with the results
from the radio lab remix competition.
We just heard our grand prize
winner. Now the runners up
[inaudible].
This first one is from a
fellow named Jeff Barr.
He's actually the editor for a really
cool podcast name risk and he calls this
one pacing about the
lab that the, you know,
the Dale
123-FOUR-FIVE-6789
41827347750
1200777777
you
okay?
I really got tuned into this, Jeff,
the sounds that aren't meant to be
music, but come off as music to me,
so I just play with that
and turn it into songs.
Mother never occurred to me that there
might be any big slice of chocolate.
There was blah, blah, blah.
There was blah, blah,
blah, blah. There was
no good.
No, it gets judged. I know will
look told them where we are.
You know it gets Japan. I know will
look, told them wherever we are.
You fucking know it gets
jealous. I know who we are.
You know it gets [inaudible]
told them. Right.
[inaudible]
wow, good. That made me think of,
it's like if Radiolab were an actual
place in some alternate dimension,
that would be like the sound of the
dead space between thoughts where you're
just pacing around,
right or or maybe or perhaps it's what
the studio is dreaming about when you're
not in it. Oh, like that random
sounds like it means random.
That is random. Sounds like
it means random. That is
sound like it means
seven [inaudible]
and of course there are other award
winning [inaudible] runners up out there.
Winners and you can listen to them.
The ones we've chosen on our website,
also an endeavors website, but
we now have, I got to say here,
the one that really, really delighted
us, we, it's neither a runner
up nor the grand prize winner.
Maybe we would call this the
director's choice. Yes, exactly.
The director's choice. So
the, just to set this one up,
we had a show about vertigo
actually about the disease.
We turned up an essay from a Burton
rouget Shea or the New Yorker who pretty
much invented the whole genre
of like medical mysteries.
Anyhow, many, many years ago,
he interviews this woman about something
she's going through and writes an
article about it and we had actually
actress hope Davis dramatize the readings.
I've been home about an hour.
Dinner was ready and waiting in the
oven and I was sitting at the piano,
not really.
Basically in this essay, this
woman loses control of her body,
started across the room.
I felt the floor sort of
shake, good heavens.
I said, what was that?
Things begin to tilt. The world
gets very strange and out of scale.
Her arms begin to feel like they're
lengthening and then contracting.
She just completely loses her
relationship to the planet earth.
Frank just looked at me. His
face was a perfect blank.
He made some remark about old buildings
stretching and settling and handed me my
drink. No, she's suffering from
a disease, uh, called Vertigo.
That's what the whole essay is about. Uh,
the surprising symptoms that
happen when you get vertigo.
Listen to what these two remixers,
these two guys who did this next remix.
Listen to how they take that
idea of vertigo and flip it.
Everything was quite ordinary. I know
we was the presence in a suit.
He was smelling solid concern.
She could tell the way he moved.
He said confidence and safe with every
breath he effort was the leave just let
loose from the tree. No idea what
she was supposed to be or to do.
She was just an outline.
Some notes on some loose leaf paper and
paper was something he knew how to use.
He worked for the paper,
capturing the tools,
a molder of material out looking
for Omni was [inaudible].
She wasn't a few sprinkles. Somebody
is, every movement is a blue box,
became her new sky. They
spread across the room.
They bled over the [inaudible] for
vision. And her view was a huge,
that covered the few things she thought.
She knew to close that overflow to face
and change the way she moved floors on
the floor shake.
It went down and up.
It was as if I were sinking into the floor
and the floor was like, it would
do under my foot and I would sink.
So can you guys introduce yourselves?
Oh, my name is mark out for you.
And I go by Demio as a producer in
the world of production. So she,
Schibsted Chang and I'm, my name is
Ryan Vinson. I go by sketch lightly.
And that's the whole world of
hip hop music. Changan de Ching.
So Ryan's the rapper on this thing.
And Mark's the guy who makes the music.
Well I think all I gave him at
first was like listen to the stems.
I think I can write something about this
interpreting vertigo as something about
love and positives and negatives. Um,
and he kind of went from there
and made all of the music.
Yeah, it was Kinda, it's Kinda, I
don't know, came out of nowhere.
So I was just trying to make something
that would fit with his style.
So now how did you go up with
the idea of, of taking vertigo,
which is a disease where you lose your
balance and your relationship to gravity
and making that about love and
losing yourself in another person?
Yeah, I dunno, I'm listening
to the other pieces, uh,
that were submitted before mine. People
would either just leave all the vocals,
basically the same and just do different
musical arrangements underneath.
And then there were some that would
take the vocals and chop them up in all
crazy ways and it was really awesome to
listen to. But being a fan of the show,
I guess I kind of missed the
story sometimes. Like just the,
the feeling from the stories.
I try to think of a way that I could
kind of sit in between there. So, um,
just the idea of vertigo,
just the feelings described in the
original piece made me think of love,
not knowing where you, how
the space works anymore.
I think it's a lot like the way
people describe falling in love where
everything seems different.
Right, exactly. Um, is that just,
I think that made sense to you in the
abstract or were you drawing from personal
ah,
personal experience or something?
I don't know. Is there something,
something behind that?
I guess it's definitely a
drawing from personal experience,
but I guess these two guys have been
in love for a very, very long time.
That's what it kind of
congressional thing.
And you could tell if you
ever see us in the same room,
you both start cranking up
towards me and then I can,
I'll start moving. And I
know that's an honest question, isn't it?
Did you, is there a real into that or,
yeah, no, there is. Um, so when I heard
the feeling described in the piece,
I was like, my question to myself
was why can I relate to this?
Like why does that make sense to
me? Cause I've never been there.
I've never had vertigo. But for me I
guess, um, I mean getting really personal.
Um, I mean I'm, I'm divorced,
I'm really young and divorced.
I guess I'm up from most
people. Um, but just, um,
the second verse talks a lot about
this unsure feeling when you,
your identity becomes
lost in someone else. Um,
when you're not sure where you stop
and they begin and that can be a really
great thing, but also can
be really troubling. And um,
when you're not sure what you
are on your own anymore, I guess.
And I guess I've, I
have gone through that.
It all happened so quickly. Head's
spinning. Trump the wedding ring,
she was his completely in, he was her
everything and she was everything in term,
but only in turn she was
Frank's wife first and nobody said,
and second she was someone who she
couldn't quite pin down the woman that she
was before she lost herself in his smile.
He was so handsome and successful in her
husband and had to say something about
the woman who loved him. Right?
These were the questions that kept
her up at night, eyes wide at the sky,
wondering what it would be like if
the Sun's light can strike them all.
She shuttered shut, arise and
pressed herself against us.
I was conscious of a new dimension.
I had a new relationship to space my face.
My whole body felt no shame.
I seem to be completely at the
mercy of some outside force.
I was in war.
Right.
Oh, you're right. That's not a person
who's safe. It's not a happy feeling.
So in that scenario, I don't want
to be too literal about this,
but who are you?
You're talking from the perspective
of the woman about a guy named frank.
I assume that you're closer spiritually
to the woman's perspective in this case.
Right? I guess I would say,
I would say I would more closely
associate to the female character,
right? Yeah. She just has these
all these thoughts and questions,
but then the last line
is like she shuttered,
shut her eyes and pressed
herself against his side.
So she's kind of brushing those away
because it was scary and going back to a
security and comfort, but we don't
yet know whether she's going to get,
you know, going to go solo. She's very
each when, thank you. Paying attention,
Diane. No, it's like it's a very
subtle like line at the end that,
I dunno,
I meant it to be that way because I
didn't want it to feel decisive that you
wrote this from the perspective of
somebody who's in the middle of it. Right.
I guess from the perspective of someone
who's in the middle of it and not sure
if she even really wants
to be on the outside of it,
but feels like maybe she should.
Oh, it's a,
it's a strange place to be at
the mercy of some outside force.
I guess. I sat there for a long time.
[inaudible]
he, it's real. It's with kind of like
humbling about that whole thing for me.
Is it like they found something that was
in the story that we didn't even know
was in there at that thing. It's
kind of beautiful. Yeah. Well she,
that's the thing. When
Liz idea was created,
it wasn't created by me because I
thought it was insane. I thought,
why would people in the business of their
lives go into our raw material and re
sculpted? I said, nobody is
going to do that. It's just dumb.
But the fact that 136 people
took the time to do it. Yeah.
It brought so much talent and energy and
end and cleverness and interestingness
to the whole thing. It's quite, it's
just, I don't know what to call it. Well,
I think it's kind of wonderful is
what it is. Yeah, it's just cool.
So thank you to everybody
that entered. Thank you.
And thank you to Indaba for
making this possible for us.
You can hear a bunch of the remixes on
an Davos website that's Indaba music.com
and they run a site that's
really extraordinary because
it gets a whole bunch of
people who love music. I love mixing
music together. Yeah. So thank you.
Indaba yeah, I'm Jen
[inaudible]. I'm Robert Krulwich.
Thank you for re listening.