You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N y.
S. C. E.
All right, so tell us who you are.
Yeah,
and I'm Andrea Navy's mom.
We are in Hopkinsville,
Kentucky for the great American eclipse.
We are about a minute to
totality. I can see it easily,
easily sat on. We can hear the CICADAS
and glasses on.
I can. I can.
Yeah, I can't look at him.
You're just holding them up.
What do you see your this
way? Is it looking dark?
Like a storm coming in?
It does look like a storm coming in. Yoga.
Wow.
Oh my God. Yeah.
Oh my God.
What
do you see?
Oh,
[inaudible].
Oh my God. Still a look.
Look up there. Hey, I'm,
I'm, I'm Robert Krulwich
Radiolab. All right,
so these last few weeks on planet earth
in this corner of planet earth had been
a little confusing. Little crazy,
but then there was yesterday
we all got to reprieve from, just got a
chance to look up. Look at that. Look,
look up at the sun.
Couple hundred people sent us recordings
from all over the place. [inaudible],
Colorado, Helen, Georgia,
Nashville, Tennessee. Kenmore,
Washington sent us recordings of
themselves watching the moon pass right in
front of the sun.
[inaudible]
the moon in front of the sun.
The moon is blocking the sun.
I think.
Oh my God, that is,
they got to see you hear these
recordings and you can help with think.
I think we're gonna be all right.
You're saying that
[inaudible]
in honor of this list, your miracle
today we're going to keep up,
but not in the direction of the sun.
Well, you know, when
you look up at the sun,
you have to put on these glasses too,
to protect yourself from the sunshine.
The sunshine is very powerful and
it stretches across vast, vast,
vast, vast distances in space.
But what we're going to do at the end
is how is we're going to leave the
sunshine behind.
We're actually going to
escape the sunshine where
humans have never been before.
Right?
And we're going to start with a story
that I've been following pretty much my
entire career at radio lab. You
kind of have to rewind back to 1977.
I mean that's not when I
started following the story.
That's when the story itself
started. In August of 1977,
NASA launched a spacecraft and on the
Kraft was a gold record and the record
carried a message. This was a
message from us to them out there.
Our story now, it was Carl Sagan.
The Cosmos is all that is
or ever was or ever will be
led.
The team that made that record and that
team included actually it was headed by
a woman named Andrew Willian.
And about 10 years ago I
spoke with Annie and uh,
we made this story that
you're about to hear.
I visited Annie at her home in Ithaca,
New York and we sat in the backyard
and your waterfall in the same spot.
She says where Carl himself would sit
and become so absorbed in what he was
reading that he would not notice a
deer standing right next to him. Sure.
My name is Annie Adrianne. And, um,
it was honored to be the creative director
of the voyager interstellar message
project,
which began in early 1977. But now,
how does this come about?
I think about the project now and
it's so exciting to think about,
I mean, it's such a romantic idea. Did
you know that at the time? Absolutely.
We felt,
first of all that this was
a kind of sacred trust that
here we were half a dozen
and very flawed human beings with a huge,
a huge holes in our knowledge
of all of these subjects.
Building a cultural Noah's Ark.
It was a chance to tell something of
what life on earth was like to beings of
perhaps a thousand million
years from now because the,
the voyager engineers were saying,
this record will have a shelf
life of a billion years.
That didn't race goosebumps then
you'd have to be made of wood. Uh,
it was also the, the, the,
the season that Carl Sagan and I fell
so madly in love with each other.
And here we were taking on this mythic
challenge and knowing that before it was
done,
two spacecraft would lift off from the
planet earth moving at an average speed
of 35,000 miles an hour
for the next million years.
And on it we'd be a kiss,
a mother's first words to her
newborn baby. Come on now.
Mosa
[inaudible] [inaudible] greetings in
the 59 most populous human languages.
Hello for children or planet earth
as well as one non human language,
the readings of the humpback whales.
And it was a sacred undertaking because
it was saying we want to be citizens of
the cosmos. They want
you to know about that.
Tell me about the moment you
fell in love with Carl Sagan.
You said it was during the
voyager compilation. Yes, it was.
It was on June 1st,
1977 I had been looking for some time
for that piece of Chinese music that we
could put on the voyager record and not
feel like idiots for having done so.
And I was very excited because I'd finally
found a ethnomusicologist composer at
Columbia University who told me without
a moment's hesitation that this peace
flowing streams,
which was represented to me as one of
the oldest pieces of Chinese music,
2,500 years old was the piece
we should put on the record.
So I called Carl, who was traveling.
He was in Tucson, Arizona
giving a talk. And um,
we had been alone many times during the
making of the record and as friends for
three years.
And neither of us had ever
said anything to the other.
We were both in Baba people.
We'd had these wonderful
storing conversations,
but we had both been completely just
professional about everything and his
friends. And, uh, he wasn't
there. I left a message,
our later phone rings pick up the
phone and I hear this wonderful voice.
Then he said,
I get back to my hotel room and I find
this message and it says any card.
And I say to myself, why didn't you
leave me this message 10 years ago?
And my heart completely skipped a beat.
I can still remember it so perfectly.
And I said for keeps, and he
said, you mean get married?
And I said yes. And we had never
kissed. We had never, you know,
even had any other kind of
personal discussion before
we both hung up the phone
and I just screamed out loud.
I it so well because it was
this great Eureka moment.
It was just like a scientific discovery.
And then the phone rang and
I was thinking, Oh, you know,
and a phone rang and it
was Carl and he said,
I just want to make sure that really
happened. We're getting married, right?
And I said, yeah, we're
getting married. He said, okay,
just wanted to make sure. And I'm
spacecraft lifted off on August 20th and
August 22nd we told everyone involved.
And we were together from that moment
until his death in 1996 in December.
Wow. Talk about Romantic Michael Magic.
And part of my feeling
about voyager obviously,
and part of what I was feeling in
the recording of my brainwaves,
my heart, my eyes, everything in
that meditation on the record,
I had asked Caro whether or not would
be possible to compress the impulses in
one's brain and nervous system into sound,
and then put that sound on the record
and then think that perhaps the
extraterrestrials of the future would
be able to reconstitute that data into
thought.
And he looked at me and beautiful
May Day in New York City and said,
well, you know, that was a million
years is a long time. You know,
why don't you go do it?
Because who knows? You know,
who knows what's possible in a
thousand million years. And so, um,
my brain waves and rem,
every little sound that my body was making
was recorded at Bellevue Hospital in
New York.
This was two days after Carl and I
declared our love for each other.
And so what I often think is that
maybe a hundred million years from now,
who knows somebody flies that
record down. And I always wonder,
because part of what I was thinking in
this meditation was about the wonder of
love and of being in love and to
know it's on those two spacecraft.
Even now in my, whenever
I'm down, you know,
I'm thinking it's still, they
moved 35,000 miles an hour,
leaving our solar system for the Great
Wide Open Sea of interstellar space.
[inaudible]
billions of years from now,
the Sun will have reduced this planet to
a charred ashy ball at that record with
Andrew Ian's waves and heartbeat on and
will still be out there somewhere intact
in some remote region of the milkyway
preserving a murmur of an ancient
civilization. That one's
flourished on a distant planet.
[inaudible]
so that's how we ended the original story
with that quote from Carl Sagan. Uh,
and um,
it happens to be actually the 40th
anniversary of the voyager probes launch.
I mean, we're sort of in between.
The two dates were probe,
one probe two were launched.
And so we were thinking
about the anniversary and uh,
our producer Matt Aronchick
called up android and again,
and they got to talking
about the fact that we still,
scientists are still
talking to those probes.
That's the thing that gets me here we
are 40 years later and for your tier one,
we're still in contact with voyager one,
we still know we're four to one and two
are we were able to build something so
well that with the energy,
which is essentially more people
than the energy in a toaster,
we can communicate with voyager as she
leaves to wander the Milky Way galaxy
intact with the message intact.
Well those same engineers said
it would work for a dozen years.
It's 40 years and it's still working.
So coming up we're going to
ask where are they actually,
where specifically are
those two probes now?
And the answer is they're in a very, very,
very undiscovered place. I
mean they are learning things
and we have never known
scally's radical. You
got Negro, the sun turns red. Elena
[inaudible]
hey this is Becca. I'm
calling from Dallas,
Texas to let you know that Radiolab is
supported in part by the Alfred p Sloan
Foundation enhancing public understanding
of science and technology in the
modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
I'm Tobin Lowe and I'm Kathy too
and we're the hosts of Nancy,
a podcast from w mic studios about all
things LGBTQ and we apologize in advance
for making you cry.
Don't you want to tell people about our
stories exploring the queer experience
today? Sure,
but I think we have to warn them about
all the tears they're going to have.
Think hydration, think tissues.
Figuring yourself out is complicated
work and that's what Nancy is.
The story is about how we define ourselves
and the journey it takes to get there
described. Did Nancy,
wherever you get your podcasts and
maybe grab a handkerchief or something.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and now we're going to ask
where are those voyager popes like right
now? I
mean, again, this is a story
we've been following forever,
and about five years ago,
producer Lynn Levy began to ask
yourself that question, where are they?
Because at that point, news was
starting to bubble up that the,
the divorce or probes were about to tip
toe their way across a truly amazing
threshold. And at that moment it wasn't
completely clear what was happening. So,
so here's what we reported.
Then we're going to break in at a certain
point and update things even further.
But Lynn began this story. We're
the last one. Liftoff. Okay.
So like in the point of the mission
wasn't really to deliver this record,
it was to go out and look at all the
planets in the outer solar system.
So starting in 1977 these two
little spaceships, two spacecraft,
voyager one and two went racing
away from Earth snapping pictures.
And so every time before your trip
reach another planet, you know,
all of the voyager people
would get together,
go into the imaging room and see the
pictures come from the outer solar system.
Do you remember seeing them? I remember
as a child saying life magazine,
you know, I was seven when
La Jolla was launched.
So this is [inaudible]
professor at Boston University.
As I grown up, she became
part of the voyager team.
All the pictures that you know,
as a kid you look at the
books and just say what,
how Knapton look out Jupiter logo.
You know, just to complete
revelations Saturn,
the image of Saturn technique
color like pink and look, reddish,
turquoise, color yellow. And
those rings just spectacular.
They could see active volcanoes on
one of the moons of Jupiter. Finally,
that vision of Neptune,
this like blue jewel,
really blue, it's all came from voyager.
We had no idea how they
look like before voyager.
Neptune was the last big cool planet
and it was the last thing they were
supposed to photograph.
After that the cameras were going
to be shut off to save energy,
but Kelsey Sagan convinced them to turn
voyager back to earth and take a final
picture. So on Valentine's Day, 1990, uh,
one of the ships slowly rotated
so it was facing back to earth
and
it snapped a picture. One last picture.
Describe it so it's mostly empty.
Um, it's, it's pretty dark.
You can see sort of streaks
of light coming from the sun
and then you honestly wouldn't notice
it if it wasn't pointed out to you.
But down in one corner, kind
of a suspended in a Sunbeam,
there is a very small dot.
Blue, a pale blue dot.
That was us in Carl sagans
words. Everyone you ever knew,
everyone you ever loved, every superstar.
If we corrupt politician, just
everyone in all of history,
everything is some total
think of the rivers that
blind they have run.
So that one indistinguishable group
could have momentary domination over a
fraction of that pixel.
It was one of those really
rare images every single day.
I hear from people who take that
Pale blue.so deeply to heart and was,
it was a complete reframing after
that that come out of a ton off.
But here's the thing, the
ships kept going, going,
going, going, drifting through
the darkness, going, going,
going. Even though they weren't
taking pictures anymore,
they were using like their other senses,
little instruments that detect
like how many particles are around,
what the temperature is.
So they were hurdling through this
empty space really fast measuring,
sending that data back and scientists
like that off where they're listening and
waiting for what was not clear,
but they knew at some point these
capsules would get to the edge,
the edge of what the solar system,
the solar system has an edge.
I thought it was just a big spiral. Has
an edge. It's a, it's like a bubble.
See The sun has a wind
if we start as a wing,
but the sun has its own wind that
blows out through the solar system.
It's very fast.
It can be between 400 to 800
kilometers per second anyway,
blows out
from the sun past all the planets
and uh, it keeps everything else.
Ouch. Oh, so it's like blowing
up a balloon. Yeah, exactly.
The wind gives it a shape, right?
So these little things are cruising
out towards this edge, wherever it is.
Scientists don't quite know
where it is or what it is.
The guys in the control room are like
pegging the ships like, Hey, what's,
what's up? What do you see in the
ships? They're like, nothing. Well,
how about now? Not much. No nothing.
And how long before they
actually see something? 14
oh man, that's like driving through
Kansas but like a million times worse. But
there comes a day I end of 2004 where
they stopped listening for a
little while because the antenna,
NASA only has so many antennas and
they have to use them to listen to
everything. So for a little while
the voyager teams like, okay,
you guys over there can use the
antennas. We're going to lunch. Yeah,
I mean it's not like anything's
happened. Nothing's happening anyway.
It's been 14 goddamn years. Ask
yourself out guys. It's cool.
And they come back a few hours
later, start listening again and
it's happened very southern. Everything
is totally changed. All of a sudden,
boom.
The speed of the wind drop from
around three 80 kilometers per second
to a hundred
instantly, like just all in one sentence.
And then everything out
there started to get
messy, very [inaudible],
much more turbulent. And
before particles are also, um,
behaving a very different way.
The fields are very, um, we are
the fields, the magnetic field.
So just like the sun has a wind,
the sun has a magnetic field as well.
The field starts at the sun and then
curves out in this kind of graceful arc
through the solar system
in the how the sun rotates,
it's create what people
call [inaudible] cart.
You know how like a skirt will
flair if you spin around real fast.
[inaudible] that's apparently kind
of what this field looks like.
But way out there, it seemed
like the skirt started to fray,
maybe tear a little threads had broken
off and it seemed to be floating around
on their own. Not connected to anything.
So what does this all mean? I mean,
if the fields are breaking down and the
wind is dying down and you said the wind
is what actually creates the
space of the solar system,
does this mean we're out to know?
I kind of thought that was what was
happening. But no, it's not out.
And it's not quite in,
it's in the edge of the
bubble. It's in the air. Yeah.
But it's not like, I'm not like a
little thin edge. It's a, it's a thick,
thick edge. So the edge is and
just a little line that you cross.
It's the place.
Yeah.
And while we listened the two voyager
ships moved through this edge for several
years.
Then something very interesting
happen is that the wind on [inaudible]
stopped
like completely stopped. Yeah.
So now we're out. No, no.
I mean this is what people thought.
But the other measurements like
temperature and number of particles,
the magnetic field doesn't tell
us that we are out of the bubble.
Nature surprised us again.
So now we think there's a place at the
edge of our solar system [inaudible] the
edge of the edge. That's
utterly still no wind at all.
A pause. People are
Connie stagnation layer.
And there is a big discussion why this
layer exist and how thick it is and by
how thick it is, she
means when will it end?
Because once we get past this. So
has anything ever crossed this,
the boundary before? No.
This will be the first manmade object
to live any star and a voyager was like
right there smelling, touching
that boundary. You know,
you only do those things
first once like your first kiss,
your first taste of alcohol,
your first time driving a car.
The first time you see the ocean,
these things open up a whole new world.
First time out of the solar system. So
when is it going to freaking happen?
It might've happened
while we were talking.
Yeah. We're thinking
from now. Any moment now.
Next couple months or three years from
now, four years from now. It's close.
Every day I opened my Google alert for
voyager and I look and see did it happen
today? Because if it happens before the
show goes out, I'm really pissed. Yeah.
Every day it's the first thing you
do in the morning. Oh, alright, good.
Like the third thing
[inaudible]
okay. So when a pedestrian levy left
that story at that 0.5 years ago,
that seemed like the voyager probes,
we're in this weird liminal space kind
of stuck somewhere in the edge of the
edge of our planetary neighborhood
and that the out moment,
that transition moment could happen
at any time. That's where we left it,
which seemed honestly kind of frustrating.
Like we did the story too soon,
you know, like that
happens every so often.
So we decided to call Marav
Ofer back. She's the scientist,
you are in the story who is
part of the voyage or team.
And we asked her to pick up
the story, like what happened.
Okay. So since then we
will waiting. Right, right.
And the stories is fascinating and a
little complicated too because this was
back in 2012 right.
She says shortly after our story was
released, a couple of months later,
so was in August, around August,
2012 but six months after our story
particles. This was fascinating.
The energetic particles
if I'm the sun, um,
dropped to some people thought, oh no
sun particles, that must mean we're out.
But couple of days later
they came back, Huh.
And then there was the same intensity
as before and then they dropped again.
It's almost failed that somebody had
open a window and they closed the window
and then open the window and
close the window. Oh Wow.
So it's kind of weird errors where
you expect the classic crossing,
it should be sudden, it should be,
oh, you're in or you're out. Yeah.
You don't have this intermediate, I'm
in, I'm out. I mean, I'm out. I know.
So, so this was not the classic textbook
and was very like, what's going on?
And there was very heated
discussions because, you know,
you're waiting to say to the public and
we really crossed the solid system for
the first time or not. And we cannot
say that must've been frustrating.
Super Frustrating.
And she says, scientists started arguing,
right? I mean there was a bunch of,
uh,
conferences and meetings where they got
together and the scientist essentially
broke into factions. Like you have one
faction. There was like we are out.
Another faction was like no, no, we're in,
and she says at one of those meetings
there was a vote. Are we in or are we out?
And I and I just felt this is
crazy. This is such a major,
my stone. It's like, you know, vote on
it. It has nothing to do with exactly.
It was almost like Christopher
Columbus, right? Did we really arrived.
America's evolved and it was just crazy.
But she says they did vote and
the vote was still well inside.
So towards the end of 2012 that's
what they thought. We're still in.
But something changed and and the
something is a sound we were hearing
or more
around the time of these arguments.
The voyager was sending back sound.
The voyager doesn't have a
lot of energy on board, right?
So they have a tape recorder. So
there's a tape recorder. Really? Yes.
I think it's an eight track. What?
Like an eight track eight track. Jan,
I think it turns out it's true
there. There are eight tracks on both of
the probes that are capturing ultra low
frequency plasma waves, two to three
Kilo Hertz, which you can actually hear.
No, that whoosh, that is just a
background of the power supply.
That's just the sound of the voyager
itself idling basically cruising through
empty space,
but she says,
when you listen to the following recording
this what you're about to hear is
eight months of time from late 2012 into
2013 eight months collapse into a tiny
clip. What you hear
are these little swells
[inaudible]. Here's one.
There's another. You'll have
those ramps. Now the spare,
it gets kind of confusing. The
essentially Murav says those swells.
That's the voyager space
craft colliding with some new
galactic stuff, so you're hearing, okay,
there is a ramp of density as you
go into the interstellar space.
I had thought that those sounds,
one of those two sounds is the voyager
bursting out of our solar system,
but she told me no,
no.
What it is is the sound of the
voyager already on the other side.
It's the voids. You're basically saying,
I'm in a new space now and after
some analysis in this part,
I cannot explain a NASA
pinpointed the ejection moment,
the crossover moment to just be
for the first of those two swells.
So if this is the first swell
[inaudible] just before
that, maybe right there
like right. Yeah. That's when we left.
It's so
we finally escaped official exit
date 25th of August of 2012 right?
Sun Is Right.
So now we have a human manufacturer
that has left the sphere of the sun,
you know, that's on the other side
in the other ocean. Yeah. It's
like I'm, I'm, I don't know,
it's a bit of swayed too to see all this
incredible data that voyager is giving
us and I want more, I would
like another mission there.
It's almost like somebody give you like
a taste look how interesting this day
that he's and booked there
living. Speaking of leaving more,
Rob says that we can expect to communicate
with the voyager probes for about
another eight to 10 years,
but then eventually they
will lose power and go dark
recording.
What time is it? It's 1133 on one minute.
We're getting close. It's getting so
dark. It's a sliver of a sliver left.
30 seconds.
It's getting dark. It's okay.
Hello. Look, rather than Leiser 29 yeah,
the streetlights I've turned off.
We are about 10 seconds
from totally clear.
Oh my God. Look at that. Look,
look up at the sun. Oh,
[inaudible]. Oh my God.
It's incredible. I've tried
black.in the middle of the sky with
white halos coming from Mexico.
Oh my goodness.
Star bags.
The stars.
[inaudible] who's Venus?
There's a plane and then there's
[inaudible]. It's still pretty. It's still
[inaudible].
Thank you to everybody who
sent in the recordings.
Big thanks to producer
Lynn Levy scientist Marav,
Ofer Manda Aronchick for producing
this update and any joint.