Oh, Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad,
I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab today things. And our
next story involves one thing,
three people. Craig, I'm Craig childs.
So you just heard I'm a writer and
traveler from western Colorado.
Ragan I'm Reagan Choi.
I'm an artist and a mother and
an educator know each other.
Oh yeah, we're married.
Okay. And finally [inaudible]
Derek Vaughn. I was a street
cop in a, mostly Denver.
Craig's a unlikely best buddy.
I mean, if we'd had
been at school together,
I would have just beat the shit out
of him in the playground, you know,
you know, we drive each other
mad, but in the end we can,
we can still scramble around just fine.
Part of what joined us is, were we
were in love with, with wilderness
for years.
They would take these trips together
out into the Wilderness of Colorado or
Utah.
No maps, no GPS, no trails, no campfires.
Even Derek and I would go off for
weeks in the desert together. Uh,
I think the longest trip we took was
a month out just, just wandering,
looking for routes.
And it was on one of these trips that
they made a discovery that I think it's
fair to say,
still haunts them today and recently
almost killed one of our producers.
So we'd been out for a couple of
days on this particular occasion.
The three of them are together and
there are a couple of days into a hike.
Where are we again? Where in Utah is
that right? Yeah, Utah, I think desert,
but rocky, slick rock,
sandstone cliffs, Canyon land.
So they're hiking
through all these canyons
and, and we actually, we split up,
Reagan said she wanted to set her own
camp and so she stayed in one canyon and
Dirk and I popped over into the
next canyon over. Really? You just
does that? Is that a normal thing or were
you guys fighting? No, that's normal.
We weren't fighting at all.
It's one of the great things about
being out together is that, ah,
there's an ease with that. [inaudible]
separating as part of that.
Yeah. And I think Reagan was
looking at Dirk and me and saying,
you guys are, are going to go
scrambling and get weird. Um,
I, I'm gonna stay over here. I
don't know if that was the case.
Well, part of it was just that I,
I was at least five months pregnant and
I was just starting to have a really
hard time tightening my backpack so that
the weight wasn't all on my shoulders.
And she says, well, she was hiking,
the pregnancy hormones were giving
her bouts of Vertigo. It wouldn't,
it was just starting to hit her like, wow,
in a couple of months things are
going to be really different.
So she needed some alone time. She
set her own camp, Dirk and Craig,
meanwhile scale up this cliff face
to get to the next canyon over.
And when we get to the very close to
the top and there's a little flat area,
this balcony of rock
overlooking the Canyon below
this little ledge. So we said,
well, okay, let's just sit here and
have some lunch, break out the pipe,
smoking some pot. Exactly.
So we sit down and, and
Ah,
and we literally both have
like the first lung full when
Craig decides to take his backpack off
and he leans over and I noticed
as I'm bending over a, uh,
a round object underneath
the edge of a [inaudible]
bolder back under the
shadow and [inaudible]
he says, Hey, there's a pot under there.
[inaudible] straight vertically below
you. I'm eye to eye with it. And then I,
I dropped to my knees and looked into
this shadow and there was this beautiful
red
jar, low and flat covered
and maybe 700, 800,
it'd be a thousand years of dust that
it's a kindness called a seed jar with
just this narrow mouth on the top.
And it had black paint design
around the, around the mouth.
We're talking about a [inaudible]
early Pueblo people, cliff dwellers,
people who lived out in that
desert a thousand years ago.
And as he looked closer, he
could see that this particular,
it had a crack down the front of it
and it had two holes drilled around the
crack.
And then a piece of Yucca twine had been
used to tie the holes together so it
was precious to somebody. Yeah.
So they might have left it there.
Maybe it was during a migration
thinking they would return at some time.
Maybe they were on the run, but maybe
someone was hiding it from other people.
Yes. You don't know who it was,
if it was male or female or what
clan or any of those stories,
but you know it was a human being in
the same position that you're in right
there.
Mm.
Doing the same thing, the same gesture.
You can see the hand reaching
out and placing the object.
You can imagine the hands and the feet
and the people in the sounds that they
would make.
They stared at it for about an hour,
not really saying much and then
suddenly it just hits Dirk.
Oh wait a second, we've
got to move this thing.
Somebody else was going to find this.
It just felt like if we can
just kind of luck into it.
What's to stop some four wheel driving
by beetle villager from doing the same
cause it's an access route. I don't know.
I felt sort of protective
of it cause you know,
pot hunters were all over the southwest
looting dig sites and that jar would be
worth a lot of money. Tens
of thousands of dollars.
At least you don't have to make sure that
they somehow didn't get their hands on
this. And so I thought, well let's
hide it. Crepe is like [inaudible].
No, I said have absolutely not.
The moment we touched that jar,
it no longer is part of that story. It's
now part of our story. He's a purist.
We, we do not move this thing, not
move it. Protect it. Let's cover it.
Like I wanted to build a corral of
stone around it to like camouflage it.
That's exactly what I'd be looking
for. In fact, I wouldn't notice the,
the seed jar, I'd noticed the rock
and I would go, Ooh, somebody,
somebody's hiding something. Yeah,
it right. Dirks looking at me going,
you and your Yoda crap.
God Dang. And he says,
we could give this
another 700 years of life.
Hell it had been there
probably a thousand years.
[inaudible] how do you resolve that?
Said, you know, we'll come back tomorrow.
We'll just leave it for now.
Oh, so you left, you left in a draw.
We left in a draw and we actually, uh,
hopped back over the
canyon to find Reagan.
Reagan's kind of like this bad ass
Samurai chick. I thought, wow. Oh yeah,
I can, I'll be able to draft
Reagan over to my side.
So they hiked back up to that ledge,
yelled out for her and the next day
she hiked on over to where they were.
I remember her hitching up her pants,
pregnancy style and kind of
squatting down to get in there.
What was your first thought
when you saw it? Um,
focus
[inaudible]
and just being right there.
Completely consumed in that moment.
And I think it went on for a long
time cause eventually they're like, so
what do you think when you hear the
truth? Like what we should do? Oh,
you guys argued back and forth for at
least an hour and a half and I just
ignored you for most of it cause I
was just looking at the seed jar.
I wasn't really thinking to
be in the position of arbiter,
but I just got fed up and I was like,
that's enough. You guys leave it alone.
It's part of an ongoing story. Like
just give it up, leave it alone.
[inaudible]
and so,
so she takes some pictures
and we and we walk away
[inaudible]
and within a year of that moment,
everything just like went whirlwind.
Reagan and Greg had a baby. Craig decides
to become a writer. He writes a book,
it becomes a bestseller.
I quit the business and got
divorced and everything changed.
But even on that day they knew with this
will be the center of things we talk
about for the rest of our
lives. The seed jar. Yeah.
The day we found the seed jar.
Do you think it's still there?
I think it's still there.
I think it is the route's pretty
complicated with that particular location?
No, I'd say 50 50
taught. Huh?
Again, if only that were
the end of the story.
I don't know. He said he went, yeah,
we could have done the thing
where you're just like, oh,
the narrative power of objects
met a blah blah. No, we were like,
it's the damn thing there.
Or did someone take it?
We got so curious about
this that we convinced Craig
Reagan and Dirk to go back.
Now they're here and check and we sent
our producer Molly Webster along for the
ride. It's half the camp
is just around. Yeah,
we've been,
I didn't realize when they were like
giving each other a hug the night at camp
and I was
there with my recorders in
their faces that like was,
it was actually like a big moment.
I guess this is a reunion trip.
We haven't seen Dirk in ages.
Reagan had said that one of the last
times now that people have kids and
families, one of the last times
you were together was the CJR.
Yay. We're so happy. And so
they were really, really,
really excited to like be together. Wait,
how long ago was this when they found,
the thing is 11 years ago. This was
11 years ago. Yeah. So the kids were,
Reagan was five months
pregnant and the kids,
she was pregnant with his Jasper
turn off the light and come on out,
come say hi. Who's now let, he just
had his 11th birthday. Me Line back,
close the door and come say hi. Hi.
Hey Man, I'm Molly. We were on dirt.
Derek had never met their
kids. Well he happened that,
but the last time you said Jasper, Jasper
was a baby. And the other thing is,
I'm just going to say
Craig and Dirk are like
brothers from another mother. Oh yeah.
Like they are like the bestest
bro Man. Like every scene.
They love each other so
much. So anyway, so we,
so we get there and we'd like drop
our bags, we go to sleep and uh,
the sleep bag woke up,
four wheel drove or drive.
I don't actually know how it goes
out into the Mesas Park, the cars.
And then we hiked a mile and a
half to the edge of the Mesa. Wow.
Basically the entire landscape felt like
they had just put me on a bonanza set,
like gnarled wharfie trees, red, red,
sandy sandstone there,
you're on this Mesa and then it falls off
into this canyon and then there's like
another Mesa and then that
falls off into a canyon.
There's another mason than that and
it's just this like unending landscape.
Bad luck. We're floating up here now.
Yeah,
and there shit, is it
just like [inaudible]?
There's no sound cars license,
no sounds, no nothing.
And is it intranet?
We don't know.
We came out the top and across when we
went back to get Rick and basically our
objective was to go somewhere into this
like canyon land down to where Reagan
was camped before. Yeah.
And come along there and somehow
find like a tiny little seed jar.
It's weird to go back because I like to
think of it like this is going to change
things if it's, if it's not
there, I'm going to be so mad.
I like to be out in the world and just
think about it. Just go, okay, there's,
there's a se jar sitting there under a
boulder right now and it will be there
for the longest time.
And, and it's just quiet.
[inaudible]
then I can imagine that the
wind going around it and,
and more sand building up and,
and it's just this really nice
thought of isolation and perpetuity.
[inaudible]
hello. I kind of want to hear it echo.
So we set up camp on the edge of a
Mesa and then we all went to sleep.
W what's the Futon? Flute. That's Craig
apparently has a flute in his bag.
Derek calls him flute. Boy. It was
weirdly appropriate. So anyway, so we,
so we, we wake up like first
lights today. The day guys,
today's the day we go find out if, uh,
if the egg is still there in the nest,
today's the day we start hiking,
we go down this 800 foot descent,
whatever those rocks. No femurs
are broken and we strap this. Yeah,
the Anasazi were some tough people
like wind around this canyon on these
cliffsides through a saddle
in the back of another canyon.
[inaudible]
and how long did this hike take to
get out there? It probably took six,
maybe seven hours. Wow.
We're going pretty slow.
The kids were amazing. Um,
but also slow cause it was starting
to like starting to bug Dirk.
I think it's the way to
say it. It's really hard.
Seven straight overhead I think. Go into
up having to park the kids somewhere.
[inaudible]
sure enough at the end
of the six hour hike,
I believe your pack so that they've
got extra water and snacks. Yeah. Uh,
the kids need a break and so we sort of
believe them in an alcove on the side of
the canyon.
What we'll spray out where it is and then
we'll get you so you guys go. Anyway,
I brought my book. Okay.
Bye guys. And Reagan's like,
all right boys, you have your emergency
whistles. Remember three times,
but no joking. Okay.
Final ascent. You know,
we went up. That
ain't go, we went up that diagonal
there. I remember it. Really. Okay.
Really clearly. I'm all behind you.
So there's this, we were slammed
up against this canyon wall.
We needed to get over it just to get
up and the only way to do that was that
there was a boulder sort of out in front
of the Canyon Wall and it created this
skinny little shoot and we had to wedge
ourselves into the shoot and like go up.
And I think getting up on it, 60 feet
don't think about their model.
I'd like to get off this plans.
I had to like put my back against
one wall and there you go.
My feet against the other
push between the two walls.
And I had this moment where before I left,
Dylan told me not to die for radio lab.
So I paused and I was like, okay,
don't do this for radio lab yourself,
just laying there.
It's every everyday now again,
hi
time we get done with the gnarliest scent.
Everyone's like see is going to be
there cause no one else would do this.
That was really hard
to spot this whole down. I've been so
Durkin Craig are like, okay, this is
it. We did that route. I am absolutely.
The seed jar should be
around here somewhere
where like walking
giant tumbled boulders looking under.
You've got like a quarter of a mile
of canyon phase to figure it out.
Just giant tumbled boulders.
Craig thinks it's to the left.
Dirk thinks it's to the
right. Anything Derek? No,
it's weird because, does it look
familiar? Ah, this I, this is, this is it.
This is this.
It's been 11 years.
Yeah, but I just, I know this is,
that's fine. I know.
Don't see the same
bought. It's just getting
trickier and trickier.
You're like just going like really
confused work that far down. We did.
I've been lucky. I don't know for an hour
and it all like looks the same but
just everything looks the same to an
untrained eye. Right?
It's like where's Waldo land and
we're trying to find Malto cover,
find Craig, get his thoughts.
I finally see Craig kind of far off
down the canyon standing by himself,
just staring at the ground and
I was like, hey, like, okay,
and you lock. I went down
and looked at what would be,
has been our likely route up. Yeah,
which is right up through here and he
points to the ground like right where
we're standing and he says,
I think it's like right here.
I think like this was the place.
I don't want to think about
this particular possibility.
See all that stuff.
I just walked across. It
went, yeah, that's all fresh.
Oh, seriously? Yeah.
Wait, what does that mean fresh? Well,
we were standing on this
pile of really sharp rock.
It was just all of these
sharp little jaggedy knives.
I mean it sort of didn't look like any
of the other areas we had been in. Yeah.
Yeah.
It's possible that the cliff has
fallen here and covered everything.
The top of
that cliff,
if you looked above us to the top of the
cliff was like someone had just taken a
meat cleaver to it. It
was just like sliced off.
This whole thing broke off the entire
cliff face had fallen off and annihilated
everything. Hundreds of
feet in either direction.
It's been totally destroyed. Yeah,
I mean it wouldn't have survived.
Even the giant boulder protecting it
like it's just, it's been wiped clean.
It reminded me of like
an iceberg on caffeine.
You see all those videos of like the
front of the iceberg just all of a sudden
cleaves off. That's exactly
what happened on this one.
So you're talking like 10,000
tons of rock falling here.
Just
yeah,
I mean I know
that's not what I was thinking.
What's the possibility?
And I'm not swallowing it just yet.
So he calls in Reagan, Reagan come Torta
and then Dirk comes wandering over.
It does kind of make sense I guess. No,
if the pot's been here for 700
years, it does make sense at all.
They would have, but no less 11 year.
Why it's not looking right here.
It was right in here.
I know it was here. No,
no, no, no. Oh my God.
Craig's like leaning against the wall.
Hmm.
Derek was like, wow man, I
guess I guess this must be it.
And there was this real like it,
we're grappling with something and I
was like trying to figure out like what
they were grappling with and Craig just
kept talking to me like not actually
about the seed jar, but about
the place. This is where, yeah,
I remember Reagan hoisting up her pants,
pregnant squatting and Derek and me on
our knees looking in on this thing for
the longest time. You know,
it was very clear in my mind
to have the place itself
gone. It's, I'm fine.
It's beautiful, it's wonderful. But Jesus,
this is a different kind of sadness
and it wasn't quite no. Are you sad?
Yeah. This kinda sucks.
[inaudible]
if it was missing, if somebody had
taken it, that'd be a sad of like, oh,
screw people. Why do you do this? This is
[inaudible].
This is gravity.
[inaudible]
Derek's gone. We should
start moving. Yeah. Alright.
That's why I think it's perfect.
It doesn't seem like an
irony at all. Just let it go.
You're going to break
into song. Let it go.
Pick a little TACO. G, G, g
c wants to hear what it
is. Like a mountain goat.
Pretty sure. Molly Webster,
thanks all suit to Craig childs whose
latest book is a Michael [inaudible]
planet
and a special shout out to Henry Ray
from emitted physics and minute earth.
He has been spending time with us, got
totally fascinated by Craig story and uh,
made a little wonderful animation
of a story that you didn't hear on.
Our podcast of our radio
show is just on the web.
So that is Henry's animation and you
should look forward@radiolab.org Yup.
It'll be up soon@radiolab.org
message. This is [inaudible].
Hi I this is her child child.
Hi, this is Reagan. So I,
Radiolab is produced by W N
Y C and distributed by NPR
radio lab is produced by
Dad Album Rad. Our staff includes Ellen
Horne, Soren and wheeler, Kim Howard,
Brenna Farrell, Molly Kenyan grub
Webster, Melissa Odonnell, Dylan Keefe,
Jamie York, Lynn Levy,
Andrew Mills and Kelsey pageant with
help from area and whack that guilty.
Simon Adler and Lily Sullivan,
special thing to Merrick Primo.
Everyone at
Naik Marker Bot makerbot the edge of the
Peters Park museum and page filled up.
That works. Thanks and
goodbye and his mailbox.
Hi, this is Frankie. I have
two things to destroy today.
The first one is a beer Stein that I
painted at one of those paint your own
pottery places with my
stupid ex-boyfriend.
It's a stupid mug and it was a
stupid relationship. So here it goes.
Yeah,
this is Jerry Miller calling from
Chicago. Noir tells me punching a wall.
This is Carolina blue heart from Brooklyn,
New York and made this flow with
the world. Did it when I was in high
school. Cause I always spend
a long time in my room and
I don't know, things
are getting better now.
Maybe it's time to like let go with
that part. So let's destroy it.
[inaudible]
my name is Mary and I'm going to destroy
a picture of me and my ex boyfriend.
I am cleaning up all the paper work from
my classes and this is sound like me
and beating them up.
This is my father's one
of my father's computers
and this week it's three years since
the stroke that killed your father.
So we're going to be out
of it with a hammer. Yes.
That was satisfying. My
name is Justin. Last year,
my life was like a country song. First
I lost my girl, then I lost my job,
then I lost my house.
Then my dog got killed,
and this is the sound of
me destroying my old life.
Thank you.