Okay. Ready? Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm
Robert Krulwich and this is Radiolab.
Today we've got a story about the
crazy power of words in particular,
60 words, single sentence that it is,
has you could say defined America
for the last 12 years and uh,
yeah, and the place to start is
a difficult one. This Justin,
you were looking at obviously a
very disturbing live shot there.
September 11th, 2001 8:46 AM
a plane has crashed into
the World Trade Center.
We don't know anything more
than that. We don't know.
This is a day that anyone
who is old enough to remember
does remember we have no
idea. You can remember where we
were on board or who we were with.
So you have no idea. Rather right.
Rather write one another plane.
Just oh my God. Another plane has jet kit
and of course we can remember how he felt.
Tell me what you just saw. Oh, fell down.
Let's go see what happened.
It just the worst attack
ever on American soil.
If you really want to understand
the world we live in now,
you've got to jump ahead.
One day to September 12th two a corner
office in the White House where there's a
lawyer sitting at a computer trying to
figure out how are we going to declare
war.
And one of the things that everybody
realizes after sort of an initial
discussion is yes, we'd
like to declare war,
but we have no idea upon whom we should
declare war. That is Gregory Johnson,
the Michael Hastings national
security reporting fellow at buzzfeed.
Now the reason this lawyer man
by the name of Timothy Flanagan,
the reason Flanagan is sitting
at a computer in an office,
it's because then president
George Bush had to do something.
He had to act and he
didn't want to act alone.
You want it congressional
approval, right? I mean,
technically in an emergency
president can defend the country,
is the commander in chief. After all, he
doesn't have to go to Congress and say,
Hey, do I have authorization
to use force? Not An emergency.
That's been with us by the way,
senior fellow in governance studies
at the Brookings Institution.
But President Bush needed
congress on his side.
He felt it was important
that we project unity,
that we're all standing together as one
and second, if this was an act of war,
the power to declare war in the
constitution is given to Congress,
not to the executive. When
Congress declares war,
suddenly the president has a
very clear and powerful mandate.
[inaudible].
Now,
the declaration of war is kind of a
dead instrument of international law.
I mean, nobody's declared
war since World War II,
but the modern incarnation
of the declaration of war
is the authorization to use
force, the authorization to use force,
what's called the authorization
for the use of military force,
or as it's commonly
referred to the a u m f.
Right? So our lawyer in
the White House Flannigan,
he's given a task go right in AUMF that
Congress can send to the president.
He really has no idea.
So he goes back to the last time that the
u s did this last time congress passed
one of these things. He does a quick
sort of search on his computer. Boom,
finds it. 1991 Iraq.
The Gulf War Flannigan grabs the text
and then he copies that into a word
document and that becomes his
template. He makes some cuts,
he makes some changes, he deletes
some words. Then he hits send
our war on Tara, a just
war and he sets in motion.
This be will during series of events by
U s drone strike in early to al Qaeda
and the wall, Wayne trapes. Hey madness.
That is basically the world. We live in.
15 members of a wedding procession or
killed by us and if you're like me,
bizarre, even sadistic treatment,
you're like me and you find yourself
flipping through the channels,
see the news, basically ignoring it,
but then every so often thinking,
wait a second.
Terrorism targets in Africa from Libya
now the U S air for drone strike in
southern Somalia. Wait, wait,
how are we doing this in
all these different places?
100 presenters are on a hunger strike
and like that protest of their indefinite
detention. How? How? How are we
detaining people for so long? Is that,
is it okay to do that? We'll just
who signed off on this, you know,
and it turns out we all did
because it was in that document.
This is the legal foundation for
everything that the u s has done.
Everything from Guantanamo Bay to drone
strikes to secret renditions to seal
rates. It's all been hung off these
60 words and that's the crazy part,
the body of this document,
the part that really matters.
And the reason that when I was reading
Gregory's reporting on this, I was like,
what is it?
It all goes back to one
single sentence, 60 words,
one sentence. Can you read it? Absolutely.
That the president is authorized to
use all necessary and appropriate force
against those nations organizations
or persons he determines,
planned, authorize, committed,
or aided the terrorist attacks that
occurred on September 11 2001 or harbored
such organizations or persons in
order to prevent any future acts of
international terrorism against
the United States by such nations,
organizations or persons. 60 words
[inaudible]
today, a collaboration with buzzfeed
and with reporter Gregory Johnson.
We're going to try to decode those words
and ask where do those words come from
and how could they come
to mean what they mean,
which is not what you think they know
and how did they end up leading us into
what is arguably the longest
war in American history.
[inaudible]
and nobody saw it coming. Absolutely.
No, but that's the weirdest as well.
Nobody minus one. Let's start there.
Maybe you should introduce
us to Barbara Lee. Right.
Barbara Lee is a congresswoman
from right around Berkeley,
California. [inaudible] hello?
Hello. Hello. Hi. It's Barbara.
And she is someone who
has been in many ways,
a lifelong activist going all the way
back to when she was 15 in high school in
San Fernando Valley because I wanted
to be a cheerleader. But you know,
since this was the early sixties
you had to have certain criteria,
like at least whether it was stated
or not being blind and blue eyes,
that would've been hard for you. I
would figure that was really hard.
So I went to the NAACP. She got them to
pressure the school to change the rules,
and I won. And she became the
first black cheerleader, um, at,
at her high school. Yeah. Yeah.
That's just by way of introduction.
Fast forward many years, she
becomes a congress woman.
She gets elected to a
second term, and on that day
there is smoke pouring out of the
Pentagon. She was at the capitol.
No one knew where to go. So then the
police officers just said, run, run, run,
go, go, go. This was an apparent
terrorist attack on our country.
So I ran out of the capitol.
Wow. Down Pennsylvania Avenue.
I remember looking back and saw a
lot of smoke, which was, you know,
the Pentagon, you know, clearly
the country's under attack.
Clearly people have died. Clearly,
we've got to deal with whoever did this,
whatever it takes. Fast forward
two days, September 13th,
Barbara Lee's back at the capitol to
meet with her democratic colleagues to
review that document that
Flanagan had sent over.
The mood in the room was
very somber and very angry.
The thing we have to keep in mind when
we're talking about this is all of this
was done within 72 hours after the
worst terrorist attack in United States
history and very confused what
would be the appropriate response.
So as she and her colleagues
read those 60 words,
there was a lot of debate going
on back and forth. Oh yes. Oh yes.
From everyone. Because this
actually wasn't the first draft.
Flanagan had sent one over the night
before September 12 2001 and that one was
something that almost no one
agreed to. According to Gregory,
that early draft had a
few extra lines in it.
One gave the president the power to
preempt any future acts of aggression
against the United States and Barbara
Lee and her colleagues knew that look,
so many things can be packed
into this word aggression,
that if we sign on to this, that if
we give the president this power,
the president may never have to come
back to Congress ever again and request
authorization for military force because
he can say that anything is aggression
and we're also giving him
the power to preempt. Two,
they kicked it back to the White House.
Flanagan took out those words and
now they have this new draft that the
president is authorized to use
all necessary inappropriate force,
which is what you heard. It's still,
when Barbara read that and saw phrases
like all necessary inappropriate force,
she thought, what does that even
mean? I said, this is too broad.
It's not definitive. It's
open-ended, and as she was speaking,
this is taking place in the
basement of the Capitol building.
She sees some of her democratic
colleagues start to nod. Yup.
People were nodding.
People were nodding because everybody
there knew the danger of ill-defined
words. You just had to go back
50 years to the Gulf of Tonkin,
Gulf of Tonkin and talking Tonkin.
Todd can with an n. Yes. To explain it.
My thought about America as
president and commander in chief
1964 LBJ announces at two American ships.
So you asked the straw yours, correct,
Denise,
Gulf of Tonkin off the coast of Vietnam
or torpedoed by North Vietnamese,
both by a number of hostile vessels.
People now argue that one of these
attacks never even happened. Nonetheless,
President Johnson wanted to
strike back, so he asked Congress,
I asked a resolution,
which they did, giving
them the power to quote,
take all necessary measures to repel any
armed attack against the forces of the
United States and to
prevent further aggression.
Making it clear that our government is
United in its determination to take all
necessary measures and support a freedom
and in the fence of peace in Southeast
Asia.
Now, it is the broad
language of that document.
Most people believe that opened the door
to the worst part of the Vietnam War.
[inaudible] the rangers and Marines,
the casualty mostly from hidden sniper,
thousands and thousands of casualty. Keep
dropping. There's nothing you can do.
Horrific atrocities.
Shawn was,
had been made that troops Carroll as
many as 567 south Vietnamese civilians
during the sleep in March, 1968
and in a television interview in 1969
when President Johnson was asked to
justify it all, he said, you
can't just blame [inaudible].
Yeah, Congress gave us this
authority in August, 1964
the new whatever made me not
sure that's pretty far reaching.
That's the sky's the limit. So
the lessons of the Gulf,
Tongan and Vietnam,
that was very much in the air in
that meeting on September 13th,
2001 several key leaders hope to
avoid a repeat of the 1964 Tonkin Gulf
resolution.
So it was understandable that when
Barbara Lee stood up and said to her
colleagues that she was worried
about some of this language,
people were nodding, people were nodding.
So there was a lot of uncertainty
about what to do. But in the end,
those concerns were ultimately
outweighed by another desire.
We've got to be unified
with the president. We can't
show political divisions.
Let's have the nation. Let's have
Congress speaking with one voice.
It was a time for unity and for action,
and so walking out of that democratic
caucus meeting on the evening of September
13th congressional leadership decided
that these 60 words, this is the version,
there's no going back
to the drawing board.
And so that 10:00 AM September 14
2001 said it will come to order.
The Senate is gabbled into
session. Cork will call the roll.
Dashiell calls a vote.
Mr Akaka, Mr Allard,
Mr. Allen, there are 98 senators
on the floor. Mr Durban,
Mr Voinovich, all 98 of them vote. Yay.
No senator voted in the negative. So
that was a sweep. Yeah. Later in the day,
the resolution would go to the house
where Barbara Lee was a representative.
Daschel had x.
You rushed the vote through the Senate
because the White House has called for a
national prayer meeting at the National
Cathedral for the victims of nine 11
that's supposed to start right at
noon. And so right after the vote,
all the senators pour out of the
capitol and get onto the buses.
I'm trying to get through the drizzle.
It was actually raining that day. No,
at that moment, Barbara League,
she hadn't decided how it is
that she was going to vote.
I struggled with it for
the previous two nights.
September 12th and 13th she stayed
up late, calling back to advisers,
to friends in California. We talked
every day, including this guy.
This is Ron Dellums.
I serve for over 27 years in the
u s house of Representatives.
Barbara used to be his chief
of staff and when he resigned,
she won his congressional seat.
You know, she would say, well,
what about this and what
do you think about that?
And we kind of talked through the,
the emotional state of the
country that we are feeling pain,
anger. We're shocked.
Both Barbara and Ron were trained
as psychiatric social workers.
So they both knew that when a person
is feeling all of those things,
it's generally better to do nothing. Yeah.
Psychology One oh one you don't make
decisions when you're morning afraid.
On the other hand, I believe
you know in unity too,
I want to be unified with the president
when the country is under attack.
I understood and he didn't tell me.
He didn't say which way I should vote,
but I did say to her,
Barbara, however you vote,
I will always respect you. You will always
be friend. You will always be family.
So at that moment with the memorial
service about to start in a few hours till
the House vote,
Barbara Lee was at the capitol that was
in the cloak room and since she wasn't
sure how she was going to vote, she
planned to skip the memorial service.
She wanted to stay. She wanted to think,
and then I don't know what it was.
May have been the spirit
move in me, I don't know.
But at the very last minute
she was drinking actually
a can of Ginger Ale at the
time. I said, I think I'm
going to go and I just ran out.
I probably was the last one on the bus.
I had the can of Ginger Ale in my hand
and ran down the steps and got on the
bus. She got to the Cathedral.
The House buses arrived about 30
minutes or so before the opening.
And so for, for 30 minutes,
she's in the cathedral about halfway
back listening to the Oregon,
thinking about the families
in those who were killed.
There are people around her who are
sort of whispering the pain and anguish.
The few people who are crying. I said,
I gotta pray over this. And
she's just wrestling with her boat.
[inaudible]
her heart is saying one thing, this is
too broad and her head is saying unity.
How is it that you can be against
the president at this point?
[inaudible]
speaking of the president, eventually
President Bush takes the podium.
We are here in the
middle hour of our grief.
Yes, three days removed from these
events. Americans do not yet have
the distance of history,
but our responsibility to
history is already clear
to answer these attacks
and rid the world of evil.
And then as soon as
President Bush steps down,
everyone in the congregation stands up.
[inaudible]
and, and they, they sing the
battle hymn of the republic
[inaudible]
which is a very powerful,
a very moving, um,
piece of music,
but it's not the sort of thing that is
typically sung at a memorial service.
It's a, it's a very forward
and almost aggressive sounding.
Has the phrase terrible with sewer. Yeah.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
Oh my God.
It was not quite what I
expected in a memorial service.
But the second speaker,
a reverend by the name of Nathan Baxter
got up and he gave a reading from
Jeremiah 31
when ancient Israel's suffered the
excruciating pain and tragedy of militant
aggression and destruction.
Hearing that all over again takes me
right back there and I remember, oh,
voices heard in Ramo
lamenting and better weeping,
weeping Rachel weeping for her children,
weeping for her children when
he spoke. That's when, to me,
it was the memorial. And
then that Assurant, he,
he started to pray
for the healing of our grief stricken
hearts for the souls and sacred memory of
those who have been lost.
And he said something that
really struck Barbara Lee.
Let us also pray for
divine wisdom. He said,
as we ask that as we act,
we've not become the evil we deploy
that evil that we deplore.
When he said that I became very,
it was the sense of peace
and calm came over me.
Uh,
and Barbara Lee says it was right. Yeah.
[inaudible]
but she knew what she'd do.
The clerk report the title House Joint
Resolution 64 joint resolution to
authorize the use of United States army.
Later that evening, the house
opens up its debate on the AUMF
speaker.
I rise in support of this resolution
which authorizes the president to use all
force necessary
Sarah and congressperson after
congressperson. Mr Speaker stands up.
I rise in support of this
resolution that's just bigger.
I rise tonight to fully
endorse and authorize the use
of force one after another
or I rise in support of the authorization.
I rise today in support
of this resolution.
We will rally behind our president
16 in a row until Joel Wellman from
California is recognized for a minute
and a half. We get to Barbara Lee,
Mr Speaker members I rise today. Really
what that [inaudible] very heavy heart,
one that is filled with sorrow for the
families and the loved ones who were
killed and injured this week.
Only the most foolish and the most cows
would not understand the grief that has
really gripped our people and
millions across the world.
[inaudible]
I have agonized over this vote,
but I came to grips with it today and
I came to grips with opposing this
resolution during the very painful
yet very beautiful memorial service
as a member of the clergy
so eloquently said,
as we act,
let us not become the evil that we deplore
just after the vote,
Barbara Lee says she was in the cloak
room again and she starts getting accosted
by colleagues. All of these friends
are coming up to her and saying,
you've got to go back. You.
You cannot vote this way.
As I brought changing my vote, one
of them actually said to her, look,
you've done so much on HIV.
You've done so much on aids.
This vote is going to take you
out. Think of the bigger picture.
They are saying, you're dead.
Yeah, but that's the right vote.
I'm not going to give any president the
authority to go to war and we don't know
when we're doing. You know, the only
congress can declare a war. Yeah.
It helped me on this guys, uh,
has the houseboat. Uh, okay.
The house is just now finished that boat
and uh,
we see one no vote or the final
vote for the house was 420 to one.
We know what's a democrat. We don't
yet know who will figure that out.
Well in a moment or so,
but that vote is now. Yep.
Barbara Lee was the only person in the
Senate or the house to cast a no vote.
That must've been a very lonely moment,
to be perfectly honest with you.
I said some prayers for my friend.
This was the right thing to do.
And you know, boats like this,
you have to be ready to,
to pay the consequences.
Over the next few weeks and months,
her office was inundated with letters.
Barbara Lee, you are a traitor and a
disgrace to the office that you hold.
You can find all these letters
archived at Mills College.
You weren't played on American society,
terrorist yourself. So much hatred.
I don't know why you decided to place
yourself into the camp of terrorists.
Those attacks came and they came
and they came. Septate head line,
death threats. No, off to hell with
you. You Benedict. Arnold wanted beans.
So I had to have security
day and night up yours.
Thanks for supporting the top hand.
Hey Hanway proper Ellie, what are you,
what do you believe in?
If you go to Mills College in
Oakland and we sent a reporter there,
you will find 60,000 letters. They're
not all negative but most are killed.
But Congressman Lisa,
she never faltered because right after
the vote and she was in her office,
my dad called me, lieutenant colonel
retired in the army. He said,
I'm really proud of you. You know,
and my dad had been in Korea
and World War II and he,
he sees it the way I see it because I
really wasn't sure what he was saying
cause you know, I really wasn't
sure which you thought. All right,
Daddy's proud of me.
[inaudible]
now we should note that Barbara
Lee is still a congress woman.
She did not pay the
price for that no vote.
And whenever you think of of her vote,
whether you think it was the right
thing to do with the wrong thing to do,
what is interesting to me is that as we're
sitting here looking back on 12 years
of war,
she was sitting there 12 years ago looking
forward and maybe she saw something
about how this would play out,
but how these, these words,
these 60 words would
start to grow and expand.
That's next
[inaudible].
This is Gregory Johnson. My
name is Benjamin [inaudible].
Radiolab is supported in part than the
national 90 nomination and the Alfred p
Sloan Foundation in handling public
understanding of science and technology in
the modern world. More
information about Sloan and
[inaudible] dot org and this message
[inaudible] on the Eiffel Tower.
[inaudible]
will you NYC studios presents a special
directors cut of the orbiting human
circus.
We invite you to try new and
exciting form of audio storytelling.
The Guardian call it addictive hypnotic,
one of the best podcast of the year.
If Diane, John Cameron Mitchell,
Julian coster and Tim Robbins,
and featuring Mandy
Patinkin and many more,
listen and subscribe to the orbiting
human circus wherever you get your
podcasts.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad, I'm
Robert Krulwich, Radiolab,
and today 60 words is the collaboration
with buzz feed and report or Gregory
Johnson.
The story is based on a,
an article that Gregory wrote about the
60 simple words that have really defined
American counter terrorism
for more than a decade.
It's called the authorization for use of
military force that shortened do a u m
F and it was passed by Congress three
days after September 11th and here it is
again read by Senator John McCain,
which says the president is authorized
to use all necessary inappropriate force
against those nations organizations
or persons. He determines planned,
authorized, committed,
or aided the terrorist attacks that
occurred on September 11 2001 are harbored
such organizations or persons in
order to prevent any future action of
international terrorism against the United
States by such nations organizations.
Sure.
All right, so why would we be
looking at that boring ass sentence?
He seems seamless almost of
saying it. Yeah, he does.
Can I just be honest with
you for a second? Yeah, yeah.
I generally move through the world
with the assumption which is,
which has been proven over
and over again to be true.
That I don't know how the world works.
Like somehow I missed that
day at school or something.
Are you referring to
something specific like a no,
I'm free to a general sense that somehow
like Oz is out there behind the curtain
pulling levers and I'm just always going
to be stuck on this side, you know?
Yeah. I think it's what motivates
the show for me. Is it like I just,
I feel kind of stupid most of the time
and these shows are a way to engage the
world and really examine
the world. Right, exactly.
And when it comes to these matters of
national security, I really feel clueless.
And so when I read Gregory's article, uh,
I felt like I understood something
crucial for the first time.
But the way words actually
operate in the world,
because like again, this sentence,
this totally boring sentence,
this is the legal foundation for
everything that the u s has done.
Everything from Guantanamo
Bay to drone strikes
to secret renditions to seal rates.
It's all been hung off. These 60 words.
One lawyer who was in the Bush
administration said, look,
this sentence is like a Christmas tree.
All sorts of things have been
hung off of this. But how, how?
Cause you read the thing and you don't
see any mention of Guantanamo Bay in
those 60 words. It
doesn't mention detention.
It doesn't mention drone strikes.
It doesn't mention drone strikes
against American citizens. You guys.
So that guy. So one of the first folks
we call to help us decode this. That's a,
that's John Bellinger.
I served as the [inaudible] Sir for the
National Security Council from 2001 to
2005 and as the legal advisor for the
Department of state from 2005 to 2009,
you can't do any speed dating
within with a credential like that,
cause the date will be over yet. That's
my congressional testimony voice.
And we asked them like, okay, so a
detention isn't anywhere in this document.
So how do you read detention
from these 60 words?
The argument with which I am comfortable
as illegal matter is he says,
if you go eight words into those 60
words and you get to the phrase all
necessary and appropriate force.
Oh, necessary, right? Yeah.
You got to ask yourself, what is force?
What does that mean? What do you do?
You know what for us is, if I punch you
in the face, that's the musing for it.
That's one kind of force can
use force to kill people. Uh,
but a lesser use of
force is to detain them.
Detention is simply lesser included. Uh,
and the use of force that comes
naturally in a military operation.
It's like a subset of force basically.
So if you're authorized to
use force to kill people,
you are also by default authorized
to use force to detain them,
essentially to knock them out of the
battle in other ways and that that forces
both necessary and it's appropriate.
And the courts have upheld that.
So that one word force, that is
how you justifying Guantanamo Bay,
all the controversy surrounding
Guantanamo Bay continues.
The authorization to use military
force act has happened at military
commissions. At this,
I've been the legal basis for
the detention of thousands
of individuals and many
of them have been detained for more than
10 years. None have ever been charged.
And the words detention
are never mentioned.
Okay. So that's the tension.
If it gets even trickier,
if you go just a few
words past all necessarily
inappropriate force to what you
get to the mention of the enemy, who the
forest is supposed to be used against.
That's right. And it seems to
be very limited language. Oh,
you mean we can't shoot everybody or
anybody? No, only the people who planned,
authorized, committed,
or aided the terrorist attacks that
occurred on September 11 2001 oak harbor
sounds much more, it sounds very
much tethered to nine 11 right? Yeah.
Which is why a lot of congress
men and women voted for it.
Joe Biden on the day of
the vote, September 14th,
2001 he says,
look, people don't freak
out about this language.
It's relates to the incident and
there's broad authority related to the
incident. It does not relate
to all terrorism every place,
because we're just
talking about all kind of
did this and the Taliban who
have harbored them, right? Nope.
Not necessarily. Gregory Johnson. Again,
over time what's happened is there's
been this other sort of catchall category
that has been read into these 60 words,
even though it appears
nowhere in these 60 words,
and that catch all category is
associated forces. Associated Forces.
Yeah. What we've been calling these
61st and 62nd word wrestle time.
It is special and few define
the enemy as al-Qaida,
the Taliban and associated forces.
It's a whole different ballgame. Yeah.
So when you read those, those,
all those words that did not include the
phrase associated forces is nowhere in
the text. So where does who then,
why could people cite something
that isn't in the deck?
This is one of the enduring
mysteries of, of this.
So the earliest example that we could
find of those two words is in a 2000 and
memo from
Deputy Secretary of Defense,
Paul Wolfowitz. He defines
the enemy as al-Qaida,
the Taliban and associated forces.
But the truth is it may have just
been there from the beginning.
What do you mean?
Because according to Ben Witness
from the Brookings Institution,
there is a concept in the laws
of war called co belligerency.
It's the idea that if you're at war with
person a and person B is on personajes
side in the war, you're also
legally at war with person B. Makes
perfect sense. If you think of
it in traditional war terms,
cause like we're at war with
Germany, Italy joins their side.
So by default we're at war with Italy
too, right? So just transpose out here.
If we're at war with this group called
al Qaeda and a certain set of groups that
aren't them join the war on al Qaeda side,
then you are legally at war with them.
If you don't think about that too hard,
it is crystal clear.
But then the question that has arisen
over time is how broad do you make that
that circle? Cause the problem
obviously is that we're,
we're not talking about nation states
anymore. We're talking about groups. So,
okay.
How close does the link to all Chi Eta
and the people who carried out September
11th have to be,
so if you have someone who's connected
to someone who's connected to someone
who's connected to someone
who is connected to September
11 is that enough or is
it only three lakes or can you
be an associate and an associate?
Uh,
no, we can't exactly know how broadly
the Obama and Bush administrations have
defined those words. And we'll
talk about why in a second.
But you just have to
look at the news, right?
And you could see that like we started
with a war that was in Afghanistan and
then spread to a lot of different
places. Pakistan, Libya, Somalia,
Yemen. Yeah.
And in Yemen there is a lot of debate
and a lot of discussion about like,
is this legal, does this have anything
to do with September 11th anymore?
Cause now the group in Yemen,
all kid in the Arabian peninsula,
which is a group that was first formed
in 2009 they have their own hierarchy and
their own structure.
And it's not clear how
and in what fashion.
They take orders from either
Osama bin Laden, why he,
it's still alive or now
I am an [inaudible].
So does this make them an associated
force or does it make them part of Al
Qaeda? The answer, at least on good
morning everyone. It is Friday,
September 30th, 2011 market
down on your calendar.
Denver 30th 2011 seemed to be, yes.
When the u s assassinated
two members of the group,
this is not confirmed yet,
but it could very well have been
a u s Predator drone strike.
That is a u s government attack.
Pretend to put all this in context
between 2002 and 2014 according to some
estimates,
there've been about 65 drone strikes
in Yemen killing about 400 people.
So much hinges on how you define those
words. So much is in the definition.
I asked the Pentagon, I said, who?
What are the list of associated forces?
So all Chi Eta. Yes, U s is a war. That's
clear. What about the other groups?
Al Shabaab, al Qaeda in Iraq. I'll kite in
the Islamic McGrath armed Islamic group.
I would say of Jemiah as
Amelia Brotherhood of this
brotherhood of that who?
Who are these groups? Who
is the U S at war with?
And the Pentagon emailed me back and
they said the list is classified enough
republican release. Wait, so we, who
we are at, we're with, we don't know.
I wait. So you're saying when
you approached the Pentagon,
did they say that they will not tell
you the names of the people were at war
against? Well, maybe they shouldn't.
It'd be that valuable. Well,
don't you want to know as a citizen
of America who were fighting?
On the other hand, do
I want to know as the,
as if the United States has
determined that I am dangerous to it.
If it announces, then that would
give me a certain amount of, uh,
notice which I may perhaps would be
disadvantageous to the United States.
It could also though act as a
disincentive for you to take action maybe,
but maybe not. Maybe they will
just get quieter, more dangerous.
I mean it's true. There
might be reasons for this.
They have not wanted to provide
a public list because they,
this is John Bellinger again.
One, the groups move all the time.
And so a few say, well these
were associated groups.
While then certain people just moved from
Group A to group B and they also want
to leave these different groups guessing,
but it still raises democratic concerns
if the American people don't really know
who the executive branch
believes is covered by the
AUMF in a democracy and in a
representative democracy
that has to be weighed out.
Should the citizens of the United States
know who it is that the United States
is targeting for death around the world,
who it is that the United States
is technically at war with?
Should war be a decision that the citizens
of a democracy of a representative
democracy have a say?
Well, we're a representative
democracy as you just said.
So I'm assuming that the chairman
of the House intelligence committee,
he knows every item on that list.
I'm not so sure. Morning everybody.
The committee meets today to receive
testimony on the law of armed conflict.
One of the more interesting Senate
hearings took place in early 2013
including the status of
the 2001 authorization for
the use of military force.
The AUMF,
the Senate Armed Services Committee.
Um, Senator Carl Levin of Michigan,
Chairman of the committee, Senator
McCain is on the committee,
like to welcome our witnesses.
And Gregory says the senators call the
couple of Defense Department officials to
answer questions. Members committee,
thank you for the opportunity to testify
about the legal framework for the u s
military operations to defend our nation.
Cause they wanted to know like now
that we're 12 years into this war,
how are you using this document?
Does it need to be changed?
So the Department of defense officials,
and there were four of
them came and said, look,
I believe that existing authorities
are adequate for this armed conflict.
Don't revisit this sentence. Don't
repeal it. This sentence is sufficient.
It gives us all the power that
we need against Okada, yeah.
And associated forces.
And as they're laying out their
case, they say those two words,
associated force, associated
forces and associated forces,
associated forces and associated force
and associated forces and associated
forces and they were associated forces,
associated force and associated forces
instead of just nodding along. A lot of
the senators were like, what gentlemen?
I've only been here five months,
but this is the most astounding and most
astoundingly disturbing hearing that
I've been to since I've been here.
You guys have essentially rewritten
the constitution here today.
That's Angus king,
independent senator from Maine
and you keep using the
term associated forces.
You use it 13 times in your statement
that is not in the AUMF and you said at
one point it suits us very well.
I assume it does suit you
very well because you're
rating it to cover everything
and anything.
But one of the most striking moments
of this hearing is when the head of the
committee, Senator Carl Levin turns to
one of the DOD officials and asks him,
is there a list
now there, is there an existing list of
groups that are affiliated with al-Qaida
senator there? I'm not
sure there's enlist per se.
I'm very familiar with the organizations
that we do consider a right now are
affiliated with al Qaeda and I could
provide you that. Listen, would you,
would you give us that list?
Yes sir. We can do that.
And when you add or subtract names
from that list, would you let us know?
We can do that as well
Mr Chairman to queue.
Let me just see if I understand what you
just said at a committee hearing. Yeah.
Say U S senator asks specifically,
so who's on the list of people
we were allowed to kill, right.
That suggested that the
Senate Arms Services Committee
who had oversight really
had no idea she pays one or like alright,
if we don't have any idea who
we're at war with in the Senate,
arms services committee doesn't seem
to have any idea. Then who does? Well,
one of the things that became clear to
me as I was reporting on this story was
that many of the people who are making
these decisions but had never been
elected by anyone to any position and
they were the ones who were making the
decision, not the elected
represented. And so who are they
going to be in YC right
thing? I guess so. Yeah. Yeah.
So we were rooting around for awhile
looking for an answer to that question
until we found this guy.
This is Daniel Kleidman.
He's a journalist and I've
covered national security, uh,
and counter terrorism for many years
and based on hundreds of confidential
interviews that became
his book killer capture.
He was able to paint a picture for us
of who makes these decisions and how he
told us about these meetings. You say
it's the s T v s meetings. What are they?
Who's in the room? How
did the events unfold?
Well, these are the, they called them, uh,
civets meetings in the
vernacular of the bureaucracy.
It stands for secure video
teleconference meetings.
You described them as a sort of a
massive top secret Google hangout where
literally hundreds
of people from throughout the national
security bureaucracy login to decide
who's on the list and who isn't and
who should live and who should die.
You said literally hundreds,
literally hundreds of people. Now,
many of them are backbenchers.
They're not participating in the call,
but they're taking notes before
they get together. In this meeting.
Many of the folks at this meeting,
he says they're given a little packets
of information on each targets.
They call them baseball cards because
they sort of look like you got a picture
and some stats like
Yogi Berra on one side,
and then you got his batting average
and his hometown on the back,
the terrorist equivalent of all
of that. So who is this person?
Where does he ranked and what kinds of
operations has he been involved in in the
past? Eventually a general will
come on the screen and say,
here's our target objective Akron.
For some reason he says they always refer
to the targets by the name of American
cities. Objective. Toledo general
might say, target is in Yemen.
We have a drone over our head, there's
an opportunity to kill this person.
Can we legally do it? And
the fascinating thing,
although maybe it won't
come as much of a surprise,
is that the people he's making this
pitch to are not generals, but lawyers,
Aaron lawyers everywhere. That is
just a basic fact of modern warfare.
Says John Bellinger, you
know, have lawyers on the
ground with artillery units,
10 commanders, lawyers in
Kevlar, lawyers and helicopters.
They are lawyers really
almost behind every bomb,
just lawyers everywhere. And that's
a very good thing. That's Harold Koh.
He was the top lawyer at the
State Department from 2009
to 2013 because it means
that we're not just shooting away at
people willy nilly or because we're angry
at them or anything. It's a considered
careful decision. Now, Harold Co Cordie,
the Dan Klaban's reporting was in those
civets meetings and he would often be
the one to answer the general's questions.
Can we legally kill this person?
So we asked him like if lawyers are now
the ones deciding who we are at war with
and who we aren't, how do you
do it and unfortunately for us,
I don't know they're going
get into that on this call.
There are multiple methods but
I'm not going to go into that.
He said he couldn't comment on any
of it because it's classified but
Harold Co is a creative lawyer according
to Dan Kleiman who spoke with a lot of
people familiar with the process.
Co in particular had a fascinating way
of determining who is and is not an
associated force.
In other words we are or aren't at war
with and it seems to be less about the
groups as a whole and more about
individuals within the group. For example,
a seniority. That was a
an important issue for Co.
If you're going to target a guy,
he has to be a senior member
of group like al-Qaida, right?
He has to be able to give orders
and he has to be unique within the
organization.
You couldn't simply under Harold coast
theory go after say a driver or a cook
who was in a Al-qaida
or even foot soldiers,
uh, because, uh, they were fungible,
meaning they could be easily replaced.
Another criteria was whether
they were externally oriented
for Co. If they were just participants
in a civil war, you couldn't target them.
But if they were targeting westerners
or Western interests, then yes.
So if you take Dan Clyde mins
account of Harold Co's criteria as a
representative and we personally
have no way of verifying it.
But if you take that as the norm,
then maybe there is a strong vetting
process in place. But I interviewed,
um, numerous people who
participated in these meetings.
And one of the things that, um,
I heard over and over again was it that
there was this kind of an extra bubble
momentum toward killing and that the
military people in these meetings could
speak with a kind of a tone
of do or die urgency. In fact,
two of the people who I quote in my
book used exactly the same metaphor to
describe that sense of momentum
that was very difficult to resist.
It was like standing on a train track
with a train hurdling towards him at a
hundred miles an hour.
Cause then I guess like
the important question for me is
like how often do they say no? Well,
it should've been 99 times. Yes.
And one time no. Or 50 times.
Yes and 50 times, no. Yeah. How
many nos are there? Well look, I,
I'd say I did not come
across many, many examples,
but he did tell us
about this one instance.
This was a meeting between the top lawyer
at the Defense Department and then a
man named Jay Johnson and the top lawyer
at the State Department who was then
Harold Harold Co and according
to Dan sources, Harold Koh,
j Johnson were faced with determining
the fate of a 40 year old man,
roughly 40 named Schaef Multi-hour Robo.
I think that's the right way
to say his name. I'm not sure.
He's a member of the Smalley group,
l Shabaab. And for context news,
World Cup celebrations have turned to
tragedy in the central African nation of
Uganda. A few months before this
conversation, this is in 2010,
Al Shabaab bombed a rugby club and a
restaurant at the same time in Uganda
killing 74 people, breaking
chairs, smashed tables,
and the sounds of pain as rescuers
search for the living and the dead.
So that just happened.
And according to Dan Kleidman at
this moment in intelligence circles,
there was a debate raging as to whether
Al Shabaab should or should not be
considered an associated force. Okay.
Time their leader had sworn
allegiance to Osama bin Laden,
but their agenda was
primarily a local agenda.
They had never struck out against
the United States or against American
interests in the region.
So you've got the top lawyer at the State
Department and the top lawyer at the
Pentagon facing off as to whether this
fellow Robo from Al Shabaab should live
or die. And how does this work?
Does somebody just like just someone
pound the table? Yes. This was,
this was a very heated
meeting. Jay Johnson, um,
argued vehemently that Robo
was covered under the AUMF.
He was after all, a founding
member of al-shabaab.
Harold Koh vehemently disagreed. Harold
Co's conclusion based on the evidence.
And the intelligence that he saw was
that Robo was not externally focused.
In fact,
he belonged to a faction of Al Shabaab
that was arguing against attacking the
United States and other Western
interests. So according to Kleidman,
these two men went back and forth and
back and forth until eventually Harold Koh
just drew a hard line and essentially
said, look, if you do this,
you need to know that you will be doing
it over the unambiguous objections of
the State Department's legal
advisor. The unambiguous,
and that's very strong
language coming from a lawyer.
And the signal that it's sent to the
White House was you will be taking a
military action,
even though the top lawyer at the State
Department has said that this would be
an illegal action. All right. So what
happened? Did they decide not to?
They did not do it.
[inaudible]
this is not academic. It's, it's, um,
lives depend on which
way the decision goes.
[inaudible]
authorized
[inaudible] land on the rise committed
or eight in the terrorist attacks on
September 3rd on September
11 2000 [inaudible]
we'll continue in a moment.
This is Jim Donahue
from Fort Worth, Texas.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is Radiolab today.
We've devoted the intro.
We're continuing to devote the entire
show to a single sentence. One sentence,
60 words. That's all.
It's the 2001 authorization to use
military force was signed into law on
September 18th,
2001 and together with buzzfeed and
reporter Gregory Johnson, we have,
we have manhandled these words. We
have dissected, we have bisected,
trisector and whatever other kinds
of sectors you could want resected.
Who the AUMF as it's called. Yes. And
you know, we've looked at how the, the,
the sentence has defined the our
last 12 years of counterterrorism.
Now how will it define our future?
Gentlemen. Thank you for being here today.
This is a very,
so when we were thinking about that
Senate Arms Services Committee hearing,
we ended up calling someone who
sat on the committee, Tim Kaine,
Senator from Virginia and who was
there that day. Yeah, that was a,
that was a very uh,
kinda hair-raising day and Senator
Kaine told us that one of the most
hair-raising moments for him was
when one of his fellow senators,
Lindsey Graham asked one of the
Department of defense officials,
do you agree with me the war against
Islam or Tara or whatever description like
to provide will go on after the
second term of President Obama.
In other words,
how long do you think this particular war
as declared in the section is going to
go on? Then in my judgment, this is
gonna go on for quite awhile and yes,
beyond the Turks, second
term of the president and
beyond this term of Congress.
Yes sir. I think it's
at least 10 to 20 years.
[inaudible] it was chilling cause like
this is already the longest war in the
history.
United States along the Vietnam and now
a dod official is saying add on 10 or 20
years. So, um, I said and use it,
the administration's
position that you tell me if,
if somebody who's born after
nine 11, let's imagine in 2030,
they join a group that has just become
associated with al-Qaida in 2030 is that
the administration's
position at the AUMF would,
would cover them and those organizations.
And without hesitation, the, uh,
the administration witnesses said yes,
as long as they become an
associated force under the, uh, the,
the legal standard that was set
out, it's not limited in time,
not limited in geography, really
troubling. Um, but you know,
I'm also troubled by another thing, right?
I mean, you know, the iconic, uh,
it's a New York picture of a
VJ Day kiss and Times Square.
I used to be in a car [inaudible] we
have a combination of every type from
typing
August 14th, 1945,
there ought to be a day where those who
have served in war that you declare that
the war is over and then you celebrate it.
All these people happy.
That's the only white
[inaudible] [inaudible]
you can ask sometimes by service
families, like when is this gonna end?
Does it ever come up? Yes, yes, yes.
You told us that something like one in
three people in his state of Virginia are
connected to the military. So
he does get that question a lot.
And the truth is we all
want to VJ day, we need it.
And so seven days after that, Senate
Arms Services Committee hearing
President Obama, it is a great honor,
gave a speech to return to the
National Defense University
where he seems to say basically it's time,
this war, like all wars must end.
That's what history advises.
That is why I intend to engage congress
about the existing authorization to use
military force or AUM at
basically announces that he would like
to get rid of those 60 words and in this
war. Yeah, but common
sense tells you, yeah,
that these are different kind of enemy,
not a state or a government.
They just, they make war, uh,
in a different way. Senator McCain
has a great line. He goes, look,
we're in an age of warfare where the war
isn't going to end with the signing of
a peace treaty on the
deck of the destroyer.
That's not how it happens these days.
There no clear start and ending.
And yet the president, he wants
to end the war, suspend widows,
and every war has come to an end.
He sees himself as a person who came in
to a country fighting two wars and he
brought them all to an end. And I think
he wants to have done that. But how,
how do you, how do you do
that? How do you end a war
when the vast amount of people that
you're calling the enemy haven't stopped
fighting? Yeah.
So what he does, America
cannot in the May speech,
and it's extremely clever and by the way,
it's really well lawyer,
is he announces a set of rules
going forward for drone strikes.
America does not take strikes
to punish individuals.
We act against terrorists who pose a
continuing an eminent threat to the
American people that he's only gonna use
drone strikes when there's an imminent
threat capable.
And it's well understood by people
who understand this kind of stuff,
that in the constitution and
also in international law,
the president is allowed
to act unilaterally in
self-defense when there is an
imminent threat,
meaning it's urgent and you can't
feasibly capture that person.
Ben Fears that what President Obama
was doing there by stressing that word,
an imminent threat to the American people.
You said he was laying a new foundation.
You're saying when the AUMF
ends and I want it to end,
I do have another way of
justifying all these things.
Maybe they wouldn't change. So the
drone strikes and the rates would,
would continue as long as you have a
capacious enough understanding of what the
word imminent means,
you might be able to continue a whole
lot of this stuff and then you don't have
to go to Congress at all
and you can say you've ended the war and
the human rights groups will cheer for
you and we're going to mysteriously find
that there are a whole lot of imminent
threats for freedom.
Thank you very much
everybody. God bless you.
Hey God bless the United
States of America.
And in the context of what
happened to those 60 words,
you do have to wonder what's going
to happen to a word like imminent.
And all the while according to Ben
Witness and pretty much everyone we spoke
with, we haven't really
answered the big questions.
When do we want to attack
the enemy? Who is the enemy?
And if we're going to be fighting them
even when we're not technically at war
with them, then what's the
difference between war and peace?
And that's why this whole subject
is so unsettling. And
again, if you don't know
the common sense definition anymore of
when you're at war and when you're at
peace, then how do you, how
do you write rules? Yeah.
This was an attempt to
begin opal war and a,
so it had the usual beginning
questions. Okay, you who are you?
Are you out there where you for how long
until you surrender and know you're not
going to surrender? Like all of the
usual, uh, business of warfare is,
it doesn't apply in this case. So then
you have to think of, now what do we do?
[inaudible] yeah, it's just
like one long improvisation.
[inaudible]
huge thanks to this hour to buzzfeed
and to their reporter Gregory Johnson.
Checkout Gregory's piece is
where we started with that.
We will link to it from radiolab.org.
It's on buzzfeed as well.
It's called 60 words.
Any war without in the untold story of
the most dangerous sentence in the U S
history. That is a
title right there. Also,
thanks to the Great Dylan Key for original
music and Glen Coachee for music from
his album adventure land and uh Oh,
and also thank you to Beth Fertig,
uh, and the w NYC archives for the nine
11 tape. You are at the top of the hour.
This hour was produced by Kelsey Padgett
and Matthew Kielty and myself of Jabu
abroad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
We'll see you next time.