Listening to radio lab radio
from W N y.
S. A. N. P. Hello. I'm Jad. I'm
Robert. This is radio lab, the podcast.
So today, uh, slightly off beat, uh,
exploration of acoustic warfare.
And we're going to do it by looking at
the, a famous, do you know this story?
Aye. I know what we're doing.
Should I, you remind me,
I've heard the phrase walls of Jericho
and I know nothing else about it.
It's most famous as a song, Josh,
the battle of Jericho. Jericho, Jericho.
Joshua fought the battle of Jericho and
the walls came tumbling down. Pneumonia.
Nudity.
No idea. You don't know
that? No. Before my time.
It's a, it's a, it's a negro spiritual
to black and said Pac American spiritual.
And it's like,
anyway, so tell us the story so we
can get started. Well, as you know,
the Hebrew people crossed the Red Sea and
then wandered around in the desert for
awhile. We'll just say I knew that 40
years, 40 years. And now we're up to,
we're almost into the promised land,
but there is this city called
Jericho who is inside Jericho. Well,
the Jared Cohen's really the Jericho
and they don't know much about them
actually. Why aren't they friendly?
Are they against God? No, they're just,
they just, I think they have all these
40,000 people showed up at the, hey,
who are these people? I get the value.
So they were just looking after
their property, I suppose.
Or maybe they just didn't like what they
saw. Okay. Now Jericho, you're reading.
Now I'm reading from the Bible.
Now Jericho was tightly shut
because of the sons of Israel.
So I guess constant gotta take
Jericho. Maybe that was it.
I'm a little fuzzy here on the cause
of the thing. It had to be done,
had to be done. However,
now quoting the Bible,
Jericho was tightly shut
because it had a wall. Yeah.
So read the part about how
they knocked down the wall.
Here's the formula from the mouth of
God, and you shall march around the city,
all the men of war, circling the city
once and you shall do so for six days.
And on the seventh day you shall march
around the city seven times and seven
priests shall carry seven
trumpets of rams horns.
It's a show far actually is a Ram's Horn
and the priest shall blow the trumpets
and it shall be the wall of the city
will fall flat down and they do this with
seven trumpets. He say yes.
All right, so here we go.
The question we have then for this
podcast is what would it really take?
Josh got the battle of Jericho to do this.
I'm talking without God only CUNY
physics through your headphones,
independent, left and right. Volume
control should be fairly comfortable.
Is it just in principle possible
for sound to blow down a wall?
That's their question. We actually
called up a guy who's thought about this.
I'm an acoustical consultant.
David Loveman is his name
and an acoustical and if you
think about the nature of
sound, it's a fluctuating
pressure. Explain the wind sound,
hits an object like the waves actually
push the object but also pull at it many
times per second in theoretically.
He says if he can get enough of
those pushes and pulls on the wall,
eventually it will begin to crumble.
So the first question he asked nationally
is what kind of wall are we dealing
with?
Oh,
well looking at the construction of
Brian's age walls in the Middle East,
uh, there were mud brick walls. Uh,
how the question then was how
much sound would be necessary?
What volume to topple a wall like that?
Yeah. And he came up with a number.
This is a technical number
for the strength of the sound.
You'd need to produce 177 DV.
177 decibels. Yes. That would
knock down the wall. Yes.
How, how many decibels? Just for scale
is my voice right now roughly? Oh,
your voice is probably
about 60 or 65 decibels.
Oh, so already a third of the way
there. Just talking. Well, no,
Jerry go body. Here's where
the issue start. Turns out,
he says it sound doesn't add up the
way that you would think a shoe.
And there's the rub. Assume that
your voice level was 60 decibels.
In order to get the 70 disheveled,
you would have to produce
10 times as much power.
Just didn't make much sense to us
until we ended up doing what he did in
recruiting some experience show far
blowers from a heading towards there are
from synagogues. Yes. We went up to all
souls. A unit. What does it all souls.
UNITARIAN church. Many times a month.
That church actually is hosting to a
synagogue. Oh my God, I hear them. Crap.
Did you hear that? Like animals dying.
[inaudible]
alright, so shofars were the horns
that apparently knocked down the wall.
So we wanted to measure how loud they
could be and we were lucky enough to find
this guy Panter Daniel Pincus,
who got together about 10 people.
Everybody with their rams horns. Okay.
A Yemenite show far. The Daniels
was not quite a Ram's horn.
Probably from either an animal called
a kudu, perhaps from an antelope.
I'm not exactly sure. It's quite big.
Quite big. It's about [inaudible]
two
[inaudible] fee plus a few inches. Wow.
In that somewhat corkscrew shape. Um,
so any case he got us started and eh,
we asked them to blow his show far as
loud as he could and we were going to
measure the decibel level
[inaudible]
just up to 96 but now I'm
not satisfied. All right,
so that was our baseline. 96
decibels for one show far player.
But interestingly when we doubled it
had to show far players listen to what
happened.
We only got up to 98 just shy
of 99 and when we doubled that,
went from two to four show far players
[inaudible]
we only bumped it up three more
decibels. Think we got a hundred a month.
Wow.
Turns out, and this is
actually a rule of thumb.
Anytime you want to bump up your
overall volume by three decibels,
you've got to double
[inaudible]
the amount of shofar players. So if
you want to go from 101 DV to 104,
that means going from four
show far players to eight.
Do you want to go from 104 to 107?
That means eight shofar players become 16.
And if you want to go from there
all the way up to our target 177 DB,
well then you're going to
have to double yourself a lot.
But here's the question. How many
Indian, how many shofars would you need?
I'll make the roles of jerk and down.
The number I calculate it is 407,380
and it might take a while.
Well wait a second. Seven is what
the Bible says. And you just said
(400) 700-0380
yes. And that would be a minimum number.
That's five rose bowls
full of trumpet players.
But of course if it was a
miracle, all bets are off.
But what if you could get that number of
people together? Could you still do it?
Can you knock down the
wall? Well, with the,
with the puny physic went into David,
we still have a problem. Unfortunately,
the problem I had was getting a very
large number of men show close to the wall
that we could produce the necessary
pressure. And as I added men,
I'd have to put them
further and further back.
Imagine he says you've got all these
hornblower's hundreds of thousands at this
wall. You've got to organize
them, put them in rows,
and that creates a little bit of a
situation. Oh yes. Well, the, uh, the, uh,
people in the front row would,
uh, have their heads blown off
by the lash of the people behind
them. That's a sort of problem.
If you're a musician, I think if you'd
like, we could do an experiment. Uh,
do you volunteer? No,
she thinks about
[inaudible].
Okay.
But what if you could put the people
in the front row and helmets to protect
them then continuously we have
another problem. That's right.
The sound according to the,
has to be focused in as to actually sort
of point at one spot on the wall when
you put that many people
together in front of a wall.
Some of them are gonna be
way behind the ones in front.
We're going to lose focus and there's
the problem. But then we found woody.
Yeah. My formal name is Norris.
I go by woody.
We called woody because, well,
he's an inventor, president,
chairman and CEO of a brand new company
called parametric sound corporation and
he may be able to help us with our
focus problem because he's invented a
technology that can beam sound
in a direct line like a laser,
which I'm going to demonstrate for your
friend here. Let's check some of these,
some of these things up. That's
reporter Kirk Conan. Okay.
First I'm going to play you
this guy to demonstrate.
He pulls out his a sound bemer.
It's like a mini satellite
dish, but kind of in a square
stand over there.
He and Kirk get on opposite sides of
the room very far apart and then what?
He shoots a concentrated beam of sound
in this case, the sound of rushing water,
right? It hurts head.
No. If I showed it at you
towards the night just aiming at my chest,
almost a hundred percent gone. [inaudible]
wow. Magic.
Does your invention allow us to take the
sound and put it into a beam such that
it will hit a spot on the
wall of Jericho? Absolutely.
With a caveat. The caveat.
There is no known loudspeaker on the
planet that can put out 170 decibels.
Really,
my company makes some of the
loudest speakers on the planet.
They're known quite popularly around the
world as an El Rad long range acoustic
device.
They're sold to the military
police departments and the
loudest unit the company
sells, which can be over
$100,000 for one unit,
puts out about 155 decibels. That's not
enough to knock down our wall though.
No, not at all. There's another
issue. This'll be caveat number two.
When you get about 150 565 decibels,
you get close to causing cavitation
in the air where the air turns into a
plasma.
What do you mean with sound won't
travel through the air only for a few
millimeters. We weren't able to, 1000%
confirmed this, but according to woody,
even if we were able to make
the necessary amount of noise,
we would not be able to get that
noise to the wall. The sound just go
mayor.
We are just, I, there's a,
there's a Anglo Saxon where
they would go right there,
but we're talking about the Hebrews.
But we are that thing and I
don't know what to do. Well,
I had an alternate theory that
could make Fi's story plausible.
Ah,
what I've imagined is that the attackers
would try to undermine wall by digging
underneath it and the uh,
defenders figuring that the
attackers would do that,
which sends spies out to find out where
the digging is so they can use counter
measures such as boiling oil.
Right. But we then the wait, no,
wait, wait, wait, let him finish
this. I'm enjoying this. Okay.
But then the attackers would say,
they'll probably send out spies
to find out where we're digging.
So let's issue orders, uh,
that nobody is to know where we are
digging and we won't tell those blabber
mouth Israelites because it's sure
to be picked up by one of the spies.
And next thing you know, we'll have
warning oral on our head. In the meantime,
the diggers, in order to keep
the wall from falling in on them,
they would prop it up with timbers. Then
when the digging was about complete,
they would pull out the whatever was
the equivalent of a Zippo lighter in the
bronze age and a light the timbers and
then run like heck as the fire burns
through,
eventually that part of the wall would
fall straight down and the weight is the
Hornblower cut into the equation.
Oh, well in the meantime,
the spies report back. We can't
figure out where those Israelites,
they're digging. So, uh, the king
of Jericho probably says, well,
we'll have to use the old hole
in the shield trick to find out.
And so they take their bronze age shields
with a hole in the middle and they
placed him on the ground.
Tackers say the defenders will probably
use the old hole in the shield trick.
We know that. So we'll have to use
acoustic warfare, make noise to, uh,
prevent them from being able
to hear where the digging is.
So let's send out a bunch of priests
with shofars and to make noise.
And so as I there to keep
the shield listening,
Jericho ins from overhearing the digging
Hebrews and the fluids are just the way
to mask the digging Hebrews is located.
Boom. Rod. Hi Robert. Krulwich. Bye.