Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich, Radiolab, the podcast. And this,
I actually brought a list.
Okay, let, what? Let's,
why don't you share with me
your list? Where is this thing?
This is Andrew [inaudible]. He's a writer
and editor at The New Yorker magazine.
Oh, I might've gotten lost.
Occasionally pops onto our show.
Maybe you were mugged. Maybe a here it is.
And he recently got obsessed with a m
it's a list of measurements. Base units.
They're called theirs, their SEI
base units. The system international,
you know, so let me do it this way. Um,
have you ever wondered
how long an inch is dumb?
Exactly. How long it's stuff. I
know I just look at a ruler. Well,
but how do you know that
your ruler and my ruler,
do I have the same amount of inch
base or that someone in China,
they're inches are inches, your inches,
my edge. And really thought about it,
but I w I'm just assumed that there's
like a master inch somewhere be on too.
I say it in French for reason and
which will feel it in a moment.
That is what was on this list
that Andrew was looking at.
It's a list of standard
measures for everything we
have around how big something
is, how far something is, how hot
something is. It's all on this list. Okay.
So when you go down the list of
the systemic Internacional d units,
here's what you get. A meter.
A meter is a fraction of a second of the
distance traveled by light in a vacuum.
Okay.
A second is how much radiation
corresponds to the transition between two
hyperfine levels of the ground.
State of the cesium one 33 atom.
That's the definition of a second.
How many times does that particular
Adam Juggle? Yeah. Wow. Uh,
an ampere which measures electric current.
You know, amp is a constant current,
which if maintained in two
straight parallel conductors
of infinite length would
produce between these conductors.
A force equal to two times 10 to the
negative seventh newtons per meter of
length. I have no idea what
that it's g, that's the thing.
If you look at the actual definitions,
any of these things am meter second,
whatever you go. Yeah.
[inaudible]
there is one standard on the list
that is unique for its simplicity.
The definition of the standard unit of
measurement that is a kilogram is no man,
no numbers. It is a thing,
a particular thing, a plum sized thing.
It is the only thing we
use to measure things.
It's the last one standing. The
only physical standard laugh.
Why is it the last and why
there is it what, wait what?
Let me just take you back to
the beginning of the story.
Like I must admit that I expected this
story to be a lot more boring than I
found. It's like an
epic story. It's really,
that is Latif Nasser Science's story in
regular on our show and he says if you
go all the way back to the very
first farmers back in Mesopotamia,
all of the earliest measurements were
super intuitive and he says a lot of them
came. The body as
in that bunny is coming close
to the net. How close dad?
Two hands. But it's not just like, well
cause we think of like hands and feet,
but it was also,
there are so many other kinds of
measurements like you would say, oh,
something is as far as you know,
my voice can carry or that something is
as far as I can see sitting on the top
of a camel or something is as
far as I can throw a stone.
So that would mean like say, okay,
I'm going to build a farm here and I'm
going to do it three throw rocks across.
Yeah. Yeah. The way I read
about it was like travelers,
like if you're a Saharan
traveler, you know, and you're,
you need to know where
the next watering hole is.
That's kind of a life and
death, uh, measurement. They
would say it's, you know,
three throw rocks away or
it's 10 throw rocks away.
But,
but you know that there might be some
built in uncertainty there because if you
ask Achilles, yeah, it could be to
throw rocks away, but he asked me,
it would be like 78
you have nailed exactly the problem
with the throw a rock a system.
And these problems kind of came up
do ahead in the 17 hundreds,
it's the eve of the,
of the French revolution in
a little town called Paris.
It's a pretty cosmopolitan place,
which means that people are coming from
different places and they all have their
own measures,
approximately 250,000 different
units of measurement in regular use,
150,000. Every commodity has its own
measures. So you have grain, wine, oil,
salt, Hay for wood,
fabric, ev, everything.
And it's extraordinarily confusing.
Not to mention it's
extraordinarily bad for trade.
So if I came to you and I say,
Miss Your, I have video of cloth,
you would say, how much cloth do you
got? And I'd say, I have two. Yeah.
And you say, what's the yard? I said,
[inaudible] these match America. I said,
no, no, he's this match. No, no.
It's this match and this match.
And then you can see the frustrating.
It was frustrating and
making matters worse.
1780s, there was a famine.
So there was a shortage of grain and
people were hungry and people were angry,
which I am going to uh, call. Uh,
they were hangry, they were hangry,
they were very hangry to
the bakers at the time.
They knew that if they
raised the price of bread,
like an angry mob would
basically come and kill them.
But they also knew that
with no absolute standard,
there was no way to be sure that what you
were getting is what you were getting.
And so what they started doing was they
started just lightening their bread
loaves by just a little.
So as the famine got worse,
people would be waiting in longer and
longer lines to pay the same amount of
money for smaller and smaller loaves.
So they were getting angrier and angrier.
And so one of the things that people are
like crying out for is that they want
standardized weights and measures.
If I go to the bakery and I buy a loaf
of bread, I want a whole loaf of bread,
right? Don't short me on this.
This is serious. Well, you,
you know what happens next?
[inaudible]
best deal is stormed. And uh,
the king is under house
arrest and then [inaudible]
under the guillotine and as soon as the
revolutionary government takes over,
they said, all right, okay, this
is one of our first priorities.
We are going to make a new standard,
but not based on something arbitrary
like a king. This is the enlightenment.
Why don't we draw on some kind
of totally different authority,
the authority of nature,
of nature of nature.
So long story short, they took
the circumference of the earth.
They took a quarter of that
circumference, divided that by 10 million,
and they got the meter, the meter,
they then divided by 10 cube.
Dick filled the cube with water,
took the mass of the water,
minted the cylinder of metal
with that mass. And Voila,
they created the world's first kilogram.
The idea of this was if we make this
thing that is so beautiful and perfect and
everybody can see it that way,
then not only will France use it,
but the whole world will use it.
Then goods and ideas can be exchanged
everywhere by all people and it will be a
beautiful, glorious [inaudible]. Exactly.
They wanted something that
would be eternal and unchanging
for everybody for all
time.
So now I guess you want
to see it? Yeah. Okay.
Okay, so it's in here.
We ended up visiting the National
Institute of Standards and technology in
Maryland, and this is
where we'll be going in,
but we're going to go with this guy,
Patrick Abbott physicist was our guide.
They took us three stories down into the
Babbitt rocks of the state of Maryland
because they want things down
here to be totally still.
We've just gone through one double
door and here comes another double
[inaudible].
Then we stepped into this vault
of the room and narrowed was,
what we're looking at then is a glass
jar with a little handle on top and then
inside that is a another glass jar with
a little handle on top and inside that
is is the thing, the thing,
it's kind of gorgeous, really.
The shiniest little soon.
Do you ever seen very small and it
looks very clean, doesn't it too?
Yeah.
It's almost hard to tell where the like
brushing doll glass jar stops because
it's so reflective. That's might be crazy
question, but can we hold a kilogram?
That's our producer Lynn Levy. No,
I'm just curious to
know what it feels like.
We've been talking about it so much.
They are very careful with the kilogram
and this isn't even really the real one.
The original of the original,
of the original, of the original
Gong cod as they call it,
lives in a basement in France.
You can't get anywhere near that
one. I could. No, you couldn't.
I get all Tom Cruise
on. Then trying. Here's how it works.
The international prototype is big Kahuna.
That's the one you used to calibrate
six identical platinum cylinders,
what they call witnesses
or Taiwan and French.
Those witnesses are then used to calibrate
another set of cylinders which are
then used to calibrate the u s standards,
which is what we saw and that one is
used to calibrate all kinds of things.
The weight of your lemons, the
scale in your bathroom, green team,
you lost 34 pounds. Every time
somebody loses a pound on that TV show,
biggest loser, 5.8
you can actually trace that
like a bloodline if you will,
or an unbroken chain back to
the international prototype.
Kilogram to a single object
in a basement in France,
the holy of holies. That is the kilogram.
Well, you're telling me that when
something is weighed in the world,
often it goes all the way back
to this one hunk of metal,
which was why the next part of the
story is so, uh, disconcerting.
What happened in 1989 is
that according to Andrew,
the folks who take care of the
official kilograms, the big K,
or they took it out of its jars,
they put it in a steam bath,
hit it with the steam, that rinses
everything, wait for it to dry.
Then they commence a
ceremonial way, right?
Well how do you waive the thing that is
the standard of wait while you weigh it
against the copies, like
the u s copy for example.
So they get one of those and they put it
on one side of the scale and then they
put the gun k on the other and the IP
k the logo on because the one is light.
It's like it doesn't how
many, how many, how much
she does it later.
Is it then that sisters roughly
the mass of a grain of sugar.
Oh yeah. So I can't
tickets measurable. Wait,
how do they know that it was light and
not that the other ones were heavier,
right? Well they didn't. So they
used the second sister copies,
still light and the third sister copies
still light in the fourth and fifth and
sixth didn't comes. The man from Germany,
light incomes. The man from Canada,
light incomes, the man from Spain light,
which led them to the
troubling possibility that the
international standard for
weight was losing weight. Well,
we think that we think the big guys,
the problem as far as how it lost
that weight, really no one knows.
One possibility is it got cleaned too
much and maybe some of it got scraped
away.
Although it's disputed whether cleaning
it more would make it lose weight or
gain weight.
The other theory is outgassing like
maybe a little hydrogen is seeping out of
the metal and then there was one thing
I read that said foul play can not be
ruled out. We'll see.
I was thinking maybe the Taliban was
clear as we may have a slightly trippy
situation here.
We've got a hunk of metal losing weight
and yet because it is the standard,
it still weighs exactly a kilogram, right?
If the definition of a kilogram is the
mass of the international prototype
kilogram, whatever happens when
you put that thing on the scale,
that's a kilogram.
You can't do that and then everything
else in the world is wrong. No, you can't.
That doesn't sit right.
That's like something that like the
North Korean government would do just be
like no more cash like that.
We can't just go around
capriciously doing stuff like that.
Invisibilia is back for new
season with all new stories. Oh,
out of 22 arrival and yell, everyone
get down. This is a robbery.
We have stories about small personal
battles. I didn't leave my house.
I wanted somebody to see me really sorry
about the past and stories about huge
cultural issues. This is probably
gonna get somebody killed. Just evil.
You can hear Invisibilia in NPR one
or wherever you get your podcasts.
All right, so if the standard of weight
is, as you're saying, losing weight,
so how do you fix that? Well, I'm getting
zero cell phone reception down here.
That means we're really do.
When we were down in that
underground room in Maryland,
we met a guy who had some thoughts
about this. Oh, there he is. Okay.
His name's John Pratt.
I'm the leader of the fundamental
electrical measurements
group at the National
Institute of Standards and technology.
John walked us through even more high
security doors and then we walked into
this, oh my God, amazing room. It's big.
It is big up three stories
tall and it's made of,
it's like a silver room.
It has a silver gray floor.
It has silver shiny walls and you're
hearing is on the silvery side very much
so. You probably wouldn't be allowed
any if you're a red head [inaudible] no,
I don't even know how to describe it.
It looks like a wheel turned on its side
with the thing itself looked sort of
just like a,
like a massive round metal
cauldron or like big metal pot.
But then there are all these weird little
gizmos and parts and then all these
coiled up wires and just
ate stunning machine.
But it's all just for
the benefit of the one.
The one measure one kilogram because
inside that giant [inaudible] and there is
an extremely extremely sensitive
balance and equal arm balance,
which is basically like a
seesaw or a teeter totter.
And usually you would set that up so
that you would literally put kid on one
side of the teeter totter kid on
the other side of the teeter totter.
Now you've been in a playground
so you know how this goes,
but what they've done here is on
one side of the teeter totter,
they'd got the kilogram,
like the ground guy.
That's kid number one on the other side.
That of another kilogram or kid too.
We'll have a highly variable
magnet. Now here's the thing,
the magnet won't be touching
that side of the scale.
It will be exerting a force at
invisible force on that side.
It'll produce a force and we could use
that to hold the balance still and the
force it takes to hold up the balance.
That of course is the same as the weight
of [inaudible] car sitting on the other
side. And if you can convert that force
into a number that everybody agrees to,
Walleye,
you have just redefined the kilogram,
you have wrenched it from the world of
things and it's become attached to the
fundamental forces of the universe.
Yep. [inaudible] grasp the gist of it.
[inaudible]
do you want to see that happen right now?
I can show you this with our lego
version of the watt balance. Okay.
If I can fire it up. Lego Lego
one. We'll see the, the, the,
the big one was being tested or something.
So they took us over to look
at the little button. Okay.
So we have have a little scale
and everything you can see.
I just disturbed the balance and
it's, you know, chilling around oil.
It's free floating. Hey,
so you're now going with your tweezers
and you're plucking ITI. Bitty. Yup.
Two gram mass puts this tiny little
thimble thing on the mountain.
Now it's going to, he says
levitate. No, it's easy.
It prompts me mass on Mass on, Huh?
Yeah. I'm going to put the mass on.
He pushes a button. Right and
okay, but when do we see the levitation?
That was it. I didn't, I missed it.
Do it again. Floating. It
was floating. It is floating.
Sitting on the balance. Okay,
and it's not floating that is
floating. Does it fall to earth?
That's a different idea of levitation. No.
The truth is that once I finally
figured out what this guy was doing,
it was actually sort of cool.
He had taken a little metal way.
He put it on one side of the scale.
Then on the other side of the scale,
it was just empty,
but yet the thing didn't tip over because
the MD side actually had a magnetic
force equivalent to the metal
holding it just perfectly still.
Right. So if they're able to do that,
does that mean that the ground
k's rain is, is done now yet? No,
because first of all we the, you have
to get straight with a lot of mat.
Mc squared equals h new work backwards.
You gotta divide by e and then by
amateur the B field. Whoo. Let's go.
I think you get your m peers and your
watts and your Planck's constant.
Lots of little bore model
of Adams and stuff. Anyway,
it is actually way more complicated.
This whole thing than I frankly
will live or understand.
But here's where we are at.
You got all these different
teams around the world.
You've got John's team in Maryland
with his seesaw. You got another lab,
actually a couple of them that have
their seesaws. You've got a third lab.
It's literally counting the atoms.
They're all doing experiments,
comparing numbers, trying
to get the numbers to agree.
So that by whatever route everybody
agrees on exactly what a kilogram is right
now, they're close there.
They're in agreement out to about six
decimal places and that's not good enough.
They want the numbers to be at the eight
decimal places. But if they can do that
and only then will the
grand k be no more. Yeah.
Because instead of defining the kilogram
as whatever is equal to the ground k
now you have a new, the new
definition of the kilogram,
the kilogram is the siu unit of mass.
It's magnitude is set by
fixing the numerical value
of the Planck constant to be
equal to exactly
6.626069 and we have x's because we
haven't all agreed what the final, okay.
Those,
the missing decimals are the limb missing
decimal places times 10 to minus 34
when it's expressed in the unit for
actions. Jewel seconds, which is um,
a meter squared kilogram per second. Cool.
That'll be such a simpler
definition. Oh yeah. No. You've,
what will happen to the grand k when
the new definition goes into effect?
Well that,
so this is the sad part
was that [inaudible] it's
like a church you each will
receive to the church.
We have the footballs,
the ground K me eventually end up
in a place like this. [inaudible]
we're so many standards have gone to
die. This is the music. These are,
they met in Paris. So this is the
beginning show 85 so was our tour guide.
Yeah. What is this a lead [inaudible]
you showed us the original liter
[inaudible] some early thermometers.
Yeah. And the VJ, but that's
[inaudible] room. He
showed us your original,
I think it was the provision meters
when Paris, this was the infallible,
the absolute standards from 1801 I
think it's in a wooden box with a velvet
packing and it's got silk ribbons at
either end and it's just a very beautiful
looking silver rod.
Oh till imagine like the, the thing,
the grand thing being in this place.
So you like seeing the pope and shorts
with something makes me so uncomfortable.
[inaudible]
special thanks to
Eric Rominger and also to take when we
don't want to forget. Richard Davis.
Ken Older Bob Waters. Michael.
Michael Newman and fine.
Thank you to our math angels soprano.
Very weird to sing my own name. Also,
big props to reporter Andrew Moran,
so lots of Nasr and our
producer. Then leaving and uh Oh,
oh, uh, also, uh,
you should go to radiolab.org not only
to support the show by clicking the
support button,
but also to check out a collaboration
video that we did with Henry Rice from
minute physics.
You can see it@radiolab.org or
also youtube.com/minute physics,
yet another meditation on what
things are unthinkable. Oh,
all about. I'm Jad Abumrad I am
Robert Krulwich. Thanks for listening.