Are you ready? Yes. Feeling, feeling.
I'm fully, I'm feeling full of value.
Well, in that spirit I'm Jad
Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is Radiolab and today three very
different stories that try to put a dollar
value move you in. It's okay. One
minute. [inaudible] $7 10 test downs,
one things that seem priceless. Priceless.
Really.
Okay, so start at the top.
So for sound, the pressure,
so to to to tell her we're going to
start the show with a story from our
producer Molly Webster. I
don't remember any of it. Cool.
We might actually want to rename Molly
Wong stir because she recently got
herself some to some serious numericizing.
Actually it didn't start as a wonky thing.
It started actually with some
medical journals. So that was,
that was interesting because it was some
of the most poetic writing I've seen
out of doctors ever.
One Journal article said like what would
one more month mean to a 37 year old
mother who has four children?
Or what would one more month mean if
you are a 67 year old who's about to go
traveling around the world.
People were just kind of like drifting
these questions out there where they
were.
All these questions seem to circle
around the seemingly simple story of the
pricing of a drug, a cancer
drug, and this story,
if you really want to tell
it from the beginning,
it begins with this guy
named Leonard Leonard Salts.
I'm a medical oncologist at Memorial
Sloan Kettering Cancer Center,
which is here in New York,
and it's one of the largest
cancer centers in the country.
We have 17 doctors here who treat
colon cancer just for colon cancer.
Treat a very large number of
patients. It's a huge hospital.
And one of the things Leonard's been
noticing in the last, I dunno, decade,
is cancer drug prices have just
gone through the roof. I mean,
we have drugs out there that are many
hundreds of dollars per pill. Really?
Yeah. Oh, just wait. Let's see.
Where does this start? It starts,
it's June in 2012 Leonard Salts is at a
conference and at this conference is a
pharmaceutical company called Santa Fe.
And they give a presentation about a
new drug that they have a drug called
Zaltrap.
And Zaltrap is a drug that
without getting into the science,
too much targets the
blood supply to the tumor.
It cuts off the blood supply, which
means the tumor can't grow that.
That's the scientific hypothesis.
So this new drug has presented and they
like present the data and they showed
that the survival difference between the
people who god Zaltrap and the people
who didn't was 1.4 months or 42 days.
In other words, if you take this drug,
you could get 42 more
days of life on average,
which means you could get three
more days, you could get no days,
you could get 42 or you could live
another three years to 42 days down to the
fine grain. Oh, please. Uh,
I could show you some graphs that have
been put up at meetings that show, uh,
survival curves calculated out to two
decimal places in terms of months.
So I'm looking at this, it not a
10th of a hundredth of a month,
a hundred of a month. That's a little
over seven hours. Pretty amusing.
Accurate. Why would you, why would you,
it's pseudo precision. Pseudo precision.
At any rate. Anyways,
after the conference,
the FDA approved the drug and basically
once the FDA approves the drug,
public insurance has to take it.
And then the private insurance
companies just follow suit,
which means you get prescribed
the drug and people pay for it.
And what is the drug cost?
That's the thing. It costs, uh,
roughly 30,000 for three
months. Course. Wow.
Whoa.
So, so Leonard's like,
wow, that is expensive.
And there was already
another drug on the market,
did the same thing and it costs half
as much. To put that in context,
this is just one drug
that's $11,000 a month.
A normal cancer patient might take
dozens of drugs. There are anti, yeah.
Nausea medicines that are
sometimes used that are, uh,
in the range of 90 to $100 or a tablet.
And you take a tablet
once a day for three days.
One needs growth factors to help
support the white blood cell count,
which you sometimes need. And Chemo.
Those can be $5,000
every two to three weeks.
If you need antibiotics to treat
infections, those aren't cheap.
And then you need a pharmacist
to prepare it there.
Labor intensive need tubing and
equipment and needles to give it,
you need trained nurses to administer it.
You need doctors to take
care of the patients.
And don't forget there's a cost
for a cat scan or MRI. And,
and then of course someone's
got to pay for the real estate,
the heat and the lights. None of
those prices are figured into it.
Oh, okay. I'm just giving
you the cost of the drug.
So Leonard calls up one of his colleagues.
Uh, my name is Peter Bock. I am a
physician at Memorial Sloan Kettering.
Peter is the number cruncher of the group.
He does the statistical analysis of,
I don't know, the cost of care,
and Len grabbed him and ran
him through all the data
and we walked through the out of pocket
expenses for Medicare beneficiaries,
medicare beneficiaries. If they
don't have additional insurance,
20 cents of every dollar
they pay out of pocket,
and that number is sort of hit him
because he realized for Medicare patients,
they'd be paying something like $2,000
out of pocket every month for just this
drug, 2100 if I remember the number
correctly. For a lot of Medicare patients,
that's all of their money,
nevermind other drugs.
That's when I thought we should go
public with it. Memorial Sloan Kettering,
they decide to boycott this drug.
[inaudible]
now that is that.
I mean I'm just stopping you because when
you guys made that decision was that,
that feels like a big deal.
It did feel like a big deal and it felt
like a big enough deal that we decided
to write the op Ed piece
in the New York Times.
They write an op Ed in the Times that
basically says, look, this is crazy.
$11,000 a month for a drug that
maybe gives you 42 more days of life.
Is that worth it? And little less than
a month after the op Ed piece came out,
the company makes sal trap.
They went to individual doctor's offices
and sent representatives and said,
we are offering a 50% discount. They
cut the price in half just like that.
Yup. Nationwide or like just
in this area nationwide.
It was sort of incredible
[inaudible].
We reached out to Santa Fe to talk about
the price of Zaltrap and they declined
to comment,
but in a statement that they released
when this whole Zaltrap thing happened,
they said that they incur so many costs
for researching and developing and
bringing a drug to market that that
is what their pricing is based on.
Leonard doesn't disagree.
We need these companies.
They're the ones developing the drugs
which aren't easy to develop. I mean,
Leonard gave us just one example.
If we talk about colon cancer,
he says for years there was only one drug
on the market called five F-you five a
few was patented in August of 1957 it
was from 1957 until 1996 that a second
drug came along.
That's how long it takes to develop
a good drug or that interim.
There were over 70 drugs
that were tried and failed.
Like I don't give it enough credit
because that just astounded me. It's very,
very hard and that according to Leonard
is one of the reasons why prices are
just going to keep going up,
but sooner or later this
system is going to fall apart.
And at what point does society say there
isn't an infinite number of dollars
that we can commit to
our healthcare system?
It's funny because I had this interesting
reaction to the word society because
all of a sudden I thought like
why is not not like a, you know,
crazy death panel way. But I thought why?
Why is society involved in my conversation
with my doctor about if I want to
take this drug that may give me
another month and a half of life?
Why is society involved?
Because you're not paying unless
you have hidden resources.
I'm aware of probably couldn't afford
10 to $15,000 a month in drug bills.
Someone else has to pay that.
Obviously. He says it's
your insurance. I mean,
say you're part of a policy
that has 1000 members.
Let's say that the
premium for that is $100.
So we had a hundred dollars thousand
people. We got ourselves $100,000. Okay?
So when we now have $100,000 to take
care of that thousand people for that
month, whatever amount of time,
if nail one person comes up
with a health care costs,
let's say it's for a month,
that is $100,000 in that month,
everybody else's in trouble,
there's no money left.
So they write this op ed saying like,
prices are too high and the
drugs are not that great.
And sort of the next like notable
wave is, um, there was this,
there's this journal called blood,
which is really big to anybody that
works in a community that has like called
blood. Yeah. How did we not know about
this and we made the blood show, oh,
I knew. Just kept it in
here. Anyhow. Um, so yeah,
so there's the journal called
blood, which is basically like the,
the journal for anybody that works
in a field that has to do with blood.
And what happens is like a hundred doctors
get together and they coast sign in
editorial,
which basically says we totally agree
with everything you guys are saying,
but we have an even bigger issue.
You know with Zaltrap you're talking
about an expensive drug that maybe doesn't
really do that much.
It's kind of easy even though it had
never been done before to say we're not
going to use this. What all these doctors
in the blood editorial are saying,
what do you do when you have a really
expensive drug? But it's really,
really good. It's like a drug
you actually want to take.
Is that like a like a one day in the
future we will face this kind of question.
No, that is like a now today question.
The most important new
medicine approved this year.
Everyone I talked to pointed me
to this new drug called Sovaldi.
It's known as Savaldi civilizing.
Many in the medical community are
calling the new medication. Blockbuster.
Sovaldi came on the market last
December, so that's December,
2013 that's correct. This
is Bruce Bruce Moore.
I'm the Editor of Commonwealth magazine.
He's written about Sovaldi and
here's the basic story, right?
Okay.
It is a drug that treats hepatitis C,
which is caused by a virus and the
disease itself goes to work on your liver.
It inflames it. It scars, it can
cause liver cancer, cirrhosis.
It can be fatal and for the longest
time the treatments that they had just
really weren't that great or they
just had wretched side effects.
But along comes Savaldi
and it's one pill 12 weeks.
You take it with some
other antiviral meds.
It is a super simple treatment option and
the side effects are very minimal like
this. It was like kind of like the savior
drug and so a lot of doctors start to
prescribe it.
In the first half of 2014 70,000 people
in the country in the United States were
treated and it had a 95% rate of cure.
In other words, the cow virus
was eradicated. That's very big.
But in fitting with our story,
this truck costs $1,000 a pill. Whoa.
For like one, one pill
that I take one a day.
[inaudible]
which as you can imagine,
angered on a lot of people with Hep C in
total it costs $84,000 and if you think
about the fact that in 2014 we know at
least 70,000 people got this drug and
you're starting to talk about
serious money. Wait, I wanna I,
I just want to say that I, I,
I just timed out 70,000 times 84,000 and
I got something with seven Zeros in it.
It's five, eight, eight and
then there's seven Zeros,
which is like a bit $5 billion. Yes. Yeah.
[inaudible]
the big question is how stage will
pay for what could be upwards of,
and so we have a situation where states
are basically having to ration, yeah.
Say in Massachusetts,
most of the insurers currently are
requiring some liver damage before you can
take the drug.
Similar restrictions are happening
in other states, Florida.
It's happening in Oregon, Illinois.
The doctor says the only option may
be to wait until you're even sicker,
and then there's Arizona
out of the [inaudible]
entire state.
Public Insurance only approves 180 people
for treatment or it's just 180 just
180 now when I talk to a representative
of the company that makes a truck,
Greg Altan,
executive vice president for corporate
and medical affairs for Giliad Sciences,
he says, you got to keep in mind this is
not a chronic care situation. This is a
sure here you're actually
curing a person of a disease.
We're talking about 12 weeks
of therapy period. That's it.
And you're done and
you've cured some. Yeah,
so he says, this is a onetime
deal. This is like one time,
$84,000 and then you're done.
Think about all the years you'll live
without having an illness. Then you'll see
over a 20 year period the savings that
will accrue to the system by having a
patient cured of Hepatitis C.
He also said it's important to understand
that every hepatitis C suffer is not
going to hit the system at the same time.
So all of the cost is spread out. Right,
which is totally true,
but I think there's like this bigger
picture here and Bruce points it out to,
it's sort of like a precursor of what
could come because these companies are
developing drugs all the time. What if,
if you could get a drug but it was very
expensive to treat diabetes and then
you're talking tens of millions of people,
an enormous segment of the population,
even if just a fraction of them
want a drug that's $1,000 per day,
that's practically our entire US
budget. What do you do in that case?
A drug comes along like that and
throws everything out of whack.
[inaudible]
this is the part where I really sort
of got hooked in where it's like,
how do you answer this
question? Is it that, you know,
at a certain point you just draw a line
and you say beyond this point we're not
paying. But beyond what point
exactly. I mean that's the hard part.
Like how good does it treatment have
to be for you to say this is worth the
price that it's been set at? I don't
think we have rejected out of hand,
but I don't think I got into
this a bit with Leonard.
In the case of Zaltrap they said,
all right, 42 days, that much money,
we're not going to do it.
But would it have been different
if it was 50 days or a hundred? Uh,
is that enough? I'm sure you
want to be talking in years,
but I guess the question is like what
would be, is there a magic line line
for you? Um, um,
if I, this is a, I can't personally
determine it for everybody.
I wouldn't presume to try,
but ultimately as a society we're going
to have to reach an understanding of
what that cut point is because
we can't afford not to.
And the question that sort of
bubbles out of this conversation is,
what is one more year or one more month
or one more day of life worth to us?
Are we willing to pay $1,000
for an extra day of life? Well,
what about a hundred thousand dollars
for an extra day of life? You know,
people like to say, yeah, so
what's the value of a human life?
And the answer is, boy,
that's a complicated question,
but a really important one because
nobody thinks it's infinite.
He said that and I was like, okay,
it's not zero and it's not infinite.
Is there an answer like in the middle?
And so I started looking around, I dunno,
I guess I was wondering has anyone
actually thought about this?
And so I started looking around and what
I realized was that the World Health
Organization, actually, I'm, I mean
I guess they almost have a number,
but it's a number per country.
They have the recommendation
that that countries spend,
it's going to get gobbly
gooky but just bear with me.
The country spend one to three
times the GDP per capita,
which is like the gross
domestic product per individual.
So take the entire fat ball of money
that is in a country and divide it per
individual divided by the individuals.
And then you spend one to three times
that on one more good year of life.
And what would that be
for us? So for the u s um,
if that's about 50 to 150,000.
Interesting. And is that,
does that have any, any
teeth that recommendation?
It legally doesn't have any teeth,
but it has teeth in the sense that um,
doctors in the u s are actually going
to start using this. Who number two,
evaluate medical
treatments for cardiology.
They said they were going to do this in
a paper and it was kind of very quiet,
very subtle. But in other
countries, this conversation,
it's very loud actually. It
happens at the government level.
They're also passing out surveys
where they're asking citizens,
what is your limit on how much you want
to spend on one more good year of life.
Have they done that here? As far
as I know, no. Why not? Because?
Because the last time we tried
to talk about cost in medicine,
it ended up in the hole
death panel, death panels,
panels or so called death panels thing and
I dunno, I just wondered into the
mess of it. Hey, times square.
If I actually tried to go out and ask
this question in a very basic way,
how would people respond? Excuse
me? Can I ask you a question?
What is a year of life
worth? Wow, what a question.
Hey dusty, can I think about,
and that's a tough one,
but I was really surprised how
seriously people took the question, man,
what is a year of life worth? That
was the first thing I noticed.
Then the next thing was no one could
answer the question until I had answered
like a million questions of theirs.
Am I going to die tomorrow? Yes.
Where do I get that year? Do I get it at
the beginning of the middle or the end?
How would I spend that year of life?
Good. It would be a good year of life.
A good year of life. Depends. It's
like a pie in the sky kind of answer.
They wanted to know would
they be emotionally half
alone with friends or family?
Where did they get the
money? They borrow the money.
They have to pay the money back where
they dying. Was it an emergency?
Other people also trying to get money
at the same time because then there'd be
like a rush on the money in
America. Oh, interesting.
Did you actually ever end up
getting numbers? I did get numbers,
but they were at least $10,000 $15,000
$13,000,007 all over the place.
Yeah, I would say five
bucks. Head million dollars.
$44,000 you're saying one
woman said 10 million,
$10 million for a year.
It's irresponsible. Well,
you asking me about my
personal choice? $10 million.
Not about a public policy question. What?
Do you have any way of parsing
all this? No, I really,
I honestly don't like,
I think my biggest takeaway was
like no one punched me, which,
which makes me feel as
if people are ready,
not ready but willing to
engage in this conversation.
But I also realized I kept talking about
things and I just wanted to be in the
room with patients.
Like I just want to patients in the room
with me because it was like we were all
having this conversation that eventually
we'll all be patients I guess.
But we were also having this conversation
around like a group of people that
weren't ever present.
Like they're not at conferences
or not in research articles.
And so that was when I
started talking to patients.
Ah, well I guess what is 42 days?
What does 42 days mean in the sense of
is that something that you'd pay $50,000
for if you were, I mean, of course
you would that it's like, no,
I almost can't even ask the
question, but I don't know. I know,
I think it's a good question.
I think ethically it would be to the
good of patients and doctors to have this
conversation. This is Susan Susan Gould,
bar rider of the living with cancer blog
for the New York Times back in 2008.
Susan went to the doctor. She hadn't
been feeling well for a while.
They thought it was some
sort of bowel issue,
but then the doctor walked into the
room and said she had advanced stage of
Varian cancer.
Most ovarian cancers are
diagnosed at a late stage and um,
it's, it's basically
incurable. It can be handled.
It can be managed that it can be kept
at bay and for longer periods of time.
Now we hope, but you're given a
diagnosis of three, five years. Wow.
That is,
you go from having unlimited time in your
mind to three to five years in like a
doctor's visit. Yeah, it's,
it's, it's a big shock.
You sort of enter the zone. Well,
you're not quite aware of
what you're doing that day.
The day she was diagnosed,
she was told, pack a bag,
get in a car and drive to
Indianapolis. You need surgery now.
So I went the next day to Indianapolis
and the day after that I had the
debulking surgery,
which takes out the ovaries and the
uterus and the Fallopian tubes and the
spleen and sometimes the cervix and
sometimes the appendix and Holy Shit,
the bowel. And Are you serious? Yeah,
it's called the mother of all surgeries.
And then just like that, she was doing
multiple rounds of chemo chemicals
that are used. Uh, they destroy
all quick growing cells.
So for example, you have no hair, no
eyebrows, no eyelashes, that you know,
uh, you, you also can, I got terrible
sores in my mouth. I have no idea why,
but I know this happens
to other people. But yeah.
The other thing is this extreme fatigue
and Susan who writes for a
living couldn't even read.
I would look at the page and
think, had I turned the page
[inaudible]
chemotherapy. It really
is toxic to the spirit,
to the heart, to the mind.
Just the normal aspects
of life feel polluted.
Have you ever had to think about cost?
I was never informed of the cost of
any drug or any procedure I was given,
which really makes me think
about how masked these costs are.
Would you want to be thinking about cost
while you're going through it or is it
better to just say, here
are your treatment options,
these are statistical outcomes,
like pick one and then we'll
deal with it on the other side.
I think there's an a kind of unspoken
agreement among everyone that the
insurance company or Medicare is going
to pay. And if it's the government,
that means that our grandchildren are
going to end up paying for all of this
money. So yes, I guess
to answer your question,
I think it would be healthier to know
what these things cost. On the other hand,
I have to say as a patient,
I was so traumatized.
I'm not sure I could have
taken that information in. Um,
I was thinking about your what,
what is worth, what's it worth?
A title. And I was thinking that, um,
the American individualistic
optimistic response would be,
well, whatever it takes, whatever
it takes, life is worth it.
Whatever it takes.
But whatever it takes
will not cure my cancer,
so I think this question changes
when have incurable cancer,
it becomes a different question,
which is when is enough enough?
I remembered she said that when
is enough enough? I was just,
I don't know that we are ready to say
there's one magic line thrown back to this
conversation that I had with Leonard
Salts where he was saying that we have to
look at everything in terms of value.
If you need to think deeply about
the kind of life you want to live,
it's not just about how many days,
it's about what kind of days.
So if you told me that there was something
that gave a 72 day survival benefit,
but it makes people feel
nauseous for most of the time,
is that worth it when we're trying to
draw this line as a society before we
figure out what we're willing to pay,
we have to think about what
we are paying for. Yeah.
I don't think we know
what for Susan, you know,
six years ago she decided that she was
going to get chemotherapy because in part
it would be more time with her daughters.
Yeah. And suddenly it's worth it.
Yeah. But I think what changed
by the treatment to, for now,
Susan's cancer is basically
under control because,
uh, she's on this new
drug for two and a half,
two years and now a month.
And I am counting, um,
I've been alive without a recurrence,
without the cancer growing,
by taking these pills every day. Um,
and I take them at home. They're not
infused in the hospital through my veins.
They are just pills and um,
it's made last few
years remarkably normal.
Like the new normal. Yeah.
[inaudible]
but when these drugs stop working and
I've been told they will stop working,
um, I'm not sure I would want
to go back to chemotherapy.
[inaudible]
but I, I suspect, I don't
know until I get there.
[inaudible], [inaudible]
producer, Molly Webster, and now
for the thank yous for that piece,
we we want to thank Steven Hall and
one I mentioned Susan Goo buyer's book
called memoir of a deep poked woman,
and it takes also to doctor a tool Guan
Day for all his help and his latest
book, which is really, I really
thought it was wonderful.
It's called being mortal. Yeah.
And thanks also to Nikki
Hanes and to Glenn Blomqvist.
Radiolab will continue on.