You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N y.
S. C. E. Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich.
I am not Jan [inaudible].
What you see who you are. Okay.
That's the oddest thing to do.
I'm a new summer Odie. I host
another podcast at w and YC studios.
Note to self.
You also are on Irish show video lab.
I'll know very, very frequently. Well,
not very frequently but frequently
enough. Frequently enough.
Brilliantly enough. Thank you sir. We are,
yes, and I am here.
Pinch hitting for Jad for a little
bit to spread the word that this is an
important time for Radiolab, Robert.
Well, it's the end of the year. The
giving time is the end of the year.
What we're about to do I think will be
kind of wonderful because we who make the
show and you who listened to the show
don't often have a chance to get together.
So in the next bit of time what we're
going to do is we're going to pal up.
We've invited some of the people who
normally listened to come on the show and
people who love Emily make the show
come and listen and we're mixing it up a
little bit.
It's a strange menagerie of humans and
we want to just go to the zoo of us.
So that is coming right up.
But if you'd like to hit pause just for
a second and make a contribution right
away, like right now,
you can enjoy the episode knowing that
you've already done the thing that you
were supposed to do,
that we're going to be on our knees
begging you to do what you've already done
it like, yeah, that's already, you've
already solved the problem. Yes.
Do you want me to take over
here? Right here. Okay. Yeah.
Slip in and then I'll think of something
to say on the, okay, very good.
So, um,
what Robert is beating around the bush
is that radio lab relies on the support
of listener contributions.
Listeners like you, yes.
Who make all the stories
that we produce possible.
So it's time that we extend a hand
to you, our podcast listeners,
and invite you to make a
financial contribution so
that radio lab can keep these
episodes coming your way.
It is super easy to do.
We ask you to go to radiolab.org/donate
to give or even easier if you live in
the u s open up your phone, probably
what you're listening on. Anyway,
open up the messaging app.
Type the word radio lab to the number
six nine eight six six that'll get you
started. Okay,
but suppose you live in Montevideo,
Uruguay, or in Zagreb, Yugoslavia,
a country which no longer exists, then
you can't. What do you have to do then?
Just go to radiolab.org/donate that's
what I always do whenever I am in central
Europe, South Asia or South
America. Again, it's really easy,
so don't be intimidated
by it. Now as we promised,
it is time for you to meet some
people whom you hear on our show,
but have never really met Arianne
wack producers a part of our show.
She's never met them either. So this
was her chance to find out about them,
our chance to find out
what Kerryann found out.
Hello. Is this Terri? Did
I lose you? Did I lose you?
Hey. Hi. Hi. How are I'm good. How are
you?
I was so touched. It was your email.
Well, I do want to hear emails. All right.
So I decided to call up this woman that
I have just been desperately curious
about, uh, for years now since I've
worked here. What's on your mind?
What can I do for ya?
Um, the reason, well,
I've been wanting to reach out to you, um,
for a while because part of my job here
is to listen to all of the spots that
come in for our underwriting and I like
choose the reads and produce them and
put them into the episodes I need
to go in. Oh, um, cool. Well,
thank you for what you
do tobacco for a second.
We have our listeners submit underwriting
reeds via the app and we put them into
the brakes of our shows. If you've
listened to the show with any regularity,
you've probably heard this.
And Hey, this is Terry Babcock.
Lou Mitch support for NPR comes
from NPR station. Terry Babcock.
Lou mish does every single one
of them. This is Terry Babcock.
Lou Is Terry Babcock. Lou Ms.
Henry Babcock is Terry baths.
Terry back documentary.
Babcock was married.
Terry Babcock more than 300 times.
And I know that if in a
pinch I need a spot quick.
I know that there's going to be
a read from Terry Henry Babcock,
the Cochlea Mesh.
Are you tired of hearing
my voice or this way?
Yeah, no,
that's why I wanted to call you guys
because there's three of you that leave.
I'm I to read almost every single piece
of copy I put up. And so especially,
you know, I,
I think you've probably been doing
it the longest out of any of them.
So I remember like when you move
that cochlear mish from cold spring,
New York from like cold springs, no
hottest is Terry Babcock. Lou Mission,
Honolulu, Hawaii down
to Honolulu. And like,
I know like when your husband is
around, hi, this is Brian Babcock,
Lou mish and this is Terry. Listen
occasionally like hip hop in. Yup. Yeah.
And so I just, I feel like
I kind of know you. Um,
well, I mean it is all based on
like evidence that I've, you know,
gathered from your phone calls and
the background noises and whatnot.
But my gosh, seriously,
this is really fun.
What's your hypothesis?
My hypothesis will you lived in a cold
spring for a while and I was like,
she doesn't, she sounds too young
to be like a, like a snowbird.
So I didn't think that you
guys had moved for the weather.
Like somebody must have
gotten a job down there.
Okay.
Uh, and then you have
grandkids. And I was surprised.
I had heard them a couple of times,
or at least they sound
like little kids to me.
Maybe they're not going
to have kids. Uh Huh.
Anything because technically I don't
think we're even old enough to have
grandkids.
Okay, good. Yeah, so I've got
conflicting narratives here.
That's still pretty good. Okay.
You want the real story? Yeah,
I would love the real story.
So my background is government.
I was the White House economist and
First Clinton administration. Oh my God.
There is no reason why I should
have gotten up with an army guy. Um,
fell madly in love. So he's
active duty military. Okay.
So we move every two
or three years with it.
Army assignment,
summer 2014 I, we got assignment to
Hawaii and that's where we lived.
Or sorry, that's the short version.
That's great. I love having the background
actually that makes me so happy.
Yeah. Have you ever heard
yourself, um, when you,
like you've listened to radio lab,
have you ever heard one of your reads?
So I haven't, you know,
right on a regular basis I'll get an
email from a former student or a friend or
whoever it might be saying that they
heard me on radio lab and it's always so
nice to go hear from someone that I feel
so detached from or we're just far away
from. But no, I've never,
yeah. On do you have a favorite episode?
I don't know,
but I think one of the things that I love
is that you take things that are very
complex and you make ideas,
whether it's, you know, CRISPR Cas,
nine or infectious diseases
or black holes or things.
I don't even know that I'm going to be
interested in you make them not just
interesting but accessible and exciting.
And then I remember it and then I wonder,
talk about it. Yeah. Yeah. So let
me ask, do you have a favorite?
Well, um,
I mean there's frequently 30
different drafts of an episode,
so it's hard to like hear the finished
product as just a listener again and not
being like, oh, I didn't
Depop that p there, you know,
like other room tone there. I could
have smoothed that out or something,
you know? And I miss, I
miss that a little bit.
Yeah, it sends out of it that way.
I'm so, yeah, I need to do it,
but I really do.
No, it's totally fine. It's
fine. Oh, go ahead. Go ahead.
I guess, I mean, I, I want to know
like why you do it? Like, why,
why you're so committed to like
giving to us in this particular way.
So I feel like what you've
asked of us is so little.
And so whether it's public radio asking
for a check or it's me writing some
credits, it's something I can
do. Thankfully it was fun.
Okay.
And it's interesting and you know,
wherever we've lived, I've wanted to,
you know, even if the case
on pledge drive, you know,
to be involved with public
radio, I think, you know,
it really is the soundtrack of
my life and I could be wrong,
but I feel like for plenty of people,
they're concerned that they can't get as
a big check that they sign Gibbs and I,
I'm often very quick to challenge
that assumption. Um, you know,
I think about the people who are busy or
for people who can't write a big check,
you know, eating just a little tiny,
what would the be present of your coffee?
I think people, yeah.
Like that's not enough.
But those copies that up and I don't
think we should underestimate our
collective power with
our coffee. Yeah. Um,
and so in New York, if I can take
you for a cup of coffee. Yeah.
Oh, I'd be happy to because I really am.
Yeah, no, that would be great.
Thank you so much. This was a,
I really enjoyed this conversation
so by,
it's been such a pleasure and I have to
admit I was very surprised by your call.
I didn't know if you were telling
me like Sandown like retired.
No, really.
All right. Thanks so much Terry.
Bye Bye.
Minutia.
Here's the thing about Terry is that
she's one of a lot of folks who tuna Sian
and then kind of join in. Like we have a,
we have a very unusual audience.
Yeah. You have an awesome audience.
Radiolab listeners are the best.
Yeah. But in very particular ways,
like, like when you meet them,
they don't come and say, Yo, I
really, whatever that thing you do,
they don't do that.
They have like very specific sort
of either compliments or arguments,
but if their listeners,
meaning they've listened.
Robert, I think what you're saying
is the listeners, you listeners,
not only do you give your time, you
give your brain, yes, the brain,
the brain.
Let's also remember you give contributions
is what keeps radio lab on the air
and in order for 2017 to
knock it out of the park,
like 2016 did we need you to
keep doing that? Yeah. Yeah.
If you were just sitting here just
sitting there and about like maybe, okay,
maybe now what would you do
right now if you wanted to,
you would go online to radiolab.org/donate
to give it is Radiolab spelled it's
two words or one? No, it's just
one. That's right. Or even easier.
Just text that one word, Radiolab
to the number six, nine, eight,
six, six to get started.
That's if you're in the u s you
can do that in any case though,
you can get it handled in a matter of
seconds and we thank you for it. Yeah,
they really do. Now,
and introduction to one of our
listeners who I recently met,
the three things that I say I love about
this country. Uh, first of all, um,
you know, drinking water coming out of
your faucet, it's insane. You're, you're,
you're thirsty in the middle of a shower.
You just open your mouth and
you're done. It's incredible.
So this is my uncle Mishra.
He's a graduate student in
ecology at Princeton University.
Then there's a bike lanes, which
are fantastic but clean. Yeah.
Because you should try riding a bike,
uh, in Calcutta. Delhi. It's uh,
it's, it'll definitely get you
closer to God. That's right. Yeah.
God does exist in India. Yeah.
So my young started out as a
civil rights lawyer in India,
often defending people whom he
thought had been jailed without cause.
He left for the United States in part
because he had sued the man who was
suddenly became the prime minister
of India. And he thought, well,
maybe I should, uh, you
know, go somewhere else. Uh,
and the third thing I love about
this country was into that. I mean,
just really great internet where I
could listen to things all the time.
And often I heard radio lab when I
first started listening to podcasts,
I first met my young after giving a
lecture up at Princeton University.
He came up afterwards and he said, oh,
I want to tell you about the first
time I heard radio that was okay.
He said that he was on a road trip
with some of his fellow students.
So I was supposed to be navigating,
I was just graduating from my master's
in public administration from Princeton.
We were done with school,
but we were still getting to know
each other because you don't,
now that we were done with
it, we knew each other,
but we didn't quite know
where everyone came from.
And we were going to beach house.
The entire class was going there to
sort of see farewell and you know,
spend a few days together.
And I was supposed to be navigating and
I got everything wrong and we went miles
away and I started talking about, um,
how I had to deal with the loss of
my father. And then my grandfather,
both a Michael just friends and um,
and you also having to deal with the fact
that we were going to leave this place
behind and leave this community behind
that we had formed over the past two
years. The first one I had in
the u s someone said, you know,
there's this incredibly greed episode
by radio lab on life after life.
I think it was,
that was our afterlife episode. It
was a series of meditations on death
on this hour. We ask that question a dead,
what happens at the very moment when
you slip from life to the other side and
what happens after?
And we started seeing it. It was just
done silence through the entire thing.
And one of the, one of the things
that always stuck with me is that, um,
I remember you were talking about a group
and it said that what happens when the
group disperses and people
go their separate weaves.
Does the group die or do
they carry it with them?
This was a short fiction piece by
the neurologist David Eagleman,
which was read on our show
by the actor Jeffrey tambor.
When soldiers part ways at war's end,
the breakup of the platoon triggers
the same emotion as the w. Well,
the death of a person,
participants amble away feeling that
they were just part of something larger
than themselves, something
they intuit had a life,
even though they can't
quite put a finger on it
in this way, death is not only for
humans, but for everything that existed.
And it turns out that anything that
enjoys life enjoys an afterlife.
And then there was something
about when you pass away, uh,
what happens to the, to the things
that make you up when you die,
you're aggrieved by all the
atoms of which you were composed.
They hung together for years,
whether in sheets of skin or communities
as spleen, but with your death,
they don't die. Instead they,
they part ways moving off in
their separate directions.
Mourning the loss of a special time.
They shared together actually haunted
by the feeling that everyone's playing
parts in something larger than themselves.
Something that had its
own life, something. Um,
wow. They can hardly put a finger on
[inaudible].
Yeah. And I think, I don't know, I
had not told about things that we, um,
I'd had never told about where
life begins and where it ends.
And my uncle mentioned another Eagleman
piece that caught is a year from the
same show.
There was this one thing that you said,
which was that one way of looking at
death is when the last person speaks your
name. Yeah. That's when you're gone.
There are three depths now.
The first is when the body
ceases to function of course.
And the second is when the
body is consigned or you know,
put in the grave.
The third is that moment sometime in the
future when your name is spoken or the
last time,
oh, with my father and my grandfather,
you know, the DV, forget them, the d,
You know, we've stopped passing on
their stories and no one remembers them.
That's when that's when they are gone.
That's when they are actually gone.
So you're listening to this, right?
And the other few people listening in,
there's this kind of deep quiet in
the car. Yeah. And then what happened?
So that happened and then that was my
introduction to listening to podcasts and
then I started listening to Radiolab
more. And what would you do?
Have a lot of time on your head.
What was going on after school?
What happened to you? So what
happened was, even in school,
I had been a lawyer and I had
reached this point where I taught,
um, you know, I was done with human
beings. I was done with human rights.
I was done with all of that
stuff because I felt like, no,
we were just too far beyond saving. Um,
and I feel like I'm clearly,
this is not where I should be because
there's a bigger world that I clearly have
some affinity to. But what did
you, what did you decide to do?
Like what was the nude?
I wanted to go back to school and
I wanted to study ecology and, um,
I attended a class on
ecology and completely blew
my mind and I decided that,
you know,
clearly I'm not on the right part and
maybe this is the part I should be on.
I remember we were living in Brooklyn
right across from the botanic gardens and
even through the winter I'd go there and
I'd be listening to radio lab and, uh,
I, you know, every time I think
of radio lab, I think of, um,
smiles and tears sort of streaming down
my face because there's all of so much
that sort of backed into it. And
I'd be sitting there in the cold,
in the snow, in the botanic gardens, no
one else around with a small notebook,
ah, listening to radio lab. And every
time something would come into my head,
I had jotted down. So sitting there in
the botanic gardens listening to us,
like, what, what did that do for you?
So open me up and held me together.
Did both things right. Um,
opened me up to this new world
of, of ideas and thoughts.
And a community of people who
also have similar thoughts,
who also want to find out more
about what's going on. Um,
and also held me together because
I was sort of by myself. Um,
um, I, I'm very, very fortunate to
have my wife with me and she was, um,
I mean she's been a
huge pillar of support,
but we have both sort of stepped out of
our comfort zones and I've thought about
all of these things, um, to
some extent because of Radiolab.
You know, every time I hear the
opening credits or radio lab,
it feels like I've just stepped back
home from the cold or something.
It's just you don't shake off the snow
from your jacket and settle in you.
You feel like you sort of, um,
solve something. I hope not.
I hope not, but I certainly feel
very happy about where I am. Um,
it's interesting because if you'll,
if you listen to the show we do,
we never solve anything.
That's right. Yeah. I never do.
So you know what I, this was,
this was something I've been thinking
about a lot recently and I was speaking to
a very close friend about this as well.
And I was thinking about what
is the role of scientists?
And I found that more
recently that there, there,
there have been things that make me
wonder what the scientific community is
looking out for.
Sometimes I think sometimes we're sort
of caught up in our credibility and the
fact that we must maintain
this credibility and we
shouldn't break rank. Um,
but no one becomes a scientist because
they read a really credible scientific
paper. They read the,
they become scientists because they're
inspired by this world around them and
they're just really curious
about what's going on.
And you inspired me
to, to be more curious,
right? Uh,
to recognize that we don't have answers
and sometimes just looking for questions
is really enjoyable. It's
a lot of fun, uh, right.
And to do together to, to,
to be looking for things together to
go on this treasure hunt around life
together. That's home.
Robert, I think I might be in love with
my encore. Yeah. Well, I already am.
I beat you there when we shook hands.
I remember like holding onto his hand
like for an extra beat because when you do
this for a living, you don't do
anything much more than tell a story.
But if you can,
if you can help somebody get out of
a hole or climb a mountain or change,
you know, change your life,
then like that's cherry on top,
super duper cherry on top.
And that happens oddly
not an often on this show.
So that's really cool. And uh,
should I just say like if you listeners,
if Radiolab has touched your life
at some point in this past year,
it doesn't mean that you had to
have a career maker like my own.
Maybe it was just like it made you smile
or it made you think about something a
little bit differently,
right? We ask you to remember,
are you part of a community?
And this community, uh,
is held together with
listener contributions.
It really is what keeps Radiolab going.
So let's suppose you were in the
mood to give Radiolab something.
How would you go about that?
It's quite easy, Robert. Okay.
Let me just take me through
it slowly instead of,
well these are podcast listeners.
Do they kind of get this whole
digital thing fast? Yeah. So
radiolab.org/donate place to go, or
if you're listening on your phone,
it's really easy opening up your
messaging app that you've got there. Yeah,
sure. I've got one of those mess app
I call it. Yeah, that's very good.
I liked the contract text.
The word radio lab's spelled fully out
to the number six nine eight six six
that's six nine eight six six
now what? Oh, now, oh yeah.
We have another story to tell.
And this next one comes from our
producer Annie Mcewen, who was um,
who wanted to meet somebody who's,
well, we all wanted to meet her.
So here we go.
Okay. So a few months back we
did a story called AlphaGo. Okay.
Is your mic on? Yeah, I'm
getting this. Making me nervous.
And the star of that show
was a woman named Amy Pearl.
Maybe I should get my epi pen. Are
you allergic to radio greatness?
That I know of. I haven't
been really exposed to it yet.
Yeah,
I'm Robert Krulwich. This,
the story was about Amy pro's allergy
to red meat and how she got that allergy
to red meat. So I'm not
gonna tell you any more.
You should go listen to the
story. Go listen right now.
But the reaction we got from the audience
on Twitter and in comments on our
website, which is insane. Usually
we get kind of like, you know,
the odd comment here or there, love the
show, hey the show, where's the science?
Stuff like that. But this time I was
just like this huge outpouring of deep,
deep love for Amy Pearl. Like you
know, get that girl her own show.
She's incredible. She changed my life.
Amy Pearl for president was one of the
tweets and I felt the same love for her
that everyone else did. And my
job by the show is, you know,
a lot of cutting tape and sound
design and music and stuff like that.
So I never actually like met her before,
but I met her through her
voice and I also thought, oh,
she's very wise in ways that I feel
like I really need in my life right now.
And so this is one way to get, you know,
bring more Amy Pearl back into
our lives again, which feels good.
Hello. Hi.
Also, it was sort of an opportunity
for me to ask a question.
I wanted to kind of like,
I recently moved here from a really
small town in Canada and I'm trying to
figure out how to like be a human
being in this city and uh, just like,
you know, not let it, yeah.
Well, I mean it's like, I mean, did
you ever hear there's a famous saying,
did you ever hear it? If you can make
it here, you can pay kids anywhere.
That rings a bell for sure.
It's up to you. No, no.
But it's really true. Everything is
hard in the city. I mean, forget it.
It's like, I'm like, oh, I have to
renew my driver's license chapter.
Your driver's side. Good. You're a
big trouble. Oh my God. Everybody
take the week off. It's not going
to work out for you, Amy. I Dunno.
Let's start a support group.
It's just like everything is hard and
like all you have to do is go for a
minute. Like where my mom
lives in Connecticut and I
go up there and she's like,
oh, I'm going to return
something. Costco. I'm like, what?
What are you kidding me? I'm only up here
for two days. You have to have it as,
and she was like, oh, it'll
be easy. You like drive up,
drive into a parking spot, get
out of the car. Walk one second.
Let me help you. You're all set. Thanks
so much. Bye. Get back in the car.
Driving to your driveway. Park in the
garage. I don't know why the city so hard.
It's so hard. What do you do?
Like what? What do I do? I mean,
well for sure a good thing being
in the city is if you know,
if you wanted do good,
you can. You can like,
I'm sure between now and the
time you get home tonight,
you can like pick up someone's
pen. Yeah. Like Fremont.
Like tell somebody they have, they
have like toilet paper on their shoe,
helps someone and seems lost or like
smile at someone that seems down or be
like, oh my God, I love that book.
That's like you have every opportunity
to make someone else's day better,
which you could just be
like, I'm a superhero.
If something happens,
I'm going to rush over there and
something might happen any second.
I'm in a city. It's like, you know,
and it's like when you're walking around
the city, I always find treasures.
Like if you look in the gutter,
you just like pick up the foot of a
Barbie and it just seems like so great and
like, I don't know. Can you tell me,
uh, what's your,
what's it like the last time you
really saw the city as beautiful?
Oh my God.
I think the last time I saw the city
has beautiful probably last night.
Oh,
that was very dark.
And I got my dog and we went out like on
the block that I walk on all the time.
[inaudible]
but somebody had swept all the leaves
and there was a pile of oak leaf on the
side and the
light from the house flicked on
and every oak leaf was like silhouetted
and that's such a pretty shape.
And I was like, oh my God, these are
just being thrown out by the tree,
these even like of youth.
And then I was like, wow,
every single here at grows a brand new
leaf and then drops it off and the girls,
another one drops it off and girls
another one drops it off at a month.
Live for like 200 years. I'm like, imagine
how many leaves the tree drops off.
I'm like, where does it all go?
And like what is all that energy
coming from and why are they doing it?
And it smells good and it's pretty
[inaudible].
I mean it's probably covered in dog this,
but I didn't get that close and I thought
it was really beautiful and it was
like, it was a good moment.
Oh Amy [inaudible].
Yeah, she's the best.
You know like she was.
So when you hear Amy Pearl Talk About
Anything Dopey Dog pee is fine because Amy
brill is what is what you
would call a an n. S. T.
What's that? A natural storyteller. Yes,
there is no way. Yes, there's no way.
She can't make everything interesting.
And she, so when this tape came in,
when we heard it, we went, oh my God, get
her on the air and don't take her off.
We could just live on Amy.
Now listen though Robert,
there's a reason why we were able
to get Amy Pearl on the show.
It's because of the pearls
that our listeners who are,
who feel precious but don't always do
the thing that precious things have to do
in order to keep other
precious things alive and well,
I don't know what that means,
but I think it was an attempt to say in
a poetic way that people who love the
podcast and give just a few
dollars make this work possible.
And exactly what was that? It?
Okay. And I want to add something.
We actually have some really
great radio labs swag. There is.
Yeah. There's a [inaudible].
Don't pretend you're not wearing
the hoodie all the time. Well,
it's a very warm hood. And
if that's not your bag,
there's a bag. Actually
there's a knit winter cap,
there's a t shirt, there's lots of
swag and it, you know what it is.
I feel like listeners, when
you wear the radio lab's swag,
I see you on the street and I am sure
of it. When we look at each other,
we give a little wink. Yeah.
But you can't get the swag without
making just a little donation.
And we ask you to do that. Oh, funny
you ask Robert, let me just tell you,
radiolab.org/donate or even easier if
you're in the u s text the word radio lab
to the number if you're on your
phone. Six, nine, eight, six,
six to get started.
Next up. A story about a boy,
his mom and Latif Nasser,
lots of his, our producer, he um, he
missed out when we broadcast this,
but he wanted to get into the game as
it were. And here's what happened next.
Yeah. And I actually chose
[inaudible] our football
episode, American football.
It was actually the first
episode I was on staff for I,
I fact checked it and it
had all kinds of things.
It had a story about the history of
football and the forward pass and the
Carlisle Indian team, but
it also had kind of what,
what is the big question now? Uh,
what's the future of the game?
And that question was
perfectly encapsulated by this
interview with this woman.
I'm Monet Bartell you could add something
like if you want, I'm Monae Bartelle.
I'm a Libra. I enjoy long walks
on the beach. I'm just joking.
So this story came to us from
our senior editor, Soren Wheeler,
who you just heard back there. And
basically the story goes like this.
So Monet Bartelle is from a family
that lives and breathes and believes
football. Her Dad, Mel Pharr,
the superstar was a star running
back for the Detroit lions.
He was a two time pro bowler.
Both her brothers were professional
football players. And so for Monet,
when she had her first son Parker,
as soon as the doctor saw his third thumb,
like, dude, we're going to the NFL baby.
Yes. And then Parker's 10,001
ounce. He's the biggest thing.
He walked out the wound,
I'm still going with third until Monet.
She signed Parker up to play in a league
when he was four years old and they
immediately, they named him the tank.
The moment he gets on the field,
he is just plowing through kids
getting touchdown after touchdown tay.
But this is where things get complicated
because while Parker is on the field
just dominating,
Mooney has a relative who played
football for a very long time and was
experiencing symptoms of CTE,
chronic traumatic encephalopathy,
which is what comes from like concussion
question after concussion symptoms
include memory loss,
sometimes bouts of anger.
In this case it was depression,
it was suicidal thoughts. It was,
it was getting phone calls like, Hey,
I need you to come get him because
he's having dangerous thoughts.
Yeah.
And Monet told us that eventually her
father started experiencing symptoms of
CTE as well.
And that put Monae in a very difficult
position because on the one hand she
believed that children
should not play football.
But then at the exact same time she
believed children should play football.
That it's a great sport
and ask for Parker.
When I asked Parker
how did he, the season,
his favorite things were the trophy
and the pizza party at the end.
He had no desire. You want to
play again next season? No,
there's no or favorite moment of this
whole story and a lot of listeners too was
when come sit with me, I
need to sit on your lap.
Parker comes home from school and sits
down with Soren and Monet and Soren asks
him, look, if you don't like football
anymore, do you like other sports
or do you really care about that evening?
I really want to do synchronized swimming.
Is that true? Is that true?
Wow. I'm mostly, because when
I saw something about it,
it looked kind of cool. Like um,
people are doing a lot
of cool swimming tricks.
So I kind of thought it
was something for me.
You playing me
synchronized swimming where this guy's
gonna come talk to me about football and
I'm going to tell him that I want to do
thicker nights. Right? No, you like it
this way and so, hello?
Hello? Hey Man. Hey,
how you doing?
Hey, I'm good with you. How are you?
You called Monet because at like every
time now that I see football in the
headlines,
I think of her and I wanted to
see how she was doing. All right.
Also like, like that tiny interview
with your son? Just uh, like I,
I think about it all the
time. He's kind of my hero.
It has grown legs.
I swear because of that interview I was
contacted about a month ago from ESPN.
Really
reached out to me and they came out
here and spent three days interviewing
Parker, following him around. Oh,
you can't tell Parker anything
now he thinks he's hot. S. H. I.
T he has now. You said in the
interview with ESPN and you know,
I know they were waiting for him to
say he was going to be a synchronized
swimmer. Now he switched it up.
Now he wants to play dodge ball.
Hey, good sport. Although
there's a lot of,
there's a lot of like unlike synchronized
swimming, dodge ball, it's kind of a
contact sport. Yeah. He's not gonna he,
I don't even think he
plays bad fall in gym.
I just think this kid live some
embarrass, embarrassed the crap out of me.
But, um, the,
the series is about the level
of football and you know,
they said, aside from
Parkers, you know, let's
okay.
Residents in, in a fell,
in my immediate family,
it was the thing of that oxymoron.
The fact that I love football so much
and that football is still extremely,
you know, dangerous. You know,
my father passed away last,
oh my God, I'm so sorry. Oh yeah, yes.
The way in August of last year,
which I'm through with all for a loop.
My Dad was like the healthiest
person that we know and he, he,
he dropped dead. I talked
to him that morning. Uh,
it was a Monday and by 7:00 PM
that evening, he, he just, he just,
he just kind of slipped away. Um,
and we got his results back. Um, you know,
we did send his brain and spinal cord and
my dad was at stage three of four with
CTE.
Oh Wow. And that's the kind of thing you
can only find out after someone's dead.
Right, exactly. And was that, were you
sort of expecting that? Not at all.
Oh really?
My father suffered from CTE.
Bad jokingly would say my
having a conversation with
my dad towards the end of
his life, yeah.
Would be like a 51st dates
because my dad will tell him,
he'll, he'll talk to you like, Hey,
you remember such and such and such?
And I'm like, yeah, Dad, I remember, hey,
you remember such and such said my breath,
but
you don't really, you know,
you don't think about it.
And then getting the results of that
from my father, I'm like, God, you know,
stays for CTE is Mike Webster.
Uh, just to jump in here,
Mike Webster was a former professional
player who was suffering from Amnesia,
dementia, depression. He
died at the age of 50.
Dave for CTE. It's junior say out
junior. Say Al was another
former professional player,
shot himself in the chest at 43 years old.
Very four is something that these
families are suffering because they're
watching their loved ones
who can't take it anymore.
So they think that taking their
lives is the easiest way to go.
That's the only way to calm whatever it
is that's going on in their mind because
they can't even explain what's going on.
I'm thankful I didn't have to do that.
I cried when I watched junior, say
I was mom in the press conference.
I cry when I watch that because
I can't imagine as a mother,
um, as a sister, as a wife, as a daughter,
I can't imagine watching my dad or my
brothers or my uncle or my cousin go
through life like that because both of
my brothers are exhibiting size now.
That's all I can really think
about is now what about them?
Yeah. So is there, what can
you do? What can they do?
That's the crazy thing. You
can't prepare for it. You can't,
you can't stop it.
There's absolutely nothing
you can do and fill with that.
Mine were at football every Friday
night cause my nephew plays.
He just got pumped up. You know,
I'm happy now that I can laugh and I
can smile because I was completely,
I,
I turned into like a vampire
when just out of nowhere.
When you're just okay, talk to you later.
Yeah. And then there never is a later.
Yeah. That, that's a tough one.
Did, did your dad, uh,
before he died, did,
how did your dad feel about
football? How did he feel about CTE?
How did he feel about all of this stuff?
If you asked my father,
he would tell you I would
not have changed a thing.
If you look at when my dad
was growing up, you know,
my dad was in an air where it
was separate but not equal.
He didn't have indoor plumbing.
He had to drink from a colored only
water fountain. My Dad would tell you,
he said, man, I ain't never had
a drink cold. Once I got to la,
he didn't even know what that feels
like. What is this going down my throat?
So cool know. So being,
being smart and black wasn't enough.
If he would have been black
and didn't play football,
even as smart as my father was, where
would that have gotten him? You know,
wouldn't have gotten him to
two dinners at the White House.
Would it have gotten him, the private
jet would have gotten him the, you know,
the, the house and us,
these private school educations and all
that would being a smart black guy in
the early forties in the forties, would
that have, what would that have done?
He was able to build a life playing for
the Detroit lions who is owned by the
Ford plant family. And then being
able to go and intern at Ford,
you know, in the off season and
then opening up a Ford dealership.
And then from there branching off to
what, 14 new car franchises. But she,
he left with, with all of us, um,
to be able to carry on that legacy
so it won't be in, in vain. Um,
we have started a foundation where
we're building on it little by little,
just trying to figure out where
and what avenues we want to go in.
We know education is huge and you know,
that would just want to bring awareness,
especially to mothers who put their
young children in football as I did.
Just to be aware of what the dangers are.
Are you willing to sign up
for that? So now I'm going to,
I'm really thinking of tricking
Parker and it becoming like
kicker [inaudible] a kicker.
It's tricky but however he
is his middle school math.
Oh really? Well I was, I was
the mascot of my high school.
What is here was I was Griffy the Griffin.
Yeah, Parker is the alligator.
I forgot the alligator's name
definitely. But he's the alligators.
How does he like being the alligator?
He loves it and he has like
a costume that he wears.
He wears an entire furry head and
everything like eating up into some kid.
Who is this kid? He, he,
he starts Babin and like
he's this other kid.
And so my husband, the first
thing my husband says is
he's like the mascot cause
they still get a ring, right?
No
now I'm like we're going to
keep you in mascot tourism,
whatever it's called because
there's scholarships. Yeah.
And a lot of them will be
their mascot scholarship. Yeah.
Our mascot scholarship. No.
Yes. I know I'm thinking way ahead of
time. He's only in the fifth grade.
So is he like,
he's developing like dance moves
or like are there signature merits?
He gets it on Fridays. He
greets the kids in the morning.
He's got to get there early, you know,
put on his costume and he's out there in
the Carpool lane greeting kids as they
come to school. He does the
special events at the school.
Like he did the fall festival
and the trunk or treat
a man.
One of his teachers won teacher of the
year award so he got to go to the teacher
of the year award ceremony.
Well as a mascot, like he's
just living it up. I hope he,
he wins all the mascot scholarships
and everywhere and makes it pro,
you know, is it is it's probably cut
throat to go pro for mascots. Yeah.
I don't know how that goes. I don't
even know how that goes. I have no idea.
Even when we get there and how much do
they get paid, you know, all these other,
but Parker off, let's be an engineer.
Okay. I'm sure he could do both.
He could do both. Absolutely.
Thinking about what you
said about your dad,
I hope for Parker that he will
be able to get that engineering,
you know, that being smart will be
enough. Or, or if he wants to be a mascot,
he can get all the scholarships,
go to whatever school he wants.
He does not have to put his body in
harm's way if he doesn't want to.
Right. He doesn't have to.
My oldest nephew, um, Trey,
he until recently had the title
as the smartest kid in the family.
He,
he played football, but he made a
plan, hey, I don't want to go pro.
I'm going to play in college,
but I'm gonna go to a college that's
going to give me a head start.
So she went to Brown. Wow, great
at Brown, won a ring, did well,
and now he's off doing his
brown thing in San Francisco,
making great money as a young
black guy because he was smart,
not because of football. So what? I
love to see my son in a football jersey.
Sure. But am I thrilled to see
him in the alligator outfit?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
So we can't offer you listeners a mascot
scholarship that is really beyond our
reach and we,
and then you'd have to choose your
animal and we'd have to make the uniform.
Yes. So we can't, it's
comp. It's a hard, it's fun,
but it's a hard world. So
we're going to streamline when,
when we think about you, instead of
thinking about animals or Griffons,
it's about those guys.
We're going to just think of you
as I'm generous and now minutiae.
Yes. If I wanted to be generous, yes.
What would I choose to do?
You would go to
radiolab.org/donate or even easier.
You could text the word Radiolab to the
number six nine eight six six to get
started. A little form pops up, Robert,
and you can donate in a matter of seconds
and then you can go back to thinking
how awesome radio labs first
spin off was two more perfect.
More of that's going to be coming up in
2017 you mentioned that because a lot of
the people who've been listening to us
to this past year noticed and or join,
okay. A whole lot of people that we never
heard from before became listeners to
something we call more perfect.
It just show about the Supreme
Court of the United States.
We thought of it because we thought
the supreme court was going to be
interesting. And now of
course with 2017 yeah,
we were right in spades because what's
going to happen next year is gotta be,
is this mean what will be near the center
of a lot of conversations for a lot of
people in 2017 so this more perfect Joe
is coming back in the spring of 2017
more episodes. And so people who want to
hear it again, it's coming. But listen,
here's the thing. Listener support is
a critical component of more perfect.
It's a critical component of radio
lab. Any amount that you can give,
just make a gift any amount, make a gift,
and show that you
understand that this is the,
the time to get a year end tax deductible.
It's also the time for us to be talking
about things that matter in a year where
these will matter a lot. So, so yeah,
we'd like you to join us both because
you want to and just because we think you
should right now, if you know what
I mean. Forget my drift next Robert.
A story that captures that spirit of
doing for others in a way that few can.
Hi, my name is Tracy
hunt.
I'm a reporter here at radio lab and I
wanted to talk to someone who has a very
different relationship with giving.
Oh, Sarah. Hello. Sarah Gray. Oh, hi.
There you are. How are you? I'm
good. I'm so good. Thank you.
Sarah was the star of a show that we
did a little while back called grace
donation.
I guess I'm like a little
bit in your nerd famous now,
your nurse Venus. What is the
weight? What does that mean?
Um, well just nerds know who I am. You
know nerds who listen to radio lab.
Just a quick recap.
Sara told us a story about how she was
pregnant with twins, Thomas and Callum,
and something was wrong with Thomas.
Doctors told her that he had NSF Lilly
being born and he said he could see that
because one of the twins had around skull
and the other one had a bumpy skull.
She ended up giving birth to both of
them and Thomas died six days later.
And then right then we called
the Washington regional
transplant community and
they sent a van over to our house and
they picked up his body and took him to d
c children's medical center.
So the story was about how Sarah
ended up going on this journey,
trying to find out what happened to all
the bits and pieces of Thomas that were
donated. So she talked about, for example,
going to Duke University where they
were using cord blood from her twins and
they were actually researching the
disease that killed Thomas Aniceph Lee and
going to university of Pennsylvania and
talking to women there who was studying
this eye cancer that mostly affects
children and called retinoblastoma.
Eventually Sarah and
Ross visited a as lab.
She gave them a tour and she
sewed them Thomas's retina.
She still has samples of it
in her freezer. Tiny little,
I don't know, tiny little vials,
maybe a third the size of your pinky
filled with frozen liquid liquified retina
already. It didn't look like much,
but it was amazing to think of how
many people were involved getting these
samples. They're like, we had to approve
it. We had to fill out this paperwork,
then the doctor had to come and remove
the highs. The NYSE had to be processed,
and then I'd have to be shipped up there.
Then they have to do whatever
DNA process they do and just how,
I don't know, valuable, maybe
even priceless. The sample is,
since the show came out, she's released
a book called an everlasting life.
And I just really wanted to get on the
phone with her and just talk about what
the impact of the show has been
and what's going on with her life.
And one of the first things I found
out was that she had a new baby.
Yes. We have a baby girl that
she was just born in June.
Oh, congratulations. Thank
you. And how's Callum doing?
He's doing great.
This is Thomas his brother.
He can now read a little bit
because in first grade, um,
and he's liking his sister. Yeah.
What, what have you told him about Thomas?
So he knows that he had a brother
who was a twin who had a very, very,
very bad booboo on his head.
Yeah. And that's why he died. Um,
and we just explained, you
know, um, sometimes kids die.
That's just part of
life. People, you know,
they get diseases just like
grown up and it's okay to die.
Does he ask you questions about Thomas?
Yeah, we visited the grave maybe
one or two times a year. And um,
when he was younger he asked, um,
is Tom Scared under the stone?
So,
and he was probably maybe two or three
questions like that were hard because I,
you know, I don't know how
to explain the afterlife.
I don't understand it myself. Yeah. So
I just told him no, he's not scared.
Um, you know, he thinks of Thomas as
being in heaven, but he also asked me,
you know, can you tell me what does it
like in heaven? And I said, um, you know,
I was really like sort of wringing my
hands. Like, oh, what do I say? I said,
um, well, you know,
some people think it's a place you go
when you die and some people think it's
got clouds and, and Callum just goes,
um, no, look it up on your phone
like you wanted the pictures. Yeah.
Well, look, I just looked up on my phone,
I'm like, you know, just be real. Be
Real. But this is what people think. Yeah.
Can you show me a picture of God?
You don't?
Yeah. Sometimes it's hard
and then sometimes it's
easy. It's kind of a mixture.
Yeah, that's it. And also since the
show, um, Sarah has kept on donating.
In fact, when her
daughter Jocelyn was born,
um,
I was inspired to donate the placenta
and the umbilical cord was turned into
four different skin grafts that are going
to be used in surgeries and for burn
survivors and also the umbilical
cord blood went to research,
but also she's been inspired to track
down the people who have donated things to
her.
As I was writing my book, I got this
idea for checking down the blood donors
when she was in the
hospital with the twins.
She actually had a traumatic delivery.
She lost half of her blood and she
ended up getting a transfusion from 11
different blood donors.
So I emailed the blood bank and I've
met with them and they have sent out a
thank you letter from
me to those 11 people.
And when Sarah was in the
hospital with Jocelyn,
Jocelyn actually got
some donated breast milk
and I ended up saving the
bottle, actually framed it.
I keep it in my office because just tears
me up to think of strangers donating
things to each other. But I emailed
the breast milk place and I said,
this is my donor id for the
breast milk. Can you tell me who?
Who are the people that donated the
smell? Can I send them a thank you?
And this is all kind of like, I know I
sound like a donation Weirdo, but uh,
you know, it's like you
receive and you give.
And I just think it's neat to make the
connection and find out how that really
work.
Since we recorded the episode with you,
have you heard any like anything new
come out of the research using your son's
tissues?
So there a study that came out on
tissue that could be my son's cornea,
this lab in Boston.
They've been studying corneal blindness
because when your corneas are damaged,
those cells,
once you lose them,
they're never coming back.
They don't regenerate. They're just dead.
That's what people have corneal blindness.
And so they're trying to figure
out ways to regenerate them. So
they took corneal cells
and they wounded them
and then added umbilical
cord blood to those cells
and they found some early stage steps to
show that these corneal cells might be
able to regenerate with stem cells,
which I believe is kind of what they're
getting at as a possible stem cell.
Eyedrops to get your vision back.
Oh Wow.
So this is like way, way, way in the
future, but at the beginning of, you know,
what if situation that, what if
we could make eyedrops like this?
You check like the, the research
often. How often do you,
whenever I feel like it,
does it feel like you're kind of
like kind of continuing your relationship
with Thomas in some way by checking on
these things?
I don't, I don't know what you call
it. I feel like Thomas, um, you know,
he lived and he died and he made this
contribution and I'm like a spectator kind
of watching how his contribution
effecting other people. Yeah. And I'm,
I'm more like learning from him
then having a relationship with him,
but I know, yeah,
yeah, yeah. I, yeah, I'm not sure if
that relationship is the right word.
I was just trying to like, it's almost,
I dunno, I don't want to say like,
it's like he's still there and
nothing like that. I just, you know,
like he's like,
he's still very much a part
of your life in some way.
Yeah. He's still relevant. Yeah. His
life did not just affect my family,
his life affected many other people.
And in fact, Sarah told me that
eight months after the show came out,
she heard from this couple in Cali,
husband and wife in California,
they had twins and unfortunately one
of them died unexpectedly and I believe
they asked could they donate on the group
said you cannot donate for transplant
because your child is too small. And
I said, well, we heard radio lab,
can we donate to research?
And they said yes.
And their daughter was able to donate
eight different tissues to eight different
studies.
Oh my goodness.
Yeah. And in fact the retinas
[inaudible]
we went to the same um,
lab and the same researcher
that received my son's retinas.
Oh Wow.
I know. Oh.
And the other weird thing is that they're
twins were born on the exact same day
as my twins
pets. Oh my goodness. That's so, that's
so powerful. I don't know. I'm really,
I'm really kind of speechless
at that. No, that happened.
It did for me at least bring back.
So, you know, when my child, I,
you feel like you have no control,
but being able to donate gave me a
sense of control back that, you know,
at least this is, this is
one thing I can control.
Right.
So I was glad that it had that
impression. It had that effect on them.
Sarah talking to me about trying to
regain a sense of control and the face of
unimaginable grief reminded
me of something else she
said at the end of grace
donation.
I used to think like the universe
treated people the way it should.
And now I don't really believe that,
but, um, I do believe that there are,
um,
really amazing kind people in the world
and science and medicine has something
to do with that.
I started feeling that these were Thomas'
colleagues in his coworkers and that
he was a valuable partner in this
important research that was being done.
And I felt even more fundamental shifts,
almost like I had felt like I was a
boat on an ocean that was like rocky and
choppy with waves. And I had this
feeling that I am not the boat.
I'm the ocean.
Like the decisions that I make are
changing other people as opposed to just,
I'm about getting slapped with
waves all the time. [inaudible]
it has made me feel
powerful.
[inaudible].