Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad, I'm Robert
Krulwich, Radiolab and today,
well today we're going to tell you a
story which we hope does not become your
future, but it raises a simple
question. We all have computers,
we love computers, we
depend upon computers.
But what if the cost of
using your computer becomes
more than you're willing to
pay two stories today,
which suggest that we might be at the
very beginning of a nightmare to first
comes from a journalist, Alina
Simone and her mother ina.
I mean do you want to start with my
mom? Cause it really happened to her,
her, you know, she, she only got
in touch with me maybe on day six.
[inaudible] Huh? Yeah.
Okay. So, well yeah, day one.
What was the first, first thing
it happened on day one,
one tampon that I called Tufts university
a t services because my husband,
folks at Tufts complaining that
my computer is unbearably amber
bliss. Slow stills it, I
don't know what's going on.
Every time I try to open a window
it's like click, click full,
practically stop to working. What do I do?
Checked whatever I said and
I'm probably nothing rebooted,
so did nothing basically.
Then she went away for the weekend and
when I came back I turned the computer on
and like it was doing something
and they so many,
many windows covering your screen
and those windows multiplied.
I cannot open any of them
and I could not figure,
but it was very late at night
so she went to bed,
got up the next day called
[inaudible] Gan asking for help.
They had no idea what was going
on. No, she says at this point,
whatever the computer had
been doing, it was done.
All the windows disappeared except now
anytime she tried to click any of her
files, pictures, videos,
I cannot open any of them. Instead,
every time this message would pop up
and the message says,
what happened to your files? My files,
all of your files have been protected
with a strong encryption encrypted using
crypto wall.
This means that the structure and data
within your files have been irrevocably
changed and in order to get
them back to unlock files,
you must pay 500 US dollars.
If you really value your data,
then we suggest that you do not waste
valuable time searching for the solutions
because they do not exist.
You're saying that somebody went into
your computer and locked up all of your
things?
Yeah, they gave me the exact clown,
5,726 files encrypted
live. When you say they, did you
have any image in your head of who?
My first thought was Russia or Ukraine,
which is even better.
Why? Because you know,
everybody talks about excellent,
fantastic education there,
especially math. I'm from the,
I know, you know, she's right.
They surpassed the u s and educating
their kids when it comes to math and
science and they've got a
severe underemployment problem,
especially outside of the major cities,
which is where these viruses often trace
down to not Moscow and St Petersburg.
But we're talking about, you know,
backwater. I was so positive that, uh,
it comes from that part of the world
that I wrote them in Russian family.
The criminals had provided her a link
to a website where she could send them a
message, you know,
customer sport. I rode them
[inaudible] I don't know how to translate
it in English. [inaudible] SAMHSA,
like I wish you all die. [inaudible]
in Russian language [inaudible] to die
for humans or in other word for animals
said use the animal one.
Yeah, it's not a curse,
but they got the message now ina says
she thought about a just wiping the
computer clean so that
she wouldn't have to pay.
Then it occurred to her that her
husband had all these files on there,
which he needed, you know,
like business receipts that he hadn't
filed yet and she's lazy to do.
So he has [inaudible] and she's
right that like, you know,
she has this tax information,
this reimbursement information and
ultimately it's worth more than $500.
My husband did not want
to buy overall themes,
so ina decides to follow the instructions,
basically one download and
installed horror browser.
So she goes and installs
this browser called Tor,
which apparently is more traceable to
Rhonda Browser in Wade for initialization.
She does that three type in the
address Bar, k Pie, seven YCR,
seven j x Q, and she's directed to a
site where it basically tells her, look,
if you don't trust us, we can decrypt
one of your files for free as
a sample that when you pay us,
you would know that you could
really get all your files back.
Huh. And I was curious,
I decided that I will try it.
So she clicked the button that
said yes and we got one file back.
But as soon as I did
the glocks, that chicken,
literally, she says,
a little clock appeared
at the top of the browser.
They gave me exactly seven days,
167 hours, 59 minutes,
59 seconds. So you decrypt the thing
and then suddenly it's a countdown.
Yes. They say, if you
won't pay by this day,
then the fire a little bit of both.
And if the wound bed in one more beat,
then you will lose your files forever
and you will never get that back.
Now in the message that it told INA
that she had to pay that $500 fine,
not in dollars, but in Bitcoin,
you know, I,
this was the first time in my life ever,
I heard the term bit corns.
So I um,
found this website called coin cafe
where you can buy bitcoins in to buy this
bitcoins is a nightmare
for what? Yeah,
what she needed to do with exchange
500 bucks for the requisite amount of
bitcoins. And at the time, uh,
500 bucks equals 1.37 bitcoins.
But before she could
even make that exchange,
she had to fill out all these
forms of all these questions.
What happened?
What is the reason to buy
bitcoin and reasons were listed.
One of them was ransom. So then
yes,
it would the first reason to
pay a ransom to the criminals.
She says after you fill out all the forms,
you have to make a big chair and send
them a photograph through the Internet.
Okay.
I did not have a camera
because your camera happened
to be in the shot or one of
them that I have to make a picture of.
My husband called in a driver's license,
Sam them this picture back,
so they was banquet the criminals.
This is the people who sell you
bitcoin in exchange for your money.
I told you that it's a
torture. It's unbelievable,
but eventually she was able to
find a neighbor, borrow the camera,
take the picture she needs to take.
Then she had to get the money she wanted
to exchange to coin cafe and it turns
out the preferred way to do it, the
most secure way to do it is not online,
but through a money order.
They sold the day before.
Nothing's given Wednesday, still had
about six days before the deadline,
so she thought, all right, I'll
just pop down to the post office,
get the money order,
but
Lexington and the whole Massachusetts
[inaudible] terrible, terrible,
no storms. For a lot of us, this
could be the biggest storms so far.
This winter, drivable road and
significant snow, a wet snow at that.
I had to go to the post office
so she plows through the snow,
almost kills herself but gets there and
gets everything together, sends it off
and it's like, all right, so
finally I sent everything out.
The post office assured me that
they will get it on Friday,
which is the first working
day after the sense given.
Okay, so one Friday she called coin cafe.
They did not get it on set of the,
they did not get it on
Monday in the morning,
nothing was delivered and I was desperate
because my deadline was Tuesday.
Samson like 12 o'clock and I start
calling the post office, whatever,
nobody knows and they sing.
They said yes, two days,
but there is no guarantee.
Finally Walk Block in
the afternoon on Monday,
but 24 hours before the
deadline, they got it
and they send me bitcoins in
exchange because they got my money.
But she says when she went online
to check her bitcoin account,
I am $13
[inaudible] nearly 400 and
and I start calling them,
I basically the exchange
rate of change on her.
She had bought it at 500 now it was worth
four 87 I asked them how often do we
change the exchange rate
in this at every minute.
It's not a joke. Yeah, every
minute. I said, are you crazy?
I was a double victim. I was with them.
Square cube. You see what I mean?
Because driving was terrible.
I have to stand on my head to get a
camera and then I was struggling to Sam
them. That's the problem with this crime.
Like the criminals need a better
way to get money from the victim,
but everything else is traceable.
I'm on the edge of my seat here.
So you're $13 short.
I'm calling they, they said there
is one more way. One more way.
And what does it, we have a ATM machine.
You said what? Yeah,
became an ATM machine.
One live one and I said, where is
it? It's in Brooklyn, Brooklyn,
New York. 200 miles away. Wait a
second, I don't understand this.
There is one ATM that is in the borough
of Brooklyn where you do not live,
but luckily her daughter,
Alina lives in Brooklyn.
You asked me how my daughter got
involved that Scow, so she calls Alina.
Yeah. My mom called me the
night before the Ranson was due.
So are you aware of any of this attack
point at this point? No. No. I remember,
you know, I was at night, I had the
TV on and I have a toddler, you know,
always all these things going on.
I was probably on my laptop too.
I was doing like 12 things and my mom
called and she was like upset with a
capital u.
She started ranting about criminals and
ransom and I literally thought she was
like talking in air quotes. I'm like,
Oh yeah, I know when I go to tech sir.
And like, yeah, they're
threats, extortion. And my
mom was like, no, like no,
really around some dope.
They're really criminals.
Her mom told her Google
crypto wall. I was like, holy,
this is really a thing.
Plus I started googling as she
suggested I do and found out that police
departments had paid this, that
a sheriff's department and Dixon,
Tennessee had just paid it
to unlock like, you know,
70 plus thousand case
files. And I was like, yeah,
go after police department. I've
gone after governments, universities,
corporations, police departments.
Question ever come up in your mind
like why my mom? No, not at all.
Cause like a million people in the u s
have been infected with criminal. Yes.
Anyhow, next day was it
six hours left to Alina,
please go to this ATM so we can
just, you done with this whole thing?
You can cut it later but they
can tell you that in the morning.
She said,
I have a date for my
granddaughter date to play date.
I won't be able to do it until
12 o'clock and they call again.
I said I was crazy. I don't have time.
So I go out to Greenpoint,
this ATM and you know I just
want to add that to your head.
Your plate like handled my po.
I didn't t I called you. You shorten it.
You might get okay. Right. Okay.
So should I cut my playdate short?
Sorry. Forget that crucial detail.
And I go out to Greenpoint and they
have an ATM and I'm just worried that
there's going to be 57 people all lined
up at this single ATM that you're there.
We're totally not 57 people. I mean most
people do take care of this remotely.
Like there was no one at this ATM.
I mean what was funny about the ATM
is like I'm expecting like, yeah,
I've been to an ATM, like I have a capital
one account, I know what an ATM is,
you know,
but this was on like the second floor
of a workshare space in Brooklyn.
It was like in the hallway there was
like a bike hanging from a wall kind of
blocking it and there was like a paper
sign taped to the wall that just had a
printout from a computer
that just said Bitcoin ATM,
all lower case letters and
an arrow to this phone booth.
It looked very Soviet.
Like if you've seen photos of those
phones with no buttons and there's just a
receiver and it's totally
scary. It's like, yeah, yeah.
Like you just pick it up and like
somebody is always on the other line or
something. It was like that.
It was just this box with a screen
and no buttons and a camera eye.
And what you do is you hold up your QVC
Code, is that what they're called? QVC?
What are they called? QRC.
Yeah, it's like a barcode.
So there's this QRC code and my mom
had emailed it to me and it was like,
you need to print this
out and this is a sent.
This essentially gives you access to
my account to top it off, you know?
And so I put this QRC code up to the
camera on and it kind of went bloop and
then it was like we are
accessing your account.
And then I got a spinny
wheel, the wheel of death,
funny wheel elitist, starts frantically
dialing her mom. The guys at Queen Cafe,
I called, you know, I left like
three phone messages. I left five.
So finally they called me back
like 20 minutes later said, okay,
we're sending a technician over to
fix the machine. Which was very cool.
I didn't think that would
happen. And so, you know,
the technician was there and he fixed
the machine and he helps me deposit these
$25 and then, um, it, we start
talking and he was, he was like,
yeah, you know, he knew
my mom cause you know,
he'd been talking to her on the phone.
He's like, I feel so bad for your mom.
We've been getting so many of these
cases. And I'm like, why are you,
why a lot of these
cases, yeah. I was like,
why are you guys getting so why is
everyone coming to you? And he's like, oh,
I know why.
Because in the ransom note that they give
a list of preferred vendors and we are
number one or two.
What does the introduction with
a bad introduction to Bitcoin,
like we're going to hold you ransom
for all your information until you,
you know, use this new currency to pay
us off. I mean, that's so terrible.
This is Mike Coats and John [inaudible].
They are the co owners of coins.
I had a few weeks back, a
grandmother who was in tears.
She was going to lose all of her family
photos and because the deadline was
coming up, you know, crawling on
the phone to me and it got it.
It felt horrible.
Now clearly people who sell bitcoin just
believe that there should be a digital
currency that is decentralized.
It doesn't rely on the banks,
but unfortunately it has become
the currency of choice for ransom.
And so they, they're
in this weird position.
So it's a tricky thing because like,
I can't sell bitcoin to someone who I
know is going to do something illegal with
it, right.
That's will wheeler who runs a
bitcoin exchange called express coin.
And he says he and the other exchanges
are really worried right now that if they
keep helping the little guys pay the
ransom in order to get their files back,
they are in effect making
themselves accessories to a crime.
I finally got a call
back from a fin cen, uh,
which is the federal authority for
Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.
They said that we could perceive
paying a ransom as unlawful activity.
And so they might choose to use that
against the company who helps out, right.
And likely until we get a straight
answer from Vince and we'll take the, uh,
overly cautious approach and start
declining these transactions.
Even though in your heart you
want to help. Well, yeah, I mean,
do I want to risk being indicted
for helping you get your, uh,
travel receipts reimbursed
from your company? And I
mean, to me the answer's no.
In any case,
after Alina deposits the extra 25
bucks in her mom's bitcoin account,
ina the mom goes online,
[inaudible] leaked
and it was gone.
But then about an hour later,
I went to my computer and
[inaudible] the message that you are
Lynn Jones out that I was
doing the half hours late,
you have to pay
$1,300 roughly.
I did not have anybody to turn to.
So she went to that same website
where you can write them a message.
I wrote them that I was late,
but I mentioned the snow storm,
the things given, which they
probably [inaudible] off.
And the, of course,
the wonderful u s uh, mail service.
I said that I tried and I was only two
hours late and then all of a sudden
[inaudible]
I am getting the message you paid in full
without any explanation.
Nothing you pay. That's it.
And I got all my files back.
Oh,
do you think that they
took pity on her eye?
Maybe I felt that
it's over. Finally. It's really over.
No.
[inaudible]
it does make you wonder
like who these people are.
Leave a story about that up next
[inaudible].
Hello. This is Michelle
from Kaka Alpha Hawaii.
Radiolab is supported in
part by the Alfred Peace,
the UN foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and technology in
the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org mahalo.
Hey, this is jad. Radiolab is supported
by rocket mortgage by quicken loans.
Chances are you're confident
when it comes to your work,
your hobbies and your life.
Rocket mortgage gives you that same level
of confidence when it comes to buying
a home or refinancing your existing
home loan. Rocket mortgage is simple,
allowing you to fully understand all
the details and be confident that you're
getting the right mortgage
for you. To get started,
go to rocket mortgage.com/radiolab
equal housing lender licensed in all 50
states. NMLS consumer
access.org number 30 30
in the moments before Charles Kinsey
was shot by police in summer 2016 he
pleaded with the autistic
man next to him to lie down.
Please lay down in the
cell phone video cuts.
I'm Audrey Quinn after effect is a
new podcast from w n y c studios.
We tell the story behind the
shooting and what happened next.
Listen and subscribe to after effect
wherever you get your podcasts.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm
Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
So here's the next obvious who did this to
you know like do we know
anything about them?
When we put that question to a Joseph
men investigative reporter for Reuters,
done a ton of work in this area
and his hunch was that Inas right?
We're talking people,
Russian speaking folks.
By and large you had a book
called fatal system error,
which is sort of a deep dive into the
Russian hacking scene and much of it is as
you'd expect, you know, young guys, early
twenties kind of Grubby by and large,
they do not live a lavish lifestyle.
There are guys at the top of
these criminal organizations
that are very flashy
there like sort of pop icon,
some of them in the same way that rap
stars are in the u s there's a hacker
magazine with Gino as has has guys with
their sports cars and the supermodels
and whatever, you know,
buying bottle service,
you know discos at three in the morning.
Those are the guys who
hire the 20 year olds.
They hired the 20 year olds where they're
their franchise and he says the 20
year old brants working
office parks. Yeah, it's like a
call center type of atmosphere.
Is there like you know that's pretty Sir
Kelsey Padgett Ivan in a cubicle at his
computer board.
He has a meeting later with Judy
in HR and he's mad about it.
Is that the kind of like environment
that these people are in?
For the most part? I think so, yes.
The larger point is that it's not just
like you're a lone wolf pimply faced
hacker anymore. Cybercrime
is now super organized.
It is often corporate.
It is big business in the whole sort of
economy seems to revolve around these
secret sites where people come together
to buy and sell, things like that.
Ransomware from our last story there,
these underground web forms, the end,
there's a variety. Some are available.
You can reach you on the open Internet.
The more impressive ones are
password protected. You know,
you have to know somebody to get
in the really, really fancy ones.
You have to have a couple
of people vouch for you.
You actually have to apply with
your resume, your hackers resume.
Here are the things I can bring.
These are the kinds of hacking exploits
that I've had and therefore I should be
part of your exclusivity
club.
That Stina Temple rast in NPR,
cyber crime correspondent.
She's been tracking the government's
attempts to shut down some of these sites,
which she describes as sort of
a hackers black market. Bizarre.
So let's say someone is looking for a
bunch of credit card numbers that have
been stolen. You can get it
there. There's at one price,
if they're mastercard gold and
another price for you know,
a higher level credit, whatever.
Let's say you wanted to know about a
boss or an employee or a girlfriend,
you can get this piece of software that
allows you to turn on their phone at
any, anytime.
You could basically ease drop on them
cause you're in their pocket and for $300
a month you would actually get customer
service and the prices actually keep
coming down. It's a very, very
evolved fluid marketplace.
There's feedback and there's escrow.
There are feedback forms coming that CIF
was not really, there was like didn't,
didn't do the fee, the robbery. Right.
Absolutely. Particularly for something.
You'll see it a lot for
um, freshness of credit cards. Cause
you know, it's easy to say, you know,
here are 10,000 credit card numbers,
but if their credit card numbers had
been out for awhile and get declined,
everybody you've just wasted your money
and these people were called rippers a
is in there ripping you off and they
will get banned from the form. Wow.
It's reputational. Just like
everywhere else. Yeah. And it's,
it's as good as Ebay. If you
feel safe doing business on Ebay,
there's no reason you shouldn't feel
safe doing business with the criminals.
Now, uh,
all of this to me frankly felt like just
a sexy hacker talk until a couple of
months ago, Dina started telling
us about this one particular site.
Actually the biggest of these
kinds of sites. It's out there.
It's called dark code. Yeah.
The way it has been described by law
enforcement is sort of an amazon.com for
hackers. Actually,
here's specifically how us attorney
David Hickson described to her in an
interview.
Uh,
dark code is the largest English speaking
criminal cyber crime forum in the
world.
And one of the, I think most people know
Silk Road and they know, for example,
you could get a contract hit a a
from Silk Road and drugs and guns and
everything else.
So would it be right for me to say
that this was sort of a Silk Road for
hackers?
Yeah, I wouldn't want to
draw that direct comparison.
I think it's probably accurate.
I would say that all measure of cyber
crime that you see and watch around the
world was in some form or
fashion connected through it.
So we got really interested
in this world of this site,
dark coat in the people in it.
And so with Deena we started calling
around trying to find anyone that would
talk. And after weeks of searching
and calling and lawyering,
we found a guy who agreed
to go on the record.
My name is Daniel [inaudible]
and uh, I am a reformed hacker
as far as we know. Dan has never
talked about this publicly.
So how did you get
involved with Darko? Well,
I was one of the people who created it
a very long time ago. Daniel story
begins, not in Russia, but in Milwaukee.
Sure. Well, let me, let me start
with a little bit of con's.
Small Middleclass suburb
right outside of Milwaukee.
Do you have brothers and sisters? Two
younger brothers and two younger sisters.
Big family.
You have to share rooms with them or
were you in your own little kingdom?
[inaudible] I shared a room with both
my brothers for a lot of years. In fact,
that sort of plays into the story cause
he says what he would do to sort of
escape is go to the basement and
play video games. So yes, the,
the stereotypical hacker in his
parent's basement. I know, I know.
It's quite hilarious.
Dan says his hacking began innocently
enough when he would monkey with games
like age of empires. I hadn't
changed the graphics change,
the artificial intelligence of the
game, the way it plays, um, rework it,
create new maps, that type of
thing. Um, something I enjoyed.
And slowly, uh, throughout my teenage
years that developed into something more
[inaudible]
I, uh, did not get along well
with a lot of my peers in,
in grade, in middle
school. So I spent, um,
a lot more time know on the computer
and on myself than I did, um,
socially at least at that age.
And he says one day he was in a chat room
and internet chat room was called game
search, talking with a bunch of other
people about video games. And um,
at some point along the way he
meets this guy, you know, this,
this particular guy was into,
you know, botnets. Oh yes.
Botnets. We all cry. Yeah. Just remind
us what, what, what's going on there.
Botnets are, you know, malware
viruses installed on computers and um,
botnets, you know,
are the way to centrally control a whole
lot of infected computers. Just to,
to put this in context for saying, cause
I think this is totally fascinating.
Joseph Mens says that this whole
botnet situation, it started with spam.
One of the easiest ways to make money on
the Internet back pre 2000 a was spam.
Spam is in and out, penis
extensions, all that stuff.
What happened was that the, in the olden
days, most servers mail servers, uh,
acted as open relays,
meaning the mail people wouldn't really
pay attention to who was sending what.
So the spammers with spam, with abandon,
and then spam got to be enough of a
problem that the techies of the world
decided that's it. They
started to block people.
Like if they found a guy who they thought
was sending too many product emails or
whatever,
they would block his IP address so
that he couldn't send any more mail.
So what the spammers and their contractors
then needed to do was to have a bunch
of clean IP addresses
and send spam from that.
So what they did, which is
totally genius, totally evil,
is they hired a bunch of programmers
to create a bunch of viruses,
disseminated those viruses
across the internet.
People would accidentally click or open
something, get them onto their computer,
and then suddenly the spammers could
now remote control our computers at a
distance whenever they wanted for maybe
just an hour or two a night to send out
their spam because these were
clean IP addresses. Of course.
What happened is that once the
spammers had these botnets,
they started thinking, Hey, I
could do something else with this.
And the next thing that came along
was denial of service attacks.
You can have all of them tried to contact
ebay.com at the same time and knock
over Ebay.
This first gentleman that I ran
into, he had a botnets of um,
well over a thousand computers, which
you know, at the time was amazing to me,
you know, by today's
standards, a thousand for.
And that is nothing now they can get
up into the millions. But um, you know,
back then it was quite incredible to me
and cause he says he was in this chat
room, this guy was there and this guy
would get into fights with people.
And anytime he did,
he'd point his 1000 computer drone
army at that enemy and bet few, man,
I'm gonna Knock your Internet offline
and there's nothing you can do about it.
You know, if it was something in a game,
he could knock the game server that
they were playing on offline, you know,
stop their game. Things like that.
Take away years ball back
in 1935. That is exactly it.
Taking away someone else's
ball over the internet.
So this for some reason intrigued you?
Yes. It was amazing to me. I'm like,
you have of a thousand
computers. Wow. You know, how,
how did you do this? You know, I, I had,
at the time I had never heard of botnets.
I didn't know about any of this stuff.
Like how did you, how did you
get the software to do this?
How did you get it onto
all these computers?
And he was quite happy to tell you
all that. Oh, he certainly was this,
this particular gentleman
had a very large ego.
And did you see him as a bad
guy? Um, yeah. To be honest,
I, I think at that age
I didn't really, uh,
think about it that deeply. It's
the Internet. It's a lot harder to,
um, kind of quantify right
and wrong there. I mean,
now doesn't mean it's easy to look back
at that and say, yeah, this is wrong,
but it's not like going up to someone
and punching them in the face.
There's no human connection there.
You don't see these people
or feel these people.
He says at the time it
was just sheer curiosity.
Okay.
So he says he asked this Pied Piper guy
to send him some with the Bot software
that made the botnet go. And that
really intrigued me, you know,
digging through the source code, trying
to understand what is this thing doing,
how does it work, how does it tick?
And this guy, was he a good coder?
Like is he good at it? Was he
good at it? Yeah. Uh, no, no,
I, I would, uh, you know,
in hindsight now, you know,
he's what I would classify as a
script kitty. You know, someone who
that is, but it's a whole new
curse to read off a script Kiddie.
So a script kitty is someone who has just
enough technical ability to Kinda take
some tools and software that other people
have created and just use them. Yeah.
To fast forward.
As Dan went the opposite direction of
the script kitties and got better and
better and started making these botnets
that could literally spy on people as
they were using their computers.
Interesting to see all the porn that
people are watching, that type of thing.
He says he found himself in another
chat room that was called Bach Talk.
This kind of place where hackers swap
tips. Brag like, Hey, look what I did.
I had to face this website,
take a look, and he says,
one day he was talking with a coder
friend of his guy named is there though we
were talking and why don't we set up a
community where we can really filter who
gets to join and to let all these
script kitties and idiots in,
I actually chose the name. I came
up with that a nice lame name.
I actually think it's pretty little
name again. Dark Code. Dark Code.
It's like with the carer.
K. O. D. E I think. Right?
It seemed cooler with the k. Yes.
So we chose the name and started getting
the site set up the rules where it
would be invite only.
So you had to have an invite and
each new person would be required to
demonstrate their skill. You know, here's
a piece of software that I created,
or here's a video of my botnet and action.
And at some point I'm not too
long after it was created,
it was decided for one reason
or another that you know, hey,
we got all these programmers on
here, that's great, but you know,
they also want to be able to sell
some of the stuff they're making.
So let's invite some people who would
be willing to buy some of this stuff.
This now begins to sound like a fair,
you said, well, I have a burglar's tool.
Do you a door, you want a burgle
and then I'll rent you my tool.
That's a simplification. But
yeah, people would post and say,
I'm looking to buy x, or here's
this piece of software I created.
Here's all the things it does,
here's some screenshots of it
in action and here's the price.
Could be a certain type
of botnet software.
It could be buying a
botnet itself. You know,
if you don't want to build one yourself,
you want to buy us one that somebody else
already created and has going. I mean,
I can get you onto 200,000 or 20,000
computers just giving me a check.
Yeah. What they called them were
installs, installs, you know, hey guys,
I've got installs and they're
$10 per 1000 something like that.
Now this is something that's sort of
surprising to us that when it comes to
botnets that there's this whole rental
market that's frighteningly affordable.
Yeah, it's bargain basement. In fact,
we were talking with one reporter,
Kelly Jackson Higgins,
who is the executive editor of dark
reading.com which is a cyber security new
site, and she told us you can actually
rent a botnet if you really wanted to.
You could rent a botnet for one hour
for about $38 a month in some cases as I
was 20 yes. As low as $20 a month. I can
go rent a botnet for 20 bucks a month.
You could.
It's like renting space here or you want
to use this to go do damage somewhere
or you want to make a statement
or you have some plan for,
do you want to send
some spam? Here you go.
You could go online right now and probably
find somewhere out there on the net,
somebody who will sell you access to
computers for cents a piece and these are
like people's computers,
like your computer,
my computer and Dan says as
dark code got bigger and bigger,
he began to see more of this
kind of activity on the site.
Like some guy would have a
bot net of 5,000 computers.
Another guy would have some software,
like the ransomware software guy would
then rent the botnet from guy one install
his ransomware ransom. These
poor people then move on.
You know, some of the
people were, you know,
doing some pretty
unpleasant things, you know,
moving more into the kind of financial
crimes territory, you know, which is,
you know, something that I really
never had a desire to be involved in.
It was largely because of that. He says
that in 2009, he decided to get out,
but unfortunately, the next year
I got a lovely visit from the FBI.
Um, they promptly, uh,
was it a like kick down in your door type
situation? They knocked, they knocked,
so, okay. What was that like? Ah,
pretty terrifying. You know, what, uh,
what's going to happen to me? What's gonna
Happen next and what did happen next?
I don't know how much of that
I can talk about, but, um,
I did cooperate with the government
and I have cooperated with them for the
last, you know, five plus years now
was a kick in the butts. You know,
my parents, uh, kind of kicked me
out. Not that kicked me out, but, uh,
assisted me with a rapid move out and, uh,
I've been living on my own since then
and, uh, became gainfully employed,
had a few jobs, um,
became a little bit more and
more serious, uh, with my,
my then girlfriend who is now
my wife. So, um, you know,
it's given me an opportunity over the
last five years to really make some
serious changes to my life.
[inaudible]. Meanwhile,
over the same five years,
dark code grew into this massive
cyber criminal swat mean where tens of
thousands of stolen social security
numbers were bought and sold.
Huge databases of personal information
and emails were bought and sold.
Malware and software of various
kinds are bought and sold.
And this continued coin to Dina Temple
and right up until July 15th of this
year, July 15th, 2015
today marks a milestone in our efforts
to bring to justice some of the most
significant cyber criminals in the world.
What ended up happening on July 15th is
that the FBI had actually gotten into
Darko with a number of intelligence
services from around the world,
and they had an 18 month investigation
in which they took down, right?
In the end, 28 people.
The FBI has effectively
smashed the Hornet's nest,
and we are in the process of
rounding up and charging the Hornets.
But here's, here's what's amazing, right?
So they take down a more than two
dozen people. Two weeks later,
dark code is up again, which just
popped back up, just popped back up.
A deep gratitude to
NPRs Dina Tempo Reston,
who's reporting really got us
going on this whole project. Yeah.
Props to Kelsey paget do produce our first
segment and emails who produced their
second segment and who can from memory
give you the extended family tree of dark
code. It's just right out of
his head, right of his head.
You got original music this hour from
dub mood and Bianco Bay. Yeah. Wow.
Thanks. Also to Andrew Zali,
Michael Shammo, Gunther Omen,
Lynn leading happy rotor. Elsa Cathy too.
Don't forget attorney David Vaccaro and
the whole crew at the Microsoft Cyber
Crimes Unit and to you,
Robert, thank you to you. Hi.
Way me because you're part of my botnet
cause I'm Jeff from Ryan Roberto,
which thanks for listening.