You are listening to
radiolab radio from W N Y s e
n p r gave this a Jad
Abumrad. This is radio lab,
the podcast. Robert is out of
town today. He's actually um,
his son is getting
married. So it's just me.
I thought in this podcast
a and wander a little bit
[inaudible] generally and that should
be in front of your mouth. Okay.
So I'm gonna Start with a conversation
that uh, Brooke Gladstone and I,
this is Brooke from on the media that
she and I had with my brother in law
Eugene. I am Eugene Thacker.
I am an author and professor at
the new school in New York City.
We talked about this very weird thing
that happened to Eugene and I asked Brooke
to join me cause I just
felt like her kind of story.
I've been wearing black since I was 13.
I just want to point out that the two of
you are head to toe in black right now.
Any case to set it up.
Eugene is a hard core
scholar of philosophy and he
writes these books that um,
sometimes can be a little dense. I mean,
he'll use words like
exegesis and radio sunation.
And so the family joke is that
he writes books for no one.
I think the joke started out, I
write books that nobody reads.
And then after a slow, long period
of acceptance, I started to think,
well, maybe I should write
books for no one to read.
And just sort of embrace that
meaning at a certain point,
if you do this kind of work, you
kind of have to ask yourself,
if you knew that this would not be
published, would you still write it?
How committed are you? And
he decided he was committed.
He would write it no matter what. So
the story begins a couple of years ago,
and I'm 2011 Eugene writes this book
called in the dust of this planet,
in the dust of this planet. It's
kind of a hard book to describe,
but if you had to sum it up in a sentence,
it's a about the end of the world,
but not in the Hollywood
sense. It's darker than that.
Your hypothesis is the greatest horror
is that nothing exists and nothing
matters.
And the world that we live in that we
define in terms of humanity doesn't care
about us.
What in philosophy is often referred
to as nihilism or pessimism that there
might not be a purpose to things or to
your life or to our existence or to the
cosmos. There might not
be an order to things.
We might not be here for a reason.
This all might be purely arbitrary and
an accident that there's no inherent
meaning to anything, but
it just doesn't matter.
This is what Nietzsche called most
difficult thought and in the book,
Eugene traces this idea
through all of these different
horror movies from slasher films to sort
of more supernatural horror and also
music. I mean,
at one point he goes into
this deconstruction of how
different types of black
metal with this thought. I Dunno, it's,
it's something, it's a way of thinking.
I've always found really intriguing
and ironically kind of inspiring.
Are you a pessimist on my
better days? Are you a nihilist?
Not as much as I should be. Okay,
so Eugene writes this book in
2011 it is dark, it is dense.
He writes it as he says,
for no one. And as expected,
beyond a few philosophy types,
no one really pays attention.
So he keeps his head down
teaching, writing, but then
some things happen.
Hmm. 2014 ghettos in the world.
I saw on get, Oh man,
Jack Gutter and outer space to
show true detective comes along.
It comes to big head. And at the center
of the show is this character Russ Cole,
this Louisiana detective who
is one dark dude. I think human
consciousness is the tragic
misstep and evolution.
He goes on these rants about how
there's no order in the world,
how humans are just this accident.
And we have to deal with that.
I'd consider myself Hurria last time,
but in philosophical terms
on what's called a pessimist.
And I just remember watching it and
being like, wow, that's Eugene's wife,
Prima Murphy, my
sister-in-law. I was like,
this replicates so many conversations
that we've had in the car. She's like,
were they listening in on us? Yeah,
it was eerie. So prayma goes online,
clicks around and all of a
sudden I see this article about,
um, the true detective director.
It was an article where
actually the writer of the show,
nick a lotto was asked how did you create
that character of the nihilist police
detective? And he lists a bunch of
things he was reading at the time.
And included in that list was
Eugene to which I was like,
cool.
At least one person is reading the book.
But I really just try to keep my head
to the ground and just keep writing,
just doing what I'm doing. But then
things got weird. Okay, so
now let's pull up the um,
the Lucky magazine and see if I
can find it. Short time later,
prima is flipping through this
fashion magazine, Lucky magazine.
And there was a spread with
this actress Lily Collins,
25 year old actress I'd
never heard of. Pretty big.
Right now she's standing on a street
corner dressed up and all of this sort of
goth makeup and clothing.
And in the photo she is
wearing Eugene's book on her chest she
had on and one of the shots of sweatshirt
that had the cover of the book
in the dust of this planet.
Big letters right on her chest. And
I was just like, no way. You know,
it was definitely,
this is crazy. Like what?
She's just casually wearing
my husband's book cover.
I Dunno. Again, I didn't react
to you, but it was just strange.
Turns out a Norwegian artists
had made a painting of the book.
That image had gotten picked up by a
fashion label and turned into some very
expensive clothes. You know, I
write books for no underwriting,
so obviously I'm not pulling
in a lot of royalties on these,
but you know, Eugene says
he's not going to sue.
I'm not going to see her take any legal
action or really do anything about it
because he says that's not why he
writes. Okay. So that happened,
but then it gets weird are still
[inaudible].
So one day my wife Carla Murthy is online.
This is the day that Jay z and Beyonce
announced they're going to do this big
international tour.
Carla's watching the video that they
released to promote that to a sort of a
fake movie. Right?
This is all, I'm the one
that's all flashy guns.
Fire occurs.
Here's smart guy. It doesn't really
make a whole lot of sense. I mean,
it's some kind of Bonnie and
Clyde thing, I think. I mean,
they're running from someone,
you're not quite sure who Beyonce is in
a wedding dress. She's got a veil on,
but she shooting semiautomatic weapons
in her wedding dress, cut tech,
car chases, cut their money
flying everywhere, but it exactly,
37 seconds in chorus, go
back, go back, go back.
It's like you're making me think too fast.
You see Jay z turn stick a giant gun out
to his right and he is wearing Eugene's
book. Hey, my life
right there on his back in the dust
of this planet. Uh, a sound as well,
and make them smile. Yeah.
This is the point at which I was like,
okay, what do we make of this? I mean,
could it be that Eugene is no
longer writing books for no one,
that somehow he has become a conduit
for this idea that we all in that
subterranean way that pop music operates,
that we all are channeling right now?
That was my thought. Yeah.
No, I think that's, uh,
that's the question is whether this is
something particular to the moment we're
living in and Eugene, his
knee jerk reaction is,
I think it could have been this
cover or a million other covers. No,
this is just meaningless appropriation.
I don't think there's anything more
than that to me then it's just,
it looks like a cool phrase to go on a
tee shirt to put on a golf Carla in some
photo shoots. And why is it cool? Right?
Cause my hunch is you might be right,
but you also might be wrong because of
the answer that you're about to give to
Brooks question. It's cool
because some publicists,
and this was sort of the conversation I
wanted to have, and so I called Brooke,
like, what is behind all of
this nihilistic entertainment
that's everywhere.
Now, Brooke, for her part,
agreed that Eugene probably is
tapping into something, yes,
but is this unique to this moment?
And to that I would say, no,
really?
You don't think this says anything about
now I think there are cycles in which
the sense of meaninglessness
comes out in sharper
relief than other times,
but you can identify
them over and over again.
Yeah, nihilism goes all the way back.
Brooke actually turned us onto this
guy, Simon Critchley and the hands,
yon as professor at the new
school for social research.
Simon wrote an article that, uh,
basically made the argument that nihilism
is the basic credo of cool because
it's, it's sexy. It's interesting
and it's been that way forever. Oh,
I have to go. I've got, I've got the
best thing for you. You love this.
It's a Russian word, right? He said
the word really got its pop in 1862.
This is 150 years ago.
There's a novel by two you have called
fathers and songs and in the novel,
the son who's the nihilist turns to
his conservative dad and he says,
we base our conduct on what we
recognize as useful in these days.
The most useful thing we can do is to
repudiate. And so we repudiate everything.
The father says, everything,
everything with indescribable composure.
So that's the gnarliest
moment everything goes.
And Simon says, roughly
from that point on,
you see a young people glom on to
this idea again and again as a way to,
you know,
say no to the older generation or to
just what's happening in the world.
For example, after World War One you
had tens of millions of people dead.
This lost generation that was confused
and disgusted at what had just happened.
And out of that says,
Brooke, you get Dadada.
I want to pull up here on the computer,
the manifesto of Tristan Saara. He was
one of the founders of the data movement.
You says, Dada means nothing.
Everything one looks at
is false. I do not die.
That abolition of memory,
Dada abolition of archeology,
Dadada abolition of profits.
Dada abolition of the future.
And after World War II,
she and Simon say he had similar movements
in the 70s and 80s with the threat of
nuclear annihilation. You get
punk rock. It just keeps going.
Pop Culture, at least since I was a
kid, has always been deeply nihilistic,
you know. All right. So it's nothing new.
But when I ran Simon through the Eugene
jacket situation and then I asked him
like,
is there something different about today's
nihilism versus nihilism of the past?
Like is there something more potent
about it? Without hesitation, he said,
I see, I see. Yes. Huh?
Based on one that's producer Andy Mills
who was with me during the interview.
Well, you know, you can,
you can get, Simon says,
it was more of a gut feeling, uh,
based on this class that he taught
last year with Eugene. Oddly enough,
I didn't actually know
that they knew each other,
but they had taught this class together.
So the seminar that we
did in the fall last year,
it was one of those rare seminars.
We're teaching mysticism.
Nobody teaches mysticism, really
obscure stockwood in desert fathers,
medieval female mystics.
This is early Christianity.
Neither of us are religious.
He says they started the seminar not
really expecting much by talking about how
in the fourth century, a d there was this
sissy Alexandria, this is near Egypt.
My Alexandra was a lot like Manhattan.
There was an offshore island.
It was a colony of a full
Moan Power Roman empire.
But it's the cease of old culture and
all learning in the ancient world.
A certain point in a full
century, people start to leave.
They start to leave
and go into the desert.
People wander off and they
seem to want something else.
The city doesn't just
doesn't do it anymore.
Why? It's corrupt. It's
broken. It's a, it's sinful.
He said crime was rampant pollution.
And so people just started to wander
off into the desert and live in these
caves. And uh,
these intense forms of ascetic practice
begin like you had these women who were
not educated because women
couldn't be educated,
who is so enraptured with Christ
that they began hosting themselves,
throwing themselves into icy
rivers, jumping into ovens.
The body is something which is you're
trying to strip away in order that you can
free the capacity for love.
Like that's a classic mystic idea, right?
The body is just getting in the way.
I want to go soul to
soul with God. Exactly,
but the premise of that again is that the,
the world is a kind of field of ruins,
but he says what really struck him is
that as he was talking about all this,
he would glance out at the students and
he would notice this look in their eyes.
I just felt that in the
room there was this,
this deep need was being fulfilled
by these strange mystics.
He said the students were just in it
in a way that almost never happens when
you're teaching. We weren't
not saving souls, but it was,
it was hissing something really,
really deep. What exactly,
I mean do you think they were starting
to form the thought of wandering into the
desert so to speak? Yeah, I think there's
a sense of wishy you, you know what?
You do a succeed, walk away. You know?
That's where a lot of people are are.
As for what's behind it all he
says, just turn on the news.
A video showing the beheading of a
second American journalist has now been
verified as these experts say,
this is turning into one of the
longest deadliest outbreaks ever.
The girls were gang raped
on strangled. Once again,
it is mostly children we are
seeing brought into this hospital.
The world I grew up, in my
sense it was completely crazy,
mutually assured destruction, but it
made sense and you could understand it.
Simple terms that he states
was the Soviet Union.
We were going to be eviscerated.
That was clear, but it, you know,
you knew what the balance
of power was. You're,
you're a nostalgic for
mutually assured destruction.
Is that what's happening now? It
seems a much simpler world. Well,
you at least knew who to blame for
it. Right? Right. That's Andy. Again,
I'd be like, that's the thing.
Like you look at the Cold War and you
could see like specifically like the
you Americans. Yeah, the nukes. That's
right. Right. That's right. And now,
yeah. Who am I supposed to say? You
too. I'm saying you to everybody.
Carbon emissions.
Speaking of which today,
the world's leading climate scientists
warn it will get worse, no doubt.
One of the reasons for the current
gloom is that we are in the middle of an
uncomfortable shift in how
we talk about climate change.
Waves will be more frequent
and last longer. This is
made official when the IPC,
the intergovernmental panel on climate
change released a report where for the
first time they stopped using the
language of prevention and shifted to the
language of adaptation. In other words,
hundreds of scientists and policymakers.
This is the world's top organization
for assessing climate change.
We're now saying we can't
stop it. It's inevitable.
And so now we need to talk about
dealing with the mass that is now on our
doorstep. That's David Victor,
professor of international relations at
a University of California at San Diego,
and he is one of the
authors of the report.
When the IPC first began back in the
late 1980s you could imagine that people
would take the climate
change problem seriously.
They would start to control emissions
and then over a period of decades,
climate would stop changing.
And instead of what's happened is people
have talked a lot about climate change,
but they haven't actually done
much to control emissions.
And now he says,
we're all in this strange middle ground
where we're trying to find the language
to say why it's important to keep
working at this while at the same time
admitting some degree of failure.
That's the kind of inevitability
that I think you see in the new, uh,
the new reports and the
reports are bending over
backwards to try and find ways
to be optimistic. You know,
the report says if you put into place
all these technologies and international
agreements, we could, we could
still stop warming at two degrees.
My own assessment is that the kinds of
actions you'd need to do that are so
heroic that we're not going
to see them on this planet.
Olive, which reminded me of that
true detective moment. Okay.
I'd consider myself a real last time,
but in philosophical terms on
what's called a pessimist. Okay.
What's that mean? Well, a pessimists
like nihilist agree. There's no meaning,
they're just a little more mopey about it.
Less likely to do something
means I'm bad at parties. I mean,
is that where we're all headed? You know,
in a recent Wall Street Journal poll,
76% of people 18 and over weren't
confident that the future is going to be
brighter than the past. Which brings me
back to Brooks question. Why is it cool?
Call it nihilism, pessimism,
whatever. Shouldn't it be depressing?
Why would you want to put a phrase
like in the dust of this planet,
a phrase that deliberately
negates the person wearing it?
Why would you want to put it on your
chest or on your back? Yeah, yeah,
that's fine. Yeah,
and since it was Jay z jacket,
which was in a way the catalyst
for this whole podcast,
we decided to talk to him for
he sorta that's coming up.
This is Darlene from Kampala,
Uganda.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by Morgan Stanley.
Your son has a gift for gymnastics.
Your daughter has her eye on a little
startup in the valley and you want to
retire early. Now,
how do you create a wealth plan that
reflects all the complexity of a modern
family?
Start with a financial advisor who
understands individuals and knows how to
bring families together around
both shared m personal goals.
More information@morganstanley.com
slash conversations Morgan Stanley Smith
Barney, LLC, member civic. Hi,
this is Chris from New Jersey.
Radiolab is supported by Reuters TV,
a new tool for busy people who want to
know what on earth is going on made by
the world's largest news organization
with over 2,500 reporters all over the
planet. Waiters TV is video news
as it should be. No hot air,
no talking heads, and no theatricals
available on your favorite device. Ios,
android, Roku, or apple
TV. It's personalized.
Always up to date and ready when
you are. See for yourself, go to
reuters.tv/radio lab.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab is
supported by Google and Squarespace.
Make your business official
with Google and square space.
When you create a custom domain and
a beautiful business website with
Squarespace, you'll receive
a free year of business,
email and professional tools from Google.
It's the simplest way to
look professional online.
Visit squarespace.com/google
to start your free trial.
Use the offer code document for
10% off on your first purchase.
Google and Squarespace. Make it
professional. Make it beautiful,
Ron. Good. That sounds great. Over there.
Hey, this is jazz. This is radio lab.
So we ended up in the flow of things, you
know, as we were trying to figure out,
like in the dust of this
planet. Why isn't that cool?
Why isn't it just scary and depressing?
We ended up like they want to talk
to me. Why? That's a good question.
Talking to this lady who it turns out
was the person who made the decision to
put it on Jay z's back. I
should say my name, I guess. Uh,
my name is June Ambrose. I've been
a costume designer for 22 years.
2023 this year, and I've
worked with everyone from
Luther Vandross to puck to Sean
tomorrow. Carey, Busta rhymes.
Mary's your blush. Alicia
keys. Dave Matthews,
pat backstreet boys. Kelly
Ripa can control do this,
but a r Kelly, go hit on Jamie Fox.
Please do for missy Elliot. Did
you do the missy with the balloons?
Yeah. That was you. Yeah.
Oh my God. And of course
Jay Z and Beyonce. That's
like culture basically. Yeah.
I was responsible for
something. That Nazi stuff.
It occurred to Andy and I
during the interview that
June has probably influenced
the fashion sense of a significant portion
of the human beings on this planet.
And she was very clear that a
costume is more than just a costume.
It's like a conversation
without words. They
really, what she's doing,
when she styles someone is whispering to
all the people that are gonna watch the
videos, come in contact with the
billboards, go to the concerts.
I don't have to talk to you,
but I can create this conversation with
a pair of pants and how they fall and
how they fit in the texture
and the color. Yeah.
The field. He says with
Jay Z for that video,
she knew she needed something epic but
like effortless. I knew I wanted a bike,
a jacket, cause there
was a motorcycle scene,
but I knew that I just couldn't give
him a black vote. I needed it to,
I need it to say some feel like
something. We were on the hunt,
her and her assistant went to
dozens of places, Tillys studios,
the showrooms looking at
all these leather jackets.
It's like finding a needle in
a haystack. Nothing was right,
but then they sound true into this
one place, black denim, this place,
it does sort of high end grunge.
They're flipping through the racks when
she sees it, the jacket, those
words, and that was it. I knew it.
I said, I need, this is what I need.
It just felt, I mean it was just
perfect.
The question was why this point? I hadn't
really told her the whole backstory,
so I pulled out a screen
capture from the video.
This is one where you see Jay z
sort of standing in the desert,
shot from behind in the
dust of this planet.
On his back and he's kind of pointing
this really long dirty Harry gun off to
his right. Sorta up like he's
about to shoot the sun here.
You think he's about to shoot the fence?
I printed it out cause it's just got
this like billboard quality to it right
here it is. I have a really cool
one in my phone too, isn't it?
Okay. So let's just look
at this for a second. Yeah.
So like why did you choose
that jacket? Um, you know,
it's something very menacing
about it. It's almost like
the aftermath
that there was something
going on that was periling.
It'd be end of an era. The
beginning of something new.
She says in the back of her head,
she was thinking about how the
music industry might be dying.
It's definitely in a place
where it's like, what? Now?
You can hear it in the music and you
know if this is the biggest tour in
history, really what now you know, and
these are the whispers that you hear,
but she says one of the loudest whispers
with super simple, just here's a guy,
massive pop star pack, a sovereign, he's
in the desert. It's about to go down.
The end of the world is
literally on his back foot.
It was almost as if he didn't
even know that was on his back.
You know what I mean? It's like that
was the afterthought. Like, Oh yeah,
the world's ending. Oops, I don't care.
Go on out and stuff. In other words,
he wasn't afraid. He wasn't afraid,
wasn't afraid. That's what, that's
what we talk about whispers.
That's what I get from it. Now, now
that you said that, it's not so much,
I don't give it. I'm not afraid. Yeah.
I mean we all have to lead the planet.
You know? Everybody has their day.
What you work on is not being
afraid when you have to leave.
Okay, that'd be cool.
Thank you. This is, um,
this was after refreshing
walking out of that interview.
Thank you. This was by the way, after
we had told her that phrase on Jay,
his back was lifted from him.
A book written by my brother
in law Eugene. Oh Wow. No,
I need to get the book and
I need to get it to Jay,
which he was very interested to know.
Can we do that? Yeah, let's do that.
And we did send him the book. You
haven't heard back. Oh my God. Anyhow,
walking out of there, I kept thinking,
is that what this is all about?
That all this pop nihilism around us is
not about tearing down power structures
or embracing nothingness. It's just
look at me, look how brave I am.
That I can wear it on a tee shirt. Yeah.
I would go with that. And this is why,
as you pointed out, you
know, from data to punk,
this isn't a recurring motif of how,
how bad ass you are in facing
mortality. Pluto. Badass.
That's what I was thinking. I think that
that is nothing more than a posture.
I mean it's all fine when you're
18 to wear that tee shirt,
but when you're like in your fifties
dealing with cancer, like okay, you know,
maybe, maybe then is when you really
have to confront those things. So I just,
it's a, it's simply a posture and
that's why it's in pop culture.
Quite cynical.
Sponsored pizza.
Say you know why we love nihilism in pop
culture is that it saves us having to
be burdened with it.
Simon Critchley again,
it saves us from feeling
it all right, we can,
we can enjoy it in our rooms. We can
get off on it and then we let it go
and we got, we got back to work.
But Simon says, you don't
have to be cynical about
this if you don't want to be.
I mean these are meeting Nietzsche,
Mr dark pessimists himself
had this idea about nihilism,
that it was just the beginning,
that if you really dealt
with it and took it in,
accelerated it to its logical end,
you could get to the other side,
which he called a reevaluation of values,
some new way of thinking about who we
are as moral creatures. And that's,
that's kind of where I am and love
love is that capacity which can see it
through that.
And that he suspects is why his students
were so interested in those mystics
cause they had found a way through
these people,
these mystics have got the
own compromising commitment
to something like love
the fact that they were ready to go all
the way to negate even their own bodies
for that love.
Right. So in a world where, where love
has been reduced to Tinder exchanges,
if that's the hell that you're living
in as a 25 year old, then yeah,
you got to read these mystics and
think I want what she's having.
I'll say, I'll say, I'll take
what she's having earned my flesh.
That's right by my friends.
And you could argue, I mean,
why not that Jay Z and Beyonce, you've
got a little bit of that going on.
I mean, part of what's made this tour,
so big biggest tour ever actually is
that it's like this grand love story and
with the love of my life. So it's,
it's like it worked. I have a fantasy,
I have a fantasy that Beyonce and Jay z
will do this tour and they will go off
into the desert and they'll live in
a little like this monastic existence
together in love in a new and
new sort of age of Aquarius.
We'll begin starting with the
two of them. That's beautiful.
The loudest Mike Trap.
Oh, any chance of that?
Are you gonna really hear me slip,
right? Yeah. That was your answer.
Finical out on the beach.
Maybe a perfect response
to Jan's question. Yeah.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
so Jen,
I can hear that you're going to take a
lot of this stuff and you're going to
look at the current moment and [inaudible]
and see how this idea is expressing
itself in this made me want to work to
go back and see when and where and how it
was x. It's been expressed
all along. Okay. So, uh,
I'm delighted to be on this. Yeah.
And I'm going to be delighted to have
you on our show in a couple of weeks.
Really? Yeah. We want you to come
on after after I've put it together.
Love that. We're pulling you in.
Oh, beautiful. I'm game. Okay.
Thank you for being game for this. Um,
you look for on the media's take
on nihilism in a couple of weeks.
Big thanks to produce Randy Mills,
who the process of helping me, uh,
put together this podcast began
to say things like other day.
I thought of it in the sense of I
saw this lady bug, my friends and I,
we were watching this lady
bug crawl around my shoe
and then it started to crawl
up my leg. It got caught in my leg,
hair fell back down to the shoe,
and we were all like, oh,
that's life. That's it, man.
We're all just bugs crawling
around on a God damn shoe.
And he was totally serious and special
thanks to the Murthy tribe and in two
zero books and of course to Eugene Vacher,
who even though we harbors no
redemptive fantasies about human beings
whatsoever, isn't awesome dude.
And this piece is an homage to him.
One of the most committed writers I know
also happens to be my brother-in-law.
If you would like to read
in the dust of this planet,
and I actually do highly recommend
it, it's super fascinating.
Go to our website, radiolab.org
and uh, we'll link you to it.
I'm Jad Abumrad thanks for
listening. [inaudible].