You're listening to
radiolab radio from Wny, c.
E. N. N. P. R.
[inaudible]. Um, we are
a church in a church. Oh,
that's,
it's not usually where we start.
We're in a church cathedral. Really?
A huge cathedral in Upper
Manhattan. Saint John,
the divine got an Oregon.
The preacher was preaching
congregation of course. Couple thousand
people in the pews. At least Jesus said,
therefore your basic Sunday service,
except today, you've also got,
here it comes.
The reason we begin here is because
today the church is filled with dogs.
I talked to you about your dog.
Yeah. What's his or her name?
His name is blizzard.
He's a Labrador and put Omex. Wow.
I have legend who I
just adopted in January.
I have Jen pow
bell by the way. In more than
dogs. You've got birds, Jessie.
It's a choir now and now. Has
this guy ever been blessed before?
I don't think so. No. Just
worn this year in hamsters.
His name is Toby. Teddy toes.
And if he'd come out you'd see why
because he's really fat and all kinds of
creatures. Got a little girl with a
falcon in behind her. Oh, it's a giant,
horrendous. This is
the Saint Francis Day of the animacy
yearly event coming toward us where people
bring their animals to be
blessed. Is it daunting?
The folks that are gathered here and
there is a little girl with a hermit crab.
They don't think there's anything
weird or inappropriate about this fact.
If you ask them in here comes up
both, here's what they say. I don't
know if it means anything to her,
but it means a to me cause you know you
want to baptize your babies and this is
more or less the same kind of thing. And
what does it, what does it mean to you?
It just means when, when she finally
does go away, she's gonna go to heaven.
What kind of parent it is?
She called [inaudible].
Don't put your hand near his face if
he wants. When you chuckle, struggle.
Do you feel like he has a, a soul
or an inner life of some sort?
It's a thinking being there. They're as
smart as we are. Really? Andrew? Okay.
Yeah. Since you invited me here. I
didn't want to be impolite or anything.
Say what you gotta say. Well,
okay. These people of course,
they love their animals.
Sure. Yeah. Can you hear that?
Because when I'm feeling sad comes in
the bed and he lays down spine to spine
with me and he just didn't leave
my side. The using a little bit.
The animals they love are going to feel
like grace of the prayer or feels the
blessing, which is a one which raises
a question.
What do we really know about what
goes on inside the animal's mind?
Yeah. All those things that you might
feel in a church. Grace, gratitude, uh,
guilt. Can the animals
feel those things too?
How much can we share and
can you measure it? Yeah.
I'm Jad Abumrad I am Robert
Krulwich. This is radio
[inaudible]
and we will begin the hour with a
story about an animal who would,
I'm sure love to have been at
the worship service, but it was,
it was a very inconvenient thing.
Didn't get eaten quite get there.
[inaudible]
okay. Just to get things rolling.
This is a story that we
heard about [inaudible] who
went off to talk about first
from the following day. Is
it or is it Mike [inaudible]?
There's way too many mics around make
men ago is his name. No here and a,
we met recently at the Emeryville Marina,
which is not far from San Francisco where
he's got a boat called the super fish
mix. Says he rents out for
all kinds of things. Sure.
Trips to ash gathering bachelor
parties, fireworks watching.
I got a little cardboard sign. I stand
by the freeway. Just have boat need work.
So yeah, that's mic. And our story
begins one morning in December,
probably eight o'clock in
the morning or something.
As I recall a few years back, Mick just
kind of sitting at home. I was at home.
Yeah, it was the middle of
December. We didn't have any work,
but then he gets this call.
Hello, you got this call.
There was the call relaying a message
from a fishermen way out at sea,
18 miles maybe outside
the golden gate bridge.
They told me that there
was a whale in trouble,
tangle up in grabbed gear and it
didn't appear to be able to move.
So after he hangs up and make
immediately calls a few dive buddies,
Jim Yong, Kim young air force, Para
rescue. And then uh, let's see,
James Mosquito, James Mosquito national
diver. I called them and said, hey,
you know, here's the deal. Are you
interested? It was a no brainer. I said,
yeah, I'm in. Absolutely. I
figured, all right, we're going.
I packed up my stuff,
grabbed my gear and I went directly
to the boat and we left underneath the
Golden Gate Bridge.
Nothing at the horizon in front of
us. My name is Holly [inaudible].
I am James's significant tethered.
We motored out for about two hours.
Had to do less towards the means.
What were you feeling when
you're on the boat heading out?
I didn't think we'd find
it. I really didn't.
But about 18 miles off the
coast, completely open water.
One of the divers spots and crab buoys
in the distance and some seagulls flying
overhead. And as they got closer,
[inaudible] saw the whale,
just the very top of the whale sticking
up about maybe six inches out of the
water at the surface, a tiny
sliver of black. And that was it.
I said, okay, we needed to
see what's going on. So, uh,
so Tim and James Jump into an inflatable
boat and they paddle about a couple of
hundred feet from the way,
and it just wasn't happening. Every
time that the swale came on up,
it would just displace the boat back
again. So it would push us back again.
Not to mention the visibility
in the water was just terrible.
He couldn't even see down there to see,
you know, what they were dealing with.
And uh, you know what, sometimes plans
have to change in, in mid flight.
So Tim and James Look at each other
and without saying a word boom,
we got out of the boat and slash
until the water
and I see a shadow
[inaudible] massive
animal, a hazy silhouette.
And we just started swimming
[inaudible]
to the whale about a hundred feet away.
You know, parts of have blubber
and skin floating around 35 feet,
20 feet, and then they see it.
My goodness, this thing's
the size of a school bus.
A female humpback whale is one of
the largest creatures on the planet,
50 feet long, 50 tons,
and this particular whale was in a kind
of c shape where its head was at the top
of the water, but its tail was
almost pointed directly down.
It was almost like somebody was pulling
her down by the tail to the bottom of
the ocean.
Yeah, there was probably 20 crab traps,
2000 pounds at least
just tied up to the tail.
She had just become an anchor and to see
her not be able to move that tail and a
struggle, just like
the will was actually really laboring
to breathe a little puff and there was
just a rope
everywhere. It went
around the whale's mouth,
around the whales head across her
eye, over her background, the pickup
Toro fins all way down to his
tail. I thought there was no hope,
there was no chance.
We're looking at a dead well and
the whale just doesn't know it yet.
But I knew that I had to try win a swim
to the whale and as soon as I decided,
okay, I'm going to swim to the whale.
Well the whale decided she wasn't
going to have that. What you do,
she put up her pictorial fin,
which is like her arm and this
pictorial fins about 15 feet long.
It's about four feet wide. And she just
splashing down the water in front of me.
This is the size of an airplane
wing coming down on top of you,
just inches from my head. So yeah,
at that point I backed off and uh,
waited, waited for the
whale to settle down.
She was physically exhausted, which did,
and then they both swim back.
James goes to the tail and Tim,
up to the wheels head, you know, I was
there with a a six inch dive knife,
cutting out line right near her eye,
which was the size of a grapefruit.
[inaudible]
hinge her, I was moving,
keeping an eye on me.
Really. Absolutely. He would
go left or I would go left.
He'd go right or I would go right.
She was tracking me and all the wild.
They're just cutting as
much rope as they can.
You really had a saw at it. It
was very strong, very tight.
Sometimes I'd cut a rope and it would
be a loose rope and all of a sudden
something else would tighten up,
which was a one rope that would let it
all free. This whole process took hours,
but finally James gets to the end of ace
at the tail sign his way through that
big clump of line and he realizes at a
certain point it to cut through all that
line.
I'm going have to stab the whale to
get my knife underneath the rope. Ah,
it was that tight though.
I a jagged my knife into the whale's
tail and pull the rope and then cut it
and it wants the rope went
[inaudible].
It was a very surreal moment looking down
and seeing the 20 crab traps and buoys
just disappear into the abyss.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
and just like that the whale was gone.
I'm spinning around going, where
did she go? Where did she go?
But as the water settled, they realized
they'd done it. They'd freed her.
As soon as they came up, I was like,
Woo. Oh. Cooping it up and yelling.
Unbelievable. I was
screaming,
can you imagine now here's where the
story takes a pretty startling turn.
In fact,
the whole reason we wanted to tell this
story to begin with is for what happens
next. So Tim and James and the other day
was her in the water there celebrating,
high fiving and then all of
a sudden James looks down.
Next thing I know I have this
50 ton whale coming right at me.
I'm thinking, oh my God,
stop. I just stayed. Wait,
so this whale is coming at you
from below like jaws? Yeah,
she's rising up towards me. Oh God. I
was just thinking this is going to hurt
and like she was only
inches away from my chest.
[inaudible]
stopped
and
push me on the chest backwards
and then released me and
then kind of pushed again
and then release and pushed again
and again. Wow.
And then she swam up right next to me,
picks her head up the water so that her
eye was above the water and then came up
and looked directly at me
[inaudible]
and for what felt like 30 seconds.
He says she just stared at him.
People didn't move around. She
wasn't looking for anything else.
She was just looking
at me.
Mm,
you're in the presence of something
that great, makes you feel small.
It really wasn't a very
emotional feeling, you know,
wasn't quite sure what to
make out of it, make of it.
But then he says she went off to
the next dire, did the same thing.
I remember distinctly how is
18 inches away from her eye.
And she just looked at me and let
me touch her and then swam off.
Then she went off to the next
diver and did the same thing.
And the next person did the same thing
one by one coming up right next to him,
looking at him really good. And
you'll inches away eyeballing them.
Just swim around to every
diver. All the guys got, yeah.
So it was about desk. Um,
the water was glass flat.
I was sitting at the helm of the boat
just in awe and they had to leave the
whale. She didn't want to leave them.
And this is a real question here.
What exactly was that wheel doing
or saying? Was she saying anything?
If you asked James or Tim or
Mike or any of the other divers,
we're in the water that
day. They'll tell you.
I felt this whale was really thanking us.
I know it sounds crazy, but I
could see the look in her eye,
this mammal, this,
this 50 ton mammal was
literally saying things.
Thanks for helping me
out. And you know, I'll,
I'll bring that to my grave knowing
the gratification that I felt
[inaudible]
wow. So what do you think we,
here's the question really.
Was that whale saying thank
you? Was the whale thing? Well
I think the whale was saying
something. I mean a whale.
If she was just free to have her ups,
I would think she would just
go off and say, well I'm free.
So the fact that she was,
she hung around and make these specific
eyeball visits, like, I don't know.
I feel that she, there's something
intentional about that. She did,
she didn't leave anyone out right now.
She went, in fact, according to them,
one of the guys on the boat,
she actually went to the boats and
did the same thing to the boats.
She said thank you to the
boats. Yeah. Hm. Well then,
so she was looking at the people,
but she also thought the craft was,
somebody should say that
you or is I deal with, yeah,
so maybe she was just
site. Maybe she was just a,
yeah,
I really don't know what I mean. I don't,
I don't feel completely
comfortable just saying,
of course I knew what I
want to feel. Yeah, me too.
But let's just try to
straighten up for a second.
We have a guy named Clive when his
teaches at the university. Hello. Hey. Oh,
hi. Is this Mr Clive
when, yeah, this is live.
When clover's within the psychology
department of the University of Florida.
Where am I taught? Here's this. This
is Jad from a radio 11 right? Hijab.
Clive also happens to be an
expert on animal psychology. Hi,
this is Robert also. Can you hear us
pretty well? I can hear you pretty well.
I'm, I'm, I'm wondering how well I'm
going to distinguish your voices.
No need to do that just as a unitary
figure. Okay. Listen, let me,
let me begin on this is Robert Talking.
We'll tell you a story and we want
to know what you think of the story.
So once upon a time and not too long ago,
we're going to fast forward a bit cause
we ran Clive through the entire wheel
story front to back crystal
to you is if a diver said you,
this whale said thank you
to me, what would you say?
Well I would be put in a difficult
situation because I don't doubt the,
what these people experienced was a
very moving moment with that whale.
But the problem is I just don't speak
whale so I don't know what thank you looks
like in whale. If I'm going to
be a cynic about it, I would say,
well, the whale has been
trapped for I believe,
over a day and may just be disoriented.
Well, but this was,
this was parking herself with one
individual and then moving to the next.
That's not a distracted. That looks
like it's got some money intention.
It shows some interest in the individuals.
I'll give you that, but how do we,
how do we get from that too?
Did you sing that the whale is trying to
express things? What do you live with?
Let's play a different example.
Let's suppose that you found a bear in
the woods that was caught up in some
netting that ended up in the woods and
you work for hours to free the bear and
then the bat eats you.
Does that mean that the bears are an
ungrateful species of animal? Yes.
No, I don't really believe
it that. Right. Well, so,
so I mean it would make as much sense to
ascribe in gratitude to the bear as it
does to ascribe gratitude to the whale.
I just don't think that's a useful
way of trying to understand animals.
And I think it ultimately it demeans
them because it means that instead of
living in a world that's full of a
diversity of wonderful creatures,
each with its own ways of relating to
other members of its own species and other
members of other species, we say, well,
we don't live in a world like that.
We live in a world that's basically a
world of human beings. It doesn't matter.
Some of these human beings have suits
on some of these human beings weigh
hundreds of tons of live under the ocean
and can hold their breath for a very
long time. None of that
really matters. Ultimately,
they're all basically like us and
I just don't find that satisfying.
Are you saying that you don't know if
there's a possibility of sharing or that
you don't think that there's a possibility
of sharing at an emotional level
between two species? Um,
I don't doubt that there is
the possibility of between
two species. I mean you,
I see it with dogs all the time,
but I think it would be a mistake if we
thought that the love we feel for our
dogs is the same feeling that
the dog has back to us. It,
it has different qualities and it where
you pet your dog wags his tail and it
seems happy to see you. Yeah. Do you
just like not trust that well, okay,
so let me make clear that I wear two
hats when I'm talking about a dog,
particularly a pet of my own.
I'm where I have two possible hats I can
wear and one is that when the dog pants
back at me, I just hug the dog and you
know, and let him kiss me. And that's,
that's life with a dog. But if I'm,
if I'm now wearing my scientific hat and
getting my blanket as wet as I possibly
can, then I ask myself, what do
these behaviors mean among those?
That was a beautiful study that came
out recently from Alexander Horevitz.
I'm Alexandra Horowitz and I study
dog cognition. Where do we find her?
She's four. She's around the corner
from you. She's at Barnard College.
So we sent our producers, so we're in
wheeler. Yup. That's me to meet her.
And he ended up hanging out with her
and her dog Finnegan in the park and
snuffle that's nice stuff.
She did this beautiful
experiment that shows that um,
when people think their dog
is looking guilty, ears back,
eyes lowered tail between the legs.
Actually the dog is just being submissive.
So here's what she did.
She tracked down a bunch of dog owners
posted on craigslist and put out posters.
And then she found a bunch of owners who
believed that like most dog owners do
that their dogs feel guilty. Yes,
my dog feels guilty when
he's done something wrong.
And then she set up a situation where
all of the dog owners had to scold their
dogs because you know, they had been
told that their dogs did something bad.
But the trick of the experiment is that
only half the dogs had done something.
Half the dogs had actually been naughty
and half the dogs had not been naughty.
But then she
misinformed the owners lied to
half of the owners to the owners.
So even the owners who just dogs hadn't
been bad thought their dogs had been
bad. So everybody scolded their dog
and everyone did this the same way,
which was to say no loudly to their dog
and maybe put their hands on their hip
and expressed as a credible
yes can again, and again
it's okay.
See Finnegan just made the look even
though he hadn't done anything wrong.
And that's essentially what she found.
Even the non guilty dogs
made the guilty look.
It didn't matter whether the
dog had transgressed or not.
All that mattered was whether it
was being chastised by its owner.
So bad dog, bad dog, right?
That creates the look,
not the deed. That's exactly
right. But, but for me,
the pivotal question here is not
whether or not they all had the look,
but what's attached to that?
Look what feeling in the dog is
attached to that guilty look.
Maybe the dogs who were
falsely accused still felt bad.
Well maybe they did. Maybe they
didn't have. Maybe there are angels
on top of this control console here.
[inaudible]
I thought it was a perfectly valid
question. We should think, uh,
Alexander Horowitz, her latest
book is called inside of $8
[inaudible]
and before we end this section,
I have we resolved the question of what
was that whale doing with those people?
Was she saying thank you or no? No. And
do we ever resolve any questions at all?
Well, we try. We give a little closer
to them. No, we have not resolved five.
We will try harder. But, but,
but, but in our snack section,
a mere 70 seconds away,
we will try very hard to actually
get scientific about it. Good.