Hello. I'm Jad Abumrad,
and I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is Radiolab and our topic today is,
do you want to say the word
stochasticity? Stochasticity t o,
which is a wonderful and fancy word that
essentially means randomness, chance,
like the kindness built into flipping a
coin or a playing the lottery or to take
things deeper when you breathe cro,
which sing about the air that's
flying around your head right now,
it's full of atoms and molecules.
They're flying about. Yeah,
smashing into each other and colliding
and shooting off in different
trajectories that can't be predict.
It's totally chaotic, right?
[inaudible] until you breathe it all in.
When you do things get predictable.
Okay, let me release. Nope. Nope.
Okay, great. The point is,
when you breathe in all of those chaotic
flexi molecules come in and become a
part of the machinery that is
you. They go into your blood,
they go into your cells, which are
themselves. These little factories,
factories full of even tinier
factories like Mitochondria.
What our Mitochondria,
I'm not really sure,
but I do know that's Jonah
Lehrer again, himself,
a factory of inside factories full
of these intricate things which,
which working, you can understand, you
know, this gene makes this protein,
which makes this organ out, which
does this thing for the cell.
This process is Jonah of taking in lab
flux and
giving it a shape, giving it an order.
That is what life does. In fact,
you might say it is the definition
of life. The closer you get,
the more you kind of stand in
awe. At the exquisite engineering
there is a sense of life is can
be the world's most elegant clock.
Nice.
Good. Now, if life is a machine,
you would think that the most,
the clock,
like most machinery part of life would
be all the way down at the bottom.
I would think so. Which for our
purposes is when a gene makes a protein
gene protein gene, this
is the basis of life.
So you would think it's gotta be
orderly. It's gotta be predictable.
Otherwise none of us would be in his area.
Very predictable, orderly systems.
So we all have beliefs.
Pretty amazing study.
But then we spoke to this guy.
Am I talking? Have I been,
have I been talking about your art?
Yeah. Okay. And he, um, muck things up,
be looking this way, but what's
your name? My name is Carl Zimmer.
He's a science writer.
Like Jonah. I wrote a
lot for the New York Times and
scientific American and discover I blog.
And he told us that, uh, this whole
genes making proteins situation,
here we are again as tick-tock and
affairs. We've always assumed it to be.
In fact, scientists have
never actually seen it. Well,
I mean it's very small,
but finally scientists have figured
out a way to turn on a light when it
happens.
So they now can see a
gene turning on a protein.
Literally see it with
their own eyes. Yeah.
And what they saw well was
astonishingly on clock, like, yeah.
At the fundamental level,
that's this sloppy, sloppy.
That's the best word for it.
In fact, in our interview,
he used that word like 42 times
sloppy, sloppy, sloppiness,
sloppiness.
Sometimes you use this word random or
this fluctuating in this noise. Chaos,
noise. Definitely use that one a
lot. Trimble noise. Noisy accident.
Noisy noise, noise, noise,
noise, noise. Noisy.
Sloppy, chaotic noise. Sloppiness,
sloppy and fluctuating. It's,
it's fluctuate really crazy in there.
He started by telling us about this
experiment that happened in California at
cal tech involving a little
tiny bacteria called E-coli,
which is Carl's favorite indeed.
Yes. So these are eco lie.
These are harmless residents
of our gut. And they're also,
as you call them creatures,
they're creatures. Sure. They,
they sense their world,
they make decisions. They,
they feed, they reproduce.
They have genes like us.
They've got 4,000 jeans,
I think their earn that title creature.
And these creatures are actually
very similar to our own sales.
Their genes make proteins just like ours.
So what these scientists did was they
took some equal eye that were exactly the
same clones and every single way
they're genetically identical.
And then they put the whole batch in
a dish and they said, okay everyone,
we're going to turn on your
genes. Start making proteins.
No. And they watched
because like you said earlier,
they had found this new way of
getting the ECO lie to glow.
Not every time it's jeans made of protein.
It seems like it ought to be like just
flicking a switch that you turn on the
genes. Click protein, protein, protein,
protein, protein, poetry. Turn it off,
turn it on. Protein, protein, budget,
body pony. But you turn it off.
Couldn't get simpler. This is like
a basic function of biology. Yeah.
This is biology one-on-one. And again,
these are genetically identical eco-line
meaning they've got the same genes,
they're making the same protein, so
they should glow the same, right?
You just expect the steady glove
[inaudible]
and all of them.
Mm.
Nice and steady. Then that's
not what happened. You,
you, you could start with like an
individual eco lie and say, okay,
well what happened with that
one? Um, it didn't start to glow.
It started to flicker.
That'd be a little bit of light.
No light, a little bit more light.
Then maybe a sudden flat, then dark again,
then a little bit of light. Hmm.
And they were expecting what
they got. At the time was
swoop. It was completely defective,
like a car with no muffler going.
More troubling still when they
looked at Ecola and number two,
it two was defective except
in its own unique way
to head his own thing going.
Same with number three.
He had his own thing going. I mean,
they're genetically identical.
Same in number four.
This is essentially the same creature
in many different copies and five,
six, two and seven.
Each one was flickering
in its own brake pattern.
Nine 10 fluctuating 11 sloppiness,
chaos, jumbo,
random Latina.
That stuck with me.
Okay.
Is this noise would not be a problem if
it's just bacteria we're talking about,
but according to Carl, it's everywhere.
Everywhere in us we are built.
He says on a foundation of chaos.
This is very puzzling to me because
if down at the deep level of our DNA
[inaudible], there's just
this random mayhem and bedlam.
How do you go from bedlam up to
the organization that I represent?
I wake up in the morning, I go to
sleep at night, I get hungry, I eat,
I breathe in, I breathe
out, listen to my heart.
I am very, very orderly.
I don't know how you
get from this to this.
That's right. I mean,
so somehow all of this sloppiness has
got to be somehow tamed because more
alive. I mean that it's not
total chaos in our bodies, but,
but you keep the sentence
never seems to quite finish.
But we don't know how that happens is
that when we have some ideas of how it
happens, I mean as,
as scientists start to understand
how genes work with other genes,
they can see ways in which
you can, you can, um,
filter out the noise and
keep, keep the good signal,
keep the music. Okay.
Set anywhere really. No.
Now this I find really cool. The
research on this stuff is really new,
but Carl says one of the ways that the
body may do this testing to Lou Lou may
go from like check to is
by doing something that I
actually do on the show all
the time, which is use a noise filter.
The body may have engineered
its own noise filters.
I'll just give you an
example from my world,
and this is the honest to God's truth.
I have a friend named little elite. Hey,
literally, hello dead.
Tell me what you're holding in
your hands there in my hands.
I have two audio tapes. Thing just
recently called me up. She said,
I've got these two cassette
tapes. They're really old.
I think they were made in the 70s my mom
found them in her attic and they're of
my grandmother, ones labeled
Mima singing, singing,
[inaudible] singing old slave songs
and old hymns and the little rings,
grandmother died last year.
She was 99 years old. Wow.
And they were really close. Very close.
They used to call me little Mima when
I was a kid. So she's got these tapes,
she wants to hear them.
The problem is that you put it
on for more than three minutes,
you get annoyed and there's
that weird like it's too noisy.
Yeah. She wants to know if I could do
something about it. Yeah. So real quick,
here's what I did. I'd put it into
a computer, launched the DQ program,
found the base noisiness,
which was around 600 hertz.
Dial that down like so.
Then I found the high
street around 2000 Hertz.
Dial that down. Yeah. Now as a final step,
I just kind of located the voice around
a thousand hertz and dialed it up.
[inaudible]
okay, so it's not a
flawless process. I mean,
now she sounds like she's
coming out of a well,
but for the first time you can
hear her voice. I don't know.
This is the first time
I'm hearing this song,
but it seems like she's describing the
night that my grandfather passed away
talking about the doctors telling her
that my grandfather's passed and then
she's describing putting a fern in his
hand and she said it should be a rose
[inaudible]
[inaudible] eh,
uh,
the thing that's applicable here is that
we started with this and then just by
bringing certain frequencies down and
others up [inaudible] we ended up with
this.
This might be how it is in the body that
you've got this noise all the way on
the bottom, these genetic circles,
which we're spitting out messiness,
but somehow just on top of that,
or other genetic circuits
which are cleaning it all
up, giving it a share. Wait,
what is that now, right? Not Quite David
Science. What's wrong with
it? Well, in there is no
grandma. What do you
mean there's no grandma.
You don't start off with some very
clear signal that gets masked by noise.
The noise is there from
the start, Huh? It's noise.
And then all of a sudden you
have this beautiful song.
Carl went on to explain it. It took me
like an hour for us to finally get this.
It's not,
there's nothing but noise down there at
the bottom and yet somehow out of that
noise, the song emerges like a phantom.
It's almost as if the noise
is somehow filtering itself.
So if to be able to get the analogy right,
little wing would hand jad a
tape with just fragmented sound.
Little bits of me, little bits of
me, mine, all kinds of random ways.
Maybe she gave you eight or nine tapes
[inaudible] and somehow he says it all
starts to kind of get into a network
where this one filters that one and that
one filters to the other one and the
other one filters that ninth one.
And out of all of that
comes grandma comes a song,
the song of a living
regular organism. Literally.
I mean grandmas are made from chaos.
I love that you say like, it's
almost like it seems like a miracle.
Think it stands up and walks.
But see the thing is you've hit,
I mean we are talking about something
that scientists don't understand yet.
Yeah. So I don't have it. So there's not,
if you want to have a part
of this show where you say,
and this people is how it
all works, can't do that. No,
but here's the thing. If you want to
get fruity about this, you could say,
and I put this to Carl,
that if all the way down at the
bottom of us there is this a fuzz,
it cannot be predicted then in
some sense we can never be known.
And if we can ever be known, then we're
free to be whatever we want. Hmm. Well,
no, I mean look,
I can sit here and concentrate and I
can think any thought I want to right
now, any thought. Sure.
But you can't think about a poem
from second century China. True.
Could you make an equivalence between
loose mechanics and sense of freedom?
Um, is, you know, I mean, does the,
the sloppiness and the floppiness of of
a protein clamping onto your DNA scale
up to what you're going to be when
you grow up on Radiolab? Yes. Okay.
All right. Well, here we are. No,
you can see it's an example of JC stone,
Non Rube DDT predictability is called
[inaudible].
Hello,
this is Carl Zimmer radio lab is produced
by Soren Wheeler and Jad Abumrad.
Our staff includes Elon Horn, Lulu
Miller and dean Capello with helps them.
Jennifer Madson, Michael Raphael
and Habermann, Jonathan Mitchell,
and then the Aronchick Charles Choice,
Emma Jacobs, Ellis skin, and Ike.
This can the Har Raja,
the US [inaudible] pronounced this word
to see beam phone was created by Josh
Kurtz and Shane Winter special
thanks to a little wiggly and Deema.
Yes.