You're listening to radio lab from
New York public radio, public radio,
W, C,
n, n. P. R.
[inaudible].
This is Radiolab on Jab and Rod.
Today we're in a doctor
Frankenstein sort of mood,
so we figure we're better to start
death test and at the museum,
American Museum of natural history where
they have on a kind of Frankenstein
exit. Okay, I'm Laurel Candle.
I curate the American Museum of Natural
History is exhibit mythic creatures.
We're standing in front of a dragon now.
Why would there be a dragon at the
Museum of Natural History? Well,
according to the curator,
Laurel Kendall, yes,
the human mind loves to wonder, well,
what would happen if we put wings on a
horse or put a tail on a beautiful woman?
Dad is human justified, however you
want that belongs in the museum.
What you see before you, we'd begin
these all strange twisting creatures,
a dimly lit, and when
you look more closely,
you realize that they're all mashups
from the natural world. For example,
she takes us over to one corner
points at a class case we're inside.
What you're seeing is this creepy
little hybrid skeleton thing.
Look at this spaced and see
how it really is a composite.
Half of it is a monkey,
the upper half monkey skull and
the lower half is a fish tail.
Like some kind of trout with some
scales, places full of stuff like this.
A Elian with an eagle head. Humans
with snake tails, just spending thing.
You can imagine. Very operatic. Oh,
and I forgot to mention the
most important part. Kid.
Tons and tons of kids
completely in awe. Oh my God.
Your uniform.
What are we standing
under here? The Pegasus.
Can you describe what we're seeing here
is a horse. The body's like a horse.
He has these really big wings,
wings like birds, like an eagle.
Maybe somehow his parents were a horse
and a bird in there. Their genes,
um, together too. Make a Pegasus.
Just what I see that what I see.
It just looks so exciting that
it just looks really cool.
And when you ask these kids, is
there a producer? Little Miller did.
Why is it cool? Like why is it fun
to see two animals mashed together?
Um, will they just look
at you like you're dumb.
So Horse [inaudible] yes. Um,
birds, they're not mythical.
They're like the regular
every day you see them,
every time you just see a pigeon
you're like, oh, whatever.
Maybe it's that simple. Yeah.
Any case the kids would get sick of us
and are dumb questions ran off to this
kiosk at the museum and set up around
the corner right here where they could
actually build their own creatures.
Okay. Now can you, your guy here?
Well he has um,
seven heads and he has a tail
with fire on it for a lay.
He has a long body and the thing
is how the legs are though,
you can't help them.
Chicken leg,
like these same kids in about 30 or 40
years might actually be able to do this
for real.
Where did that grown up?
Those kids will be at home in
the new world of biotechnology.
They won't be ready to
put their skills to use.
That will be do it yourself kits to breed
new varieties of pigeons and parrots
and lizards and snakes.
I buy like a snake and then like a
bird. Oh, can I do it? Cause I never got
genetic engineering.
Once it gets into the hands of housewives
and children will give us an explosion
of diversity of new living creatures.
That is physicists, Freeman Dyson.
We'll hear more from him later. Now,
whether it's true or
not, what he's saying,
it does seem to be the case that we
are at this pivotal point now where the
stuff that we used to only imagine
might actually turn into reality,
which is why maybe you get an exhibit
of fantasy creatures at the Museum of
natural history. This is a
celebration of the human imagination.
Human Ingenuity. Human. Yeah.
[inaudible] name of God. Oh, I
know what it feels like to be gone.
That's our show today. Life, but not as
we know it. Life as we might invent it,
tweak it, augment it. Yes. But if
you augment, tweak, and remake,
people will quickly come to you
and say, Hey, don't fuss with this.
It's not natural. It's not right.
Speaking of right and natural and fussing.
Who are you? Oh I'm sorry. I, Robert
Krulwich who was always right,
always naturally and always
fussing that word you,
you mentioned um, natural. Yeah, that
one. Natural. What does it mean exactly?
Let's just think usually means what it
means, what's familiar, what we know,
who we know. Let's say.
Let's just muck that up a bit because
it turns out when you look in nature you
will find things that are frankly
very strange and not familiar. Like,
well, let me tell you a story.
It's an amazing story about a woman
heard about it from a reporter,
Soren Wheeler. I sworn right. Hey,
it's a Soren. Tell me about Karen.
Well Karen is, I'm a mother of three,
a middle aged woman living outside of
Boston and the suburbs of Boston and uh,
she lives there with her husband Pete.
The kids are out of the house now.
Tell me what you were thinking when
you walked up to her door. Well, I,
I was nervous. I was kind of
strangely nervous about meeting her.
Hi Karen. Hi. But I got there and
she was just friendly as can be,
bring in a couple of cups
of tea. She made me tea,
we sat in the living room
and talk and uh, she was just
normal, which it's kind of weird given
the story that she was about to tell me.
So let's start at the very beginning. Oh,
well in 1995,
I was told that I needed a
kidney transplant immediately.
What's that like? Like what are you
going through? It was frightening.
The doctors told Karen
they needed to act fast.
They asked me who in my family
might be willing to donate a kidney.
The two older boys, that's Matt
and Jess and Karen's husband Pete,
you all went in to get what should have
been a pretty routine DNA test. Yup.
They had the blood work
done and they waited.
A couple of weeks later I got a phone
call from the hospital and they said,
Mrs Keegan, um,
this is a very unusual
situation that we're, uh,
going to explain to you. It's
something that we've never seen before.
But uh,
when the DNA testing
was done on your sons,
we found that they didn't match your DNA.
Is that how they said it? They
said they match the father,
but they're not a match for
you. What does that mean?
That they didn't match her
DNA? She's not their mother
ready much here. And this was
crazy. Yeah. I mean she told them,
well I was there. This could not
possibly be. I gave birth to these kids.
I felt the pain. You know,
you better do the test again
because you're obviously wrong.
And so they did do the test again.
Same result. The read was correct.
There was not a laboratory error. This
is one of her doctors when you, we,
we felt particularly after the
second time that it was real.
And then they said,
now we have had situations where
the husband's DNA didn't match,
but we've never had a mother whose
DNA didn't match their children.
Mm hmm.
So wait, if the DNA saying she's not
the mom, then what would explain that?
Well, first thought was that
there was some kind of mix,
some switch babies or something like a
baby switch right after birth kind of
thing. Yeah. But the problem with
that is that the dad is, the dad is,
or the fathers. Right.
So you have to figure out like how
could they have gotten the wrong kid,
but the right dad says, then
what if, if that's the case,
here's the thing at this, at this point,
as we got further involved with this,
people are thinking maybe Karen's
done something kind of fishing.
There must be something
that you're not being told.
Like maybe she implanted her womb with
another woman's baby and then she just
kind of lied about it. Yeah, that
she lied about it. They said, well,
could you tell us what hospital you
had these children and how exactly how,
what would,
I'm still confused as being accused of
being some kind of monster who maybe
wish they had children stolen
that child or something had to be,
because obviously DNA is
never wrong. It's never wrong.
Wow. So how did she talk
to her family about this?
What are those conversations like?
I do remember some very
sort of sad moments.
Bless my sons. Yeah.
You know, I told them,
I don't think they maybe even
completely realized what I was saying.
Lynn, Karen's doctor couldn't
get this out of her head.
Something wasn't adding
up. Didn't make sense.
So she thought about the fact that
they'd done all of the tests on Karen's
blood, only in our blood cells.
So Lynn started thinking maybe the next
step they ought to look at some other
parts. And to do that we would
need to test other tissues,
scrape the inside of your mouth and get
a little saliva and maybe a hair or to
thyroid and a skin biopsy with
you're getting all sorts of parts,
you're getting a law parts and
all kinds of parts from me.
That's when things started to get strange.
When we got the results of the tissue
studies, we identified two, two,
two, two sets of DNA. Two people
to what? Another person in Karen,
she had another person
inside her. Well sort of.
She did have a separate set of DNA.
So it was like she had another person
with its own genetic identity in her body.
And the thing is that that other
person that was the mother of the boys,
well how did they get there? That,
I mean that's what the doctors were
wondering. So they all sit down,
put their heads together and try to
figure it out and then it hit him.
You were a twin. You are a twin. She,
I mean she had a twin.
No, she's both twins.
Here's what happened in
Karen's mother's womb.
Originally there were two
eggs, two fertilized eggs,
twin girls side by side,
developing in their own separate
sacks. Then after a couple of days,
something strange happened. Somehow
the two embryos bumped into each other
and they fused into one unit
and that one became Karen.
Like a mixture of the
two of them. Well, no,
they didn't blend according to Lynn,
what happened is they kind of
claimed different parts of,
they still had their own,
I want to say boundaries.
One twin claimed her blood and the
other twin claimed her thyroid and her
bladder. And Karen is a plural.
Yeah. [inaudible]
is this, has this, has this happened
before? Well, supposedly it's pretty rare,
but it does happen. In fact, there's,
there's a scientific
word for this condition.
Karen first heard that word
from her doctor, Margo cres.
Margo came to my bedside,
explained that I was a Chi.
Mira a term which I had never heard of.
Did she fall? Did she come and say,
you're a Chi Kymera and it, yeah.
Yes.
Now that was interesting because I
called my son the English major and said,
Matt, I've found out I was a
Chi Mira, and he said, oh, well,
you know what a Kai Mira is, don't
you? And I said, no. And he said,
well,
in the ancient Greek myths, I,
Thai Mira is an animal
that has like a lion,
has a donkey's a goat, Kale,
you know, it's a mixture and Greek myths.
The Camaro was a monster that
the heroes opposed to slay.
That didn't make me feel very good.
Then Karen learned more about what
Kymera meant medically and what could've
happened to her.
If the eggs hadn't
fused. Within four days,
I would have become a Siamese twin.
When you hear that,
you immediately have a more
concrete vision of two selves.
It brought home the reality
that I really was a twin.
She is a twin. One doctor said,
do you think you have two souls?
I think of myself,
yeah. There is
almost a sort of subtle sadness to
sink did I would've had a sister.
Yeah.
And so there is sort of
a shadow feeling of loss.
There could have been more
thanks to reporter Soren Wheeler for that.
Let's make things a little more
disturbing now because human beings,
scientists are now capable of
creating kindnesses purposefully.
And we talked to Lee silver who is a
scientist at Princeton elite. Okay. Lee,
you have to say something.
Okay. You know my left ear is receiving
more than my right. Is there a,
when he told us about
an intentional Kemira,
a creature created by a Danish
embryologist named Steen Wilson.
Keith took a goat embryo and a sheep
embryo and he pushed them together in his
petri dish.
But that mixture of
embryo back into a female,
I don't remember which species.
And then what was born was an animal that
was part part sheep and he called that
agape. Was it visibly kind
of goatee and kind of sheepy?
Well it was actually,
yes, it was very visible.
And what happened because of
the way development occurs,
parts of its body looks, sheep like
and parts of its body look goat.
Like which parts? Well,
he did this multiple times and so he
actually got multiple gifts and sometimes
the animal would have for goat had, but
then parts of his body would be sheep,
like with wool. Other times
it would have a sheep.
How confusing it would be at the dance.
You wouldn't know like who was
supposed to dance with home? Could,
could gifts relate with
one another in that way.
I don't remember. It's not
a deep, as you may look,
a little beard and
everything in the hooves.
Ah,
I mean, just to give you a visual,
we've got a picture here of three
beeps hanging out near a tree.
Do you want to describe
it? Well, the Geeks,
one of them looks like a naked animal
wearing the coat of shaggy hair is,
it's got this streak of sheep
wool running on its back,
but the rest of it looks kind of
Godi. Which deal do you find a cute?
I kind of do find it cute. Well,
Bucknell, it's an cuted a bit.
Suppose instead of talking about
mixing sheep with goats, okay,
since you're not a sheep or a
goat, let's make it more personal.
People are most worried about combining
human embryonic cells and monkey or
chimp embryonic cells.
And so the idea is if you took a chimp
embryo in a human embryo and you push
them together based on the Geek results,
based on lots of other data that
scientists have accumulated,
it's very likely that you'd have an
organism born that was part chimp,
part human. Well, there once
was a creature like that because
if you believe in evolution,
you believe that chimps
eventually became humans.
So somewhere in history there is
someone who is 10% chimp and 90%
and that common ancestor evolved
continuously and slowly from a chimp like,
um, individual to human. And in every
point along the 100,000 generations,
the children didn't look very different
from their parents. But here's the,
here's the very sad Hollywood movie.
I go and I go and I create a creature,
a jeep like you know, amalgamation,
which is 50% chimpanzee,
ape and 50% human homosapiens and he's
the only one that's like creating a
tragedy. It seems like because you'd be
creating someone who is isolated in his
physiology.
Yes. I mean this is agreed with
him on, maybe they could, but
at the cost of you're
taping us opening something.
I'm opening something for good.
This is actually a play here.
You can look at this. It's going
to be performed next week. Sweet.
Sweet Motherhood, isn't
it? Yes, that's it.
So this is a play at the
Guthrie Theater in Minneapolis.
Shelley McCann wants to baby
a human chimpanzee baby.
Oh.
Shelley's been spending too much time
partying to build up a respectable grade
point average. So she proposes
the following senior thesis,
fertilized one of her eggs with the
sperm from a chimpanzee in her womb.
It's an interesting term paper.
So professor Harry Stein must do
everything he can to stop her.
The play is inspired by
a true event. Really?
This is your play. Yes.
Jeremy character is the main playwright
and I've collaborated with him.
What is the true truth? And I watch this,
his base, the true event is that, uh,
about 10, 12 years ago now,
I was talking to my usual flippant way
to a bunch of students and a sequence
information had just come out showing
that chimps and humans were almost 90% the
same at the DNA level. And so I
just threw out the idea, well,
based on what we know about goats
and sheep and everything else,
you probably could have a hybrid
developed between a chimpanzee and human
beings. It was a thought
experiment. What would it be?
How would it developed which of
its characteristics be human,
which would be chimpanzee?
The next day a student,
a junior came to my office and said she
wanted to do the experiment inside her
own womb. Ah, and uh, so then yes, uh,
in real life, what did you do? He hit
her on the head with a baseball bat or,
well, no, I had a long,
I was flabbergasted.
She was absolutely serious
because she is actually true. She,
she was this student who partied a lot
and she needed and the senior thesis at
Princeton counts an enormous amount
in towards your final GPA. So, uh,
she wanted to do this unique experiment
hoping she'd get an a plus in her senior
thesis. And she was very naive obviously.
That was the last time I saw this
little chimpanzee up for adoption.
As soon as it was born. Well, no, no
worse. She posted that she, I asked her,
what would you do with this individual?
I said, well, if it's a human being,
you have to raise it like a human
being and as rights, like human being,
if it's a chimpanzee, you put
her in a zoo or you use it,
use it for experiments
and what's it going to be?
And her answer to that question was she
would abort right before it came time to
go into labor, she'd board.
And so the whole idea of the senior thesis
was to study the development of this
hybrid inside of her womb. She
really wanted to do this for real,
not just on paper for a project,
but actually she wants, yes. Now,
there are many, many, many, many problems.
Do meaning liberal arts
education, really liberal here.
We talked for about an
hour. Um, I dissuaded her.
I never saw her again
except in a way in his play.
The, when he cowrote road.
This is the play about the
teacher at the fancy university.
It happens just to be
teaching a biology class,
the human ovary within the masters.
But it happens to have this notion about
what would it be like if chimps and
humans had babies together.
Actually in a number,
I am more similar to a MailChimp than I
am to my sister happens to have in the
play. The student who comes
up after class and says,
I want to combine one of my eggs with
chimpanzees wants you to do this except by
the way in the play checks
he goes through with it.
But you know, he,
he wrote the play to keep a conversation
going that wouldn't get out of his
hand. And the question is
what is a human being? Um,
if you look at a developmentally,
evolutionarily through these
hybrids and time areas,
where's the boundary between
human being and non human being?
And at the end of my quest,
I personally concluded that there
is no boundary. No, no, no, no.
It's fuzzy. So in other
words, if you look at,
the analogy I like to give is look at the
color spectrum between green and blue.
When you go from green to
blue along the color spectrum,
it's a continuous gradual
change from one to the other.
There's no point in which you say, here's
the boundary between green and blue.
And if you take that analogy,
which I did, two human beings,
you say during development
or in evolution in the,
in terms of a Kemira, there's no boundary.
But the social effect of having staked
out that position is that you aren't
going to defend our species
against all kinds of amendments.
There is a consequence to this
kind of thinking, right? I mean,
you can't do it cold porter,
anything goes, can you know? No,
I don't believe you can do anything
goes. My purpose is to say,
not that anything goes,
but that in theory,
all these outrageous things could
happen and actually are happening.
Here's an example,
since 1980 scientists have
been taking human genes,
genetic information, putting it into mice.
I mean this is sort of a routine procedure
and for people who do mouse molecular
genetics,
and in fact the really exciting thing
that people are doing now is they're
making cows that are engineered
to produce human blood.
And the idea is that you want to change
all the genes in the cow that normally
produce the proteins in cow blood.
You want to make them all human so
you'd have a cow making human blood.
I don't think most people would mind that.
And then you could use it
for blood transfusions. Wow.
Could you make a cow with human blood
and a human kidney so that you could use
that to, well, actually, uh, Ma, uh,
Israeli scientists have already created a,
that has a tiny little functioning
human kidney can't out.
I could show you the
picture. Yeah. So, I mean,
and you know when there are other people
who are working with sheep and trying
to make human livers and side sheep
and the whole ideas is regenerative
medicine, sacrifice the animals
to get a new kidney for you. Now,
I actually think that as long as you
don't play with the external features,
I think society walks up
to it. I mean, you know,
people eat pigs and if you can eat a pig,
why not grow a pig to have a
human liver or kidney or heart?
As long as it still looks like a
pig, you're saying that's right.
As long as it still looks like a pig
and it's still behaves like a pig.
You know, if you put a
human arm onto a pig,
I don't think people would like that.
But you acknowledge that the
distinctions you're drawing are emotional
distinctions and not rational.
Absolutely. There are emotional,
and I'm saying that sometimes
emotional distinctions matter. I mean,
I have no solutions. I mean, I
don't know where to draw lines.
Society has the draw lines.
[inaudible]
radio, Radiolab. We'll
continue in a moment.
Message one. Hi, this is Lee silver.
Radiolab is funded in part by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
the corporation for public broadcasting
and the National Science Foundation.
Radiolab is produced by W N Y C York
public radio and distributed by NPR
national public radio.
Hello, I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert
Krulwich Radiolab. Our topic today is, um,
what is our topic today?
Robert today is making life that isn't
there before you arrived in the room.
Okay. Uh, life not as we know it yet,
but as we might invent it or make it.
Well, let's talk about
life. You and I. Okay.
So when you look around in the world
at living things, and I say, Look Dad,
there's a cat and next to that
is a dog and that's a tree.
And you noticed that those things
of course are different. Yes.
And later when we go to school,
we learn about phylum's and
categories like kingdoms and stuff.
So we've learned about the
nature of those differences.
And then you're taught about
struggle and competition.
Darwin species,
there is a new theory that's being talked
about that turns all of that on its
head. I heard it first from
this guy. I'm Steve Strogatz.
I'm an applied mathematician at
Cornell and the story he told me,
which is based on analysis of DNA
and very tiny organisms, microbes,
is that once upon a time he says,
life began with a very primitive,
very simple collection
of cells and these cells
[inaudible] like to shoot. It appears
that legend, when you go back far enough,
there's a kind of rampant
sharing of molecules.
It's a kind of orgy in which there are
no well-defined species or organisms and
I can give you my genes and
you can pass. We're a commune.
It was a calm year. What?
What does that mean? He's like, it was
a, what do you mean? What does it mean?
I know what it means in the 60 screen.
Love sets, but what does it really mean?
What are, what cells are
exchanging is chemicals,
chemicals that give them talents and
traits. Genes. Here's what happens.
I did this with [inaudible]
that are in our ancient puddle in Darwin
thought the life might've begun in a
warm puddle. Let's say that
you and I are both cells. Okay?
So once upon a time there was you and a
puddle and I'm in the same Preble as you
and it gets a little colder in the
puddle. So we should all get sick.
But you don't get sick, you don't
have some kind of accidental talent.
You can handle cold water. I'm shivering.
Describe again what happens in it at
this point in the glorious old days,
my membrane that is I, I'm a cell, I've
got a membrane, I've got my outer layer,
maybe a little bit porous and maybe
Lipson. I'm on my jeans just leaked out.
Okay.
We're not talking sophisticated organisms
and maybe your poorest too and oh wow.
You just absorbed some of those
genes. So now we both have this,
we both got and you both come.
And if I've got this clean
now I can survive cold water.
And because it's part of me and if I
bump into you now it's part of you.
So now the Steve Jean
has become a Robert King,
which has then become Jag gene and we're
doing it over and over and over and
we're getting really um, come here.
[inaudible]
it sounds so friendly. I actually
don't think of sounds like, yeah,
people shout out all these exchanges.
This gene swapping was not intentional.
It's not purposeful sharing.
That's Nigel Goldenfeld.
I'm a theoretical physicist at the
University of Illinois and he and his
colleague Carl woes did the science
that led to some of these kind of goofy
ideas. It's not me sort of saying, hey,
I'm going to just help out my buddy
over there. Here's a couple of jeans.
I think you'll find handy. It's not
something like that. You can still,
if we're swamping jeans
so much and you know,
you're giving me yours
and I'm going to be mine,
what does it actually mean to be me? Yeah.
So much of me is spread around.
Well, would be very weird.
Imagine a world in which for a
while I have your nose, God forbid,
and then I get my nose back.
You'd have Steve's hair, then I,
Steve would get my ear. Then he
would get your nose on to stall,
having a lot of exchange. Take Your
Chin. Okay. And you can have my,
um, allergies. And then you start
even asking what does it mean, um,
to be a species. You can have
my love affair with doubt.
You may not even be able to
talk about individuals. Yeah.
If the mixing is good enough, we're
all kind of indistinguishable.
So identity would be very
strange in this ancient world,
but a lot of the concepts
that we take for granted, the
biology become more and more nebulous as
you get further and further back to the
roots of the origin of life.
Take for instance Charles Darwin.
What Nigel is really saying is that for
the first billion years of life with the
be good to be everything
that Darwin teaches,
all that stuff happened in no borders,
no individuals has no species.
That is Darwinism evolution as we now
understand it. That's an interlude
[inaudible]
and the real story of life,
it's only what's happening now.
What you got back at the very beginning
was a whole bunch of cells swapping
genes, swapping advantages, swapping
disadvantages, and this kind of goes wild,
Huh? Tremendous explosion.
What diversity in a way that
life has not seen since then.
[inaudible]
until
one dark and terrible
day, 3 billion years ago,
as interpreted by Freeman
Dyson, sweetening famous
physicist and delivered here.
Now our friend, the mathematician,
Steve Strogatz, hears d one evil day,
a bacterium anticipating Bill
Gates by 3 billion years.
Refuse to share,
refuse to share. Ooh, the first
bad guy is this cellular bill.
K Two who decides that you,
I've got an innovation that I don't feel
like sharing or possibly by found a way
to keep my membrane from leaking. That is,
I'm not going to be a sharing
soul anymore. And why?
I mean what made that one little
cell decide to stop sharing?
That's a good question.
We don't really know,
but what we do know this is was maybe the
most dramatic moment in the history of
life on earth.
This transition from the age of,
if you want to call it the age of
sharing to the age of selfishness
and gradually once one
creatures stopped sharing,
pretty soon the others followed and
then more and more did the same thing.
And now for the first time in the
history of life, finally we get Darwin.
Now we get species. Now we see
differences. Yes, it's the age
of identity of individualism.
It's also the age of, of
stasis. Things change,
but they change much more slowly.
And any great thing, you know,
like you are a bat and you've figured
out sonar. I don't have sonar,
I can't get sonar. I mean
I used to have sonar.
Like you're at a little electric fish
that lives in the muddy waters of the
Amazon. You don't care. It's
totally dark. You can see,
because you can see with electricity,
I can't see with electricity.
If I'm in the dark, I'm bumping my head.
[inaudible]
okay, so here's go.
We end up chapter one one a greed
orgy of genes swapping chapter two,
do your g ends. We passed genes. Now,
not two other guys, not randomly,
but just to our own children.
And finally here comes
chip proposed by Freeman
Dyson, the physicist in Dyson.
After 3 billion years of life,
slowly evolving through random
mutations who bumps in the night?
One species. Jad Human beings, you and me,
we have become so smart,
so well some of us so advanced
that we can swap genes.
We now decide who gets what genes and
thanks to us evolution as Darwin described
it is beginning to end and now we
welcome evolution as described by Freeman
Dyson to the graduating class at
University of Michigan. I see it.
Bright future for the biotech industry
becoming small and domesticated rather
than big and centralized
Freeman thinks that in the
future everybody means everybody.
They will all be creating new life
forms and why? Because they can. Yeah,
that will be do it yourself kits for
gardeners who will use genetic engineering
to breed new varieties of roses and
Dawkins kits for lovers of pigeons and
parrots and lizards and snakes
to breed new varieties of pets.
Genetic engineering.
Once it gets into the hands of housewives
and children will give us an explosion
of diversity of new living creatures.
[inaudible].
The final step in the domestication
of biotechnology will be biotech games
designed like computer games for
children down to kindergarten age,
but played with real eggs and
seeds rather than with images.
On the screen playing such games,
kids will acquire an intimate feeling
for the organisms that they're growing.
The winner could be the kid who is seed
grows the picklist cactus or the kid
whose egg hatches the cutest dinosaur
[inaudible].
So there's your future. I'd like to
make it your future for the moment,
but it doesn't sound that bad. I mean,
maybe a little cy fi. Well, actually the,
here's the interesting thing is that
what he's describing has already begun.
There are kids doing this right
now or something very close to it.
How old were you when you did this?
I guess I was 20 and 21 right now.
Okay. Who are you, what's your name and
what do you do? Uh, I'm Steven Payne.
I'm a senior in biological
engineering at MIT. Oh,
here's the thing about Steven.
He like most kids who are in the sciences
in college had to spend hours and
hours and hours in the lab waiting for
eco lie slowly grow in a petri dish.
Eco Lie, like the stuff that gives
you food poisoning, it's the stuff,
it's common bacteria that lives naturally
in your gut. And it's, by the way,
a big laboratory favorite.
And the problem is,
has Rashman said he was
a grad student at MIT.
Is He [inaudible] in the Ra
actually smelled really bad.
What does it smell like?
I actually kind of smell,
I guess maybe like
pool. What do you think?
It smells like feces. Anyway,
Steven and his friends got into their
heads that they could make Nike colada
smell no nicer, nicer,
like cinnamon or cherry
or I like minty fresh.
We ended up deciding on
Wintergreen, wintergreen. Oh,
you've got something against
wintergreen. Let me know.
In the real world who has winter
green? Ah, it's the Petunia plant.
Petunias have wintergreen. I have no idea.
Yeah. A lot of folks study.
Why plants make nice smell.
So why do roses smell nice?
Why do Petunia Smell Nice?
So what we did was we were requested
from one of these folks and Italia Dude
River from Purdue university.
We asked her to send us a sample of
one of the genes she had studied that
produces this winter green smell.
Oh, she mailed it through the mail.
We opened it up. They took it.
What were you taking out? A little bit
of gum. It's actually living cells.
Living dried cells. Yeah.
We pulled out the DNA,
put it into a new cell
and once the new DNA had done its thing,
Steven called everybody into the lab
and then we all came over and
were like, Whoa, these, you know,
the sea cola culture actually
does smell like mint.
And we were like, Yay, that's crazy.
And so instead of smelling pool all
day, they get to smell a winter green.
Well actually there was more than that
because after their winter green success,
Steven and Rashman decided, you
know, why should we stay in the,
in the lab all day,
even though it smells nicer now because
we have to sit there and watch these
ecol I grow and grow and grow until
they are ready to be experimented on.
We could be outside playing Frisbee.
So they decided to put a little
trigger inside the ecollege.
So when it's done growing,
it switches from winter
green to banana. Banana,
yeah, the banana show. But yeah, it
smells like a banana milkshake. I mean,
and it smells more like a
banana than a banana does.
So winter green means it's still growing
and banana means we're done. Yep. Wow.
That's kind of awesome. Awesome
is a word I want to discuss.
The awesome question here. Okay.
Were you at all intrigued by the
idea is that, as far as I know,
and I'm maybe as far as you know,
maybe as far as anybody know in the
history of the eco-line creature,
there has never been an eco lie
that smelled like winter green.
Yeah. You made it yourself.
Well, with the help of my
team members, yes ma'am.
Did you feel a little spooked by the fact
that you just created a life for them?
New to new to creation? Um,
I mean at least we're doing something
that's, you know, smells pleasant,
but you didn't feel like a doctor
Frankenstein or a god or a not at all.
What does it feel like to make
something that's never existed before?
Just feels like basic engineering, right?
Yeah. Or engineers. I would say we're
engineers. We're building stuff,
building stuff, building
[inaudible] stuff,
stuff, stuff, living stuff. The Rhoda
Dan
[inaudible] will fix the problems of
today by building stuff with [inaudible].
We're slicing genes,
we're building creatures that being extra
useful features more waiting daughter
when styling and slopping
jeans as long as small
stuff building stuff.
[inaudible] goes whereby
it's mankind's only fighting chance
designer jeans, not Denny bites.
We'll stop disease and greenhouse
gases when seeing nucleic acids.
We've seen the light where the
[inaudible] is fried and clear.
[inaudible]
thanks to Josh curves and Shane Winter
for that music radio lab will continue in
a moment. My name is Alyssa Hargrave
and I'm calling from Shakopee,
Minnesota where it is currently
negative 25 degrees Fahrenheit.
Outside Radiolab is supported in part by
the National Science Foundation and by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hello, I'm Chad and I am Robert.
This is Radiolab and today
our topic is tinkering,
tinkering with nature or life.
Yes, but don as we know it. No,
because before the break we heard about
some kids doing something that they call
directed evolution.
By sticking wintergreen into a place
where wintergreen has never been before,
which definitely qualifies
as life, not as we know.
Now let's get into the true grit of this
because those kids are looking at life
in a, in a fairly different
way than most of us do. Yes.
It's very interesting that the people
who are creating these living systems are
engineers. This is Lee silver from
Princeton University. I mean, they,
they really look at a living system
as no different than a computational,
uh, electronic device. And you, your
hunches there, right? Am I have,
they're wrong. I don't know quite why
by hunches. They're right. But, um,
most of the world doesn't believe that,
which would include me because I just
make it very hard to imagine that I've got
a life form talking.
This animal leaves for a span of
years and then dies. You know,
it's like when they die and
the spirit kind of goes on,
it's hard for me to believe that that is
just a chemical machine of several from
parts. Really. Yeah. Well, okay. I
mean, I guess I can understand that,
but let me introduce you to
a guy now who's whole. Uh,
admittedly young career is based
on the idea that life is a machine,
that it's made of parts, parts that
he can build and sell. Okay. So I'm,
I'm Brian Bains. Brian,
we met actually just down the street
from those MIT kids. He is 31.
That's right, just 31 and he
runs his own biotech company,
one of the founders of
caught on devices here.
We make custom synthetic genes from
scratch and he's doing pretty well.
The industry is gray, sickly doubling
every two years at this point. I mean,
just to give you a sense of what
Brian does, you with me? Yep.
Just take your example. Those MIT kids,
let's say I'm one of those kids or
someone else who's heard about them and I
want to take my stinky bacteria
and make it smell better.
Or maybe I want to make it glow. All
I have to do is call Brian. Sure.
Cause he'll sell me a simple gene
like that for about 1500 bucks.
I just have to go online. Look
up the chemical recipe for
darn yes. Here it is. 1200 letters, t, G,
Z, Cesar, letters of DNA, g,
a t and a c of for fundamental
building blocks of DNA. The next step,
just list out those A's, g's and t's
and C's. Just type them into an email.
Generally they're not typing at themselves
and imagine trying to type in 2000
letters by hand without making a mistake
and it would take too long. All right.
Just copy and paste them into
an email. Send them to Brian.
When we get that in house, we, um,
we're going to take that into our facts.
Brian then plugs the string
of letters into this machine,
which is about the size
of a desktop computer.
We have a census system where it literally
has a bunch of little A's and a jar
and a bunch of g's in a jar and t's
and C's. These chemicals are inert.
They are store bought hundred
dollars a bottle. The machine,
they're all connected to reads all
the letters that Brian plugs in
and when, if he's in a
machine, squirts out some pay.
Duck is a t
words out some t test,
we can add an a or a g or a t or
a c to a growing strand of DNA.
And so we literally adding
one base at a time fee fees.
So what starts as one letter pieces
then grows to 50 then grows to maybe 500
then it grows to be 5,000 and at a
certain point all of these inner chemicals
hold hands.
And that's literally how
you make DNA chemically.
That is how you go from dust to
something that is not exactly alive.
But if I take this little speck of DNA
and stick it into my cell, amazingly,
it will start to glow or smell better
or whatever it is that I want it to do,
it will do it.
It's almost as if the cell is a
computer and this little bit of DNA is a
software program. That's the way
synthetic biologists think about hm.
And what synthetic biologists are hoping
for us as leads that the software,
quote unquote will get standardized.
It will come down in price.
So that one day installing
new features into organisms.
We just as easy as when you install
new software on your home PC,
but a word processor, you put a
spreadsheet program user friendly.
That's kind of the logic. Yeah,
but that's not that. That's that.
We're talking about life here. Life
like you know, a game of Lego's.
What if it is,
I mean I know it's weird to think it's
wrong in other words to describe it,
but what if it's not wrong?
Just imagine you can start to look
at things in a completely new way.
You can look at that
creature over there and say,
that creature right there has a talent
that I really like and that one over
there. The second one, it
also does something cool.
Maybe if I take talent one and
talent to stick them together,
put 'em into a third creature.
Then I've got a little factory that can
do really cool stuff for gait living,
things that have very important
functional values. As an example,
in our earlier conversation
with Lee silver,
he brought up a guy named George Church,
George Church as a scientist
at Harvard medical school.
He's thought to be absolutely brilliant
by everybody that knows him. Well.
He actually happened to have a picture
of Georgia on him and he and he showed
us. Oh, is that he does. He
does look like a radical.
Describe him. He's wearing
an army shirt of some kind.
He's got a nice bushy
beard and a spit curl. Oh,
was Santa Claus played
by Clark Gable? Well,
we had to visit him
and George is unusual as scientists go.
I'm George Church professors genetics
at Harvard Medical School in the last 20
years.
He's been going further and further and
further in terms of synthesizing life.
Okay, I'll slide. You know what
I'll do? I'll slide. He he's,
he's stuffing some kind of big black
rod up my nose. That would be the Mike.
Now the kind of creatures,
the George Church engineers are the
same kind of those MIT kids use eco lie.
By taking these little tiny Nikolai and
adding a few genes from other organisms
and and tweaking the internal chemistry.
He has gotten the
Nikolai to suck in sugar,
which is what they normally like to
eat, poop out all kinds of things.
Most notably drum roll please. Diesel
for real. Oh yeah.
And the company I co founded
has produced hydrocarbon status.
Just a fancy way of saying
among other things, diesel,
three different kinds to run in
three types of engines, cars,
trucks and planes. I was
curious to see how it all works.
So he took me to a room at the back of
his lab where he's perfecting the process
and he pointed to a small container.
So here's an example where we might
grow up a large batch of of cells in a,
in a fermenter. So this big Vat right
here, which is, I don't know how,
what's the size of a couple
of leaders? Pretty small.
It's about the size of a coke bottle.
And right now he can
only make a few drops.
So there are some scale issues to solve.
But I asked him you to close
your eyes and you know,
where does he imagine this stuff going
and project forward into the future?
And he painted. Describe it for
me. What would it look like?
An amazing picture of
huge bodies of water.
Giant pawns or lakes of gas. I mean,
just imagine we could take a boat,
paddle around and be beautiful birds
chirping except under the surface.
Trillions of bacteria, gloomy,
busily eating plant life,
burping out diesel fuel,
which they float to the surface
as this kind of gassy foam.
And you can skim it off, skim it off,
throw into a pipe. There you have it.
I mean, this could be the
oil refinery of the future.
No more pumping out of the ground and
fighting wars. Forget that. That's old.
Now we're talking to
Mike Robes and Mike Rose.
And this could be just the beginning.
I mean, according to Lee silver,
people are hoping that this kind of
bioengineering can produce all kinds of
stuff. You know, a drug that cures
malaria. Something that makes plastic,
I mean, anything. Well I,
they would be good. Yeah.
But there is part of it that makes me a
little uneasy. Why? And, and then, well,
I wanna introduce you
to another bioengineer.
He's often called the leader
of the pack, like the rat pack.
Sort of like the rat pack. His name is
Craig Venter and like the Red Peg folks,
he's very talented. He very
ambitious. He's very driven.
He's also working on a bug for fuel.
He also thinks that the earth is in
trouble. We're messing our nests,
something terrible. And when we were
at the 92nd street y in New York,
he said to just right
out loud bio engineering,
creating new life is our last hope.
It's probably our one major chance of
having our species survive on this planet.
I mean this is the engineering of the
rest of this century and that's a little,
I mean, stand beside young lamb.
I'll rescue now with my magical scientific
ability and my natural engineering
skills. Kids saved the world that stand
aside and throw them a parade. Well,
except that you don't realize just
how ambitious these these guys are.
What's wrong with
ambition? Nothing really.
But what you don't know is
just how bold this guy is.
He not only wants to mix and match
traits that already exist in, in,
in life to make new funds or life,
he wants to do original design.
He wants to think of things
that life is never done before.
Things that are in his
head that are entirely new.
He even dreams of life life
form from scratch, from scratch,
completely, like 4.1 billion years
ago. Kind of like in Genesis.
It'd probably take a little longer, but
I think there will be new life forms.
You think it will be possible in your
lifetime that someone will go into a
store, buy dust,
figure out what it is that they have to
do with that desk so that what they make
will be unmistakably alive,
not alive than alive.
Yes. Yes,
but using the knowledge that we have
from studying this 4 billion years of
evolution. What?
What if I told you that I thought no,
I don't know why. Just know.
I think you reviewed my grant.
Nobody. There's a, there's a
candidness to scientists that I,
that puzzles me a little bit. Isn't
there something that you think,
and this would be really close,
it creating life that just
might be out of our grasp.
It might be forever and
mysterious and yet you guys like,
is there anything in the
way of engineering life?
Is there anything that
you think is not doable?
Do you think it's never going
to happen, that you'll meet,
create a conscious life form from scratch
or it will never happen that you will
create a morally, you know,
a sense of a creature with moral sense
of right and wrong, but I don't know.
I think you think that everything
is possible. Everything.
I think you're right.
[inaudible]
okay. I get that Craig and people
like him might have a little bit of a,
of an attitude about
what they can accomplish,
but is that your problem that hit that
he, it's his attitude? No, no, no, no.
It's a sense of life,
I think is wrong here.
I really appreciate because of
Darwin and Darwinian evolution,
that it takes 100 million,
200 million a billion years for creatures
to figure out how to live in the
neighborhood of life, how to know what
to eat, what to avoid, how to fit in,
how you, you know, if
you're going to sustain,
you've got to learn how to live
harmoniously with the rest of nature.
It takes awhile,
but here come these engineers over
some weekend think I have a new ideal,
maybe the lead oil or audible and then
you stick it into the world and you've
just stuck something into a rich fabric
of life and you have no idea of all the
different consequences that could
follow from that decision. I look at,
look at what happens right
now with antibiotics.
That scientist Nigel Goldenfeld,
who we heard from, you know before,
50 years ago we declared war on microbes.
We fed antibiotics to cattle, to
kids when they had virus infections.
We put so much antibiotics into
our bodies and into our food,
but the bacteria we were trying to kill
figured out a way to avoid our medicines
and now they're stronger
than ever. Melt smart.
We didn't know there were things that we
didn't really understand that we didn't
know that we didn't understand and
we're paying the place for that now.
I am frightened that these people have
so much ambition and so much certainty in
them that frankly they
don't fear what biologists
don't know about life.
It's a really a Frankenstein
story that is there.
So much hubris in this and as
Steve Strogatz will tell you,
biologists and pic scientists
in general, no veer.
We now know how much we
don't know about life.
If biology really is
about collective behavior,
the interaction of billions of
molecules, billions of species,
and this network of of life we
barely understand. You know,
we keep being surprised about life.
On the one hand we can tinker in this
engineering way like the MIT students do
or like venter is doing.
But on the other hand,
the best biologists are still mystified
that we only have that about the same
number of genes as a worm.
We're really still missing
99% of the picture, literally.
So it's a scary time today to start
playing doctor given how ignorant
do you know that it
Stony Brook University,
where your mom worked for all
those years, there was a scientist,
maybe a few doors down from your mom who,
who made from scratch
using the dust particles.
We've talked about the polio virus,
which the whole world has
been working to eliminate.
Polian made a new polio
virus. Why? I don't know. I,
there was a lot of controversy about it,
but there is a guy could perhaps in a
cave somewhere in Afghanistan who wants to
make a polio virus and who will use it
against this technology. You're right,
you are right that there is, there
are some bad things that can happen.
Very bad. So the question is then what?
Like what do you do in the face
of that risk? How do you proceed?
Do you say to these guys, stop.
Would you have these guys
stop doing what they're doing?
Stop doing their experiments.
Asking questions, being curious. Oh,
that'd be ridiculous to tell a science
not to do science. So what then
I, I don't know. I have to, I
don't, I don't know exactly,
but do I want them to,
to not do experiments?
No, I'm not saying don't know.
So I'm not going to be a troglodyte
and say we shouldn't play with these.
And Steve Strogatz agrees. I think
it's great to play with them.
But I'm scared too. I Dunno. I'm confused
about it because we have to play.
That's how we make all science, you know,
they speak of Homo Lutens human
beings as the player that we,
we are what we are because we like
to play with nature, with ideas,
with language. This is how we
learn things. So we're gonna play,
but we have to be very
careful about how we play.
And we don't want to fall into the
idea that we know more than we, we do.
[inaudible]
we have a vast ocean to
discover it before us.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
okay, well, I guess that's
all the time we have. Um,
anything that you heard this hour that
you want to hear again, more information.
It's all on our website, radio lab.org.
Any creature you'd like to build already
designed for creature that you'd like
to build or any monster that you have
in your head that you'd like to make a
real living flesh, send that to us
too. Yes. While you're on our site,
send us an email as well. Radio
lab@wnyc.org is our email address.
I'm Jad Abumrad I'm Robert
Krulwich. Thanks for listening.