You are listening to
radiolab radio from w n y.
S t e n n.
P. R. Everybody level check.
We're going to start the show with
this fellow. His name's Ben Zimmer.
He's the on language columnist for
the New York Times magazine because we
figured since we wanted to
do a show called at break,
we thought we should call Ben.
And so we came into the studio and he
brought with him a bunch of his favorite
oops
example. I just wanted to give
one of my favorite examples of a,
the first one that he hit us where the,
uh, began its life. Was it in an AP,
a news article?
Mm, well, it was an AP story,
but the AP story was fine when the AP
story appeared on a news site from the
American family association, which by the
way is a conservative Christian group.
Um, the headline, first of all,
said homosexual eases into
100 final at Olympic trials
and then kissing guys with something
that they would be good at. Well,
if you read on, if you're confused by
that headline, very, here's how it starts.
Tyson homosexual easily won his semi-final
for the a hundred meters at the u s
Olympic track and field trials.
And it goes on to say, you know,
throughout the entire article,
you know, on Saturday,
homosexual misjudge the
finish is opening heat.
The entire article had the word
homosexual in place of gay.
The, his name is Tyson [inaudible].
According to Ben, this is a classic,
classic example of a search and replace,
oops.
This group apparently did not like the
word gay because gay makes homosexuality
sound very nice and they're gay, right?
So what they did was they ran a search
and replace every instance of the word
gay with the word homosexual,
but then you get Tyson gay
becoming Tyson homeless, sexual.
This was just a one that a, they
were a little careless with.
Just to be fair, here's a
contrasting example. In 1990,
the Frizz Newbie ran martyr
about the, uh,
Massachusetts budget crisis and had made
reference to new taxes that will help
put Massachusetts quote back
into the African American. Um,
and they had to issue a correction saying
it should have said back in the day,
no, this one might've been a
newsroom prank. We're not sure. Good.
Then get into paper just for the
hell of it. Here's one last one.
This one happened after the famous
broadcast, or Walter Cronkite died.
When did the Chicago Tribune did
their online obituary for Cronkite?
What happened was every instance of
Cronkite got replaced by Mr Cronkite.
You can understand the thinking
behind that. They deciding,
okay for deceased males, they should
be referred to with the title Mr.
But then what this, uh,
turns into is an obituary where
it says he was born Walter Leland,
Mr Cronkite, Jr,
and he refers to his radio show,
Walter Mister contact's 20th century.
It's got things about his family has
his son, Walter, Mr Cronkite, the third,
his daughter, his daughter
Kathy, Mr [inaudible].
My heart went, Ooh, Jed. The
moment that my heart went, Ooh.
And I'm Robert, I never will
forget to this episode of Radiolab.
The moment that I have for
oopses starting with a tree.
Oops. Then we've got a goose
oops. And an entire town. Oh, oops.
And a Harvard professor
that really want it. Yeah, no, we should
just say before we start, oops. Oops.
Is oops, can be a misleading term.
Really what we're talking about
here is something Greek. Well,
you try hard to prevent one thing and
then you get exactly what you didn't want
to get back at you. Right. And our
first story falls into that category.
Back a few seasons ago,
we were doing a show on deception and we
ended up talking with a professor named
Ruben Gore. Hello. Hi. Is this
professor Gar? Yes. Speaking.
He's a psychiatrist. Works at
the University of Pennsylvania.
And I'd call them to talk
about his research on self
deception, self deception.
It's fascinating stuff.
And I'm not gonna go into it now
because somewhere along the way the
conversation took a really
weird turn. No. Oh yeah.
Get Out. Yeah. Yeah.
And it happened when he began
to tell me about some studies,
range studies done by a,
uh, what was the guy's name?
His name is hanging in,
I don't remember. Second.
MMM. MMM.
What's his name? Henry Murray.
And the reason we want to hear about
Henry Murray is what? I built it up.
Don't you want to know more than that
yet? No. Hold on that. Tell me why. Okay.
I'm going to let it unfold because we
were so interested in what rubigard told
us that we found a guy.
Yeah. Hi. How's it going?
Who knows a whole lot about professor.
Mary's name is Austin Chase.
Very windy day today, isn't it?
He lives in a remote cabin in Mon Ghana.
Got Another one coming
in the foothills. Okay.
Professor Marie was a
very prestigious scholar.
He had been a professor of psychology
at Harvard before the Second World War.
During the war. He, uh, went to work for
the s Shasha Office of strategic services,
which was the forerunner of the CIA.
And a couple of years into his
government service says Austin.
Something happened.
It really spooked him and spooked
the country during the Korean War.
Uh, there were some Gis, he said he'd
been captured in Korea and afterwards,
after the Korean War,
they refused to come home.
They appeared to have communist
portrayed their country,
their own country, and disappeared
behind Red China bamboo,
correct John, if anybody wants to go home.
[inaudible] and their
military establishment was
very much concerned that the
communists had found techniques for
brainwashing and so Marie and other
psychiatrists in the government were
charged with preparing those soldiers to
resist that kind of brainwashing.
And Marie himself developed
a style of interrogation.
Stressful interrogation was the term used
that the army could use on its pilots.
Yeah. He developed this
method of kidnapping.
Then before they were sent them to mission
and then says Ruben Guru. He'd run
them through a battery of tests.
Let's just see if they break and if they
didn't break, they were fine to fly.
This kind of psychological training was
most kind of a new front in the Cold War
and in the 1950s Marie's back at Harvard
and he's thinking of ways to fine tune
his techniques and this is
where things get interesting.
He took a clash of Harvard undergraduates,
20 some odd sophomores, mostly. Oh.
Students were told to write an
autobiographical essay like a diary,
and he told him, you know what,
make it very personal, right.
You're deep his thoughts in their highest
aspirations and hopes while you're at
it,
right about your sexual fantasies where
class and after the students were done,
he said to them,
now I'm going to pair you up into groups
of two to debate or discuss what they'd
written. Students were
like, okay, we'll share.
No big deal, but they were duped.
They were walked into this
very brightly lit room.
Just turned out to be an interrogation
room with a one way mirror,
put in a chair, strapped in.
Electrodes were attached
to their arms, chest,
their heart to measure stress basically,
and they were also filming through the
mirror and then instead of a classmate in
want a total strange older man.
This guy was holding their essay,
they didn't know it,
but Murray had trained to do everything
he could to anger and humiliate the
undergraduate and he just tore them
apart piece by piece using the essay.
The mock was shooting aspirations.
Then after this was done,
the students have to come back week after
week to view themselves on film being
humiliated. That to me seems like the
worst part. After they'd been humiliated,
they had to watch themselves
being humiliated over and over.
People became tearful and miserable and
he was proud how he destroyed people.
What, what
kind of person is this? Like why
did he do it? Yeah, why he did it.
There were any one of a number of
explanations and they all could be true.
One is it was a grant grabbing. He
was getting money to do these things.
I'll say, you know, this was the Cold War.
He was fighting communism may have thought
it was justified. Yeah, but, but he,
but he just said he was
proud of this. Well,
it also happens to be the case that he
was having an affair for about 30 years
with a woman, not his wife,
and they had a sexual relationship
that bordered on the shadow mask.
In fact, wash
sadomasochistic another word,
Moorish interest in these
was intensely personal.
Whatever the case in
those Harvard experiments,
there was one student who was
just not prepared for any of it.
His code name was lawful, lawful.
They gave each of the students our
code name because he was considered so
conventional. He was
really still just a boy.
Graduated High School at 16 was
living a thousand miles from home,
two shirts and two charges to his name
and lawful apparently was an especially
lonely kid. The notes I found, okay,
Marie did refer specifically
to lawful Sesay,
which she shies highly alienated.
So when lawful walked into that
room, sat across from that stranger.
The guy really did a job on him.
He was young so he was
barely growing a beard.
So the first thing that guy tells
him is, what is this on your chin?
Something trying to look like a beard.
Then the guy opens up lawfully essay
and lets him have it. Meanwhile,
like all the students lawfully had been
hooked up to all these stress monitors.
I a analyzed his data compared to all
the other participants he had firing
awake, strongest response. Physiologically
you mean like it's heartbeat.
The fastest are linked to everything.
[inaudible]
amazingly,
this experiment went on for
three years and decades later,
a lot of the subjects were still upset,
considered it one of the most traumatic
experiences they'd had in their 20s
lawful never forgot it. That's right.
It was resentful at the way
he was treated at Harvard.
He had nightmares about Professor
Murray after he left Harvard.
So what happened to this guy? Oh,
well he finished up his four
years at Harvard, got his degree,
and got a phd in math,
and he began to teach math and
then he became a household name.
What do you mean? Well, I mean this,
yes,
Bi raid began just afternoon in a remote
mountainous area called Stemple pass
about five miles outside the
town of Lincoln, Montana.
Turns out that lawful, his real
name your door Kosinski yeah, no.
Oh yeah. Kazanski was no out. Yeah.
The FBI dubbed him the
Unabomber in nearly 18 years.
He found targets all over the country.
His meticulously made bombs have killed
three people and injured another 23
blew my arm off to the side like this.
And the first thing I thought
was why did they do that?
Do you think that this study
had anything to do with, uh,
Ted Cruz in skis subsequent
very infamous act?
Well, I think he probably would have,
if it hadn't been for that experiment,
he still probably would have been maybe
reclusive living somewhere in a
cabin in one [inaudible] regardless.
But I think the evil twist
was, uh, was done there.
Years later while he was researching
a book, Austin Chase corresponded
with Kozinski
and one of his letters,
he mentioned that he participated in some
psychological experiments conducted by
profession. Marie, of course,
I was very curious and I wrote it back
to tell me a little bit more about it.
And he shed while you really, uh, don't,
I don't know if you want to
go into that can of worms.
[inaudible]
Rubin Gore is a professor of psychiatry
at the University of Pennsylvania and
Austin Chase is the author of the book
Harvard and the making of the Unabomber.
[inaudible]
oops. Oops.
Here's one more
from Ben Zimmer. What
is the Cupertino effect?
The Cupertino effects is the name given
to the phenomenon of when you rely on a
spellchecker too much, it
will give you a suggestion.
And very often it's a suggestion that
you really shouldn't take. It would,
why is it called the Cupertino
effect? Well, in early spellcheckers,
if you wrote cooperation, the
word cooperation, c, O, o, p, e,
r, a, t, I, O, n,
perfectly typical spelling of the word
cooperation in early spellcheckers.
Um, that word was not there because it
expected you to spell it c o Hyphen.
And so what it would do is it would give
you a suggestion and the suggestion was
Cupertino is in another
town and then in California.
So if you look at documents that
are still online from the UN,
from the EU, from NATO,
you'll find dozens and dozens
of Cupertino's that have
found their way in there.
For instance, here's a German
NATO officer was quoted as saying,
the Cupertino with our Italian
comrade proved to be very fruitful.
And then there was a proposal from the
EU scientific and technical research
committee. They proposed quote,
stimulating cross-border Cupertino.
Oops. Number two, you go the the next.
This is the next one is just
a different flavor entirely.
We're going to meet someone. I don't know.
I can't really say they did
anything wrong. It's just,
I mean this one is more like, like
would you say luck mixed the poster.
You just picked up a toothbrush and
it was connected to a snake that was
connected to a monster that was
connected to the devil himself.
You wouldn't know. You're
just picking up a tooth.
So this is a case where really bad
things happen. The story comes from our,
our own reporter Pat Walters. Yeah,
it concerns [inaudible] go ahead and,
okay, so just to start, I want you
to imagine you're on a mountain top.
Okay. This mountain is in western Nevada.
The second highest peak in the
state of Nevada got a name,
it's called wheeler peak and it
was this, this is Michael Cohen.
I go by Michael P. Cohen.
He's a nature writer and he tells me that
up on top of this mountain there is a
grove of old trees.
You can see the trees from a distance
and Eric Wood is so bright that it
actually glistens in the sun.
What do they call it? Oh,
bristle cone pines. Yes. Can you
describe what they look like? Sure.
They tend to be shorter, broad
at the base. They get very,
very old and as they get old they
become towards your door gnarled.
They sort of twist up towards the sky.
The overall effect is sort of electrical.
They look kind of like what
you'd seen a Tim Burton movie.
So you have that picture in your
mind? Yep. Okay. So the story,
it's about the scientist named Don Curry.
I'm going to take a drink of water.
Wait, I'm going to take
a drink of water. Okay.
Story starts in 1964 don
curry was a graduate student
from North Carolina and he
was young. Do we know how old he was?
He was 30 years old and he'd just gotten
a big grant from the national science
foundation to do some climate change
research. Not like climate change.
Now though,
climate change thousands of years ago
because he learned that you can actually
sort of travel back in time,
go back into the past using
this spacing between tree rings,
the annual rings. This is Ron Lanner,
he's a retired forest service scientist
and he says you can use the width of the
tree rings to determine whether it was
colder at one time or Rainier at one
period in the tree's life or whatever.
So curry up on top of this mountain up
amongst these trees and he needs to find
one that he can look inside and kind
of see what the weather was like.
Way Back in the past five minutes
of looking is all it was involved.
This is from a Nova documentary.
Carrie died a few years ago and this
is actually the only time that he ever
talked about this story on tape.
Literally he found a tree there,
first old tree that we climbed to that uh,
he described as looking super, super old.
So curry takes out this special drill,
which scientists used to take like a
core sample to look at the rings. Yeah.
And presses it up against the tree,
give it a good push to get it through
the bar and he starts twisting it in and
clockwise into the tree.
But he wasn't having much luck.
The normal approach to coring
the tree wasn't working.
It becomes harder and harder for him
to turn this thing into the tree and
eventually
the bit of his drill
broke off in the tree. Oh
this isn't just any drill.
He ordered it from Sweden and
the whole time he's thinking,
if I can't get this thing out of the tree,
that would mean the research
project would be lost for the year.
So at this point,
kind of lumbers back the
mountain and dejected.
He managed to find the district ranger
and told him the problem guys might
drill. It got stuck in the tree,
what should I do? And they tell him,
don't worry about it done. We'll just
cut the tree down. This is one tree.
There are dozens of
these trees all around.
So they start slicing into the tree.
It takes awhile to cut it
down cause it's really dense.
Knots are old and eventually the tree
falls over. Then they cut some slabs
out of the lower part of the tree.
Curry gets one of these slabs back
to his lab, throws it on a big desk,
finds a magnifying glass because the
rains are really small and he starts
counting one, two, three. As he counts,
he's making little pin holes or pencil
marks every 50 year, a hundred years,
three 17 by the end of the first day,
he gets back to a thousand years like
the dark ages where in Europe eating raw
pasta
day to 2006 by the middle of the
day he gets back to like Jesus,
Roman Empire, gladiator, Centurion.
But even at that point he was only like
half [inaudible] wait, he finished.
He kept counting. We can begin to see
that we were getting over 4,000 years,
over 4,500 over 4,600 and we
ended up around 4,900 years.
4,844 annual rings in
it and at that point,
the oldest tree that anyone had
ever found was 4,600 years old.
In other words, he had
himself the oldest tree ever,
but he had killed it.
And you've got to think,
I've got to have done something
wrong. I bet her recount.
I better recount again. But no matter
how many times he counted the rings,
the number never went down.
[inaudible]
the world's oldest tree was dead.
Uh,
it was, it was truly, it was
horrifying. It was a, it was a,
like a family tragedy.
Uh,
people had given these trees names.
There was Buddha and
Socrates and Methuselah.
They called Curry's tree,
the promethium tree.
And the guy who named that particular
tree was so angry that he wrote a magazine
article where he called Don curry
a murderer all across the country.
There is a tremendous uproar. Same thing.
What about killing the world's
oldest living organism?
Ma, I thought we were just saying
it was the oldest living tree. It's,
it's both. It's the oldest tree
and it's the oldest organism.
It wait, wait, wait. You mean that
the oldest continuously living
okay.
And [inaudible] shrub mushroom, eh. Oh,
you making it. Are you sure
about this? This head with,
this is the oldest living, continuous
individual alive on the planet.
I know what I said. This tree was older
than any other tree on the planet,
older than the oldest sponge,
which is like 1500 years old and
older than the oldest animal.
Just some sort of oyster,
which is 405 years old,
older than any other living
thing on the entire planet.
Oh God.
Where do we go? Here we go from there.
So where does that leave you, Mr. Curry.
So what happened to him? Well,
right after this happened,
Currie pretty much stopped
doing research on trees.
He basically studied salt flats
for the rest of his career.
[inaudible]
big treeless salt flats.
And aside from that little Nova
clip that we played before,
he hasn't really ever gone
on record talking about this.
So it's hard for us to say like
how we really felt about it.
There was this one moment he was
being interviewed by a TV reporter,
like about his salt flats research.
And this would have been in the 19
probably the late eighties early nineties
years and years after
the whole tree incident.
All of a sudden out of a clear blue sky
[inaudible]
the television reporter asked him, oh,
aren't you the curry who
killed the world's oldest tree?
He was completely empty.
[inaudible] yeah.
Curry just turned his back and ran away.
[inaudible]
who is it that's the same? It's just
we're off. Somebody on the other hand, he,
he did have the incredible ms switching
to kill the oldest living organism on
our planet. Yeah,
but this is 25 years later and he's
still getting hassled about this tree.
[inaudible] we're talking
about one tree here. Well No,
we're talking about the tree here. Right,
but thing about a tree that lasts
for four almost 4,000 more than that.
5,005 almost five years. Is
that the, it is a repository.
It is a talisman for 5,000 years of
earth history. But I mean would it be,
would it be any less bad if the tree
were three and a half thousand years old?
This is just one more
old thing. No, it is.
It's the oldest of all taking like the
Guinness Book of World Records. Oh,
you keep making me into like a
Ripley's believe it or not guy,
but no really what
you're being, no, no, no.
There's a when you've been around
longer than everybody else,
there's a certain percentage
of your experience. Yeah.
Well I'm older than you.
I walk in here and I look at you
and I feel pity for other things.
You don't know [inaudible]
with the treatment of
film in a right blade,
but it must have been around as your
board and Pat Walters right about a month
or you the round line and we're happy
to say that since our original broadcast
at the story, a new oldest
living tree has been found.
It's also a bristle cone pine also in
the white mountains and its current age.
According to Dr. Peter Brown of the Rocky
Mountain Tree Ring Research Group is
just about 5,060 years old,
which makes it actually older than
don Curry's tree when it was cut down.
So Don Curry, if you're out there
listening from the afterlife,
you can now rest in peace. We'll
continue in a moment. Little brains, man.
Hi, this is chuck from Albany,
New York radio lab is supported in part
by the National Science Foundation and
by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information about
Sloan at www dot Sloan
Dr. Ward,
this is Annie Schrader
calling from Salmon, Idaho.
Radiolab is supported by Casper and
award-winning manufacturer of one premium
mattress.
It's engineered for supportive comfort
and ships in a compact box right to your
door with free shipping and returns
with supportive memory foam,
Casper creates a sleep surface
that contours to your body.
Casper gives you quality
mattresses at a great price.
You can order online and try it in
your own home risk-free for 100 nights.
Save $50 on your Casper
mattress by visiting
casper.com/radio lab and using the
offer code radio lab.
And now to keep us in our oopsie mood.
Here's another Cupertino oops
from language expert, Ben Zimmer.
So back in October, oh six Reuters,
the news wire had an article
about honeybees. And uh,
there was some very interesting sentences
in this article about honeybees.
For instance, did you know,
quote Queen Elizabeth has 10 times the
lifespan of workers and lays up to 2000
eggs a day. That's why
she's a very nice girl,
but doesn't have a lot to say because
there's all these eggs dropping on the
floor with it's highly evolved social
structure of tens of thousands of worker
bees commanded by Queen Elizabeth.
The honeybee genome could also improve
the search for genes linked to social
behaviors. So every time
a clean reference came in,
they were commanded to that
particular queen. Whenever the words,
the Queen appeared in this
article, they had to be the queen.
So the queen was being
replaced with Queen Elizabeth,
unfortunately in an article about honeybee
[inaudible]
Ma'am
this next, Ooh, singular. Ooh, wouldn't
it be, I mean, if you have one, oop.
Wouldn't never heard that, right?
No sister. A new clean edge. Oop. This
next one, it raises the question of,
I guess you'd say, of moral balance.
The question that I don't think any of
us would want to have to answer comes to
us from our producer Lulu Miller.
Okay, so set up this story a,
this story happens and where it's in a
little town in northern Michigan called
Myo 7:00 AM just drove through
the Delaware water gap.
That's me on my way out
there from New York.
The Sun is rising and it's about an
800 mile drive and is just gorgeous out
here. Listen to you lush and
I'll enter the outdoors. No,
yeah, I know,
but I'm just one of those people by
windows and when I get out into nature,
bear dive, feel my place in
the [inaudible] world. Anyways,
it's crossed into Myo. What was the
reason you were going again to see a bird?
A very, not just rare,
not just the kind of bird birders
get obsessed about this is a bird.
This is what they call a life bird. Oh,
life. Birders wait their life to see.
It really only found right
here. What's the bird called?
The Kirtland warbler. Now have you,
have you seen apparently before? No,
I've never seen one. This is my
first trip up here. This right here.
Where are you?
We're just outside of the town on the
edge of the forest about to go in and I
was standing with about 15 people
who've come from everywhere.
You folks coming from to see this bird
Toledo. I'm from South Carolina. Yeah,
we're from Oregon, Wyoming.
We'll walk out to a spot,
try to stay single file park ranger leads
us down a path into a little clearing
and pretty immediately in the
background there. Way Back there.
The guy from Ohio spots of
Kirtland. Huh? There you go.
Good tiny yellow bird
back there. Right there.
Up High and the Jack Pine Tree.
Oh Great. To sing it like crazy.
The lady from Dayton starts clapping.
Can you describe what you're seeing?
I see a lovely bird with a
gray back is a guy from Oregon,
Jim Coleman, blue gray bag,
and his wife read us smaller than a rob
and brilliant yellow in the sunlight.
It's just an absolutely
radiant bird. Yeah.
Is this worth the trip tomorrow
again? Oh, you bet. I don't know.
It just makes me thankful
that I'm here. Yeah, so,
and it makes me break for
them. My wife is here.
I know this is something she's
wanting to see a lot. For a long time.
Jim Actually starts to tear up.
It's a very special bird. Hold my hand.
He had a guy and that's what
this story is really about.
How special is this bird? Meaning
well, how much is a species?
Um, well here's the backstory. Okay.
In the early seventies the
warbler almost went extinct.
The reason why it thought was because
of a little creature called the Calbert.
I want to go in. Okay. That's
just the sound of them.
It's a parasite. You know
when someone who is this guy,
this is Chris Mensing fish and wildlife
biologist with the u s fish and Wildlife
Service, and we're standing
in this cage full of Calbert,
but it looks like we've got
six males and one female.
Let me grab a couple who just
reached out and grabbed two of them.
You can get it that the
males, oh yeah, go ahead.
Imagine a tiny little gnarly crow
got really sharp little. Yeah.
But with this blunt dagger like beat,
very drab body. I'm very doll to,
here's what the Calbert does to the
warbler while the warbler is out of its
nest, like getting an
alarm or something. Yeah.
The Calbert lay is one of its own
eggs in the nest to make room for it.
So the warbler doesn't
know anything is up.
It pushes out one of the warblers
eggs. Oh yeah. Out of the nest.
[inaudible] and the timing is such that
the cupboard egg will hatch first and
will double its size in 24 hours. So
by the time that the host birds hatch,
that Colberg may be up
to four times the size,
and when they start begging for food
foods, the parents, the loudest,
most aggressive chick is going
to get fed the cupboard chick.
So the warbler mom ends up shoveling
food into this Calbert chicken. Yep.
Oftentimes it gets so much food
that another Warburg chick will die.
So when the cowbirds first showed up in
this area in late 18 hundreds early 19
hundreds the warbler population
just started plummeting.
This huge drop by 1971 or
only 200 males on earth.
Wow.
So what do you do? Are you asking me? Hmm.
Um, I guess you get it. Yeah.
Kill the cow. Birds. Um,
this is one of 54 traps and new
one that we just built this year,
which is why we're out in this cage. It's
actually a cowbird trap. Oh, she did?
Yeah, she, yeah,
she bite me just like anyone that's
yet someone larger grabbing you.
They don't appreciate it too much. And
so anyone know how to kill, I kind of do.
Yeah. The rassic compression is the term
we use. We basically squeeze the bird,
suffocating and preventing
it from breathing just with
your hands. There's no,
Yup, Yup. Yeah. You have to do
that. Yeah. Like all the time. Yeah.
Did you see this? No,
but 1972 fish and wildlife service sets
up a bunch of traps a few years at about
12,000 dead cow birds. Later it work
[inaudible]
kind of the population stopped dying off,
but then it didn't start bouncing
back. What's going on? Yeah.
Why aren't we seeing bigger numbers
now that we're catching the competence?
That's Rita Helgeson.
She worked with the forest service back
in the eighties and we thought, well,
if we finally concluded it must be
just there is not enough happening.
10 like they don't have enough
trees. Is that right? Well, no,
there are plenty of trees,
but the thing about warblers is
they like a specific kind of tree.
They like them very young.
[inaudible] I could feel it at
the same. They like I'm young now,
but they like young trees
is what you're saying? Yup.
And there aren't young trees in
this place? No. It's really weird.
When when they started
looking around this forest,
they notice all the trees
were really, really old.
Why wouldn't there be
young trees? Well us.
Oh, you can
[inaudible] hey, smokey bear. Let's see.
When humans began to settle in this
area of Michigan in about the 1880s they
brought with them at certain
human disdain for fire,
could perforate forest fires.
The fire is exactly what's needed
up there to make new trees. Yeah.
This ecosystem is a fire
ecosystem. That's Chris.
It Burns because when these trees burn,
they release their seeds and
make room for new trees to grow.
It is a fire ecosystem. It
is made to burn. So I asked
do you again, what do you do?
Do you start fires? Would that be the
solution that would be the solution. Wild.
So the forestry started doing
what we call a prescribed burn.
Basically says Rita, they burned
down a little patch of forest,
a few acres to regenerate it and one
windy spring day in 1980 at a place called
Mac Lake. The forestry service started a
fire that they probably shouldn't have.
Okay. My name is Dick Lord. At
the time of the Mack lake fire,
I was part of the ignition
crew for the prescribed burn.
What is an ignition crew?
Uh, they light the fire.
So at 10 in the morning they can his crew
go out into the woods when the plants
start setting up perimeters and they
begin lighting, a few stands of shrunk.
I was driving home, that's Bob Burner.
Best name ever for firefighter.
I could see forest service starting
to do a burn, and I thought,
this is not a good time. It was
windy. They didn't have the man power,
and I said, well, I'll probably be getting
called out here. The name. Basically,
we did not realize that the weather was
going to change as rapidly as it did and
the wind came up suddenly,
something nobody could predict,
and it took the fire across the road
into a standard mature Jack Pine.
[inaudible] flames, probably
a hundred 150 feet year solid.
It's like a roaring train.
Boys guys jump into their bulldozers
trying to plow trenches alongside the fly,
pinch at all, and you can feel the heat.
It was really out of our control
hitting the tops of the trees rolling.
I knew at the rate it was traveling
that nobody's going to be a major
catastrophe
within six hours. It had
burned over 20,000 acres.
It's one of the fastest moving fires ever
documented. Yeah, we're through here.
[inaudible] as you can see, it was
all black. These are two guys. Hi Bob.
I'm like, oh, houses in the
area that got burnt murder.
The guy down there in the corner, yeah,
grabbed it off there and dropped the
black chard. Their houses were okay,
but 41 houses were destroyed all the
way up to the lake. She's completely,
Yep. Nothing Green. No.
Like something out of a moonscape fires.
You could see everything gone and the
worst part about it for all of us,
that's three to help us. Then again,
one said it killed one in the
foreign service employees,
a very young wildlife technician who
was very well loved by his coworkers.
A guy named Jim Swiderski. You
know Jim was a good friend?
Yeah.
As well as an employee
declared. Again, Jim's boss.
He told me that Jim had been
a postman for a few years,
but just loved birds so much that he
took a huge pay cut to come and help
protect the warbler. Basically
what happened was, oh, okay,
the fire overran him. Oh,
the press was having a heyday just tearing
into the forest service from what had
happened in the towns. People were
very angry at the forest service.
How could you do this? We just,
as they were told not to wear their
forest service uniforms in town. Gosh,
it was so terrible in the
forest itself. You know,
there was nothing there.
It was completely silent.
But a year later,
a little bit of green started to poke up
and the next year a little bit more and
eight to 10 years after that Mac like
Bern just seemed like every word you
turned around, you'd stop for, listen. No,
hardly five or six birds. The tremendous,
that was the, the answer to the
mystery. The fire, you know,
if you look at a population graph,
that's Christmas thing again.
After that Mac lake burn
population went like that,
he points his hand straight
up. So it's pretty dramatic.
And today the numbers are
up to almost 4,000 birth
and growing singing like crazy.
Now that the birds are
back, but a man is gone.
When you walk around this town,
a question lingers in the air.
Your wife over before your
mum worth the life of a bird.
Take a woman. Look at her.
No,
in my opinion it isn't. This is Ed Faucet.
I W I wouldn't trade your life for a
bird and sitting with him and his wife,
Mary Jane,
a man in a diner and no matter
where you go in this town,
but the government doing people don't
tend to be huge fans of the warbler.
It's just a small bird. I've been up
here since 68 I've never seen one.
Did you ever see one? No, never have I
seen it in and back to Ed. I just got,
I say to you,
what would you think about it if your
father or were killed for a bird?
Be Pretty hard to accept when,
but if you zoom out one human
life versus the end of a species,
you know how many warblers
there are in the United States,
there's something like 37 species of
warblers are the real number is actually
closer to 60 wow. That's
kind of ridiculous.
And that's not all they ask you. When
are you done? And we really say never.
Chris explained to me that they have to
keep killing the Calverts and they have
to keep doing burns, these smaller burns.
But every single year if we let things
be, the bird would be extinct. Wow.
That's the hard thing about this job
is knowing that we're never done.
How many people are working,
how much you're probably
looking at hundreds of people.
Well over $1 million a year spent.
All of this began to really sink in.
I'm one of my last mornings
out there. All right.
It is five in the morning. It was
the annual Kirtland warbler. Census.
We're birders from all over the world
show up to help count how many warblers
there are out there. Is it like there
is a warbler stepped up. Steps up.
There is a warbler. Yeah, that's
actually exactly how it works.
I was paired up with
this guy, Dave Mendez.
We're going to kind of walk through
the middle of these transects.
We're going to come up. He's like, he's
kind of a dude, dude. He's an older guy,
got a beer and works for
an electrical contractor.
Told me he's got a man room and man
room. You know most guys that got sports,
but I've got Kirtland's warbler
pictures up on the wall. Nice.
So I went into it thinking like, this'll
be really cool. We'll march along.
We'll count it. I looked at the
map. It was a mile maybe of a walk.
We'll be done in 20 minutes.
Well, okay, maybe not.
We're walking through the
forest on our top and they did.
We set off dense brambly
forest. Still Dark.
That was a hermit thresh. Okay. Let me
just play you a quick little time lapse.
20 to seven right now the sun's just
coming up and it's getting a little muggy
out here. That was the
curtains. Oh yeah. Yeah.
We can't count them though.
He's in that intersection.
Seven oh seven heard one way
back that way. Yeah. Yeah.
There it is again. Yeah,
but I'm not gonna mark them in because
I don't know exactly where he's at.
Seven 33 there we go.
Yeah. Yup. Right there.
Did you counter? No, no, no, no, no, no,
no. We want to be a lot more accurate.
We want to triangulate them. Nine
56 and all's well and the warbler.
Woods couple of anther bite
me. Yeah, they hurt down there.
They do a little bit.
Yeah. Get out of there.
[inaudible]
10:45 AM I know that
there's a bird out there,
I can still hear that
burden way back there.
So we ended up staying out there
for seven and a half hours.
Just marked one, right? Yep.
I've only mark one and I don't mean
sound like I'm making fun of Dave.
I mean he's doing his job well,
but at some point in between the fire
ants and taking four hours to confirm this
one bird, he's going to
be right off right here.
I just started thinking
about all the effort.
It takes Rosa trees over from us and I
can't see him. I just suddenly thought
[inaudible]
it's missing Fussy, fragile little
bird and it hasn't evolved. Who Cares?
I mean this is not worth it.
And so I started asking
people who protect the bird,
why I do that with so much
money and it's all for a bird.
And I could see it maybe
if it was for some,
but it's just one warbler of 18 million
different kinds of warblers like why do
it? Oh, we do it cause we, we should,
you know, we're stewards of the land.
That's Chris mincing
again. Cowbird killer.
It's for future generations and well,
here's the firestarter Dick Lord.
You know,
the Kirtland's warbler was listed under
the endangered species act and we had a
charge under the law to do what
we could to recover its existence.
And that's the only thing
that I can say that, you know,
we had to do what the
law required us to do,
so we should do it and the
law tells us we have to do it.
Vincent and that question is a little
wasteful for firemen worth the life of a
bird. And that guy, ed at the
diner, it just duck in my mind.
And I realized I couldn't leave this town
until I talked to the people who lost
the most and I just skated. Introduced
yourself full name. Yeah, sure.
Robert Sweaters, ski age 54
Kathleen Sweaters, Ski Florence,
Wider Ski. The mother, mother and
the mother. The guy died. Yeah. Yeah.
I guess that's it. What ice
tea or water or anything.
We're all sitting around
the kitchen table.
There's a lot of dogs and bureau over
there. Kim's brother-in-law's there too.
So off Kevin, Kevin Debris and I
asked them to tell me about Jim.
Pretty Guy. Soft spoken.
Smart is quite a character.
Yup. They told me at
first they were furious.
They should have never ever sent him
in there. Angry at the forest service.
Angry about this bird.
No. Very angry. Now,
three decades later, I say you keep
that a little vertical. Exactly. Really?
Jim's younger brother Robert said that
the thing he wanted the most is for the
Kirtland's warbler to become
the state Burke by that.
That would be the ultimate, Huh?
That would be the biggest accomplishment
ever would be that be in a state bird.
Well I guess I'm, I'm,
I guess in some ways I'm surprised
like I didn't mean to come here with
expectations,
but in some ways I thought if it was
my family that I would hate that bird,
but I would just hate that
bird. No, it's not the bird.
I mean that bird didn't do
anything to any of us. You know,
if we can keep it going, I
mean that's what he out to do.
Let's keep it going. They
think about Jim's death.
Any of the military guys
like the death of a soldier,
where would you be setting right now?
We would have lost all those soldiers
in world war one. World War Two,
he died protecting us. You
know, it's only one species.
Well then this could be another species
in another species, in another species.
Next thing you know, he'll walk out
in the morning and it'll be quiet.
Thank God for the Teddy Roosevelt and
the boys that made our national parks.
Imagine what if we didn't have those? It
costs money. It's painful, blah, blah,
blah. You gotta have the guts to do that.
And Jim was really that kind of
guy. Wow. That is convincing. Yeah,
but I mean, do you agree
for us? And I asked the mom,
what can I say? The bird
took become and back,
but the life is gone.
So why bring it up again? It's done. It's,
you can't bring it back. So
you have to live by that,
but there's always a hole in your heart,
something that none of us
will ever forget forever.
Don't ask me any more questions, please.
Okay.
And then, oh good. Oh, the power went out.
Give me a break. Oh. Oh,
cool. We go home and get the generator.
Lulu Miller.
If you want more information on warblers
or anything or if you want to subscribe
to our podcast, go to radiolab.org
hey Radiolab. This is Gretchen
cosmo and I'm sitting in Oakland,
California looking out over
beautiful Lake Merritt.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by Squarespace.
The simplest way to create
a website this new year,
make your next move with Squarespace.
Whether that's starting a business
or launching a passion project,
no matter what your goals are.
Squarespace's award winning templates
can help you present your ideas to the
world.
Beautifully use offer code Radiolab
for 10% off your first purchase of a
Squarespace domain or website.
squarespace.com make your next move.
Make your next website.
Didn't hate him. I'm Jed. I'm Robert
Dune Dude. You and your topic remains.
Oops. [inaudible] final loops coming up.
[inaudible] it's sort of a double hoops.
I would say we start with an oops.
That leads to a another,
oops. That then self negates.
It comes to us from a fellow who within
the confines of the show we will call
oopsie wheeler.
So maybe we could just start with the
both of you kinda introducing yourself and
saying who you are and what you do.
I mean just something basically
like I'm Andrea sterly. Oh me.
I'm Donald Sterling. This is dawn and
Andrew Sterling. They're chemists.
They're actually a research team here
at a University of Montana and they met
back in the 70s 1979 at the
University of California in San Diego.
We met and almost fell
in love at first sight.
We dated for a week. He proposed,
I accepted they got married and not
long after don got offered a job.
So they left their home in
Sunny California and mind you,
we lived about half a mile away
from the ocean. Nonetheless, they
packed up a truck with all of our stuff,
including about 200
plants and they moved to a
Butte, Montana, which is a
different thing altogether,
but an old mining town that barely
had a tree in the city limits.
I don't know if you want to know Andrea's
first impressions of Butte or not that
shirt. I actually burst into
tears and then started laughing.
I think we call that his [inaudible].
Yeah,
the viewing stand used to be up on the
hill over here when this was an operating
pit, so I actually grew up in the
town over from Butte, Montana.
It's kind of that town that you were
afraid to go to when you were a kid.
Filled with abandoned buildings, depressed
and actually if you walked
through town right there,
right next to the middle of town,
remember exactly where it was.
I remember being consistently enormous
open wound on the hill, like, oh wow,
this, this deep pit.
This is where the pit is,
the Berkeley pit and the guy saying,
wow is Barrett Golding. I actually,
I couldn't get back to Butte myself,
so I asked Barrett to go over there
and visit with a couple of engineer's.
So tell me who you are.
Okay, well, I'm Joe Griffin,
Montana Department of Environmental
Quality and I'm Nick Tucci.
I'm with the Montana Bureau of Mines
and geology and the three of them are
standing at the edge of the pit,
which is kind of hard to imagine,
especially the size of this thing,
but when you're at the edge of the pit
and you look down in what you actually
see is how can you
convey what we're seeing,
this enormous lake kind of, well,
it's 40 billion gallons of
water, which is a lot of water.
It's one of the larger lakes in the
United States. It's carved into this hill.
Yeah. The main difference though,
between this lake and one that you might
decide to take an afternoon dip in,
is that this lake is a
color of the water, is red,
is kind of sickly red,
and also rains and gray and black.
Oh
[inaudible]
shimmers in this way that
like words can't describe.
And when you're standing there
you can't help but wonder
the question I really have,
and I'll rephrase it after I ask it
cause it's not quite, it's like what the,
what happened? What happened? Well,
it's just a, you know, the price of copper
in the 1920s when we were stringing up
telephone wires and electrical wires and
going through world wars,
a third of the copper in the
u s came out of this hill,
you know, the long and
the short of it is, um,
you wouldn't be standing here broadcasting
this or recording this without copper
in your wire right there.
And in his heyday, you know,
before the pit was even around
Butte was this mining boom town.
But by the 1940s,
the price of copper or drop a company
that owned all the mines and BW wasn't
doing so well.
And so they figured if it'd be cheaper
and easier to just blow the top off the
hill.
Things just kept getting worse.
And by 1982 right around the time when
don and Andrea were coming to town,
going over the man,
mine's completely shut down when they
shut the pit in early 1980s right?
Here's the things, while
they're actually mining,
they keep all the groundwater pumped out
of there so that it's dry and they can
work and when they shut the mines,
they shut off the pumps. The
company turned off the pumps,
I think it was Earth Day 1982
yeah. On Earth Day after that,
the a p it started filling up with
groundwater and it took a good 10 years to
actually see a kind of a rust colored
puddling in the bottom of the pit itself,
but it was a puddle that was growing
and growing and growing and growing,
growing. Now here's the
thing about that water.
The rock around the pit is filled with
pyrite and when the water hits the Pyrite
in the air, the three reacts
to create sulfuric acid.
Oh, in turn, that's Edwin Dob.
Freelance writer had been for about
20 years. I actually grew up in Butte.
The sulfuric acid hastens the
removal of the metals from the,
or itself like gold and
silver and copper, copper,
cadmium and row sink,
iron sulfate, arsenic.
And what you end up with is
this toxic acidic disaster
and it's still rising.
The fact that, you know,
since we started working on this piece,
Jed, it's arisen like about a foot.
Um, there was an incident,
infamous incident in the mid 1990s.
Anybody who grew up anywhere
near Butte knows this
one stormy night, some
340 snow geese landed.
They landed on the water looking for
shelter and they of course drink some of
it.
The next day there were 342 goose
carcasses floating on the water.
They were all dead and the autopsy showed
lesions in the esophagus throughout
the digestive system. Oh, so it's like
the water ate their insights. Yeah.
Were you struck at all like
Alan Pon arriving there?
Did you actually kind
of go visit the mind?
The old mine site avoided
it like the plague.
We were to staunch
environmentalist in the idea of living
in a mining town was so completely
foreign. And when they first showed
up in Butte, dawn and Andrea,
or they were kind of struggling to fit
in at the university because they're
trying to study this, a little
microorganisms sponge in Bermuda,
but they're in Butte and
locked Butte, Montana.
To make matters worse when they
took off for a year on Sabbatical,
our college accidentally
unplugged our refrigerator,
destroying all of our
samples on desperation.
Definitely had no funding. We
decided we just needed to start over.
But one day a scientist named Bill Chatham
came into their lab with a piece of
wood and on this wood there was
some green, slimy stuff and he says,
you won't believe this, but I found this
stick with the slime on it in the pit
floating about a foot below the surface
of the water. No. Here's the thing.
I mean that lake is, this is like,
this is the most deadly place
you can imagine. I mean,
nothing grows here. Nothing should
grow here. Nothing. Absolutely not.
Not even anything but nothing.
Yeah. Less than nothing.
Maybe absolute nothing like
negative numbers of nothingness.
It's more than nothing is an
active getting rid of thing.
It's an a gating nothingness. You
know how there's love and hate.
This is not a lack of
love. This is hate. Okay?
But they got together
with some colleagues.
They looked at the slime and
they realized against all odds
the stuff was alive, life, an acid mine,
waste life that no one
had ever studied before.
It really is what started everything
we've been doing now. Gosh,
for the last 15 years
[inaudible] so far we found
virtually hundreds of compounds,
organisms that were growing,
organisms that make molecules
that can fight viruses,
several turn out to be good in our
Andi cancer screen, like cancer,
really per click acid in
Berkeley ammonites and the
Berkeley Assa Towel is now
published. Tons of papers. I mean
their work has just taken off,
so it's been pretty exciting research.
But then they told me this story
that totally took them by surprise.
It was about a year after they'd first
started looking at the Pittwater.
We found this sort of a
sticky, opaque, thick,
gooey black organism. Then
they noticed that weirdly,
if you put this little guy into a
thing of the water from the pit,
it actually absorbs the metals in
Pittwater. What does that mean?
Like they're taking the
metals out of the water.
They become little metal sponge. Yes.
But so they're cleaning the water
is what you're saying? Yeah.
And there's lots of people that work
with micro organisms to try to clean up
metal, laid in water. But usually these
things take in maybe like, I don't know,
10, 15% of the metal.
This little guy will actually
absorb between 85 and 95%.
Whoa.
So they got really curious about it and
they started trying to figure out where
it had ever been seen before we had it
identified and they eventually discovered
that the only place this
yeast had ever been found was
where?
Well, in the rectal swabs of geese.
Oh, okay.
You mean like the snuggies
that landed on the water? Yeah.
Hmm.
The geese left a little, uh,
a little something behind
[inaudible].
So on wheeler, more
information@radiolab.org.