Hello, I'm Jad Abumrad and
I'm Robert Krulwich, Radiolab,
the podcast hugged podcast. And one of
the things that we do on this program,
of course, look at big ideas, try
and figure out how the world works.
And to do that, we often
talk to scientists who are,
you know, asking questions,
doing experiments, giving
us data and statistics.
But there are some questions that
science just can't get to. Well,
this just holy week.
So there's Easter being celebrated
and then we're going to hear over.
And so it seemed like inappropriate time
to not ignore the fact that for most of
the world's,
some of the deepest and the
most unknowable questions
are examined through Bible
stories. That's right. And Robert,
this is a sermon that you
gave it a synagogue, right?
It's my attempt to try to reason to try
and make sense out of one of the darkest
and most difficult stories, ways that
humans have ever told each other.
The chapter in the Bible begins with
the question. It's only one word, long.
One word. Abraham was at home with
his family, his surfing, his wife.
We don't know what he's
doing at this moment.
The story doesn't say it's probably
an ordinary day and day in his life.
And suddenly Abraham hears a
voice and the voice says to him,
one word, Abraham and
Abraham answers, here am I.
This is not just a voice.
This is the voice of God.
The Bible says God,
the creator of the universe calling
down to one man calling to Abraham,
not for the first time, not at
all. When Abraham was younger,
God appeared to him and told him to
leave his home, which Abraham did.
And then God told Abraham to go
to a strange land, which he did.
And then God and Abraham exchanged
promises and had a covenant together.
And God told Abraham to send his first
son Ishmael away into the desert,
which Abraham did.
And God told Abraham he had a plan to
destroy the people of Sodom and Gomorrah.
And this time Abraham argued with
God and they went back and forth.
Abraham and God,
can't we save those cities or some
people in those cities or anyone in those
cities? And later God sent angels
to tell if the coming of Isaac,
so it was not completely out
of the ordinary. It wasn't.
I get down on your knees miracle when
God came to where Abraham was and asked
Abraham and Abraham answered, here am I.
It was just the start
of another conversation,
another in a series
until the next sentence
with God's next utterance.
This conversation changes shape and
becomes like no other conversation in the
Bible like no other story in the Bible
like no other story because God says take
now thy son by an only son whom now love
is even Isaac and get the to the land
of Moriah and offer him there for a
burnt offering upon one of the mountains,
which I shall tell thee of now. Most
of us know the circumstances here.
The back backstory.
We know that when Abraham was a young man
living in Uber with his father and his
brother,
God came to him and told him that if he
left door and traveled west away from
his home, far from the places he
knew God would give him children,
and from those children would come and
mighty nation as numerous as the stars in
the sky. And Abraham obeyed and traveled
West and settled in a strange land.
And he waited for his first child, the
child who would spawn this mighty nation.
And Abraham waited and
he waited and he waited.
And his wife Sarah waited.
And nothing happened.
Nothing happened until Sarah
was very old and old woman.
Well past childbearing age.
And that's when three angels
appeared at Abraham's tent and said,
now is the time for Sarah to have the
baby. And Sarah said, oh, come on.
Even laughed out loud at
the craziness of that idea.
But in fact the baby was
born. Isaac was born.
His arrival was a little awkward because
there was already a boy in the house,
Ishmael, also Abraham son
by his servant, Hagar.
But God had his mysterious priorities.
And Ishmael was banned from the house.
And God made it clear that the
future of Abraham's people,
the seed of this great nation lay
not in Ishmael, the oldest boy,
but inside Isaac. So Isaac,
for the purposes of nation
building was Abraham's only son,
the one whom thou love
is even Isaac. But now,
years later on this day, now
that Isaac was almost a grownup,
now God says, take now thy son,
nine only son who that lovest,
even Isaac and get the into the land of
Moriah and offer him there for a burnt
offering. By which he
means a human sacrifice.
The Hebrew word is law, meaning an
offering which is totally consumed.
So Isaac is to disappear,
to be reduced to ashes.
This the boy who was to be
everything, one male be nothing.
And what does Abraham do
when he hears this command?
What does he say in the
story? He says nothing.
Instead it says,
and Abraham rose early in the morning
and saddled his ass and took two of his
young men with him and Isaac his son,
and he cleaved the wood for the burnt
offering and rose up and went under the
place of which God had told
him. He does not argue.
He does not question.
He does not hesitate.
He does what he's told
and he does it in silence.
It is hard to fathom really. How
could he not at least tell Sarah,
his wife that he's going where
he's going, why he's going.
He has to know that when she hears
Isaac has been killed by her husband,
if this is going to happen, if
it's really going to happen,
he has to know that it will be the single
most terrible fact of her life and of
their marriage. May Be Abraham is
hoping it won't happen. We don't know.
All we know cause he leaves early,
early in the it says maybe to
avoid being questioned by his wife.
Where are you going with the chop wood?
Why Isaac and Abraham and Isaac walk
side by side with the donkey and the two
servants heading to this place
that God had chosen in the text.
They don't speak, at least not out loud.
So much of what happens in
this story happens in silence.
In silence. They walk for one
day, two days, three days.
On the third day he says
to his servants, stay here.
And I in the lad will go
yonder indicating the mountain.
And he puts the wood on to
Isaac shoulders and his back.
He takes out a knife and some hot
embers. And now the two of them,
the father and the son, they walk on
alone. And that's when Isaac stops.
And for the very first time he asks his
question, his heart rending question.
Father, he says, and Abraham
and shoes, here I am my son.
And Isaac asks, behold
the fire in the wood,
but where is the lamb
for the burnt offering?
And Abraham says,
God will provide himself the
lamb for a burnt offering.
My son and Isaac doesn't answer.
At least there's no answer in
the text. And the two of them,
they keep walking together.
Two Isaacs in dilation saying nothing.
Why no protest, no argument,
no questions. Why this quiet?
There are few silences in the Bible,
so troubling, so hard to understand,
but there is another one.
It's also in the Bible and maybe the
two silences speak to each other.
This other silence occurs
earlier in the story of Noah,
Noah and the RQ member.
The God sees too much wickedness in the
world and decides to destroy what he has
created except for one good and righteous
man named Noah and his family and a
collection of animals. Two of every kind
that Noah will gather on board a boat,
a big boat, the Ark.
So Noah builds the arc and he brings
all the creatures on board to buy two.
Actually few of them came in sevens,
but mostly it's to buy, to add on.
They come. There's a beautiful children's
book about this by the Dutch artist,
Peter's spear. It's gorgeously
illustrated in simple,
delicate line drawings with small
splashes of color and in spears book.
Then in my imagination,
Noah is kind and hardworking and
comfortable with animals better than
comfortable. He can handle them
and comfort them and tend to them.
He's a lover of living things
and then the rain starts and
Noah in Zooey, confusion,
rushing from Tamarind to baboons to us
sprays, feeding and caring and managing.
He looks out the window
and he closes the hatch.
Now's the time to batten down,
keep the living cargo dry and in Peter
Spirits version as the rain puddles
around the ship, as the clouds mount
up and darkened and flash promising,
annihilating rain, very quietly,
animals begin to appear
out from the forest.
They come down from the hillsides and
out of the ground and down from the sky
and they gather first. It's a little
group and then a large one by the arc,
but the big closed silent arc.
I mean you're not there
in two by two by twos. No,
they come in haphazard combinations.
Three drafts, seven gorillas,
30 Armadillos, then a Robin,
a panda, a dozen lionesses.
These are the animals who are
not going to travel on the Ark,
who are not going to be protected.
We're not going to live.
And together they stare up at the clothes
dark at the boat that contains the
survivors, the lucky one,
and there is no sound
in my imagination. And in spirits
book, you see them all so quiet.
Just the jaguars staring and getting
letter in the camels and the elephants in
the mice who had one could
argue, never been wicked,
who outnumber the humans on the planet
by hundreds of thousands, by millions.
They stand there silently accepting or
maybe just enduring this in explicable
end
and in the silence I imagine a chimpanzee
baby nuzzling its mother in the light
rain asking how long will it rain Mama?
Just as Isaac asks his father, where
is the lamb for the burnt offering?
Okay.
And there is no answer. A parent
can give to that question.
There is silence
and the animals stand in the silence
and make no noise of protest.
They don't cry out. They just stand
there as the sea level rises in the drip,
drip, drippy, endless drip of
Lorraine is the fish, the Octopi,
the macro where they less guilty.
Why did they get to survive?
Maybe even thrive in an
expanded watery environment.
There there aren't any answers to these
questions and what of Noah tending to
his creatures, feeding them,
keeping them warm and dry,
caring for their babies and
nursing them and their sickness.
What would he have thought just
before he closed down the ramp,
when the slow tortoise or the last two
snails are a pair of lazy worms were
scuttled inside with Noah, the good man,
the righteous man looked out on all those
creatures all over the world settles
to death by drowning and starvation.
What did this righteous man say?
The Bible doesn't tell us it's safe to
conclude that he turned away and he said
nothing.
Had he closed the ramp and he walked
onto the ship and remained silent.
I imagine it was a pregnant silence,
but the Bible doesn't tell us.
Here's life. Life we're told is precious.
Life is dust touched by the breath of God
or life is chemicals that somehow know
to attach to each other chemicals that
link and bond and split and bind and
become a jellyfish. Pulsing
in the Sea of butterfly.
Flittering in a forest that can form
the shy gaze of a Fox pop ready to play.
That can become the glance of a boy
carrying wood. Who asks his father,
where is the lamb for a burnt
offering to take that boy,
that Fox, that butterfly
to extinguish that life,
that breath you would think would wound
the universe, would Payne the creator.
We know this pain.
I think of Abraham Lincoln down
at the war office in Washington,
D C checking telegrams from the front,
reading the names of casualties,
sometimes known to him of people
who'd been killed or wounded.
A newspaper correspondence
saw President Lincoln there,
watched him reading the list as he wrote
with bowed head and tears rolling down
his furrowed cheeks, his face pale and
land his heart heaving from emotion.
And when the president walked out of
the building, he was in such a daze.
He and I'm quoting, almost fell
as he stepped into the street.
A good man knows the weight
of hurt. When someone dies.
Abraham Lincoln sent other people's
children to kill and to die,
and when they died, he shared
their hurt. And this image,
the image of Lincoln in anguish
is our image of a good man.
That's what we admire, to have a heart
big enough to feel another's troubles,
to sigh with others, to cry with others,
to join their suffering or indifferent
circumstances when the occasion is right,
to laugh with them, to share their
joy and every so often to love them.
That's the best of all to step
out of our lonely cells. However,
briefly as the poet Paul Ceylon is
written at times when only the void stood
between us to get all
the way to each other,
that's the highest
expression of ourselves.
There's nothing more sublime between two
people, between parents and children,
between friends and for
those lucky few who feel it.
To experience it between man
and God and to feel the other,
to be touched, to be heard, to be loved.
And yet here in this chapter of the Bible,
in this moment between God and Abraham,
God who loved Abraham and
Abraham who loved God.
And if this is a love story,
this is the most twisted love
story you have ever heard.
A loving God wants to test
his favorite disciple,
the man who loves him the
most. And so he says that son,
the son I promised you that would be a
nation that would grow and multiply the
son. You and your wife
waited for all your life.
The Sun that was so improbable that
when angels came down and told Sarah,
a boy was on the way, she laughed.
That son, the one you nurtured,
promoted over the other boy, Ishmael,
the one who will be your future.
In spite of all the things I told you
what I promised, what you counted on,
what we agreed upon, I
want you to kill him.
Would you do that? And Abraham.
Father Abraham, who had
discovered this, God in his heart,
fought with his father, Terah
destroyed idols honoring other gods,
left home fought battles for God.
Abraham who had contested with God,
bargaining over the lives of
Sodom and Gomorrah. Abraham,
here's this command from the God
that he loves and he doesn't argue,
he doesn't hesitate, he doesn't refuse.
His love is so great.
The sages say so powerful
that he saddles up.
He takes his son and walks
to mount Moriah in silence.
He doesn't say yes. He
just goes without a word.
What are we supposed to make of
this story? What's it telling us?
What kind of God would put his creation,
his favorite to a test like this?
And what kind of man would pass the test?
Here's a guy who wants a human sacrifice
as proof of devotion and a father who
would kill his son for God.
Both parties got an Abraham
turned devotion into murder.
Why doesn't Abraham say, why?
Why does a Noah say why and the sage,
you say, we should admire their devotion.
To which I say, I don't know
what is there to admire here.
[inaudible]
it's interesting to see what happens to
these righteous men, Abraham and Noah,
after they do as they're commanded.
When Noah rides out the flood and releases
his cargo back into an empty world to
start over, what does he do?
Well, he plants a vineyard.
He presses those grapes into wine
and he drinks. He drinks hard.
His children find him half naked
in a silent stupor. And Abraham,
he comes down from Mount Moriah and
returns to his servants and he heads home,
but not with Isaac.
Isaac is somewhere else,
not with his father.
The silence between them has deepened
Abraham returns alone to Sarah.
And what of Sarah? Well,
presumably she heard what happened.
It would almost happened, but
as soon as Abraham returns,
in the very next sentence of the
very next chapter, Sarah dies.
She dies and Abraham is alone and he
stays silent and Noah stays silent and God
says to Abraham, because of what you
were willing to do. The Bible says,
I know that thou art a God fearing man,
seeing that thou has not withheld
thy son, they only son from me.
And God goes on to promise Abraham that
he will multiply thy seed as the stars
of the heaven and in thy seed shall all
the nations of the earth be blessed.
And to Noah, God creates a rainbow,
a sign that promises never to
destroy so much life again.
These stories describe remarkable men
who put their faith in God over their
deepest instincts, over
their horror of suffering.
And we're rewarded Noah with a
rainbow. Abraham with a blessed nation,
but at what price?
The thing that makes this story
so alive to me is the silence.
Abraham seeing nothing.
Noah saying nothing.
And I am a hunch about these men,
their silences look respectful or maybe
due to four fearful or maybe hopeful
that the suffering they were about to
allow it somehow be explained away or be
justified later on.
But I don't think of their silences as
acceptance or submission or an expression
of blind devotion. They were
says the Bible, good men.
And because they were good and
caring and above all human,
they could feel the suffering of others.
Like President Lincoln
did like good people do.
Abraham felt for the people
of Sudan and Gomorrah,
Noah for the animals that he
noticed and he cared for it.
And so I have to believe that beneath
their silence is barely contained,
was the furious roar
of two wounded, angry,
voluptuous human hearts filled
with questions and worry
an insult and wonder why
my son? Why Isaac? Why slaughter so
many innocent creatures in a day lose?
Why is this happening? Why
is this necessary? I can't
do this. I need a reason.
I need an answer. I need to know.
And I believe Abraham and
Noah had those feelings,
but they had something
else too. They had a hope,
a deep hope, that beyond reason,
that beyond understanding that somehow
there was good in these terrible deeds,
that God is merciful in
ways we can't understand,
that we are not meant to
know or built to know.
And their hope barely just barely
contained their harbor and their anger and
their insult.
But I have to think it was in both of
them a mighty struggle to smother what
their hearts felt,
to put their hope in a power that was
beyond their understanding because the
other part of being human and being a
good human beyond our capacity to love and
to care is that desire for
answers, for explanations,
a desire to know why,
and here I think is the key to this
story's power because all of us,
not just Noah and Adam,
all of us live with this paradox
to see things that seem wrong,
that seem cool and do
wonder, is there a logic,
a higher logic to explain what we
see and if we can't know that logic,
if we can just hope for it, hope
there's an explanation. Is that enough?
Can we live with the fact that we may
never know that all we have is hope?
Can we face the terrible silence of the
universe with just hope in God in good?
This is a powerful question. When
cosmologists study the universe,
they also tell a story,
a story about silence.
Their story says that everything we
are, all the particles, all the forces,
the duct tape of our
existence popped into being,
they say entirely by chance out
of agreed quiet out of nothing,
out of flux, a quantum flux.
Suddenly with a bang that made no
sound matter and energy appeared and
eventually formed.
Adams and the Adam stitch themselves
and the compounds and the compounds hung
around for a long time and spun themselves
into stars and then into planets and
seas and clouds and air and at sometimes
somewhere somehow maybe God breathe
life into those molecules or maybe the
molecules assembled themselves according
to some deeply rooted plan,
but cells beget cells and life began
on earth and maybe elsewhere and those
cells. Then we combined to form newer
and newer forms of life and for a long,
long time for billions of years,
sea dwellers and then land dwellers
and evergreens and flowers.
None of these creatures,
none of them had evolved.
The ability to appreciate
what was happening,
to have a feeling for the beauty and
elegance and chemistry around them.
To ask the question, why
are we here? Until very,
very recently say the
Darwinians life produced mind,
a creature with a brain who
could ask, where do we come from?
How are we made? Why is the rose
red? And what a lovely, velvety,
beautiful red.
So the universe at long last got and
appreciator after 14 billion years of
self-assembly,
we now have physicists and one way to
think of a physicist is to say that a
physicist is the Adam's way if
admiring themselves. After all,
a physicist is made of Adams and can say
what a good job those Adams have done.
But a human brain not
only appreciates beauty,
a human brain has a moral sense,
a desire for justice for good.
A human brain can suffer and love and
care and feel the suffering of others.
We may come from silence, but mind,
mind breaks. The silence of the
universe. Mind introduces meaning,
or at least the search for meaning.
Maybe this is in the master
plan because with our minds,
we can ask if love and
mercy are good things,
why are they missing so much?
At the time? Abraham can ask,
Noah can ask, and I can ask,
how dare you kill those
animals, all that innocent life.
How dare you ask a father
to que his son, his own son?
How dare you kill that boy in
Darfur and Treblinka and Baghdad?
I hope there's a reason.
I sometimes think there's a
reason for the life of me.
I can't think of what the reason could be.
I know enough of life to know that God,
you don't always send angels down to stay
the hand of the killer as you did with
Abraham. Sometimes the killer kills.
Often the killer kills and get
against that awful indifferent.
Somehow we survive and we hope,
which brings me to the last and the
most interesting player in this story to
Abraham's son, to the boy who was bound,
was tied to a rock while
his father stood above him,
holding a dagger ready to use that dagger,
ready to kill Isaac saw his father's eyes,
saw his father's will,
and then Isaac survived.
What was Isaac thinking when he went
down alone from mountain Mariah when he
walked into what was left of his long,
long life. He must have asked himself,
why was I tested? Why was
I spared? What's the point?
Am I an accident? Am I alive because
my father passed a test? What?
I'd be dead if he didn't pass the
test. Do I matter? Am I precious?
I don't know. I don't know.
So what do I do? I go on. I grow older.
I marry Rebecca. I have children
of my own. I make mistakes. I have,
I saved for my love for Jacob
and for Esau and for sunsets.
I hope that I'm here for a reason.
One day. It'll make sense. Sometimes.
I believe it does make sense. Sometimes.
Now I've seen cruelty
and I've seen kindness.
I hope the kindness wins, but
I don't think about it much.
I just hope in silence.
[inaudible]
alright, well,
Radiolab is funded in part by the
corporation for public broadcasting,
the Sloan Foundation and the
National Science Foundation.
I'm Jad Abumrad and I remember,
we'll see you in two weeks.