Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm
Robert Krulwich. Radiolab.
Today is our animal minds
animal mind, right? Do, do, can,
can one animal really know what's going
on in another animal's head? Yeah.
Like really? No, really. No
thanks her kidneys.
So we were thinking about that whale
story that we heard before the break.
Yup. You know,
where the DIYers make the whale and they
were sure that we always saying thanks,
literally saying thanks. Thanks
for helping me out. Okay.
That is their opinion.
But we wanted to know like what can you
actually scientifically say about that
kind of exchange and that question.
Let us introduce yourself. Like,
so this guy, uh, my name is Patrick Hoff.
I am a neuroscientist at Mount Sinai
School of Medicine in New York,
although actually the truth is he's
really from someplace like Geneva.
He's from, he's a Swiss from the
French part of Switzerland. Right.
We came to him because he may have
found a way of separating the animals,
of knowing which animals can genuinely
have human emotions and which can't.
It's, it starts,
it starts in 1995 we were studying the
anatomy of the human cingulate cortex.
It's part of the brains right
here, Kenny, between your eyes,
but down and a student in my
lab, Estonian still named scheme.
She was looking at some brains
and she saw something, ah,
these very slender of bipolar on the run.
I've never seen a neuron like that.
Maybe it's abnormal to probably
pathological, just to be sure.
She got some slides of other human
brains looked in the same place.
[inaudible]
and we, there was again,
started to see them again and we
were very pleased. They, okay.
We have discovered a new cell type, whew.
Something that is unique to human,
but then they went to the library and
discovered that some guy whose name is a
Constanta Fun Economo
[inaudible] Romanian Guy [inaudible] it's
seen these cells 70 years ago and you
named them spindle cells
because of their shape. Oh,
that must've been a very sad
day for us to know. No, no,
it's now they believe that these little
brain cells may be a key to how humans
relate to one another.
And whether or not other creatures
can relate to us in the same way.
Right. Is it possible to, for us
to see a spin they'll sell at?
Yeah. I wait,
can we can show you a spinels of
Patrick half took us down the hall. Yep.
Chad went first and parked
him in front of a big
microscope. Yeah, fine sense. Again,
look at it. Will it be obvious to me?
I'm looking at crossing the middle of
the field. You can see a series of tall,
slender and making me dizzy. One, two,
three, four, five. Is that the spindles?
Yep. Oh, they're everywhere. Yeah. Aw,
you want to see them? [inaudible] I mean,
yeah, you hold them mind.
Oh yeah. There's like a,
there's a whole troop of them when
they're long and skinny and purple.
It's funny cause the normal brain cells,
which you can also see in
there are like dot, dot, dot.
But these ones are do like
little purple bananas,
like a team of Purple Banana and
the thing that makes these cells so
interesting, she mean to hit
off in this direction. Yeah.
According to Patrick
Hoffman is that, you know,
in the normal brain cells they
just talk to their neighbors.
But these ones because they're so
a long, they seem to be yelling
across a beat. A distance.
Exactly. We know that the cells
send an action at some distance.
Okay. Hello?
Uh,
it's across the valley. Yeah, it's across
the valley. Exactly. It's projecting
the projecting what and
from where to where. Well,
Patrick Hoff doesn't entirely know,
but he says he can make a pretty
good guess based on, well,
if you look at the microscope
noticing things. Yeah.
Yeah. So, so here, here,
the top of the spindle points toward the
surface of the brain or the job he says
seems to shoot up boards.
Those more modern parts of the brain
that involve high Yoda cognition. Yeah.
Language, abstract thinking.
Whereas the bottom of the spindle seems
to shoot down deep down lower centers in
the brain towards those older parts
of our brain that involve feelings,
emotions, instinct.
Wow. Perhaps this is
what Patrick off things,
the desales are a kind of
network, a really important one.
It allows the different parts
of our inner selves to connect.
Like you've got the parts of us down
here that feel things can now communicate
with the parts of us up
here that think things.
This is an oversimplification
of course, but the point,
the larger point is that this is exactly
what happens when you look into the
eyes of another human being
[inaudible]
because it begins with a kind
of thought, your eyes seem sad,
but then that thought within you travels
a great distance and connects with the
feeling of sadness that you feel sad too.
I mean it's the basis of a kind of a m.
Exactly, exactly. You know, I,
I see you happy, you know, so,
so that I feel good about it and
you know, and consider those times.
I mean not just empty where like your
thoughts and feelings are in conflict and
if you've got to really talk to
one another, like for example,
when you kicked in front of me at the
microphone yet again, and I hate you,
but I know that I have to work with
you. So I, I, I sit on that feeling,
I just sit on my, it's going down to
the bottom of my brain. But I say,
take taking that,
see that's the best part of your spindle
situation is that it's not just the
thoughts, connected feelings with its
thoughts can sometimes suppress feelings.
Yeah.
I think that's the idea is that humans
in social interactions can rely on these
hardwired emotions in the same way
other animals might be able to.
That's [inaudible] science writer,
a regular radio lab contributor and a guy
we often call to help us make sense of
things. Um, you know,
we can like a dog just hump every
other dog and see what happens.
We've been Scott to flirt
and be funny and you know,
buy a couple of drinks and that, that,
that was, you guys have to cut back.
Cause I just, I am so astonished. Wow.
We gotta use that. Um, I just, I
just turned into a frat boy. So,
but the point being that
our social interactions are
very complicated and that,
and we can't rely,
it's much tougher for humans to rely
on simply these hardwired primitive
instincts you get into the job of
spindle cells is to simply broadcast
content to the rest of the brain because
without our whole brain involved,
we never be able to navigate the social
world and make any kind of connection.
Right.
So if spindle cells then allow us to talk
gently and emotionally to one another.
The question is, this is
the question for our hour.
What about introduced species is an
intra or Inter Intra in Charlotte?
[inaudible] yeah, that's inside I
think across species is what you mean.
Does any other animal have spindle cells?
We're taking the end as it happens. So we,
I'm taking you to my cold room
just down the hall from his office.
It's professor Hoff has a
freezer a way. High Stone.
The specimens are very big
door to full of brains,
so it's going to get
through the cooler here.
[inaudible]
all different kinds with brains of volume
species. The CETACEANS are over there.
We have the great apes around whale
wall. That's the way the wall, yeah,
he's got dozens and dozens of rains and
buckets in new jars and it keeps them
all organized. Well, each category
of species has its own shelf.
You have more apes down there
with the gorillas and orangutans.
Ah, it was really cold there.
So what they did was they took a bunch
of those brains off the shelf and walked
him down the hall to the lab and put
little pieces of them under a microscope.
They didn't expect to find
any of those bizarro neurons,
any of these other creatures.
Cause he was pretty sure this is
something that is unique to human.
But one day we will looking at
the brain of the Humpback Whale
and we stumble on spindle cells,
plenty of spindle cells. Well,
so what was that? Did you, were you
surprised? And I was there say, okay,
this is fascinating. You weren't
expecting that. I wasn't that.
I told expecting that.
But on the other hand,
here we have the humpback whale,
which is a very social
animals. They, they,
they fall clans, they, they
communicates the males, they have a song,
they hunt together, they
develop punting strategies,
which requires perfect
coordination of many whales.
So they have to act together to do that.
Now if acting together is the key you
and having complex social structures,
well then these things shouldn't just
be limited to whales. And in fact,
over the years half and other
scientists have found spindle sales in
chimpanzees, elephants, dolphins,
gorillas. Which begs the question
[inaudible]
like if we want to have an experience
with another creature and now not just at
the zoo, but a real shared experience,
do those creatures need
to have these things?
Do you think the existence of spenders
so creates more of a possibility of
having that cross species
sharing moment? I think so.
[inaudible]
if we assume that these cells
have zilch on influence on, uh,
the sociability of the species,
it is very likely that you would
experience something of that kind with a
species that has,
then I doubt you would get a very good
experience if you were trying to do this
with the Hyena.
So maybe what we see when
we look into, you know,
the sad eyes of a blue whale or when
we look into the eyes of an elephant
cradling a baby elephant, which are
just the cutest things on earth.
Maybe what we recognize is is
is that same flavor promotion,
that same inner life, a
feeling maybe and it's the big,
maybe maybe that in our
life requires spindle cells,
but how big is that? Maybe it means
a sounds like a really maybe, maybe.
I mean, yeah, it's important
that this is all just a,
I think this is still very theoretical
and in fact if you asked people like
Clive Lynn, the fellow who who,
who poopooed our our whale,
thank you from before as Clive,
like could you look at an animal and find
something in the animal that says yes,
if he has that he's got feeling
well wrong.
I don't for a moment imagine that there's
going to be a type of nerve cell or a
type of structure in the brain,
which is going to be such an acid test
of whether an animal has a particular
psychological capacity that we could
then find that kind of neuron and say,
well now we know without having to
look at the behavior of the animal.
Now we know that this species has
this or that psychological ability.
Well, let me ask the question
a different way. I mean,
do you think spindle cells
are no spindle cells?
Let's just toss them out for a second.
Do you think there are a category of
creatures that are more likely to have
empathic experiences with us? Would
you draw lines between beings?
Well, the thing that I would,
the thing I would emphasize if we are
looking for empathy between different
species is their um,
developmental experiences
to make his point.
Clive told us about this
experiment. This is,
let's take a chimp with all the spindle
cells inside the chimp brain there,
but the champion who room
and in front of the champ,
let's put two cups face down.
Now, one of the cups has a grape,
something delicious under it,
and the chimp doesn't
know where the grape is.
Could be under cup a or Cup B.
So what you the experiment do you simply
point to the cup that has the grape?
Like that's the one. That one right there.
I know the animal has to
do is to go to the cup.
That's pointed to it seems simple
enough. But chimps, Clive says,
chimps find this stunningly difficult
to understand. Get this wrong.
What do you mean? I mean, they just
look at you pointing and they look into,
you're pointing and they look and
you're pointing and they just go, wow.
Whereas dogs who don't have spindle cells,
most pet dogs get this from the get go.
The dogs can do this
and chimps can't. Yeah,
they quite spontaneously recognized
that you should go where they,
where they point. And Clive says,
the explanation here is not the dogs
have some special cell in their brain.
It's simply because,
because they grow up in our households
if they grow up with us. Right.
To test this idea. He did the
same study, the pointing one. Yep.
Except this time with some wolves because
wolves are the animals from which dogs
are descended but they haven't lived in
human households obviously and normally
like the chimps,
wolves totally screw up the porting
tests that we've done some tests on some
wolves that were hand reared by human
beings and are very friendly to human
beings and we find that those
wolves behave just like the dogs,
that they are just as good at following
the human pointing to find the food.
Really. Did you have to train them or no?
We did not train them while
they just picked it up,
but these are exceptional bulbs in so
far as they were reared by human beings.
They were bottle fed when they were wee
babies because there are things that go
on earlier in our development that are
crucial and that include learning who are
your, who are your kind,
what do, who am I, what am I?
And you learn that in a critical period
in your early life by looking around you
and seeing who you're interacting with.
Pretty much every dog you might meet
has learned to accept humans as social
companions. And that's because
it was reared in a human home.
And because evolution has prepared it
with a relatively slow development so that
it's pretty easy to tame a dog.
The Wolf on the other hand,
it goes through its childhood and
adolescence in the blink of an eye and the
course of just a handful of weeks.
And so it's actually extremely difficult
to successfully hand rear a wolf
because you have so little time available
to you and you have to invest 24 hours
a day,
seven days a week during that brief
period that a wolf is open to the
possibility of learning who its companions
might be. That's really interesting.
You know, one of the pieces of the
interpretation that I find intriguing,
and I'm gonna, I'm gonna run by you,
is that, oh, that's so interesting.
I'm now sitting here thinking, boy, if I
could raise a whale with a baby bottle,
then I would know whether the will was
saying thank you to me because I would
have learned, it's not like I have to
learn, but whale would have learned human.
Wow, that's right. I mean, of course,
this is completely hypothetical.
The whales are really
bad example to choose,
but my guess would be if
you bottle fed or whale,
you would get a whale that might plausibly
do something like a behavior that
expresses things. That is such a
hard mental image to conjure. Well,
that's right. That's right. Bottle
feeding. Oh, well, yeah. Well,
because we have to keep rising to the
surface for 21 years to breathe before I
actually get to the experiment.
There are a number of
drawbacks to that experience.
Radiolab will continue in a moment.
As soon as I come up to breath.