Wait. Do you want to do, do we should
run that just at a classic intro? Sure.
Hey, I'm Jad and I'm Robert. This
is the radio lab podcast. Yes.
The podcast. And, uh, I gotta be honest.
I have no idea what we're about to do.
This is a,
hello. What's this?
Are we in a boat? No, but
we're going to be, Eh,
this actually story actually
starts in a supermarket.
Why did you give me the boat?
Was a tease. Yes. That's a tease.
That's what a classic. So
give me some supermarket,
then I'll give you some supermarket.
So
that's hat Walter. See, I asked pat a
few weeks ago to hi Pat, by the way.
Yes. Pat Walters, regular person here.
That is one of our producers. I said,
I want him to look for stories
about old lobsters. Why? Well,
I'm not going to tell you that
right now, but you'll see later on,
why come I give me a hint? No,
I'm not gonna give you a hint,
but he found a lady. You could
just, uh, introduce yourself.
Do you want me to say whatever you
wanna say? Okay. Hi, I'm Bonnie Hasan,
I'm a registered nurse and, um,
and Bonnie told us a pretty crazy story.
Did just tell you briefly, uh,
what happened was I had just
gone to work grocery store
just to just any old day. It wasn't okay.
Tenille Day, nothing
special about that day.
And where's this and where's this just
all right. Where I live,
little McMurray, Pennsylvania.
We about 15 miles south
of Pittsburgh. And uh,
the year Jed? Yes. Is 19,
1990 19 August of 1990.
So I was looking around, you know,
admiring the new seafood
department and I noticed this tank,
the lobster tank and a, there were
only two lobsters in the tank. One,
she says it was really
small, but the other one,
this huge behemoth
that
well, it's just so massive.
How big is big in this case? He like
from the tip of my finger to my elbow.
Oh, that's big.
Yeah. So she sees this big
lobster and she's like,
that tank is way too small. She thought
the lobster looked cramped. Yeah.
So she goes over to the guy behind
the seafood counter and she's like,
[inaudible],
what are you going to do with
this? Take a lobster. And uh,
he kind of just let me know that it
was a promotional for the new seafood.
Oh, I think it was just this big lobster
that would get sent around to different
supermarkets when they
wanted to attract attention.
Oh,
I just made a few more inquiries and
worked my way up to the store manager and
he referred me to the vice president
of the chain and straight away.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Because if they
didn't, they couldn't answer my question.
I probably was a little
bit of a pain. Right.
Like what are you going to do with them?
[inaudible] this is the moment where
the manager at the store decides, okay,
we have a complaining lady. I
think I can solve the problem.
He makes her an offer.
The bottom line was that I could have him,
if I could arrange for him to return,
she could have him, if she could
somehow get him back to Maine for Nate.
I don't know why. I guess
all lobsters are from Maine.
He thought so that's the author
like, okay, how do I do that?
That's a good question. Is this
Eh, in usual experience? I mean,
at least this is one case, this, this
actually has a long history of, uh,
people rescuing large lobsters. That's
true of course. And he's the author of,
what is it, the secret life of lobsters.
Yeah, the secret life of lobsters.
Some people may remember the
story of Mary Tyler Moore. No.
In 1994,
Mary Tyler Moore developed a crush on
a large lobster 12 pounder who is named
Mr. Grant. He was named spikes in Malibu,
California in a restaurant
called Gladstone's.
She put up $1,000 for the right to
rescue him. Wow. Hundred dollars.
And then rush limbo heard about this
and he called the restaurant and offered
$2,000 for the right to eat spike. Well,
so what did the restaurant
do? They refused, refused.
Uh, and there's been
other cases since then.
Trevor told us that he's actually read
about dozens of these lobster rescue
stories, but our lobster story is the
original lobster story. And he very first,
I don't want to make the claim forever
for sure, but I'm just saying to stay.
If you googled it, this is your opening
lobster. All right, so it's still 1990.
Yeah. Bonnie having now left the
supermarket. She's at home thinking now.
I really, I didn't know what to do
and she doesn't have the laughter
yet. She has no lobster yet.
That was when I started calling some
of the local animal organizations,
animal rescue league,
the ASP ca this locally trying to see if
there was anybody else there they could
help. They really wasn't there.
They're more into mammals.
I probably never even
heard of such a thing.
He basically told me forget it.
So what are we talking weeks of
research here are seven hours. Really?
Oh I was on the phone for hours,
but I had the time and it was kind of fun
project for her. Yeah, it's a project.
Yeah.
Cause then I called the Cousteau society
because I wasn't never the Cousteau
society. And um, they suggest
that I call our local newspaper
article appeared Saturday morning paper.
Oh really? Did I have it right here.
It was in crustacean station.
Cruzen like Cruz.
Yeah. Not Cruising, but
Cruzen. C. R U. I. S. I. N. K.
Presentation. Mick Murray, woman talks
supermarket into releasing large lobster.
I really didn't talk with him. I'm just
quoting now. Yes. It's a long story.
It began Friday morning when Mrs Hasan
enter the Dyanavel supermarket here and
this store is newly opened seafood
section. She encountered Nick Nick.
Oh, the lobster has a name. Yeah.
Yeah. It clearly,
the king of crustaceans was lounging in
a large circular saltwater tank along
with several lesser lobsters.
They must've done something in the
way nick moved, spoke to Mrs Hasan,
so she spoke to several
giant Eagle employees.
This is hasten who described
herself as environmentally active.
Told them she thought nick might
be happier back home and name.
Then on someone's where? I really
didn't say that. Don't worry.
Mrs Hasan was told it was a
professional lobster. 70 years old.
70 years old. Yeah. Well,
we don't actually know.
There's no way to technically
age a lobster. Perfectly.
Estimates are from 50 to a hundred
years for those big suckers. Wow.
I'm not an invite. I didn't say
that. I'm not an environmental crazy.
I eat lobster, but I think they're
over harvested. Nick must be set free.
I didn't say that either. I see
you pounded him, your sister? Yeah,
Nick,
they tell me I could have nick if I
promise to take him to the ocean is Hazen
has no money for such a
trip, like a destitute.
Anyway, I guess that's what
appeared then in this state.
[inaudible]
and that could have been the end of it.
Saturday morning we got an early phone
call and there was this woman on the
other end of the line.
I'm Tony Leone.
Angie was saying she was in town
for my dad's funeral and yeah,
she was returning that afternoon tonight.
No. Yeah, to Maine, Portland, Maine.
So I figured I'll just bring
him back with me and about,
well why would you leave and
think to do something like that?
Cause he was a massive lobster in a
teeny weeny tank that literally he could
barely move in.
Now there's one other thing I remember
she was back in Pittsburgh for her dad's
funeral. So is this in any way
an Omaj to your dad? Oh my God.
He loved lobster. He absolutely
loved to eat lobster. To eat lobster.
Yeah. He would eat them like
crazy, but he also loved it.
His oldest daughter would do things that
none of his other kids would ever do.
Yup. He would know that I
would do something like that.
He would expect me to do something
like that. So anyway, Tony and Bonnie,
they're on the phone at first. Finding
is actually a little suspicious.
Hello? Are you sure you're not just saying
that to eat them? Because I mean no.
And I said no, I wouldn't eat anything
that's big. He's, you know, he's too old.
I wish she reassured me
and she sounded very nice.
So we agreed to meet at Jiminy. Yeah. Yes,
that's correct. Now I'm getting my
daughter, my youngest daughter, oh,
they to hurry up and dressed.
They got to go to giant Eagle and
the woman met us at the store.
She had a two o'clock flight or that she
was there with the manager and I didn't
know they was going to be a photographer
there from the local PBS station in
Pittsburgh Anyway. How many bought the
biggest styrofoam cooler she could find,
which really is still was
a little too small for him.
We got him in there, taped
it up as best we could
put them in a van and way they would.
When we got to the airport, we
get up to the reservation desk,
handed him to the stewardess and she
put him in a chair in first class.
What kind of like, wait a second.
We ran coach this last year.
Is that from that first? No. The
plane then touches down in Portland,
Maine where the wildlife
police are waiting again.
Is anyone able to determine what everyone
here seems to have assumed that this
lobster comes from Maine? No fact
that it probably wasn't caught here.
Why'd you say that in Maine? You
can't catch big lobsters like that.
That's illegal because the big lobsters
are the ones that make more babies. Oh.
They have size limits that
they have on their lobsters.
So you are bringing a lobster then to a
venue that you reasonably suspect is a
foreign place. A foreign country. Wow.
But he could make friends.
So the next morning the
harbor patrol called and said,
do you want to go with us? We're
going to put him in the water.
So we jumped on their boat
at a newspaper reporter.
Went out in the boat with
them that morning too.
Okay, tell me, this is from
Maine. Read it to us. Yes.
After 1:00 PM as the marine patrol
boat locked in 30 feet of water,
Tony Leon carefully dropped
him dick over this side.
She washed in the sink and the
choppy frog. Shrouded waters,
then grin. I'm glad he made it
at night. It is nice.
But here's the real deep question here.
When we look at our fellow creatures,
we decide, well who can we?
Who Do we want to protect?
We include some groups
and we exclude others.
It seems almost entirely
arbitrary. For example,
why would someone save this lobster? Yeah,
I mean a lot of stories not cuddly
by any stretch of the imagination.
Certainly not soft. I mean, was
it, was it its beauty? Well,
I actually think that, uh, that
lobsters are very attractive.
Really. You mean, do you always think
that? I have always thought, you know,
they're a lobster is like, it's, it's um,
how can I say this
appropriately for radio? Uh,
they're muscular and curvaceous at the
same time. You're like Popeye arms,
those claws, and then there's
that nice curving tail.
And I just think that lack of a hunky
mass lobster calendar, lobsters,
I'm not thousand eight. I'm not
talking about that on the radio.
That's just weird of you.
That can't be the reason why people
keep saving lobster. No, no, I know.
So what is it? I think that, uh,
it has partly to do with our
obsession with longevity when it's,
when it's one that, that big and that
old, suddenly the rules are changed.
Here is, here is a creature, you know,
that has made it through all the tests
of life and it deserves our respect.
Now.
He was, he was unique. He was
special. And I just felt that, um,
didn't deserve to be in
that tank as his age.
Everything kind of converged at
that moment. I am asking my way.
I can explain it. It
just kind of went with it.
[inaudible]
the story about lobsters. Thank you, pat.
I thought of dropping patty into
the cushion along with nick,
but when I had him upside down,
I realized he was kind of attractive in
his own right and as if you could pick
me up.