Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm
Robert Krulwich. This is radio lab.
Our topic today, songs that get
stuck in your head and won't unstick.
Now in the last section we would got,
we've talked about people who were invaded
by music and couldn't get the music
out of their heads. Yeah.
Now let's switch and talk about people
who desire more than anything to get a
tune a melody into their heads. Oh No,
it was just specifically people who
are professional songwriters like Pam.
Hello, my name is Bob Darrow and
I'm visiting here with radio lab.
Is that it? What is it? It's radio.
Everybody is completely aware
of our program, but then again,
not everybody would be necessarily
aware of Bob Durrow was that good?
But you may know this
conjunction junction.
What's your function, Liz?
I'm just a bill. Yes.
I'm only up and I'm sitting
here on campus though.
This si low, my hero.
How wonderful you are.
If you grew up in the 1970s and 1980s
which I by the way, did not new.
So everything that we've just heard
I never heard before. Oh my God,
am I heard this? So you
know schoolhouse rock. Yeah.
And you have Bob Durrow to thank for all
the songs that will not eat your head
xe. We invited Bob over to
my apartment to sit my piano.
Talk a little bit about
Hook Enos. That's right.
What makes a song so sticky, so sticky
for your head? How does that happen?
No one ever gets that. You get your,
he told us a story of getting a call.
This was back in 1972 from a felon
named David [inaudible] call.
He was in advertising executive,
the president of a small
advertising agency,
and he simply said, my little boy
can't memorize the times tables,
but he sings along with Jimmy Hendrickson,
the rolling stones and gets their words,
why can't we put the
multiplication tables to music?
We'll call it multiplication in
rock. Why do you think looking at me?
And I said, yeah. Did you
say ea with confidence?
Well, then I did some research.
I looked in the math books that I had
in my library and then I just came to me
as the title three is a magic number.
[inaudible] hey, that's
good. [inaudible] match.
Want to hear Martin
somewhere in the ancient mystic trinity
and then I went to look in the Bible and
I looked everywhere, right?
It is one of the magic numbers and
then I thought of Buckminster Fuller.
Why button fits because of that
GDC film thing? Well, the triangle,
the train strongest shake there
can be because it can't bend.
A square can sag, right, and become
a parallelogram or something.
But a triangle is fixed match.
Very triangular parity, right?
Every tracking has three corners. Every
tracking has three sides, no more,
no less.
You don't have to guess when
it's three sees the magic number.
That's a badge. [inaudible]
I guess a magic as you can hear from
these remakes three really isn't magic.
Okay.
In any case, at the end
of this conversation,
I asked Bob Duro to think back way
back before you did schoolhouse rock,
before you became a jazz musician,
back to when you were a kid.
Do you remember the first time you got
a really good musical idea when a melody
that kind of popped into your
head? He said, of course I do.
Let me play it for you. No,
the doorstep side by side.
Since I'm the doorstep when my bread
tonight sitting on the doorstep tonight,
we'll do the forced.
Definitely known that
doorstep and that's all there.
That's all they are like that was
your first song. Not a bad melody.
[inaudible] terrible words.
I made it up plowing.
I was helping uncle John on the
phone. I was riding a heroin.
I don't care what you were around
here period. So right off the bat,
bomb bump on [inaudible].
That's a pretty good hook here.
What I care about is weird.
Did that come from,
from hearing pop music?
You pick up the phone even though one
school I would say I knew something about
songs sub consciously form because it's a,
it's the architecture of
all those other ones. Yeah.
Do these things like when you hit
the right one, do they like shout?
I'm the one they do. They do.
They do. I'm not gonna Forget it.
Now I can go to town and shop
for groceries, go to a movie,
and the next day it'll still be there
because it identifies its shelf almost
kind of like it feels like it
has. Suddenly it has weight.
I it has weight and
identity in there. It Ish,
it's there.
Sometimes I get the melody and then it's
just sheer labored and make the word
spirit. Where does the melody
come from? Melody comes the Muse.
You ever met this muse?
A lot of people are visited by the
Muse and they don't recognize her.
When you were plowing that day,
way back in a head amuse. Yeah,
but did you know that you had one or
do you just think it was just something
that like,
like like new shoes and I thought it was
something that just came out of the air
to me. I wonder if I stole it.
That would, that would
worry, I guess. Yeah. Yeah.
Oh that's one of the
songwriters mean objectives.
When you think of a melody say,
am I stealing that? See that.
That's how mysterious this is.
You don't know whether the idea was
yours as originally yours or whether you
heard it in some earlier part of your
life and it belongs to someone else you
don't know.
So the muse is a tricky kind of goddess
and you know where it really gets extra
tricky.
Imagine if you write a tune and it has
weight for you and people begin to enjoy
it where you live.
And then very mysteriously it
begins to circle the world.
And people who don't share your
language, don't share yours.
Tradition your culture. Share your tune.
That is really mysterious.
Okay, with that in mind, uh,
I got one for Ya.
Here is a delightful English artist,
England's popular young recording star
at Chula Clark. So let's have a very fine
welcome. This is a tune that was written
by a British guy who came in New York,
sang by a Parisian who everyone thought
was American and what they made.
Everybody knows. One of my
favorite records to the clock
down down though,
listen to the music downtown. And
this particular record has
special memories for me.
Bitter sweet memories if you
like, because, uh, I mean,
I'll pull the record out of the
case here. Um, there'd be, oh,
this is the original single that I would
have bought at the time. High records,
no scratches. Always looked after.
I chewed a glock downtown
written by Tony Hatch.
I didn't write downtown
specifically for Petula Clark.
Yeah.
Well I'd been to New York in October,
1964 I stayed on central park,
turned left from the Essex Challenge
and a walk down Broadway. And by
the time I got down to Times Square,
I feel was strange that there
wasn't a song called downtown.
When you're alone and
life is making you lonely,
you can always go downtown.
Just listen to the music
of the traffic in the city.
Linger on the sidewalk, new on the
signs of prison. How can you be
lovies dally
[inaudible]
it had different leanings
in different places.
But for me on that first trip there,
it was the center of life. It was, um,
a great place to be. And even though
I was on my own, I didn't feel lonely.
That's the first line of the song.
When you're real low, none.
Life is making you lonely.
You can go downtown.
I brought the idea back to the UK and
in those days in between recording
sessions and mixing down
the recording session,
I used to have about an hour in the
recording studio and I would go and sit in
the studio and just a doodle
around. It was a good time.
After a three hour recording session,
the mind was very active and the
music was flowing very freely.
I actually then wrote the tune to
downtown and that was it. I left it.
Well, I remember when Tony Hatch
came to the apartment in Paris.
That's where I was living at the time.
You know, I had moved over to France,
I'd married a Frenchman,
already had two small
children and a life was great.
This was I guess in 63 or four
and I said, well, I tell you what,
I'll go make a cup of tea and you
play something to me on the piano.
[inaudible].
I played her the bones of downtown, the,
the outline of it and the few words that
I had and put the word downtown into
wherever it was going to go.
And I was in the kitchen making tea when
I first heard the music for downtown
and I absolutely adored it. And
I came back with a t and I said,
that's the one I wonder record.
That could be a fantastic
song and a great record.
We were in the studio maybe a couple of
weeks later and and recorded a monster.
Right? Right. Now, here's the
interesting thing. As the song grew,
something happened. The
meaning began to change a bit.
I mean, here's a song that was
initially a celebration of the city.
You go downtown, you see the
bright lights, you with people,
you'll never be alone.
Well, after a while,
Petula Clark and some of the people who
sang it expanded the song to include the
exact opposite, meaning
instead of comforting,
the city is now a haunted place and
you are now more alone than ever.
Same Song, completely new flavor.
It's got a lot of character and a lot
of different angles you could take on it
too. One that sprung to mind for
us was the kind of blade runner,
like a much darker picture of
what it's like to go downtown.
[inaudible].
I always thought with the original that
it presented a very happy bright lights
thing,
but you always had this
sense of shallowness that
if you were on your own and
you went downtown, it probably stay
on your own and get quite depressed.
Actually watching lots of
people having fun around you,
right? You got resolved.
The noise that early saves your health
by just being out on the street,
being with other people
and seeing the lights.
There's a kind of slight
desperation in that.
How can you, the lights
are much brighter there. You can forget
all your troubles. Forget all your care.
I liked that line. The lights
are much brighter there.
You can forget all your troubles again,
all your care while you can't actually,
but you can go out and try [inaudible].
It takes your mind off stuff.
Don't hang around and let your problems
surrounding there own movie shows want
to go downtown.
Maybe you know some little places to
go to where they never close downtown.
[inaudible]
thank you to Alan hole and the BBC and
falling tree productions for that piece
you note.
I think if our question right now is
like when a song falls from Song Heaven,
why does it find an audience?
Sometimes a global audience?
I think it's not really the music in
this case. I mean it's catchy. Sure.
But the experience of going downtown
in New York and you're excited,
you want to see the bright lights,
you want to be with people and
you get there and it still sucks.
You still lonely. I think people in
Shanghai understand that feeling.
People in Bombay, everybody
knows that feeling. Yeah.
It's like migration music
in a way. Yeah. You know,
moving from one place
to a new place. Yeah,
and there is interestingly precedent
for this 50 years before they wrote
downtown,
this was already happening on a much
bigger scale than I had ever imagined.
Right here.
I learned about this from,
from this Guy Aaron, a Fox.
He is a professor of musicology
at Columbia University
in New York and the Damn
Country Western league
guitar player country,
not that rock and roll one too deep.
Dan and Aaron n and and
turning [inaudible].
I hear that train to come in nitro over
and round the bend country music is a
genre we normally associate with
Kentucky and Nashville, West Virginia,
particularly part of America. Boys
pick up. Yeah, but it has spread.
He says to the most unusual places,
so some examples of that and there are
quite a few that include the extreme
popularity of American country and
Western music over the last 50 or 60 years
with aboriginal Australians.
You mean Hank Williams
would be recognizable to
somebody somewhere in Western
Australia? Absolutely. Really? Dolly
Parton being another one elite part.
Dolly Parton is this international
global star of the world's music,
especially in southern Africa.
She's a revered like a saint
[inaudible].
It's true. Zimbabwe as love. Dolly Parton,
you can fill the venue with a band playing
Dolly Parton song and everybody will
know.
That was fun. Yes, doing good.
He was into that rocket job
and most universally
evolved. Don Williams,
I left Oklahoma
[inaudible] if don Williams were to go
to Dar es Salaam or to Zanzibar or to
Kenya or someplace and book a club, Don
Williams has actually gone to Zimbabwe,
uh, where he has filled a soccer stadium
with 40,000 people twice in a row. Wow.
[inaudible]
imagine 40 thousands and Bob Williams
crammed into a peak state and down here in
the center and the lights
is done, we'll use Texas.
I just wondering
what exactly are they hearing?
I have asked Grenadian Saint Lucian
and this Trinidadians or Macon,
Norwegian [inaudible] Chinese and
American Aboriginal Australian, Thai. Um,
why do you like country music?
And the first answer is virtually
always something along the lines of,
it's the stories. Like as in
the stories in the lyrics,
I was drunk the day my mom got out of
prison and I went to pick her up and the
rain,
but before I could get to the
station in my pickup truck,
she got run over by a
damned old train. Um,
that doesn't sound very aboriginal to me.
You know how many aborigines are
actually run over by trains. Thousands.
Actually that's not what
Professor Fox is saying.
He says ignore the details and
listen for the larger story,
which has to do with moving,
with migration and with regret.
Your lonesome for something and the thing
you're missing is the old home town,
the green, green grass of home,
the green, green grass overhaul,
Aaron Foxes. You can boil much of
this music down to just this feeling.
You look and look around you
long for something simpler,
something that used left behind and I
realized that I was only dreaming what
would be the best couple of examples
you can think of of I miss the firearm.
I miss the crickets.
Oh, where do you dark?
The first hit country song was
in a static reverie for quote
old log cabin in the lane performed by
Jimmy Rogers and Finland, John Carson.
The song was recorded in 1927 and
that happens to be the moment.
If you look at the u s census cause
he'll tell you when the United States
crosses the threshold from more than
50% agrarian and rural dwellers to more
than 50% urban dwellers. In other
words, country music really exploded.
And this is not an accident when most
people no longer lived in the country.
Country Music is born when the
country becomes an nostalgic idea.
And so in America anyway,
suddenly there was this dreamscape of
country places that no longer existed
except in heads and the
music started just been so.
If people in Los Angeles and in
Chicago heard country in their minds,
it seems just as logical that people
who move from the country to the city in
Asia,
in Africa and Australia might have exactly
the same experience that these songs
are sung in English.
If these people in these far
away places don't speak English,
what are they hearing? Well,
it's important to understand English and
the real enthusiasts around the world
are English speakers. However,
one explanation for its popularity
elsewhere is that even if you don't speak
English, the message is
literally in the music itself.
There is grammar here in the
vocalization, the singers,
this is a very normal
country western thing.
They actually make a croaky sound
that is very distinctive. You know,
it's a golden goose.
Ah, oh, long day,
one of the principle vocal articulations
is what country singers call it crime
[inaudible]
in my book by parcel,
the cry break into dozens of
different specific articulations.
[inaudible] no,
Eh,
and it's not just the voices by the way
says Fox. It's, it's the instruments.
Instruments seem to be crying. In fact,
the steel guitar is the signature sound
of country because it's recognized as
iconic of a crying human voice.
Hmm.
It's called the crying steel.
Uh, um,
you can hear the loons of there
and what seems to come rule is things
just aren't what they were before and all
over the world where people are leaving
from the country to the city and they
are an enormous number.
[inaudible]
this is a story. All kinds
of people can understand.
Country has just as much
Grenadian music as it is.
Kentucky music is just as much a why
and music at it as it is West Virginia
music. Is that one,
when you feel a football stadium
with Dolly Parton listeners,
are we saying that they're there in
part because the song she's seen,
are there stories too? Yup.
Yup. This is our music.
I've written a lot of songs about
the smokey mountains where I grew up.
We had a good life back there and heals,
and we're all going through
some version of, you know, oh,
on one to two or 300 year change from
being essentially peasants to being
[inaudible].