Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm
Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
Today we're going to start off with
a building, not just any building,
but a building that is
heavy with secrets and it's a building
we first really learned about,
or at least got a picture of
from this woman Katie Engelhart.
I'm a reporter at Vice News
in London, in Katy. Like now,
all of us at radio lab
is obsessed devastatingly
obsessed with this place called
Hansel o park.
So Hansel park is this huge sprawling
complex in Buckinghamshire near a town
called Milton keens, which
isn't too far from London.
And our producer Jamie
Yorke, check, check,
check happened to be in London on
vacation. So we asked them, well,
why don't you scrap your tape recorder
and go down there? Yeah, let's do this.
Check it out. So it's a
bit of a drive from London,
about an hour and a half on the
m one m two you approached this,
this sort of beautiful town with adorable
little posh cottages and little pubs.
Not from around here. I'm
looking for, yeah, I mean it's,
it's your sort of typical
e all day British village.
About a four minute drive past that new
old town. You go through some fields,
crest over a hill and there it is.
This massive, massive buildings surrounded
by razor wire. What's going on here?
So the archives are housed in a purpose
belt belting from the 90s and these are
archives, by the way, from
the largest empire ever known.
It's like if you were creating a movie
set for like a secret government compound
where they keep secret files, you
would literally just make this
Jamie parked a quarter mile away and
walked up to the gate. There's some pig,
looks like electrified
fence through the gate,
taller than me pass these traffic spikes
and just as he barely stepped inside,
are you going to call to call with? No,
I'm no comfortable with
any of this activity you're
doing. The guard grabs him,
takes him to a guard house. That
is, it's a microphone disconnected.
While you're in here though, please.
And then where is your vehicle?
Right. Okay. They walk him.
Are you going to escort me all the way
back to my car the entire quarter mile
back to his car.
Now we've heard it said that
the files in that building,
if they were ever released, could
rewrite 200 years of history.
No idea if that's true, we just don't
know. But we're starting to know,
and today we're going to focus on
the one story that has so far anyway,
tumbled out kind of by
accident. And it's a story
that we find kind of startling and we
should also warn that there's some stuff
coming up that is graphic and
disturbing. So if you're listening with
kids, you might want to skip this one.
Although if you're not listening with
kids, don't skip it. Don't skip it. Okay.
[inaudible]
a story is the Puna.
Kenya was always a scene.
This is a story in David Anderson
and a kind of Sepia tinted Hays.
Many of you guys are go Kim white band
of adventure pioneers who found the
country beautiful. The climate
kind on the soil per tile.
Bougainvillea sunshines
smiling, happy servants.
David says in the 1910s twenties thirties
the British public was obsessed with
Kenya. You had books,
eventually television programs.
It was one of the crown
jewels of the empire.
And so you had all of these Brits leaving
Britain and going to Kenya to start a
new life. And many,
many of the settlers who flopped out
to Kenya were lower middle classes who
could have a much better salary and a
much better living standard in Kenya than
they ever could back at home.
They stayed and found of
the young culinary where men
make the homes where that
children are born, taught
and grow strong and healthy.
Now it probably goes without saying that
this new life for the Britta citizen
came at the expense of the Kenyan who
was already living there to problems that
were always encountered in Africa and in
general with colonization is the issue
of land in the issue of labor. That's
Harvard historian, Carolina Elkins.
She'll play a big role in our story.
So in Kenya they solve the land problem
by simply alienating it and giving it to
the white farmers, but then
becomes the labor problem.
How do you force Africans to
labor cheaply on plantations,
right? Like in this case,
tea and coffee? Well,
the way you do it is you create
what are called native reserves.
We had them here for
four native Americans.
She basically says that the native
Kenyans were forced off of their land into
slums where they could
barely eke out a living.
And so the only option they had
was to work for the white people.
And that's how it went for, for
decades until the second war
or act as the question has
started, all cards gather
in 1939 suddenly thousands
and thousands of men,
young Kenyan men are forced in the war.
The people of Africa are doing excellent
work to help the allied cause many get
thrown into the British army,
you kings African rifles and among the
finest troops in the empire where they
came in contact with ideas of independence
and they anticipated when they returned
the day that they're,
that they
would have access to land, that their
conditions would be getting better.
But nope, they, uh,
they find their condition is not only
not gotten better, it's gotten worse.
And so after the war,
a few of these vets from the largest
ethnic group in Kenya called the Kikuyu,
they get together and they
decided to take an oath.
No owning is traditional amongst
the Kikuyu. So for example,
men a hundred years ago or more would
take an oath pledging allegiance to their
ethnic group as they went to war
with somebody else. In this case,
they'd take an oath pledging themselves
to kick all Europeans out of the colony.
Then the earth good, something like this.
I pledge to kick all Europeans out
of the colony, uh, out of Kenya.
And if I don't, may this oath kill me.
I pledge to take up arms against the
Europeans if I don't make this, Oh,
kill me. Now of course, the last
thing that was said always was,
if I reveal the contents of this
oath, may this oath kill me.
She says, the first thing they did
was attack the settlers livestock,
doing things like hamstring cattle,
hamstringing cattle cut their hamstrings,
your hamstrings, so they can't walk.
They started destroying property.
Their oath started to involve
things like goat eyeballs, Ram,
scrotums and tested blood.
Things that absolutely a,
the local European settlers
and put terror into them.
And why do they end up calling
themselves the Mal Mal? Well,
that's a good question. It's the
etymology of that as much debated, um,
with nobody quite agreeing on,
on how it, how it came to pass.
But Malmo is many thing.
Is this why he only derivative of sort
of more and more that there's, you know,
um, uh,
some say it has to do with you [inaudible]
I don't play this one over hearing
what was the Malmo Oath,
whatever the case in 1952,
[inaudible]
colonial government, which was
served the British arm in Kenya,
they declare a state of emergency and
those pudgy and legions to the Malmo,
they escalate. They start
going after the loyalists.
The Kenyans had been helping the settlers
savagely attacking the defense that
shooting them or they weren't at the
monitoring one assassination
after the next men and women were,
their bodies are whatever they
raid loyalists, villages with club
[inaudible] in the British or
they're terrified, oh, sorry.
In the streets of Naomi,
this is the night of the long nights
coming to into reality and it's only about
to get worse.
And that happens on the
night of January 24th, 1953,
which was the murder of the RUC family.
The rucks were these very young,
lovely couple. Roger
Rock was a farmer as me.
Ruck was a doctor who actually
administered to the local
population and they had
a little boy named Michael
who was six. Just that day,
the little boy had fallen off his pony
and his one of their trusted servants
carried him back up to the
house. Later that night,
a group of Mamao crept out of the forest,
lured Roger Nesbie ruck out of the house,
killed them, and then the whole gang,
including that same servant that had
helped the boy, they march into the house,
go up to the little boys room and they
hack them to death and there's a very
famous photo of the young
boys dead, absolutely buddied,
which is an every major newspaper
and almost overnight mal mal becomes
synonymous with pure evil in our mind,
in children's mind.
Mauer bigger than life,
darkest, dark people that you
ever saw. Men, men, men, men,
men. Yeah. And actually
as we were reporting this
story, one of our producers,
a lot of Nasser told us about how his
mom grew up next door to Kenya in what is
now called Tanzania Jack.
And to her and her friends,
the Malmo were like like a monster
to children. The boogeyman,
that was sort of a threat
all the time. Our barrier,
our mothers especially would refer to if
if you don't drink your milk or if you
don't sleep [inaudible] hey my mama. Okay.
Bolani so the Mama will come and
get ya. And how scared were you?
You know what? Just the
word Mau would make us run,
crawl under the bed.
I'm old enough to be one of the people
who thought that there were a calming
[inaudible].
They were like a isis or some weird
sort of self organizing terrorist group.
Yes. The most peace Geo horrible,
awful savage movement that I had ever
hit the face of the British empire. Okay,
so here's where we get to the part
of the story that is in deep flux.
After the murder of the rock family,
the settlers demanded that the colonial
government do something and they did.
They pursued the Malmo fighters,
supposedly small band of
fighters into the forest. Uh,
there were skirmishes that
lasted for years. Story goes,
the Malmo Movement never quite gained
traction and ultimately the British
quelled the rebellion. They handled it.
Now as for how they handled it for the
longest times, people would look back.
It was this giant blank spot.
No one quite knew what happened.
And here's why. According
to David Anderson,
by the time the British finally decided
to leave Kenya, and this is 1963,
by that
time, Kenya is around the 20th different
colony that Britain will leave.
So it's about halfway down the list.
So there's already in place a process.
Kathy, well Hello Stadium.
The articles of independence were handed
by the Duke to the country's prime
minister.
There's a formal exchange of powers.
They set off fireworks and then
at midnight they union. Jack
was low at about the last time,
the Brits Rollout, in other words,
date run us Ruth and
colorful and happy exit.
And at some point in that well-worn exit
process either right before the exit,
right afterwards there was, as David
calls it, the weeding of documents.
I mean the British
government conducted very,
very sophisticated purge operations
in all of its former colonies.
It's Katie Inglehart again, she says
everywhere you look, Uganda, Palestine,
Rhodesia, Zanzibar, Nigeria,
Jordan, Malaya, Hong Kong.
There are stories of papers being kind
of tightly packed into boxes and dropped
at sea. A lot of papers were burned.
There's a joke in among Indian historians
on the day the India achieved its
independence when the celebrations
were taking place in Delhi.
You could hardly see what was going on
on the podium cause the waft of smoke
blowing across from the
bonfires of burning documents.
All of which is to say
that it was, you know,
as soon for 30 years did that blank
spot of the Mal mal emergency would just
stay blank and the
story of the Evil Malmo,
which is continue because there
were no documents to say otherwise.
But then we get to Carolina
Elkins. How did you,
like once upon a time you were a
curious young Grad student or something?
Not more or less. In fact we,
you even have to go back further.
You know I'm dating
myself at age 45 but the,
I have to go back to my undergraduate
years talking 1990 and I was at Princeton
and when we were,
you know you do senior thesis there and
Princeton was ahead of its time and I
got lots of funding and I
went off to London and Kenya.
And how old are you when
you're taking this trip?
Oh I'm 20 so Caroline is working in
Nairobi and I'm doing research at the time
my senior thesis was
looking at the Kikuyu,
which is the largest
ethnic group in Kenya.
And I was looking primarily
at the shifting roles of
women and the ways in which
they were impacted by
colonialism. So Caroline,
it was wake up every morning and would
walk to this old colonial building right
in Nairobi city center called the
National Archives. It's loud, it's dusty.
It's, um, you know,
sometimes you had to jump under the
desk for several hours cause there was a
shootout across the street
and really? Yeah. Wow. Yeah,
that was quite a Saturday.
Um, long story short,
so one day she was at the archives
flipping through some files when I came
across some files on, uh, detention camp
[inaudible] detention camp
[inaudible] commit to you saying
come meet t k a m as in Mary,
I t I and this was a Nairobi just
outside. And I remember okay.
And I said, Gosh, you know,
I know nothing about this.
So she calls over the archivist guy
named Evanson and I said, ever see?
Got Anything else like this? He
said, yeah, let me take a walk.
And then Evanson starts bringing me some
other files also related to committee,
very bureaucratic files. These pages
were filled with the, the details,
numbers of prisoners. A
lot of them were women,
well over a thousand because they would
mention a hundred of this and a couple
hundred of that. And at that
point I thought, what's going on?
So short time later she gets back to
Princeton and being the good little
undergraduate history
major that I was, I just,
I searched high and low about
detention camps in Kenya. Nothing much,
no mention of this center any,
there's nobody who had done a
systematic study of it. Okay.
And that's what I was at.
So without anything else to go on,
Caroline just started driving up country
as they say, in the middle of nowhere.
Kenya, all these tiny little
villages in the central province.
I mean really if you wanted to find
middle of nowhere on the map I was in it,
I would just show up at somebody who's
a little Shambo or farm one day and
[inaudible].
Next thing you know, I'm
conducting an interview.
Can you ask her while working about
how many Hailey? No, these are tapes.
She recorded on a few of her trips.
She would speak to people through her
research assistant, Terry Wirey Mu.
I mean,
some of these interviews go on for hours
than one interview begets the next.
Every time you finish an
interview you say, you know,
do you have somebody else who I
could talk to? [inaudible] they say,
Oh yeah, I've got my friend lives
three bridges up in four hills over.
So she would talk to that person.
[inaudible] and then the
person they referred to
[inaudible] and then person
they refer to to move in.
Like this is what she
did for like five years.
I went and interviewed
several hundred villagers.
And what exactly are they telling you? Um,
stories you can't imagine
[inaudible]
what the stories were, what those
stories have begun to unravel is up next.
[inaudible]
maybe do
that. What you mean?
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] hello
[inaudible] good.
[inaudible]
Darlene calling from Kampala, Uganda.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
[inaudible]
hey everyone, it's me, Michelle Buteau.
I have a new podcast you can listen
to right now. It's called late night,
whenever from w NYC studios and it's
like a late night talk show before your
ears. We've got it all honey monologues,
a live audience and musical fad kick and
so many celebrity guests like Bridget
Everett, Leslie Odom, Jr Phoebe promise.
Then you see where I'm going with this.
It's look good, shower. You don't want
to miss it. That's late night whenever.
Subscribe where ever you get your
podcast. But don't subscribe whenever.
Subscribe now.
Hey, I'm Jeff. I'm Ron and
I'm Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
Before we get to the stories that
Caroline was referring to, um,
we should say that as we were
sort of reporting this story,
we really kind of fell in deep,
uh, to the point where Jamie York,
who had already gone to London to get
hassled by those guards at Hansel Park,
he then decided to spend
part of his vacation
in Kenya, basically following
in Carolina Elkins footsteps.
Yes. And that's when he stumbled
into something kind of surprising.
So it got picked up early one morning
in Nairobi and driven about three hours
into the countryside and okay,
after what felt like five right?
Turns 37 lefts.
We finally wind up in this
completely rural place.
It really does feel like
the middle of the nowhere.
It's like a little
village or something. Yup.
Little cluster of houses and rolling
hills in a county called knee area. Okay.
Got My stuff. Got Out of the car, followed
Terry who uh, had arranged the trip.
My name is [inaudible]. I am 41 years old.
This is the same Terry who translated
for Carolyn Elkins many years.
Anyhow, best a few kids
and Terry walks me into
this little clay hut.
There's a table in the center of the room,
there's a handful of plastic
chairs around it and eventually
people start showing up. I'm good.
Here I am with women. You are gay.
Nine women who are all in their
late eighties early nineties.
I'm like [inaudible] making reductions
and honestly I'm a little bit
disappointed because the Malmo,
I thought we're just men,
Jimmy fighters and seeing these
women. I thought, I don't know.
I realized most of the men
have died of old age. Oh,
so you thought you were going
to meet anybody. Exactly.
How you curious for myself,
but I thought, okay, I'll just,
I'll just ask how many of them
are women? Like show of hands,
how many of you would identify as
Malmo at today about to give will be
instantaneously put their hand
up. All nine people. Yeah.
And then started to sort of chuckle if
I did fun that we asking them because
it's obvious to us are
putting Mama. They were like,
of course we were supporting the
Mama. We were, the was like that.
That was everybody.
Oh, interesting. So it wasn't just
like a small band of militants.
It wasn't a small band in
militants amongst the cuckoo you,
it was almost everyone.
This is one of the first things that
caught Carolina Elkins attention made her
really questioned that official narrative.
Cause when she was doing interviews
15 years ago, she says everyone,
she spoke to every one to a person and
we're talking hundreds of interviews
started with, I took the
oath on such and such a date.
Very interesting.
Seem to her. What you had here
was not a small insurrection.
This was a mass movement and she would
discover that the British responds to,
it was also massive.
1953 shortly after the murder of the
ruck family, the white settlers marched,
demanded that the colonial
government do something,
and so what happened is that the colonial
soldiers, they came to the village,
they started going to villages across
Kenya. They rounded everybody up, no joke,
slaughtered their cattle,
slaughter their goats,
burned down their homesteads and
put them into these prison villages,
some 800 barbwire villages
throughout central province, Kenya,
[inaudible].
The village was like a concentration camp.
The thing,
the thing to grasp here is that this
is very carefully designed and very
practical.
David says there was a very
carefully planned system at work.
The barbwire villages were
primarily for women and children.
Men were usually sent to these detention
camps, which are basically prisons.
Now.
The logic of those camps was actually
thought up by a group of British academics
who met in 1953 it's sort of an emergency
meeting to discuss the quote Mal mal
problem and they decided at that meeting
that clearly the real reason the Malmo
are rebelling
was that they were captured by
some kind of mental illness.
Had nothing to do with the fact that
their land had been taken away from them.
No, it was set.
They were temporarily crazy
and the committee decided
it must have something to
do with those. Oh,
oh.
So was seen by the British as a primitive
way of capturing a cocoon mind and
making the person
unreasonable and insensible.
The only way they argued you can get rid
of the oath was to convert the person
back to sanity. Part of that involved
a confession of what they'd done.
Once confessions were made,
they would then be rewarded
by a better prison regime.
Then we moved into another compound
given privileges, give them better food.
You moved along the system,
they called it a pipeline.
You would along the pipeline
until you were released,
but you first had to confess to a,
to a confess to confers.
This is good to walk
Hungarian freedom fighter.
I joined as the Momo freedom
struggle when I was 17 years of age.
He quickly became an organizer,
recruiter and therefore a target.
They had to uh, such for
me and they caught me.
They put me into a detention camp.
They want us to say
loudly that was for sick,
the mouse struggle but
refused. We refused.
In fact, one man told us the story of
how in one of the barbwire villages,
every once in awhile [inaudible]
would come to the edge of the forest,
just outside the villages fence.
These were the fighters that
hadn't been captured yet.
They'd come right to the edge of the
camp where a lot of the children would be
playing. And because the
no [inaudible] does that,
anything about what was
happening in their country,
[inaudible] people in the village used
to use the children to take messages to
the people in the foot,
the fighters in the forest.
That's how they pass food and
information to the fighters.
And in a way kept things going.
The point is, according to David,
that inside the camps you had massive
resistance and so in many cases the
British colonial soldiers
would double down.
Morning the following
is pretty graphic. Um,
there's a BBC documentary called
white terror that has tons of these
frighteningly common stories
of abuse from detainees.
He told me how naked tied
by his feet to the bars.
He was brutally beaten on
the testicles with a stick.
One of them is a man giving
a tour of the prison cell.
He was kept in [inaudible].
Then they said his eyes with hot coals.
They kept him there for eight days.
There's another story of these three
men who were made to strip naked.
Well,
one of the men who was made to put his
head into a bucket of water with the
[inaudible].
Then the white officer held one of the
prisoners legs aloft and when you're
smiling, God held the other Eh
[inaudible] and another
God brought some sand.
So they started to push into the
detainees anus with the stake
[inaudible] [inaudible] they kept on
doing this or trinity putting in sand and
water. All the while pushing
the mixture in with the stack.
[inaudible] [inaudible] two
gives me nightmares to this day
because that was something that should
never be done to a human being. What
in that period of coercive violence,
it lasted throughout the 1950s
now the the moment we're bad guys, listen,
there's nothing to excuse
this kind of terrorism,
but the Kenyan campaign was a
sledgehammer used to crack and not
[inaudible].
There've been a lot of different estimates
to try to pin down the scale of the
British campaign. They range
from 160,000 people killed,
maim, torture, detained to
much, much higher numbers.
Caroline outcomes did her own
calculations and according to her,
by the time it was done,
nearly the entire Kikuyu population
of a million and a half people were
detained, tortured, murdered,
systematize force labor.
And you have to look at scale and if
you are the balance sheet of this is how
many Europeans died? 30 to 32 huh?
Like, why isn't this a tale that everybody
in the world knows in the event, say
of the enslavement of the
Hebrew people under the Pharaoh,
they were slaves in Egypt. The
Pharaoh wouldn't let them out.
Moses had to cross the river.
It becomes the national
story of the Hebrew people.
In this situation, you have Jomo
Kenyatta who I believe is a cocoon.
You becoming the first president. Why
wouldn't he make this the national story?
Well,
Kenyatta comes out of detention and
one of the first things he does is he
denounces Malmo as being hooligans.
The same organization that
accelerated independence in Kenya.
She says the same movement that scared
the British [inaudible] scared him. No,
he didn't want them suddenly
organizing and taking his power.
So for decades from 1948 until 2002 the
ban on Malmo that had been put in place
by the British corneal
government remained in place,
meaning it was illegal
to even talk about it
[inaudible].
But eventually in 2005 Caroline
publishes her book imperial reckoning,
which included the hundreds of interviews
and painted a picture of just a
systemic violence. The
book was well received,
but she says a lot of critics
told her nice story, but
no, this is an act of fiction,
an act of fiction. I made it up,
but you had all these interviews, right,
but one of the lines of critique was
that it's all based upon oral testimony.
Oral testimonies aren't
usable. There is no story here.
She says a lot of that was
just blatant racism. You know,
Africans make up stories,
but buried in there
is sort of a legitimate concern.
I mean memory is faulty.
We know that oral histories
are notoriously unreliable.
If you're going to
rewrite an entire history,
you need to get beyond personal
anecdote. You need documents.
Let illustrate and prove it
beyond doubt. And as we mentioned,
besides those few that you found,
the documents didn't seem to exist.
Nonetheless. Fast forward 2009 that book,
Caroline's imperial reckoning became
the basis of a very large lawsuit.
These Kenyan independent veterans have
in June of 2009 five mammo veterans
representing over 5,000
mile mouth flew to London.
The seat of an empire they say is
responsible for torturing them and filed a
lawsuit against the British government
the first time the British government had
ever been sued by a former
colonized population.
[inaudible] veterans want an apology
and some form of recompense for what
happened. Are you at all
nervous going into the court?
I think the word nervous is
not the word I would have used.
I tell my partners to write off the case.
I was not at all convinced that
we're going to go anywhere but down,
but that's smart day.
He represented the Malmo veterans in
court and the reason he was so sure that
the case was going to go down
in flames was, well, same issue.
You just didn't have the documents.
All he had were stories that
weren't exactly rock solid.
The eight was a nightmare. Old
Kenyans, their late seventies
and eighties first of all,
most Africans in my experience
find dates extremely difficult,
but people in their seventies
and eighties almost impossible,
and this was actually a huge problem
because in the British system,
if you're going to bring forward an old
case like one that's more than six years
old, the key question to the judge
is, can you still get a fair trial?
And the government can plausibly
argue, no, too much time has passed.
We were really worried that
the judge would say, well look,
there can't be a fair trial because
actually these witnesses are so old,
so up and down,
just in terms of their memories that
really their evidence is worth a great
deal. So to recap, I
wasn't really optimistic,
but then it's kind of a last ditch effort.
He contacted historian David Anderson,
two dozen expert witness because David
had written a book about African history
that was chocked full of legal documents
and they approached me to ask whether
there was material in the legal cases
I dealt with that might be useful.
And that's when he told them something
that would ultimately lead all of us back
to that scary building of secrets.
He told them for the past 20 years.
He has had this hunch, well so long
before the mammo trial came to court,
I and a number of other
historians believed that
documents had been brought back
from Kenya to Britain.
David says in that same Nairobi archive
were Caroline Elkins had found the
document about detention
and thought, gosh,
you know what's going
on in that same place.
Somebody else had found another document
that had also fallen through the
cracks.
This one was a simple packing slip
listing of documents for transportation.
I don't know if they're packing up and
removal as for where those documents were
moved to. Well, no one knew. No.
Maybe to an incinerator or bottom of the
ocean bumped from 1990790890 nine like
a starving man with a single
Pringle. David kept on.
I eventually bought documents from
the National Archives in Britain that
confirmed the stuff from Kenya actually
landed in an airport in Britain on the
eve of independence. I then was
able to find out who took them,
which van they went in, even got
the college registration number,
but that's when the trail went cold.
They filed document requests after
document requests and we get nowhere.
Then something totally unexpected
happens to historians working on southern
Africa actually got
access to Hounslow park.
They got inside.
One of them was a former
colonial administrator,
so he could work some connections
to get its way in any out.
Afterwards he sends David Anderson a
text message telling me the enhanced loop
park keeps seeing miles and miles of
shelving of documents from other colonies,
including Kenya. Was that a figure
of speech miles or was that a,
I think he meant it literally.
So He'd seen a vast a hangar as he
described it with row upon row upon row of
document. So when Martin Day,
the lawyer David Anderson
and asked him, can you help us
with it? Our case, David said,
here's what I can do.
I can't actually give you any
documents because I don't have any,
but I can outline for you the documents
that I think might be out there.
The documents. I believed the
British government were hiding away,
so he wrote a witness report for the
judge summarizing everything he knew,
giving all the details I had, I
didn't mention Huntsville Park.
I didn't say what I thought they were.
I just said I knew they'd
come into Britain and I want
you to know what happened
to them. The judge read that report
and then basically ask the government,
do you have them or not? Look, if
you can't answer this question,
you'll be held in contempt of
court. You'll be in another,
which I will interpret this as you're
withholding information and that basically
means you lose the case.
No,
that decision was the turning point
half a century on from
Britain's withdrawal from
Kenya documents detailing the
alleged brutality employed by the British
colonial authorities have finally been
released and suddenly having spent years
denying these documents existed within
four days, they found
Kenyans were waiting in my ruby
today for the news from London.
What are you going to see the
reaction of these people here?
Take one important battle here
today. I mean, we're talking,
we're talking something like
300 boxes of files, you know,
tons of missing documents, 15,000
papers relevant to the case.
This again is Katie Engelhart of vice new.
She reported on the trial
and the extensive number of
files that the government
produced a hundred linear feet. I
think those, those files held, um,
and they contained really,
really damning evidence of
Britain's conduct in Kenya.
The files made it clear that the central
government in London did know what was
happening in Kenya.
There was specific documentation
of rounding up of Malmo fighters.
It was even a memo about a
Kenyon being roasted alive.
And there was this pleading letter written
by detainees up in smuggled out of a
camp and it said, hurry, hurry, hurry.
In order to save our souls. I mean,
absolutely damning evidence.
The government ultimately agreed to pay
about 20 million pounds to the people
who brought this lawsuit, which
works out to roughly $4,600 each.
Yes. Here's what I don't understand. Why
would they even save those documents?
Well
looking through the collections
that have now emerged,
it's quite clear to me that they wanted
to save documents that showed that not
all the European stuff in Kenya had
been happy about compulsive force.
There's a letter written in 1953
by the colonies attorney general.
He observed that detention facilities
in Kenya or quote distressingly
reminiscent of conditions in Nazi Germany
or communist Russia. Oh, interesting.
So you think the people,
some of the British officers in Kenya
Save the files precisely because they were
damning.
Yes. They save stuff that would
demonstrate that we didn't like this
[inaudible]
whatever the reason.
Here's why the memo cases become so
much bigger than just the Mal mal case.
As soon as journalists and historians
learned about the existence of those
files,
they started to relentlessly poke and
request more documents and soon those 1500
very soon,
that became 8,800 files and then 20,000
files and then 1.2 million files and at
the time the estimate was that the
files occupied about 15 miles a Florida
ceiling shelving, what, 15 miles
the [inaudible] has been
invoked by the mammo case.
Is going to have even wider
repercussions than people yet realize.
We got a little arrived in,
in just a little laughed of them when
we were talking with a woman named Mandy
Banton, a senior research
fellow at London University.
She used to work at the National Archives
in London and we called her just to
help us parse all this stuff.
And at one point I asked her,
is this just the Kenya thing? And
she said, oh, no, no, no, it's not.
It's not by any means. Um, and she
explained that after the Mamao case,
the Foreign Commonwealth Office, which
is the technical name for the place,
it was holding those documents
almost immediately afterwards.
It admitted that he actually had, um,
documents from 37 former colonies.
Oh yes, exactly.
You mean that there could be
dirty stuff from Malaysia,
dirty stuff from Palestine,
dirty stuff from Cypress?
I believe the [inaudible] sort of
trouble spots if you like. I mean,
this is like a rewriting of history
essentially is what you said,
ray writing of history. And I mean
there are now quite a lot of people.
I'm looking at these, you know,
comparatively newly released records now,
both David and Katie o cautioned us that
the new stuff when it comes out might
not be quite as regulatory
as all those mammo files.
Well, I think there are nuggets. I
think there are nuggets and I think,
I mean I think historians will
find them for David Anderson,
one of those nuggets might be
the documents about the Cold War.
Those could be historically really very,
very important for Caroline Elkins,
Israel and Palestine.
Then Malaya in Singapore and I want
to know is in those Hong Kong files,
there's over 250,000 documents
on Hong Kong, just Hong Kong,
which sort of brings us to the
situation that we are in now.
Just the most ridiculous, ridiculous,
stupid situation imaginable,
which is that for the moment the
British government's policy is that all
[inaudible] documents must be
reviewed and redacted before release.
So each file needs to be looked over
by what's called a senior sensitivity
reviewer, although
colloquially it's just weeders.
It's basically retired senior diplomats.
If you can imagine you've got 15 miles
of papers and you've got literally a
couple of dozen retired diplomats
and they sit in an office,
literally turning pages, trying
to stay awake, sitting here.
Just imagine like take little sip
tea and redact all day long sip,
redact,
sip deck and at the rate that we're going,
by the time these files
finally see the light of day,
it will not be within my lifetime.
I mean it could literally
be hundreds of years. I,
I keep thinking about these two groups
of elderly folks. Again, producer,
Jamie York, the litigants and the Mama
case are in their eighties and nineties.
It just strikes me that what
a crazy lucky break for them.
That in the very final years
they're alive. They survive.
To hear this apology from the British
government and acknowledgement of the
story that had been
telling for 50 years. Well,
I find speculating there's
going to be so lucky. Yeah.
Thank you for putting it that way because
I am having got to know the plaintiffs
in the case. When they came to
London, it was very clear to me that,
um,
what mattered to these people was
not a financial settlement at all,
but rather acknowledgement,
just simple acknowledgment that
these things had been done to them.
So on the day that the barrister for the
crown stood up in court and to all of
our astonishment shed, quite simply,
the British government
admits the tortures.
Once I gathered my wix and looked
around and behind me in the court,
two of the plaintiffs were in tears
and it brought home to
me what a traumatic,
appalling experience this had been
for them from start to finish.
So yes, I agree for them to get
that triumph was remarkable,
remarkable.
[inaudible]
but since our producer, Jamie York,
it was really remarkable
only for some people. Yes.
So w when I went to Kenya and I was
talking to these people who had lived
through the emergency,
I wanted to know about what
they thought of the settlement
[inaudible] [inaudible] and a lot of them
were like, what settlement thing? The,
they had a little mass about the
government of Britain having a green
[inaudible]. Some of them had heard
about it. Some of them hadn't.
But it doesn't really matter to them
because the people that got paid,
that's just a tiny sliver of the vast
majority of people who've suffered.
Who are you doing?
[inaudible] what this one guy
told me is that he and most
people, what they, what they want
need isn't so much an acknowledgement.
It's, it's to get back
what was taken from them.
[inaudible] pieces of land. Oh please.
We one can keep some good cows.
[inaudible] so the Deacon do with
any 80 90 year old wants to do,
leave something behind Eh
[inaudible] to give their children
and black children a better life.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
special thanks to [inaudible] Schwartz
for first bringing us this story and to
Martin Marvin, Gina and
to faith BlueBay Bay of
the Kenyan Human Rights Commission. Nia,
can you Canada for the use of their
music and Sruthi peanut and many for a
production support.
This story was produced by Matthew Kielty
original music from Matthew Kielty and
a hell of a lot of travel and
reporting support from Jamie York.
I'm Jetta. Boom. Ron, I remember
Krulwich. Thanks for listening.