This is Radio Lab, I'm Jad Abumrad
[inaudible] today on the show,
14 meditations,
1211 1111 meditations on the moment
of death and what happens after now?
Number eight nine nine a
title which simply escapes me.
Boo-Yah Mozart from producer Lulu
Miller. Hi there. Can you hear me?
Okay, great. So I called up this
guy at the University of Leicester.
Yeah, Deli ceviche. I'm a,
I'm a ecologist who basically
works from Earth history,
but in his spare time he's
been studying what he called
future fossils.
Like let's go ahead.
Hundred million years,
which is roughly at the time that
separates us from the dinosaurs.
We will be dead. All the species
that are around us will be dead.
So I asked him, well, any of
our stuff, the books we write,
the buildings we make, well,
any of that still be here.
And here's what he found.
[inaudible] concrete is probably
going to preserve pretty well.
Glass will preserve, but it
will probably turn opaque.
It's a brickwork corroded piping, some
types of plastic and a rubbish dumps.
Oh, pretty good camps.
It would be preserved.
What about paper do we know is again,
we can treat that paper is plant
material. It will carbonize
because when we see fossil plants,
they can be preserved for tens or
even hundreds of millions of years.
So the shape of paper will
be preserved almost forever.
Uh, but the print, the print on
paper will almost certainly be lost.
If you have a book preserved, it
will be a, like a little piece of,
of oblong coal.
So the ideas that we produce
that I cannot see surviving us,
you know, so Shakespeare and Gerta and
all, all the people we call the mortals,
you know, Mozart Music, um,
that information I think
will be lost forever.
[inaudible]
oh one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, 10 psi.
Bertrand city, Sydney. It's a,
it's a word of our own coinage,
cyber trinity and it comes to
us from producer Emily Voit.
This story is about dealing with death
in a world where no one really dies.
At the center of the story
is the guy named Wyatt Amman.
I knew I, and uh, I
consider him my best friend.
That's Donald Dover. Why hadn't, I
both had office jobs at the same time.
And together we decided that this wasn't
enough because both of us were spending
so much time in front of the computers.
So the goal was going to
be to join the Peace Corps.
And we had talked about doing
the Peace Corps together,
but why it got things going.
First he quits his job,
he signs up for the Peace Corps and
within a few months was headed off to
Zambia.
He called me to see him often. Um,
we sat there and sat there and sat there
sort of avoiding the fact that he was
gonna actually have to leave.
Um, finally he's like, all right,
you need to go home. I need
to get on a plane. So, um,
he walked me to my car and, uh,
gave me a big hug and I said, yeah.
He said, uh, she's been a
great friend of mine, Donald.
I said, yeah, you too. Why
not? He said, don't worry,
I'll be back in two years.
Nobody's going to die.
But 10 weeks into the trip,
why it was hanging out with some friends
on the fourth floor of a hotel and he
leaned back against a window,
a almost floor to ceiling
and the play glass gave out.
He fell four stories and he bled to
death. His lungs filled with blood.
He never regained consciousness.
When the Peace Corps called it, I just
said, I don't believe it. Who is this?
What are you, what kind of sick thing are
you doing? This is m and why it's mom.
He said, fatal injuries. I said, what
do you mean fatal? What does fatal mean?
[inaudible]
I couldn't, my mind would not
comprehend what that word meant.
[inaudible]
I, I felt so betrayed by God. Um,
I had prayed for why at and had felt that
God would keep him safe. And you know,
it isn't, it's, it's such a crock
[inaudible]
so two years go by
and right at the time that why it would
have been returning from the peace
corps, something happened.
Jeanie, can you tell me
about getting the letter?
Yeah, I remember.
So clearly Greg and I were both home and
we went to the mailbox and walk to the
kitchen and um, we ripped open the,
the envelope and inside
was a letter from Wyatt.
We were really unsure what was going
on. It's hard to describe. It was,
um, it was really incredible.
So what happened is
this before why it died,
he had been playing around on the
Internet and he went to this site called
future May, a website where you can
send a letter to your future self. Why?
I wrote his right before
he joined the Peace Corps.
And the idea was that the site would
hold onto it and email it back to him in
two years. But of course why it
wasn't there to get the letter.
But Donald, his friend
found it and sent it.
And so Greg and I both stood there at
the counter and we read the letter. Okay.
So what did it, what does it say
dear future me, I'm leaving DC.
So far I've managed to do pretty much
everything other than what I needed to do.
You know, it's about the fact that
he's leaving for Zambia. First of all,
I have no idea what to expect.
He talks about his ex-girlfriend
sometimes love is like crack.
How he hates his office job.
I truly believe that I was meant to be
a semi transient being, you know, he's,
he's sort of being a little
melodramatic. I want the Sistine Chapel,
not a ranch style home in the suburbs.
That letter really captured who,
why it was my life is my canvas, you know,
with all his ramblings in
these grandiose things already.
Schizophrenia really colorful,
intricate and dizzyingly amorphous.
He knows that he's seeing too much in
that. He kind of has to humble himself.
How pretentious is that?
And that's what he was like.
He was always keeping a check on yourself.
One thing's for sure I'm
capable of rambling on and
on and on and on and on and
on and on. I have the same problem.
I just remember feeling,
yeah,
I felt like w y had had just sent us a
letter. Greg shook his head and he said,
that kid, you know, and um,
it was like a part of him was still alive.
[inaudible]
Emily [inaudible] let me just
interrupt for just a second. Okay.
Because it will be easy to hear.
The story is just like a fluke,
like a letter shows up from
a kid who died and liquid.
It means to the mom
and his friend. But no,
this might be where we're all headed
because he internet, you know,
it's always on.
And one of the things that's happening
is that there are sites that are popping
up that allow people to speak from
beyond the grave and to keep on speaking.
In fact, David Eagleman,
who we heard from earlier,
the guy who read those stories and
a neuroscientist, he started one.
So I started the company DEF
switch.com. This is a real thing.
There are hundreds of subscribers.
Yeah, no kidding. Oh yeah.
The way it works is you sign up for the
site and then you keep checking in with
the site to prove you're alive.
And if you disappear for too long,
the computer deduces you are dead.
Then it sends out all those emails
that you told it to your company,
telling them what the
passwords are to your family,
telling them where the gold is buried,
or even just to remind
them that you loved them.
And he says that these switches, these
desk switches are going off all the time.
But lots of people tested the deaths,
which is to make sure that it works.
So they might not be real yet,
but they will be pretty soon.
So it's easy for him to imagine.
I'll let her like this happy
87th birthday. It's been
22 years since my death.
I hope your life is proceeding
delightfully, which may sound funny,
but imagine that that's
you in the kitchen,
getting a letter from your mom or
from someone that you lost too early.
How would you feel?
Um, it was like a part
of him was still alive.
So after genie gets the
letter, what happens? Well,
Jeannie's starts writing
Wyatt as if he hadn't died.
What do you mean writing and where? Well,
Y had been a huge blogger and Jeanie
discovered that a lot of his blogs were
still active. One of them was even
updating his age. It shows his age,
his what he'd be now you know, it
doesn't know that he's not here anymore,
so she goes on and leaves him comments.
My latest one was on November 5th of this
year. Do you want me to read that one?
That'd be great. Why?
It feels like you are still here living
in Zambia and it is 2005 I feel frantic
to do something to stop the 17th from
happening in your mind when you comment on
a blog, oh Wyatt, another
holiday without you.
Where do you picture that
it's going well, I think,
I wish you could just let me know what
is like and how you feel now. Maybe.
I think I just figure it's like on a
screen and somehow he's getting it.
Why it's dead
for Donald.
Getting the letter was just a reminder
of that [inaudible] had died and Zambia
and in fact the idea that
technology could keep them around.
I guess I'm sort of, that
just didn't work for Donald.
I sort of feel that the way I imagine
why it felt in his letter he talks about,
um, not being static.
I want to learn and grow and see how
other wants to continue moving and seeking
and building and growing. And I will
not rest. It can be kind of frustrating.
Like he's, he's stuck in
a 24 year old. Why it, um,
before I died we had, um,
we decided we were Luddites,
we were anti-technology. And um,
the hilarious part is that then wild
then googled luddite to find out things
about Luddites. Um,
but initially the plan was to
leave to meet Wyatt and Africa.
And when Wyatt died, I knew that
I still needed to make that break.
So we did
[inaudible].
I left my office job to go live on a
small island in the middle of Chesapeake
Bay to 200 and [inaudible]
40 Acre island.
Here's Peter Ward.
I'm a paleontologist and professor of
biology and earth and space sciences at
the University of Washington.
In 7 billion years,
our son will
okay
suddenly go red giant
[inaudible]
and the earth is just burned to a crisp.
Is that happened like one morning or does
that happen over several hundred years
or, yeah, that's good. After
you take a few thousand years,
but the oceans will have
been actually long gone.
The oceans are going away in 2 billion
years. Oh dear. Because the sun,
that nasty old sun just keeps getting
brighter and brighter and brighter,
and about 50 to 60 centigrade, we
rapidly lose in the ocean, in the space.
This is the opposite of Noah's flood.
Instead of the gas descending
into the giant oceans,
now the oceans pick up and go
back into the sky. Exactly.
And then things get worse from there
because 5 billion years after the oceans
are gone, the sun starts
to expand and it happens in
pulse.
There are actually four to five
pulses that are gonna take place.
The first four pulses will not eat up
the earth, but it will certainly sterile.
Yeah.
Why is it
the whole surface will
melt. It'll be glowing.
The last one, the sun
just keeps expanding.
Our Sun will expand be
almost to the orbit of Mars,
and so the earth is totally gone.
I mean you've just got snuffed out.
But the nice thing is that your
Ropa will become the new Maui.
Ooh,
yeah. Jovian satellites. If
you buy real estate there now,
and I hear as jerk sheet, that
will be the tropics, Jovian Moon,
Jovian Moon. How many of
your candidates for Maui's?
There's Europa and Ganymede
and io, not so much,
but he's in Europa. When the ice
melts on Europe as is just an,
isn't it an all watery is just gonna be
a nice warm ocean would just be a ball
of water ball of water. A hundred
mile deep water too at that.
That's regular liquid water. H Two
o yes. Oh, it's beautiful stuff.
Taken the view. Think of the views
of Jupiter under he so spectacular.
The downside with these Jovian moons
is that you couldn't breathe there
when you left that out.
Minor detail burry,
that foggy that you can
certainly go water skiing.
It's just have a little respirator on.
Oh, that was a small little asterisk.
Come on now. Just compare it to the
end of the world. That's minor detail.
I see. All right. So now
let's go further out.
At what point does any possibility
of solar system existence and oh,
that one's tougher. That one's very
tough because after the red giant,
we become a m mclass or a dwarf,
which means the Sun after being this big
now expanding Redstar Ridge giant sinks
back into itself and becomes much, much,
much smaller and much, much cooler.
So Europa, our little little
paradise now freezes. Exactly.
And then the only thing left is things
like voyager, things that you, um,
you sent. Oh off. There's
still going off somewhere.
Bits of us. They're going
and going and going and gone.
And the chance that they'll ever
intersect, the star is very small.
The end, the end.
Now, the final end of course,
is way off into the future because
the universe keeps expanding.
That means eventually Adams'
themselves get pulled apart.
[inaudible]
little protons and neutrons.
They get ripped away from one
another and we're somewhere else.
Something else somehow else.
And then everything that is isn't
[inaudible]. Goodbye. Well, goodbye.
Goodbye. Proton. Goodbye. Neutral.
Good bye everyone.