You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N y.
S. C h. N. P. R.
Hello David. Yes. Hello. This
is pat. Oh, hi pat. All right,
let's begin with this story from our
producer Pat Walters. Pat, go ahead. Okay.
So I heard this one from this guy
named David, Ms. David bus to ss.
He's a psychology professor at
the University of Texas at Austin.
And this particular story, it comes
from a book that David wrote. Um,
could you just, just tell me, uh,
the little story that
you begin your book with?
Okay. Yes. Um, this is one
of the things that's, uh,
this was one of the things that sparked
my interest in the topic of murder.
The whole thing happened several
years ago. I had a very good friend,
another professor at the university,
and I used to socialize
with him and his wife.
And one evening they were throwing
a party and invited me over.
And so, uh, when I went to the party,
a party was already in full swing.
And I got there, uh, walked
in and asked his wife, uh,
where this friend of mine was. And, uh,
she got a disgusted look on her face
and said that he was up in the bedroom.
And so I went up to the bedroom
to find them. And he was in a,
in a rage, in a rage.
How, like you walk into
the room, what do you find?
Well, he started, he started fuming
that his wife had, had dissed him.
And what did she do? Uh,
she expressed disapproval about his, uh,
clothing choices. She made
fun of his shirt or something,
but did it in publicly in front of
her friends. So it was a kind of,
he felt publicly humiliated.
And while David's sitting in
the bedroom with this friend,
the guy looks up at him and he
says, I'm going to kill her.
How did he say it? Like quietly
or like through his teeth,
you know, uh, I'm going to kill her.
David had always known this
guy to be pretty mild mannered,
but he is a, uh, a large,
very strong man, um,
with a black belt in karate.
I knew what he was capable of.
And so I suggested that we go out for a
walk and I basically spent the next half
hour walking around with
him, trying to cool him off.
And eventually he did.
He just calmed down.
And did you go back to the party then
and like continue dinner partying for
awhile? Yeah,
I did too. Yes. And he did too.
And then he seemed fine
when I said goodbye to him,
he seemed calm and I left and went home.
And then it was several hours later in
the middle of the night that I got the
call and it was his friend and he says,
can I come over and sleep on your couch
if I don't leave my house right now,
I'm going to kill her. He was in this, um,
a state of fury, he said, and um,
and instead of hitting his wife,
he smashed his fist into the bathroom
mirror and then realized that he had to
leave the house or he was
gonna do damage to her.
And, and so he says that in, you're
like, okay, yes, come over now.
Like, yeah, exactly.
Meanwhile, later that night
and the other side of town,
his wife went into hiding,
literally disappeared for six months
and didn't tell anyone where she was
because she was terrified
that he was gonna kill her.
This story made us
wonder, is David's friend,
is he unusual or just everybody at some
point have something dark in them that
just tiptoes out just
from time to time. Yeah.
This is Radiolab and today we're
going to get back so to speak.
We've done a good show.
This is the bad show.
So you asked like why
do people do bad things?
It actually mean to be bad anyways.
Like how do you tell the real bad ease
from the rest of us that time? Hour.
I'm Jad Abumrad I remember coach,
this is radio lab, the bad show.
[inaudible]
back to bed. Okay. Uh, so what happened
to David that night with his friend,
got him really curious about murder
and badness and all these things we're
thinking about.
But it wasn't until a few years later
that he learned something that really put
what happened that night into
context. The next by this point,
David's moved on to a new university
and he's teaching an introductory
psychology class
and I devoted one class session to the
topic of homicide and why people kill.
And I designed a little, um,
questionnaire where I simply
asked the students, you know,
have you ever thought about killing
someone? And they would circle yes or no.
Then he left some space at the bottom
for them to elaborate if they said yes,
and, you know,
the class ended and I went back to my
office and I just sat at my desk and I
started reading these
and I was just astonished
to find page after page of
yeses and not just yeses,
but these very vivid descriptions
about who they would kill,
where they do it, when the precise method,
how many of them went
into that kind of detail?
Uh, I would say 75 or 80%. Wow. Um,
were you a little bit like
horrified? Like, oh my God,
my students are murderers. Alright. Well,
no, I, a horse horrified as
I was. I was pretty stunned.
And so I expanded the sample where we
asked about 5,000 people all over the
world. Singapore Heru the
UK. That same question,
have you ever thought
about killing someone?
And 91% of the men said yes.
And 84% of the women [inaudible]
said, yes, I've thought
about killing someone.
Yes.
If any sizable fraction actually
acted on their homicidal fantasies,
the streets would be running,
running red. [inaudible]
yeah, but that's just it.
Those are fantasies. Some
of them actually seem like,
well, here's one, something
more than just fantasies from
uh, a woman. Sure. Okay. This is
a 20 year old female. Uh, we ask,
who did you think about killing?
And she said, my ex boyfriend, um,
we lived together for a couple
months. He was very aggressive.
He started calling me a whore and
told me he didn't love me anymore.
So I broke up with him. Then a few
months later he started calling me,
trying to get back together,
but I didn't want to.
He said that if I ever had a
relationship with another man,
he was going to send the videos of
us having sex to all the people in my
university. The thing is that
I do have a new boyfriend,
but my ex boyfriend doesn't know it
that yet and I'm terrified that he'll do
what he says. Then suddenly the
thought occurred to me that would,
my life would be much happier without
him and existence, and then she said,
I actually did this.
I invited him for dinner and as he
was in the kitchen looking stupid,
peeling the carrots to make salad,
I came up to him laughingly,
gently so that he
wouldn't suspect anything.
I thought about grabbing a knife
quickly and stabbing him in the chest
repeatedly until he was dead.
I actually did the first thing,
but he saw my intentions and ran away.
When asked how close she came to
killing him, she estimated 60%
60 I don't think I've ever had a fantasy
that that anatomically specific where I
would see the part of the other person
that I was going to stab or plan it like
that. Well.
Have you ever been blackmailed the way
this woman was being blackmailed? No.
No one has ever sent about a sex tape
that I've ever, no. So you don't know.
It is a fair question to ask.
What are the conditions under which
you or me or any of us could do awful
things. I think they'd have
to be extremely extreme. Well,
you know how my died?
No. And you know what?
This actually brings us to
our first top of the hour.
So let me just to set it up. Robert,
I'm going to give you this piece
of paper here. What is this?
So these are some word pairs. Read these
words that use these words here. Yep.
Nice Day. Fat Neck. Yes. Sad face.
What is it? Soft hair. Yeah. I don't
know what this is. You just wear it,
period. I want you to commit them to
memory. Commit them to memory. You know,
and while you're doing that,
just give me your finger.
I'm going to ask that first
little electro test finger.
Let me go hard there and just
wait a second. Clear air it.
Give me the paper back.
W already time's up.
So I'm just going to go into
this other room over here.
Can you hear me? All right. So I'm gonna
talk to you over this intercom. Okay?
I'm gonna give you a test. I'm not
ready for that attention. Right?
To the best of your memory, which
word was gnashed with knife?
Was it nice day. Nice sky. Nice job. Oh,
nice chair answer for you.
I don't [inaudible] just push the button
to correspond to the right way to go.
Okay. I'm choosing job. Wrong.
Answer is day hiring map to 185
votes have to give you a little bit.
What did you just hear? Drums.
Obviously no need to be an
alarm. That was not a real shock.
We were just enacting an old,
very famous experiment that you
might've heard about. It is May,
1962 done by this guy.
That experiment is being conducted in the
elegant interaction laboratory at Yale
University.
That's Stanley Milgram talking about the
experiment in the film in case you've
never heard of, this probably happened
in case you haven't. Here's what he did.
He recruited a bunch of subjects.
Subjects are 40 males between the ages
of 20 and 50 he's normal everyday dudes.
The subjects range in occupation from
corporation presidents to good humor,
man in plumbers and you ran them through
something like what you and I just did.
Right.
He would have each subject sit down
at a table right here in front of this
really impressive looking machine machine
that had lots of switches on it. Oh,
generates electric shocks. When you press
one of the switches all the way down,
the learner gets a shock and in the
other room there was a guy he called the
learner who is supposed to have memorized
some words and every time that guy got
a word wrong like you just did. Yep.
Tapping Casa volunteer was instructed
to shock that guy with higher and higher
voltage. Now the volunteer couldn't
see the guy. He was shocking,
but he could definitely hear him
Milgrom stage. The whole thing,
like it was some experiment
about memory and punishment,
but of course it wasn't
about that until you please.
It was about how far
would these people go,
how many times would they shock that sad
SAP in the next room just because they
were being told Tim guy yelling,
of course was an actor and
the shocks weren't real,
but the questions in the air at the
time were very real prosecution.
The attorney general, this is a moment
when human cruelty was on trial.
Quite literally when I stand before
you judges of Israel in this court,
I used to accuse or don't five
from them and any or maybe he did.
I do not stand alone.
The Milgrim actually begins these
experiments the same year that [inaudible]
Eichmann goes on trial for Nazi war
crimes. That's radio producer Ben Walker.
He'll be our guide for the segment
and in the trial when the prosecutors
essentially ask him how you
came to commit genocide,
he would say over over again,
it was not my Greyson on a fair.
I was just following orders.
I had to do what I was
ordered and it's this defense.
This is basically what Stanley Milgrom
set out to test 185 volts in a lab at
Yale University. With a
bunch of regular Americans.
Okay.
Like is that something that's universal?
Yeah. Or just 10 Eichmann thing. Yeah.
He figured maybe 1% of these men would
keep flicking the switches up to the
highest voltage,
but yeah,
that's not what he found.
65% were willing to shock their fellow
citizens over and over again even past
when they were screaming in pain.
Sounds happened to that man in there.
Even when they stopped screaming.
Yeah. When they were maybe dead.
You better try and get on him. Sir.
You want to answer me or nothing?
Please continue. Go on please.
They continued shocking there
corpses.
His experiment remains one of the most
famous experiments of the 20th century in
1962 Stanley Milgrom shocked the world
because his study on obedience is still
trotted out to explain everything
from hazing to war crimes.
What is there in human nature to gang
behavior allows an individual to act
inhumanely genocide harshly. It's
like a downloadable from the Internet.
Instant defense for doing wrong, but
if you look at Milgram's work
closely. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like this guy did, oh x,
how's Lim professor of psychology
at the University of Exeter?
Then a different picture will emerge.
Really that story has been told
1,000,001 times for the last 50 years.
We've just got to get out.
Got To get out of here.
Now what you need to understand about
Alex Haslam is that he hates it when
interviewers only want to
talk about the baseline study.
The one that everybody knows, the
so called baseline, the 65% one,
the one we just talked about. Yeah. So
there's more, there's more to it. Yeah,
because actually he studied between 20
and 40 different variants of this same
paradigm. Stanley Milgrim took
electric shock with very seriously.
He did this experiment a bunch of
times and a bunch of different ways,
had all sorts of different things that
you would change where the shocker and
the Shaki Sat.
Yet women participantcy had an
experimental who wasn't a scientist,
but it was a member of the general
public and every scenario produced a
different result. Really? Yup.
Let me, I mean, I'm just, uh,
I've got in front of me, I've just got
the, uh, the data from the Milgram study.
Let me just get that
out. I mean, so again,
the baseline studies is the one where
65% of the volunteers go all the way,
highest dose of electricity x, x,
x. But in experiment number three,
if they put the Shockey in the
same room with the shocker,
so the shocker could actually see the
person that he's shocking obedience tropes
to about 40% and in
experiment number four,
when the teacher has to hold the
learner's hand down on the plate,
in order for him to feel the
shock, it drops to about 30%. Wow.
Experiment 14. If the experiments
are, he is not a scientist,
but is an ordinary man not wearing a
white coat, obedience drops to 20%.
Well, how low can we go? Okay,
here's another one. Experiment 17.
There's you and there's two
other participants, both actors.
If those two participants
refuse to go on, like saying,
I don't want to kill a guy, boney
10% under those circumstances, go on.
And then the final one,
experiment 15 of course,
normally you just have one experiment
who's giving you these instructions.
But if you put two experimenters in the
room and they start disagreeing with
each other and this one you get 0% going
all the way. Zero in that condition.
You said Zero Nolan and go right to
the unknown at one person, not assault.
Exactly. 0% well, all right,
I'm starting to feel a little bit better
about my fellow man. One second. Hey,
okay. Where is he?
Am I'm in a closet closet cause this room
is echoey and you know there's nothing
like a closet full of clothes to like
help balance that out. That's true.
That's true. All right,
keep going. So you see,
it's just in that one experiment that
65% of people are willing to go all the
way. But in all of these
other scenarios they don't.
And even when they do say yes, even
when they go along with the experiment,
as you can see in the film, they struggle
using the last switch on the board.
Please. I'm not getting no answer.
Please continue. The next word is white.
They have debates with themselves.
Please debates with the experimenter.
Not once we started the
experiment, something's happened.
Then man attacked or something on that.
The experiment requires that we
continue to go on and put the man's,
help me in anything, whether the
learner likes it or not. We [inaudible].
What's interesting is that
how all of these struggles,
all of them play out the same way.
It's the experimenter
prodding the shockers along.
Yeah. Nothing came together on
what? 450 volts every shot now.
Correct. For me, it's all
about the prods connect words.
This is what totally
pulled me into this story.
Prods Stanley Milgrom had four scripted
prods that he wrote out for his
experimenters for when the subjects
didn't want to continue. Yup.
The first one was,
please go on and if they
didn't go on, if they resisted,
he experimented, would break
out prod and number two,
the experiment requires that you continue.
Well, the experiment requires a
lot. I mean, I know it does, sir,
but I mean he's up to 195 o's
and if they still were resisting or
struggling, they'd get prod number three.
It's absolutely essential
that you continue.
Absolutely essential. Like you
can tell a little bit more direct.
It's a bit stronger. It's not
an order, but the fourth prod,
really the the critical, the critical
false prod is an absolute
order. The fourth prod is
you got to know where the choice
teacher, you have no other choice.
Choice teacher, you must continue.
That is definitely an order.
Exactly, but every time the experiment
are pulled out, the fourth prod,
and this was confirmed when the
experiment was redone in 2006
total disobedience, Hodel disobedient.
Anytime the experimenter said you
must continue, the shocker would say,
hell no. I've
don't. You have no other choice
teacher. I have a choice.
I'm not going to go ahead with it.
Well, we'll have to discontinue
the experiment then. I'm sorry.
Here's another one.
You have no other choice.
You must go to have a choice.
How does, if you don't continue,
what we're going to have to discontinue
the experiment after he says cut it out.
After all he knows what he
can stand. That's my opinion.
That's where I'm going to stand on it.
So the subjects seem willing
to shock another human being,
but as soon as you say it's an order,
they don't do it. Now that's important.
It's very important because if
you ask university undergraduates,
what does the Milgram study show?
They will invariably say something like
they show that people obey orders. Okay.
Well actually the one thing that the
study really doesn't show is that people
are, Bay audit is a pretty big thing. To
me. This is a pretty big thing to miss,
isn't it? Really? See, wait,
if it doesn't show that people
are just obeying orders. Yeah,
and what does it show? Okay. I think
it looks, it's like this. All right,
let's go into our instruction.
We will begin with this test.
The participants are there in the, in
the study, I've got a very plausible,
very credible high-status scientist and
as I say, it's a scientific institution.
Yale, who is going to do this
powerful piece of science,
direct your voice toward
that microphone is the room.
So they sit down in the chair thinking,
wow, this is really important.
I'm about to help this quest
for knowledge. I really
want to do a good job. Now,
as we sort of know in life,
lots of things that we do if they
worthwhile doing and not always easy.
And you find yourself in a situation
where you've got to do something that's
hard, like shocking, an
innocent stranger over and over.
But if you think that's the right thing,
if you think that science is
worth pursuing, you say, okay,
I'll go along with this.
So you're saying they are shocking
these people because they thought it was
worthwhile. Look, the participants,
you know, they're not, it's not.
It's not just blind or beaten. So,
oh, you tell me. So yes sir. No Sir.
Three bags full sir.
They're engaged with the task that
trying to be good participants.
They're trying to do the right thing.
They're not doing something
because they have to.
They're doing it because
they think they ought to.
And that's all the
difference in the world.
Suddenly I'm thinking this
is actually a darker interpretations.
Say original. Absolutely darker.
They are doing it. No question
about it. They have the agency. Yup.
And they think it's right.
Although clearly they on
some level they know it isn't
does this sort of chilling comparison,
which is a speech that Himmler gave to
the SS cmss leaders when they were about
to commit a range of
atrocities. And he said, look,
this is what you're going to do is
of course you don't want to do this.
Of course nobody wants to be killing
other people and we realize this is hard
work.
But what you're doing is for the good of
Germany and this is necessary in order
to advance our noble cause.
Wow.
So then, hey wait, I'm almost done
guys. Give me two more minutes.
Two more minutes. So in the mailroom case,
[inaudible] with the ideas that people
will do bad if they think it's good,
like the good Nobel cause. Well what's
the noble cause in this case? Science.
Science.
You can see this in the surveys that
the men filled out after the experiments
were over. This was exactly what
was on my mind. If the experiment,
if the experiment had to be
successful, it had to be carried on.
The questionnaires they filled out are
part of the Milgrim archive at Yale.
I'm willing to help in
a worthwhile experiment.
And it's Kinda surprising.
A lot of them are really positive even
though they've just been told that they
were duped. Research
in any field is a must,
particularly in this day and age.
Do you think that more studies of this
sort should be carried out? Definitely,
yes.
We as, as onlookers to this study,
we have this kind of Godlike, uh,
sort of vision of like, well, of
course what they're doing is wrong,
but if it looks at it
from another perspective,
there's a sense in which you could
celebrate what they're doing. I mean,
I'm not suggesting one should,
but I'm just saying there is a sense in
which these people are prepared to do
something that's very painful to them
and to someone else because they want to
promote science. Well, you know, you
can see that's a good thing. I mean,
you know
God cause it's like we started with this
experiment that we all see as evidence
of humans, latent capacity for
evil. You tell us actually no,
under some circumstances we don't do
the bad thing we're told to do because
here's another flip. We don't have to
be told, in fact, we hate being told,
but we will do it on our own
if we think it's good. Yeah.
Now you're saying actually
that you could read that,
that very dark fact as being actually
evidence of something quite quite noble.
Well, if you dressed it up and if
you just had some minor variance,
the paradigm, you could presumably
make, you know, make this out these up.
These are people who are
incredibly noble. They are,
I mean it's the fact of course that
they're administering pain to a stranger.
That's what's horrifying about it.
But imagine they were
administering paint themselves.
Imagine they were really where I had
to administer shocks themselves or
something. But if they
were prepared to do that,
when I suspect a lot of them
would, um, then we'd say,
these are people who really believe in
Saas and isn't this a good thing that we
have people in our society who are
willing to make sacrifices for the greater
good?
Hmm.
So in the end, where do you come down?
Do you leave this experiment in a light
mood or an a dark mood? Uh, I, th I,
I overall, I would say in a powerful mood,
we're close to some really fundamental
truths about human nature. And you know,
my views about human nature is that it
affords infinite potentials for lightness
and dark. There's lots and lots of lessons
here, but one is, I think, you know,
when you're enjoined to do
something for the greater good,
maybe ask yourself the question,
what is greater and what is good?
Oh, that right there. Slap
some quotations around that.
Yeah. Yeah.
[inaudible]
right. Thanks to Ben Walker whose podcast
he has a podcast and it's a good one.
It's called too much information.
Yes, it's awesome. Thank you Ben.
And also thank you to Alex Haslam,
professor of psychology at the
University of Exeter. We'll be right back
the start of message. Okay,
you guys take one on his Benjamin Walker
and here are some radio lab credit.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and the Alfred
p Sloan Foundation.
Enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world or
information about Sloan at www dot
Sloan or g radio lab is produced,
Dubuque, n y c o,
distributed by NPR, Voila,
and A. I'm hanging out.
Hello, this is Tom leads from Oaklawn,
Illinois radio lab and need your help.
Please visit WWE NYC dot
podcasting survey.com and
tell them a little bit about
yourself and the podcast you love in
a five minute anonymous survey. I did.
You can find the link on the show
page for this episode Radio Lab.
Really appreciate your help.
Knowing more about you helps them
make more of the shows that you enjoy.
Thank you very much.
Oh, okay. They're going
to record it over. I mean,
I'm going to record it here
too. All three, two, one.
Hey, I'm Janna. Boom. Ron,
I'm Robert Krulwich. This
is radio lab and today evil,
although I don't know if that's the
right word for this next thing. Yeah.
Cause it's sort of more complicate
when you call someone evil,
then you're kind of done with
them. But there's been a fellow,
I've been thinking about him from
better part of the year as you know,
[inaudible] such a puzzle to me.
I can't quite please him though.
It's very fun to try. And uh, I heard
about him from science writers, Sam Keen.
Well let's talk about Fritz Haber. So,
so first of all, could you just like, uh,
when did he live and what did he
look like and that kind of stuff?
Uh, he was doing his,
his great science work right around
the turn of the 20th century.
So right around 1900 very distinctive
looking man bald on top trim,
nice mustache. Wore a little, um,
uh, peas Nez. Is that how you say?
Is that [inaudible] so
I'm not sure if, okay.
One of those very tiny old fashioned,
a pair of glasses that
would pinch on your nose.
And he was someone who
had very big ambitions.
Just to put that in context, they bring
a few other of our storytellers in.
He comes from Breslau, Germany,
that's Fred Kaufman reporter,
which is a fairly small, you know,
smaller sort of town. And uh,
so does Clara. That's for topper's wife.
We're going to meet her later, right?
Clara comes from the same town
and they're both secularized Jews.
But this was a moment in German history.
He says when Jews had a
decent amount of freedom,
and this is the difference between
Kaiser Wilhelm and of course Hitler's
Germany. Yeah, put it in context.
Dan Charles, he's a historian.
His was the first generation when a young
Jewish boy could truly imagine that he
could just be a regular
part of that society.
He could do anything and he
believed it. Fast forward,
10 years for topper is a professor, small
university is working with chemicals.
It's about 1880.
And he throws himself with one of the
central issues facing Germany that at that
time Germany has a problem, a big problem.
It has enough what they used to
call then solar energy, you know,
energy from the sun to grow crops
to feed about 30 million people.
However, that leaves
behind 20 million Germans.
Do you mean they're looking at
20 million people going hungry?
That's what we're heading towards. I
mean you have to remember it during the,
during the Crimean war in
the 1850s Europe starves,
so around the turn of the century
for German scientists like hopper,
this was the challenge. He is, he wants
to feed, he wants to feed Germany,
and actually this wasn't
just a German thing.
A lot of people were beginning to worry
that with about a billion and a half
people on the planet at that point that
maybe we were maxing out that the earth
couldn't support this many people
and everyone thought, well,
we know the solution. Yeah, we just need
a whole lot more of one simple element.
Nitrogen, nitrogen, nitrogen,
nitrogen, they needed more nitrogen.
Nitrogen is an essential part
of amino acids and proteins.
And when you stick a seed
like wheat seed in the ground,
one of the reasons that grows is because
it's sucking up all the nitrogen in the
soil to make it cell
walls. Without nitrogen,
you don't have life. Now,
of course you could find it
some nitrogen out in the world.
Natural deposits would be like
seaweed or manure was one. You know,
you could find it in cow
manure or [inaudible],
which was basically poop and seagull
poop, which made that poop valuable.
And actually two nations in
South America went to war,
literally over bet. You could say
people were crazy, by the way.
That's reporter Latif Nasr you know,
this was like oil is today. This is,
everybody was desperate for
sources, new sources of nitrogen,
and to make the problem
even more annoying,
the most common source of
nitrogen is in the air around us.
[inaudible]
ah,
it makes up four out of every five
or so molecules that we breathe.
So it's very a lot. Yes.
80% of the air is nitrogen atoms.
So all the nitrogen you'd
ever need, what's right there.
You can't like throw that air onto
a plant. They couldn't deploy it.
They deploy it, meaning they
couldn't capture it. That's right.
And part of the problem here,
and although once again we're
getting a little ahead of ourselves,
we'll be right back to that. But,
but wait, wait, let's just finish.
This is that is that
nitrogen is try Vaillant try,
try Vaillant. In other words,
nitrogen has really strong
attachments to itself.
And what he means is that when nitrogen
atoms are just free floating in the air,
they will clean to each other.
These little nitrogen atoms will
fiercely hold together and it's almost
impossible to pry them apart.
His calculations showed
that it couldn't be done,
at least not without a
tremendous amount of energy,
more energy than seem like possible
to make. Yeah. Yes. But you know,
being ambitious harbor starts
thinking, in order to do this,
we need to Ah, pressure this. We need
to put it under a lot of pressure.
So he starts experimenting.
He figures out a way to take a lot of
air that's filled with these little
nitrogen bonds clinging to each other
and pump it with big iron pig under
extreme extreme pressure at
high temperature and then
he forces hydrogen into
the tech. Get in there and you
have a number of chemical reactions
and what happens is that you're elbowing
the nitrogen apart from excel and then
forcing it to on [inaudible]
with the hydrogen in a new way. And when
hydrogen and nitrogen bond together,
the thing you get is ammonia,
a liquid that is captured the
nitrogen right out of the air.
You literally get a drip, drip,
drip of ammonia.
Oh
it is.
It is arguably the most significant
scientific breakthrough of the mall bred
from the air was the phrase cause hopper
had figured out a way to take nitrogen
from the air, put it into the
barren ground and grill. Wait,
this has allowed the world
to have 7 billion people.
This is what's driving the
world towards 10 12 by 2050
[inaudible]
now we're seeing about a hundred million
tons of synthetic fertilizer produced
industrially each year.
And that tonnage is then
moves into our food source.
Our food source then moves into our
bodies and the rough statistics are that
half of each of our
bodies contains nitrogen.
It's from the harbor process. No, really
[inaudible]
and so in 1918 fritz hopper gets
a Nobel prize, but this is my,
this is such an interesting
guy. Around the same time,
officials in the u s government
are calling him a war criminal.
[inaudible]
all right. Just to back up for one
second, after Hopper's nitrogen discovery,
he was promoted. You know,
he takes over the leadership of this
institute in Berlin and he starts
hobnobbing with a whole different level
of society that Stan Charles Again,
I mean, it's a pretty
heady thing for, you know,
a Jewish kid from Breslau to be
hobnobbing with the emperor and cabinet
ministers. He's part of the club
and he really, really relished it.
And not just because he was vain,
which everyone agrees he was,
but because he loves his country. He
loves the fatherland and he loves Germany.
So when World War One begins,
he signs up immediately sends a
letter volunteering for duty saying,
you know the process that
I use to make food. Well,
I can use that same
process to make explosives
because the thing that you put into the
ground to grow more food is also the
thing you can explode to make a bomb.
That's correct because it takes such
energy and pressure to separate it.
This try Vaillant bond is so strong
that when it comes back together,
that energy that's released,
it can be used for life or death.
In any case, back to World War
One, there's trench warfare.
It gets bogged down
and harbor has an idea.
It goes straight to the German high
command and he and he pitches this idea.
He says, well,
we can drive those enemy soldiers
out of trenches with gas.
Chlorine gas will basically bring
it to the front and when the,
when the wind is right,
we'll just spray it.
But the generals were not all that
convinced now. They just didn't like it.
A lot of them were like, this
is not how you fight a war.
It's like playing dirty
sort of unsportsmanlike.
But he organizes soldiers.
He organizes whole gas units and no one
even had to ask takes command of them.
Partially he travels to the
front. And on April 22nd,
1950 and 1915 Hubbard finds
himself in a little town in Belgium
called e, y. P. R. E. S. Actually
the Americans called it Yips,
whatever you call it.
This was one of the bloodiest
arenas on the western front.
The Germans were on one side, the fringe,
the Canadians and the
British on the other.
And there behind the German lines is
our, our friend, our friend of me,
uh, for topic, our friend,
he's bald. He has a pot belly.
He has these [inaudible] spectacles.
He's chomping on a Virginian Cigar.
He was always smoking these Virginians
cigars and he's wearing a fur coat
really? And what is basically
like the Baghdad of his time.
But nobody had done
what he was about to do on the
scale that he was about to do it.
So basically at 6:00 PM on April
22nd when the wind was just right,
he says harbors gas troops on
unscrew, they opened the valve
on almost 6,000 tanks
containing 150 tons of chlorine.
That's like an adult
blue whale of chlorine.
Just trying to imagine
that as that like a,
like a green cloud does that some people
describe it as a cloud and then others
describe it as this kind of 15 foot wall
kind of hugging the land and it's just
sort of approach and it's moving at about
one meter per second and according to
some accounts as it crept
across no man's land,
the leaves would just sort of shrivel
and the grass was turning to the color of
metal.
Birds would just fall from the air
within minutes the gas reached the allied
side and as soon as it did,
soldiers began to convulse. They
were gagging, they were choking,
hundreds of them were
falling to the ground.
What is the guest doing to them exactly?
I think what it's doing is it's a,
if you breathe it in,
it sort of irritates your lungs to the
extent that they sort of fills up with
fluid so quickly that you sort of drown
in your own flam sitting like actually
drowning, literally drowning on land. Wow.
Yellow Mucus was frothing
out of their mouth.
Those who could still
breathe would turn blue.
This is the description of hell yeah.
But harbor solid has a
wonderful success and wished,
wished that the Germans had been better
prepared to exploit it because he felt
like they really could have made a
terrific advance if they had had more
confidence
and he is celebrated for it.
He gets promoted to the rank of captain
and he goes home for a few days a hero.
But when he gets there, he has to
contend with his wife, Clara Emma Var,
Clara also from Breslau office, also from
a Jewish family and also a scientist.
Huh.
Unusually so in those times she was
actually a sort of a genius herself.
She was one of the first women
to earn a phd in her country.
And shortly after his return, Clara
allegedly confronts him and says, look,
you are morally bankrupt.
How could you? Um,
but Haber just kind of ignored
her. And according to legend,
he actually threw a dinner party
in celebration of the big victory,
invited his friends over. Now we don't
actually know if he threw a party.
Like I consider that apocryphal.
Dan doesn't think so.
But what's clear is that he saw no
reason to question what he had done.
And that infuriated Clara especially
because she found out he was leaving the
next day to direct more gas attacks and
they'd probably had an argument. Yeah,
undoubtedly. They had an argument
that's historian Fritz Stern,
who also happens to be fritz Hopper's
Godson. They had a quarrel more than that,
let's call it a fight.
And later that night after the party
harbor takes a bunch of sleeping pills and
goes to sleep. Um,
and she takes a service revolver,
if it's pistol walks
outside to the garden and
pulls the trigger,
shoots herself in the chest
and is found by her son,
by her son. Yes. Age to teen, I think. Uh,
and he finds her actually still alive
with the life about to run out of her, uh,
harbor. It's unknown what happens
for the rest of that evening,
but it is a well-documented fact that
the very next morning on schedule,
he goes back to the, to the front,
to the eastern front. Leaving. Yeah.
His son, uh,
alone with his dead mother. That's
cold, Huh? Yeah. Heartless
ed was a terrible moment.
Did he run away? Was it duty? The sign?
Eventually after he immigrates to America,
[inaudible] kills himself.
[inaudible]
see now around this point,
I just don't want to have anything
to do with this guy. This is a,
I just want to take a
shower. Walk away. Yeah.
Yeah, me too.
You know, on the other hand, I mean, if
you look at the grand calculus people,
he's helped or fed versus
people he's killed. I mean,
he's felt that billions of people.
I don't know that you could
entirely call him bad.
I might even tilt towards saying
he's a little good to be honest.
You wouldn't though, would you really?
Would you really think that this
guy's a good guy? Honestly, yeah.
Just because of a mathematical summing
up. We're talking billions of people.
He's standing there on the front pushing
the gas into the lungs or other human
beings. It's merely, it's a war, but
still, then he goes and you know,
and celebrates that and then walks away
from his child and his wife did in the
garden and says more of that please. Well,
there's something distasteful about
the fact that he was too into it.
But like I do think on some level you
have to divorce the man from his deeds and
you've got to ask, is the world
better with him or without him?
I think you've got to
answer it with him. Right.
Well, to keep going with
the story. Yeah. Alright.
So Sam, what happened to
this guy after World War One?
He actually was very humiliated that
Germany had lost and especially humiliated
over the fact that they
had to pay enormous war
reparations to other countries.
So he decided he was going to invent a
process to pay for these reparations by
himself. And what he decided
to do is go into the ocean,
into sea water, which contains, um, uh,
very small levels of gold. But you know,
over the entire ocean there's a
lot of gold dissolved into the sea.
And he spent five years
in a few tile effort to distill
gold from the ocean's waters.
Sounds insane. On the other
hand, if anyone could do it,
he was trying to repeat this master
stroke. Needless to say, he fails.
It was actually a crushing
blow for, for him.
And then things really take a turn.
1933 comes and Hitler takes over.
And one of the first acts that the Nazis
do is to basically issue an order that
says there shall be no Jews in the
civil service. Now harbor was Jewish,
but because he'd served in World War
One, he technically would be exempt.
But 75% of the people who
worked for him at the institute,
they were Jewish and they
would have to be dismissed.
So he decides to take a stand
and says, this is intolerable.
I'm going to resign. He says that he's a,
he's always been hiring people based
on how smart they are and not who their
grandparents were. So he sends a letter
to the Ministry of Education, resigning,
and he leaves Germany telling a friend.
He felt like he'd lost his homeland.
And then he starts this
a period of roaming.
He eventually goes to England.
But in a famous incident,
one of England's leading scientists
refuses to shake his hand.
And he is basically homeless
at this point. You know,
he's a man adrift. Meanwhile,
his health is failing.
In 1934 he takes a trip to
Switzerland, to a sanatorium,
but before he can get there,
his heart fails and he dies.
Mm.
Now there's a footnote to
this that is very strange.
Um, I got a little, uh, my, I,
this is my dorsal hairs stood up
when I read the end of this. Right.
So during World War One,
harbor's institute had
developed a formulation of, um,
insect killing gas called Zyklon Zyklon a,
which was originally just a pesticide.
Once again, another nitrogen compound.
It was developed in his institute.
He knew about it. In fact,
his chemist had given this
particular pesticide, a smell was,
it was a warning smell so that people
didn't inadvertently breathe it in and get
sick. But after the Nazis take
over, this is after he died,
they reached back to the shelf and they
find this xy clon stuff and they asked
for it to be reformulated to take out the
warning smell and it becomes Zyklon B,
the killing gas of the
concentration camps.
[inaudible]
did members of Hubbard's family die
in the concentration camps? Yeah.
Members of his extended family did.
Certainly friends of his
did is something deeply,
deeply wounding, stressing,
upsetting at the thought that he
had anything to do with sibling B.
But he did the use of it.
He couldn't have imagined
[inaudible]
so how do you feel about him
now? Because I don't know.
I can't help but feel bad for
the guy despite the chlorine gas.
Like he didn't intend for that to happen.
He could have never imagined that. No,
but, but there's part of
me that says, you know,
here's a guy who just wanted
to do everything better
than he had ever been done
before. Whether it was feeding
or killing or any does. He does,
but he does it with a kind of
amoral athleticism. You know, he,
he does it without humility, without,
without a lot of doubt. And you know,
it's a craft,
but it's a craft with consequences and
to approach it with kind of crazy joy.
I don't know.
I would rather have scientists who
carry doubt with them as they proceed.
Yeah, I agree with that. Maybe
it's all about doubt in the end.
[inaudible]
thanks to all our great storytellers,
Dan Charles, Sam keen, lots of Nasser,
Fred Kaufman and Fritz Stern. You can
find out more information about it.
All those guys on our
website. radiolab.org
hi, my name's Josh and I'm
calling from Harlem New York.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org thanks.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and today we're
talking about, well,
we're trying to think about what
goes on in the mind of a bad person.
What makes a bad person so bad that he's
different from the rest of us and we
don't really come to any kind of
agreement with the hopper thing. Yeah,
I don't think we quite know, but you know,
we ended up walking this question around
different people want to talk about bad
people in Shakespeare.
And oddly enough, we came,
got a really interesting take on the true
nature of badness from this Guy James
Shapiro,
professor of English at Columbia
University and he said to start,
you want to know about bad? I'll
give you bet in Titus Andronicus,
there's a character by the
name of Aaron, the Moore,
and there's a moment in the play
where Aaron gets up on stage,
looks at the audience and says,
let me just tell you the kinds of
things I've been up to recently,
said deadly enmity between two
friends make poor men's cattle,
break their necks, set fire on bonds,
and he stacks in the night
and bid the owners questions,
quenched him with the tears off.
Have I digged up dead men from their
graves and sit them upright of their dear
friends door? Oh,
even even with this sorrows
almost were forgotten.
And on their skins is on the bark of
trees have wind my life with my knife
carved in Roman letters.
Let not your sorrows die though I am dead.
So he's bad. Yeah, but see, here's the
interesting thing. According to James,
he's not the baddest no in Shakespeare
or in life because ultimately the play
offers up a reason for his nastiness.
The reason why he's telling all this
stuff is because he has cut a deal.
They will spare his son if he fastest
up and and tells them what they need to
know. So there's a way in which
is a touch of spark of humanity,
just a little glimmer. And he
says that's what people wanted.
They wanted someone who was
really thrillingly bad but
in the end was a redeemed
a bit. Yeah. This wasn't
just a theater thing. No.
Cause if you couldn't afford
a ticket for a player,
you'd seen all the plays in the 1500 you
could always go to a public hanging and
you'd go for much the same reasons. And
those days if you're a convicted felon,
you are, you know, strung up, but you're
not allowed to hang until you die.
You're cut down before then warning,
this next part's a little graphic.
Then the executioner cast rates,
you cuts you open and takes out your
internal organs and then separate your
head, which is put on a post. But even
with all that Gore and horribleness,
there was often a moment
that people waited for.
And in a way we wait
for it still. Even now,
we want what Alyssa beef
and Scott at the scaffold,
which was a confession before
the guy is cut to shreds.
He's allowed to confess. You
know, I, I hardly, you know,
regret the fact that I, uh, kill
the young Baden or defame the king,
whatever it is.
The expectation is somebody is made to
make his peace with his maker before he
dies. That's what you do. And that's
what Shakespeare did. And all his plays,
he would give all his baddies at least
one moment where they could be understood
except this one time.
So be like a two
in tough. He is a soldier.
He works for a general, the general's
name is a fellow there supposedly chums,
but General Othello has
no idea that he Jago
hates him.
So he plans to destroy a fellow
and then we don't exactly know why.
There are hints of reasons like maybe he
thinks a fellow sleeping with his wife,
we're not sure.
But the weird thing is that he decides
not just to take down the fellow,
but everybody, no, no, no. What you did,
he stirs up hatred
between friends, friends
between lovers. He even
schemes against his wife.
This is just somebody who's performing
brain surgery without anesthesia on other
people. Uh, he's a master planner.
And as for why maybe a fellow
was sleeping with Amelia.
But as the play goes on, you begin to
think that maybe that's just another lie.
Eventually Iago convinces a fellow
that his wife has been disloyal,
which she hasn't. And then Othello
goes and kills his own wife,
smothering her with a pillow.
This is just at tsunami of
Eva passes through the plant.
[inaudible] is good. And at
the very end of the play,
when everyone finds out what y'all
goes done, fellow asks him, why,
why did you do this?
Any Jago he refuses what
we fully expect and what everybody on
stage at that moment fully expects from
him. You know, what does he say? Um,
demand mean nothing. What you know,
no, from this time forth,
I never will speak word.
I'm not saying a word. I'm not
going to give you what you want.
I'm not going to give you,
I'm not going to help restore the sense
that there is a moral order to the
world. And a moral norm.
[inaudible]
what you know, you know,
if this is the singular moment in
Shakespeare where he gives you an
understandably evil man.
No Motors, no reason.
Hello.
Any idea what the hell he was intending?
What's she know, you know
of it? Meaning, I mean w any
idea where he was in his mind?
Was he trying to make a commentary? So
there was he grappling with something?
Do we know? No, you know, dammit
the goody Algos make you want to shower
the minute you leave the theater cause
you are Sally by them.
Thank you to James Shapiro who his most
recent book is called contested. Will.
You know what you, unless
you have you there. Yeah.
Well you know what I'm left thinking
though. He's like, if you could somehow,
I mean that was make-believe,
but if you could somehow get a real Jago
in the room and subject that person to
questioning and really get them to
sort of fess up as to why they did it,
would that make a difference?
We should say that this next section of
the program has some references which
are extremely graphic. Yeah. Not to
everybody's taste. So we have kids in the,
in the room and maybe this is at a time
they tell them to go brush their teeth
or something. Yeah, yeah. It comes to
us from our reporter parenting. Scott
is Jeff Johnson. Nice to meet you. All
right, so who is this guy? We're here.
This is Jeff Jensen and he's a reporter
in La and he wrote this graphic novel
that I read about one of the most
prolific serial killers in u s history.
Gary Leon Ridgway, the green river killer.
The first victims of the
green river killer were found
in the summer of 1982 the
green river murders terrorized
Seattle in the 1980s in Seattle today,
a man called the green river killer.
Ridgeway murdered at least 49 women,
so called Green River killer.
It's suspected that it could be upwards
of 75 making him the most prolific
serial killer in American history.
All the victims were prostitutes.
He buried them or left their bodies
in these little clumps in the woods.
The kind of seemed to a place to
bodies as if they were mannequins.
And in January of 1984,
the green river task force was formed
and my father was recruited at the task
force. So Jeff wrote this book
because his father, Tom Jensen,
was one of the lead
detectives tracking Gary Way.
He ultimately spent 17 years searching
for this man. In December of 2001,
my father and his colleagues make the
arrest DNA testing matched him to the
crime they arrest Gary
League, Leon Ridgway. And on
June 13th, 2003,
Gary was secretly taken out of his
jail cell and brought to a sort of very
nondescript concrete,
ugly office building. And
um, over the next six months,
from June to early December,
it was Tom's job to get Gary to open up
and give up the few details that they
really needed to link him
certifiably to all these crimes.
Today's date is June 17th, 2003,
at the time now is zero eight 36 hours.
So every day they would bring them into
this conference room is a continuation
of an interview with Gary Leon
Ridgway and interrogate them.
What did you remember
since we last talked? You
got those all attuned mostly. Um,
some that, uh,
I remember picking her up and um,
it immediately became apparent that there
was going to be difficulties as far as
I know. I don't know if I
did or not. You would deny
things. He would obscure,
he would dance around things
you didn't really want a cop to.
Everything that he did.
Did I gotta Tell Ya? Uh, I mean,
not totally comfortable that you're
providing all the information,
especially when it came
to one particular fact.
What my father and his colleagues know
is that something was done to these body,
many of them after they
were murdered. Does he,
is he saying what I think he's saying?
Necrophilia Gary is
dancing around this topic.
Gary had denied this to his own lawyers
and that we're not going to be shot.
So my father and the other interviewer
in that room, that morning,
detective John Madson,
they start using a line of,
uh, attacked of, uh, of
interviewing him. That was very,
it's okay. It's okay
if you did. Stunningly,
shockingly empathetic,
nothing to be ashamed.
Thousands of people have done it
before. You know, I'm not the first one.
You know, you're not the first
person that's ever done this,
not going to be the last
one. You won't be the last.
That's one of the things that we really
need to know if father's trying to like
reach out to him. Okay. I know
it was more than marriage.
It's okay to admit this. You need
to admit this. Okay. It's all right.
We've got to note that.
That's one of the things that you have
to know and that's why it's okay to let
him know and he does a yes,
I did lie about that. Potential is a,
I would bet one time before that I,
like I said, I've got to give it out.
It can't keep holding
and holding it numbers,
building up.
This was a major breakthrough so he ends
up admitting it in graphic detail and
it gets even more disturbing for my
father as the conversation suddenly pivots
to another victim
other than one
that was real close to me by the name
of Carol Christian said Christian.
I dated her several times,
three times, two times.
He brings her up as an example of a
of a woman that he actually had strong
feelings for
like just like just girl
lecturers. She was skinny,
she was good to me
and as it happens my father has very
vivid memories of investigating the Carol
Christianson murder. Speaking with
Carol's mom, Carol's little daughter
killed her. She was, I
knew she had a daughter.
And so your last,
Gary's starts going through this
narrative of what he did to Carol
the last time she was in our hurry.
She like was allegedly in a rush
and she didn't and like it kind of
[inaudible] hurt his feelings
wasn't satisfying me with make me
mad because she very much hurry.
She doesn't melt in her mind, and I
killed her killer at shelter with my arm
and weight killer cared for because I
dated before, but this
tape didn't turn out right
up until that point.
Gary refused to say that from the
minute I picked these women up,
I wanted to kill them. He claimed
they were in the middle of a sex act.
He would get distracted, something would
happen. He just kind of went crazy.
He had snapped and almost like blaming
the victims and my father wasn't buying
it. Let's hold back up
a little bit. The fact
that he kept on doing it over and over
and over again, it was like, come on.
You've been through this a lot of times
before and she's already told you she's
in a hurry. You knew what was going
to happen and you've done this.
How many times? 10 Times,
10 1520 times.
You know what's going to happen is she
pisses you off and you like telling this
all,
get you go into this knowing full
well that it could end up in her dash
and Gary just says, yes. That
is true. When I picked him up,
I was going to kill them. Finally
acknowledging. Yeah, that's true.
There's a pause and my
father just says, why? Why?
Why did you do this? You need the killed.
And that was a question that had
haunted my father for decades.
Why isn't that why and that one
simple why that he asks Gary,
there was a lot of
questions. He was asking,
why did you inflict all this
suffering on them? On us?
Why did you take these women off the
streets and wanting to destroy them? Why?
Why?
The answer is
unsatisfying. Yes. I did need to kill,
kill her because,
wait, what?
I just needed to kill because of
that and then he just trails off.
I need to kill because of that.
That's it. It just, you know,
I just wanted to kill him.
I just needed to kill them
in that moment. My father, he
stands up. Then he says, touch me.
You've touched me, Gary, you
touched me. You take a break.
Okay, we're going off tape now.
Is there a nine 24
hours on June 17th year,
2004 he walked out of the way a
room and just started weeping.
They spent the next six
months interrogating him.
They brought in psychiatrists and
forensic psychologists to try to get an
answer. Gary says, I needed to kill
him. They go, why? And he says,
because of the rage
and well, why the rage?
And because women have stepped
on me all my life. Well,
why can't you deal with
it in a normal way?
Each answer just begs another why and
even though in the end they got him to
confess to these 49 murders,
they never really get any closer
to an answer than this first one.
[inaudible]
that afternoon he gets
in his car, goes home,
he finds my mom on the deck,
he sits down next to her
[inaudible]
she says, what happened
today? My Dad said,
I don't want to talk about it.
And to this day they have not talked
about that day and he hasn't talked about
it with anyone until I
interviewed him for the book.
And
why is it so important do you think,
to understand the why
behind such an evil act?
Well,
the thing that haunts me about the why
question is that I'm reminded of like one
of the oldest stories in the
Bible, which is the story of job.
The story of job is that one day God
and Satan are having a conversation and
they're saying, have you checked out
job? You know, I'm really proud of job.
He believes in me and he trusts me so
much and he has such great faith in me and
Satan is like, ah, I bet
I can change his mind.
And so Satan basically
systematically destroys job's life,
takes away his wife, his children,
all his material possessions.
What follows is this ongoing conversation
between Jobe and his friends about why
does this happen? Why does
God allow this to happen?
Only then does God speak
up and kind of say like,
you're going to question me
like, you know who are you?
My point is sometimes when we ask
the why in the face of profound evil,
I kind of wonder if what we're doing is
that we're daring God to show himself
and I think what we want out of
the y is meaning meaning to life,
to reveal itself in a way that restores
order and gives us hope that all of this
isn't just meaningless chaos.
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
Jensen's book is the Green River
Killer, a true detective story.
It's a graphic or an
illustrated novel. Thanks.
Also to reporter Aaron Scott for
that story. This is Radiolab.
Thanks for listening.