I think,
I think there's a lot of moments in
your life that you find yourself doing
something. Okay? There's anybody
in here. My name is Brittany.
I'd love to be able to talk with you
and you take that moment
and step back from it.
Are you here
and you realize come through to
us. What the fuck am I doing?
What just happened? Was this real? I
think that was one of those moments. Hey,
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and today on the podcast.
Okay,
a ghost story. Really. We're going to
do a ghost story at Halloween, Dude.
Well, you don't even know what, we're
just listen. All right, let's listen.
Okay. Okay. This one comes from
our producer Matt Kielty yet.
So I first heard the story from a buddy
of mine. Do, do, do, do, do who do?
His name is Dennis Conroe. Dennis. Andy.
Hey, what's up dude? That's producer,
Ania Mills. You guys are all buddies.
[inaudible] total buds. Anyways,
the story. All right, well, Dennis,
yes, it's about a lot of things,
but in particular our house. So
let's, let's start with the house.
When did you move back in? Uh, well,
let's see. I was probably, I don't know,
age 20. Dennis had been going to
college. Yep. By the way, what did you,
what did you study? Uh, creative
writing. Okay. But, uh, yeah,
like just cut and just kinda got bored
there. Kinda stopped going to class.
I think once white
parents realize that, uh,
they weren't very happy and I would
assume so. And so, uh, so yeah,
I was kind of uh, asked to come back home,
back to a town just outside Kansas
City, a little town called Grandview.
Did you grow up in this house? I did. I
did. And the house was fairly old. Yeah,
it was about 105 years old at
the time. Two Story White House.
Nice little porch awning over it.
Typical Farmhouse Style and see you,
you were at your parents' home in
your, in your old bedroom. Yup.
And my old childhood bedroom. Yeah.
So there was always a sense of like,
I need to get out of this house that's
holding me back somehow from things.
So we got a job,
worked a job and got laid off and one
year turned into two and then three,
then four, and then five. It was not, not
a great time to be there. In what way?
Just that I felt like I was still 16
he says he'd overhear his mom telling
people on the phone. Oh, well yeah,
he's never gonna move out. Is He?
And then she started circling
classifieds, jobs for typists,
creating press sales rep type setter. I
Dunno. I think everything in my whole,
my life,
however I mean for it not to sort
of moves at my own snail's pace
eventually. Well it was fairly old,
like 27 maybe. Actually he was,
he was 28 after eight years in this
house, Dennis gets a steady job,
finds this cheap apartment,
this ratty six plex apartment,
packing up his things. But right when he
said to move out to finally leave home,
my mom got really sick. Dennis,
his mom had been remission from
breast cancer for like nine years,
but that summer her doctors told her that
it had returned and had spread quite a
bit. So I said to her
like, uh, you know, do you,
do you want me to be here or do you
want me to go? And she was like,
well, you know, if this is my time, uh,
she wants to go knowing that her
kids can take care of themselves.
So Dennis moved out about five
months later. His mom died.
Yeah, she went pretty fast.
About about a month or
so after my mom died,
my dad found out he had stage
four prostate cancer and
he was really too sick to
take care of the house and just being
the guy by himself at that point.
Now Dennis pretty much had to come
home. I'd take care of him three,
four times a week. And as he got
worse, he had said to me like,
Hey,
let's try to find you a house to buy so
that I can teach you how to like do all
of the kind of stuff that
one has to do. You know,
that men know how to do things like change
out plumbing, all this kind of stuff.
And so we put an offer on a house,
but that fell through and before
they could find something else,
the cancer from his prostate spread
to his brain. And uh, you know,
the last week of his life,
he was really not there.
Hmm.
I can remember one day. Yeah. Like maybe,
maybe a week or so after he had died,
Dennis was walking through the empty
kitchen and uh, there was so much stuff,
there was so much stuff,
papers all over the place,
junk mail all over the kitchen
floor, down in the basement,
tools all over the place. You
know, I had this moment of yeah,
here are his tools and I add,
now I have them in my hands and you know,
I just remember picking up this claw
hammer and just crying because this is now
my hammer. This is now my house.
This is now my problem.
But few days pass and you start
thinking, okay, I can handle this. Yeah,
just gotta get in there, clean
it out, sell it clean and flip.
That was the plan. So at
the age of 32 moose back in,
there was all this junk in the basement,
put that stuff on the curb
sale after sale after sale.
And one day he finds himself standing in
the downstairs bathroom looking at the
nasty for tile. It was just horrible.
His dad had meant to replace it before
he died, but you know, couldn't finish.
And my thought was like, oh,
we'll just do this one bathroom.
So it looks pretty good to
sell. Problem was steady,
never showed them how
to do any of that stuff.
That's that point that
I was like, oh, youtube,
all the tile in one hand firmly.
And then your sermon towel.
Never went online. Learn how
to tile, do some plumbing,
any redid the and turned out pretty
good. It was kind of fun. Uh,
and then the next thing I knew I was
taking wallpaper off of the kitchen flats.
Gotta go hardwood floors, insulation
in the attic, glass block,
windows in the basement. And pretty
soon that turned into the whole house.
And how long does that take? Uh,
five years. Actually it was six.
Wow. And he says the whole time he was
doing this renovation at night, uh,
I would have these dreams where, mm.
My parents just kind of came through
the back door and it was just like,
oh, what are you doing here? Oh,
that's right. You're your dad.
And then I would turn my back and then
they would have somehow undone
all of the things that I did. Oh,
they had brought the house back to where?
What state it was in when
they were alive. Yeah. Huh.
And I probably had this dream, I'm not
kidding, like at least a hundred times.
Wow. Night after night after night.
We just kept going on and on and
ultimately kind of drove me crazy.
And so one day after yet another one of
these streams, Dennis is finally like,
all right, I'm selling it, puts it up in
the market, starts waiting for a buyer.
And then something strange happens. Well,
something kind of strange.
I had made this friend and she
came over for the first time,
like a date lady friend. Yeah. It was
a lady friend. You'd got on a date,
you'd taken her back to your house.
And so just giving her a tour,
showing her all the improvements until
she was in the kitchen right by the
basement door in the kitchen
when she was like, oh,
there's some kind of weird presence
here. And I was just like, ah, okay.
Well that was kind of a sign
that it was not going to last.
Fast forward a few years,
it didn't really think too much about
it until one day dentist is really there
is having an open house, no one shows.
So she was in the house by herself and
Dennis starts getting these text messages
from her like, dude,
your house is haunted.
Like I can hear people walking around.
And she texted that there was definitely
something weird going on right by the
basement door. Oh wait, that's the
same spot. I was like, ah, that's,
that's kind of weird. But then
here's the crazy thing, uh,
not too long after this, Dennis bumped
into an old friend of his and he's like,
Hey, funny thing, two different people,
two separate occasions had come over to
the house and they said they felt this
weird presence and she was like, wait,
right by the basement door, get out.
Yeah. I was like, okay. So I've got
Heather, I've got Stacy, I've got Carla,
all three who say they
feel this weird presence.
Would you consider yourself a bit
of a skeptic about such things?
I would say so. Rationally. I'm
just, I'm just going to say no.
So you don't believe in ghosts? No.
All right. What happened next? Well,
this also happened to be right at
the time that I sold the house,
Dennis had finally put some pen
to paper, signed a contract,
packed up all stuff. And so Carla,
the girl that first felt this thing,
the girl he went on a day with me, they
stayed friends, uh, said to me like,
you know, I'm really
curious about this. Uh,
would you mind if I call like these ghost
people to come and like check out this
place? I was like, well
sure. I don't care. Yeah.
It's like why not? I mean,
so very shortly in a few minutes
actually we are bringing paranormal
investigators to find out what's
in the basement. You know,
I'm just kinda walking through the house.
I think I got this on tape of just
me walking through the house. Like,
well yeah, this is
probably a waste of time,
but I'm still kind of curious about it
Friday night. What else you got to do?
Right. It's a Friday night, mid November,
around six o'clock I can see
some cars parking on the street.
So I go downstairs,
people start filing in maybe 10
people all have different specialties.
Larry's our tech guy bought for
techies, two sets of clairvoyants.
Sean tells the psychic she's very gifted.
Who are all these people to just say
your name. My name is Brittany. Well,
they're part of the Kansas City paranormal
investigators club or some kind of
thing.
And pretty much right off the bat when
you guys came in and you were saying like
you could talk to, but
when we first got here,
we both saw a woman
looking out the window.
She looked like I didn't really see
what she looked like. She had hair,
it was like gray and she was wearing
one of those weird old tiny dresses.
Dennis was like whatever.
They set up cameras in the basement
and in the kitchen and the clairvoyants
decided they wanted to try to talk to
this woman or maybe any other spirit in
the house. And so Brittany
even explain to you what we do,
who was like the ringleader of the night.
She sort of explained how she does
things, you know, she was like,
the best way that she could get them
to talk to to to them was through a
flashlights, Huh? Yes. So what they
do is they take a few flashlights,
turn them on,
and then they unscrew the tops of them
just enough so that they turn off and
then they just kind of set the flashlights
that are now off in the room by
themselves.
And the idea is that if the ghost
or the spirit wants to communicate,
they can just sort of touch the top of
one in the flashlights with their gusty
finger and that'll turn it back on.
I'm just like, okay.
So she took three flashlights and we all
sat in this dark room in a circle and a
Brittany sets the flashlights in the
middle of the circle by themselves.
No one's touching them. And
she says, my name is Brittany.
I love to be able to talk with you.
Can you turn one of those lights on?
And we sit there and you
sit there, are you here?
Then all of a sudden this light
whoa kind of barely blinks on.
And then she said, okay,
thank you. Please turn it off.
And then it goes off. What we can do
with these lights here is if I can ask,
and then she says, we have three lights
here. The one you just turned on,
we'll call. Yes, please turn on
one more. And that will be, no,
you could do that for us.
That will be wonderful.
And then a second light comes on. No Way.
He likes scanning the room,
like looking for somebody who has like
a little switch or something. Yeah.
But like we didn't pay these people
so they have no reason to fake this I
suppose. But you know, I just
keep thinking, well, you know,
the counselors really close to the
train tracks and maybe maybe the train
vibrations of the train.
Yeah, yeah, that makes sense.
But
all of a sudden they were like,
can you hear that
footsteps? Sounds like that's okay mom.
Okay.
And they're going towards
the kitchen and I could hear
dishes rattling on the
countertop in the kitchen.
No one's in the kitchen.
If you're in the kitchen right now,
can you turn one of these lights on?
And so they sit and stare
at these three flashlights
and then
I didn't miss, remember leaving the room.
What happened?
Um, well, uh, actually everyone,
everyone in that room, um,
died except for Dennis.
Yeah.
I have no idea why I even
invited you into this building.
They did not die. What happened to them?
Actually, they're fine.
It turns out that, uh,
there was a guy downstairs
in the basement,
one of the techies walking around pitch
black down there and he just like bangs
his head into like an air duct and the
sound just reverberated throughout the
whole house. Scared him a little bit.
It was very Blair witchy. Yeah. Anyhow,
the techies decide that they want to get
the three psychics down in the basement
by themselves. And so, you know,
these three lumen go down in
the basement by themselves.
We kind of hear them downstairs talking,
but we don't really know what's going on.
Was interesting. Yeah.
They come back upstairs
and they said, uh, the girl
was downstairs with the,
she was definitely down there.
The old woman that they first saw when
they got to the house and they said that
she was standing down in the basement
next to where the old furnace used to be.
And they told Dennis that she said that
she'd lived here for a long time and
Dennis was like, wait a second. He knew
that back in the thirties or something,
a woman had lived in this house
who was kind of not all there,
and one day she had gone down into the
basement and thought she was picking
Weiss off of chickens and throwing
them into this big furnace that was
downstairs in the basement at the time.
She got a little too close
to the furnace story, goes,
caught herself on fire and then
died there I guess in the basement.
Oh.
But then there was another man
downstairs. He showed himself to me,
but he won't talk and just completely
disappeared. What did he look like?
He was bald. He was about Rick
site, but it wasn't right.
Um, yeah,
a lot like that. Not a lot,
but similar. Definitely.
If I were to show you
a picture of my father,
would you have any sense of this
was him? If I saw a picture of him?
Yeah.
Dennis goes and gets his photo of his dad
that he had that was leftover from his
memorial service.
Yep. That's man I saw. Really? Wow.
That's just, just a second. Like here,
she's very hesitant at the beginning.
Just like, well, you know,
jump in here really quick and just tell
you that this was actually the first
time that Dennis had ever listened
to this tape. Really? Yeah.
And the reason is because for a long
time he didn't want to listen to it. Why?
Well,
I think part of it had to do with this
moment because this was the point where
my skepticism kind of kicked off and part
of it had to do with what happens next
that's coming up when we return.
This is Chad [inaudible] calling you
from my living room and Cincinnati, Ohio.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology and the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org thanks.
This is Julia calling from
San Francisco, California.
Radiolab is supported by
gunpowder and sky's new film.
Hearts beat loud starring Nick
Offerman and Kiersey Clemons,
heartbeat loud tells the story of a
father and daughter songwriting duo that
become an overnight success selected
as the closing night film at the 2018
Sundance film festival. And
costarring. Ted Dancing,
Sasha Lane life Tanner, Toni, Collette,
heartbeat loud opens in select
cities starting June 8th
okay.
Radiolab is supported by swell,
investing and impact investing platform.
What if you could invest in our planet
while also investing in your financial
future? Think about that. Our
resources are diminishing.
Our population is growing.
Companies solving today's biggest
challenges will beat tomorrow's leaders.
Swell helps you invest in high growth
companies working towards clean water,
renewable energy, and green technology.
It's a market opportunity
you can feel good about.
Get a $50 bonus when you
open your account at swell.
investing.com/radiolab
from WM YC studios comes the untold
story of one of the most aspirational and
delusional teams in sports history.
We knew that we could
beat anybody in the world.
I'm doing everything I should be doing
and it's still not working sucks.
What do you guys complain about?
You guys are the ones that fricking
cause this whole thing. American fiasco.
One teams.
Insane journey to the 1998 World Cup
hasty by mate Roger Bennett of men in
Blazers available wherever
you get your podcasts.
A bad world cup is better than
they woke up. You Bet your ass.
This is radio lab.
Let's get back to Matt Kielty's ghost
story and we're pick up with our main guy,
Dennis Conroe,
having just heard from the ghost hunters
that they encountered a spirit in the
basement of his home who looks
remarkably like his dead father.
Yeah, that's man. I saw you.
Yep. So He's here. He's here.
Can we, can we try to talk to him?
We can try to talk to him at the
basements or here or all over.
He went upstairs. Not
In the basement anymore.
Can we go upstairs and
just talk to him? Yeah.
So no,
I hadn't really told them a whole lot
about what the different rooms in the
house were, but they led me
upstairs to what was his room
and to the corner of the
room where his bed was.
And they had no idea that that
used to be, they had no idea. And
I said to them, okay, well if he's
going to talk, he'll just talk to me.
[inaudible] are you here?
Did you turn on a lights?
If you are. Thank you.
Thank you ma'am. Uh,
we're gonna call that yes.
If you can turn that one off
now and turn on the no light.
Any other light?
I need to know that you're here.
Thanks God.
Do you want us to leave? Um, Dad, what?
Do you like these people to
leave and just talk to me?
Yes. Okay.
Uh, Damn. I'd want to know,
are you in a good spot? Are you okay?
Are you okay? Are you okay with that?
Yes. All right, good.
I'm glad to hear that.
Okay. Everything off.
Think so off. Almost. Almost.
All right, thanks. Yep.
And it asks you is, you
know, is mark here too?
This mom here too and okay.
The other of the three
flashlights lights up, huh?
Yes, she is.
Oh,
she goes here and I miss you.
I have so many questions for you.
I can't ask them all and
just yes or no questions.
But I said, well,
have you been able to see the
things that I've done to the house?
And both of the lights
lit up very brightly. Yes.
And then, so I've lived
here for six years.
Three of things, you know, I said, what
do you think? Are you happy with this?
Are you happy with the things
I've done with the house?
And they both lit up very brightly. Yes.
And, uh, I said, are you proud of me?
Are you proud of what I've done?
It's very funny. Yes.
So in a few days, uh,
I would probably never stepped foot in
this house and I don't want you to like
stay here and feel like
you belong here to free.
Can you look blue? Cool. This house
willing to fight.
[inaudible] yeah.
I'm going to brief you guys
that you hadn't haunting
my dreams on this house.
I know it's very important
to you. Important to me.
This is the time we leave.
Okay.
Yeah.
[inaudible] so that's where it ends.
Yeah. Uh,
that's how I recall it
being exactly like that.
And yeah, I kind of teared up and pen.
Um,
and keep in mind that this was the first
time that Dennis had heard this tape
and so we played it back to him cause
we just wanted to see like how he
remembered that experience.
Yeah. I guess part of, part of,
part of my fear of listening to it was
that it would change it and that it would
be a different experience.
It would be a little more hokey and it
would be a little more unclear what was
happening. But, uh, listen
to it again. I, you know,
it was as I recalled it being [inaudible]
so in the end, does he believe he was
actually talking to his dead parents?
Well, um, no, no. Uh, I,
I ended up actually calling this guy
who explained to me how this whole
flashlight thing works and that there is
a perfectly non paranormal explanation
as to what's going on with the flashlight.
It almost feels bad manners at this
point to have a practice later.
But I'm very curious to hear it.
Sure. Well, what's going on is, um,
you turn the flashlight on. Yeah.
And when you turn the flashlight on,
the bulb gets really hot, right?
And then you take the top
of the flashlight and you
unscrew it just like enough
that the flashlight flickers off.
So the flashlights off and um,
the bulb, it got really hot.
So the inside of the flashlight also
got really hot and there's this little
piece of plastic inside the flashlight.
And when it got hot, it expanded.
And now as the flat sends the
flashlights off, that piece of plastic,
it starts to cool down and starts
to contract. And when it contracts,
it pushes these two tiny
bits of metal together.
These two little bits of metal come
into contact and that's your circuit.
So the circuit opens the light bulb,
it goes back on, then it warms again,
and then it gets hot. Yeah. And
so the little piece of plastic,
it starts to expand. It
pushes the two pieces apart.
People chose this flashlight because
it had that particular property. Yeah.
Do you think it's like a con or
something? No, I don't think so. No,
I don't think so. I mean, I even
talked to Dennis about this. He's like,
I think they're just trying to make sense
of, of randomness. I mean they don't,
I don't think they necessarily know
that this flashlight does this thing and
therefore they can manipulate people.
Here's why I don't think it's a con
because in this case it's such a,
it's such a strange coincidence that
whenever he wants his mom and dad,
his ghostly mother and father to approve
of him and congratulate him and honor
him with a yes. I mean it's
random. He could get to know,
but he gets a yes. It's just chance.
And you told Dennis all this?
Yeah, I told Dennis, cause you told me
to tell Dennis [inaudible] I forced him.
Okay. So when you told him, what
did he say? Um, well, on one level,
like it, it didn't phase him. Dennis
basically said like, look, I know,
I know that the way that the world
works is the way the world works.
People don't come back from the dead.
People don't talk to you through
flashlights. But he also said that like,
he's not gonna let go of that experience.
He wants to have it both ways. I guess.
So I guess I guess I want to have both.
Yes. This didn't happen and yes, this
absolutely happened. I understand that.
Yeah. Because even if you are
the world's biggest skeptic,
if you don't believe in ghosts,
like there really aren't that many ways
to talk about these sorts of things,
these sorts of things that we
all feel, you know, guilt for,
for the things that we've done in
our past. The loss of those who,
who we've loved,
that like ghost stories kind of seem
to stick around because they are an
experience. I'll be at like
a metaphorical experience,
but an experience that lets us talk about
these things that we can't adequately
talk about. Um, you know, that
feeling of, of being haunted.
[inaudible]
anticipate. Did he eventually sell
the house? Move out? Yeah. Yeah.
Sold the house, moved out. No more
dreams of his parents haunting in.
Oh,
well it's been odd in the time that I've
sold the house now I thought the dreams
would stop and now the dreams are that
I am the one haunting the house of the
new people where I will just walk in.
Really? Yeah. And just be like, Hey,
I'm here. That, yeah. And Are you like
going around repairing things? Nope.
I'm just like being somewhat
shocked at what they've done to it.
It's like, it never stops, you know?
Thanks Matt. No problem. Matt. Guilty.
And, uh, if you want to
know a little bit more,
a little more detailed
about the flashlight trick,
it's not really a trick
flashlight phenomenon. Uh,
you can check it out on our
website, radiolab.org, uh,
Mexico posts there that
explains it in greater detail.
And also you can see some pictures
of Dennis's house and, uh,
yeah, that's all we can say at this
holiday moment. Indeed. Set their names.
I guess I'm Jad Abumrad Hi, I'm
Robert Krulwich. Thanks for listening.