You are listening to radio
lab radio from W N y.
S. C. E. Yup. Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich Radiolab.
Today we have a mystery
that is vanishingly tiny,
shockingly hot and manages to
combine submarines, Keanu Reeves,
red lobster and game of Thrones.
And of course our producer Molly Webster
and many members of your family. Hello.
Hello? Hello? Nope.
Where are the children?
So we all know you want to begin in
the beautiful state of South Carolina,
South Carolina. The time on appear. Yeah.
Is My radio gear waterproof?
No, on a dock. Oh, okay.
So we're going to walk down to the donkey,
which is just like this place where
they all put boats in the water
and that's where we always [inaudible].
I'm going to explain why dockets. Okay.
My parents recently moved to this marshy,
swampy area on near the
intracoastal waterway,
which is like a connecting
series of salty channels.
And we grew up in Ohio and so this is
like a totally different landscape than
what we grew up in. Okay.
And those little people would be
my nieces and nephews, my bike,
Sylvie can ride it. You
that America is there.
My children getting along and compromise.
That would be Chrissy Webster and one
of my sisters and we sound a lot alike
anyway, so, okay, so this is
the story. The story is, um,
so when my parents first moved there,
I remember going out on the docks with
my dad and we were sort of looking at the
beautiful marsh, right.
And there was this really weird
sound like coming off the water.
E Y D I recently took my nieces and
nephew out to see if they could hear it.
Okay. So we're not going to move
and we're not going to squeak. Yeah.
Can we talk? We're not gonna talk. Oh,
okay. So we leaned down off the dock.
Ready? Now we're going
to see if we can hear it.
Huh?
Oh my gosh. I hear some crackles.
That crackling sound. Yeah. What is that?
That was the question.
It sounds like rice crispy.
Most of the scientists you talk to say
it sounds like bacon frying or twigs
crackling in a fire. Maybe have
a large Perrier factory just yet.
I would say that except there's no
bubbles popping like on the water. Oh,
so it's not a gaseous emission.
It's a clickety clack.
Let me just play you a better
recording. Yeah. Pull it up. Wait,
do I have to put it
through the producer PC?
Uh,
this is actually an underwater
recording. Oh my God.
Oh
Gosh. In a teeny world. That would
be like the 4th of July. Yeah. Wow.
That's big. It's bigger than bigger
than Bacon and Bacon. I know.
It depends on how much
bacon you're frying.
So what, sorry, what is this sound?
What is it? This sound is, um,
a very tiny [inaudible]. Let
me just back it up a second.
Well, th the story started in the
forties. That's Michelle verse Laos,
professor of Physical Acoustics and
medical acoustics at the University of
Toronto in the metals.
Basically what he said is World War II
is the first war where we're like really
using submarines and [inaudible]
sonar.
And so you've got all of theseU s navy
submarines down deep in the ocean and t
hey're like listening out for the enemy.
But what happens is all they hear
is this like crazy crackling sound,
the sound levels that were measured.
So, so this lab, this sounds very,
very intense.
He says in some instances it was
actually interfering with the sonar
[inaudible].
That was a a bit of a problem.
Yeah. So I found it.
I found a classified document that was
declassified right after the war where
the navy, they actually hired this,
they actually hired this scientist,
this guy named Martin Johnson.
This is in cal,
I believe it was in San Diego.
They hired this guy to figure
out what is the sound like?
What is the sound we're hearing
like all over the ocean.
What is it already jazz like, just
tell me what the damn sound is. Yes.
Well it turns out I don't
want to go too fast here.
It was noted in those years that
that sound originated from the ship.
It was a shrimp. Oh yeah.
The shrimp is called the snapping
shrimp or a pistol. Shrimp.
Ooh, I like that. Yes.
And interestingly,
I found these like old navy recordings
rolled about one foot in length that they
would give to the navy guys where they
had to learn the sounds they were hearing
coming in through the ship and through
the sonar in your own work with the
expendable radio sono bully, you
will probably hear in many songs.
Although then the submarine song,
it was like, this is the
sound of [inaudible],
nothing different. It produces
a harsh clicking noise.
And I was like, okay, shrimp
sonar. Cool. I get it.
Thought maybe it would end there.
And then I found what felt
to me to be a crazy article,
which was this newspaper clipping from
1946 basically says shrimp's help win the
war.
And it's about how the American navy
admitted that one of their tactical things
during like World War II was that they
would hide their submarines in the beds
of these shrimp. So like the Japanese
submarines couldn't detect our ships.
Oh my goodness. It was like a
marine in visibility cloak. Yes.
And according to Michelle,
the u s would also put speakers
on the hall of the ships
too, to simulate snapping
what it was. Sound Cammo. Yeah, see,
wait, wait, wait, wait. Are these trims?
Are they like normal normal
shrimp cocktail type shrimp?
Well, there are about five
centimeters. Two inches,
so like smaller than a
shrimp. I might eat. Well,
it depends what sort of shrimp
you eat. I don't, I don't know.
Whatever red lobster's. There's no
wait a second. If they're that small,
how are they making that sound? That
is an excellent question. Wait, where
do you think the sound comes from?
I'm thinking it's this room
be are eating their food
in the noises. Their little
key. Ooh. Shrimpy tea.
I think it, for me, I think it
comes from their like snappy clot.
Then you
and that's what you would think, right?
Like especially if you look
at these things up close,
they have two front claws and the
claws aren't the same on each side.
That's Nancy Knowlton. I'm marine
biologists snapping shrimp expert.
There's that claw that's specialized for
pinching and that claws tiny and a claw
that specialized for snapping. And
that claw is like exponentially bigger.
It's like 10 times, 20
maybe three times bigger.
It's quite a bit bigger.
And so they use it to defend themselves
against potential predators or
competitors. And they're very territorial.
She's as in one tramp
runs into another shrimp.
They can get into these prolonged snapping
matches where they snap at each other
to show me, me, me, me,
me is bigger and stronger.
[inaudible] okay, fine.
And they can pretty much judge how
big they are by the power of the snap,
all of which is to say, my
niece, Sophie's guests. Okay.
Because for there like
snappy clot, then he's like,
yeah, of course.
It's like the two sides of the
cloth just like snapping together.
Just like you snap your fingers
like this, just a snap, snap.
But that turns out not
to be true. So not true.
Two things were wrong
basically with a picture.
I gotta know if you've ever tried to clap
your hands in the swimming pool under
water,
but it's very difficult. Yeah.
You don't feel very smart
when you make difficult work.
There's not a lot of sand.
And that is because there's a lubrication
layer of water in between that
prevents a direct mechanical contact or
yes,
there's this lubricating layer between
the two claw haves and it makes snapping
hard. And the second problem was that
the sound just seemed way too loud.
Like when they measured the
decibel level of a single snap,
it's about 220 desi bells of sound
that that can be produced by,
by a single snap.
To put that in context, that
is basically equivalent to
[inaudible]
jet plane from just one snap.
But it's very impulsive.
So in a very, very short
duration, it's still,
it's like one of the loudest
sounds in the ocean. So was like
probably more than snapping going
on here. Yeah. So, so, okay,
so it was 1999 Yup. The new high speed
camera in our lab. And so they're like,
okay,
we're gonna point this camera at the
shrimp and see what happens when this
shrimp snaps its claw.
So they take the little shrimps and
they glue screws on their butts,
glue screws on their button and they
screw them into tiny platforms in like a
little aquarium so that they were fixed
in space and that that was important
because a happens in like a microsecond
and they need to keep it still so the
camera can just focus right on
the claw and to do the experiment,
what we needed to do was to tickle
them a little bit with the paintbrush.
You tickled them with a
paintbrush? Yeah, exactly.
Then they cock their clothes and then
they snap and then it fires and the camera
captures the entire thing with like
thousands of frames per second.
And did they see anything? They did
see something or what? What? How?
What is it when they looked
at the footage of the moment,
just after it snaps in super slow Mo,
you saw a very blurry object
in front of the shrimp.
What? Blurry Ha. It was just
like [inaudible] blurry,
something that was blood blurry.
I mean it turned out that we
were sort of out of focus.
So they refocus the camera. They do
the same thing. They tickle the shrimp,
the claws snaps. And they see
that when the closs snaps, ah,
they see this like bubble in front of the
shrimp claw and it turns out that it's
that bubble that's causing the
noise and so much undersea turmoil.
The bubble is at the
root of everything. Okay.
And with the high speed camera they were
sort of able to see how it all breaks
down and it sort of unfolds
like this [inaudible]
what actually happens
when this club closes?
Is that the water that's
in between these clothes,
can we stop at high speed? The typical
speed can be up to 60 miles per hour.
Like as fast as a car goes. Oh yes. Yes.
So this jet of water shoots
out like 60 miles per hour.
And what happens is like
behind the jet is that Ah,
this like empty spaces created like a
little void in the ocean and all the water
molecules in that space. Cause they're
like, Ooh, look at all this room.
They start to expand outwards
and essentially they just
become like a little gas
bubble. They actually change
from liquid to gas. Yeah,
they actually go from like liquid is
like tightly packed molecules and then as
they spread out they become like gaseous
and they create this like little gas
bubble pocket in the middle of a huge
ocean.
And as they have all the space they like
it bigger and bigger and bigger until
the ocean is like nope. Microseconds.
Later the ocean start pushing back in
on this bubble and the all the little,
little uh, air molecules in the, in,
in this bubble have nowhere to go and
they're getting forced closer and closer
together. And so they really
want to get away from each other,
all those air molecules.
But you're pushing them together really
hard and since they can't get away from
each other, like the energy
builds up super, super cute.
She had the pressure rises
and the temperature rises
really rises 5,000 degrees.
The surface of the sun
is also 5,000 degrees
and the gas that's inside
the bubble turns to plasma
and that plasma and mix very
short, intense flash of light
as the, the bubble implodes.
And then like a microsecond later
it generates the shop
great.
And that shockwave will
basically kill or stun any,
uh, prayed at this nearby.
Somebody from the College of exaggeration
graduated this particular explanation
because teeny Google that animal,
whether the blood was bubble as hot
as the sun, then I'll think, oh yeah.
Okay.
Fairly crazy.
But it's amazing how evolution has
created this kind of sonic weapon.
So basically yes
strips,
they're like super awesome cause things
call that generate huge bubbles of heat
and it's like Gomez a trip
because it's a black belt. Wow.
So it's spitting out light
and hot, hot hot temperatures.
Yeah. Does that mean that God, the
sun thing is crazy? That's crazy.
I feel like it should be like
a marvel character modeling.
Yeah. Cause if you scaled this up,
the bubble would be the size
of a basketball in human scale.
What could I do with the
basketball of Sun, heat and light?
I could rule the world with
that. I'll be having that cat.
Hey, hey that last piece of
cake is mine. That was low.
When my sister is hanging
off the dock, she asked like,
can we use this stuff power
like the world or something? No.
The answer was no,
but the same physical processes that are
involved in the shrimp bubbles. Right.
So like the temperature and the
heat that bubbles can create.
Researchers became really excited about.
Is there a way to harness
this bubble power?
Yeah. There's also a Hollywood
movie. I think I did it.
Is it stable on the powerful of bubbles
with Keanu Reeves? I believe. Really?
Really? Yes. Yes.
There is enough energy in this glass of
water to power the city of Chicago for
weeks. They went too far. Oh.
[inaudible] fly boom.
Taken with a weapon with a
weapon. Possibilities. Yeah.
My nephew got excited about this
too. My name is Oliver. Huh.
But I hate to tell you,
I don't think there are any mean
you can't like make a bigger claw.
Put It on a sub. Nope. Sorry guys.
[inaudible] oh, there is
this one thing where uh,
researchers are thinking about using
bubbles and this goes beyond the shrimp
bubbles in a way that could save lives.
Okay.
My name is Joseph Packard. I'm
calling from Columbia, South Carolina.
Radiolab is supported in part by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information about
sloane@wwwdotsloan.org
this is Radiolab.
And now we're going to go back
to the story from Molly Webster.
So you were saying people here are
trying to use bubble power to save lives.
Yeah, so when I was talking to
Michelle verse Laos Applications,
we're talking on the phone and he
explains all the crazy bubbly stuff and
somehow like in the middle of the
conversation, he just said, um,
if you think the shrimp bubbles are cool,
everything we know about
the shrimp bubbles like can
also be like adapted to use
bubbles in the body. Oh.
And I was like, Whoa, wait,
but bubbles in the body. Isn't that, isn't
that an embolism? Loa? Yeah, totally.
I had the same thought,
like when divers get the Benz or when
they like tap bubbles out of ivy lines and
stuff. But these are very, very small
bubbles, smaller than red blood cells.
According to verse Laos,
they're like one 20th the size of human
hair and they are completely harmless.
And he told me about how uh, in Toronto,
and they actually just did this
for the first time in November. Uh,
on a patient they're using bubbles to
get across the blood brain barrier.
What is, what exactly is the
brain blood brain barrier?
Is it cells or is it tissue? Super,
super tightly packed cells.
It sort of sits between the
bloodstream and the brain.
It's like this protective wall and it
keeps out all of the nasty stuff so it
keeps out any like a bacteria or viruses
that would be in your bloodstream,
can't get past the wall
to get into your brain.
I kind of keep thinking of it as like,
I'm never actually watched game of Thrones
except for like one episode and in it
there was this giant wall
to protect civilization from
sort of all the bad things,
the wild things and it was made
of ice and it went up forever.
That kind of feel like that wall in game
of Thrones is like the barrier between
the rest of the body. And the brain.
But you said it's there
to protect the brain.
So why would you want to
punch a hole in it? Well,
you can imagine that if somebody has
a brain tumor and we want to deliver
chemicals in there that we
think can help fight the tumor,
those chemicals, the brain
does not want in there.
So the blood brain barrier can create
problems. According to Todd main prize,
I'm in neurosurgeon at Sunnybrook.
He's part of the team in Toronto
that's using this new bubble technique.
And here's how it works. Wow. Okay.
So say you've got a tumor on
the right side of your brain,
right above your ears.
So main prize and his team will stick
you in a chair and then they'll put a
helmet on you. Special Helmet.
This helmet has 1024
ultrasound transducers
and we
aim the thousand 24 all to the same spot,
right on the spot at the wall where
the tumor sits just on the other side,
just out of reach. Okay,
so that all the ultrasound waves kind
of [inaudible] I guess at that one area.
And then we inject the bubbles.
How many bubbles are in a dose?
Um, like hundreds of thousands.
So they just put an IV in your arm and
the bubbles go in and they'll go like
into your arm, like over your shoulder,
into your heart, to your lungs,
back to your heart. Eventually some of
them will get up to the brain. You know,
it takes approximately 28 seconds from
the time when you inject the bubble into
an arm vein to by the time they start
going into her brain and eventually some
of those bubbles get up to
the blood brain barrier,
that wall to the spot where that laser
beam is focused, that specific spot,
that tumor sitting on the other
side up. And when they cross paths,
would that be
ultrasound waves causes the micro
bubbles to oscillate in size.
They'll go big and small. Big and small,
big smile, big smile, big smile,
big smile. Oscillate inside.
I think of it as like a, uh,
like a bubble dance party.
So at this really specific
part in the brain,
and it can be smaller than like one
millimeter by one millimeter square.
All these bubbles are dancing. And
what that does is it causes the wall,
that specific spot almost loosen.
And so like a little like a window of
space or a little hole is created in that
wall. And if you happen to have
chemotherapy in your blood,
which you will because we'll
give it to you ahead of time,
the minute that hole is open. Okay.
The idea is the chemotherapy in your
bloodstream would be able to just sort of
flow through that opening and get
straight to that brain tumor tissue.
So they're using sound to turn the bubbles
into little dancing drill bits. Yeah.
And drill through them.
Yeah. Wow. Now the body's
a living organism. So,
uh, over the next six to 12 hours,
they will close those gaps.
Transient meaning it heals
itself in about six to 12 hours.
And you're saying they tried
this on someone already?
Yeah, last November and
they think it went well.
One of the things these researchers
said was once you're able to open these
passageways to the brain, um, it's
not just chemo that can get in there,
but like suddenly any type of drug
you might want to send through can get
through.
And we've just never had access
to the brain before in that way.
And there's this question of like, how
will drugs interact with the brain?
We kind of don't know. They've,
they've never been there before.
It's like a whole new frontier.
You think shrimp and time is done.
So I mean,
basically all boils down to the same
sort of physics of bubbles that we have
learned from the shrimp and that
we can apply to many other, uh,
applications.
Fun. It's dinner time.
We're gonna put it on the radio so you'll
hear it. The people that like shrimp.
What do people don't like?
Shrimp Nail. Just skip it.
I can't believe Molly's putting this
on the radio. I make no promises.
This has gone on the radio. Oh, Yay.
Molly Webster. This piece was produced
by Molly and Annie Mcewen
with help from our guests.
Sound designer Jeremy Bloom.
Special thanks to Calavo James Byrd,
Lawrence crumb, and Elliot, Sophie Oliver
and Christie, all of them. [inaudible]
next up, a story from our
producer, Simon Adler, who, uh,
who got interested in bubbles
after Molly found her shrimp piece,
got interested in bubbles and he managed
to find a guy named Dave Stein who has
taken bubbling to a whole new level.
It's a bigger bubble. Better,
I think trying to make things
bigger as a function of growing up.
I don't know,
I always thought that this was kind of
inherent in the human psyche is to want
to do certain things bigger and
better. And so, well, may we,
we might even make this
a Stein's law. Okay.
Steins Stein's law. Law
of bubble of bubbling.
No Stein's law of size is kind
of off the top of my head here.
But for any given object,
there is a larger size such that the
nature of the object is transformed in,
in simple English. What would that mean?
That as something gets
bigger it gets what? Okay.
Jake in Jupiter. Okay. Gaseous
planets. Okay. All right.
If you make Jupiter bigger
and bigger, bigger and bigger,
there is a size at
which it becomes a star.
Hagen, it ignites, it becomes a Sun.
It transcends what it was.
Then can a bubble get so big that
it's no longer even a bubble?
Well, before the invention
of the bubble thing,
1984 bubbles,
we always thought of as being
relatively small and relatively round,
but as soon as you get
up to a certain size,
say five foot diameter
kind of in that range, uh,
now a sudden suddenly they're not round
anymore and they don't pop in the same
way. People who would think of bubbles
popping instantaneously because they're
thinking of the little round
bubbles from the dime store.
And what really happens in very large
bubbles like the ones I and my friends
make, the bubble doesn't
pop instantaneously.
It gets punctured at a certain point
and then it rips open like a zipper and
there's a sound to it. It kind of goes
like that. So it's not
[inaudible] from one end of
this long bubble to the other.
Can we back up to tell me the
story of how you like why,
who were you in 1984 when you're like,
I'm going to make this bubble thing?
What, what, what, what
motivated all of this?
Well, what motivated all of this
was I was an architect at the time.
I was working for hardy Holzman Pfeiffer,
a very fashionable firmed out [inaudible]
and he says he spent his days designing
these really intricate buildings where
like glass staircases
meet the stonework of the building at a
45 degree angle and the roof is going up
at another angle, all has to
work down to the 16th of an inch.
Who wasn't very happy
at it actually. In fact,
I used to worry about
structural collapse. Okay?
He says he'd be walking down
the streets of Manhattan,
imagining some building he
was building in his mind,
say the a addition to the
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts.
He's imagining this building and then
all of a sudden his mind would shift to
worry about that building
collapsing. And he says,
this just kept happening
with every project.
All these buildings kept just
crashing into the ground. Like,
did this keep you up at night? Did
you wake up? Yeah, I felt I had to.
I felt that as a re architect,
it's my responsibility to imagine
all the possible disaster.
He says it became this not so
healthy occupational obsession and y.
W. Y. Alright. That's a good
question. Let me tell you something.
I'm probably getting some
of these details wrong, but
my grandfather Clarence bulky,
was a metallurgist who had a,
something to do with building
the atomic bomb and so did my
uncle. And um,
my mother was quite traumatized by being
a daughter of the bomb, so to speak.
And it says it became part of the family
legacy and maybe warmed its way into
his psyche and poisoned his work. Well,
that's just the way I
registered it. I'm just,
what I'm trying to basically trying to
say was that I was not really happy as an
architect. Anyway, that summer,
1984 my little daughter Kayla,
who was one and a half saw a man blowing
bubbles with one of those little dime
store wands and she was just transfixed.
She was transported to another
realm. She had a lot like any kid.
And so from that point on we
were always blowing bubbles,
all kinds of small bubbles, medium
ones, large ones. Pretty quick.
He started to wonder, how can we make
these bubbles bigger? And we used to,
you know, we cut out the ends of the
coffee cans, dipped one end in the soap,
blew through the other,
got maybe a bubble that might
be a foot foot in diameter,
tried getting a coat hanger
and bending it into a circle,
dipping that into a frying pan full of
soap. With that you can make a bubble,
may be a two foot or something.
And is your daughter getting more and
more excited as the bubbles get bigger?
Is this about you? She was getting
kind of bored with it actually.
Dave started to get a little
upset. Yes, that's definitely true.
And I was thinking, you know, this
is an interesting design problem,
maximizing the size of bubbles
and know how you go about that.
Initially his thought was,
and this is kind of everyone's thought
when they start thinking about this,
you just need a bigger circle, a bigger
hoop through which to blow the bubble.
It's like a hula hoop with a handle on
it and you would need a a little one of
those little plastic swimming
pools full of bubbles, soap,
which starts to seem kind of like a
lot of, so from a design perspective,
like how do you scale that up?
You can't just keep making the hoop and
bucket bigger. Like that seems crazy.
So at that point I was sort of stuck,
but whatever he was going on with
his life designing buildings.
But then he says one day in the summer
of 1984 I was lying in bed one morning.
I can still remember the the
pattern of cracks in the ceiling.
The idea hit him like a ton
of bubble shaped bricks.
Why not have a collapsible hoop?
I sort of instantly saw
this thing in my mind,
which was what we now know as
the bubble, the bubble thing,
and so Dave leaps out of bed
heads to the hardware store,
buys his stuff and I bought the Gel and
the chain and the fascinating stories.
Home starts assembling the device
where you in your kitchen where,
where were you when you were doing
well you don't do this indoors.
Ultimately he stepped outside and what
he had in his hand was really nothing
more than like a stick with a loop of
chain attached to it and one end of the
loop you could kind of slide up and down
on the stick so that you could expand
and collapse the loop. That's
the beauty of this design.
To have that control and be able to
close any weight back in the backyard.
I closed the loop so it was just
like a cord, like a straight cord.
I dunked it in the bucket of soap.
I raised it up, I open the loop
right away. There's huge
bubbly
starts coming out, tube stretches
for seven, eight feet. He's not sure,
but at a certain point that
closes the loop to pinch it off.
Now it's a free floating bubble
and it's sailing away over the,
over the house top and through the farm.
Suddenly there's this gigantic
bubbles floating away,
the biggest bubble ever blown,
I believe since it was somewhere between
the size of a refrigerator in a car
iridescent and wobbly and
then suddenly it popped.
What did you feel in that moment
where you were you, Dr Frankenstein,
who had just let this monster
out into the world who I had,
I got this cold thrill
going down my spine.
I'll never forget that. And as he sent
more and more of these into the air,
pretty soon people started arriving
in their cars and trucks.
Everybody was totally astonished and um,
I thought this might be my ticket
architecture.
So Dave was able to patent the bubble
thing and made enough money to get out of
architecture.
And in the process he transformed bubble
blowing from a thing that just like
kids do to this, I don't know,
kind of sport where you
have like bubble athletes.
My Name's Gary preroll.
Matt and Megan Park,
Rick Findlay, all over the world in
Mexico, they call me [inaudible] hall.
I currently am the a champion,
the heavyweight, the big boy.
People are blowing like
really big bubbles.
You could picture a say a two 18 wheelers,
a stacked on top of one another.
That's about how big the bubble was.
That's a slight exaggeration. But anyways,
there are debates going on
about what kind of soap to use,
which is the best polymer to add to that
soap and what kind of fabric to use for
the loop. But despite
all this experimentation,
pretty much everyone uses a variation
of Dave's original idea that these,
these people are sort of
my followers. You see,
I find it very interesting that you had
this fear of your buildings collapsing
and here you go into this world where
all of the things you're making are meant
to collapse. Well, here's the thing. Uh,
it's true that every bubble will collapse,
but there is no blame.
See and nobody got it.
I think we might be able to get some here.
So that night Dave took me
out bubble baking powder.
We have thermometer, we have
test strips for measuring Ph.
He'd been watching the humidity
was okay, but the wind,
this amount of wind is
usually very difficult.
So we'll go down and
try to find some shelter
corner of what? West
end and one oh six here,
midnight in Manhattan. Pretty much empty
couple of cars, almost no one walking.
So now I'm going to dunk it in the
soap and now I'm going to raise it up
and I'm going to open the loop and I'm
going to see if I can make a bubble here.
There we go. Okay, that
one's pretty good. Okay.
It is sailing along into the intersection
and I wanted to now chasing the bubble
is now chasing the taxi.
How, how big is that one? Uh,
that's about the size of a killer
whale. I'd say maybe 20 feet long.
When you get these giant bubbles
sailing around among these buildings,
it activates the space.
He says it seems to transform the
architecture and it definitely did. Um,
like it made this city look suddenly
beautiful and like a lava lamp and alien.
And we've got some people walking by
that are now taking videos of them. Jay,
look at that one. Oh, that's a great
one. That's, that's the size of a,
of a smallish baby
elephant and maybe, okay.
And the taxi has now just done a u
turn to watch us and see us. We got,
we've got a bike messenger who,
who's rubber necking as he goes by.
Even if midnight and audience just
materialized. It just incredible.
Like everybody, okay, New Yorkers
are assholes and people are stopping
stopping with smiles and their click.
This taxi has just stopped in the middle
of the road to want you to do this.
So you do, you often stop
your taxi to look at a,
to look at things are really
different things. So big.
I see this small on before,
but this is totally different like this
and it's so silly, right? It very
similar. Sillies it's very wonderful.
Very dizzy.
Very Kitty. Oh there. That's the
size of a killer whale for sure.
You ever feel silly out here? I,
uh, sometimes do,
but I also sometimes compare myself to
my grandfather and I'm much happier to
have invented the giant bubble
thing than having invented the bomb.
I also think, you know, I, in a way,
I feel like I have started an art
form and that is going to go on.
And, uh, and
you've all
[inaudible]
thanks to producer Simon Adler,
and we also want to thank all the
Radiolab listeners who came out
recently and blue bubbles with us.
Prospect Park, Brooklyn
[inaudible]
the message one, this is pretty
Webster [inaudible] all one word,
no fee by proxy, the girlfriend's out.
But we are reading the pregnant
Radiolab is produced by
our director of
[inaudible] wheeler is in your ear.
It's already here. Include Nine Adler
Gabble Nam healthy Robert
[inaudible] year. Melissa [inaudible]
helping Padgett and Ariane, when
you're [inaudible] from,
how do you then get
that? Yeah, Cam Maestra.
Hello. Aka, I fact check [inaudible]
dashes and the in the it hat in the
shower head in which I've had a fight.
And this message.