You are listening to radio lab radio from
W. N. Y. S. T. E. N. N. P. R. So the,
I guess my first question is like what?
What conceivable set of circumstances
led to you doing what you did?
I just thought it would be a weird
thing to do. Oh yeah. Yeah. It's like,
well that would be weird. We don't
know if it's funny, but we try it out.
So yeah. Is it going to be
weird? We'll do it. Yeah.
Is it going to alienate
half the audience? Yeah.
No.
Okay. Wait, just to set
things up, you'd better.
Those two people that you just heard
her wrist and show and Kurt Brown? No.
Hello?
They are comedians. That's it.
And we first heard about the bit you're
about to hear from Jesse Thorn. Yes.
The host of the sound of young
America. Yes. Great. Yeah.
Are you rolling over there, Jessie?
No, let me record you. Okay.
From my phone. Okay. Yeah, I'm rolling.
So you said that when Kurt and Kristen
walk on stage, what happened? Well,
there's a cuddle of jokes up top.
You know, they joke about this,
this TV show that they hosted in the
70s uncle Ben's farmyard courthouse.
I explained the American judicial system
using a court house made completely of
animals. Yeah, it was
canceled immediately. Yeah.
And so the audience is kind of laughing
at the jokes, thinking like, oh,
this is going to be a regular comedy
sketch sketch from it tonight. All right.
Hey Harrigan. I got ready.
I'm ready. Okay. Okay.
And then they go into this song.
Oh, okay. Tom.
Oh good. Tom Is
does this maniacal singing, clapping.
Christine is doing this horsey day.
It's like, Oh wow,
wow,
wow.
Can you do this viewer in like why
Titian Jad like when we do it, we like
at the, after the third [inaudible]
my last name. They get it like, oh, they
could just going to do over and over
and then somewhere around like
four AV around the fourth time.
Then it's not really enough.
Money I use is quiet.
They're like, I'm done with this, I'm
done. I don't want to watch this anymore.
Why are they still doing it? And then,
and then that changes the
actual hatred and they're like,
you stupid people, you to stupid people,
but somewhere between like nine and 11
and they then they're like, oh,
I like this. You could be like
[inaudible] you get this next level,
which is they can't continue doing this
and then they do continue doing it.
Okay.
But again, they really, their eyes
are starting to cross by that point.
I'm dripping sweat. Kristen's
angry that I've gone that long.
It's like look good.
I mean you can hear a Kurt in that thing
like losing track of the song because
he's going into some kind of fuse.
Wow.
Have had her on stage whisper, stop it.
I love here I walk in my house
[inaudible]
this is maybe my favorite thing
in the history of the world.
What I love about it is that your brain
is trying to make it into what you want
it to be, which is a joke, but
there is no joke happening.
And so what these two people are doing
is creating the expectation that the
expectation is going to be broken,
but then breaking that expectation that
the expectation is going to be broken by
just delivering the thing that they've
been delivering over and over for the
past 10 minutes. What's the longest
10 minutes in Australia?
Cause you were drunk? Yeah,
it seemed like it seemed like 10 minutes.
We can't be sure if it was 10 minutes.
It seems like there's no way
it's 10 minutes. You what?
It was 10 minutes and
the audience went crazy.
No, but you really do
Kristen Schaal as a whole.
Justin Scholl is a home.
The good or okay to go
look good or dance like, Oh
hey, I'm Chad at boom. Ron's in
Charlotte. I'm Robert Krulwich dance.
This is Radiolab and today,
oh today it's all about loops.
Things
that happen over and over and over and
over and over and over and over and over.
Coming up. Lipstick hurt you stream
loops that heal you. Dangerous sleeps,
that scare you.
Loops and loops and loops
that incomplete you at what?
Kristen's
a [inaudible].
So where, where are you guys?
What? We were in San Francisco.
You're in San Francisco,
you're not in Texas? No,
just sounds like we're in
Texas. Yes. She's from Texas.
So like can you guys actually
just a, if you don't mind,
introduce yourself so we know we
have your name and all that. Sure.
I'm Mary Sue Campbell. I live in Novato,
California and my daughter
Christine is 30 years old.
I live in San Francisco. Um,
and I was raised in Nevato in the
house that said this didn't happen.
That shall we begin. Okay.
Tell me the beginning w how this
story starts from the beginning.
I thought it was odd.
Christine actually called
me Tuesday morning about 10
o'clock and just said, oh,
what are you doing mom? And I said, Oh,
I'm just going to go out in the yard and
do some yard work and run some errands.
And she said,
we ought to do the yard work early
because it's going to be hot today.
So we're in, we're in the summertime.
It's summertime. Yeah, it was August,
August 24th and apparently
what, 10 minutes later,
half an hour later,
she said, I called her,
she had left me a voicemail, something
like, Hey Christine, it's mom.
Something's, something's not
right. Something's wrong.
I need you to call me back.
So I gave her a call back and,
and she said something thing
about the house isn't right.
There's things look weird in here.
What's weird? What are you talking about?
And then she said, well, I'm looking
at the calendar and it says August,
2010 and I'm like, uh Huh. No. She's like,
well that's not right. And I said, well,
yes it is August 24th,
2010 and as soon as I said that
out loud, I grabbed my purse
to leave. Oh my God, she's
had a stroke. That was my, my,
my first reaction. And um, oh,
that makes me feel emotional.
And so Christine says she walked
out of her house to the car,
keeping your mom on the
phone. What else do you see?
I'm just trying to keep her
talking to me. All the while.
Her mom's telling her one thing after
another just doesn't look right.
She says there's a strange
black truck on the driveway,
which is the truck that belongs to her
boyfriend that has been parked there for
10 years. So I'm of course,
increasingly, I mean,
I'm just freaking out at this point.
So she hangs up with her
mom and then calls the the
paramedics and a half hour later,
Christine arrived at the hospital.
By the time I walked in,
she had been there for five
or 10 minutes at the most,
and as soon as I walked in, the doctor
greeted me and said, I said, uh, yeah,
this is her doctor, Jonathan bellows.
Christine. It's immediately evident.
It's not a stroke, not an infection.
That's, that's a huge relief. But I said,
your mother has, has transient,
Global Amnesia, fancy and global.
Transient. Global. How did those words
hit you? I'll be honest with you.
I had no idea what that meant. I think
the word I heard the most was amnesia.
Oh, your mother has lost her
ability to form new memories.
She can't remember, but said it's
not going to last forever. Um,
it usually lasts between one and 24
hours and we're not sure what causes it.
And it's at this point where the story
goes from something kind of frightening
to something a little more surreal.
Yes. So when I came in, um,
her mother is sitting up in bed,
she's a smiler and she immediately
started asking, yes. Okay,
so what's the date? I said, well,
it's Tuesday, August 24th. Yes.
And of course we have a video on youtube
of this. My birthday's any pants. Yep.
Do you remember how I remember that?
I'm trying to remember the last date.
I remember. I don't
remember if never. Yeah,
we hung out.
You came over to my house and we watched
a video that I made for you when I was
in Texas and all of your sisters
and some of your brothers said,
happy birthday to you on the video.
Yeah. But we still have the videos.
You can watch it again,
but you're going to remember eventually
they say it's just temporary.
Where it was, it was at
home. You're at home yet.
You're at home doing some gardening
and you called me and you're feeling
confused. So I called the paramedics
had been come and get you.
And then we came here. You defend your
tests on you. Okay, so what's the date?
August 24th it's Tuesday.
I'm trying to remember the
last day I remember. Yeah,
I don't remember my birthday. Do you
remember your birthday? Yeah. Yeah.
That must've just been recently.
Yeah, a couple weeks ago.
Now you might've missed
it, but this conversation,
they're having just started over August
because every 90 seconds Mary Sue's
memory resets. August 24th
what's strange is the repetition,
like we started that last clip.
You heard with her saying this,
trying to remember the last day. Damn,
remember 90 seconds later after
her memory resets, she says,
try to remember the bias. A date.
I remember 90 seconds later,
I'm trying to remember the
last day. Damn remember.
And as you watched this
video for a few minutes,
you realize what's happening here.
Is that Mary Sue Dan Week? It is, no,
it's in a loop and it goes
like this. First, the date.
What's the date?
August 24th she then responds in
almost the same way every time.
Birthdays. Yes. She's missed her
birthday. All right. Yep, Yep.
And every time she says that, darn in
exactly the same way. If you fast forward,
it's already past my
birthday though. Yeah.
She must enjoy your birthday quite a
bit. Eventually. Then she laughs, Hey,
what happened? Then they recapped.
You're working in the garden
and you gave me a call.
Christine explains the whole thing.
It's usually when she says
the word paramedic called
the paramedics right there
and have them come and pick you up.
The Mary Sue's eyes get really wide in
this look of sheer and utter disbelief.
Yes. Yeah. Isn't that creepy? I
mean, every single, and you say that.
Isn't that creepy? Creepy.
90 seconds later is some
creepy 90 seconds later
and it's often at this
point right after creepy
that you was sets. Okay,
so I don't know. Tuesday,
like somebody put it on rewind
over and over and over again.
Yes.
Add repeated the birthday summit that
the nurse apparently was behind me
mouthing the words. Yeah.
Oh, that's my birthday. Yeah.
Girls like groundhog day
in here, groundhog's Day,
every two minutes we're doing a
list. The same thing. Yes we do that.
We have had the same
conversation over and over again.
Every two minutes for the last two and
a half hours. Two and a half hours. No,
they, we can't seem to
talk about anything else.
That is what we're talking about today.
What Day of the week is
it? Tuesday, August 24th
you didn't miss it. You were
there. Yeah, I'm watching it.
I wanted to slap me and you know I wanted
to reach out and slap me and say damn
it. I just told you that for the record
I would never slept. My mom would not.
No she would not. And here is a clear,
this is a person who's lost her memory.
Yeah.
But why would her behavior from one
cycle to the next be so precisely and
consistently the same? I mean
sometimes exactly the same. Yeah. Why?
I think what it is is one of the things
the nurses said is that when you have
something like this,
your true self comes out.
Your true. The word true
is interesting. So yeah.
Is that what we're saying on the
video? Is that your true person,
your true self? Oh yeah. I mean that's
my mom through and through right there.
I mean, she's, what Christine
means is not the repetition,
but that her mom keeps asking so
many questions. She's inquisitive.
She just wants to know what's going
on with, with all sorts, you know,
across the board. I love
problems. I love puzzles.
Are you like a Sudoku fiend? You know,
I am. I am. I hate to admit this,
God, I play Escape Room Games
on the Internet escape room.
What are those?
They're stupid little games where they
have little hidden pixels that you find
you're, you're stuck in a
room and you have to get out.
You've got to find the key to the door
and there's all these little hidden
places. Oh, this is the perfect,
perfect metaphor then. Oh yeah.
I was my own escape room. I'd
be like, Hey, didn't get it
Tuesday. There's a different way
of seeing this. First of all,
Jonathan blow that er doctor who's seen
a bunch of these cases, he said, well,
that puzzler instinct,
that's not just Mary sue.
What everybody does is struggle over and
over again with where am I and when am
I? It's just the brain in survival mode.
And another thing that everybody does,
and he's seen him about six of these
patients so far, is it everybody,
not just Mary sue,
but everybody becomes a broken
record right down to the,
the phrasing of the sentences,
which keeps them out a little bit.
It makes, you know,
it makes the brain seem a little
bit more like a machine. You know,
you give the machine the exact same
set of inputs every 90 seconds,
give it the same doctor,
the same hospital room,
same beeping machines and see
if the output ever varies.
And it doesn't, it almost
seems like the patient, uh,
has no free well.
And so sometimes in the back
of his head he thinks, God,
if I had that condition and someone
videotaped me, I would love to see,
see my own tape. Why,
you know, I think, uh,
I want to see, could I somehow
escape the loop? Huh? Or,
or would I, would I had depth
and depth with the rest of us?
Now, thankfully, according to Jonathan,
what normally happens in this
condition is that as time goes on,
that 92nd loop starts to slowly expand.
So it's actually more like
two minutes or three minutes.
Eventually four minutes. Now it's
five minutes. And for Mary Sue,
after a few hours as her
loop got longer and longer,
her old memories started to
creep back in. By that evening,
she was remembering up until um,
like that Sunday, few hours later,
her memory began to extend
into Monday morning.
By the time we left the hospital, she
remembered Monday night. And then finally,
shall we begin? Okay.
Tell me the beginning how this
story starts beginning. Uh,
I, it was odd.
Christine actually called
me Tuesday morning about 10
o'clock and just said, oh,
what are you doing mom? And
apparently 10 minutes later,
hour later,
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. I'm Jad
Abumrad man, we'll be right back.