Hello, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich this is radio lab, that podcast.
So today on the podcast we are going
to continue the conversation that we
started in our last hour. You know,
animal minds like what can
you share with say your dog,
like really truly share, right.
In this 10 minutes we're going to explore
a kind of sharing that we didn't get
to in our last hour.
One that's arguably a deeper kind of
sharing comes to us from reporter Ben
Calhoun and grew out of a
conversation that he had with a well,
just listen. Okay. You can start
anytime you want. All right.
Thank you very much, sir. You're ready
to go. Are you? Yeah, absolutely. Jerry,
you ready? Yes, sir. Whenever you are,
let's just start with the having you
introduce yourself. I'm Jerry stones.
I'm the facilities director at the Gladys
porter zoo. That's where Jerry is now,
but he told me this story.
He was working at the Henry Doorly zoo
in Nebraska and he was working with this
orangutan named Fu Manchu.
I call him food that everybody that had
loved that old boy referred to him as
food or fully wait, let me just set the
scene. So we're in the Nebraska Zoo.
We were in Nebraska. Is this in Omaha?
Oh, in Omaha. Okay. In the Omaha Zoo.
It's fall 1967 late 66 or 67 kind of coal.
The leaves have fallen off the trees.
Jerry stones is just going
about his daily business.
What is his daily business and
being in charge of the zookeepers.
So he's kind of the top dog among
the crew of zookeepers there.
And he's up at the office and then all
of a sudden here comes a couple of the
keepers running up over this
hill is Jerry, Jerry, Jerry.
The orangutans are into trees
by the elephant building.
[inaudible]
the line went dead for a minute cause
I couldn't figure out what the blazers
they were talking about.
And I said, wait, what?
And they said the rangs in the
trees by the elephant building.
So the orangutans are no longer
in their assigned area. Yes.
So I took off with them and we ran down
there and sure enough there was this
grove of elm trees on this
hill overlooking the elephant
building and an air up
in the top of these trees were all
their Rangataua and, Oh God. Yeah.
And there was a Fu Manchu and his
female Tondo Leo and an old female named
Sophia, big heavyset girl and Toba,
young female and dentists' a young male.
And they were all up in the trees.
Five of them. I have a, I'm up there,
you know, look like these
huge red clumps of grapes
at this point. Jerry's a young
guy, so he went Tarzan on them.
Back in those days,
I didn't think anything about going
to the top of a tree and grabbing an
arranged by the hand and leading him
back out of the tree, even though I,
couple of them had already bit me.
So he gets them all back in the exhibit
and they didn't know how the orangutans
had gotten out. No question.
And everybody and not listening.
I have a tendency to do
that, you know? Anyway,
I would get them down to the building.
We put them away in the Cajun and we
go out to see what was going on in the
exhibit itself. There's most on each side
of exhibit, you know, like a zoom out.
You've got the exhibit and then you've
got where people look from and in between
there's a mode, right? Well, down at the
bottom of this moat, there was a door
to a furnace room,
big metal door that had just a
regular lock and everything on it.
It was always shut, kept locked
all the time that door was open.
What had happened, the rings
had climbed down in a moat,
went into the furnished room, which
was in the basement, up a ladder,
did a janitor's closet on the first
floor. One, two, three, four, five.
They all emerged from this janitor's
closet and then just pushed the big glass
doors open, went out into the park.
I figured somebody had not locked
the door shut. Oh right. Okay.
So Jerry stones gathers his zookeeper's
around and he says basically when we
needed to be more careful,
somebody evidently went out
in that moat to do something.
And when they came back in,
they did not lock the door a mistake
and it should not happen again.
And everyone at buddy bowed that this
would not happen again. And it didn't,
it didn't happen again for
about a week. A few days go by,
I can't remember where
I was at. And again,
the orangutans during the trees by the
elephant building and Jerry, we, we,
the door was locked. Jerry, we didn't do
it. We didn't do it, you know, not ana.
So they take them all back into the
building. Same thing. I get there,
go down to mote. That furnace
room door is open again.
I was convinced that these people
were not sharp enough to shop,
tie their shoes, you know, and, and,
and uh, and they said, but Jerry,
we don't go down there.
Well, somebody screwed up.
So I'm discussing with these capers,
what's going to happen to them in
their short lives. Now, I swear to God,
I said, Dude, look,
next time this happens,
somebody being fired few days later,
somebody runs up to you on Jerry, come,
you got to come see this. I'll go, no,
not now.
They ran out into the zoo and they went
to this hill that's near the exhibit,
peaked over the top of it. Commando
style down at the bottom of the moat.
Fu Manchu was messing with that
furnace room door. What was he doing?
They couldn't exactly see what he was
doing because of how far away they work.
But he was fiddling with the lock and
he's fiddling and he's fiddling and then
the door,
the dam is popped open and we went
bowling down the hill and we caught him
before he could do any damage.
You mean the rang hands seem to be
opening the door? Yes. You know,
I realized that it wasn't
their fault and you know,
I hate the crow that I had to eat and uh,
we still didn't know exactly how I did it.
And we went out there and we looked
around and there was few little sticks and
stuff laying around. We thought, well,
he must be using this stuff to pry the
door open or do something, you know?
So Jerry figured, easy solution, clean
the exhibit every day. I said, look,
from now on we need to go out in this
yard everyday before we put the rangs out
and searched. That plays
over and again, you know,
make sure there's no sticks or anything
out there. I don't know how he did it,
but he did it. You know,
we knew what the problem was
and we knew how to deal with it.
Went along like that for a week or
two. And then here come to keepers,
Jerry, the orangutans are in,
into trays by the elephant, Billy.
And we checked it. Jerry, we did
everything we were supposed to do here.
You know, they're, they're bound and
determined. They didn't do anything wrong.
Should we sit down?
So they had been searching this exhibit
every day and make sure that he didn't
hear was no, we walked that exhibit.
We cleaned them all, we did everything.
There was no sticks, no anything. We
could find that he used the pride,
that darn door open. No tools, no
tools, no nothing. Wait, how do we know?
Like how can this be? How can this be? How
can this be? So he's ushering
Fu Manchu through the building.
They've got all the orangutans,
they're moving them and all of a sudden
he sees in the corner of Fu Manchu,
I saw this little blink of light,
just a little glimmer of light, like
a silver filling or something. Yeah,
a little shiny thing. It's the
corner of his mouth. He walks over,
pulls down through
Manchus lip and in there,
low and behold there was a piece of wire,
uh,
about four inches long that he had bent
into a horseshoe to fit in inside of his
lower lip and around his gum.
And he's had it there for so long
that it was just polished, shiny,
suggesting what this animal has been
secreting his actual key all this time.
Yeah. All this stuff that we're
picking up and hauling away,
it keeps him from opening the door was
of no use because he was carrying his own
key with him all the time.
What he had done was stick the wire into
the space between the door jam and the
door, wrap it around the
latch and pull it back.
It's like the credit card trick.
You know, nobody taught him this.
Nobody ever did anything like that around
him. Not only did he make the tool,
but he put it in a place
where I couldn't find it.
He was smart enough to know that if I
found it, I'd take it away from him.
The locksmith union of the United States
gave him an honorary membership and the
zoo in Omaha had that hanging
on their wall for years.
I don't know if they still have it or not.
[inaudible]
well, this has been very
interesting. So really great story.
[inaudible] very nice. But I don't quite
understand like what, what exactly was,
why are you telling it to me? What is
the reason for this? Well, you know,
there's a lot of stuff,
stories of orangutans
using tools, right? Yeah.
But even though this is a funny story,
there's actually a really serious question
at the heart of it about deception.
Why? What's so important about,
well, deception is special.
It requires that the deceiver get into
the mind of the person who they're
deceiving and nobody has been able to
prove that animals can actually do this.
No. A human beings
thoughts intimately enough,
get inside their heads and you
know, consciously deceived them.
So
I took the Fu Manchu story
two
a scientist, a primatologist
named Rob Shoemaker.
Hello, Rob Shoemaker.
Hey Rob, it's been, am I catching
you at the great ape trust in Iowa?
And I studied the behavior
and cognition of Orangutans
and he says,
the food man choose story doesn't prove
that animals are capable of doing this.
It in this particular case, I
can't prove it one way or another.
There's always a question of whether
or not it was really happening,
but when I really pushed it, I'm
just wondering like personally,
do you believe in his case
that it was he said yes.
Do you know if, if I had to just
give, um, an opinion about this,
that deep down,
I have no doubt at all.
I 100% believe it was deception keeping
a tool concealed over a whole number of
days and timing his escapes so
that no one was around to see him.
I think the evidence is just absolutely
compelling to suggest that he who met
you was able to deceive and was deceiving.
And if someone really has that
much trouble believing yet,
I think then maybe they add a question.
Is it because I don't believe what I'm
hearing or I don't want to believe it
because it's an orangutan.
If they don't want to believe it because
it's an orangutan, that's no excuse.
It was like who tardy? I just,
I couldn't figure it out. I mean,
when you think you're so smart that all
the other animals are way below you and
all of a sudden you find this animal that
does these sort of things and you know
people that couldn't open the door
with the key right there. You, you,
you know you have to be in awe.
[inaudible].
I've been around a lot of other
orangutans in my almost 45 years in this
business,
and a next time you go to a
zoo and you're around one,
you just look at their face and you look
at their eyes and you can see in there
there's this, these wheels
turning, trying to figure you out.
[inaudible]
then Calhoun is a reporter
here in New York City.
Thank you to him and thanks to the people
who make radio lab possible. They are,
well, they're the national
science foundation and they
are the Sloan Foundation.
Yup. I'm Jad. I boom, Rod, I'm
rubber coach. Thanks for listening.