You are listening to radio lab radio, w.
N. Y. S. C. E. N. N. P. R.
I thought we would begin, uh,
by looking backwards at a,
at a wonderful moment in the
history, cinematically of parasites.
Here's the cinematic history of parasites.
Okay. So do you remember that movie?
I'm not going to tell you the name
of it. Yeah. Starts out. In fact,
I have the script right
here. Setting space.
[inaudible]
okay. Vast empty space
script continues to stars shine cold
and remote like the love of God.
Ooh, you imagining this? Yes.
Now floating in that vast
nothingness as a tiny dot of a ship,
you can barely see it
to the interior of the ship dead.
Here we are in a ship full of
astronauts who are tired and dirty.
Renee will tell you, look dead, no
bouncing around and you
just get the feeling.
This is a normal day in
their astronauts lie until
they're on the computer. Radar is a
disturbance, some kind of distress.
Second transmission here. Yeah.
Do you think we're going to check
this out so they trace the signal,
eventually get into a pod and show me and
they find themselves at this abandoned
ship.
Totally abandoned. It's like a ghost ship.
I've never seen anything like
it. I knew I hadn't had to crow.
It's empty except for these weird eggs
and the astronauts are like looking at
the eggs and touching the eggs and going,
okay, now fast forward. We're
back into the first ship. Okay,
everything's fine for the most part and
then something happens and I want you
to, I've got the computer there in
front of you. Okay? We'll push this.
Push the space bar. Space bar.
All right, you're at the table.
Everyone's dressed.
The first thing that I get to do
when I get to get some decent food,
you can dig it, man. Talk to talking,
chatting me or having like
salad was eating and talking.
One of the guys gets a little weird,
right? Oh, he's not feeling so good.
One of the guys, what are you doing?
Oh, now he's coughing, coughing.
Don't tell me trouble breathing.
He's falling back onto the table. His
chest is heaving, his wrist. Oh my gosh.
He's kicking his head wildly and he's
like flexing all over the table and
something. He's like, Oh,
Oh God,
there's a red thing. I read
the horrible sneaky thing.
This is of course the classic scene
from the original alien movie scene
where the little thing bursts out of
the guy's chest and like hisses why did,
because I think I figured out
why that scene is scary. I mean,
when I first saw this movie, that scene
went over and over and over in my mind,
and it's had this effect on a lot of
people and I think I know why. What are,
you know, it's not that the little
creature is disgusting, which it is.
It's that it was there all
along. Sitting there. Yeah,
inside him, like incubating,
waiting to think that you sitting in
that seat right there could have in your
gut these little worms that are wriggling
around doing more or less what that
alien was doing and I
can't even see them in, you
can't even talk about it. So it's not,
today's subject on radio lab will be
flowers. Even meadows coming up after this
[inaudible]
no, we're not doing that. We're doing,
we're doing that an hour on parasites.
These little creatures that live inside
us invisibly and yet can have a huge
influence over who we think we are.
What is a parasite precisely and
mature. And just to sort of slide us in,
get us into the mood. I'm
already not in the mood.
We thought we would get things started.
Maybe I'll just move this over here.
Well there really is no other way to
start a show on parasites except with this
guy. You should introduce
yourself. My name is Carl Zimmer.
Carl's is a science writer and parasites
have been on his radar ever since.
He was a little boy.
I grew up on a little farm and my mother
would raise tomatoes sometimes in her
pensionable garden and sometimes there
would be these caterpillars feeding on
them.
And my mom would be very annoyed and every
now and then I would notice that some
of them didn't look very well and they
had this little sort of fuzzy white bumps
on them and I didn't really
know what they were. Well,
it turned out that they had been
attacked by a parasitic wasp,
which had laid its eggs inside of it.
Those exit hatched and had become larvae
and those larvae were swimming around
inside that Caterpillar while I was
eating my mother's tomatoes and they were
growing, growing inside the caterpillar.
And then finally when they were ready,
they came out and only
then did their host die.
And when he finally found out that that
is what was happening inside those fuzzy
white bumps, profound situation,
this whole universe of a baby's
growing into adolescence,
that's when I guess I
sort of got very hooked,
which is probably an understatement
because you are sort of like capital p
parasite man. And if you look, yeah,
in the New York Times or science magazine
or any of the places, Carl writes,
a suspicious number of his articles
are pretty flattering to parasites.
People who have been dismissing
parasites for a long time,
calling them degenerates.
Now I would argue that
parasites are not degenerate.
They have gained the ability to
live inside three, four, five,
six different species. So do
you find that you sort of,
you're a lawyer for them. Hey Sir, you
call this degenerative. How dare you sir?
Say that.
I think I'm a defender of all in the
collected and put upon species out there.
Why wouldn't a parasite the what?
I think you mean when you say
degenerate because the title thing,
it infects something else. It sucks.
Whatever. It's not independent. Right?
So when you say it's not degenerate
[inaudible] what do you say that? Well,
let's start with saying it's not
independent or any of us independent Kit
Carson. How have you stripped all
the bacteria out of Kit Carson?
Kit Carson would get very sick.
Daniel Boone on the other hand,
now there's a guy in the pendant
alone in the woods. Daniel Boone eat,
I guess Daniel boot eats pigeon like
the rest of us. What's your point?
Right point is the Daniel Boone eats meat.
He ate bread, which came from plants,
was the question of degrees.
Though we're not living inside the
intestinal track of some other creatures,
so why does living in side seem like
it's a degenerate thing as opposed to us
know?
We can't even synthesize a lot of our own
vitamins anymore where the degenerates
in a lot of ways, no code, no com.
If you are a creature that lives
off someone else's vitality,
cheaters would be another way of putting
it. But listen, can you appreciate it?
I'm going to cut this short right here.
Carl says, no, no, no. They're amazing.
Time and time again, he says, no,
no, no. In the argument went on,
still waiting to hear about how you,
how you are able to photosynthesize
until you answer. Do it for me,
but I go about it in a mental way. You
can't even do it yourself. Like I said,
the argument went on and on with Roberts
saying one thing and Carl firing back
and me adding another. Okay,
and here's what we're going to do
just to be fair and square about this.
We're going to bring in an independent
moderator. Lolo yourself. Yeah.
You're going to be the monitor.
Yeah, you'd get that Mike, Right?
You're going to be the moderator
and a you listening right now.
We will leave it to you, your decision
and this one lightning round of go ahead.
Should I like to do that?
Okay. Yeah. Parasites.
Are they evil or are they
awesome? Starting with number one,
that a parasitic wasps,
there are probably 200,000 species
of parasitic wasps out there.
Big Wasp, small ones.
They're generally pretty tiny and
they go after all sorts of things.
Some will lay them in house caterpillars.
Spiders are the one Carl's
going to tell us about this.
This particular wasp is called imp
likes. Compressor goes after [inaudible]
[inaudible]
and for those of you who never
thought you'd feel sorry for a caucus,
[inaudible]
keep listening. So what
it does is it [inaudible]
flies around and it looks for a cockroach.
And once it finds that Cock Roche
kid land and then
the fight begins, they
tumbled back and forth around,
around until finally the wasp somehow
manages to arch its back around the body
of the cockroach and uh, stings it
right in the belly. The
cockroach twitches for a second
and then false. The cockroach is
paralyzed. Now the wasp takes its time.
Repositions itself puts its butt
up right near the cockroaches head
[inaudible]
and delivers a second stink.
The Stinger actually threads its way
to a particular spot in the brain.
And this does something odd.
Moments later the cockroach recovers
of stands up. I can walk again,
but something is wrong, very
wrong. It just stands there
like a week.
It can't run away. Move.
It has essentially lost its
will. What does that mean?
Uh, it's,
yes, it is a puppet. It's
become a Zombie basically.
And so now the wasp will literally grab
onto the cockroaches antenna and start
pulling on it. How does it grab with,
what does it grin? I plead with its mouth.
Imagine tiny wasp guiding a
cockroach across the desert floor,
like a dog on a elite.
And so it leads it down, down, down,
down into a little borough it's
made and the cockroach says, okay,
whenever you want to go. Then
once the wasp has the Roach in the borough
lays its eggs on the underside of the
cockroach.
Tonight you've got this drugged roach
sitting on top of some wasp bags and then
the wasp goes out and
it seals the borough.
It buries the cockroach
alive. Well, it's a shell.
It's in a little chamber. It doesn't
want to kill the cockroach because this,
the cockroach is gonna feed.
It's, you know, it's young. Yeah.
So then the eggs hatch
and then they drill inside. The
cockroach is still just sitting there.
How's it staying alive at this point?
What parasites are very careful, you know,
they won't eat vital organs
that will kill it. Instead,
Carl says they just
feast on the extra stuff.
There's a lot of stuff
inside of a cockroach,
a lot of fluid just floating around.
It's of Wonderbread essence of skin,
old hair, and you can just feed
on any, the host stays alive. Wow.
And then what happens?
Eventually a little baby wasp larva grows
up inside the cockroach and develops
into an adult. And then
one day in the wash
eats its way up a little hole out of the,
out of the cockroaches body shakes
off its wings and flies off,
and then the Roche dies, then the
roach dies. Why only then? Yeah.
[inaudible]
that to me sounds like of the purest
description in nature of evil that I can
imagine. Wouldn't you agree? Well,
Darwin certainly said that God should
not be personally blamed for having
created parasitic wasps.
[inaudible]
but if you ask Carl, he'll have
you think about that moment.
The moment where the wasp stings,
the brain parasitic wasp can attack a
cockroach and inserted Stinger into one
specific part of the cockroaches brain
and inject a precise little cocktail of
drugs that then turns the
cockroach into it. Slave.
I know that that Wasp didn't get a phd
in neurobiology and yet it has performed
a kind of brain surgery very
precisely in a very elegant way. Uh,
or evil might be the other
way. [inaudible] go. Go ahead.
But there's a complexity
there that you can't deny
[inaudible]
or can you, we leave it
to you bringing us to example number two,
parasitic mean to food. I mean, here's,
here's a another example that I
actually was looking at today.
Can you holding your computer up to the
glass and on the screen is a big black
and it looks like it's carrying
a cherry, right? A Cherry.
That's about twice the size of the ant.
That Red Cherry is actually parasites
inside of the aunt making it look like a
red cherry. What part of the aunt is
that? Is that it's bought essentially?
Yeah. Wait a second. Is it,
it looks like it's sticking.
It's big red button up into the air.
Yeah. Their behavior is changed or they,
they waggle around their, their,
their tail as it were. Now.
Why on earth would a parasite turn on
ants but red and then make it stick?
It's bought up into the air. Well,
let's say you put an ant down.
It has this bright red from your end
and an ordinary and in front of a bird.
Birds can go for that red and very quickly
because it thinks it's a berry. Yeah,
and then what?
It's going to swallow this little
package full of nematode eggs.
So that's the way the nematode
eggs get into the sky.
They buy their airplane tickets by
advertising themselves as berries. Yes.
What's the benefit of
being in the air? Well,
the only place that this parasite
can reproduce is inside the bird.
And how better to spread your seed?
Far and wide, the drop from the sky
with the birch droppings. That
is brilliant. That's brilliant.
I mean, look at the
[inaudible] that it's red.
It's up in the air. Yeah. Is it amazing?
It's like how can a stupid
little thing be so brilliant?
Because they're not degenerates,
but they're still cheating. And
then just to bring his point home,
just to pick a common one. Carl
offered up his third and final example.
Number three, blood flukes.
Blood flukes are, um,
related to flatworms tapeworms.
So their eggs start out in the water,
fresh water in Africa, Asia,
parts of South America.
And the first part of their life,
they go into a snail and come back out
into the water and they're swimming
around and they start looking for a human.
So imagine a foot going into the
shallow end of the pot. I see toes,
I see bottom of foot, I see ankle.
Well, if you're a blood fluke,
you don't see anything. You don't have
eyes. But eventually you find a foot,
secrete a little enzyme,
basically turn a little bit of skin into
butter and you slip into the vein and
now
you're going to swim
my circulatory system.
Sure you're going to
ride along in the blood.
And now it's time to find a mate, a mate.
So their sex. So there's a male and
female. So what you're saying, sure.
They're animals. They're animals. I
would have never called them animals.
It's interesting you say that. That's
a whole nother topic I guess so.
All right. So the female is very thin,
literally have a standard
issue where I'm kind of thing,
but the male is very strange. It's,
it's kind of like like a canoe.
It's gotta be trough
down in the middle. Uh,
and at one end it's got a giant sucker.
Should we urge some of our listeners
to tune away at this point because,
but it's about to happen. May Not
be acceptable in family hour. Um,
actually blood flukes are, are fairly
monogamous and loyal. So you know,
if you're looking for or for animals
to reinforce your family values,
blood flukes pretty good.
And eventually two blood flukes find
their way toward each other and the male
does this sort of court ship or
whatever reason the female says, yes,
I accept your courtship.
The female joined,
the male fits in the trough.
Oh, so it's like a groove.
The female goes and occupies the
groove right now this isn't just,
this isn't mating. This
is way beyond meeting.
The males will feed the
female for starters,
and they will stay this way for
a long, long time. Really? Yeah.
Like days, years. Years,
years. Yeah. Oh my God.
Years in human or years to them. Just
years. Years, years. Years. Years.
Like the earth going around the
sun kind of years. Yes. In fact,
there've been cases where people show up
at their doctor's feeling awful and the
doctor does some tests and says,
oh, you've got blood flips.
No, you had to have been in
Africa to get this disease.
When have you been in Africa?
And the person said 40 years ago,
44 zero 40 years ago. Yeah.
And the reason that they're getting
sick is that these male and female blood
flukes are still together making eggs.
And Carl's literally glowing when
he says this. I have to admit,
I do love the thought that parasites
are among the most monogamous animals on
the planet. It's heaven. I mean,
you're going to spend the
rest of your life together.
And so our story concludes that
the image of two blood flukes
in your veins for nearly half a century
got hand to him. He's good.
Carl, you mean? Yeah. Yeah.
And there is a a species of take part
that's going to be named after me.
No kidding. Wow. It's not quite
as much of an honors do you think?
At first I was talking with the Paris
autologist and she was telling her fellow
expert about how she was going to name
one for me and then they got into a
conversation about, you know,
that was good that you named
that particular tape form
for him because he's kind
of thin and it's kind of a thin day
for him. You know, my aunt is, she's,
she's a little round and it's a kind of
a round table of nine named her after
and you just suddenly discover there
are a lot of tapeworms to be named.
How many is a lot. I mean tens of
thousands of species of tapeworms. Wow.
So they got us beat many times over.
I once a estimates that if you took all
the viruses in the ocean and you stuck
them into end, how far
would it go? And, um,
it was many light years, way
beyond our galactic neighborhood.
They other ones there more cheats
than there are honest people.
Honest creatures on earth. Oh yeah.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
we should go to Brackney.
Same. And I think we can,
thanks to Lulu Miller and of course
Carl Zimmer, who has written many books,
including parasite rex,
a book we shamelessly parasitized for
the making of the previous segment.
Also want to encourage you to go to our
website where you can find pictures of
the, uh, the blood fluke spooning
the ant with swollen red button.
And of course the a wasp with
the cockroach, Letcher porn,
and it's all yours. It radiolab.org
[inaudible]
I'm Chad album, Ron. I'm
Robert Krulwich. Stay with us.