You are listening to
radiolab radio from W N y.
S. C. E. Yup. Hey,
this is Radiolab. I'm Jad
Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
Our topic today is goodness,
goodness, selflessness.
So we've done the math I as the map.
Okay. So you ready for this? All right,
I'm ready. Alright, so a while back we,
we did this story that for us at
least really stuck in our heads.
It was a story that was, uh,
asking this really deep question and the
answer that we got to you answer didn't
quite click right. I remembered
that one. Yeah. Just to sort of, uh,
set the table. The question was,
why do people do good in the world?
So we asked that question, looked at
it from the perspective of genetics,
computer science, all kinds of things.
We ended up profiling these three
extraordinarily heroically good people.
Yes, they were heroes. They did
remarkable things, each one.
And we told their stories
with that question in mind.
Why do certain people do good in
the world and others don't? Yeah.
And so we're going to revisit that
question today and the story that we told
because I think we have something better
and smarter to say about it. Final,
something very peculiar to say
about it as it turns out. Yeah.
So we're gonna play you the original first
and then we're going to come back and
hopefully shed some new light
on it. Yup. So here we go
again. This story just began with a
simple question, that question. Let us,
well, for Koski two,
a guy named Walter with cal scoop and
I'm the executive director and the
secretary of the Carnegie
Hero Fund Commission. Cool.
Well thanks for doing this.
Can you just give us, uh,
a little background on the hero
fund? What is the Carnegie Hero Fund?
Carnegie Hero Fund is a private operating
foundation that was established by
Andrew Carnegie in 1904.
And what we do is recognize civilian
heroism throughout the United States and
Canada by giving an award
called the Carnegie Medal.
And accompanying the Carnegie metal is
a financial grant. How much? Uh, well,
currently the amount is $5,000. Wow.
And how do you guys choose your heroes?
We judged the heroic acts
against a list of requirements.
So then you have to have some
kind of definition of hero,
which includes some and excludes
others. Yes, perfect. Basic definition,
which is a civilian one
meaning no military who
voluntarily to leaves a point of
safety. Three to risk his
own life or her own life,
or to an extraordinary degree. Five.
To save or to attempt to save
the life of another human. Six.
How about seven y, can you hear? Can
you read that one more time? Okay.
I wasn't reading that
just came from memory.
So what is it that happens in a person's
mind at that pivotal moment when they
decided to voluntarily,
voluntarily leave a point of
safety line of sight and your risk,
their life to an extraordinary degree
to save the life of another human?
That's what we wanted to know.
Should we just jump in? Okay.
So the first one we have on our
list is a Laura Shrek. Okay.
That's file number seven three five
four six and the award number is 8,005
I am Laura shrike. I'm
from Matt Toon, Illinois,
and I currently live in
Dubai, United Arab Emirates.
Oh Wow. Laura spoke with our
producer, Tim Howard. Okay,
so we're going back a
little bit here. Yeah.
15 years back in the mid Nineties
1995 to 21 year old college students,
and I was driving through the country and
I saw a woman getting mauled by a bull
and a pasture. So she stomped
to see what was going on,
jumped out and started yelling
at her to see what I could do.
The woman was on the ground and
the bull was 150 pound Jersey Ball,
tossing her in the air and back on the
ground. Wow. She was clearly struggling.
And where were you? I was right
on the other side of the fence,
but the fence was electric.
[inaudible]
so here's the moment that we
find fascinating. At this point,
Laura can either go forward
through thousands of volts
of electricity toward an
angry bull that will
likely mall her to, or
she can stay safe.
No,
I want it.
Hadn't just climbed through the fence
and I don't remember ever feeling fi
electricity.
She says by the time she got through
crazily enough and Labor had shown up and
threw her a piece of pipe maybe about
two feet long or she approached the woman
who was still conscious the
whole time she's yelling at me,
hit the ball on the face as
hard as you can and don't stop.
So Miss Shriek went up to the ball and uh,
it repeatedly diffuse two
foot length of tubing.
I think it distracted the bull enough
where she was able to get out from under
him.
And as soon as we were outside the fence
looking back into the pastor and the
bull was literally right
there at the fence,
correct the ground a few times and
snorted. He was not, he was not happy
to our question.
When you were there at that fence and
you had the choice to either stay put or
to go through it, what was going through
your mind? Was there a calculation?
No, I can't really say that.
I mean you don't weigh your options
or anything like that? I did not know.
It was just, here's the problem,
here's what I need to do.
And something needed to happen.
Huh?
So there was no choice moment?
Not that I recall. No.
If nobody came to this woman's
rescue, she would die. Unfortunately.
This is the usual explanation.
Says Walter lobular no explanation.
I couldn't stand there and not do
anything. I would, I was compelled to act.
I didn't really take the time to
think about what else could happen.
No, I can't say I ever really thought
about my own life at that time. I mean,
I think we just jumped ahead
because we thought we'd try again.
That's the voice. The next
Carnegie Hero that, uh,
Walter told us about William
David Pennell, William Panel,
who is the 8362nd person to
receive the Carnegie metal.
I produced your Lynne Levy tracked him
down. Can you hear me? Yeah, I can hear.
Oh, William David Pennell was 37 years
old at the time of his heroic act.
Was It 1999? Yes. I was,
uh, early in the morning.
It was like 3:19 AM in a small
town near Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania, Monongahela, Pennsylvania.
We was in bed sleeping and
my wife heard a lot of crash.
I actually didn't hear it from an
adult. My one dog was carrying on.
So right away I run down there.
Mr Pennell went outside his house.
There was a a very bad
automobile accident.
A car crashed head on until utility pole
was like whiplash up the windshield out
from under the hood from the responded
to the scene wearing only sweat pants or
shoes or shirt or nothing
on their chest in air foot.
So here we are, bill standing
in front of this ball of fire.
There are three teenagers inside that car
though he doesn't know it can either a
do nothing or B go in
through the driver's door
and his big fellow slumped out the door.
So I reached in and grabbed a
hold of them around the chest,
pull them from the driver's seat
out to the ground. The meantime,
the car was just like blazer
and my neighbor was there.
She was hollering. There's more of them
in there. So I run back to the vehicle.
We found that the front seat
passenger was trapped in the wreckage.
I finally got him loose
and pulled him out.
And currently Mr Pennell was aware
that a third person was in the car.
Third Young Man, Mr Pennell
entered the car a third time.
By then there was tires blown flames
had grown to about three feet above the
car's roof. The interior there,
like the headline or at the car,
the stuff was stripping like
plastic Donald, my back.
I mean I'm in there screaming, you
know, somebody give me a hand in here,
but nobody, nobody would help. And uh,
I reached in and grabbed a hold of the
kid who was in the back by the scruff of
the neck and pulled him out.
All right,
so when you were coming out of your
house and you're looking at that car,
what was going through your head?
I'll just this to try to help. I mean, I,
I did what any normal person
would do. I mean, you know,
I just kept saying this to somebody
whose kid, you know what I mean?
It's a time my daughter was like 16.
And I'm saying to myself, you know,
if something, God forbid,
whatever happened to her,
that I would hope someone
would be there to help.
Do you ever talk to your neighbors and
ask them why they didn't come in there?
Uh, you know what, that's funny you
brought that up because no, I've never,
never brought it up. Never brought
it up. I don't know. I guess,
uh, maybe I probably wouldn't like
their answer. I don't know. Uh,
I don't
know why.
I've never asked him about what do you
think is the difference between you and
those other people who just
sort of stood by? Uh, I,
I couldn't answer that
[inaudible] answer that.
So our bull girl, she didn't know.
This guy didn't really know either.
Somebody must be able to tell us something
about what they were thinking at that
moment that allowed them, that gave
them the courage to do what they did.
I can't give you a definite answer as
to what propels people to do this. No,
we took one more shot with Walter
and uh, after we take a quick break,
we're going to hear one more hero story
from him. That's when we come back.
This is Sam.
You're calling from Denver, Colorado.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation enhancing public
understanding of science and technology
in the modern world war information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm forming u s attorney. Prepare
Rara. I have a show called, stay tuned.
We talk to the best minds in
politics, law and culture.
Like our recent guest, Maggie Haberman,
a couple of Trump advisors over the years
have said to me that people close to
him in variably begin to act
like him. And that is true.
I have observed that
personally. You can hear,
stay tuned on apple podcasts or
anywhere you get your favorite shows.
Jan, Robert Radiolab. We're
back now with Walter Rakowski,
who's going to tell us the third and
final of his hero stories. He told us,
well that of all the cases he's heard,
this is the one that puzzles him the most.
The case of Wesley James Autry,
a construction worker from a New York
50 year old man who did jump into the
track that in a subway
station to remove a fellow,
a young man who had fallen onto the track.
The gentleman was a six
foot 280 pounds. He was,
he was in earth and yet Mr Autry persisted
despite the fact that a train was
coming. There would come a point and
let's, at least in my estimation,
where you would have to say,
I have to get out of here because I'm
going to be killed on, I'm not suicidal,
but Mr Autry didn't think that way. He
and I parked in this in this manner.
What he did was he lay a top the victim
between the rails while the train passed
over them in the farthest
reaches of my imagination,
I can see myself jumping onto a
subway track to attempt the rescue.
What I can't see myself
doing is lying at top,
the victim while the train passes over me.
[inaudible]
making this story even more nuts.
When we finally met up with Wesley Autrey
on the platform where this incident
happened under 35th and Broadway.
He explained to us that his
daughters had been with them.
Okay. And uh, how old are
your daughters at that time?
My daughter was four and six. And this,
this them there should this
picture. Oh my God, super cute.
The one behind me is Shuki
and this the baby Sashi.
So when they're standing there and
this guy starts convulsing and then
eventually falls off the platform onto
the tracks, right as a train is coming,
his choice is pretty stark. In order
to save this complete stranger,
he's got to leave his daughters
behind potentially without a dad.
Yeah. I'm shaking and going into
another seizure for some strange reason.
A boys, I don't know, said that,
don't worry about your own,
to worry about your daughters.
You can do this. So he jumps,
runs to the guy. Is he conscious? No, no.
Tries to grab the guy's hand and
he's on my, grabbed his hand.
We'll slip a pride in a way he slipped.
I look up, the train is getting close.
I grabbed his hand again, we'll slip
apart just this goes up 50 feet,
20 feet, 10 feet, and then it's right
there and all you can do is grab the guy,
get them in a bear hug and flatten his
body again against the guy as much as he
can.
The first train car just grazed my
cats train car went right over it.
Train came to a stop over
the five cars passed over us.
I looked him in the eyes. Excuse me,
you seem to have a seizure or something.
I don't know you. You don't know me.
So I just kept talking to him until
he came through and he was like, well,
where are we? I'm like
willingly portrayed. He said,
well, who are you? I said,
I came down to save your life. So he kept
asking me, are we dead or when heaven,
I gave him a slight pinch on his
arm. He's that hall. Just I see you.
You are very much alive. Have you,
did you ever ask yourself at this point
like what am I doing here when he asked
it, what am I doing here? What about
you ma? I can hear the two ladies.
We had my daughter standing
the man between their legs.
I can hear that daughter screaming.
So when that train come to a stop,
I yelled up from underneath the train.
Excuse me. I'm the father. We are okay.
I just want to let my daughters know that,
that I'm okay because I know
that they are worried about me.
Everybody started clapping.
Can I ask you a question?
So it's the point at which you said
you heard a voice. Yes. That said,
I can do this. I can do this.
What's, what's what is amazing to me?
Is it you left your daughter's
right here and die after a guy.
You don't know if he was a stranger.
Total stranger. But you know what?
The mission wasn't con
completed. I was chose for that.
You felt shows like you were
cheating. I felt like I was a chosen
lift for a religious person
though. I would wonder why me?
Well, you know what, uh,
maybe 20 years ago I was
supposed to be at a certain point
and then he explained to us
exactly why he had jumped.
He was the one guy who could, he said
right before his feet left the platform,
this one specific moment
from his life flashed to mind
this thing that happened. You know,
I had a gun pulled to my temple,
but you know, it was a misfire.
So you know a gun was put
to your head and miss them.
So you are almost dead for a
second as the most dead, you know,
so you think you might might've been
spared for a spare for reason after that?
Right.
A moment. He says when the gun
went click and he didn't die,
he always wondered why had God spared
him that moment until he was on the
platform and he saw the guy
fall off. He says, then he knew,
this is why I can do this. I
can do this. I can do this.
That voice, when that boy said
that you going to be okay,
I knew everything was going to work out.
You know what I think at the
end of the day. What's that?
I don't think that there's an
answer to the question we asked.
I don't really hear real
question. Why were you a hero?
I don't think that any
three of these here.
I mean the last one had
the longest explanation.
He had been selected for some purpose,
but does he know why he was calling?
Not a clue. A CIA guy number three gives
me something. What does he give you?
Okay, so the first two, right?
They have no idea. None.
So there's just something
in them that made them act.
The guy number three is talking about
circumstances like the world prepared him
for that moment. Serendipity. So it
makes me think, well, what if uh,
circumstances are just right? Maybe
any of us could do that. I'll get,
I'll get a mailman. He, he used to
say to me all the time, he says,
how did you manage to do that up? Or
how did you manage her pulling kids out?
I don't know if I could've done that.
I said, well, you know what? I'll say,
you wouldn't do this or you wouldn't do
that to you're put in that situation.
In fact, when we asked Walter, how
many nominations do you get a year,
are they hard to find?
No, they are not hard at all to find a,
we are fortunate to be living in a
society regardless of what you hear
elsewhere.
We are fortunate to be living in a society
where people do look out for others,
even strangers.
He told us they've even had to up their
guidelines to make it harder to win
simply because of the vast
number for road deeds that, uh,
happen in day to day life. Okay. Okay.
Um, I guess I gotta say that, um,
we went with is feel good thought about
about all the people who are doing good
views. I honestly don't think we knew
what to say to end that story. Well,
it's nice to know that there'd be
lot more good people than we thought,
but we went and we, we were
trying to figure out why people,
why people who do that do that and why
we're different or they're different than
us. And at the end we didn't really
get there. Ah, but then yeah,
this guy walks in, you should say,
just for our purposes who you are.
Once again, I'm Robert Sapolsky,
I'm a professor of neuroscience
at Stanford and university.
Robert has been on our program many,
many times talking about any number of
things and he had just come out with a
book called Behav trying to
explain why we do everything we do.
It goes into the brain and the
history, the culture, everything.
And we figured well maybe he would
have something to say about our,
our little puzzle. Yep. Probably.
Well let me just let, just ask you,
you've heard all three of
these things. What does this,
what do these three tails make you think?
I think what we see with all three is how
highfalutin moral reasoning plays like
zero role in what went on there. More
reasoning doesn't do anything. Right.
And you know, the first thing
that Robert Spolsky told us,
which maybe wasn't that surprising,
is that when we were asking
people what were they thinking,
that was sort of the wrong question.
And everybody as you saw, we
just gives the same answer,
which is I wasn't thinking,
I was feeling about what if this were my
16 year old daughter I hearing a voice
or with the bull woman saying, I
wasn't thinking like before I knew it,
I had jumped in.
The evidence suggests Soboleski
says that in situations like this,
people just don't reason their way to
a decision. That's not how it works.
Correct. People don't think
their way to or moral decision,
and in fact you give people enough
time to really think their way in a
circumstance like that.
Most people think their way to concluding
this isn't my problem or somebody else
will take care of it or here's why it's
their fault. So then we ask them, okay,
if it's not thinking or moral reasoning,
then maybe what these heroes are doing
is there. They're feeling they're there,
they're empathizing more
than the rest of us,
and that's why they do what they
do. Ironically, probably not.
I'm probably not. Yeah.
Okay. So empathy, you're,
you're feeling somebody else's
pain, pain, whether it's pain,
your toes on fire or pain, you're
feeling the pain of somebody else.
Pain is painful and if it's painful
enough and acute and burning enough,
what that translates
into is I can't take it.
This is too upsetting and you
need to run away at some point.
If you're mostly focused on
my God, what were this to be?
What would this feel like if
this were happening to me?
That's the predictor of people who don't
necessarily don't very readily make
that leap from feeling empathy to
actually acting compassionately.
Oh, that's not what I expected you to say.
I thought you were going to take it
the other way. So you're saying, okay,
when it's hot, when it's me, me, me,
me, me, might, your pain is my pain.
Those people are less likely
to step forward. Yeah, well,
they're less likely to actually
go and do the compassionate thing.
Spolsky told us that there have actually
been studies that have found this,
that when someone actually empathizes
physically feels in other person's pain,
they're more likely to turn away from
it rather than step forward and try and
alleviate that person's suffering.
You put somebody in a
circumstance and for example,
how many shocks are they willing to get
to intervene to help somebody in some
simulation game for example,
and you look at is this the person
whose heart rates sores when they see
somebody else in this tough situation
or is this the kind where it remains
fairly steady, the ladder is more
likely to act compassionately.
So interesting. Okay,
so what we're barreling towards here is
it's not so much about moral reasoning,
it's not so much about vast empathy,
but it's about a type of empathy that
allows you to remain detached enough to
actually act.
So emotional distance will create
the humane or charitable act.
Exactly. You need a certain
amount of detachment.
That's surprisingly where it comes in
and that runs counter to so many of our
instincts about what
empathy should be about.
And what I think we see here is probably
the most reliable realm of people going
in doing the heroic thing,
which is when it's implicit,
when it's automatic, when it's not,
you sitting there reasoning through,
well how many copies of my genes am I
going to pass on if I do this or among my
close relatives and
where it's not empathy,
oh am I feeling for this person or as
this person or with this person or above
this. And instead, before I knew it,
I had jumped in the
river to save this child.
And I think that's where you see
some of the most interesting,
reliably sort of heroic
stuff when it's implicit,
when it's automatic and know how a person
can get that kind of compassion made
implicit. Is it a,
is it something you're born with or
something cultural at your parents? Uh,
or do you have any idea?
The thing is we don't know a ton about
the neurobiology of how a moral good goes
from being a frontal
task to an implicit task.
But we know a ton about how that
works in a much more mundane area,
which is like you'll learn how to do
something like you're a pianist and you're
learning some new tough piece of music
and there's this really tough trill and
every time you're playing it, as you
approach the trail, you're thinking,
here at comes, remember,
Tuck your elbow in and lead
with your thumb and do this.
It is what would be called a
declarative task, declarative,
explicit knowledge. And that's
completely about this part of the brain,
the hippocampus talking to the frontal
Cortex, and it's sitting there saying,
here it comes, and remember how you do
it and remember how you do it wrong,
what happened last time and how great
it felt when you talk to your elbow in.
So remember to that.
And then suddenly there's the day where
you're playing the piece and you realize
your four measures past the trill
and you played it just fine.
That's the first day you played it without
having to think about it and jargon
in the learning field is it has stopped
being an explicit declarative task and
it's become an implicit procedural task.
That's the first time your hands,
no would better than your head.
Does me take somebody who's like beating
the pants off of you a tennis and
they've just done like some amazing
backhand and crushed you and what you need
to do strategically now is forced them
to take that procedural knowledge and
make it declarative again,
stop at that point and give him this
like obsequious smile. I said, oh my God,
you're an amazing tennis player. That
was an amazing shot. How did you do that?
Do you put your hand over on this side
or that side and what about your butt?
Are you scrunching your button on the
left side or the right and you force him?
It's like you make somebody like think
very explicitly and procedurally how you
go down flights of stairs and you're
going to fall down the stairs because none
of us have done stairs.
Proceduralise since we were
about two and a half years old,
a bunch of professors had swarmed over
our threes and released their first two
of our three sims. They might've
been ruined for the next experience,
but if you let them do their natural
thing, then they would rescue again.
Maybe if they could just keep it implicit.
Do you think that if it's implicit,
do you think that, uh, that there's, it's
a clean, it's a clean analogy. I mean,
do you think that that is the
people for whom it is automatic?
It's automatic because they've practiced
it in some way in the way that like
they probably in some
way, yeah. For example,
lots of studies were done as to which
people in either Germany or Nazi occupied,
uh, Europe, older Jews gave them shelter,
put their own laws at risk and it
wasn't predicted by level of education.
There goes all that moral reasoning
stuff and it wasn't even particularly
predicted by things like religiosity
was people who had simply been raised,
you do the right thing. It was
automatic. It was implicit for them.
They didn't have to sit there and think
about or feel about it was automatic
because that, thank you mommy and Daddy.
Is that what that is? Thank you mommy.
Daddy, rabbi priest. What is
that? I think it's mostly that,
but of course it's messier than playing
a trail on a piano or doing a tennis
backhand.
I mean people first learned about it
and you literally can see the transition
from which part of the brain's handling
the task. So the initial view was, okay,
that's how you do trills on the piano.
But then you see something
even more amazing,
which is more complex stuff happens. My,
my father in his last years
had a pretty severe dementia.
Um, he was a professor,
he was an architectural historian and
he reached a point where he could not
identify the names of all of this kids
consistently, didn't know where he was,
what decade, etc.
But prompt him and he could
give you this totally lucid,
opinionated, cranky, entertaining,
10 minute lecture on the history of
flying buttresses and then come back two
minutes later and prompt him again and
he'd give you the exact same one again.
For him, that was as
implicit as, you know,
the tennis player doing the backhand
or playing the trolls on the piano.
When I fully expect when I'm demented,
someday I'll give this exact
lecture that I just gave in.
I can do it over and over and over
until the student's complaint.
So all sorts of stuff.
More complex than a tennis
backhand becomes implicit.
I think what we're seeing with the woman
with the bowl there in the electric
fence is some incredibly high level
abstract stuff becomes implicit as well.
You don't like fling your elbow way out
to the right when you do the trill and
you don't stand by and watch somebody
being like done in you just before you
know it, you don't reason. You don't
feel you just do it. Before I knew it,
I had run in there. No. Is
this one of your lectures?
Do you talk about this very
thing? Um, in other words,
when we come and visit you in 13 years,
will you be treating us with this
very elect? Precisely. Empathy.
Empathy is an interesting topic.
Sit down. This will be on the final.
Okay, good.
Big, big thanks to Robert Sapolsky, whose
new book is called Behave [inaudible].
This piece was produced by Amanda
Arran Cheque and um, if you liked it,
this story and it's Kinda got you
thinking, go and listen to our good show,
which is@radiolab.org. It's a lot of
stuff in the good show. Lots of stuff.
There's a lot of good in good
chef and the good show. Yes,
I'm Jad Abumrad and Robert
[inaudible]. Thanks for listening.
This is Graham Ellwood from Memphis.
Radiolab was created by Jad Abumrad
and is produced by Soren Wheeler.
Dylan Keefe is our
director of sound design.
Maria Matisha Patea is our managing
director. Our staff includes Simon Adler,
Becca Bressler, Rachel Cusick, David
Gebel, Bethel hub t Tracy hunt,
mad Kielty, Robert Krulwich,
Annie Mcewen, Latif Nasser,
Melissa O'Donnell,
Arianne Wack, Pat Walters,
and Molly Webster with help from
Amanda Aronchick. Shima Oli David Fox,
Nygaard Fatali, Phoebe
wink, and Katie Ferguson.
Our fact checker is Michelle Harris.