You are listening to radio lab radio lash
fromW and y. S. E
n n p. R. Three two one.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich. This
is radio lab, the podcast.
And lately we at radio lab have become
a bit robot obsessed and we met a guy.
All right. My name is Latif Nasser,
he's a Grad student in the history
of science department at Harvard.
And he got us thinking about really
old robots like hundreds of years old.
And I, for example, I've heard
rumors whispered by store,
mostly a about a pooping duck approve. Oh,
so the pooping duck is really famous.
Actually the duck wasn't
really eating and pooping.
They had like a store of like
pre pre pooped duck poop.
I don't know what it was.
Look like duck poop maybe.
And you would feed this robot duck and
then watch it actually pool. I mean,
all you see is you see sort of this in
and this out and people believed it.
People thought this was a,
this was a pooping duck. Um,
and so we talked about a bunch of these
ancient robots and most of them were
kind of funny.
But then he told us about one
in particular that was actually,
it was kind of haunting.
Yes. Not poopy at all.
So the year is a 1562
this is 450 years ago,
not so long after Columbus, Ferdinand
and Isabella, and as a new king of Spain.
Phillip. Phillip. Yeah. And he has
a son, the 17 year old crown prince.
His name is Don Carlos. And one
day he's in the royal lodgings.
I was walking down a flight
of stairs. He trips, he falls,
he bashes his head against a door
near the bottom of the stairs.
This is the crown prince, you
say the crown prince of Spain.
So this is a national clam,
but it is a national calamity because
he's the heir apparent. Right. So, so,
well at first it doesn't look like it's
such a bad injury. He's still conscious,
but then his head starts to
swell to this kind of crazy size.
He becomes delirious and
feverish. He's struck blind. Oh.
And so at this point the, the king comes
right? This is King Philip the second.
So he is at this time, he is the most
powerful man in the world, right?
So he basically controls
the, all of the Americas.
He controls much of Europe. The
Philippines is named after him.
He was tight with the pope at this time.
The pope and the king were kind
of like, you know, BFF. So,
so the whole Spanish court is
going nuts. Um, across the country.
People are uh, seeing this, reading
this as a kind of sign that uh,
that God's very angry. Right.
And so they're, they're fasting.
They're doing these kinds of uh,
prayer precessions things like this.
And according to a lot,
if the king calls all the best doctors
in Europe to come to Spain to help his
son and these doctors
are trying everything.
They are drilling a hole in his
skull to relieve the pressures,
relieve the pressure. They are
bleeding him and blistering him.
And they are purging him to the extent
that he has like 20 bowel movements
within just like a certain hours.
They're like smearing all
over the wound. They're,
they're smearing like Turpentine
and honey and Pudong Carlos,
even after all of this, um, they
sort of look at each other. They,
they look at him and it's kind of
like, this is, he's going to die.
It's so he's dying. Yeah.
He's basically on his death.
[inaudible]
so at this point, according to
lot of the king goes to the son,
Legend goes that he kneels beside his
son at his son's death bed and he makes a
pact with God. The pact is, if
you help me, if you heal my son,
if you do this miracle for me, I'll
do a miracle for you. Wow. Let's,
that's uh, it's quite a hubris stick of
a, of a human being to say to God, Oh,
a little Tulsa. Remember
the, he's the, he,
the most powerful men in the world at
this. He is a god among men. Really? Yeah.
You bristly or not? This is,
this is what he says. Yeah. Okay.
All of a sudden his son just gets better.
Really within a week. He can see
again within a month. He, he,
it's as if he didn't
volatile.
He just pops right back up.
Yeah.
And King Philip must have thought,
well my God, this is exactly is my God.
It's probably exactly what he called
and when his son can finally speak,
he says to him, Dad, you know, the
weirdest thing happened when I was out.
I had this dream. Oh, that's a
great story. This is Elizabeth King.
I'm an artist and a professor in
the Sculpture Department at Virginia
Commonwealth University. She's
actually the one that hooked a lot.
Tough on the story. Yup.
In any case, the dream,
there are documents of Don Carlo next
morning saying that he had had a dream,
this vision that better
there a figure in a,
in a Franciscan habit,
shaved head sharpen,
knows this marvelous monk entered his
room and approached his deathbed holding
across and basically told
him, you're going to be fine.
And that's quite well
documented. Apparently there
was a witness in the room,
in the sick room with him that night,
overheard the prince talking to a ghost,
sort of mumbling things in his delirium.
So Don Carlos has this stream.
Suddenly he's fine in the natural question
that people are asking is who is this
monk? Yeah, yeah. I mean is it just a
generic Mongo? Is it somebody specific?
Some Messenger from God
and from his description,
physical description and the shaved head.
The point he knows the monks habit
piercing eyes, even though kind of cross,
he was using kind of everybody in town,
the king, everyone was like, oh yeah,
like we know exactly who this guy is.
Can only really be one guy kind of local
fryer who died a hundred years before
named a Diego de Alcala, Diego de Alcala.
Who is he?
He is a local holy figure who was
corpse was associated with a number of
documented miracles. In fact,
this guy was so holy in this town,
actually not just in the town.
You want to know something?
There's a bit of trivia ever heard of
San Diego, California you mean? Yeah,
as in the Padres. What does he have
to, is this the same guy? Same guys,
but he was the patron saint of the
people who found it. San Diego is holy,
so holy in this town.
Then people believed his
corpse is 100 year dead corpse,
had healing powers. And some
people, they're different stories.
But some people say that
even they, uh, these,
that unbeknownst to Don Carlos,
that night that he had the dream,
the priesthood and the king
himself according to some
stories went and they got
this corpse out of the
church, out of the crypt.
They carried it through the streets.
They brought it to the bedroom.
They literally put it, they sort of
snuck it in bed with a don Carlos.
And that's how you healed. They didn't
stick him in bed with this bone. Right.
They just say they brought him into
the room. There's different reports.
There's a picture of him in this
engraving. Oh. Um, and if you can,
you probably can't see it, but
look at this picture right here.
She had a, uh, a copy of a 16th,
see roughly of 16th century
woodcut showing you this
scene where you could kind
of see, oh wait, so
he's in bed. The two men in bed together
or about to be, well, they couldn't be,
you know, they could be just laying
him down. Okay. Caught in the middle.
Meanwhile, back to our story,
you got Philip the second who
has asked God for a miracle.
God came through through this monk
and now fill out the second is like,
oh, I got to deliver King Philip
the second. Oh, he's got a miracle.
Yes he does. And he's,
he's acutely aware of this.
So basically what he does is he
enlists this really renowned clockmaker
a clockmaker. Yup.
Named one Nelo Tory Yana
one Nelo two Riano. Yeah.
A huge band,
upbeat ox of a man described as always
being filthy and blustery and model a lot
of fun to beat.
Okay.
But a great, great clockmaker.
Certainly among the best in Spain,
maybe the entire holy Roman empire.
So the king goes to this
guy and he says, look,
I want you to make a mechanical
version of Diego de Alcala.
What? A mechanical version of
this 100 year dead holy priest.
Yes. Like a mechanical monk. A
robotic Ponderay. Yeah. Which,
and this I did not expect,
still exist now the monk bodies in the
Smithsonian. Perfect working order.
No Way. I swear, I swear
that since 1977 no. Yeah.
The first time I saw this speaker,
I was drawn to it and then repel.
That's Carlene Stephens. She is a
curator at the Smithsonian in DC.
About a week after I
left the fund I spoke,
we ended up in DC meeting
with her and she showed us.
Oh Wow. Wow.
The monk who lives in a little glass case,
what we have here is an
automaton over 400 years old.
Um, so the first, is this the first
robot that we know of? No, no, no, no.
Idiot.
The ancient Greeks had things
that could be considered robots.
Okay. Back to our story, 450 some
odd years ago. Our clockmaker,
what's his name? Tory Yanno Dariano.
He goes into his shop and he does
whatever he does next one gear to another,
to another for hours, weeks, months.
No idea how long it takes and
I don't think anybody does,
but emerges one day into the
bright sunshine with luck.
What did you call it? A
robotic Ponderay. Yeah.
It's a 15 inch high figure made of
wood and iron has the sort of habit,
has it, the sandals, has the rosary,
has the cross and poking out at the
top of the habit is a little bald,
hairless head with that sharp
nose, like a, like a razor.
And the rather ferocious,
I like intense or like
a like doing business.
Ferocious like I'm focused,
I'm focused like maybe I'm only 15
inches tall but I am focused on something
much bigger than you. You human.
So did you like turn it on or
push something? Yeah, that,
why would I get on a train and go
for three hours? Just look at it.
Obvious question. Okay. Do you wouldn't
mind? Sure. Yeah. Okay. Okay. Do it.
So Carlene takes us out into the
hall, we sit down on the floor,
she gives lot tiff a little brass key.
He sticks it into the secret
slot in the, amongst the side,
I think it goes
counterclockwise. You went can,
you would tend to want to do it this way
and lots of winds up the monk turning
it counter clockwise and it's surprisingly
sort of taught how much should I
turn. And so if you sort of wind
up this sort of secret spring,
I think there's a stop and it'll,
okay. All right. I'm going,
I'm going put it on the ground,
right. All right. You let them go.
Give them a place. Walk very slowly.
One foot after the other coming out
from under the Catholic. In fact,
there's actually a
little wheel under there,
but yet you see the teeth coming out.
The head is turning from right to left.
The eyes are rolling in the head and
mouth is opening and closing is if it's
sort of monitoring like a prayer,
the arms are in motion. One arm
is raising and lowering cross.
The other arm is beating the chest. Wow.
A symbolic gesture. Who? Catholic
that is called the mayor.
Kulpa after three or four steps in the
arm holding the cross though something
new,
it moves to different new directions
to bring the cross to the mouth.
And the figure kisses. The clock.
It's bodily. Like mesmerizing.
Yeah. Yeah.
The next thing is doing is it's turning
and moving in a different direction and
then walking its paces and kissing
across as we watched it turn once,
then twice, then three times, four times.
Let it go back to where it started.
So if you imagine a table with a
number of people sitting around it,
probably it's going to sort of at one
point or another head for you and then
turn away and head for someone
else and then turn away.
Why would the king of Spain who
could have, you know, I don't know,
built a church or, or taking a crusade
to Jerusalem or done something, you know,
he could've done anything.
Why did he decide to commemorate his
son's revival by making a little automatic
doll? Like what was that for? Yeah, lots
of, what was he thinking? Yeah, it's a,
it's a good quote. That's the $64,000
question. It's a great question.
It's a really good question.
The truth is there's really no way to
know for sure. As a historian, I gotta,
I gotta rely on the documentation and
this not a whole lot of that in this case,
but one interpretation certainly
could be that, you know,
the king had this amazing,
miraculous thing happened to his son and
now we had a way of sharing that with
his subjects because he's got this
device where it's a, it's an illusion,
like the machinery of it. It's completely
hidden. There's no visible man that's,
yeah.
That's one of the craziest parts that
it's all sort of hidden underneath the,
the robe. So when he put it down
on a table or in a court yard,
people would have seen it move on its own.
They would have been amazed as we
were, and he could have said, look,
here is the miracle. Look
what God did for our country.
God likes Spaniards. Yeah.
Look at what God did for Spain,
which would have been a useful thing for
a king to be able to say, right? Yeah.
That's, so that's one possibility.
The other is it just on
a more utilitarian level?
This was a machine that was built to
pray and this was a period when you could
by prayer repetition.
So if you had the money,
you could get someone to pray for you
while you go do something else. Oh,
that's, you're cool. You're
covered, you're covered.
And if you think about it
from Phillip's perspective,
he needed to say thank you to God.
And here he had this thing that if he
wound up was an automated thank you
machine. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you. Thank you. Yeah. Can we thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Or it could be,
I love you, I love you. I love love.
It could also be, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. It could be please, please,
please, please, please. But if you need,
but if you think about it more
expansively says lot of like,
what did it mean at that time to be a
catholic? Like what did it really mean?
Well then this robot was maybe the
Catholic you could ever hope to be.
What counted his prayer was, was,
was quite specific in the sense that
if you say the right things and,
and do the right actions
in the right order,
in the right time and in the
right place, Sorta, that's prayer.
That's when God notice it. So it's about
method, it's about method, it's about,
and maybe this monk he says was like
method embody. That's a good one. I mean,
why not, right? It is in fact perfect.
It repeats itself over and over and
over and it replicates the idea.
So it's basically what it is is a
little, a little teaching object.
Like this is what you're aiming for.
Here's how you do it. Like this is it,
this is the perfect prayer.
It's a perfect prayer.
This is doing it the perfect way every
time. And I, because I'm, I'm just this,
you know, lowly, imperfect
human. Um, I'm not,
I can only aspire to this perfect piety
that you're making this up or do you
think that this might, the monk
might've actually been seen this way.
It could be true. I don't
think it's so crazy,
especially if you think about what was
happening at that moment and this is
counter-reformation Spain, right?
Not so long after Luther, you know,
is nailing his theses on the wall and
there's this big debate raging about how
actually do you get closer to God and
you'll have the kind of protesters with
with Luther who are saying
it's not about you know works.
It's not about saying
something this many times.
It's about whether you feel it and then
you have the kind of Catholic argument,
which is to say you do these
rituals because these are
the rituals and these are
the way you get. This is the way you get
close to God. This is the way you pray.
You pray like this thing
Josh, like this thing.
If you're a Catholic
Kenyan, if God's a Catholic,
you better hope he is and if you're
filled the second you look at the sky and
you say, God,
you and me are square
special. Thanks to a lot of
Nasser. Yes. Latte. Yeah.
Graduate Student at Harvard History
of Science Department and to Sarah
[inaudible] production
help on this story. Thanks.
Also to the amazing Elizabeth King,
Carlene Stephens at the Smithsonian
end to David Todd. David actually, um,
is himself an expert. Clockmaker he
constructed a, a replica of the monk,
which is actually what we heard because
at the monk itself is very old and you
don't want to be winding that
thing. But big thanks to David Todd,
we couldn't have done
this piece without him.
And actually he and Elizabeth King
will be publishing a book soon,
which is called a machine,
a ghost, and a prayer.
The story of a 16th century
mechanical monk. And thanks.
Lastly to Stephen Vitiello, who recorded
clock sounds in David Todd's workshop,
which we used in the piece. Huh?
I'm exhausted from this thing.
I see so much gratitude. And of
course, thank you. Really? Yes.
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.