You are listening to radio lab radio
from [inaudible] W N Y s e
n n p. R. Alright.
For the money for all the glory
for the Gold Robert Jad take four.
Hey, I'm Jen. I have them Rod. I
remember killing that actually.
I'm a jab boom rod. I remembered
Krulwich this is radio lab, the podcast,
the podcast. So we've been talking about
animals for the last few podcasts. Um,
particularly how difficult it is to
find something like a shared space.
We're building to the podcast that
follows this one where we've got this
enormous and wonderful
story. But this one, uh,
the podcast you're about to hear is um,
an elegant and kind of momentary
communion between us and them.
Hi, this is Michigan radio. I have
your guest. Hi, this is Barb. Hi,
this is Robert [inaudible] and
how do you say your last name?
Smart Smiths and that splits. But Smith's,
Barbara Smith is a professor
at the University of Michigan
where I teach courses
on animal behavior. And back in the 70s,
she moved to Kenya in
Africa to a remote area.
We out on the plains fairly open grassland
and she tried to get friendly and
then get access to a
troop of baboons. No. How,
what was the deal like you
would wake up, drive some Leer,
get out of your van or whatever, walk him.
I get the break of day before the break
of day and then follow them around all
day for how many days? A week?
Seven for for weeks at a time or
a month at a time or two years.
Two years. Yeah.
Um,
this trip hadn't been studied before,
so they were afraid of people,
but because the
area was very open, it was possible
to approach them from a distance.
She positioned herself, you know, like
about a hundred feet away. And then,
yeah,
and day by day I would
kind of inch closer,
80 feet away, 50 feet.
And then as soon as they started
running, I would stop moving
towards them.
She says sometimes they would
flash their teeth at her long,
sharp canine teeth and then
she'd edge off pretty scary.
And then slowly she'd try again.
I can get a little bit closer.
Mm.
30 feet,
20 feet
until finally after a couple of months
I got close enough so that I could see
their faces.
I could record and begin to recognize
them as individuals and they could
recognize me. That's when
things started to shift.
It was like they realized that I was a
social animal like them and that we could
negotiate the distance between
us. How does that work?
I started by just talking to them,
telling them that I wasn't a threat
in English or in gratefulness.
Yet all mammals recognize that a, um,
fairly high pitched voice is someone
who's not threatening as opposed to a very
deep voice, which scares them.
So I would talk to them in a light
tone of voice to reassure them.
Finally,
I got to the point where I could be just
a few feet from them and nobody would
even glance at me. And what if one comes
up to you and goes or whatever they do.
Then I would think it was a warthog at
Boone grunt sound like,
Huh, Huh, Huh, Huh,
okay. They smack their lips in between
grunts the fee if they do that to you.
And they're getting
closer. What do you do?
You would respond in kind
or what do you do? Yes.
Sometimes I would respond in
kind with it. With the grant.
It's not polite.
If someone says something to you to
just act like a rock leaves that,
would that be an insult? Yes.
Say hello when I say hello,
it's excellence, but isn't this one
of these rules of field biology?
Aren't you supposed to act like you're
not there and they'll act like you're
not? Yeah, but it doesn't
really work that way.
They're social animals and
they know that you are,
so your solution was to become,
as I figured it's you're like you be
try to become even very shy. Baboo yeah,
shy and pretty boring. And did that work?
Did you pick 10 I found
myself very naturally sitting
the way that many baboons
do,
which is they stick their legs out in
front of them and they hold their toes.
The longer I was with them, the more,
well completely automatic it
became for me to be shy by Boone.
I didn't have to think
about it. I just was,
as this progressed as are you beginning
to feel like you're a shy bubble? Yeah,
I felt increasingly, uh,
aware of my animal self.
I mean the scientist is doing the
things the scientists needs to do,
but I think I was kind of
in this a sub universe.
Me and the baboons I was going where they
went and resting when they rested and
walking when they want.
And one day she says she saw a beautiful
baby gazelle prancing by and the
baboons pouched on the animal
rifted apart to eat it.
And watching Barbara admits
that she salivated. Yeah,
I did. I couldn't help it.
And I am a vegetarian,
but she says the real transforming moment
was she was out on the plains one day
and [inaudible]
I got caught in this pouring
rain and lost the baboons.
So I headed downhill to toward the
lake because that was the way home.
And when I got to the
beach it was still boring.
So I [inaudible] did to this hut.
There were these little, um,
fishermen's huts on the
beach that were empty,
completely dark inside.
And after I was in there
for a minute or two,
my eyes started adjusting to the dark
and first thing I noticed were these sort
of lumpy shapes.
And then I realized that there
were bad balloons in there.
And as my vision got better,
I I could see about 15 or 20 members
of my troop who had gone into the hut
probably just before me. I
had the same idea that I had.
And um, I,
I was quite touched that they were silent
when I moved in there and that nobody,
you know, nobody said, are you
doing in here? This is our hot,
they were just silent.
I think someone even shifted over
slightly to make room for me.
And we just sat there
for about 15 minutes,
started to kind of steam up, you know,
from their breath and they smell it
kinda like grass and leaves cause that's
what they've been eating.
It's a nice smell.
Did you ever think for
even that at all a while,
maybe in that hut was the moment.
Do you ever think that you
had done something close to
some kind of trespass or,
ah, did you steal something
here? I, no, no, no, no.
That was just in a weird, we are so
loose used to this dividing line.
There's humans on one side and then
there's all the other animals on the other
side and we don't meet up.
But if you go back in
evolutionary time, I mean,
that line wasn't there. So rather than
feeling like I was stealing something,
I felt like I was retrieving
something that was my heritage.
Hmm.
It felt so completely
natural to just be with them,
to not be doing anything, to just be
[inaudible].
Barbara Smiths now spends her
days in Ann Arbor, Michigan,
cheesy teachers here
at the beak university,
and her African days are well
there now a couple of decades old.
But what a tale. Yeah. Speaking of tails,
we are at the tail end
of this little podcast.
If you want any more information on this
piece or anything you've ever heard on
this program. radiolab.org is
the place. I'm Chan Abu Miranda.
I'm Robert Krulwich.