Three, two, one. Hey, I'm Jad
[inaudible]. I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and this, this like this.
This is Alex bellows. Okay. He's a writer.
He's written a lot about sports. Uh,
particularly about Brazilian soccer
but also math or he likes to say maths.
And when I read my first math
book, here's looking at Euclid,
I went and gave loads of talks and at
the end of the talk that all be someone
who put their hands up and they'd
say, what's your favorite number?
And this used to just irritate me because
I myself don't have a favorite number.
You don't have a favorite
number? No, I think it's stupid.
I know that's actually incorrect.
I did think it was stupid.
I just didn't have one. Okay. And
why would the question annoy him?
[inaudible] to me it's the most
normal question you could ask. Well,
but this is, remember this is this is,
he's talking about a math
book to math enthusiasts.
What's your favorite numbers?
Like sort of a, it's like,
it's too silly or maybe it's
like they're making fun of him.
I got so free rated that once I think
I was a bit tired. It was like, Hey,
I don't know where the Gig was. And I
just said, well it's your favorite number,
just turning it back at the person
in the audience. And they said,
um Oh 12 I was shocked with it. But you,
you weren't asking me because you were
kind of taking the piss out of the math.
No,
you actually really wanted to know because
you wanted to share your own favorite
number. And he's like, oh yeah.
And then the person sitting
next to them were like, yeah,
like mine's eight and then my mind seven.
And I thought this is interesting and I
can remember asking the audience as well
who he has got a favorite number and at
least half the people put their hands
up.
And in a way that you go from being a
smoker when you stopped smoking to be like
a rabbit. Anti-Smoker I went
from being your favorite number,
agnostic to being obsessed with
favorite numbers. B started a website,
favorite number. Dot Net. You know,
just asking people to hit the question
and I put it out there and I helped them
out on my blog and I had
within the first few weeks,
I actually more than 30,000 people.
Hello? Hello. Hi. From all over the
world. This is Jenny from round lake,
New York. My name is Sitar from
Dubai, [inaudible] Sydney, Australia,
[inaudible] Bhaskar, Norway
telling me their favorite numbers.
My favorite number is definitely
eight 30 29 11 and the reasons why,
the reason it's four is because my
favorite card is ace of spades and it's
commonly called the death card.
My birth date is four 1459
so by from nine is four.
My favorite number is 100
because it is two zeroes.
Okay, so here's what's fascinating about
this, at least to me. First of all,
the volume of response.
He got about 30,000 submissions
from all over the planet.
We put out a call on our app, which are
the voices you're listening to here.
And we got 30,000 no, we got a
gin. That's good. That's okay.
I clearly people want to talk about
their favorite numbers and about their
reasons which are
from the heart. The numbers.
Five was always a friend cause it feels
like home and family and it's kind of
whole and balanced. People
talked about it in emotional
terms, really warmness, coolness,
standoffishness inviting this.
It's this a hole in emotional landscapes
in here under the numbers and nothing
to do the numbers really, but it's just
there. It was there from the very start.
Okay. First of all, where do
numbers go? Who invented them? Well,
it depends what you mean by numbers.
If by numbers mean this idea that we can
tell the difference between two things
and three things and we'll then we've
had that ever since and if humans existed
and you can test on
animals and they do it too,
but if you're talking
about symbols and words,
abstractions to designate
specific numbers.
This is probably only about 5,000
years old and was an invention of the
Sumerians,
which is basically Iraq and Alex is
from the moment they came up with these
samples,
they then added sort of extra
layers of utterly [inaudible] stuff.
Writes, like, let's take the
Sumerian word for one. Um,
and apologies for my accent and Sumerian
fall. You, I am, I assuming
it's been very rough, I guess,
which has ges, I, I usually
say get pass. Yes. Yeah.
Or however you say it.
That's the word for one.
And that is also the word for Phallus.
And the word for to is min mean,
which is also the word for woman.
And one can only really speculate,
but there are, you know why.
One is man and two as women,
it could be, um, could be,
they had some sort of Adam and
eve notion in mind, like me first.
You second or could be our distinguishing
feature is that we have one of what
makes us a man and that woman has
two breasts, where to look, look,
whatever they were thinking,
they were not the only ones to
be thinking along these lines.
You go forward 3000 years, 3000 years
later, you get to [inaudible], right?
The [inaudible] theorem guy
yet. So Pythagoras repeated.
The one is male, two is female thing.
By saying that odd numbers or masculine
and even numbers were feminine,
even tried to justify by
saying look like do the,
do the calculations here because
when you add even to odd,
say three plus two, you get odd five,
which means that when
you add man to woman,
you get man said man is kind
of stronger, um, than, than,
than women by that logic.
Odd plus odd makes even so what
does that two males make a female?
I mean the whole thought is
a little farfetched to me.
So that is Steve Strogatz, professor of
math at Cornell, irregular on our show,
friend of radio lab.
Peter of the Pythagorean way of thinking
about numbers except for the triangle
thing, which he loved. But, but
here's what's weird, is it, you know,
go 5,000 years after the Sumerians and
right up to the present time when Alex
does this worldwide survey though,
what's your favorite number thing? Years.
Something weirdly familiar. I
will just read you for example,
some of the adjectives and reasons why
people prefer the number one strong,
strong, independent
pendant, honest, brave,
brave, different tying earring,
lonely, lonely cowboys.
Knows your cowboy words. Exactly.
A picture,
the number one as a man in a really
nicely tailored Italian suit.
He's got dark hair.
I don't know why it's like Marcella
Mastriani rather than John Wayne too.
Cautious wise, pretty
soft, nurturing, cold,
fragile, very personal.
Unintimidating open, a friendly,
relational, sympathetic, complimentary,
quiet, easy to understand. Flexible.
It makes more sense. The kind of
feminist kind of feminine, well,
stereotypically feminine and we use our
both men and women contributing these
descriptors for these
two numbers. Yeah. Yeah.
That was really striking to me and
it made me think, do you know what?
We could all laugh at Pythagoras and the
Sumerians and all the kind of ancient
people saying, well one is
male and two is female bits.
Some fragments of that remain this way.
This is not like a scientific
study well serve actually.
The more that you look, there's
kind of some science behind it.
In fact, there's a guy and
this study in Indiana, a place,
you know a yes. This guy, James Wilkie,
assistant professor of the university,
you know, or damn. So James and
his team, here's what they do.
They take a baby that's just
been born. Yeah, a few weeks old.
Impossible to say. Just with the
face, whether it's [inaudible].
So you had to get a 50 50 they show
people pictures of these androgynous,
a little bay region buried over in the
side where you would hardly notice them.
All heart strings of four
or five digit numbers.
Numbers happen to be either all even
or all odd. Right? And James Guy say,
don't worry about those. They there,
they're there for the storage.
These are tracking numbers.
Go ahead and adore these.
Just focus on the babies and the
pictures and tell us male, female,
just look at the face and tell us
whether it's a male or a female.
And it turns out that if a
baby is next to our digits,
you're more likely to say that it's a by
that f the baby is next to even digits
really well with me. How much more
likely by a lot or by a teeny bit.
By statistically significant
amount, not a landslide.
Do you yourself assign any gender
to either one? Do you find odd?
A little more male in some, no, not at
all. No. I've never felt that at all.
I've known that they were a bit different
because they sort of feel different.
So he decided to investigate just to
see if there's anything behind it. Yeah.
Why not? Which led him and us to
a guy named Greg Roland. Okay.
Okay. This is Robert. Hi Robert.
How are you? This is Andy.
I'm a producer working with
Robert m d so first of all,
can you just tell us like w
e you have a peculiar job,
I guess at least peculiar to
me. Like what do you do? Well,
I have founded a company called the
semiotic alliance, which is a business,
right? It is a consultancy. Yeah.
So Greg is paid very good money,
but some of the biggest
brands in the world,
Coca Cola for IBM to give them advice
about how their brands would go down.
We look at people's emotional responses
to culture, symbols and ideas.
On the basis of this, we can help
companies with packaging, advertising.
And often he says what that means is he's
helping companies harness the symbolic
power of numbers. I think
one of the most exciting, um,
encounters with mathematics
for me was with KFC
with the 11 Herb's a spices
who, who
[inaudible] 11 witches
capitalistic in its,
in its secrecy. Such a
strange number. Well,
I thought that Colonel Sanders was in his
experimental kitchen and just and just
happened to Sanders. You
southern Oh Sanders fan.
Colonel Sanders was in his kitchen and
he was just fiddling around and he came
up with 11 herbs. We call
the herbs here and spices.
That's one version of the truth.
But the symbolic truth is far more
interesting and potent 11 has enormous
mystical potential simply because
it's not 10 or 12 or five.
It's not a sensible number.
What's wrong with 10 if I say
with my 10 herbs and spices,
because with tenure implying
that you have a decimal balance.
So work is going to be very hard to
engage people emotionally with with 10 10
Phil's ordered feels highly rational.
Greg says it may have something to do
with the fact that you have only 10
fingers are looking at them.
Dan as seven 11 just is that extra
one that has made Colonel Saunders on
copyable and the same thing might be
happening with five oh one jeans like you
know,
why is it five oh one jad and not 505 oh
one again has just gone one beyond the
place you would expect to get to wait
a second. What if you don't want that?
What if you want a product where
you need to play it safe? Well
then you can stick with multiples of
10 which is really useful when you're
trying to be practical or sorry,
tip it absolutely. For example,
I'm being attacked. We're
winning the war against sin.
Take the act, be cream, oxy
10 which viewing your face,
I know you're not entirely unfamiliar
with it. 10 there is obviously,
you know that's where
we get to a solution.
That's where are the fingers
on our hands run out.
So there is a sense of completion there.
The sense of we've gone through the
process and we're going to come out. Okay.
Um, and of course that's why
11 is interesting. Just your,
your embarking into the infinite. Um,
at that point you're going to be
on the human finger count. Ah,
interesting.
[inaudible]
11 herbs and spices. That's right.
How did the you say that as if you want
to taste the thing I do like I used to
love getting that as a kid.
I did the 11 did the 11 number 11
some tickle you in any way? Yes,
definitely would not buy it
with 10 herbs and spices.
That sounds very solid
and Stalinist. Really?
No, I'm Yanking, I'm yanking. I'm
yanking your wishbone. Oh really?
I was kind of hoping, no, I
don't mean it. No, come on.
I got to agree with Steve. Like the, the,
the idea that 11 is mystical
because it's one more than 10 mm.
Although with 10 I think he has
a point. It is boring. I agree.
Here's just a fact.
Big Companies With Large Checkbooks
called Greg up all the time for it.
I think the thing about numbers is
that because they are so rational, uh,
so abstract for that very reason, they
ask you us in some way. Bizarre. Huh?
I think human beings have an absolute
need to invest emotion, love,
hate,
fear to invest in non rational into things
which seem almost obscenely rational.
Hmm.
My magic number is number eight.
I turned age 18 on October the eighth
1988.
Number four because I want a
swimming race in a plane for
as a child.
My favorite number is three because
to me it recalls to mind the trinity.
Now, however you feel
about all this stuff,
one thing that seems
pretty interesting to us,
I had to Alex's you'd expect if you were
asking the world to give you a favorite
number, that'd be a huge difference
from one culture to the next.
13 is an unlucky number.
You don't have a 13th floor in America
in Korea that doesn't have a fourth floor
because it's unlucky for
over there. Yeah. Yeah.
But here's something
interesting. The entire plan,
all the continents and everyone in
all the continents came to a kind of
consensus around one number. Yeah.
So tell me Alec,
what was the world's favorite number?
I hope you got some good audio
of a drum roll coming up.
Movie [inaudible] myself
seven it's seven. My favorite
number is seven. I like the number,
say favorite number is number seven
and we heard pretty much the same thing
in second place was three and
the third place was there. Yeah,
but it was a big win for seven 30% I had
a three I became really interested in
seven because yes, we all
lose the favorite number,
but why is it the people's favorite
number and when did that begin?
And I have one. Oh Great. I love
hearing reason. Holes in your head.
Years two and two. One in one
nozzles. Three and four. Five yeah.
Six and seven. Yeah. Seven,
seven holes in your head.
There is no way that can be true.
Well then then look up at the night sky
and BMS at potassium so you don't have
a, what do you see? The Sun,
the moon and five planets.
Seven you spend the whole night
looking at seven. Yeah, of course.
That's not what you hear from people.
Then number seven just looks beautiful.
What you hear from people.
It's about how beautiful it.
I liked the way it looks when I write
it is a good looking number or how it
sounds. Sounds beautiful. Sounds perfect.
A lot of people came in about the sentence
sound of seven. I get on that train.
I think seven comes out of your
mouth real nicely. Yes. Sevens set.
I just didn't feel like the number
seven belongs to me. I guess.
[inaudible] it even sounds
good in Arabic, right? Yeah.
Hebrew Sheva really similar. See
it. Oh it sounds great. In Spanish.
Oh this. This makes me feel a little sad.
Not to get silly but on you,
but there's a certain pleasure that people
are getting that I'm not getting from
numbers ever. Cause I feel like,
like if someone says eight is curvy,
part of me feels you're talking about the
shape of the way that we draw than the
number eight as a numeral.
That has nothing to do with
the number eight talking about.
It's the way I see you say eight to
me. I see. I don't see eight apples.
I see that curd IC, the two circles,
one on top of the other best
income makes me, that makes me sad.
That makes me feel like you're missing
the reality of the number eight which is
that eight has intrinsic properties.
That's really dry speak, but,
but eight eight is a, I mean like 10 okay.
10 to me is much more like when you go
to the bowling alley and the 10 pins are
lined up in that triangle pattern. Yeah.
You know what I'm talking about? Yeah.
There's the one and the two
then the three, then the four.
That is a gorgeous way to think about
10 10 is about this magnificent symmetry
that can make a triangle, but seven is
a disaster as a mathematical object.
I mean it doesn't have nice symmetries.
If I tried to put bowling pins
down with seven it's ugly.
However you arrange it to me,
so it makes me feel left out that I
can't have the same fun that other people
are having. Okay. But if you ask Alex,
why is seven the world's favorite
number he says is because seven is
arithmetically unique.
If the only digit of the first 10
numbers that can either be multiplied or
divided within the group,
so one, two, three, four,
five we can double them and
they stay under 10 in the group.
You've got to keep them in the group six
what's left? Seven weeks? We had six,
eight and 10 as you can have them and
the ones left are seven and nine and nine
you can find by three. So seven is unique.
So you think that there's
enough arithmetic in
everybody that without having
worked it out as
painfully as you just did,
people will still find that there's
something unusual about seven
mathematically, not about memories,
not about culture, not about shape,
just about the math itself. You cannot
separate the math of all of those things.
The way we understand numbers is to do
with their arithmetic and that it's,
the arithmetic has been
absorbed by culture and sort
of the greatest example of
that is the predominance of seven
as the most special religious,
mystical number that there is.
Oh, so he thinks it's not so much that
the culture has gotten into the math.
It's the other way around that the math
actually was there first and then that
got into the culture. Yeah.
All right. You're making me feel better.
[inaudible]
would you like to thank somebody? I would.
I like to thank Steve Strogatz once again
for joining us whenever we call him.
I'd like to thank Sally Bellows, whose
book is called the Grapes of math.
How life reflects numbers and numbers
reflect life. Right. Well, we should go,
I guess I'm Jen [inaudible]. I'm
Robert Krulwich. Thanks for listening.