Um,
so we want to finish the night with a
salute to a guy who's been on our program
and part of our family pretty
much from the beginning.
I have known him for more than 35 years.
Early on when radio lab started,
I asked him if he'd help us out
and send us a few story ideas.
He didn't send us a few. He sent us
bushels, tales of chemistry and medicine,
hallucinations, music people.
So many extraordinary people that he
knew or found or help cause the guy just
doesn't run out. Dr. Oliver Sacks.
[inaudible] is a guy who noticed
is everything,
is deeply interested in everything
that happens around him and to him.
And tonight we're bringing them back on
tape for what I'll ask may be his final
offering for us. As many of you know,
Dr Sachs recently was diagnosed with liver
cancer and he wrote about this in the
New York Times. He said he plans to spend
the time that he has a left writing,
being with friends, not doing interviews,
but he did agree to share his thoughts
exclusively with us tonight for you
gathered here. Um, cause
he's one of our family.
So as I've done for decades now,
I went over to his house in Manhattan
with my mic and I said to him,
I just need to know like what, what
just happened a month and a half ago?
You were fine. And then what? Um,
at the beginning of the year, I
was fine. On the 3rd of January,
I felt a little queer and
I passed some dark urine.
I thought had a little
gallbladder attack and, um,
didn't pay that much attention, but
thought I better get things checked.
And, um, the extra day,
which was expected, Ooh,
need to show a couple of gallstones,
showed hundreds of cysts in my liver.
Uh, although my doctor said
he didn't know what the,
his one I would need further
tests. I, I knew what they were.
I said, it's happened.
And he was right.
The doctors eventually confirmed at a
cancer that had been found in his eye nine
years ago had spread
to his liver. Where you
frightened or relieved or console or what,
what? No, I, um,
I think my first feeling was
one of, of overwhelming sadness.
Um, now all sorts of
things I won't see. Um,
and I won't do one or two people
have written to me in the, you know,
consoling me and said, well, you
know, we all die, but fuck it.
It's not like we all die. It's
like you have four months.
Has that, has your PR, what is
your prognosis at this moment?
Cause I know you had an eye. Oh, well
if it gets revised, it depends on,
of course, on how the
cancer responds to and, or
how quickly it spreads so far. Um,
the metastasis from my eye, uh,
only in my liver I'm told
they love liver. Actually.
I love liver as well. And,
and one of the magical things I did was
to go and have liver and onions sued
after the doctors and thinking
that liver looks better than mine.
He, this is what he's like,
instead of being frightened by
the thing is trying to kill him.
He's thinking about loving liver and
liver lovers and looking for connections
and wondering. He doesn't stop. He,
he just notices that the case in point a
few months ago, his doctor said to him,
we're going to run a line up your liver.
And in effect we're going to try to shave
off a star of some of the cancer cells
first on one side,
then on the other to see if we
can give you a little more time.
But they weren't him as the
metasticies die, they um,
put out various unpleasant
chemicals that may exhaust you,
tax your system badly.
And um, at one point,
shortly after the procedures,
I started talking a
little strangely and um,
as I was talking I was also writing, um,
you'll be the first person to see this.
So he showed me a notebook and we are
showing it to you in just a moment.
You can see they're sort of writing
there on the left. It's all,
he's writing a book, actually a children's
book about the elementary table.
But as he was writing, if you,
if you look to the next page,
if you can see that it gets a little
bit wobbly, the letters and then,
and then there was some
crossing out there. I see.
And then while the dramatically the
lighting changes and actually there's,
there's a large slash
across it and then you,
it seems a little incoherent
at the partners. Okay.
And then it turns the pure scribble
that has delirium and crept up on me.
All this happened over the course of 10
minutes and I see what he's doing here.
He's figuring, okay, I'm
writing at a constant speed.
I know pretty much how fast I
write and so I can time this out.
I can figure out exactly how long it took
me to slip into delirium and then out
of this delirium and he's
doing this very, very sick man.
It's science to write it
out in a more medical way.
I think this would form a
lovely illustration you put
in a timeline of delirium
to us coming like that.
Why aren't you more frack like unusual
for any doctor and a man of science?
You don't seem to worry at all when
things become incoherent or strange.
You're now showing it to me as
if like, Ooh, how interesting.
I was crazy here for a little bit.
The truth is Oliver is fascinated by
what goes on in the human mind no matter
how strange he gets up there at one
time when he was a young resident in
California driving his
bike. And by the way,
I should show you what he looked like
back then when he was driving his bike.
This I think is him in New
York, a kind of, you know,
in the 60s he was also a champion
weightlifter. They called him Dr Squat.
And in this picture that
you showed you here,
that's him raising 600 pounds
in order to win a trophy.
Like this is a that he was a champ. And,
and you can see more pictures like these
cause we have signed copies of Oliver's
new memoir out for sale in the lobby.
It's pretty good book too, by the way.
So in any case at this time and the 1960s,
in addition to being all muscled out,
Oliver was a serious recreational
drug taker. And because he's Oliver,
he was extremely curious about his
highs no matter how weird they were.
One time for example, he took 20
pills that he shouldn't have. And then
to my surprise, um, uh,
there was a spider on the
wall which said hello.
It had a voice like broken crosser
and famous mathematician and it, um,
it asked me a while,
the technical question as to where the
Russell had excluded free eagles paradox
and um,
we had this conversation answered
the spider [inaudible] onto this fine
discussed fracas paradox with this
minor. I didn't deed cause you,
you trust your perceptions. Okay.
Many years later when I mentioned
this to an entomologist,
fed up Cornell and the philosophical
spider, he said, yes. He said,
I know the species.
So thinking Oliver's way, taking
it all in, talking spiders,
whatever the generosity of his
curiosity becomes profoundly moving and
transformative when he's
treating his patients.
I want to tell one story here really
quickly to demonstrate what I mean.
Oliver once had a patient
whom he called Mrs o c
she was an old woman.
She was 88 years old living in a nursing
home and one night she was awakened,
jarred awake by a loud sound.
Um,
it was a song.
Yeah,
and she thought, well, somebody left
the radio on, but when she looked,
the radio in the room was off,
her roommate sound asleep,
which was odd because the song
was really loud. Good. Doris.
After that, there was another song
[inaudible]
and then another song is a
home. Mrs [inaudible] thought,
well, maybe my roommate can't hear
the songs because the songs are,
are coming through the fillings in my
teeth. I've heard that it's possible,
but no, her doctors told her,
this is something in your head,
you need to see a neurologist,
which led her to Dr Sachs
at when he met Mrs OSI, he,
she could barely hear him.
The song sung by the female
voice were coming and coming.
She was frightened and justifiably
worried that she was going crazy.
But Oliver said, no, no, no, I'm going
to do some tests. And when he was done,
he said he'd found a slight stroke or
condition that it triggered musical
epilepsy. These sudden
production of music in her brain.
Now a normal doctor might say,
okay, we've got the diagnosis,
and he thought that the songs would
probably fade and it will pass.
So they would be done. But Oliver
did not stop. He doesn't stop
[inaudible]
he kept talking to her.
She told him she was born in Ireland in
the 1890s her father died before she was
born. Her mother, when she was only five
often alone,
she was sent to America to live
for the welder for beating maison.
She had no conscious memory at
the first five years of her life,
no memory of her mother of Ireland.
She had always felt this as
a key and painful sadness,
this lack or forgetting of the earliest,
most precious years of her life.
So we asked her about the songs, what
are they like? And Mrs [inaudible] said,
well, I think they're lullabies.
Can you sing them for me? She did.
And then after checking with,
I'm not sure who al ever figured out
that these songs were happened to be
popular Irish ballads from the 1890s
when Mrs OSI was a little baby and that
gave him an idea. Now what
he does next isn't science.
It isn't in any traditional way medicine.
He just told her a story
and it goes like this.
You know how nobody remembers anything
that happens to you when you're one or
two or three? Well, there was a
theory once, not honored much today,
but it sad that those earliest
memories get locked away,
deepen our brains in a special
safe that we can never open.
So let's suppose Mrs o see that you
are stroked by some crazy chance.
Open the lock that none of us can break
and release those first memories in you
just for a little while so that
the voice you're listening to
there is a home [inaudible].
Maybe that isn't a radio voice. Let's
think that it's your mother's voice.
Pat's your missing mother.
And so at the ripe old age of 88 you
finally get to be back in your mother's
arms. You get to be a baby again, and
Mrs z thought about that and said,
okay,
it sort of fits.
I'm an old woman with a stroke
in an old people's home,
but I feel I'm a child to Ireland. The
Gate, I feel my mother's arms. I see her,
I hear her voice seen
the green, it clean.
Who's Ron? [inaudible].
Shortly thereafter, the songs
began to fade. The pauses widened.
Mrs OSI had been so frightened by this
music in her head was now sorry to see
the songs go, but it was Oliver who
noticed how those songs had touched her.
Who noticed that the songs might become
a comfort to her because that's what he
does. He listens closely. He
can hear another person's heart,
and this is really the profound puzzles
for me of Oliver because reading the new
autobiography,
you see that while he was so full of
heart as a doctor in his own life and in
the relationships that really mattered,
it turns out he didn't get a whole lot
of affection. He was, for a long time,
a lonely guy.
I'd say he was very lonely and he's
talking about that now for the first time.
Let me, let me talk about
love for a minute. Um,
in this book you tell the story of your,
of your very first love a fellow
by the name of Richard Selleck.
Can you just tell me
what happened with him?
Um, yeah. Um,
he was a road scholar at Oxford and I'm
a poet and handsome and beautiful beyond
belief and I sort of fell for him. Um,
although I didn't say
anything because I was um, uh,
very haunted by my mother's accusations.
What did your mother well,
to go a couple of years back
then my father had opened
a conversation that I was
about to go to Oxford and have sort of
father son conversation and he said,
um, you don't seem to have many
girlfriends. And I said, no,
wishing the conversation
would stop. He said, um,
something wrong with girls. And
I said, no, that they're fine.
Perhaps you prefer boys. And I
said, well, yes I do. I said,
I've never done anything but I do.
And then you knew that. Then I knew
that. Then I'd known it for six years,
probably since I was 12. Um, and I said,
don't tell mom she will
be able to take it.
But my father did tell my mother and
the night and the next morning she came
down with them.
I somehow wants to say a face of funder
and raged at me and among other things
said, you're an abomination. I
wish you would never been born.
And then she suddenly shut up
and said nothing for three days.
And um, uh,
the matter was never mentioned
again in her lifetime.
And then two years later I found myself
for the first time in my life falling in
love.
This was the gun guy, Richard
Oliver at the time was in college.
It was a very positive feeling though.
I didn't know whether it was one,
which I did express,
but I did say so with my heart and
my mouth to each other. How about,
did you remember what you said?
I, I said, I'm in love with you.
And Richard gripped me by the
shoulders. And he said, I know.
He said, but I'm not that way,
but I love you in my own way.
And um, I was glad I had said that I'm
glad that has been received in such a,
a warm, friendly way. I thought we might
be friends for the rest of our lives.
But then one day he came into me,
he said he'd been bothered by finding a
in his groin and he was worried could I
have a look at it?
And I looked at it and I felt it and it
was hard and tethered and turned out to
be a particularly malignant form of
lymphoid Tema what was called a lympho
sarcoma. And, um,
he never spoke to me again after that.
I don't know whether since I had been the
first to recognize the ominous import,
I don't know whether he saw me as a
harbinger of death or messenger of death,
whatever. But you, you were left
with the, with that silence. Yeah.
Yeah. A few years later I'll ever
met an man named Mel. He was young,
he was a sailor. He like Oliver.
He was into weight lifting,
they became close friends and
they began living together.
I adored him and was in love with him
and loved physical contact with him and
they'd work out and they'd wrestle and
ride motorcycles kind of tightly and they
never talked about what might or
might not be happening between them.
But one day they were together and
outer was giving male a back massage,
which Mel often asked him to
do. And uh, I love to do that.
And Oliver says sometimes he'd
get a little, you know, excited.
And so long as I gave no explicit
indication, it was okay, but, but,
but one day things went a bit
too far and I got sort of, um,
I went over the brief instead
of just before the Brig. Um,
Mel immediately sort of got up
and had a shower and said, I,
I can't stay with you anymore. And um,
I found that very cruel and upsetting
and heartbreaking and it made me feel,
I don't want to have
anything to do with people.
I must've fallen in love and it
cannot share lives with anyone again.
And he didn't share his life with
anyone for a long, long time.
In fact,
he told me a story about something that
happened to him maybe eight years ago.
I was just joining the faculty at Columbia
and I was having a swiffer interview
and a one point the interviewer
said to me, she said,
I have something whether private
to ask you, we do like Ms Edgar,
your system to leave. And I said,
no, she's privy to all my affairs.
And I then said thinking she was
going to ask me about sex. I said,
I haven't had any sex for 35 years.
I'm in fact what she was going
to ask me, my social security
[inaudible] first it's loft. And she
said, Oh, you poor thing. She said,
we must do something about it. Well,
the truth is Oliver didn't do anything
about it because he didn't think he
could. I mean, he chosen, Richard
lost, Richard Chosen Mail, lost mail.
It wasn't the point he was
thinking. And then finally,
and who knows when or why
these things happen to people.
But a man came along
who for the first chose
Oliver,
I have met Billy is I meet a number of
people because I'd been sent a manuscript
or proof for book and
intimacy grew between us.
I don't think I quite
realized how deep it was.
But then there was a particular episode
in Christmas of Oh nine when he came up
and in a sort of serious way,
he has a serious careful way. He said, I,
I have conceived a deep love for you.
I have conceived a deep
love for you. Yeah. Um,
that is a story that's like got a
few extra words I have conceived. Um,
okay. Was He scared to
say I love you or um, no,
he likes the English language. I think it,
I think it couldn't have been put, um,
more cautiously and yet more strongly.
I think it was a beautiful
way of putting it.
And then I realized at that moment with
his saying that that I had conceived a
deep love for him and I
am among other things.
I thought good goddess happened again,
two
and I'm in my 77th year and um, and,
and what next two things, um,
basically have gone happily ever since.
[inaudible]
and supplies in me. Look, Leslie. Um,
because then again, I'm not dealing
with all what I'm dealing with a hoop.
I'm dealing with an individual
[inaudible]
I am not dealing with a, um, uh,
a condition defined by medicine or law.
So Oliver's still doesn't know how much
time he has left, but for the moment,
as you can hear, his mind is
totally intact. He's still writing.
He has two books in addition to
the one you'll find in the lobby,
B that he's writing and
the children's book,
Bunch of New Yorker stories in the last
few months and a New York review of
books story. He's got energy to spare.
So I want to do one last
thing before we close.
And this comes from yet
another conversation I had
with him. And it's a story.
I know Oliver Wood heat because he's
not a capital I religious kind of guy,
but he is somebody who
definitely embraces mystery.
And for a long time he's been
mystified by a color called Indigo,
indigo,
which Newton had inserted
between blue and violent and no,
no two people seem to agree
as to what indigo was like.
And so I built up a sort
of chemical launchpad,
meaning he took lot of drugs
[inaudible] base of amphetamine
for general a while.
So then some acid and a little cannabis.
And when I was sufficiently
stoned, I said,
I want to see indigo now.
[inaudible]
as if it were reply and does if phone by
a giant paintbrush that appeared a huge
trembling,
pear shaped blob of what I instantly
realized was pure indigo on the white wall
in front of me.
It had had a wonderful luminosity
and in particular I am,
although I am not a religious person,
I thought this is the color of heaven.
And I lived towards it and I sort of
ecstasy and then suddenly disappeared.
And he says he had one more moment
like that this time. No drugs.
He was in a museum staring
at an Egyptian artifact.
He sees this re in color
back again, just for a beat.
I was given five tantalizing
seconds of, of, of radiant,
ineffable beauty,
and then again, it vanished.
And that was in 1965 and I've
never seen an indigo since.
But who knows? You know,
someday I like to think Dr Sachs
may get to see that color again.
[inaudible].