[inaudible].
You're listening to radiolab from
New York public radio, public radio,
W C
[inaudible]
testing, testing. This is radio lab.
I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert Krulwich.
And since this hour we'll be talking
about brains and bodies and how they
communicate.
We thought we'd begin the program with a
guy with that we'd go to quite often he
knows about this sort
of thing. Oliver Sacks,
Oliver is a neurologist. As I
get closer to very famous author,
he took us to his study to show us
something that just fascinates him.
Um, I've become fascinated.
I'm incidentally, I hope you,
you have to be careful with
your watch or your computers.
[inaudible]
um, he showed us a silver ball.
I should just describe here I am looking
at a silver ball about the size of a
small, small ping pong ball,
which he handed to you, right?
Would you care to lift up
that little steel ball?
[inaudible] and as soon as he did,
I am trying
the ball flying through the
air, taking your hand with it,
smack into the nearest bit
of metal in the vicinity,
which was a plate Latier left
very fast and it hurt it.
Wow. That'd be cool. I've got a cat. Okay.
I don't put it too near your watch and
also you have to put it down very gently.
Otherwise it may fly with great violence
onto this nickel slam. What is that?
Um, and what are we
talking about it. Okay. Um,
well this is a little rare earth
metal magnet of great strength.
[inaudible]
these magnets orient themselves almost
violently to the earth's magnetic field.
If you have a couple of these things,
say in your pockets and you go
for a walk, as you turn a corner,
you will feel them really at
themselves in your pockets.
I like like little animals.
So your, your pockets would tell you
whether you were going north, south,
east or west,
your pockets or wherever you,
you have the way with magnets and
how you have very weird man. How
would you propose to use this?
In what situation that you have imagined?
Would it be a happy advantage? Well,
I myself, I'm always
getting lost. I have no,
I have no sense of
direction. I would function.
Do you all ever come downtown to meet me?
You would know because of the pressure
on your thighs from these little balls
that you were carrying out, whether you
were going downtown or not downtown.
See, and I may need things like
this. I am very bad at all.
Anting myself in space.
He's trying to do with the
birds too. Right? Bird.
Because birds have magnets in their
brains or something like magnets,
which lets them fly south. Yeah. Yeah. So
they know where they're going. They fly
in when they're migrating, right? Yeah.
He's trying to start a
conversation like a bird,
but he's cause he's choosing his thighs.
He wants his thighs to talk to his
brain. I've often wondered as an aside,
uh, the extent to which
one, um, one could develop
the nuisance. That's what this hour
of radio lab is about. Human beings,
not just Oliver.
All kinds of folks who are attempting
to add census and mostly to subtract
census. We'll have stories about
both adding and losing senses.
And more generally, you look at
how brains and bodies communicate,
often fail to communicate
because believe it or not,
it's not an easy relationship
between your brain and your body.
There's a lot of
confusion, deception, even.
That's what new research shows
and we'll get into all of that.
So let's get into it. All right.
Okay. Ready? Yeah, we're first, well,
let's begin with an urologist.
Listen, my cell phone is ringing,
so let me pause until it stops.
So that's Robert Sapolsky.
He's a professor of biology at Stanford.
I've never figured out how to do voice
messaging or whatever it is even has done
in this century. Prisoners of our
machine is, okay, we're in business.
Okay, so to begin now,
I said to Robert Sapolsky just to get
my head around this, let's imagine it.
I decide to visit my best friend
in the world, Tommy, Tommy.
I walk over to his house. I have a
key. So I opened the front door, Tommy,
I walk into his apartment
and then I see him
sprawled on the floor, dead
[inaudible]
and in a horrible,
tragic, instant like that,
I wonder what would be
going on in my brain.
And I asked this because his
answers suppose gives the answer.
It was so we heard
according to supposed ski,
what happens happens
in the following order.
First Light bounces off Tommy's
corpse and Andrew's my eye. Okay?
It goes up some nerve from your
eyes and into one part of the brain,
which turfs it onto the next part.
And then the information keeps moving.
A couple of steps down. It gets into
what's called your visual Cortex,
which turns the dots into
lines and lines into shapes.
And that's just like a local train.
You're taking eventually that local
train carrying the image of timing,
chug and chug deeper into my brain, to
my cortex. And after a few more stops,
I will finally know, I will
consciously know that Tommy is dead.
But now here's the surprise.
Information can move through the brain
in different ways at the same time.
And there is a second route, it turns,
there's a second pathway into my body,
into my nervous system, which bypasses
all of that visual cortex stuff
like a bullet train and goes straight
to this area called the Amygdala.
And what the Amygdala does is instantly
it tells the heart to pound your heart
speeds up the stomach to clinch
stomach muscles, clench tears to flow,
and you're still a couple of seconds
away from like even consciously making
sense of what you're,
and by then already your
stomach is heading towards
your throat or your throats
in your mouth or whatever the cliche is.
So as I'm standing there in Tommy's
apartment looking at this figure on the
ground before I even know
what I'm looking at before,
I am consciously aware that Tommy is dead.
My body already knows. That's
exactly the punchline, right?
Your body knows that before
you consciously know it.
[inaudible]
which is an astonishing idea. It is
astonishing, but it's
not a new idea. Yeah.
This goes back to what was originally
viewed as this totally asinine theory in
psychology back around
1,901 of the, you know,
grand old Poop Oz of
psychology, William James James,
and he's trying to answer the
question where feelings came from.
That's Joan Alara science writer.
He really likes William James.
He's written a lot about him and
he says, a hundred years ago,
William James poses a thought experiment.
He gives the example of a bear.
He says, imagine you're
walking through the woods.
All of a sudden I'm behind a tree,
a bear attacks. Any wonder William
James did. Okay, so the bear attacks,
you're gonna feel scared.
But what exactly is that
feeling of fear made of?
Which seems like a strange
question to ask. Yeah, but,
but he was trying to
be empirical about it.
He was trying to be a good psychologist.
And his answer was that the feeling
is the perception of your body,
meaning step one, you see the bear, you
see a bear with his teeth and his claws.
Step two, your body responds
fast. Heartbeat, the adrenaline,
cursing in your bloodstream.
And it's only in step three.
When the brain sees the body respond,
does it then trigger the feeling?
Yeah,
a fear and the feeling of fear comes
from the perception of those changes in
your body. If you took away the
heartbeat, if you took away the body,
there'd be nothing left
to feel. Needless to say,
when William James proposed this idea,
people's got solutely crazy. He was nuts,
completely nuts. They said,
you know, if you're right,
then someone who's paralyzed from the
neck down and who doesn't get signals from
their body,
well that person would see the bear in
the woods and they wouldn't get scared,
which is ridiculous. Completely
ridiculous. So the critics said,
William James is wrong, dead wrong,
and that's the end of it. Well,
it's not quite the end of it. Hello,
we happen to bump into a
neurologist, Antonio Damasio,
director of the brain and creativity
institute at University of Southern
California. Wow. What a nice place.
So we're sitting near with demasio where
we happen to be talking about William
James and his critics, which we always
do always do on, you know, lunch.
We don't go into a luncheon at for
lunch and before we order a tuna fish
sandwich, we always mentioned
William James in his critics.
This is something we do. So I
said to the, I said, the Moscow,
you know the critics call James Wrong
because he said people who were paralyzed
couldn't feel anything,
and he says, you know,
it's funny you should mention this
because been a series of studies thinking
about James One more time and it's very
interesting because the first study that
was made in this area,
it was made by a paraplegic psychologists
who thought that he felt less
emotional than he was before and he
talked to others and others reported the
same.
The studies reported that people who had
once been able bodied and then became
paralyzed, felt less, less
happy than able bodied people,
less sad than able body people just
less our B is rooted in a body state.
If I would be able to remove from your
brain the representation of your body,
you would not know that you were you
and would I not be sorry at my friend's
Daddy. You definitely would
not be sorry. At anything.
What is in fact the essence
of being joyful or sad?
If you don't hook those
notions on a changed body,
he's right. You know? I mean, if you
think about the last time you were sad,
like really sad, how would you
describe that feeling to yourself?
In fairness, when I guess I would,
I would say I felt dragged
out and heavy. Yeah.
That feeling is completely
rooted in your flesh. Wow.
Brain has nothing to do with that
thought. Made me say it and then my body,
hold on. Hello?
Oh, hi. Yeah. Yeah. Hold on one second.
Is Your wife here
Robert? Yeah. I can't believe you're
still there. What are you doing there?
What do you mean you were
supposed to be home an hour ago
in the studio. We were
on the, I don't care.
What do you mean you were
supposed to be home an hour ago.
I reminded you this morning. I
reminded you last night. I was pissed.
Not Important to you.
There's not such a big deal.
I'll be back and actually this just a
supplement example of what we've been
talking about. No, Robert's having
a fight with his wife, Tamar,
and while he's fighting inside his body,
his stomach is clenching his hardest.
Palpitating. Hers is doing the same thing.
Their brains are picking up these
signals. I'm thinking anger, feel angry.
Look at people who were just as important
as your WIC and you plan on screwed it
up. How did they screw it up? How
did I screw up [inaudible] job? No.
At a certain point,
Robert will probably realize he
has screwed up and just get home.
He'll apologize. I'll see if I get
home in 20 minutes. I'm really sorry.
I know this is horrible. Is Everything
okay? Yeah, yeah. It's just a sec.
Sorry. Okay. He'd be like, no.
When it comes to brains and
bodies and men and women,
the interesting thing is that when a man
and woman fight these systems in their
body, the heart palpitating,
the stomach clenching,
while these systems do turn on at
the same speed and it takes like two
seconds according to Robert Spolsky where
there's an interesting gender difference
is how long it takes to turn off the
system and ladies, sorry.
In advance and in general it turns
off more slowly in women than in men,
which may explain something that
happens to couples all the time. Okay.
I'm really sorry this
isn't right. I know. Oh,
I'm really sorry and like here we are.
Maybe like maybe at later we'll go
do something or I'm really sorry.
Robert Stomach is relaxing.
This was really stupid. I know.
His heart is slowing versed where
he thinks the fight might be over.
Okay,
but you know this is something you
do all the time. We're going to be,
we're having a dinner right after we got
engaged and we went to the restaurant
and I was waiting for you and I've
made the reservation and that was
for like 45 minutes. You didn't even call.
Did you hear what just happened there?
It's this William James stuff coming
back to haunt us a century later.
Topolsky says sometimes the
body actually tricks the brain.
Tamper knows the fight is over
mentally, but her body's still tense.
Her heart is still racing and
her brain thinks, Whoa, wait,
if my heart is still racing and I
consciously know that this issue has been
resolved,
it must be because I'm still pissed off
about that thing that happened in the
Carter Administration. Minimize
every day we made it goes for you.
The brain fills a vacuum. You
have a list, you have a list.
I do. I have a long list. Know How
often you do this sort of thing.
I do it like one. I can tell them
it's your, the babysitter calls.
I'm going to be out of town and says,
should I make dinner for Robert?
Because quickly you can't make
dinner for yourself and the kids. No,
I do make dinner. I haven't made much
of the anything Tito's. Last week,
Wednesday I made the baked
potatoes. That's just applying heat.
I want to thank my wife,
Tamer Lewin for what I think was a
pretty startling lead that really,
I mean I show performance,
which I don't know how she did that
because it's so unlike our rest of our
marriage. You know,
this story, by the way,
came from Robert Sapolsky and
he tells it about his wife too,
but they're not reporters. They're
scientists, so they do it differently.
My wife's in the same business as me,
so the very words we will
say to each other is, honey,
don't forget what the half life is
on the autonomic nervous system.
Then suddenly it's all over with.
That's such a rare exchange
between two people. You know?
I know we're just sentimental.
By the way, Robert Spolsky's
latest book is called Monkey Love,
which is where that
wife anecdote came from.
Speaking of brains and bodies,
let's put the science on pause for a
moment and take a brief detour because
often what gets you into these ideas
like take this kid. For example,
Christopher seals go to the Blake
high school isn't the science.
It's more basic than that.
It seems something disgusting
and not being able to look away.
You really just can't believe
that if something feels like this,
it actually came out of a real person
who just don't get the feeling.
When we bumped into Christopher, he was
gingerly holding a pair of human lungs,
but it is a real person,
but you just can't really associate it
with a real person because it's there in
front of you and it doesn't look like
a real person in case. That sense of,
whoa. That's why we originally went to
the Walter Reed Army Medical Center in
Washington d c but here's
what happened. Our tour guide.
Okay. Steven S. T. E. V. E. N.
Solomon, s. O. L. O. M. O. N. He showed
us a particular photo
that got us thinking.
So famous photo in our
archives. It's called field day.
It's a civil war photo
hanging in a sign gallery.
It's a picture of legs,
Heil of amputated legs, a
huge heap of severed legs,
some feet thrown sort of
haphazardly into a pile.
Wow. It's oddly beautiful in a way.
Drusen Skousen at the next time.
Immediately after was what
was happening at that moment.
Right to one side of the picture frame.
Must've been an operating
table and on the table,
soldier inhaling chloroform and at the
foot of the table must've been a doctor
signing away.
A circular amputation involve cutting
straight through the skin to the bone of
flap.
Amputation required the tissue to be
cut leaving two flaps of skin that were
used to create a stump and in fact
your typical army surgeon was basically
graded on how quickly they
could do an amputation.
That was one of the first orders where
you really had doctors being aggressive
in terms of taking off limbs. Like
I said, that photo got us thinking,
so we went back to Jonah Lehrer who has
written but a very ghostly side effect
that pops up during the civil war
as a direct result of all of that,
taking off of limbs, this,
this one astonishing syndrome that these
men who have had their limbs taken off,
they describe very,
very often this a very common thing
that they still feel their phantom limbs
[inaudible]
they say, they say, yeah, they say,
doctor, I, I still feel it. Move.
They can feel it hurt. Give you that.
Sometimes get hot, sometimes very cold.
Imagine you're a civil war
doctor and you hear this.
You don't even know what germs
are yet, but one guy, Dr Silas,
where Mitchell decides he's
going to get to the bottom of it,
the first thing he did was he
wrote some clinical reports.
Only about 5% of the men who have suffered
amputation never have any feeling of
the part as being still present and
circulated them around the hospital.
While the remainder seems to
retain a sense of its existence,
so vivid as to be more definite and
intrusive than it is of the truly living
fellow member,
the stump is liable to the most horrible
neurologists and to a certain curious
spasmodic paralysis.
No one could make sense of this.
Even our Guy William James,
even he looks into it,
he did a very authoritative study where
he sent out questionnaires to all these
amputee victims and wanting to
know about their lost limbs.
He has to all of these civil war
amputees, all these questions,
does your phantom limb hurt? Can you
move it if you really concentrate?
And what he found was that there were
no patterns, no stereotypical lost limb.
Every, every experience was
different. In other words,
phantom limbs are like
real limbs. They're yours.
Well, on this topic of Phantom limbs,
there is a guy who has figured at least
something out about this phenomenon.
Dr v S Rama Shondra. I
am a v S Ramachandra. I
remember him. I remember him.
He's a well known neurologist.
He works in California at the
University of California, San Diego.
And one day he says,
a patient showed up in his office and
it seems that the guy had had his arm
amputated. It was his left arm.
And then ever since this man had an
uncanny feeling that he still had an arm
where his real arm used to be. Yes,
it's important to emphasize
this is not a delusion.
He doesn't think he has an arm. He
knows he doesn't. He's not crazy,
but he vividly feels its presence.
And the rough part was that this arm,
it hurt. This sometimes happens
to people with phantom limbs.
He would have days where his phantom
arm would seize up in pain. Doctor,
it hurts me really badly. Goes
into this painful clenching spasm.
The nails dig into my palm.
So he has a phantom hand at the
end of his phantom limb. Yes,
and he'll say things like,
it's going into a cramp with the nails
digging into the phantom palm and it's
excruciatingly painful, but there
are no nails. There is no no problem.
And weirdest of all, the patient
couldn't do anything about it.
He try to unclench his phantom nails
from his phantom palm to make the pain
stop, but he couldn't. He said,
I cannot move the fountain.
The fandom I'm wouldn't obey.
I cannot volitionally move it.
And I started thinking to myself,
what does he mean when he says he cannot
move his phantom limb like an oxymoron?
There is no arm there.
Drew Ramachandran was
confused what's going on. He,
he checked with the patient and discovered
that 11 years earlier before the
amputation,
he'd had an injury to his spine and after
that his real left arm was paralyzed.
He could not move it. He tried his
brain would issue the commands.
His brain was saying move the arm,
but he was getting visual feedback and
indeed feedback from his muscles saying,
nope, move the arm. No move.
No. And this went on for months,
move. No, so maybe the Dr Rameshchandra,
maybe this patient got so frustrated
trying to move his real arm that at some
point after a few months or a year,
the paralysis got learnt by the brain,
snapped into the circuitry of
the brain. No, I call it learned,
learned paralysis. So even
when they cut the patients,
I'm off a year after the accident,
he still didn't get any relief
because the problem wasn't in his arm.
It was learned paralysis.
It was in his head. Now,
and that is when
Ramachandra thought, well,
maybe the solution here is to trick this
man's brain to unparalyzed to get his
cells to think, well,
actually we can move an on
the patio trick a brain.
How would you do that? How would
you do that? How would you do that?
How would you do that?
Indeed he thought for a bit.
Then I hit on this way using a mirror
property inside a cardboard box,
a mirror mirror prompt
inside a cardboard box,
a mirror pro parked inside a car.
I mean, I got a box cropped up. Oh,
it was kind of a home
depot solution. Really.
[inaudible] took a long and skinny mirror.
The kind you'd hang on a closet door,
right? Any propped it up, using a
cardboard box and then turned it sideways.
Place the side right in front of
the patient like right on his nose.
So he couldn't see himself. No,
couldn't see anything in the mirror
yet unless he hooked his neck around.
Took a pee. Oh, otherwise he's just
looking at the side. Ramesh Arjun says,
I want you to imagine
this with me. Jeff says,
I want you to take your good
on your [inaudible] arm. Okay?
And stick it out in front of
the mirror. So do that. Okay,
now make it do what the phantom arm
does. Pick your good arm. Make it stiff.
Curl your hand into a fist. Dig Your
fingernails into your palm, deeply.
Make it hurt. You're doing that. It's
kind of hurting. Now when I tell you,
Cook your head so that you can look
into the mirror and on your left,
just where the phantom ought to be. Let's
pretend that that's your phantom arm.
It's cramped. It's curled
exactly as you'd imagine it.
So now look in the mirror,
okay. And there's your arm.
You see it there in nearer
your phantom arm. Got It.
Now very slowly keeping
your eye on the mirror.
Now I want you to
[inaudible] curl your hand.
Patient says, okay, he
opens his real hand, my God.
And of course it looks like his phantom
is opening. That's not surprising.
He's got to do the mirror there.
But he says, my God, doctor,
you're not going to believe this.
The movements have all come back.
All these movements in
my fingers, in my elbow,
in my wrist from 11 years ago,
come flooding into my mind.
So is his pretend nails are now
ungripping from his pretend palm.
And the whole problem of the
pretend pain goes away, goes away.
That's what he said. For how long? By
the way, till the middle was in place.
But when Dr Ramachandran took away
the mirrors, the pain came back.
I said, fine salary, you
know, and then I said, look,
why don't you practice with the mirror
for the few weeks, every day for an hour?
Then maybe if you do it repeatedly,
you can unlearn the learned pain.
So this guy goes home, I got him. You
give him a mirror to take home? Correct.
And you don't know if it was took $2 take
it with you. So he takes it with him.
He was delighted. And then
after about another week,
he phones me and he sounds all
agitated on the phone and I said,
what's going on? So talk, you're not
going to believe this. It's gone. I said,
what's going on? I thought maybe the
mirror was gone. He said, no, no,
not the mirror. The friend
Tom has gone, gone, gone, go.
That's what I said. Gone. Done. What
do you mean fandom is going? You do it.
Well, this phantom arm I been having
for the last 11 years is disappeared.
What am I, my initial reaction
was alarm. I said, my God,
does this bother you that if you said no,
you know this has happened three days
ago and in the last three days you
remember the excruciating elbow pain and
wrist pain? I got several times a day,
but I don't have them any more
because I don't have an arm.
Okay.
But my fingers,
okay.
They have not disappeared and they're
still up here dangling near my shoulder.
They're still painful. You
mean just disconnected?
Disembodied fingerlings yeah,
finger looks dangling from the
shoulder. What does that mean?
This guy saying that he seems to have
fingertips hanging on his shoulder.
He said you a mirror doesn't work anymore,
so can you redesign it and push it
prophet near my nose so I can look at the
reflection and maybe get,
get rid of the fingers.
So he now wants to get Dr
Ramachandra in to prop up the mirror,
point them at these phantom fingertips
and have the mirror erase the fingertip.
You thought I was a magician
and I could, you know,
eliminate his different
body parts in sequence.
And this is amputation
by mirror? Yeah, it's,
as I tell my medical
colleagues jokingly, I say,
this is the first example in the history
of medicine of a successful amputation
of a phantom limb, so don't
leave me hanging here.
Did the phantom fingers
eventually dissolve? Nope.
We still haven't been able to devise a
technique to get them and it turns out
that the pain, they're subsided a bit,
so he's not that worried
about us getting rid of him.
So somewhere in California there's
still a guy walking around with a sense,
fingers on his shoulder. Yeah. Are
still dangling out of his shoulder,
which is not only weird.
It suggests that there's an awful lot
to know about how brains and bodies
interact. Many things to learn,
but for a work a day doc who has to deal
with whatever comes through the door.
Dr Ramachandra and had what I would call
a pretty good day at the office. Yes,
exactly.
[inaudible]
vs Ramachandran is a neuroscientist
at the University of California in San
Diego, author of many books, including
a brief tour of human consciousness,
which is where you can find out all
about the mirror experiment. Next up.
Let's scale it up a bit.
We're going to go from lost limbs
to a guy who's lost everything,
his entire sense of his body. I'm
Jad Abumrad rocker crawler tonight.
We'll continue in a moment.
You're listening to radio live
from New York public radio.
V. U. N. C. H. N. P.
R. Wait, what is that?