You're listening to radio lab from New
York public radio, public radio, w.
C. N. N. P. R. I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm
Robert Krulwich and this is radio lab.
You ever wondered why it is,
um, that all living things die?
I do wonder about that actually,
which it keeps me up at night,
which always leads me to the
next question. Do we have to,
do I have to the topic of our show as a
matter of fact and the natural place to
begin to look for an
answer. [inaudible] a rush.
[inaudible] here we are in your
garage. Three are in my garage.
The owner of this particular garage is
one Leonard Hayflick. He is a biologist.
He takes me to the corner
where he's got this above.
So describe what we're
looking at here. Well,
what we're looking at is I barrel
shaped a device, metal canister,
metal. The side is shaped kind of
like a thermos except big opening.
He twists off the top and
look at that.
Out comes all of this smoke dry ice
from Halloween is what it looks. Well,
this look at hydrogen is
used in a lot of movies.
He reaches his hand into the liquid
nitrogen fog right into the bowels of this
canister and pulls out, and
this is what I'd come to see,
what some test tubes,
boobs in which these
animals are cut immediately.
They're not how much to look at. If you
know what's in there, it's almost holy.
Each tube has millions of
frozen human cells in there,
and these cells have completely changed
how we think about mortality and
mortality. And You keep it in
your garage. Yes. Why? I mean,
I think it's pretty cool,
but why? Why it goes,
nobody else think of looking
here. Oh, okay. Well, I won't,
I certainly won't divulge your address
or anything, but just don't tell him. No,
of course I wouldn't, but that's in
California is all I'll say. Well,
where else would you want me to put it
in mind? But no, I don't know. I mean,
it's, uh, I imagined something like this,
you would find it in the most started
for Leonard Hayflick about 50 years ago.
I got the back story actually not in
California. In Philly. I'll check.
Do you want to tell me where we are?
Where we're sitting on the 12th floor
of the William [inaudible] House in
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania,
which happens to be my mother's apartment
who has just celebrated her hundredth
birthday. Just that day,
appropriately enough. In any case,
let's rewind to the 50s biology was
facing a problem. Basic problem.
How do you study human
cells? Cells are us.
It is what we are, but you can't exactly
put a microscope up to your wrist.
I willing, you know, I guess you could,
but I wouldn't say it's impossible,
but it's certainly highly
impractical. What you can do instead,
and Hayflick was among the
first to perfect. This is, well,
he explained it to me.
If I take a tiny biopsy from any part
of your anatomy that you're willing to
surrender to me, like say a fleck
of mine, like my wrist, your wrist,
kind of anywhere you want, the tip
of your nose and to be your toe,
I don't care where it is.
And then you raise a pyramid of skin
by grabbing onto the tip of a hair,
pull it up.
And then with the other hand you'd take
a sterile scalpel and one little tip of
that pyramid of skin off.
And I drop it into a test tube and I
introduce an enzyme preparation called
trypsin. And that material dissolved.
It's the cement that holds
all the cells together.
Think of your tissue as a brick wall.
And once I dropped that
brick wall into my test tube,
I need to dissolve the mortar. Right.
And now I have your individual cells
NFI feed them and treat them nicely.
They will divide
[inaudible].
Each cell produced two cells.
Hmm.
Each cell produced two cells
to sell to sell. Can you do the math?
You'll find that they'll cover the
city of New York and about three weeks.
I mean, you know, that's if you had
a big enough petri dish. In any case,
this process, it's called cell culturing,
is the simplest thing in the
world these days. I mean,
modern biologists can do it with their
eyes close the back in Hayflick's Day in
the fifties it was very fuzzy because no
one really understood the mechanics of
it. No one knew exactly what a
cell liked or what it didn't like.
And so the people that were really good
at getting the cells to divide from two
and a four and eight and 16 whatever.
Yes, they, it was like they had the touch.
They had what was called a green thumb.
There was a mystique about them because,
you know, don't forget, this
was the early days biology. No,
biology at that time was
still kind of a black art.
Well,
I'm interested in the use of the term
black art because that attribute was given
to the field by a single individual who
dominated the field for about 20 or 30
years. His name was Alexis corral.
He believed that the contamination of
tissue cultures with airborne bacteria
could be eliminated or prevented by
maintaining sterile circumstances.
That in his mind included
everything being painted black
[inaudible].
No, don't ask me the rationale for
that because I can't explain it.
It's so gothic. I love it. Exactly.
All of his technicians on he himself
were dressed from head to foot and black,
and he had a gallery around the lab
where reporters could wander to see these
mystical black figures roaming
the laboratory and keep
lore doing strange things
with strange implements and ending up
with cells growing. It must've
seemed like wishcraft on.
It didn't seem like they
believed it was witchcraft,
especially because Alexis corral claimed
to have kept a chick heart alive for 46
years at chick heart. Yes. Like
the heart of a baby chicken.
It was a fragment of tissue from
the chick heart. So for 46 years,
the cells divided and divided every
couple of days. That's what was alleged.
Now, 46 years is a long time. Right.
And so scientists thought that
if they've gone this long,
they'll probably go forever
because of corral. And a
couple of other scientists,
they always thought that cells are
immortal under the proper conditions,
the grow and definitely and Carell's
little chicken heart seemed to be proof of
this. It just kept spewing new cells,
which he'd keep dividing into new bottles.
It was the New York Post said quote,
if all of the cells produced
by Dr Carel from his culture,
chicken heart were kept together,
they would produce a rooster that could
cross the Atlantic Ocean in a single
sheet.
Yeah.
Boy, I wish I'd come up
with that myself now.
Or was that a quote that was made lovingly
or admiringly or was that a sort of
sneer made to sell the New York
Post? It did. People bought it,
I guess is what I'm
asking. You're darn right.
They bought it until it was torpedo.
Yeah,
right. Well that's the story
that I want to get to next.
It happened by accident.
You did not set out to torpedo the
rooster or the whole idea of cellular
immortality. It just kinda
happened. He was in the lab.
It was the 50s he was just a
kid and he becomes worried.
This was an ordinary worry at the time
that his little cells would become
contaminated.
I knew at the time that if you cultured
normal human tissue from adults,
you might grow simultaneously unwanted
viruses because in adults the viruses
would sometimes sneak into the cells
and hide there. And I didn't want,
of course, my culture is to be
contaminated with these viruses.
So I zeroed in on human fetal tissue,
human fetal tissue as in from abortions,
sorry to ask an ignorant question,
but it w abortion at that time was,
was it anything like the crazy political
thornbush that is now no farm or
rational? It was actually quite easy.
He says he just picked up the phone and
called my friends at the University of
Pennsylvania and said I want wanted
fetuses whenever they were surgically
boarded.
And as you might expect when you put
your order in for a fetal tissue,
you know, not when the phone will ring.
He never knew when the
shipments would arrive.
I would receive maybe one fetus one week
and then two weeks later, another one.
So to keep track of, and this
turns out to be key. He kept a log.
Every time he'd get a new shipment,
he would jot down the arrival day and
then dropped the cells into the flask and
Washington divine, do you all deal.
And then every couple of weeks he would
come check on them and that's when it
started. I began to realize that
some of the cultures are unhappy.
The stop divided. At first
it was just one, one batch.
What were you thinking at this point? Uh,
I didn't know what to say cause it's
just an observation and it was just one
batch batch a, let's call it yet. All
right, no biggie. We'll see how it goes.
Let's come back a and a month later I
find out that not only ey is still not
doing its thing, but
B and c aren't either.
No three batches of cells had
gone. Caput said to myself,
well that's peculiar.
Peculiar because here he'd done the same
with these cells as he'd done with all
the others, put them in the same
glasses, same solution, same conditions,
didn't add up. Now I have to
find out what the cause is.
So I'll go back and look at my records.
Sure.
And that is when it
smacks him in the face.
What
the thing that all three
batches of sales hadn't come in,
and he knew this because he'd kept
the logs, is that they were the oldest
[inaudible],
so to speak.
He'd received each batch of fetal tissue
from the hospital received from the
hospital roughly nine months ago.
At nine months or thereabouts.
They just kind of hit a wall
and they stopped divide.
But the ones received one month,
two or three, one for them.
Upon the six months ago though sales
were doing just fine. Perfect, beautiful.
And he kept seeing this simultaneously.
Two thoughts enter his mind thought
number one, this can't be an accident.
If it was a accident, it should
be rand thought number two.
Wait a second.
This has to be an accident because
I hadn't been taught by experts.
It's cells are, they will grow forever.
Okay. All right. Fast
forward a few months.
Those two conflicting thoughts are still
fighting it out in Hayflick's mind.
Along comes the annual biology
for the biggest scientific
meeting in the world.
That time the meeting was
held in Atlantic city.
Hayflick and a few friends decide to
hop in a car and crashed the meeting
because the featured speaker was a guy.
Hey flick really admired
guy by the name of Ted puck
because I want to hear what he has to
say and I'm gonna if I can get enough
guts, I'm going to ask him a question.
I remember distinctly it was
a big whole house and people,
I'm sure it's exaggeration,
but huge are lots of people and I'm
somewhere in a little listening to this
talk.
You see the match previously developed
whereby single cells and at the end as is
customary, asked for question.
Are there any questions?
I timidly raised my hand.
So yes. The young fellow
was sent to you. Yes.
And I asked him the following
question, Dr Puck, have you ever
found that the cells that
you culture stop dividing?
Did you want to give him a kind of that?
Gotcha. What were you thinking? I want,
I was ready to publish. I wanted
to know whether I'm in trouble,
whether I have an artifact on my hands
that nobody has seen because they do it
right. I see. I'm still worried. Got It.
And so he says he looks at me, you
know, like in the video we'll of course
the cell stop dividing occasionally.
Of course I lose myself occasionally,
but I simply go back to the
freezer and reconstitute it.
Meaning that when the cells stop
dividing, which he just had been in,
they do all the time. He just said, Eh,
something happened. I don't know what.
I'll just go back to the freezer
and get, well that's not right.
Because if they stopped dividing,
they might've just died.
It's not that he was cheating, it's
that he thought he had screwed up.
Oh, then I know it was a Gotcha.
Well, he didn't yell. Gotcha. Right
at that moment, he just sat back down.
But now he knew it was real because even
the brilliant Ted puck had seen it too,
but like everyone else
for the past 60 years,
he just hadn't recognized
it for what it was.
I imagine in labs all over the country,
there must've been a lot of moments when
cells stop dividing and at every one of
those moments you're saying the thought
that popped into the technician's mind
is
Yup, absolutely.
That seems like a crazy
kind of mass delusion.
It's called dog Gerry. Another
definition of the word dog.
I've heard that word before. That's it.
The concept of mortality was
absent from people's minds.
Well, wait, if they didn't
understand the idea of mortality,
then how did they scientists exploring
getting older and moving towards death
for pre torpedoing? Yeah.
Radiation. What? Radiation?
Well, what do you mean? No, seriously?
I mean it was this idea that like
stuff is happening outside the cell,
that the radiation is bombarding the cell,
like gamma rays and Alpha rays
and these kinds of things. Okay.
And then that somehow ages the cell.
So the trigger is outside the being
not inside this owl in, right.
My discovery and I pointed it out that
first paper was to indicate that it's in
the cell, not outside the cell.
That's where the action is.
Hayflick argued that
somewhere in the cell there,
there's a counter one too.
There's gotta be for something on sale
is the keeping track eight nine 10 11
because after about nine months
of happy dividing in a petri dish,
when the cell gets to 50 divisions,
sometimes the few takes more.
If you takes less than 50 is the
average and when it reaches 54 45 little
counter inside cell 49 50 says, ah,
50 is the magic number. Where
did this number 50 come from?
Ah, you'll have to ask God that question
nonetheless.
Hayflick not God has his name forever
attached to that number because it's known
as the Hayflick limit.
[inaudible].
Now, one of the interesting
things hatefully told me
while we looked at a secret
stash of fetal cells in his garage is
that there is a way to tinker with the
cellular counter. If you
lower the temperature by say,
putting the sales in liquid nitrogen as
he has the dividing one will get slower
and slower and slower.
I don't know
until it stops at 250 degrees below zero,
the cells will not divide
and they won't die.
They'll just wait for as
long as you keep them frozen.
The sales I have in my freezer,
I've been frozen for 44 years,
is that make them long.
These cells are the longest frozen
normal human cells in the world.
The fetal cells these
talking about incidentally,
are the ones that he use to
discover the Hayflick limit.
He calls it WWI 38 what do we know
about the mother of the fetus that
created WWI 38 she was a Swedish woman and
she wanted an abortion because she
had many children and was very poor.
Her husband was not a good father and uh,
that's where this tissue
came from. Here's the kicker.
After the Hayflick limit
experiments, these cells,
this particular strain was used
to incubate and produce vaccines,
all different kinds. Polio,
German, measles, measles, mumps,
rabies,
and anybody born in the last 50 years
who's had any of these vaccines has had
these cells in their body.
The numbers of people who have benefited
from these vaccines now exceed 1
billion people. That's billion
with a B billion with a B.
Wow.
One aborted child creates a fleet of
cells that vaccinate a billion people.
Think about that for a second.
And is it true that that you have a
cell and from, is it your daughter? Yes.
I also have cells in there from the
amnion of my daughters, Susan Hayflick.
Do you keep them for purely scientific
reasons or is it sort of like stamp
collecting? You have them. Oh,
well it would be is a scientist now
herself and so I'll probably give the
ampules to her so she can do it
with a monk. She what she wishes.
But You keep them because it's your
daughter mostly? Yes. Mostly. Yeah, sure.
Yeah. That's really sweet. Here's the
interesting thing. Scientifically,
if you were to warm these
cells up, give them some food,
alright.
They'd start to divide again,
five six and not only that,
they pick up right where they left off.
Oh. And even if you froze them again,
30 the 1615 doubling 16
and kept them that way,
a thousand million years wouldn't matter
because as soon as you unfroze them
off,
they'd go 1718 1920 on their way
to 52 23 without missing a beat.
What does that tell you?
Tells you that the cells,
remember they have a memory.
Somehow the cell always remembers
where it is in the count to 50 oh,
the cells can't count. How
did they do that? Oh, that's,
and that was the next big question.
So we set about to do a number
of experiments. However,
the next big breakthrough came in 1971
and not by Hayflick while he was doing
his experiments in Philly, halfway
across the world, the very same moment,
a Russian name,
Alexia Lubna cof was attending a
lecture to lecture in the house.
He flicks research and he left that
lecture puzzled by this question that you
asked. How do the cells remember? And
when he, have you ever been in Moscow?
Hmm. Well.
Anyhow, so he ended the
Moscow subway station,
went down to the railroad platform,
and suddenly he had an insight.
He had a brilliant insight. When
he lifted the railroad track,
the first thing you thought was
those tracks look a lot like DNA.
If you take real attraction,
you tuition, you got DNA. Okay,
say it some DNA and that DNA job
is to count to 50 and then yellow
[inaudible].
Well, we know part of the DNA has the
job of yelling, but the other stuff,
the rest of it, what if it's
just a long sequence of nonsense?
Nonsense. What if every time that
cellular copier comes along to cut
you, you sell it, you lose
one little piece of it.
The nonsense. Well,
if you had seen 50 pieces of nonsense
as a buffer around the cents part,
the switch,
well then it would take 50 copies to
snit away all the nonsense until you left
with the switch, which
would turn on entail.
Listen to stop divine
back in Philadelphia. As we were
wrapping up that first interview,
a question occurred to me. If we kind
of understand how that off switch works,
shouldn't we theoretically
be able to take her out?
How to tinker with when the
switch gets switched? In theory,
I suppose you could. Yeah, sure.
And within that allow us to have
a longer amount of cell divisions.
Well that certainly it doesn't violate
any knowledge about the system of course.
And wouldn't that theoretically
give us something,
whether it be extended life
or something? Yes, certainly.
Hey, flickered clearly been asked this
question a million times and he patiently
explained to me that there is a way right
now that we can tinker with the timing
of the switch. You take an enzyme
called telomerase, telomerase,
throw it into the mix and every time
that cell gets copied and loses pieces of
track,
the telomerase enzyme comes along and
adds and back on [inaudible] and maintains
the length constant. That
way the track is always long.
The stop switch never gets switched
and the cell can keep going,
going and going. That's
how they become a mortal.
So you're not going to tell me, well,
let's inoculate everybody with Tom Rice.
Yeah. And, well, if you volunteer,
we'll have a shot at it.
Are you ready there? There must be. If
I were to go out and shout from you,
how can you right here,
get a hundred people who would want to
try only not after. I tell you what,
you still don't know. What's that?
95% of all tumors contain telomerase,
which normal cells do not contain the
single most distinguishing criteria
between normal and cancer cells. No,
today is that fact.
So the tradeoff for cellular immortality,
at least in this case, is cancer.
But here's the weird
thing. If you look around,
you will see that our Hayflick
limit of 50 is not the only one.
We do know that if you look at the
normal cells of a Galapagos tortoise,
which has been reported
in the literature, uh,
they undergo about 125 doublings,
if I remember correctly.
So their Hayflick number is one 25
and ours is 50, apparently. Yes.
Does that correlate to the, the Galapagos
turtle living twice as long? Well,
it's the same. It seems too, but
that comparison may be anecdotal.
I'm not universal. That's what
Hayflick is up to these days.
He's become fascinated by animals
who age differently than us,
who might have a doubling
limit of, you know,
200 500 or no limit at all.
There are the whole class of animals
that don't age will get like what the
American lobster lobster
doesn't age either does not
age or the rate is so slow.
We can't measure it. I don't even know
how to imagine that. What does that mean?
That it does? What it means is that
the animal gets bigger and bigger,
which is growth. Yes. There are
lobsters that have been found.
I are recently, I read about
one of those over 50 pounds.
Hm.
I looked it up. The largest lobster
ever reported was close to yes.
50 pounds found in the 1950s
just off the coast of New Jersey.
New Jersey. Yeah. Hi, Ho fit.
How old is a 50 pound lobster?
Who known vacation was wearing a
Grover Cleveland for president button.
So y'all, I'm Jad,
I've been riding I prequel
[inaudible] this is radio lab will be.