I'm Kelly. Can you hear me?
Yeah. Okay, good. All right.
So we're just doing this because,
because that article you wrote with one
of the most amazing things that we've
ever read. Oh, I thank you. Okay.
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and today a story about a
decision about a decision that we as human
beings, we've only recently begun
to consider. Yeah, sure. There are,
there are stories like this elsewhere,
but somehow not too many. No,
maybe not know. So we're going to devote
the entire hour to just this one story,
which I think is the
first for us think it is.
And the story comes to us from a
woman named Kelly Behnam. Okay.
She's a reporter for the
Tampa Bay Times in Florida.
Maybe the way to do this as
chronologically, just sort of across time,
where were you and who,
what did you want to do when I
decided to have a baby? Yeah. Well,
you one of those people who,
who ever since you were young,
you knew that you would be a mom.
Yeah, I did, but I wasn't like, um,
I didn't play with a lot
of dolls or babysit. I bet.
I always just kind of had this weird
certainty that I might have a daughter and
a daughter and not a son, maybe
a son too, but I don't know.
I think I always thought I would have a
daughter and I sort of had this image of
her in my head. And what was
the image like? Really Feisty,
mischievous, dark hair. Um, dirty face.
Okay. We've, we've left princess
land, not a princess at all.
Like a tree climber and a dog chaser.
I really wanted to have a baby.
I wanted one very badly,
but I just couldn't see how it
made sense for me to be the father.
That's Tom French,
also a journalist at the Tampa Bay Times
or he was at the time he and Kelly had
been dating for a few years, but he
was a good 10 years older than her.
I had two kids,
sons approaching the end of college and
I was ready to travel. I wanted to see,
yes. Spain and Greece and
the world tour on the,
on the cruise ship where you get
to be the, you know, poker master,
whatever you interested.
The only world tour I would have
been insured with Springsteen,
Springsteen following
Springsteen around Europe.
I'd made up my mind no more kids,
but she was insistent. I stuck to it.
She saw our daughter
very clearly. Oh yeah,
I saw that I was destined to
be that little girl's father.
And was that a happy gentle disagreement
or the other kind? Oh, it was brutal.
Broke up. And when we
worked at the same place,
there was kind of an
invisible line in the,
in the newsroom that neither of us
would cross. The line was the mailboxes.
There really wasn't one. Wow. It was a
horrible time. We call it the dark era.
The dark period. What turned you? Uh,
it was the, uh, it was the
Halloween section of target. I,
my sons and I have
loved Halloween forever.
I love it when I was a little kid and,
uh, I just wanted to see what they had,
if they had anything new,
cause I had, you know,
I usually check out their gargoyles and
their stuff and so I just was kind of
walking through the section
browsing and then something
[inaudible]
just stop me in my
tracks. Apparently it was,
it was really like kind of a lightning
bolt epiphany. And I just said,
wait a minute, maybe you are not
thinking about this straight,
you're acting as though you're 80.
And then it hit me that nobody knows how
much time they have to have a child is
to embrace a future
that you can't control.
Remember those words.
[inaudible]
so I, I, you know, I had this
come to Jesus meeting with
myself among the gargoyles and that was
when I realized I need to just take a
step back and try to restart the
conversation with Kelly. And so then he,
you know, went home and wrote
me this long letter and I just,
I was over and by that point I
was like, I wasn't looking back.
So, you know, over a few months, took
a little while, they patch things up,
eventually got married and
started trying to make a baby.
We thought that this would just happen
right away. And then of course it didn't
[inaudible]
after trying and trying the regular way,
she took drugs that make you drop a
bunch of eggs at one time. After that,
the Turkey based or method,
there's like kind of a process that they
walk you through after Turkey Beyster
IVF test to stuff. Yeah,
and I never thought that
it would get that far,
but it would go farther because after
trying IVF three times, that didn't work.
So they said, well you can
try it with an egg donor.
Meaning you get a friend who'd be
willing to donate the egg, take the egg,
put it in a dish, forcibly
impregnated with Tom Sperm.
Then you insert the egg into your womb
and that's kind of the magic bullet it
seems in fertility.
It's kind of like if you don't
know what's wrong with your car,
you just replaced the whole engine.
Kelly asked a good friend
to be an egg donor.
They've been planted the egg and
shortly after she took a pregnancy test,
I tested away too early. Um, and
so the line was super, super faint.
Wasn't even sure I could see it at all.
So I took a photograph of the pregnancy
test and I put it into Photoshop and I
actually had to dial up
the contrast to make the,
the line up here.
That is everything about this
is so high tech. Right. Wow.
Did you see what you wanted to see?
Yeah, and I was like, oh my God,
I think there's two lines there. So I
waited and I, and I did it a second time.
Um, and then I, then I told Tom
and did you go into like the
expectant parent mode and Oh yeah,
they touched up to paint. You know, I
patched the little holes in the wall.
Everything was perfect.
Everything was absolutely
perfect until it wasn't
five months into her pregnancy, 20 weeks,
which is just about halfway
cause the full term is 40.
Kelly was at a park
playing with her dog and
I just,
I felt a little bit weird and just
started to bleed like not a lot,
but any amount of blood
is not a good thing.
And I called the doctor's office
and they didn't seem too concerned.
They were like, yeah,
you probably want to go to the
hospital and get that checked.
And I went to pick her up then
[inaudible]
by the time we got to the
hospital, she was in a lot of pain,
cramping, cramping, cramping. I knew
something was really, really wrong.
They got me into one of those wheelchairs
and they wheeled me into the, um,
sort of triage room. And by that point,
like blood was just coming out of me,
chunks of blood coming out
of me and I didn't know,
I thought it was baby parts
like falling out and I thought,
I'm having a miscarriage. Like the
babies kind of drop out on the floor.
I was throwing up and then the
doctor came in and he looked scared.
There's the doctor say
something or what happened?
Um, the doctor
explained to me quietly,
there was something that was making
it difficult to stop Kelly's bleeding.
And if they couldn't
stop it, we might lose.
Kelly and Kelly heard the doctor
say this, and I need to tell you,
Kelly is the toughest, most
fearless person I've ever known.
But she grabbed my arm as hard as
anyone who's ever grabbed my arm.
And I remember just asking
him, don't let me die.
Please don't let me die. It
was terrifying. And then, um,
at some point they,
they brought in an ultrasound machine to
see what was going on with the baby and
I assume the baby was long dead. I mean,
I thought they were baby parts
on the floor. I didn't know.
And they hooked up this machine and
they were moving their on and around and
around and trying to pick up a heartbeat
and there was nothing. And, um,
I was apologizing to Tom,
I'm sorry, like, you know,
I just knew the baby was
gone. Then all of a sudden
[inaudible]
there, it was just as hard.
this is sound. She
recorded on her cell phone.
[inaudible]
baby's heartbeat. Super, super fast. So
it sounds like a rabbit or something.
You just hear it on the Sonogram. Yeah,
this heartbeat pops up and then there's
the baby and you can see and she looks
fine. She's totally oblivious.
She's just right there.
So now I thought, oh my God,
I'm going to watch her die
when going watch her die
in front of me. And um,
then they started just pumping me
full of drugs to try to get this labor
stopped.
There's this drug called magnesium
sulfate and one of the effects of it is it
just makes you kind of
boil from the inside.
But eventually they got the contraction
stop. They got the bleeding stopped,
they put me in a hospital room and they
said get to 24 weeks because that's,
that's the limit. So
four more weeks. Yeah.
It was almost like they
drawn a line in the sand.
Like you must get to 24 or
there's no hope. And why 24?
What's special about that? That
number they told me that um,
24 weeks is kind of the loose
definition of viability.
[inaudible]
that sort of grew out of when
they were fighting out Roe v Wade
in Fondren birth at state for example,
the court rule that a woman who commits
an abortion on herself is guilty of no
crime. Okay,
okay, so here's the story as I understand
it Robert. Okay. In Roe v Wade,
the supreme court was trying
to strike this balance.
They wanted to protect a woman's
right to choose as we know, right?
But they also wanted to say that
there are limits to that, right,
that there is some moment
in the development of the
fetus in the course of this
pregnancy,
we crossed this line and suddenly it's
no longer just about the woman's rights.
Now you have to think about the
state's interest in the [inaudible]
born child. The problem of course,
it's weird you draw that line
now that is the million dollar
question. This is neither pharaoh honey.
She's a law professor at Duke University.
So the kind of best gas at that point,
the best medical objective standard
that the justices could come up with.
And this is in 1973 was viability and
Norton viable in this case means can it
survive on its own? Yes, outside of
the woman's womb. In other words,
when a fetus is developed enough that
you can take it out of the mother's room
and it can still survive.
That the court suggested is the point
when it is no longer okay to have an
abortion because of cross that
line, a fetus is quote viable.
So then the question was, when
does a fetus cross that line?
When can it survive on its own?
Well,
we begin Mr. Justice in our brief with
the development of the human embryo.
And here's where you get
to the 24 week thing.
What ended up happening was that the court
considered what was known about fetal
development. And there are charts that
show this, um, go like this. Three weeks,
the fetus was brain and heart begin
to develop eight weeks, nerve fibers,
13 to 16 weeks, the fetus begins
to move and then kick at 23 weeks.
Some fetuses respond to familiar, sounds
like a mother's voice and at 24 weeks
[inaudible]
air sacks form in the lungs.
And the thinking was
maybe that's the point,
the minimum point where the fetus is
viable because perhaps it could breathe on
its own. But this was
just a theoretical idea.
No one was testing it.
No one was trying to take the fetus out
of a mother at 24 weeks to see if it
would survive. In fact, throughout
the 70s and eighties most hospitals,
according to Kelly drew the line of
viability back a little bit farther at 28
weeks.
And that is because somewhere
around the 28th week of gestation,
the lungs start to produce
a fluid called surfactant,
which prevents the lungs from collapsing
and sticking together between breaths.
So that's a really important
thing. So for a long time,
the actual viability line, not
the theoretical one was 28 weeks,
but then in the late seventies someone
invented an artificial lung surfactant.
It's kind of a slippery white stuff
that they shoot down the ventilator tube
when the baby's born. And that
combined with Ivy Nutrition,
new super small ventilators moved the
line of viability back to around where it
is now. Where it is now is
generally around 24 but uh,
here's the thing, depending
on what hospital you're in,
even what doctor is on call,
sometimes it can be 23 or 25 or in some
cases 22 so given modern technology,
you could imagine, so there's need a
one day the line could jump way back,
which will make things really tricky.
If for example,
we get to the point where modern science
is able to develop an artificial womb.
Yeah. Does viability start at the
point of a fertilized egg? You know,
if the standard is the point at which
the developing child can actually survive
outside of the womb using any
technological intervention possible,
that is a slippery line. Indeed.
They said get to 24 weeks
because that's the limit,
which meant that the doctors
have to pump Kelly full of drugs,
keep her feet elevated for
at least another four weeks.
But I just kept going into labor in
and out of it and they felt like they
couldn't hold it off anymore.
And at 23 weeks and four days,
a doctor tells her that there's
nothing more they can do.
The baby is gonna come
in a day, maybe two.
The guy comes in and um, he, he,
he seems a little uncomfortable like
this, that was not pleasant for him.
He said, you know,
your baby's probably coming in 24 to 48
hours and we know how hard you work to
have this baby and we know how much you
want this baby and we assume that you
want everything done. What does that
mean? We had no idea. So we said,
we're not sure if we do want everything
done. Paint the picture for us doctor.
And he said, you know,
there's about a 53% chance that the
baby will die no matter what we do.
53. Yeah. Whatever we do, whatever we do,
there was a small chance that she
could be fine. What were those chances?
About 20
[inaudible]
I felt like, like 20%
you know, it's not an,
it's not an impossibility. It
seems like a like a reasonable,
it seems like worth a gamble until you
really think about what the 80% means.
I mean, she could be on a
ventilator for the rest of her life.
She could have a massive bleed in her
brain and it was like eat holes in her
brain and affect her ability
to think or talk or walk.
She could pretty good chance
she could be blind or deaf.
And there was no way for
the doctors to predict.
But with the doctors didn't know is
that when the baby came into the world,
it would need a ton of medical support.
It may even need to be revived.
And so the question for the [inaudible]
for Tom and Kelly was, do they
want the doctors to do that?
Do they want them to pursue
every measure possible or no,
and just let nature take its
course? And he said it would be,
we should decide before the baby
came because once the baby came,
if we saw the baby, it would be
really hard to say no. So if,
if no was going to be the answer, we
needed to say that before the baby came.
Yeah, it's the worst night ever
and you're trying to make up your
mind about what's what's right.
Like would we be torturing
this baby for nothing?
We didn't want her to be born and have a
life that she would hate us for having.
There have been instances where children
with birth defects or genetic diseases
have filed wrongful life suits,
essentially claiming that they
should have never been born.
We had to really debate what
was in her best interests.
What would she want?
I started to really struggle
with whether I was being selfish,
whether I had already pushed too far
and this was like God or the universe
pushing back. Well, think we
went into pleasing our house.
Our marriage might break up.
We would lose our ability to
try again for another child.
I felt like I might get a baby,
but I would lose everything else.
And I think I got pretty close to no
[inaudible]
all night as we're talking
this through and yeah.
[inaudible]
crying and trying to figure it out.
ah, we could hear the baby's
heartbeat through the Monitor.
[inaudible]
baby was letting us know all
night. I'm right here, right here.
[inaudible]
but there must've been a moment where
you had to say yes or no out loud.
I um, we asked for a second
opinion or not a second opinion,
but another console.
We had some more questions and a nurse
practitioner from the NICU came to the
room. Yes. My name is Diane Leisel.
I'm a neonatal nurse practitioner.
This is the next day had asked to speak
to someone again and set up just citing
numbers and statistics. I don't give
numbers. It's different for each baby.
She kinda started to paint a
picture. This is what I've seen.
I've been doing this 30
years. But more importantly,
I also told them that it
wasn't a yes or no decision.
[inaudible]
she said, you know, you don't
have to decide right now.
They could have the baby. The
baby came out crying and active,
then we should do everything we can
for the baby. But if the baby came out,
blue and limp intervened,
tricolor hemorrhage
[inaudible]
we could stop. We didn't
have to keep going.
If something goes horribly wrong,
we can withdraw the support and then
you could hold your baby until it dies.
But you can give your baby a chance
and see how it goes. In other words,
in a very real way, they could
give this decision to the baby.
That same night I was feeling
like I'm just uncomfortable.
A couple hours later,
discomfort turns to pain.
Finally a doctor came in and
was like, yeah, your labor,
we have to go right now. So then
it was like super, super quick. Oh,
our light shot in the spine,
cutting me open and then,
oh my God, there's a
third person in this room.
[inaudible]
but not really. Not Quite,
almost. I mean, she was so,
so early. And what did she look like? Um,
well I didn't see her then. Um,
I just saw like her kind of Whiz by in
an incubator and she just looked like a
little dark smear in a hat.
And did you make it to 24 weeks?
So we were one day shy of 24
[inaudible]
23 weeks and six days.
we'll be back in just a moment.
Hi, this is Kelly friends. Tom French
sham leaving credits. There we go. Okay,
here we go. I'll try it.
Regular lab is supported in part by
the national science foundation and the
Alpha t phone foundation enhancing
public understanding of science and
technology in the modern world. Hi Diane.
Lays out more information about
Sloan can be found@wwwdotsloan.org
I'm Bessie music.
I hosted esoterical talk show in
Egypt after the Arab spring until the
government tried to throw me in jail.
So now I live in America and I host the
podcast three made in America presented
by cafe where I interview all kinds
of outsiders from comedian Maz.
Do you run to journalist Maria in a
wholesale and filmmakers here in view?
And I try to use those conversations
to figure out my new country,
American subscribe to remade
in America presented by cafe.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is radio lab.
Today we're spending entire
hour on a single story,
which we saw in the Tampa
Bay Times. Kelly Behnam,
a journalist published an unbelievably
wonderful set of articles about her and
her husband Tom Fringe,
who was also a journalist.
They had a baby except their
baby came very, very early.
So full term, as we've
mentioned, is 40 weeks.
Their daughter arrived
23 weeks and six days,
which works out to be just a
little bit over halfway. No,
just to put that in context,
if a baby is born before 22 weeks,
it's generally considered a miscarriage
and pretty much no doctor is gonna
intervene. If a baby
is born after 25 weeks.
There've been all kinds of studies which
show that doctors then feel morally
obliged to save that life no
matter what the parents say.
So before 22 and after 25
things are pretty clear,
but between 22 and 25, you
land in this gray zone,
this strange little liminal
space between life and death.
We have to answer some really tough
questions like should my baby live at what
cost and who gets to decide. And
ultimately when does life begin?
And she has shown us that
so many Kelly and Tom,
like many parents who land in this zone
decided that for the hardest question,
ultimately it's up to the baby.
The baby will tell them whether it's
going to stay or whether it's going to go.
So they delivered by c-section. And uh,
their daughter with that
point didn't have a name,
was whisked off to the neonatal
intensive care unit or the NICU.
And eventually they went to see her
and they incubator for the first time.
And she was, um, like,
like weirdly perfect.
[inaudible]
if she had all the parts,
these long fingers and long feet,
delicate little nose and she had hair and
fingernails and eyebrows and you know,
all the things that they're supposed
to have. But she was translucent.
You could just see right through her.
You could see all the veins running under
her skin and you could see her heart
thumping in her chest. Um,
and her eyes were sealed
shut like a puppy. And um,
she was like beat up.
Like she had bruises all over her body
and she had a black eye just from the,
you know, they were very careful
with them when they're born,
but just that very delicate handling, um,
kind of batters these babies
because they're so fragile. I mean,
it was like weird. Like I didn't
know how I supposed to feel.
I mean, you want to believe that the,
the minute you meet your daughter,
there's going to be like
butterflies, you know,
or like Unicorns or something. It's
supposed to be the best moment of your,
but there was so much
terror inside that moment.
I was terrified because
I love being a father.
My relationship with my sons is extremely
important to me and I was really
terrified that she would be so alien
having been born at 23 weeks, six days,
that I wouldn't recognize
her as my daughter and that
I wouldn't bond with her,
that I was now that thought was filled
me with a real dread and I went up to see
her. I could see that she was
only a half finished, barely a
pound at that point. So tiny.
My brain couldn't even
process how small she was.
And the nurse Gwen, um, she said,
well, you can touch her, you know,
and I was stunned because I didn't think
I would be able to. And so she had me,
I had already washed and sterilized my
hands once and she had me do it again.
She showed me how to reach in through
this little round porthole into the
incubator and explained
how to touch her. You,
you don't rub the skin because the
skin will come off if you do that.
When they're born that early
you, you just press gently.
And so the baby was lying
there, not with her fists,
but with her arms extended
with their palms open.
So her right palm was right there.
When I reached my left hand,
Dan and I just put my,
my left finger gently into her
poem and she just grabbed on tight.
Mm.
And in that moment, um,
[inaudible]
all my fears about not being able
to bond with her washed away.
And um,
hi. Uh, what, what got to me was
how
I could be so afraid.
Oh, when she was so strong and
at that point I just,
she was the most beautiful thing
I'd ever seen and I told her,
hey, peanut daddy.
So that's why my daughter, yeah.
When a baby is this early,
the parents and the doctors are watching
it very carefully trying to guess,
is this baby ready to be out in the world?
Is it going to make it? And Tom says,
when she grabbed his finger,
that wasn't just them bonding,
he felt like she was saying something.
She made her will very, very clear.
Baby declared itself like
declared its will to live.
And that was a phrase we
heard again and again.
Some babies will for can use the term
to declare themselves over the first few
hours and days of their
life. That's a neonatologist.
We spoke to Keith Barrington,
you get a gut feeling and that's Diane
Lez elegant and the nurse practitioner.
After meeting the baby that this one
looks very fragile or this one can do it,
the baby's declared itself. Now
there's a real question as to like,
what does that mean?
What are you seeing when something that
prematurely declares itself and here we
ran into a real difference.
Parents will often see will in a credible
will and resolve doctors and nurses.
No, not so much. That sounds
a bit too mystical for me.
I wouldn't take it as there's a voice
inside the baby saying I'm going to be a
fighter. I'm not one is sick enough
not to be able to fight and one isn't.
Can you see a spirit in it in a kid?
Can I think you can see for
some fight, I call it spunk.
A lot of times that is Tracey
Hollet. I'm a registered nurse.
She was Kelly and Tom's primary nurse
at all children's hospital and like
everyone we spoke to on the hospital
side, when it comes to this issue,
she chooses her words very carefully.
I maybe try to keep things a little bit
more neutral than talking about their
will to live.
Because you know a baby at 23 weeks
barely has folds on the outside of its
brain. Its brain is still
smooth for the most part.
So who knows what it's capable
of thinking or feeling? Oh,
that's a difficult question.
And the truth is things like fight
spunk may just boil down to physiology.
Maybe that baby had a few
more lung buds to start with.
Maybe it had an easier time and utero
may have nothing to do with will.
In fact the baby grasping
the finger of the parent,
it's actually a reflex
[inaudible]
that the babies have a grasp reflex.
I never tell a parent that because they
think it's an intentional movement.
Because you know, putting
yourself in the parent's head,
if you've gotta decide how
much am I going to push,
how much of my heart am I going
to pour into this little creature?
Maybe if you can see something like
will or something like intention,
if you see, oh, that's a person in
there. Or maybe if you don't see it,
maybe it's the only way you got to
make this decision. Yes. My wife,
the professional ethicists often says,
we don't make important decisions in our
life for rational reasons. Very often,
no. Keith and his wife, Annie,
John VA have done a huge amount of
research into the ethics of extremely
premature births.
But one of the primary reasons we wanted
to talk to him is that in addition to
being a neonatologist and a guy who
publishes a lot of stuff in this area,
he and his wife recently had a baby girl
who was born at 24 weeks and five days
[inaudible] 20 grams, one
and a half pounds. And, uh,
she was actually in my
own and ICU. Oh Wow.
I was actually the director
of the unit where she was
[inaudible].
So he was in his unit into the place
where he usually worked. He saw babies,
make it not make it,
and now suddenly he
was a parent that place
and several weeks after his
baby was born, there was a very,
very big complication. She actually
didn't move at all for about 36 hours.
How many thought maybe it was a
little and maybe it's time. Yeah,
so they decided he and
his wife to let her go.
Yeah,
peacefully.
But I went back into the en ICU
to see ya in something happened.
He looked down and he saw her lips move.
[inaudible]
barely just thought he was sucking on
a suitor that the nurse had put in her
mouth. She was sucking on a
pacifier and it was just a reflex.
The most basic baby reflex, the
sucking reflex. He knew that,
but just that movement
to slicking on the Sioux,
that changed his mind completely.
I went and bank to Manny and said,
we can't stop. A really neat to, to
continuing and give her the chance.
But you knew that some of the
sucking responses and not,
that's a fairly deep brain.
Yes. It's a very basic,
it's just the brainstem is not, you know,
you and you need a lot more than be
able to suck to, to, um, to do well.
But as I say, I was trying
to be the parent there or
not then in etiologist. Oh,
could you remember if the doctor in
you was surprised at the father in you?
Yeah, I think I was
actually a little, yeah.
I think if I had to have
been more evidence based
and rational and scientific,
um, I, I could have gone either
way, but just as a father,
I couldn't at that point let it go.
I just didn't really
know how to process it.
I felt like she was,
I just had this very acute sense that
she had just been like violently ripped
out of my body and I could feel
where they had cut her out,
you know?
And like I just wanted to put
her back and make her safe,
you know? Yeah. And I had had all
these questions going through my head,
like, you know,
like how long does she have to live for
us to get a birth certificate for this
to be real. Like I felt
like she might die and, and,
and like, it wouldn't count and
I, and I wouldn't be a mother,
you know what I mean? And,
and like what if she died?
Like what would happen? Like
what do we have a funeral?
They make caskets the size of shoe
boxes. I mean, all, he's like,
it's so screwed up that that's
the stuff you think about,
but your brain goes places you
just can't control or predict.
Um, and if she, I want
her to like, if she knew,
was she really aware that
I was even standing there?
Like was it just a reflex that made her,
grabbed my finger and when she grabbed
it, did she know that you know,
I was there and if she didn't know I was
there, did she wonder where I had gone?
Hmm.
Did she feel alone? And then she's scared.
Oh, she could really do at that
point, we'll sit with those questions.
And it just became this waiting game.
A
[inaudible] [inaudible]
continuing about moment.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab and we are spending
the whole hour with Tampa Bay Times
reporter at Kelly Bennom and her husband
Tom French and the story that they're
telling us to bet this limbo a space
that's literally between life and death.
We have to tackle some
really big questions. Yeah.
Oh the, here's an easy one.
Tom, when did you decide to name your
daughter? Juniper [inaudible]? About
about five days after she was
born. No, in those five days,
pretty much everything
in their lives changed.
I mean on the most superficial level,
they began their hospital stay
days zero in the maternity ward,
which had butterflies on the
walls and images of roses opening.
And um,
everyone's really good looking like in
an er sort of way or like in a Grey's
anatomy kind of way. We had
like one super hot nurse,
we called her cupcake and she had
this like glossy hair and you know,
people would visit me. They'd be
like, Hey, is cupcake here with,
is cupcake? Come on by. And so that's
where their hospital journey began.
But five days later everything had
changed and they find themselves on a
different floor of the hospital stranded
in this unit that is perhaps more than
any other place on earth. The
physical embodiment of this limbo,
the neonatal intensive care unit,
the NICU where they just have to wait and
hope that that will or whatever it was
they saw in juniper takes hold.
We had been like yanked out of our
lives and out of everything that we
recognized, you know,
out of our jobs at our
house and we just been
okay
dropped into this like science fiction,
nothing was recognizable babies
that even look like babies,
you know there was one baby that had
his intestines be outside of his body,
like piled up on his
belly like in this back
and everyone's wearing uniform,
don't know who anyone is
and everything like
beeping and humming and
you don't know how long you're going to
be there and you don't have any sense of
time. Like day and night don't
mean anything. And you know,
we're sort of dimly aware of the Sun
rising and setting out the window.
But other than that, it's just,
it's just like minute
to minute, hour to hour.
You're afraid to leave even for you for
an hour to get some lunch because the
baby could die.
You know, if we went home to get
some sleep, would she, would she die?
I mean is that critical? And
she had roughly five, six
days that went pretty well.
And then that next weekend
blew a hole on our intestines.
That was the real beginning
of a lot of problems.
And her belly turned dark
and got real distended.
They were inserting drains in the belly
to try to drain away the stool and gunk.
And she just had this little straw
sticking out of her belly and then they
couldn't maintain her blood pressure.
So I was thinking of
everything I could do,
cause you don't want to feel
powerless in a situation like that.
You want to feel like
there's something you can do.
So in quiet moments with Tom would do
chapter one, the boy who lived his,
he would stand over juniper incubator
and he would read her Harry Potter,
Mr and Mrs Dursley of
number four privet drive.
We're proud to say that they were
perfectly normal. Thank you very much.
They were the last people you'd expect
to be involved in anything strange or
mysterious. As I started reading
to her and as the days went on,
she has no idea what I'm reading.
Right. But there is something there that
she responded to. I wanted
to say she liked because her,
her sat number would go high
at that point. Her sat number,
what is it like her oxygen, the
saturation of oxygen in our blood. Ah,
Tim says that number on the monitor was
one of the only ways that they could get
feedback about how she was doing. Because
you know, her eyes were still closed.
There'd be times when she wasn't moving
around a lot. The higher the number,
the better. And he says
when he would read to her,
her numbers would go up. Not
just slowly but instantly.
But then when I got deeper into the story,
I read in Haggard's voice
buyout it, professor Dumbledore,
Sir said the giant climbing carefully
off the motorcycle as he spoke and she
decided instantly
and the alarms are just going off and
going off and Kelly hit me and she said,
you're scaring the baby.
And I'm like, what do you,
what you could see even before her eyes
opened that she was really responding to
what we were doing. She didn't know a
chapter is, but she was in her own way,
very eagerly waiting for the
next chapter and I don't know,
a better way to describe to be alive.
Then you want to find out what
happens next. Unfortunately,
what happens next is that one night at
around two o'clock in the morning on a
rear, NYPA Bay actually
went to sleep at home.
They get a call from their doctor in his
first question was how far do you live
from the hospital? And yeah,
that's not a question you want to
hear from your child's doctor. Leave,
like rushed to the hospital.
And, um, when they get there,
they were told that she did it
again. She got another hole,
neither hold her intestines and
she started to really spiral
[inaudible]
I it really go downhill. Her blood
pressure and oxygen levels were crashing.
She was on a hundred percent oxygen.
The ventilator settings were turned up
as high as they could go and she was
still struggling and
faltering and you know,
once they are giving your
baby a hundred percent oxygen,
they can't give her any
more. At that point,
I had done everything
that I could possibly do.
This is Fauzia Shaquille neonatologist
at all children's hospital.
She was Juniper's doctor at the time.
She said she'd given juniper everything
she could think of, blood pressure,
medicine, antibiotics. She'd
put a drain in her abdomen,
but obviously it was not enough. If
something was wrong, instead of be wrong,
we might lose her at any second.
The only option left to take her to
the operating room with car open,
clear the intestines,
relieve the pressure.
How do you do a surgery on a one
pound baby? Seems no, exactly.
I mean you don't, she was so
extremely premature, so fragile,
so tiny. That operating
seemed kind of crazy.
And Dr Shaquille began to really
consider the idea that maybe this was,
it had at that point. Um,
I was at bedside looking at her, um,
trying to figure out what
to do and all of a sudden
[inaudible]
she opened her eyes.
Really?
Yeah. She opened her eyes.
Why? And she looked at us,
her eyes were like wide open and she
was looking right at the doctor directly
staring at her hard. And uh,
it was a very powerful moment.
[inaudible]
Dr Shaquille says she decided right then
and there. Well, going into surgery,
I think she deserves a chance to tell me
more about why you made that decision.
Oh, well,
typically babies who are that critical
or they're totally unresponsive.
Yeah.
Because they're just fighting for every
breath and the ability to just open her
eyes at that stage in her life when
she had no blood pressure that I could
barely record when she had hardly any
oxygen for her to just open her eyes and
look at us. It was a very powerful
statement that I'm still here.
I'm here, I am still here, don't
give up. So Dr Shaquille Summon,
the pediatric surgeon told her they
want to move forward with the operation,
but the surgeon, no
[inaudible]
the surgeon was adamant that she did
not want to do it. She said it's Eh,
it's few title and it's um, she,
her blood pressure's so unstable that
she will not make it out of the Er.
And the surgeon told her, yeah,
even if I can open her up and do the job,
her skin is so papery that I might
not be able to set her back up.
There are guidelines that medical
industries have even basic things like the
hippocratic oath do no harm. That's
law professor and emphasis. Nita,
Farrah honey. Again,
many physicians legitimately believe
that if you have a preterm and fence and
that infant is in serious
peril of spending a life of
suffering and pain and the
only way to do no harm and fulfill
your oath is not to do the surgery.
But she says, if you ask
the courts, you know,
right now the law favors life.
The courts have seen very few cases
that involve disputes like this,
but in every one so far,
she says they've supported the person
who's arguing to keep the child alive.
I never, there's life. There's hope.
So this is our window. We should do it.
Now for Dr Shaquille,
the argument that ultimately
won the day was simply this.
Basically what I told her was that
if you think she's going to die,
well he is dying right now
as we speak in the unit.
So we can either do nothing and she
definitely dies or we can do something and
she probably dies. But you never
know. There is a slim chance.
So they're wheeling the incubator with
the baby in it and I'm holding her little
hand and she's getting
ready to go into surgery.
And she was looking right at me.
And she hadn't done that before.
I mean,
it really seemed like she was aware that
I was there very clearly and she was
locked on my face. So I, we know her.
I gave her a little kiss on her forehead
and Tom did the same thing and then
they wheeled her away. How
long was the operation?
It was, we, they,
they co they paged us much more
quickly than we expect it to come back.
So we knew something was wrong.
The nurse assured Tom and
Kelly into a separate room,
this little windowless conference room
and the surgeon came in and she said,
you know, I, um,
she was supposed to go in
and clean everything out
and rinse everything off and
find the hole and patch it
and, and do all these things.
And she said when she cut the baby open
and touched the baby's intestines with
her, a little probe, she's, the way she
described it was everything fell apart.
It was just falling apart and falling
apart. And you're hearing this. Yeah,
juniper had survived the
operation, but barely.
So we're thinking like, okay,
this was an incredibly risky surgery and
we just put her through it for nothing
either. I thought there was no way
that bay was gonna live til morning.
I had been really
working hard to avoid thinking about all
the bad things that were possibly going
to happen here. Just trying
to hold on, you know,
and I sort of thought it was my job
to do that and I'm just kind of funny,
kind of stereotypically male of me. Um,
and uh,
and Tom says they were in the car
around the time of the surgery as we're
driving, you know, by that time Junebug
and I were about two thirds of the way.
So the first book and this
thought just snuck in on me,
which was,
what if I don't get to
finish reading her this book?
What if she doesn't
get to hear the ending?
Okay.
And you know, she never finds out.
You know, what happens to Harry,
Hermione and Ron
that thought led in all the other flats,
very difficult thoughts about all the
things we wouldn't get to do with her.
She wouldn't ever get to know.
And I had this terrible thought that,
you know, she was in this incubator,
this isolated this plastic box.
And I had this terrible thought that
she was just going to go from one box to
another.
Hmm.
And I had to pull over, you
know, cause I just lost it. And
at that point I wasn't maintaining
anymore. There was no holding back.
This flood of, uh, of,
of what was happening.
And we had a rural Kelly and I, which is
that only one of us got to lose it at,
at a time. And you know,
that was my turn to lose it.
We're in a very unnatural situation
of neonatal intensive care,
which is so recent in the developed world
and still doesn't exist in much of the
world. And we're working so
hard to save babies is very new
neonatologist, Keith, Barrington
and evolutionary history.
Newborn babies very frequently
died. And most parents who have a,
any significant number of children
had lost one or two or three or more.
And in order to be able to carry on with
your life and to provide for the rest
of your family, we had to be able
to adapt to the death of babies.
And now that has become much
less common to lose a baby,
even no miscarriages and stillbirths,
to now we realizing how much
that hurts. And in the past,
maybe we've hidden some
of that from ourselves.
No way that bay was going
to live til morning.
But what happened was really strange.
She continued to just not die
[inaudible]
and the next day she, you
know, she was still there.
Okay.
The surgeon was surprised and
no one can quite explain it.
The more I thought about it,
the more I found it like surprising
and interesting, you know,
because she doesn't know
that there's a better place,
you know that she's
just in this box. Yeah.
And she's gotten needles
coming out of every which way,
and tube down her throat.
She has no idea that one day, you know,
she'll just be held and rocked and then
we'll take her out for ice cream and
she'll play with the dog.
And I just wondered like
what is she fighting for?
[inaudible]
and so that became, you know, our job,
the best that we can articulate it
was to try to give her some sense of
something beyond that place.
After the surgery, things
did not get easier.
She would stop breathing many times a day.
Teams would rush into the state, come
on g, but come back, come back. I just,
I remember the room spinning and then
she started to swell for like weeks and
weeks, but she continued to not
die and she began to gain weight.
And you know, nurses are very
superstitious. A lot of them,
they won't say the word at home
for some reason. When the baby's here,
that word is Tracey. Hold it again.
Primary nurse, they get sick and we
just, it's a superstition obviously,
but something happens and
sometimes it can be devastating.
So what do you say instead?
We'll say that place that the baby's
going to go when they leave here. Wow.
I got so tortured. Sometimes we spell
it, which makes no sense at all.
Um, after about four and
a half months, Diane,
that nurse Practitioner told us that we
might want to think about buying a car
seat. That was the first
inclination that we might be
able to take her out of there.
That's the first time I've ever imagined
a choir of angels singing around
mention of Carthy. Carseats
right. But when you're,
when you want to have a baby really bad
and everybody else has a baby but you
and you can't have a baby.
Things like shopping for car seats
become like fantasies, you know, like,
and finally, you know,
the doctor gave the all clear and we
took the monitors off of her and she was
completely free and untethered,
not hooked to anything.
And we strapped her into this car seat
and I put a little pair of sunglasses on
her
cause I didn't know if her eyes
would be okay in the sunlight.
She'd never seen the sun. Wow.
And we all kind of walked out. And um,
Tracy's is really not a hugger, but we
like grabbed her, hugged her and cried
and all over her shirt.
And then we put the baby in the
car and we went to chick-fil-a.
Yeah, that was totally
before the gay thing,
before I stopped going
into filet and all in all,
how long were you in the hospital
for? Six and a half months.
I was 196 days.
How is your super now what? What is, can
you give us a snapshot of her morning?
Sure.
Actually Tom and Kelly
were nice enough to, uh,
allow us to send a reporter to their house
to meet her cousin.
She's two years old now.
[inaudible] hi, June book.
That's Jennifer [inaudible] say hi.
When we got there, she was still, she
was still in bed. It was just waking up.
She's not being very cuddly
this morning. Snippy.
But then she just sprung up,
jumped out of bed and took off.
Huh? Yeah. You went to Daddy.
Isn't that funny? Hoses.
Come on, show me where the kitty is.
I know you want to give
the kitty a hug. She is,
he don't look nice.
She's kind of your typical two
year old. [inaudible] Chantal.
And because we were their juniper,
it felt it was kind of important that
we see some tricks. She's learned.
Oh,
is radio. So they have no idea what
you just did. Even somersaults,
you know, it's, it's interesting
because as journalists again, we,
we spend a lot of time chronicling
sometimes very terrible things.
And uh,
what's interesting is that through
the chair yesterday morning,
by journalistic standards,
nothing happened, you know,
we need to do is change your
name. It was, it was, it was,
wouldn't even be on journalistic way doc.
Oh Huh. But what, you know,
as a parent comes in, especially after
you've been through what we went through,
if you come and see Mommy, I'm
on kiss. You was everything.
Come on Kesha.
Nothing you can do about
it either. We ready one.
Everything happened yesterday
in those couple of hours,
the entire world was contained
inside that morning. Okay.
Of Eskimo kisses and all of her
[inaudible] now all the blank chapters
of her life were inside that morning
waiting to be written. Huh?
Which, what you want this
book to me and it's called.
Oh. And do you feel like you're
out of the woods? Well, um,
both Tom and Kelly said no way.
And then Tom told us about these
flu shots that juniper gets.
They're not just flu shots.
They're like, um, flu shots,
like super flu shots and they,
there's four shots you get and I swear
to God that costs $14,000 for those four
shots. And that is, that's a real number.
You just said that's a fact. That's,
yes, they are designed to
help protect her from a RSV,
which is a virus that in most people
just presents as a common cold.
But you know,
her lungs are still recovering and
are still developing and RSV can be
devastating and there are
some other concerns that
could still creep in down the
road. Some studies have shown that
kids who were born prematurely, uh,
struggle more in school
with reading and math.
That's often they're more susceptible
to depression and anxiety.
But I will say that, um,
we took her to visit a preschool the other
day and we took her there and sat her
down and she just took off and like went
up to these giant children and started
taking their toys and they were seeing
the wheels on the bus and you could see
it in her eyes.
I know that song and she didn't
care about Tom or I one bit,
you know,
she was totally there with those kids
and she was so ready and I thought,
wow, she might be okay.
She is okay.
[inaudible]
and now for an update, um,
we originally aired this story in 2013
when juniper was to here's tape from just
a few months ago.
Right. How old are you?
Huh? Four. Oh my gosh.
You're about to turn five
in April and do that.
What's going to happen when
you turn five? Oh, lable Oh,
Earl Jones. [inaudible] wow.
Juniper is about to start
kindergarten and um,
her and Tom and Kelly live in Indiana now.
We're Tom and Kelly teach journalism
at the Indiana University media school.
I actually happened to be
in Indiana just yesterday,
so I hooked with Tom and Kelly.
We stood on the side of a busy street
in downtown Bloomington and they gave me
an update and they told me that in the
nearly three years since we heard this
story,
and this is generally not what you would
expect from a baby born that early.
Um, physically we have had
shockingly few problems.
Like she, she hasn't had any,
I gotta knock on some wood
somewhere. She never had like a,
a horrible bout of the flu or was
never back in the hospital. Um,
her kidneys are a little bit small
and they're watching that, but
there's a savagery to her.
It's true. That is amazing.
They told me that she's
this extremely headstrong,
active child really into climbing
trees. How did you get up there?
You climb, but you're so high up.
Sh like she goes horseback
riding. She does gymnastics.
Does she have some awareness
of the incredible journey
she went through just to
be four and a half? Do you guys
talk about it with her each night?
We talk about it because
every night she asks, Oh,
tell me the story about when I was
a widow, tiny baby in the hospital.
Tell me about when I was sick. Tell me
about when I had the hole in my tummy.
So you know, for a long time I would just
tell her the story. When you're born,
you're born very early,
a lot more early than you
were supposed to be born.
We just super extra small or her.
I called the hospital over
the summer and I said, hey,
like every night we were talking
about this, can I show her the NICU?
Like would you let me just show her the
space and what an incubator looks like.
And they were amazing about it.
And so they set up an incubator in an
empty room and they let her come in and
just play in the room.
And she took her a little doll baby
that I ordered for her on Primi doll,
baby.com or whatever that's like the size
and weight that she was when she was a
baby. Oh, is that a real thing?
It's a real thing, you know?
So I got her the stall that's so she
could get an idea of how small she was.
I don't know. I thought it
would be useful someday.
So she took it to the NICU and she put
it in the incubator and we showed her how
we would reach our hands through the
little portholes and hold her hand.
And she reached in and held her
little babies, little cloth hand.
And then because she's juniper
and of course she would do this,
she climbed into the freaking incubator
and laid down and asked Tracy the nurse
to close the lid. Whoa. Yeah.
Well like she, what was that
like for you? Was that like,
was that like traumatic flashback
or was that like really cool?
And she said at one point during the
visit, this woman walked by the room
and she kinda stuck her head in the
doorway and her eyes were all red and she
had that look about her.
Like she was a couple
days postpartum and I was,
I thought, Oh God, you know, Tracy
kind of whisper in her ear. Then Tracy,
the nurse and um, she looked
at Jennifer and she said,
oh my God, she's so beautiful.
And then she told us that she had just
had a baby if few days before that was
born at 23 weeks and six days.
[inaudible] hi, hey baby. Hey
Baby.
Now speaking of that, a specific
chunk of time, 23 weeks, six days,
we ended up checking back in with
Nita ferry honney professor of law and
philosophy at Duke University about
that whole viability question,
like that line of when a
preterm infant comes viable,
which at the time we did the story
seemed to be roughly around 24 weeks on
average. Has that changed at all?
And she pointed us to a study that was
done in 2015 which did sort of a big
survey of outcomes for preterm infants
and it basically argued that we might
want to push that line back even further.
The study author believes that 22 weeks
is the new standard for viability and
that 23 weeks and 23 weeks and
six days that that's too late.
She says, this is now the new
conversation, 22 weeks, not 24.
Um, you know,
this is something that physicians and
hospitals were being educated about and
look at. We're already at 22 weeks, um,
you know, and, and it's just been, what,
two years since we last talked about
this? Yeah. Three years at most, right?
I mean, so in three years, if
we've moved back two weeks, um,
then talk to me in another way,
a quarter of a century and
we'll be at the beginning,
she thinks it's just a matter of time
before we get to that artificial womb.
Maybe case Lessing I'll say by way of
updates is that Tom and Kelly are about to
release a book about their
experience. It's called juniper.
And normally I'm not one to Gush,
but this book is something else.
Like we got into this story because of
some really haunting articles that Kelly
had written for the Tampa Bay Times. Uh,
and this book takes those articles so
much farther goes into way more detail
than we could ever get into a it is,
yeah, it's totally worth reading.
And if you want to preorder it,
there is a link on our website.
Go to radio lab.org
your lab is produced by Jad Abumrad.
Really loud TDO rat at dish guys.
Jad Perfect.
Soren Wheeler is senior editor.
Dylan Keefe is director of sound design
challenge that you had to say the whole
thing though. Dylan
Keith really loud though
is director and they let go of
sound design. It sounded right.
Jamie York. I work
as senior producer. Amy
will get the new boot too.
Our staff includes Simon
Adler, David Gebel,
no p Robert Krulwich male
Latif Nasser Kelsey pageant,
Molly Webster with help from
Alexandra Lee Young Jeezy, not
Stephanie Tam and Michael [inaudible].
Our fact checkers are Eva
Dasher and Michelle Harris.
Special thanks to Lynn Paltrow,
Jennifer drinkers, John Lee.