Wait, wait, wait. Don't
let me just hit record.
Okay. And now, what were you saying
spontaneously a moment ago? Hey,
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is radio lab and today bliss.
And in our last segment we met a guy who
dreamt of a perfect world where words
can never muck things up. Got a little
carried away. So let's forget about Drey.
Forget about him.
Now we're going to look for perfection
right here in the physical world. Okay,
so, so, so this story,
and we're going to do it with the perfect
person Latif Nasser, it begins with a,
with a birthday present.
It's February 9th,
1886 miles outside the tiny town of
Jericho, Vermont. And we're on a farm,
a family farm, a the Bentley family farm,
and the scrawny 15 year old kid named
Wilson gets a microscope from his mother.
So it's February and it's
Vermont. And so naturally,
the first thing this kid does
is he grabs a handful of snow,
picks out a single flake and he
puts it under the microscope.
And what he sees
is, is, is the most beautiful thing
he's ever seen. It is ethereal and,
and, and perfect. He, he
calls them masterpieces as,
as if they're these, you know,
great works of art because him that in
his 15 year old diary, looking back,
he talked about that moment and
what he was thinking when he,
when he sort of first saw it
and, but obviously, you know,
within minutes or maybe even seconds,
these masterpieces just disappeared
without leaving any evidence that
they, that they ever existed.
They just sort of evaporate.
Huh. And as he remembers it, he,
he sort of decides then in there that
he's going to dedicate his whole life to,
to documenting these masterpieces.
Otherwise no one will ever
know they even existed.
He's going to spend his whole
life documenting snowflakes. Yeah.
It's a good life jet
and it pays well. Right.
That's exactly what his father said.
His father thought he was, you know,
he was just lazy and didn't want to do
the farming chores as far as his milk,
the goats. And he goes, now the
beauty, the beauty. Right, right.
And apparently he was a real, he
was really good at digging potatoes,
but he just sort of was so busy futzing
around with his microscope that he,
you know, I don't like this kid. I don't
like them to friends. Your work ethic,
it does so fucked up his neck.
So he takes his microscope and he moves
it to this unheated woodshed behind the
house. Um, and he starts sketching
these snowflakes, right?
And while he's sketching,
he can't even breathe because he was
worried that his breath would melt his
specimen. So he's sort of
holding his breath and, and,
and drawing these, you know,
these extremely complex crystals
that can take you maybe, you know,
maybe an hour to draw, but, but depending
on the temperature of the humidity,
the size of the crystal he had
at most, he had five minutes
at the end of that, he, he looks at
the mall and, and he's not satisfied.
He just felt like he
wasn't doing it justice.
You know what he calls
these miracles of beauty.
So Bentley persuades his mother who
persuaded his father to buy him a camera.
Why is that great? Wait, wait, wait.
1880. We're in February, 1880. I have,
we entered into, in the era of
picture taking, just, just barely,
and for a farming family,
this was like a lot of money,
but they buy it for him and he gets it.
Any sort of Jerry rigs to the microscope.
And at age 19,
Wilson Bentley is the first person ever
in history to photograph a snowflake.
Okay. I'm going to cue the snowflake
celebrations are secure, right.
[inaudible]
from then on, basically for the
next 46 winters until he died,
every, every snowfall,
every blizzard is a Bentley would stand
in the doorway of his little shack, uh,
holding out a wooden tray,
uh, with, with thick mittens.
Cause you would wear these, they're
almost like oven mitts to, to,
to make sure that his,
none of his body heat would kind of leak
out and inadvertently melt any of the
snow. So He'd sort of stand there and
sort of give it a once over with his eye.
If nothing was promising.
He, he basically had a,
a Turkey feather and he would sort of
just wipe it clean with this Turkey
feather until he did find something
you liked. And then he would,
he would take this tiny little wooden
rod and he would just certain really
delicately tap the center of the
crystal and like really, really,
really gently lifted off and
then transfer it onto the,
onto a glass slide so that he could put
it under the microscope and he could
photograph it. Over
the course of his life.
He'd basically photographed about
5,000 snow crystals for his whole life.
He was just a farmer doing
this kind of as a hobby. Uh,
but he sold copies of these photos for
5 cents a pop to places like Harvard and
the British Museum and the US
weather bureau, research journals,
magazines like nature and
national geographic. And I mean,
you've already seen the photos like you,
you've gotten them on a Christmas card,
they're on your like ugly Christmas
sweater in your closet somewhere. Um,
remember throwing a shirt with them
on right now. Yeah. Um, they're,
they're, they're, they're everywhere.
They're beautiful, symmetrical,
really clean. And Complex.
A lot of the greatest scientists who
ever lived like Descartes and Kepler and
Hook,
they all tried to sketch and draw and
kind of capture the essence of snowflakes,
but none of them could do it as well as
this one obsessive loaner from Jericho,
Vermont, whose photos were perceived to
be kind of more faithful to nature than,
than, than anybody else's.
But that was until, um,
this
other guy came on the scene,
this German guy Q, the other guy.
Germanic theme music. Yes. Hey, yes.
See she got through,
he was a German meteorologist named
Gustaf Hellman who stuff? Hell man.
Not of the mayonnaise
fame. I don't believe,
I haven't even thought of that
actually. Like it's a helmet. Is this,
is he a contemporary of
Bentley? Yeah, he is.
And he's working on his own book about
weather and so he hires a kind of a micro
photographer who's another German guy
named Richard Newhouse when Mike is a very
teeny photographer who he
kept on his desk. Yeah,
he's a microscopic himself and he
just takes normal size photographs.
Anyhow,
he hires this guy and they take a
bunch of photos using basically similar
technology camera and a
microscope essentially.
But what they find is totally different.
They do not find the, the,
the elegance and metrical ideal
snow crystals that Bentley found.
The crystals they found were like flawed,
lopsided, usually like broken.
And the way I think of it,
it was like a Martian who had only ever
seen like glossy fashion magazines had
just been given some like random family
photo album and it was like, Oh wow,
this is, they're not so pretty. Like
these are kind of ugly, you know,
these humans, humans
are not all symmetrical.
These Germans day, they basically called
them out. They, they basically stopped.
Bentley was a fraud.
There was a particular way that
Bentley prepared his photographs.
What he would do is he would use a,
a pen knife to scrape the
negative around the snow crystal,
which is what gave it that kind of Nice
black background because he thought it
would kind of put it in maybe
starker relief. Um, and,
and the German guys said that's it's,
it's misleading that it kind of
mutilates the snowflakes, um, away.
So he's photographing these snowflakes
and then significantly messing with the
photograph. Exactly right. Exactly right.
So here's a quote from the photographer
who said, quote, in many images,
Bentley did not limit himself
to improving the outlines.
He let his knife play deep inside the
heart of the crystals so that fully
arbitrary figures emerged.
So He's, Oh, I don't know.
That doesn't seem so no longer a
candidate, is it? Well, that's,
that's the question. So then, but
then, so they basically lob this,
and this is kind of going
into these journals,
but Bentley basically
launches a counter attack.
And what he says is that in
fact those guys are wrong,
that not correcting
your photographs was an,
he used this word like perverts to him.
Why wouldn't you remove specks of
dust or other imperfections? Why,
why photograph of a broken snowflake
when you can photograph a complete one?
So this is a quote from Bentley. He said,
a true scientist wishes above all to
have his photographs as true to nature as
possible.
And if retouching will help in this
respect than it is fully justified.
So he thought his retouched snowflakes
were truer than the normal ones.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
The scientist is supposed to be
kind of this very experienced,
almost like a sage who is seen every
different variation on a snowflake,
but can sort of bring that
all together in one drawing,
one sketch, one photograph,
and that's the true snowflake.
So if I brought him a slightly
gloppy snowflake and said,
look,
this is what fell on my nose and this
is a true snowflake because it actually
fell from the sky and it's, you
know, it was an an enhanced,
yeah, he would say that. He would say,
Robert, you're, you're an amateur.
Like this is, this is not good work.
You know, this is an aberration.
This is an abnormality.
Why would you choose to kind of highlight
an abnormality as opposed to kind of
this, this true ideal snowflake,
you know, and does that one exist?
I mean, that's the key question for me.
Like does the ideal
snowflake exist in nature?
You think there are such
things I exquisitely beautiful.
I would like to think that there are no,
so I think if my facts are right,
the world's snowflake expert is
actually in, in Pasadena, California.
All right. Check, check,
check, check, check in.
Can Sunny Southern California.
Yeah, I'm wearing a tee shirt.
I have sunscreen lathered and I am going
to talk to the world authority on snow.
How are you? His name is Ken Lee Breck.
He's a professor of physics at cal tech.
He is in a way,
he's like the modern day Wilson Bentley
because he takes a ton of of snowflake
pictures taken about 10,000 now and uh,
and he actually makes snowflakes.
Oh yeah. Artificially. Okay.
Wow. So this is a giant tank. This
is a nitrogen here. Nevermind that.
And to get to your question about
the ideal snowflake, a few things.
So number one, they're a
bajillion different kinds,
dendritic crystal stellar
Denverites needles and columns
and hollow columns and,
and a sector plates. That's one thing.
The second thing is that snowflakes are
never static. They're never one thing.
So at every single moment
as it falls to the earth,
it's either growing or shrinking.
Depending on the kind of
trajectory through the
different pockets of weather as
it's moving down.
So there is no real platonic ideal
form of a snowflake because it's,
it's, it's so influx. I mean,
there's no such thing
as a perfect snowflake,
but that doesn't stop Kenley Brag
from, from looking, you know,
I tried up in Tahoe and Japan, Vermont,
Michigan travels all over the world
looking for Bentley's perfect flakes.
Alaska. I've been to Alaska, Sweden, but
my favorite spot is northern Ontario,
a little town called
Cochran population 5,487.
So where do you go and do
you just, just anywhere.
They're just falling all over the
place. Mostly it's the, it's the, uh,
parking lot of my, my, my hotel. He
says there's a lot of waiting involved.
You'd only really snow as
well about once a week.
Even then things have to be goldilocks
perfect. If the clouds are too high,
then they evaporate a little on
the way down. They look for pretty,
or if the clouds are too light
or too heavy, that's bad too.
And a lot of times the temperature is
wrong if you want those Christmas card
supermodels, snowflakes, uh, eat.
But you need to have exactly minus
15 that's five degrees Fahrenheit.
You need to have high humidity,
not so much wind so that they'll putter
down slowly and have more time to grow.
But every once in awhile, I mean
when the conditions are right, yeah,
you've got side all hopeful and
dissipating and it's like, oh crap,
there's nothing garbage
out here. So you're back.
Go back inside and read some more email
and you'll come back a half an hour
later, nope, still lousy and
you half hour later, nope,
still allows it and you know,
you do this for hours and then all
of a sudden they'll get really good.
And then,
and then just out there and frantically
trying to collect as many as I can.
Well one of the things I like to
think about this is, you know,
here I am with my little piece of
cardboard in the middle of a continent.
It is snowing all the time.
And so I am catching some incredibly
small number of these things.
For a brief period and getting
some really cool pictures.
And so you kind of wonder what the,
what else is out there and
what are you missing? I mean,
imagine just all the beautiful little
works of art that are just falling down
totally unnoticed and then
they just disappear. I mean,
stuff that is far prettier than,
you know, the pictures I have,
cause they're out there, you know,
they're out there statistically
they're out there. And so, you know,
there's just an awful lot of really
gorgeous things such, it just started.
Like you say,
they're just totally a femoral and
you'll never see them and they're falling
constantly. So you sort of want to
just stop the world and you know,
go look at them.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
thanks to lots of Nasser and to Ken leap,
Rick who wrote the book the
secret life of a snowflake.
[inaudible]
this is Matt and newly
Dawson from Asheville,
North Carolina and bliss is this sound.
That's the sound of my seven month year
old daughter reacting to my puppy dog
waking her feet. Hi, my name is Igor
and I'm calling from Nova Sod Serbia.
Bless this. Indiana Jones, all free parts.
The radio lab,
this is Steve Strogatz
bliss is the taste of HACCP.
Pastrami at Deli in the lower
east side of New York City.
We live, we're five hours away from New
York and don't get there very often.
So I spend a lot of time in between
visits, thinking about that first taste,
hot pastrami. So for me,
that's plus I get to think about some
kind of almost unattainable perfection,
except that it is attainable.
I just show up in there it is.
This is Mary Roach and I'm in Oakland,
California. And I have a list of lists.
My list list number one, uh,
laughing uncontrollably. Number two,
zero gravity that were for the
first 10 seconds in a hot hot pack.
Number nine, a raw waster,
very fresh that no larger than
infants ear
[inaudible].