Uh, hello. Hello. Oh, all of that.
How are you? Oh my God. And Great.
What did I do?
Literally talking to another
world. I'm Jad. I am Robert.
This is Radiolab and today we are
reconnecting with an old producer of ours.
Brenna feral. Yeah. Past life.
Yeah. Ooh. Since leaving Radiolab,
she's been busy with work,
but also raising two kids
is crazy hard with family.
Just trying to like take my vitamins and
like exist on a low grade panic attack
all day. Well I guess we should start by,
let's just try and recall
like what it was. That's,
I don't even know how you
bumped in. You don't normally,
okay. So back in 2015, my husband,
nick and I were in our tiny apartment
back in Brooklyn and we were new parents.
Our Son Marty was 18 months old
at the time and one morning,
I think it was about 5:00 AM like still
dark. Marty woke up and he was just,
you know, crying, crying, crying.
And so I tapped my husband.
It was his turn to get up early and
go get Marty. So he got out of bed.
I fell right back to sleep and
the next thing I knew, I was like,
felt somebody tapping me and I sort of
rolled over in my bed and there was just
this little person looking up at me
covered at this greasy stuff all over.
His face was shiny and he was laughing
and he held up in his hand this giant jar
of diaper ointment,
the special medicated stuff that
we had bought just that last week.
And I just thought, oh my God,
he just ate all this medicine and
I have no idea how much he ate.
And I look around at my husband who had
gotten up with him, changed his diaper,
and they put them down on the floor
to play head because he was exhausted
falling asleep in the chair right
while watching him.
So I just flung myself to the end of the
bed and I grabbed Marty in one arm and
started frantically searching the label,
which was filled with words
like petrolatum, Sarasin,
panthenol glycerin is a Bolo.
The Brenda says she didn't register any
of those words because right underneath
that list of ingredients I just
saw this bold type that said a if
swallowed, call your doctor or
poison control center immediately.
[inaudible]
and so I'm clutching my son
and I'm clutching his jar.
And then I yelled to my husband
to wake him up and I'm like,
I need you to find the number and call
poison control while I hold Marty.
And so nick snaps into action,
leaps off the chair into the other room
so he can make the call and Brenna is
left sitting there in the bed holding her
18 month old son who is about to throw
up, pass out, die.
She's not sure like have you ever felt
that hollow feeling where you're like
your whole chest just drops
and you just, it's like,
it feels like missing a step.
You're like, he's just utterly sick.
And then just like all
sweaty up in my temple.
So I'm sitting on the edge of our bed,
Marty's in my lap and I'm eagle eye
watching for like whatever's about to
happening to him.
And I had always heard that like you
have your mother's instinct or whatever
that is,
and like moms know best and moms can tell
when something's wrong with their kid
and like sometimes, maybe that's true,
but for me Brenda says she just froze.
Wow.
I was imagining like this huge like
glop of ointment has worked its way down
your esophagus and now what is it doing
to your stomach lining and what's going
to happen when it had like, I was
just like, I can't take it back.
Like what do I do?
So nick has gone to the next room and I
hear that he's on the phone with someone
and then just moments later
he came back out and he said,
well, that was the most pleasant
phone call I've had in ages.
[inaudible]
there he was completely calm,
kind of like smiling at me in the doorway
and I'm just still hunched over the
bed, like hanging on to Marty
thinking what is going on?
So nick straightened up and then went
into like, oh, okay, here's what happened.
I called, they immediately picked up
and then it says that Nick told her,
you talked to this man, the guy asked him,
super matter of fact
how much Marty weighed.
Nick told him that 20
pounds or whatever. Yes.
Then what brand of diaper ointment did
Marty eat? They told him the brand. Yeah.
And then the guy did a
little mental math and said,
your child's going to
be fine. Totally fine.
Those was probably not a big deal at all.
It was really common. No vomiting, no,
no, nothing. Nope. He was like,
just like a slippery little piglet at
that point. So cleaned him up and then,
uh, you know, let him play
[inaudible]
but for the rest of the
day I just kept thinking,
what the Hell is poison control?
I honestly didn't think we still lived
in a world where you could just call a
hotline,
like get on the telephone and talk to a
live human who somehow knows everything
about this one specific brand of
diaper ointment. And then Bam,
like 45 seconds later, this full
blown crisis in my mind was just gone.
And then I, you know, I just was
having this weird moment of like,
there's this invisible network out
there that was just kind of primed and
waiting to help, um, who are these people?
So a few months later,
I'm totally obsessed with poison
control. Let me check, check, check.
And I ended up in a skyscraper in downtown
Chicago up 19 floors down these four
twisty turny corridors to the oldest
poison control center in America are here.
Tony, when it got there, you know, our
staff for service of natural light,
Carol, the senior director,
it took me on a tour a lot smaller than
I would have expected even though it's
not a dome, but it definitely is
an office was uh, I, you know,
I think I was expecting like just banks
of like high tech gleaming computers and
instead that phone hasn't worked in at
least five years, but it's still there.
It was this narrow
office with Greg carpet.
You have a crusty mushroom up there, great
cubicles. I don't know who's cubs hat
that is, but it's been here for a while.
At least. Kind of reminded me of like a
basement college computer lab, you know,
like where all the machines are kind of
still running windows 95 or something
like that and sitting in front of those
computers or the poisoned specialists.
Um, I'm, I'm the steak bite person.
I love paneling steak by calls.
Here's Aaron who's in snakes,
like the little old lady who's like
working in her backyard and there was a
snake and she chops off his head with a
shovel and then she brings a snake head
into the Er to show them what
bitter. And there's Connie,
I'm sort of the go to person
for mushrooms. How I look at it.
She takes us room calls even when
she's on vacation. Is that true? Yes.
And she gets excited about it. There's
Cindy who used to work in the Er.
I'm a nurse by background is Jessica,
take the home calls, there's art,
all of it. It's all fun. And
then Brian is here. There's Tony,
he's the expert in everything
Illinois poison center. And while
I was there, the stream of calls,
it was just nonstop. If I buy, as
soon as one of them would hang up,
the phone was in the
center, Illinois poisons,
another call would come in
and five normally healthy.
Okay,
gently wipe off his lips with
little warm water on a washcloth,
give him something to drink. They all
told me that in order to work here,
you need a background in medicine,
special training and toxicology.
On top of that, it helps to have a good
memory, good math skills, but you know,
more importantly what you really
need is to be able to stay calm,
calm.
I usually tell people they're going to
be overwhelmed by the first three months
was in center because
sometimes the calls, you know,
glow stick is not going to be
a problem. They're adorable,
but other times, boy, they're like this.
He has a temperature of 104 this
is an er call is a sugar. Again,
the hospital was calling about a male
patient who had been found unconscious,
completely sweaty, diaphoretic at
home, so the medics are assessing him.
His blood sugar was 40 is
Tylenol is three 72 his pupils,
she said are bouncing all over the
place. I don't know what that is.
After she hung up, I asked Cindy
if this was a self harm call.
It's believed to be yes. She was saying
that his wife just died of cancer.
Yeah. Is that somewhat rare to get
one that serious? No, not at all.
We get them all the time. At least
[inaudible] center.
Can you spell that?
Can you spell the name of that drug
and how many milligrams did you say?
I ended up spending about 12 hours there
that day and if you sit in a poison
control center that long,
you just poison center.
These calls are washing over you.
They're just coming and
coming and coming and center.
You start to feel just kind of overwhelmed
by the fact that every single time
the phone rings,
there's somebody on the other side of
the line and they're in a moment of
uncertainty or panic. When did she
take the Tylenol overdose crisis?
This could be pretty
serious and the scale of that
is just kind of shocking.
We manage 80,000 calls a year out of
this room and that's just this one center
that's just Chicago. If you take the
poison centers all across the country,
they handle almost 3 million cases a year,
so you get a call like mine or much
worse about every 14 seconds or so.
You know,
this is a very poisonous planet and
thinking about just how many of us are
bumping into these things that
we think might be poisoning us,
snuck mercury that are poisoning us.
Gold is poisonous to some extent.
Silver, not so poisonous,
but it'll turn you blue.
I decided to call up Debra [inaudible],
director of the Knight Science Journalism
Program at MIT and poison enthusiast.
I love poison. It's true. I even wrote
a book called the Poisoner's Handbook.
You're my husband worries
about that a lot. In fact,
he has not let me pour him a cup of coffee
for the last six years since my book
came out. Very serious. He really
was. Seriously, he's always like, oh,
I'll get it.
So never says it helps to kind of think
of poison control as part of this much
larger back and forth kind of a dance
and evolving dance that we've been doing
with our poisonous planet
for thousands of years.
We've been dancing with them in
different ways for a very long time.
If you go back and look at
the hieroglyphics in Egypt,
there's actually references to death
by peach and that refers to cyanide
poisoning because cyanides are the primary
poison than the pits of peaches and
flying peaches actually written in a
wall of a temple somewhere or that's
exactly right. Endeavor says, if you
go back to the beginning of that dance,
you'll find that like with so many things,
it starts with murder because we humans
first got really interested in poisons
when we realized we could
use them to kill each other,
and one of my favorite
examples is actually our snack,
which in early 19th century
Europe was by all accounts,
the perfect comma to Seidel poison.
It was tasteless. It was odorless.
You could put it into vanilla pudding or
oatmeal mimic the natural illness. Gee,
Connell looked like they
had a bad gastroenteritis.
And at the time we had
no way of detecting it.
Literally when we come
into the 19th century,
science has not figured out a way to
detect a single poison in a corpse.
We'll so what ruined this
perfect murder? Well,
there was a chemist in Breton named James
Marsh who worked out this incredibly,
it's, I mean by just standards
today, primitive test,
which involved mincing up the tissue
from the dead person and adding some acid
and heating it up and distilling it.
And then as this vapor comes out,
it cool onto glass.
And if there was any arsenic
in the original tissue,
that arsenic forms tiny dark crystals
and you've got a sort of blackish silver
mirror forming over the glass.
And that was actually
the first great test in,
uh, forensic toxicology, the marsh test.
This is sort of the moment Deborah says
that modern science joins our dance with
poison because as you see the rise of
industrial chemistry and and our ability
to synthesize cyanide and strychnine and
some of these amazingly toxic elements,
you also see people's realization
of how useful they are.
Man, people are so cool around
here. Where are we in Soho?
We're in West Soho, West Soho.
What started happening was at the
beginning of the 20th century,
there were all these new cleaning products
hitting the market designed to kill
germs and pharmaceutical products
designed to kill headaches or whatever,
and suddenly all these poisons that
used to just be out there in nature.
We're in our homes or in
the drugstore for example.
You see it's fun sunglasses
there. Here are producers,
any mcewen and McKelvy
ticking a jaunt. Okay,
here we are in Hudson pharmacy
on our time on Tuesday afternoon.
This is during working hours and
they only got the weird devito.
Flavors come in to the local
drug store cleaning aisle. Wow.
So draino bottom of the
shelf, easy for kids to reach.
Now let's read the ingredients
contain sodium hypochlorite,
sodium hydroxide, and sodium silicate.
Okay, let me see. One second.
Quick check. Online sodium
hydroxide. According to Wikipedia,
it's used to digest tissues. Say
there's like roadkill in a landfill.
They hope put the roadkill in a sealed
container with sodium hydroxide and
water. It's like breaking bad. Yeah,
and the body turns into a liquid with
coffee, like appearance. Apparently.
It's like turns people into coffee.
Yeah, little higher on the shelf.
Everybody's favorite childhood
cartoon, Mr. Clean Meadows and rains.
Then same thing. Sodium hydroxide coffee.
People don't open it. Don't open it.
It's not as if, okay,
I have to buy it. No,
look as I, what's this thing? This will
amounts. There's Windex, Windex, oh,
this one is just called ammonia.
If you mix ammonia and bleach,
what happens?
A poisonous gas results also occurs
naturally in the atmosphere of Jupiter and
Saturn. That's impressive. Next one,
this little gray bottle
up on the highest shelf.
Goodall's brush and Kapa Polish,
a brass and copper Polish and
contains to detoxy ethanol.
It has a sweet ether like
odor and I'm going to, Oh,
you just open it and smell it.
Oh, it said harmful, if any. Okay.
Well it says it can cause
adrenal tumors in animals.
It's carcinogenic and rodents.
I hope I didn't smell too much of
it. Matt. Let's just get out of here.
You don't want to get
some chips. All right.
We're very comfortable with the fact that
we walked down the grocery store aisle
or open up the medicine chest and
we're surrounded by these, you
know, in pill form or liquid
form or spray form or whatever,
but these different compounds
that actually are dangerous.
We're used to that.
We live with that. Right?
Snakes, which brings us to a guy.
Let's see. Oh, and I use a
plaque for Lewis. Good. Actually,
I saw this plaque dedicated to him on
the wall at the poison center in Chicago,
appreciation of the initiative and
devoted service of Louis Godalming RPH,
founder of the poison and drug
information center. Anyway,
a guy named Louis [inaudible],
Louis Scotoma and who is a brilliant
scientists in the state of Illinois.
Louis passed away back in 1995
but his wife Catherine, yes,
it's still very much alive.
Absolutely. She's 98 now,
but she met Louis back when she was a
20 year old nurse working in the Saint
Luke's hospital in Chicago.
It was 1948 and he was a pharmacist in
the hospital and everybody knew Lou and
we all loved him. And I was
the lucky one. I caught him.
Louis was sort of a shorter man,
dark hair, big dark eyebrows,
and he had a great personality and he
would take care of everything that came
along friendly. But when it came to
his work, he took it very seriously.
The pharmacy was directly across
the hall from the Emergency Room.
And so what started happening is, and
noticed this trend, like just to back up,
this is the 1940s and doctors are totally
winning against infectious diseases.
And what that meant was that as
far as the public was concerned,
keeping your family healthy
in germ free is a big deal.
And that meant keeping your home
clean, super leaving Cli duper no.
Why clean it, really look clean
that day. And at the same time,
oh, that guy,
there's just this explosion of new
cleaning products coming into the market.
Babbo glean your thing brighter than
any other cleanser in the world.
Johnson's jubilee, new blue
cheer. Great for as well as long.
So our kitchen cabinets and cupboards
under the bathroom sink meeting,
oxycodone was getting like filled
up with all of these things.
Extremely smelly powders and liquids,
brightly colored bottles and boxes. Oh,
leaving cute Mr clean is now the most
powerful I've ever put into a box.
Ooh, good.
And getting back to Lewis,
what he began to notice was that more
and more these doctors were coming across
the hall to his pharmacy, like first one
and then more and more. And you know,
they're saying like, Hey, we've
got this kid over in the Er.
He just got into this new cleaning
stuff and we have no idea what's in it.
Can you help us? So, uh,
the interns and residents in the emergency
room would naturally come across the
hall to see Lou and Lou helped them
find out what the child had taken.
For example, if the child
had swallowed Ajax Guy,
that meant he had actually eaten sodium
carbonate and sodium decile benzene
sulfonate, which could mean
nausea, diarrhea or vomiting.
And Lou used to keep cards
on every patient that it saw.
So with each new product that was
brought into the emergency room,
Lou would write up a new card, white
sail, bleach, sodium hypochlorite,
just pain, vomiting, safety.
Glueck decided this was a a thing that
was very needed because by the 1950s
there are over 250,000 different
trade names, substances on the market.
And so doctors, they just couldn't
keep up and so lose stack of cards.
It grew taller and taller and
taller and pretty soon word got out.
Dogs across the country would hear that
there's this guy in Chicago who gives
out help on poisoning cases and so many
calls are coming in at all hours of the
day and night eventually get dom and
just started telling the switchboard
operators they could go ahead and
transfer the call to his home.
We, you get calls from all the different
little law in emergency rooms in the
hospitals. In the state. And what was,
what was it like once you're doing this,
then it seems to me that you don't really
have normal hours because emergencies
will take place whenever they
take place. So yes. How did,
what was he going to be on
call 24 hours a day? Yes.
Really? Yes. Yes he was.
We would get calls in
the middle of the night
or even during dinner time.
So what happens if you know he's in the
tub and you're cooking dinner and the
phone rings? I would take
the phone to him and the time
and uh,
that's the way it started.
And eventually lose little operation
became the first poison control center in
the United States in 1953 in Chicago.
One 802 two, two one,
two do do one 802, two,
two, one, two, two, two k up
your thing. Get Mad at poison.
And the first thing you should do, who
is calling? One 802 two, two one, two,
two, two. Oh, Isen is the kind of
thing you'll not suppose to touch.
All prescriptions cleaned and
stuff for spider bites and such.
If you swallowed something bad.
Oh, thank you. Took two months.
Call the poison control center hotline.
We're the people you
can trust for posting.
Hi there. This is Kirsten
recording from Orlando, Florida.
Radiolab is supported in part by
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
this is Julia calling from
San Francisco, California.
Radiolab is supported by
gunpowder and skies, new film,
heartbeat beat loud starring Nick
Offerman and Kiersey Clemons,
heartbeat loud tells the story of a
father and daughter songwriting duo that
become an overnight success selected
as the closing night film at the 2018
Sundance film festival and
costarring Ted Danson, Sasha Lane,
Blake Tanner, and Toni Collette.
Heartbeat loud opens in select
cities starting June 8th
Radiolab is supported by swell
investing and impact investing platform.
What if you could invest in our while also
investing in your financial
future? Think about that.
Our resources are diminishing.
Our population is growing.
Companies solving today's biggest
challenges will beat tomorrow's leaders.
Swell helps you invest in high growth
companies working towards clean water,
renewable energy, and green technology.
It's a market opportunity
you can feel good about.
Get a $50 bonus when you
open your account at swell.
investing.com/radiolab
from WM YC studios comes the untold
story of one of the most aspirational and
delusional teams in sports history.
We knew that we could
meet anybody in the world.
I'm doing everything I should be doing
and it's still not working. Sucked in.
What are you guys complaining about?
You guys are the ones that fricking
caused this whole thing. American fiasco,
one team's insane journey to the 1998
World Cup posted by mate Roger Bennett of
men in Blazers available
wherever you get your podcasts.
A bad world cuff is better than
their workout. Do you bet your ass
do one Jad Robert Radiolab. So we are
back with your porter, Brenna Farrell,
who is continuing to um, to inquire
into things poisonous. Before the break,
we just, uh,
learned about Lewis Godolphin who started
the oldest poison control center in
the country back in 1953 in
Chicago. Yeah. And so today,
now we have 55 poison control centers
all across the country and it's one phone
number that anyone anywhere in the u
s can call whenever they need help.
What poison center are there
at certain times of day?
Like is there a rhythm
to the day? Generally
usual pattern.
It's busy in the morning and kids are
getting ready for school and the peasant
anyways for were people brushing
your teeth with muscle rub cream,
kids drinking a little
mouthwash, eating some sunscreen,
eating some old mayonnaise, double
doses in the morning. You know,
each parent will give the kid a ADHD
medication or then the mid afternoon kind
of tapers down a little bit til like
four or five is the slowest and then that
evening,
the busiest time of the day overall and
it's like between 6:00 PM and 10:00 PM
people coming home from work trying to
get dinner superglue instead of eyedrops
superglue instead of lip gloss.
People take the the dodger cast medicine
by mistake instead of their normal
medication. Yeah, that's
a frequent scenario.
It gets to be with
adults. I have literally,
I have a list here of all the things
that have been used instead of blue.
It's just busy. It's, you know,
just a hectic schedule that
we're living in right
now and good almonds,
old stack of cards that's become this
huge database that's tracking like in real
time these things that are cropping up.
Salmonella that may have
made 22 people sick already,
whether it's a salmonella outbreak or
like last 11 deaths appear to be connected
to heroin being sold in western New
York that's laced with fentanyl.
Oh, weird drug reaction
that people are having.
Or maybe it's a new product
that's unexpectedly dangerous
or laundry detergent
pods that look like candy.
Now they are being linked to
a tragic death of a child.
They can see that in real time and let
health officials or whoever else know
about it. Wow. Which is pretty
cool. But I mean, honestly,
just selfishly thinking about
myself as, as a mom, um,
coming out of the trip to poison control,
I remember writing down this
feeling of like, you know,
like what if I just approached all
the scary decisions in my life?
The way that poisoned
control did. Like what?
Like kind of thinking like what would
poison control do? Like it just,
it felt like such a relief to be
experiencing fetal Barbara Toss,
64.8 milligram tablet. And
how much does she weigh?
Like this super rational place.
Like it was just completely
rational and when did it happen?
How long ago we have this data, we're
going to, what's the name of the product?
Take these questions from you.
Nine 25 let me see if this is even going
to be a problem and then we're going to
tell you this is what we think is
going to happen. Okay. Stomach pain.
Now she's awake and they'll let you
make a decision or they'll tell you like
straight up, don't worry about it.
I think she's going to be a, okay,
I from here. I know. And then take
it again, but you will be okay. Okay.
It just felt like it's stripped
away. A lot of the, um,
like the guilt and the
anxiety and the like,
should I do this and politics and all
those other things that have often swirl
around even seemingly to me innocuous
questions about how do I keep this person,
this little person's safe and healthy.
There's all this stuff swirling
around it and they just,
we didn't have to get into any of that.
I still remains.
For me the most interesting part of this
is that the idea that we're supposed to
know things like, you know, I
talk about this with my dad.
I mean there was this
time in medicine when, um,
it was all about the doctor in the white
coat. It was this paternalistic thing.
Doctor knows best and no
one wants to go back there,
but that there was something
emotionally clean about that.
Whereas now we, we have all the
information, it's right there.
This is hand in hand with
the rise of the Internet.
And so increasingly we're
expected to be our own experts.
And it's usually presented as this sort
of simple idea that information is power
and it isn't power. I mean it is,
but it's also paralysis. Yeah.
I actually had a rule where I wouldn't,
I would only let nick look things
up cause I couldn't, like I was not,
it started when I was pregnant.
I like would have a panic attack cause
there were so many different things and
like always the top searches are the
ones that like you're going to die.
Um Oh yeah. And he's really, he like
you get into the comments field,
oh forget it. Oh God. Right.
I mean there's something about when you
look at an answer on a screen and you
just one click away from anything,
the exact opposite answer.
And then when you're on the phone with
someone it's just you and that person.
Like there is no other distraction.
Like there's something built into
the technology that creates exactly
the kind of connection
you need at that moment.
You know, people, when they call you,
it's an emergency there that are
panicking and I think half the battle is
getting them to settle down. And
so this is Tony Berta, the know
everything guy we mentioned earlier.
I started in February a of 81
he's been that calm voice for 30 years
and while he was in pharmacy school,
he had an accident. Yeah,
I actually started pharmacy school as
a sighted person when I finished as a
blind individual. What, what happened?
I he, he didn't want to say, oh,
I don't dwell on it,
but like I was sitting there seeing him
doing all of this math and spitting out
these numbers. Yes sir.
They're sights and half lives
and volumes of distribution,
which is totally incomprehensible to me.
But he told me that he also like pretty
quickly had discovered early on that
there was this whole other
part of doing this job
since September of 82 let's see,
I would have probably had like a year
and a half of experience at that time.
I remember I was sitting in the poison
center was another pharmacist and we had
the news radio or am station on,
it was about 10 30 in the morning.
It was news to his flash.
[inaudible]
bizarre and terrifying story today in
the Chicago suburbs in Arlington heights
and elk Grove village,
a 12 year old girl and two men who were
brothers are dead ever taking poison
capsules of extra strength. Tylenol.
Several people died from Sinai
that they believe was from Tylenol,
five deaths in Chicago, and that
number might be changed to six.
Six deaths have now been
linked to the capsules,
which are leased with cyanide and link.
It was this terrifying moment where
thousands of people just simultaneously,
we're all thinking, oh my God,
this thing I brought into my
home to make me feel better.
It could kill me today across the country,
Tylenol products were
being pulled from Michelle.
The police are like driving their car
slowly on the street with loudspeakers.
Like
I think anytime
the back your Tylenol,
don't take any Tylenol extra strength
for the time being until you hear
otherwise. And so, you know, Tony told me,
he's sitting there hearing these news
broadcasts going across the radio and he
just turned to the guy sitting next
to him and the poison girl, senators,
holy s, we're gonna,
we're gonna get killed.
Yeah.
[inaudible] your phone has been ringing
off the hook at rush Presbyterian St
Luke's medical center in Chicago. He
says he's boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
So as soon as you hung up the
phone, the phone rang again.
All we've been receiving calls are
about once every 15 seconds this other
pharmacist at.
And I just grabbed the references and
try and make ourselves cyanide experts,
you know, real fast
morning.
And the interesting thing about this
case is that in every single one of these
calls that was coming in, if someone
was terrified, someone was panicked,
but they weren't actually in any danger.
Officials, hearsay, right? If anyone has
taken a cyanide laced Tylenol capsule,
we wouldn't be able to make it to
the phone call. So in some way,
this moment you think about it,
it really kind of highlights this thing
that is really at the heart of poison
control. The specialists not
only were calm, but they, they,
their job was to just reassure like they
were letting people know it was going
to be okay. But if you flash forward
to now that's changing. It's,
they're getting more calls
that are more serious.
They're getting calls from hospitals,
they're getting calls from people
who have taken multiple drugs.
And so does that mean that they're
getting less calls from like normal people
and parents that kind of, yeah,
those calls are going down and they
calls over all sense. Like the,
in the past decade there've been fewer
calls to poison control. Do you know why?
My sense is we don't like to make
phone calls anymore. Like people don't,
they're, you know,
like the Internet is there and that's
what we're used to and that's easy.
And so they are, they just launched
this new, like instead of calling,
you can go to the website and plug in
answers to the questions that they roll
through and it will give you the same
answer based on hopefully the same
knowledge. But then as a person who's
lived through it and like, oh my God,
please don't take away that phone call.
Because when you're in that panic,
the thought of having to sit and type
an answer out while you're holding your
kid and like wondering if
you've really screwed up.
It's like you're taking away something
really valuable that maybe we're not
valuing here. I did have this
one event when my older son,
I've got two sons. It's was very little.
We were living in Sacramento. Yeah.
By the way, his author
Deborah Bloom again and uh,
they didn't have fluoridated waters
so our doc gave them these tiny,
cute, they were really cute
fruit flavored fluoride pills,
the kind of thing you
could get a toddler to tay.
I don't know what we were doing,
but somehow we had given him his daily
fluoride pill and then like idiots left
it on the kitchen counter and he grabbed
it and pretty much inhaled the whole
bottle and I was really free.
I just didn't know how
poisonous that was going to be.
And I call poison control
and I did I, I was like,
am I suppose what I wanted to know
was whether I should panic, right.
I mean he seemed fine.
It wasn't like he was getting sick in
any way and they were completely non
freaked out about it. There's like, yeah,
I remember that experience.
Do you remember here?
Did you hear their words or did you
hear their tone? It was the tone.
They were so calm and they
could tell I was frayed and,
and it can just tell you I'm standing
in the kitchen. We had this phone,
my son's by me, I, you know,
he can tell I'm afraid,
but he doesn't really know I'm free.
And I sat on the floor
after I talked to them,
I just sat down on the floor with him
because I was just so grateful and I was,
and that's what I remember
is how grateful I felt.
Hello? I'm my, my two and
a half year old daughter.
Just the eight most of
the tube of a eight,
five ounce I'm saying is correct.
You're not feeling for some control.
[inaudible]. I gave my gun 12 and a
half milliliters of children's Motrin.
And what did you wait
five years? About 25 to 30
Oh 0.2 43% zero point queer
[inaudible] water from it.
[inaudible] this was a brand new
[inaudible] Gotcha. Problem here. No,
amp e. R r. O. Yeah. Sort of
[inaudible] to the other hero.
He didn't say anything
[inaudible] no, it's true.
You know I have four to five dot.
Ly or five percentage for it might
be percent. I'm not sure I what?
Five dot. Y 0.4 maybe?
Maybe. Yes. Five point.
Yeah. I'll tell you I bought
board. I thought a problem. No,
I'll go give her no me to drink and
she'll be fine. Okay. Yeah, definitely.
Nona, even close to the basketball. Toxic
dog. No, that happened all the time.
Yeah, she should be fine. Yeah. All right.
Well thank you so much for your help.
I'd watch him, you know,
he'll be fine. Wow. Let
[inaudible] you just put it at ease
and I appreciate you during much. Oh
well an 802 two two one two do to Ron,
802 two two one two D to
Get Bang, get mad at boy.
Why isn't is the kind of thing
you'll not suppose to touch
ida bites and sell eyes and if you
swallowed something bad or thank you to
(800) 222-1222
calls to poison control are
confidential by the way. Oh,
we got permission from the callers you
heard to use the audio if you should ever
need to call poison control.
The number is (800) 222-1222 and if
you text the word poison two seven nine
seven nine seven nine it'll
save the number in your phone.
Debra Balaam's latest book,
the poison squad is going to come out
this fall and you can find out more on our
website. Thank you also to nit kappa DJ
Wendy Blair, Stefan Marian Moser Jones,
Andrew Perella with Pennington
Richard Dart and Natalie Wheaton.
This episode was reported by Brenna
Farrell and produced by Annie Mcewen with
help from Jake Arlo. I'm Jad Abumrad. I
remember Krulwich. Thanks for listening.