Okay.
All right, great. You're
listening to radio,
the podcast from New York
public radio and public radio.
W. Y. C
n n p. R. Hello Chad here
every, this is radio lab,
the podcast coming to you now with, uh,
not one of our big hour long situations,
but rather one of those in-betweens
that we do, uh, between seasons.
Our next season is about two months off
and one of the programs that we're going
to be presenting is about people who fall
in love with science and then fall out
of love with science.
And in that spirit we thought we'd
play a conversation for you now,
which is more on the falling in love
side. Robert Krulwich, my esteemed cohost,
who you are here in just a moment,
recently interviewed maybe one
of the greatest scientists alive,
really e o Wilson. He is a
biologist. He's an entomologist,
meaning he studies bugs. He's an
author, a world famous conservationist.
He recently started the,
um, encyclopedia of life,
which tries to make a list of
every single species on the planet.
Pea discovered so many things
about how animals communicate,
which you'll hear in a moment,
particularly ants. And, uh,
if you heard our emergence show,
you will recognize a bit, uh,
from that show that repeats
in this conversation.
But it's really cool to hear the whole
conversation that too many edits,
which is where I'm going
to play for you now.
So here it is.
Here's Robert Chromebooks speaking with
e o Wilson at the 92nd Street y here in
Manhattan. I see. I prefer to, for
starters, I'm just curious. Um,
what did you know,
do you remember the moment when
you said the word scientist? Comma,
I want to be one, not shy, I
guess anthem biologist. You know,
I just wanted to work on that
entomologist blog. Oh yes.
When I was about eight or nine,
I discovered that there were people
who actually made their living, uh,
chasing bugs. Uh, and, uh, you know, I,
I every kid has a bug period. I've just
set now, I'll never to grow out of mine.
Your right of what you said. And
I, uh, down in Alabama we had, uh,
people who are driving around in green
trucks for the Department of Agriculture
and Sullivan were
exterminating intersects and I,
they were made their living by finding
and studying bugs. I said, well,
that's what I want to do. Nevermind
being a fireman or anything like that.
I don't want to do that. Kill
by. I was, yeah, I was, uh, uh,
I was frozen in that, uh, in that
ambition at the age of seven,
five, eight or nine or nine when I really
shuttled down four with [inaudible].
Okay. Now did, did,
did science sees you or did science
rescue you cause you were you,
how many schools did you go to before
you were the, of 14 or whenever it was?
Ah, yeah, it was about, uh,
13 or 14 schools and 11
grade. I skipped one grade.
Well that made me always
the runt of the class,
which didn't help see what the run
social skills and new kid every,
a new kid in the neighborhood.
Yeah. So that means what now?
Do you have a choice here? You could
be the class clown or something,
or you could go off into the forest and
make friends with a worm or something
like that. Well, yeah, I guess
that's the way of looking at it. Uh,
I turned into, um, nature
in the woods and so on.
And then I discovered that this extra
intricity made me a socially acceptable in
an odd way.
So I had the nickname bugs when I
was in my grammar school hanging,
but then I had a snake period
as snake period. And, uh,
this was in southern Alabama,
I guess I was about 15 or 16 by that
time and there were about 40 species of
snake sound down there. And then
a period of time, about a year,
I managed to find them all. I kept a
lot of them in the back yard alive.
And so I was now known
as Snake Wilson. Uh,
it wasn't because in this
intense football culture,
I went out for football at this point, uh,
at the Bruton high school in
Alabama and I weighed 112 pounds.
I was second light as kid there
probably couple of snakes. Have you
[inaudible] story. I A I,
you're a tough competitor anyway. I,
uh, so, uh, it turns out your three,
there was, uh,
there were 23 people on the squad
and I was entire third string.
But anyway, I got respect
in part because, uh,
I was doing all these
strange things and, and uh,
Alabamians are really, uh,
they're really very tolerant
of eccentricity. They
kinda like it, you know,
the old odd, the aunt that lives up in
the attic and you know, that Kinda thing.
I got along very well, uh,
both as a naturalist, you know,
fanatical collector and naturalist at the
[inaudible] then in high school to any
rate. Um, so I, at the age of 16,
I decided that the time had come to
get serious about professional with the
biology. And so, uh,
I decided to select the group of
insects to study and I said flies.
They have marvelous, tremendous diversity.
And so I would start collecting flies.
I wanted to become the
world expert on slides,
but the year was 1945. And
in order to study flies,
as many of you understand,
you have to have insect pins,
special pins to put through the
body of the specimens. It'll still,
insect pins are were available at that
time only from checklists of Akio and the
supply had been cut off in the United
States in check. Pins were unavailable.
So I said, what's my favorite
group of insects? You know,
I don't have to stick pins
through and that the ants,
so I got started my collection by going
down to the drugstore and collecting
these little pill bottles
and that was rubbing alcohol,
which is ICO protocol. Alcohol got
massed in my collection started.
I built a large collection of events
that I took with me to the University of
Alabama.
Could you say that launched,
but for the permit that for lack of
pins and for the availability of rubbing
alcohol,
therefore ants or wears aunts always
going to be it and you would've gotten to
it by whatever route or,
well, I think I eventually
would've ended up with anch,
but I would've been retarded there.
I don't think I would've been able to
do serious research until maybe I was
Jean. Um,
now let's get onto the joy of, of this
may not be obvious to other people.
The joy of an studies cause
you know if you think about it,
they do seem like somewhat indifferent
to anyone that was observing them and so
on and that you might not wonder exactly
why somebody would get delight out of
looking at ants. But I want to
take you back to one moment,
which I think is one of my favorites ever.
The question is how do these little
ants communicate with one another?
The year is 1953 and you're
considering the problem.
We know that at least for us,
most of our communication goes because
of things we hear or things we see.
This does not seem to
be the habit of ants.
So you have some fire ants and the
question is you noticed that they,
that a scout will go find a piece of
food and somehow tell the other mans,
look what I found. Come
here and get the food.
How do you figure out how the scout
aunt tells the other aunts were that a,
there is food and where
it is. We had the idea,
even back then people did biologists
that the ads were somehow laying a trail
down and then they were telling the
other ants go out and follow that trail.
But nobody knew where the trail came from.
And I didn't know really how it worked
and I didn't know how ants communicated
otherwise. And you're perfectly right.
Human beings are really
unusual along with birds. They,
we are audio visual and, and uh,
and that puts us in a tiny minority
of all of the creatures on earth,
which are primarily chemical
in their communication.
It wasn't understood or
appreciated at that time.
Pheromones in many of you who've
heard the word pheromones,
pheromones are the key to understand the
communication of the vast majority of
the animals species. We didn't
know it then. And uh, so, uh,
one day I set out,
I was culturing fire ranch than in
the laboratory at Harvard and I said,
I'm going to get to the bottom of this.
And the way I did it was
to, uh, dissect these tiny,
tiny, it's very difficult to do,
but I just selected them and we just say
[inaudible] so you're watching the aunt
going along and it's laying on its
abdomen or some part of its body is mainly
off the ground. That's right.
I can see the ant running along and
under magnification I can see that it's
sticking out sting and dragging the thing.
Something's coming out of that sting,
like kind of like a fountain pen or
something through little bit like that.
Yeah. And uh, so, uh, I proceed to, um,
believe me folks, this is
the way science goes. I mean,
it really is simple minded.
It's only later when you're doing
the technical paper, you know,
and you're producing the mathematical
models and you're describing the micro
analysis and so on that it
looks tough. It's really,
this is the way of thinking when
you're doing something. So I said,
I'm going to find out what the organs are
inside this hat and I'm going to track
down where that stuff is coming from.
So what I did was to do and that to me,
and then, uh, you know, just detected,
I knew approximately what the different
glands were and so on, when you snip,
you snipped off the part where
the glands, where you see there,
well you just detect open or you
opened it, you know, and, and uh,
and just the way you would in the animal
or it's exceedingly difficult when it's
about the size of a great assault.
That's the tough part. But anyway,
aren't your hands going [inaudible]
well, yes, your hands is vibrating.
And in fact, it was down at the limit.
I didn't go to a micro manipulator,
you know, which is when you're doing
it with me and controlled. And, uh,
I did it raw manually, but
it was right at the limit.
So the way I did it was I got
these very fine needles in, uh,
and because there was this
inevitable vibration in your hand,
you can see it when you put it in
a microscope. Everybody has it.
It's a little vibration, but
the highly magnified it. Uh,
it allowed me to use a needle like
a Jack Hammer. I could jack it.
I could do it if I did it just right.
You know, and just open up the anthem.
Anyway, I took out the various
organs, one after the other,
and I made a preparation and I made an
artificial trail and we waited a second.
Make strains, follow this. You know,
I've got like six organs and you've got
the smooshed each one of the six organs
and then you're going to take, let
me just see if I remember this.
You're going to take a a sharpened
Birchwood applicator stick.
Yes. And then I smeared out
one organ after another.
No effect. Well, where are there
ants? Are there answers? Yes.
You have brought in. Why? I'm leading,
I'm leading my artificial trails from
the colony that I have in the lab,
so they're ants over here.
You got your birch stick here and
you're drawing lines of gut stuff,
I guess basically what it is.
Yeah, just an or different organs.
I've watched each one in
turn and then smeared it out.
And finally I came to a
little finger shaped organ,
which we didn't know the function of
his at the tiny little thing talk down
there and I mirrored that out
and incredible. It wasn't,
I didn't have to tell them to follow
that trail. They exploded out of them.
This running along that thing. And does
that mean like if you'd taken the stick,
could you go, did you, did you,
did you do it when all the wheels
would go droop, do, do, do, do, do, do.
Well I what I actually have, I
started playing around with this.
It was so effective for demonstrations.
I would write my name and a column of
102 hundred three a hundred ants would
come pouring out back and forth and
they'd actually write my name and I am so,
well that was the beginning. I, you know,
just to show that there is
some seriousness to this.
That was the beginning and we
were able to defended aunt lovers.
We were in the roof.
Alright,
now I want to finish this little section
because this is my favorite story of
all. When you get bad, you get bad.
This is once you begin to figure out
how these chemicals and the fear and the
smells that they give off the
com communicating devices,
you discover that when an aunt dies,
this doesn't happen to be exactly
in a category. One man dies,
aunts not being the
smartest creatures around.
It just sorta dies and it just sits
there and for the first day or two,
all the other ants just don't
even notice it. And then,
and when the deans to decompose,
it begins to give off a smell and then
the first time it gives off a smell.
I guess the next ant
that passes by goes whoa.
And says we have a dead aunt here.
And he takes the hand and puts it
in the dead place, I guess the aunt.
Yeah, dead place. Yeah.
I'll tell you about the experiment
because I had a lot of fun with it,
but first,
but let me show you that
my chemist colleagues and I
quickly worked out that the
chemical code of the ants, we found
somewhere, or a good part of it,
we found that the answer communicating
somewhere between 10 and with tens of 20
chemical signals,
they have glands all over their bodies
as at the functions which were unknown.
And many of these glands produce
pheromones, you know, some for two alarms,
some the recruit, some to
identify themselves as a
member of a cast and so on.
And one of them says, I am dead.
I am, I'm coming to that.
Uh, well how does an ant,
when it dies, how is it
identified as you say, you know,
the others know when an aunt dies
then for a while it just lives there.
You know, if we fall, wish all one of
us just lying on the ground like this,
we'd probably do something. Maybe
not do it in New York, but I mean
usually we do something because you
know, we're audio, we're audio visual.
But in the case of the ads in New
York, most aunt likes city in America.
Anyway, go ahead Eddie. Right. The um,
so the aunt against the decompose,
and I was really going crazy with
this. We were still successful. I mean,
we were making one discovery after
another. It was wonderful. And uh,
I was going crazy with the show. I said,
how does an an identify a corpse?
It's got to be in this,
the substances that are being produced
by decomposition, it's gotta be,
and in those days we had just
hit upon animal behaviors,
generally had just hit upon
the idea assigned stimuli
that animals don't grasp a
whole lot of stimuli
the way we do, you know,
an assess the gestalt in a variety of
signals when they usually work out of one
substance or a very small number of
substances or a site, and then that,
that releases their a complex
behavior. So I was going to find that.
What's the corpse substance?
It turns out, well,
this is how science works across.
It turned out that for some
reason I never found out.
The chemist had already identified a large
number of decomposition substances in
rotting insects. And so
with that as my guide,
I gathered in pure form on my laboratory
shelf, a whole variety of them.
Uh, and uh,
the place for a while filled
like a combination between a, uh,
an outhouse and a choroidal house. Cause
there were, you send me the smells,
you'd have rotten spit smell
that know rancid body smell.
Yeah. That's uh, that's uh, the uh, uh,
fatty acids that you have in volume.
When we were walking up the
corridor at your, in your building,
what did they like stay? I
never tried to explain to them.
Uh, but there was, it was, it was a,
a very strange smelling place. Uh,
you know, skate coal with, uh,
one of the comments. That's,
that's the essence of
theses. Yes. Well, any rate.
I then started with my, you
know, a typical experiment.
I started dobbing dummy aunts with tiny,
tiny amounts of these different substances
and observing and nothing happened
until finally I came to one of the
substances oleic acid who leak acid is a
fatty acid of a particular
kind. Bingo. The, uh,
then picked it up and
the dummy with nothing,
but the only signal they had was a leak
acid and a took it and dropped that
dummy on the refuse pounds. And so
I had it and essentially had it.
Now here's where you get bad. Ah, yeah,
that's a trait. Okay, well, you know,
you get to play around at this point.
So I said what would happen if I
put a Lia, cast it on a live amp?
What happens is that
nothing, this aunt says,
if they said anything, you
know, nothing. The ad does, uh,
does any good because now it is a
course and the other ants pick this live
kicking ant and I'll, it goes and
it's dropped on the refuse path.
So it's a weekly,
obviously alive and perfectly healthy and
the other aunts thinking, you're dead,
you're dead, you're dead all the
way to the great bye. Goodbye.
What happened then was that the ant would,
uh, proceed to clean itself, answer,
always cleaning themselves and finally,
but if it didn't clean itself
enough when it got back,
picked it up and brought out til finally
as clean enough and then it can reenter
the realm of the living of I you have
one sometimes describe the process of
science as you do it as,
as a form of story telling.
[inaudible] what did
you mean by that? Well,
I mean I think it's everyone
here understands that, um,
human beings are the
storytelling species. We,
the way we think is a
narrative. You know, we built,
we build scenarios forward hole and
we, when we're making a decision,
we're running one scenario.
After another forward,
we're telling a story to our
shows. I'm going to do this,
that will then that will follow and
joins. What? We'll probably do this and,
and I will lose that, or, oh,
gain this or I will finish that.
And they tell stories of real
past what happened to me.
And then of course, this allows
them to make fictional stories.
Uh, the scientist tell stories and
he hopes it will be true stories.
He's thinking, oh, there's
this, there's that, uh,
this creature is doing this.
That creature must be detecting
this or have a bald instruction way.
And then they make you make a series of
story and these are called hypotheses.
And the fancy term then for doing
science by storytelling is a,
the method of multiple competing
hypotheses. And then you figure,
you do the experiments to
find out which of the two,
which of the stories is true
[inaudible]
that was a conversation between
e e o Wilson and Robert Krulwich,
my cohost, and let us know
what you thought. Radio
lab@wnyc.org is our email address.
Want to thank the 92nd street y
for making that available to us.
Also want to thank as always
the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
the corporation for public broadcasting
and the National Science Foundation for
making all of this possible.
[inaudible]
I'm Jad Abumrad thanks for listening
to this, a podcast from Radiolab.
Hope you enjoyed it.
See in a couple of weeks
[inaudible].