Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert
Krulwich. This is Radiolab and today.
Do you want to say that today's a speed z?
This is the perfect example of
what we've been bumping into.
All our humans are slow.
We're just too slow,
but now you have to know
this Lena. It is all right.
Now we have a story that should
make us all feel a little better.
Can I just say,
I didn't even think this was remotely
possible but we're about to talk about the
heroine of our story.
Is Lena Vestigo or how is that a
hyphenate vista go is my middle name.
How is the last name and
my first name is lead.
Selena is a physicist at Harvard and she
has done something with speed that is
just remarkable. It's
the only way to say it.
If we sort of stepped back once we asked
her to walk us through what she does
step by step because
it's totally worth it.
We start out with a clump
of room temperature sodium
and at room temperature.
Sodium is actually a nice shiny metal.
Lina and her team, they take the sodium,
they put it oven and heat it
up. Exactly. And as it heats up,
Adam's in the sodium start to
vibrate faster and then faster, uh,
when the temperature gets to
around 350 degrees centigrade,
the Adams form of vapor,
super high pressure.
And then she forces the Adams to this
little pinhole have a little hole in the
source.
So this thin stream of Adams now comes
out of a hole and we hit them head on
with a laser beam. So you bang
them right in their pathway? Yes.
Kick them in a direction opposite to
their emotion and that slows them down.
Excited.
And now we can load them into what we
call an optical molasses optical molester.
This is so baroque. I love it. In
the obstacle. Molasses, the ams,
will you be hit by laser
beams from all directions?
Is that your way of like saying
don't go this way, don't go this way.
Don't go this way. Straight. Yes. You
corner them in from all angles. Yes.
Then we can get them to
where really slow down.
It feels a little bit like you've
enslaved these Adams. I feel bad for them.
It's going to get worse. Yes.
Because that's not good enough.
Now that she has these alums trapped,
she needs to make them
sit as still as possible.
So she turns off the laser's
told darkness in the lab
and then we turn on an electromagnet,
use the fact that he used the fact that
the Adam says small magnets to hold them
in a particular point in space
so they don't all fly apart.
Then we can flip the magnet of this
small Adams and selectively kick out the
hardest. Just the hardest of them.
So they will fly out of the
magnet and we just keep a,
the lowest energy by flipping them.
You can say to the, there's one Adam,
that's a little bit too jumpy.
You say, get out of here.
Get out of here cause you, cause you
want just quietest Adams to stay.
That's right. So now after all this,
Lina has this teeny little cloud.
Oh 0.1 millimeter in size. Typically
just a few million atoms, like five,
10 million. And she says at this
point, they're all very, very still
because temperature is really
just a measure of speed really.
You know when Adam's are moving
quickly, we call that hot.
When they're moving
slowly, we call that cold.
These Adam's because they're so still,
these atoms are really cold,
colder than anything on earth.
Colder than the middle of
empty space. Basically.
These are the coldest things
that have ever been cold. Yeah.
And at that point we have a
tone of new state of matter
[inaudible]
and of course she was curious about
this new state of matters. That's right.
I am a curious lady and now
we get to the part where, uh,
this is the whole reason
we're telling you this.
She now decides to poke this
Adams basically a center light,
Paulson shoot a beam of light into this
called Adam cloud and see how hard we
act. You know, we have a total in,
what was it like when, you know,
light fascinates me. I mean she says,
here's this thing that goes 671
million miles an hour, you know,
that nothing goes faster than light.
And the question just occurred to her
like what would happen if I took the
fastest thing in the universe and stuck
it into the coldest thing ever made.
Exactly. Yes. So she points or laser Epi,
adding the laser beam hits a
switch. So here you have this,
a light poles coming in,
zooming through space.
Then the front edge will reach our Adam
cloud and unbelievably the light bulbs
in that moment
from 186,000 miles per
second to 15 miles per hour.
Are you kidding? No. So
the light is going like
right?
That's right. Wow. In
Oh Adam cloud. Amazing.
So,
and then
it just chugs along at a leisurely speed.
Something that you could
beat on your bicycle
and ride your bike faster
than the light. Exactly.
You can sort of think of this race
between a bicycle and the light pearls.
I mean,
imagine you could just bike next to this
blob of light and you could reach out
and maybe pad it a little bit,
then bike on a head, but
then you'd be in darkness,
but you can go and go maybe to the edge
of the cloud and wait for the lights.
And it's all that when it comes through,
you could just catch it. Well, no,
you can't catch it because when the
light gets to the other side of the item,
Cloud d,
the front edge will accelerate back
up to this enormous normal lightspeed.
And then it rushes off. It stretches
out again. So here, can you,
oh, go ahead. I'm sorry. So, so if you've
got it down to 15, is that a kind of,
uh, uh, like a, uh, a limit? I
mean, can you, can we, we could,
we could bring it Lloyd.
It's, it's not a stoplight.
Can you actually stop light? We can, yeah.
So that laser goes in and doesn't come
out. Yes. I mean, you hold it like a,
like a, we hold it. How do you do
that? Huh. Okay. So what we do is a,
it's actually, uh, okay, so things get
a little technical here, but basically,
probably too simply,
Lena has figured out a way to tweak
the properties of this Adam cloud.
She can make it like a brick that like
bounces off of or she can make it clear.
So like cruises through, in this case,
what she does is she shoots
the light into the Adam cloud.
So we slow it down and then right at
that moment, because it's chugging along,
Chuck Chuck Chuck at 15 miles an hour,
she tweaks the Adam cloud to make it
well thick and the light parts will say,
oops. Uh, it'll come to a
heart almost like it's frozen,
ah,
in a block of ice in this. Oh,
so just sits. Yes, it just sits.
Wow. When you, when, when
you realize what you done,
did you do a little a Jig or what
did you do you have? Oh, yes,
there was amazing. There is like
sitting in the lab of course,
in the middle of the night
and just knowing, Whoa,
you're the first one who has been in
this part of nature. Yeah, it was joy.
No,
you know, of course, to
some extent I'm an engineer,
but this whole idea that I can take
this light poles and bring it down to a
human scale, that's
something you just, uh,
at a very personal level
gets excited about.
This is more like, you know,
I mean, you can sort of say a,
you know, like, like, like,
like, uh, a sculpturer will,
will create a beautiful sculpture
for me, as I was thinking about this,
actually, think of it in terms
of painting, like Vermeer,
you know, the painter,
like,
he could create this illusion that light
was just suspended there on the canvas.
Just shimmering. Yeah. You
Timo captured the light,
but that was just an illusion.
Lena actually did it.
Yes.
Woo.
Do you ever, do you ever wonder,
do you ever like, you know,
after this night you walk out in,
into the log and imagine next day in the
sun is shining and you just look at the
light and you think, Huh, Oh,
I've got your number. You're like,
Zeus. No. You could resist for a moment,
perhaps being Scandinavian, right. Where
we love the uh, light around midsummer.
Yeah. You have a whole lot of it or
then a whole lot. Yes. Yeah, yeah.
Maybe you could do something about that.
Maybe you can store it
for the winter time.
You could store it up and then you could
unleash the cloud and suddenly there'd
be sunshine. When there other men
there was darkness. So save it.
Save it for the winter time. Yes. Yeah.
We've been doing this
for a number of years.
One of the more remarkable
conversations. Thank you very much.
This is wonderful. But you didn't get
through a real important, oh wait, whoa,
whoa, whoa. What? So, um, we
can play a trick. The twig is,
we can stop and extinguish the light
parts in one part of space and we vive it
in a totally different location. You mean
you can transport hands port it. Yeah.
At this point we were like,
what weird ass science fiction movie
did we just slip into? Lena says,
when the light hit those atoms
back in her cloud, they're like,
pulse cloud will create a
little imprint in the atoms.
It's like if you were to punch soft clay
with your hand and then you could see
the imprint of your
knuckles there in the clay.
That's what happens when
the light hits those atoms.
The Light Poles will change the atoms
a little bit. That's how it imprints.
It's inflammation in the atoms and
according to Lena, that imprint,
it's like a physical impression of the
light. All the information about volite,
it's frequency, energy, whatever. All
that stuff is copied in the atoms.
So there's shadow of light. Does that
mean it's a shadow of light? Yes.
And now we can put poulet imprint out.
So now what we have out in free
space is a perfect Matta copy.
You mean like physical matter? Yes.
And then we can move that around.
We can put it on the shelf
four, we can move it around,
we can squish it and then we can
take it all. If she wants to,
she can then make a few
tweaks to the cloud.
Then the light pulse will come back to
life propagates slowly through the cloud
and then excellent. Speed back up. So
you could store, I mean if you were,
if you were President Obama and
you said, I would like to put it,
put the light around me right now in a
time capsule for later generations to
experience, he could take it using your
process, put it in an archive somewhere,
and then putting a bottle in
thousand years later they would,
they would know the light
that surrounded him. Yes. No,
that's what she said.
How would you know that different
light is the same? How do you know? Oh,
that's the same light.
It's a contained in my medical RP
that preserves the information.
So when the new light turns on,
it identically copies the light from
before in a way that that makes it as as
specific as saying, that's Mary
Kay Jones again. Yes, that's right.
Oh Man. I've also also also wonder
about, you know, because we could,
in our lab in Cambridge, we could send
a light person, stop it, extinguish it,
make our own little medical.
We put it in a bottle.
I could put it in a suitcase, say bring
it to Copenhagen, turn it into light.
But I've thought about also,
how do I get that bottle?
So security in the airport,
what would it look like?
Would it just be a bottle full of a
full of emptiness? It would be a vacuum,
but there'll be a little
clump of atoms in there.
We'll have to be less than three ounces
of Adam's or they would have so much
less than three. Yeah. You could
just walk through the airport.
You've got no problems. Yeah.
Oh, you can open it and be like,
you want to see some cool blind him and
then that would probably be also against
the law. Yes. How am I going to
get my light through security?