You are listening to
radio lab radio from W.
N y. S. C. H. N. P. R.
All right. K. Yup. I want to start
with a parental daydream for a second.
It's an idea that's been kicking around
for me since my kids were born. Okay.
Actually the idea itself is pretty
old. It goes back to the 18 hundreds,
right around Napoleon's time to a
fellow by the name of John Baptist,
Pierre Antwan, Monisha Bulgaria,
the Lamar Lamarck Jean-Baptiste Lamarck
who according to writer, same keen.
He was really, uh, one of the
first grand theorists in biology.
He actually coined the word biology
to really? Yup. His big idea,
as you might know,
is that what a person does in their
lifetime could be directly passed to their
kids very easily. His famous
example was giraffes. Lamarck said,
do you want to know how a giraffe
got his long neck one day?
This giraffe mother draft,
let's say he was looking up into tree
and saw some fruit and had to stretch her
neck and stretch again,
whole lifetime stretching.
And then when she had a baby stretching,
got into the baby and then that baby
would stretch and stretch and stretch and
him give a little more stretching to its
baby and eventually over the millennia,
what you'd get is a creature with a very
long neck because they're reaching for
the tops of trees. It makes a
kind of common sense really.
It does and it does make
kind of a folk sense.
He thought it worked with humans to his
example with humans was a blacksmith.
He thought that because they're
swinging hammers all day,
they got big bulky muscles and then
they would pass the muscles to their
children.
The sneaky idea here is that
the blacksmiths, the giraffes,
they made it happen. They
will the neck to get longer,
the muscles to get bigger,
and the key point is that it
wasn't something in born in them.
It was something they acquire
during their lifetime,
which they passed to their kids. Right,
and that's wrong. That's not how it works.
We're telling you now know that that's
not the case, but, but it'd be nice
if that's how it worked. Let's,
let's read the book first
because you know, now that I've
got these two kids right now, I'll
find myself thinking like, okay, I know
these kids have their jeans half for me,
half for my wife, and I know
I can't change those genes.
I know fate is going to give them a
couple of random mutations in those genes
that I have no control over that.
It's just the cold logic of Darwinian
evolution. What's offensive?
I mean the idea that they could
be constrained by their DNA,
maybe one of us gave them a bit of
DNA that's going to hold them back.
It's a terrible thoughts. This letter
right here. How about this one?
And so what you do, I
think all parents do this,
is that you slip into this Lamarckian
delusion that knows what you do with your
kids could somehow rewrite all that that
you can somehow by just being nice them
reading them stories or
whatever, that you could break
them free of all that. Rewrite
their, their, their blueprint. Like,
I dunno, you don't really say it
to yourself that way, but yeah,
you can make a deep difference. Yeah.
Like you can help them overcome you.
Is that cool? Hello?
No, you can't. I know.
That's what Darwin says.
You can't, I know, I know.
[inaudible]
once they're born,
their genes are fixed and change does
not happen in a generation or two.
It happens in really,
really, really slowly.
Gradually. Achingly slowly one parents
stretching isn't going to do anything.
See that's the bummer of
Darwinian evolution. As a
parent, you are a tiny blip
and a very, very long story.
[inaudible]
but this hour we're gonna fight this
sort of sad sack feeling of inevitability
and impotence and rewrite the so-called
rules of genetics. That's right.
Today on radio lab, we are going to
lick some rat, starve some Swedes there.
Realized some women. I mean we're
not going to do that ourselves. No,
but we're going to play the stories
where these things actually happen. Yes.
I'm Chad. I Rod, I'm Robert Krulwich
this is Radiolab. Stick around.
It's gonna get messy.
[inaudible]
okay, so let's get going. Uh,
and stick with your boy to the
mark just for a second. Okay.
Cause we were talking to science right
across Zimmer and he told us that back in
the early 19 hundreds, this, um,
tension between the mark and
Darwin got extra tense. Yeah.
In a sort of fascinating way.
Right. And it all started in Vienna
at this really marvelous
place called the vie varium.
[inaudible] yeah,
this was a really radical place at the
time because you have to remember that
people studying animals up til
now, they were basically, you know,
studying a preserved specimen and so on
at the Vive varium as the name suggests,
they have
man, it was like a zoo.
Well it was a zoo where there was
all sorts of experiments going on,
you know, the fact is that
taking care of animals,
trying to keep them alive in a
building is not an easy thing,
especially if it's 1903.
But Luckily for the vive and
for our story, they had a guy,
Paul Kammerer, who was he?
Um, so he, and when was he?
He was born in 1880 in Vienna,
Jewish family, by all accounts.
A pretty good looking guy
in, in pictures. He has that,
you know that crazy Einstein fuzzy hair
thing. Virginia's cut. Yep. He's 22,
23 and you already had this reputation
for being amazing at keeping animals
alive that otherwise would just die.
His reputation was, did he could get
inside the mind of say a salamander.
I know just
what it wanted to eat or how much
humidity it preferred. Right.
He was a born nurturer and he adored
animals. He actually named his daughter,
uh, less Serta, which
is a genus of Lizard.
That's the Kinda guy he is.
So of course the folks at the varium
asked him to build these terrariums and
aquariums and stock them with animals,
including a particular in fib Ian, that
plays a very big part in this story.
The midwife towed the midwife
towed, right? That's right.
You're Sam Kean again.
And here's, he says what you need
to know about the midwife tote.
Basically the midwife toad has a strange
habit for toads. Most toads, he says,
love to stay in the water.
They like to hang out in the water and
the females like to lay eggs in the
water. But with the midwife toad,
the female lays her eggs on land and
then the male midwife toad comes along,
grabs the eggs and actually kind
of sticks them to his back legs,
like a bunch of whitish grapes and then
hops around with them basically until
they hatch. So he's got to live his life
as a towed with all this baggage on him
just until they hatch and then til
they go off still it's a burden if he's
carrying a big burden there. Is
your wife going to hear this?
She cares your kids for nine months
and you're like that par mail toad.
Anyhow, so you've got this Guy Paul
Camera, who's good with animals.
You've got these toads who hate water
and in one day we can imagine he gets
curious as he's doing his rounds,
he stops by the midwife toads where,
and he looks down at that little mail
towed with a grape stuck to his legs and
he wonders how adaptable is that
little guy. I mean, he hates water.
Females seem to hate laying eggs in the
water, but is that the end of the story?
What would happen if I
made them go in the water?
Could they adapt? I know what I'll do.
I'm going to set up a terrarium for
them and I'm going to make it hot,
really uncomfortably hot, but I'm
going to give them a base and a water.
Nice, cool water, and he would
basically turn the heat way,
way up in music aquariums until
they had to go under water.
You can imagine these tilts are
like, dammit, fine. All right,
I'll get in the water. Maybe
they'd try and jump back out,
but it was still hot so they'd
have to jump back in and sit.
The camera kept the heat up.
Toads basically had to stay there in this
watery place that they had not evolved
for. Darwin's theory
would have said, you know,
90% of the toads are going to die.
There's going to be this massacre of
toads and only a few lucky ones are going
to survive. And those lucky ones,
according to Darwin's theory,
they would've had to have been born
with some random mutation in their genes
that gave them an
advantage in this situation
and that advantage, whatever it was,
because it starts with one individual
and then it gets passed onto the kids and
then onto their kids.
It would take a long,
a long, long time to
spread through the whole
population because generally that's
how evolution works. It takes awhile.
But according to camera, here's
what happened. When he heat it up,
the toads little cage that hit spend
more time in the water as expected.
And when it came time to mate,
the males and the females,
they would meet in the water and at first
didn't go so well because you know if
you're Atlanto and you trying to have
sex in the water, it's kind of hard.
Your slippery partner's slippery.
You just have it evolved for
this and there's no way you can,
at least not quickly,
but according to camera,
shortly after these toads got into the
water, they did begin to evolve fast.
They began to grow these little
puffy things on their hands,
the these kind of rough scratchy pads,
what's known as a nuptual
pad, nuptial path, right.
It was just what the males needed so
they can grab onto the female and hold
tight while they're mating. And
they didn't have these on land? No,
they did not have them on land. They
just appeared in the water. Yup.
And how long did it take right away,
Willie? In just two generations.
These toads seem to have done something
that should have taken, I dunno,
50 a hundred generations maybe
more camera thought. Wow.
They can respond to the environment.
Do we revealing it with experiments?
They're not trapped by their genes.
Around 1908 he starts publishing all of
these results and it's big news and he
grabbed his toads and he hit the road.
He hit the lecture
circuit and he hit it big.
He was known for going around and giving
what he called his big show lectures
where he would wow whole
audiences of people.
And in 1923 he actually comes to England.
There was a newspaper
called the daily express,
and they have these headlines that
come out. It says race of Superman.
That's the headline for his
doc race. And below that,
right below the headline it says,
scientists, great discovery,
which made change as all what's
he talking about? I said,
we're just talking
about a tote. I thought,
it's not just talking about toads anymore.
He's gone way beyond toads key
extended this idea to people.
He thought that you could kind of
engineer societies by changing the
environment. I just have
to read this to you.
The results make it probable that our
descendants will learn more quickly.
What we know well,
we'll execute more easily what we
have accomplished with great effort,
we'll be able to withstand what injured
does almost to the point of death where
we sought. They will find where
we began. They will account
and this idea won him a lot of fans,
including not surprisingly the Soviets.
Yeah, it was a very attractive theory
to them in Moscow because the Soviets,
they believed in Karl Marx's idea that
human beings are an improvable species.
That if you can change the conditions
around people, you change the people.
Your camera was saying, you know,
you can do this even on a physical,
but
you know,
there are a lot of skeptics and there
were from the beginning when Cameron
published his results initially
a bunch of immediately began
to say, wait a minute, hold on here.
It'd be nice if life was like that.
But life isn't like that. Life is hard.
People can't just will themselves into
a more perfect form according to Darwin,
life and changes are ruled by chance
and fate and to believe anything else
that's naive. So this whole toad
thing to the Darwinian faction,
it didn't scan really.
So some scientists began to ask camera
if they could look at his totes and just
take a little peak for themselves
and every time Canberra or said, no,
they were his specimen, get your own.
It was kind of this
struggle for a few years.
Then world war one came and that
kind of disrupted everything.
Camera for one was sent off to work as
a sensor for the Austrian military and
his lab ended up getting
destroyed, including all his toads,
except he had one,
one,
he had one remaining midwife
towed to this whole debate, two
totally different ways of seeing life.
It all came down to this jar with his
towed in it and you have to bear in mind
that at this point it
only had one hand left
the right and had been cut off
for, for microscopic slides.
And so you could only see one nuptial
pad and it all comes down to this and
all of it was just about to fall
apart. What happened? Well there was a,
a uh, expert on reptiles
named g Kingsley Noble
Gladwin Kingsley Noble [inaudible] sounds
like trouble. And he was for camera.
He was mighty skeptical. So he, uh,
he actually went to Vienna,
visited cameras lab when camera wasn't
there and he makes a very careful study
of this hand. Andy, when he examined it,
he noticed that there
was a syringe hole there.
And he says, this isn't a nuptial pad.
It looks darkened, but that's just ink.
What do you mean ink ink? Like the big no,
like India ink. What?
Yes, he doctored the toad.
That was the implication except camera
or tried to defend himself by saying,
do you think I'm a dumb cop or an idiot?
Because that's what I would have to be
if I left a forgery with ink standing
around openly in the laboratory where
so many of my enemies would have entry.
So how did he explain it? Well,
he thought it might've been an assistant
trying to frame him because he was
Jewish and you know, there was kind
of antisemitism growing at this time.
So he thought that someone had framed him.
And six weeks after a noble
published his results in nature,
camera rose sent a letter to Mascoutah
turning down a job that they'd offered
him because it would reflect
badly on the Soviet. And then
following day camera puts on a suit and
he walks off into the mountains outside
Vienna on a rocky mountain trail, and
he shoots himself.
Chase Lamarckism
pretty much died there.
Uh, uh, uh,
uh,
so then over the next 70 some odd years,
lamarck basically became the poster
boy for like the big dumb idea.
The idea that you want to believe in,
but that, you know, isn't true,
but, but, but there's, but there's,
there's like some hope here because, um,
okay. All right. This is interesting.
Then Carl told us about this
research that showed that if,
if a mother really couldn't quite
remember the details, does what a mother,
a mutual for Carl mouse or rat, I'm trying
to remember. Was it rats or mice? No,
it's rats. Rats, Yup. We ended up
talking to the guy who did the work.
Michael Meaney I think.
Yep. I'm a professor in
the Faculty of Medicine at McGill
McGill University in Montreal.
So here's the backstory. About 30
years ago I was in undergraduate,
Michael was in school and he got
interested in a very, very basic question,
but how things get passed down. Like,
have you ever had one of those moments
where you suddenly are your dad and it
catches you off guard? Oh, of
course. I mean it's pretty common.
But like here's a, for instance,
my dad from my entire life had this
thing where if someone was whistling,
he'd be so, he would like,
they could be whistling six tables over
to a restaurant and he would turn around
and be like, stop that. Like it was like,
it was scraping his very nerves and the
other day someone was whistling and I
was like, stop it. And it just hit
me. I was like, Oh God, that was hit.
It's never appeared until now. And you
went to like weird. Did that come from,
is that a genetic hatred of whistling
that I just had or did I somehow learn
that that in a sort of ass backward
way, it was Michael's question,
how does that happen? How do these
simple little traits get passed forward?
So, so we started looking at
maternal care. Many years later he,
and this woman, Francis Champagne,
who now works at Columbia University,
they decided to explore this
question looking at in rats.
So we have our rats in
the lab and they thought,
let's just see if we can figure out how
it is that rat mothers pass down their
parenting skills. That's right.
If you were a great rat, mommy,
what would you be doing with your baby?
You would be looking them quite a lot.
Uh, that's what good rat mothers
do. They look their babies a lot,
but she says you can tell right away just
by looking at some rat moms don't look
their kids a lot. There's a
normal distribution, right?
You got your good parents and your bad
parents would they decided to do first
was to try to figure out which rat
was which, which meant interestingly
counting all the licks,
putting this into context,
you know you have a rat mom and they
have about 16 to 20 babies all at once at
once and we're watching 40 litters
at a time. How do you count those?
That's 40. That's too hard. You have to
look at one cage say, are they licking?
Yes. No. Okay. Move on to the next cage.
Yes, no, move on to the next cage. Yes.
No. You have to do that for five
hours a day for six consecutive days.
Move on to the next cage. Yes. No,
move on to the next cage. Yes. No.
See, this is the story of science
that that doesn't get told.
Just mind crushing tedium. Yes.
Yeah. The next day. Yes. No.
Yeah. It drifts into something like
a shopping channel. In any case,
what they saw the end of all this
counting was, well, first of all,
what they saw was this pattern that rat
pups who got licked a lot as babies when
they grew up,
they lick their babies a lot and the rat
pups who didn't get licked a lot when
they grew up, they didn't
look their babies a lot.
So the great rat nightmare comes true
with the females become their mothers.
Okay.
I think that makes a lot of
sense actually. It's kind
of obvious, right? Right.
Yeah. I mean, we all kind of know this,
that there are cycles of
abuse or whatever. You know,
like if you're abused as a kid, you
were more likely to abuse your kid.
It's still, you've got a wonder
why. Why would that happen?
How do those cycles perpetuate?
I mean like with the licking,
is it a teaching thing
where you know,
the babies become good mothers because
they've learned it by watching their
mothers, they've seen it and
they've repeated the experience,
or does it get passed on such a deep
level that doesn't even require teaching?
What do you mean? So that's
the reason of course,
that we work with rats because
we can get inside the brain.
So Michael and Francis looked
inside the brains of these rats,
and what they saw was that the rats
had been licked a lot as babies.
They had more stuff in their head. What
do you mean? One more brains up more.
What kind of stuff brings us more up?
More of this particular kind of protein
that activates maternal behavior.
When rats have more of this protein,
they will act more motherly. And they,
they had more. So we'll think
about what makes proteins
DNA. Well, yes. Genes and
DNA. Yeah. Don't you see some,
how the mother's tongue is getting all
the way down in there and going messing
with the baby's DNA? Is
that what you're saying?
That the leaking is changing the
baby's DNA. That's what I know.
I'm quite saying that because
you know that that's out. Again,
that's the rule against the rules.
You can't change your DNA. Yeah.
You can't touch that. It's off limits.
But that tone is doing
something to the DNA.
So what is [inaudible]
the licking doing that,
that's, that's our challenge.
Do you have any theories for how this
tongue is tickling the DNA or whatever
it's doing? Um, well so then,
so what Michael just
launched into this thing.
What happens when moms lick their
pups is that the puppy comes aroused.
The reason they're more
aroused is that the mom's
licking
activates the release of adrenaline
and noradrenaline in the pop.
He says those two chemicals
kick off certain hormonal
systems and one of them is
called the thyroid system.
Irate hormones then get into the brain
and they turn on certain neurochemical
signals.
And the neurochemical signal that gets
activated during licking is Serotonin as
in the mood chemical. Yup.
So mom's looking activates serotonin and
it's released onto brain cells in the
hippocampus. You still with me?
I think I'm with you started with
the tongue four or five steps later.
We are in brain cells,
so almost instantaneously the mother's
tongue has reached into the baby's brain
cells.
Now inside the cells in the center
coiled up little spools is the DNA,
so we're getting close to the
moment of truth. It's there. It is.
That's the stuff that makes you you,
but that you supposedly can't get to.
But here's what I did not know
about DNA. According to Francis,
it's not just sitting off.
They're perfectly preserved.
It's in the middle of
the cell, it's crowded.
You've got all these chemicals
around racing by, you know,
in the south and very often
one of them will just go
crashing into the DNA
and it'll stick there like a, like a
barnacle or a glob of peanut butter.
Exactly. Peanut butter. There we go.
What will happen is it'll get stuck to
one little part of the DNA and now that
little bit of DNA is
very difficult to get at.
It's basically unusable because it's
got the thing stuck to it. Yeah,
and these things are called
apparently methyl groups.
Methyl groups are pretty sticky.
They're hard to get off. So
imagine the DNA in that brain cell,
all of these chemicals racing by
crashing into it, sticking in.
One of the bits that gets covered up is
that little bit that makes the proteins
that create a maternal instinct,
the bit of DNA that we'll give this baby
when it grows up instincts to be nice
to its baby and lick them. And you're
saying that part of the DNA is covered up?
Yes. And when methyl groups
stick to that part of the DNA,
the maternal instinct is
effectively turned off.
But if you've got a mom who licks you,
mom's looking activates serotonin.
Serotonin gets into the brain
cells and according to Michael,
unleashes a whole series of
molecular events inside the cell.
The critical part of this is
it all these changes wake up,
this little gang of proteins
known as transcription factors.
And if they see methyl groups sitting
on that bit of DNA, they are pissed.
And so they bring water friends to the
party, they all go down to the DNA,
surround that methyl and just
knock it right off the DNA. That's it.
And then they're going to basically
revel at that particular spot.
Turn on that gene.
So now the genes can make the proteins
that make the rats a good mom. Exactly.
Exactly. That was awesome. Wow.
That was amazing. Why? Why are you
so thrilled? Well, think about it.
This is nature and nurture slamming into
each other. Like you know when people,
smart people say, you know,
there's no such thing as nature nutrients
on the interaction with the team and
you're like, what the hell does
that mean? Well, this is it.
This is real physical chemical
interaction between what's going on in the
environment and what's
going on with the DNA.
Because you begin with a mothers
lick that ends up with a deep,
deep change in the baby, not just
the good, warm, fuzzy feeling,
but a fundamental shift
in who that baby is and
who that baby will be.
You're now hearing the Mark's name invoked
these days because there are things
beyond genes that we pass
down to our children. Now,
according to Carl [inaudible], Jeez are
still fixed. We can't rewrite our genes.
That is impossible so far as we know.
But there seems to be this
layer on top of the genes,
this second channel of heredity.
If the genes are the bottom floor,
then this layer on top is
sometimes called the epigenome.
And that thing can change
based on your experiences,
which when you think about it, it
has a very lamarckian flavor. Yeah.
I think that's where La Mark's ideas
can be woven in and make some sense.
So do you call yourself a Lamarckian?
Not usually because it upsets people.
And I'm Canadian. I don't
like to, plus, you know,
the mark didn't get all the
biological details right.
Had no idea about DNA or very many
of them right at all. But you know,
his basic idea seems to be true.
I mean, when you think of camera,
there was a report in science, um,
outlining a theory about how cameras,
toads got these characteristics
that invoked the,
these epigenetic inheritance
and, and imprinted genes.
And it made it plausible. Oh,
so redeeming him. Yeah. Maybe
or maybe not.
[inaudible]
thanks to Francis Champagne
and Michael median.
Sam Keen who writes about Paul Camera in
his book, the Violin, his thumb. Also,
thanks to Carl Zimmer whose latest
his evolution making sense of life.
Start of message. Hi,
this is Carl Zimmer. Hi,
My name is Charlotte Samurai
name new friend consumer.
I'm Carl Zimmer's scatter
nine nine you're eight. Sorry.
What do I know? Uh,
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and the
[inaudible] family foundation enhancing
public understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information about Sloane at
[inaudible] Iga, the adapt sloan.org
hey, what's up? I'm Jessica
Williams and I'm Phoebe Robinson.
We are back this spring, an all new season
of our hit podcast, two dope queens
from w NYC studio. It's comedy.
It's conversation with your fave celeb.
It's me and Jess telly tribe stories
about my bottom up session. Gross Dude,
why are you even bringing
that up right now? Anyway,
this season you'll hear from John Hamm.
Carrie Bronson did your Tyro gave her
union and more. My pits are sweating.
Just thinking about [inaudible] girl,
come on over to two dope queens.
Wherever you get your
pocket Bon, I'll call me.
Yeah.
And Go, Hey, I'm Jen. I boom, rod.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich, Radiolab.
And today it's inheritance today. Yeah.
We're exploring questions of like, uh,
what can you pass down to your
kids in their kids? What can't you,
how much of you will echo into the
future and how much of you won't?
And I gotta say, I'm feeling pretty good
about this show so far because well,
if, uh, if, if a mother,
a little rap mother licking her baby
can have such a profound effect,
basically change the expression of the
genes in the baby. Well that's you.
You'll think you can get deep down.
Look, in the end, what do I know?
I take it that we have more control over
our destinies and our kids' destinies.
And we would've thought, well, let's not
get too excited too fast because, uh,
we own it. We have a story
to tell. And this, this one,
this tale leaves me a little
queasy. Oh, there was a contact.
Hello? Hello. Yup, it's me. Oh, this
is Oola. Hi. We'll let you get in.
I'm in public health,
the Karolinska Institute in Sweden
where he studies population data,
looking for patterns in cardiovascular
diseases, high blood pressure and such.
But the story he told us
begins around 25 years ago,
way up in northern Sweden
that Sam keen again,
he's the guy who told us about all his
work in our little community called over
Calix. What does it look like? Is
it a big town? A little village?
It's a small forest area. Very beautiful.
But this was a really, really
tough place to grow up.
Very isolated and very cold.
Are you near the Arctic circle or north
of it? North of the Arctic Circle. Yeah.
My home village grows 10 miles
north of popular circles. Oh,
so you grew up in uh, over Kaylin's.
Yeah, we had uh, an expression here.
Dig where you stand.
And it just so happened
cause this town is a perfect place today.
Okay. I'm here.
Fix Our keep at the kingdom
archive because there is more data,
more information about the people of
overkill is going farther back into the
past. And you could find almost
anywhere else on earth. Yeah,
we are really data rich. This
is the era of colleagues. Yes.
Church parish. Yes it is.
Because here's the thing.
The churches up and over Calix
kept incredibly detailed records.
We actually sent our friend pike off skeet
to the archives in Stockholm to check
it out. Vicky Easter Register.
In those books you can meet everything
about the citizens of over calyx going
back hundreds of years. What's his name?
You know their names? Yes, yes, yes.
[inaudible] what year they're born?
1814 1881 she was born 1904 and this is
everything happening in the family is in
these books and they listen. Who was
an idiot? He was an idiot. It's, sorry,
what does that mean? He was an idiot, I
guess. Yeah, he was, you know retarded,
right? Yeah. ELN the at score that
he was, he was miserable to look at.
It's not very politically
correct. In any case,
these books tell you when
each of these folks died,
how they died from disease,
from a pneumonia accident.
She drowned. Oh my God.
A lot of diagnosis actually. I mean
influence cancer, heart disease,
brain disease,
[inaudible]. The church is also kept
track of the farmers, crows crops,
lifestyle, how much they
were growing each year,
which turned out to be kind
of an interesting thing
to look at because at time
the people in over calyx who were farming
trying to make a living out of the
soil, we have 'em how much they harvested.
They would experience these wild
changes from harvest to harvest.
What you see in the records is that
one year potatoes crops to do great a
hundred liters. Wow.
That's a lot of potatoes.
A few years later there'd be a harsh
winter and the crops failed and when the
crops failed. Fabulous.
Yeah, so sad. They basically start,
I mean when you look at the records,
you don't see huge spikes in mortality,
so they didn't starve to death.
They suddenly had to get [inaudible]
tiny fraction of the food that they
were used to. It didn't have grains.
I mean they didn't tell the partridge
until they just had to hold on for the
entire winter, but then a few years
would pass. Craps would bounce back,
but we have a lot more grain
here and suddenly plenty of food.
I could eat twice, three
times as much then oh no.
Total crop failure
fam. And again, these changes
would just bounce back and forth,
famine these salmon
east again
and looking at these swings and Fortune
Oola realized what he had here was a
nice natural experiment
because with all this data,
he and his team could follow families
forward in time through the generations.
So if they saw somebody who was starving
as a kid in 1820 they could then see,
well, when those people had
children and grandchildren,
did anything change? Were
there any consequences?
They wanted to see basically the effects
of starvation on multiple generations.
What did you discover?
Whether it was very interesting in
this gallery, that's a little odd
actually. Here's what was a says. He,
he found in the data, if
you were a boy in overkill,
it's between the ages of nine and
12 years old. So that's the window,
nine to 12 year a boy,
and then we have one of those terribly
rough winters and you're eating much less
than normal,
assuming that you can survive the ordeal
and you grow up and you have kids of
your own.
The data seems to say that your kids
will benefit from your suffering.
Yeah,
better if you have a starving daddy.
It turns out that the baby actually
gets some sort of health benefit really.
And these effects in fact were so
strong that you could trace it to the
grandfather, the
grandfather, two generations.
It seemed to have been passed
down from multiple generations.
You mean if you had a
starving grandfather,
you would be a healthier
grant boy for the,
because you had a starving grandfather,
you got a health boost. If you
had a starving grandfather,
what sort of health boost? Well,
um, we'll have told us, uh,
take heart disease or disease.
You said if you were a boy and you starve
between the ages of nine and 12 and
then you went on to become a father,
then a grandfather, your grandkids,
they were protected. Meaning that they
had less incidents of heart disease,
much less how much less, whether it's um,
one fourth of them can receive
one fourth. Let me say this again.
If you're a starving boy between
nine to 12 years old now,
it doesn't matter a whole lot.
What happens to you after this?
Your grandchildren will have one
quarter of the risk of heart disease.
And if you were eating a whole lot
between nine and 12, one quarter,
not only that, apparently those
grandkids were less prone to diabetes.
They lived longer lives. Something
like 30 years on average.
This was a [inaudible] effect. Instead
of dying at 40, I'd live to 70.
That kind of 30 years.
Yes, exactly. I just don't,
I wonder, it's such a surprising result.
I wonder how much you believe
in it so that it's solely a,
the mechanisms are not so clear,
but the results are very clear.
The results are obvious to you and there
it is. The results are quite obvious.
Just to be sure. We asked Francis
Champagne, which she thinks of this data.
I believe it. Oh you do? And
I'm Michael Meaney as well.
I think the Swedish data are, are
really, really strong and very reliable.
Everybody we talk to seems to think
there's something really interesting going
on here, but what exactly, maybe
you can explain this to me, Robert.
What exactly happens between nine to
12 that makes this big difference? Wow.
So here's the thing. How
old are your boys right now?
Three and eight months. Okay, so
here's what you're going to notice.
Your boys will first grow taller
and taller for the next few years,
and when they get to be up
about nine 10 years old,
they're gonna stop growing just for
a few years. This is what's called
the slow growth period.
Just for those years. That's
nine 10 11 just before puberty,
they won't grow much on the
outside, but on the inside,
that is the time where the
sperms probably developing
what's happening during this time is
that you're setting aside the stock of
cells that you're going to draw on
in the future to make sperm cells.
So they are pre sperms.
So the thought is when those little
boys in over cakes were really,
really hungry,
their hunger started a chemical process
that reached all the way down to the
DNA. Inside the boys' sperm.
Something happens on the
molecular level. What exactly?
Well, uh, the DNA,
the RNA micro RNA is a histone.
Anyway, that's it that you're just renamed
methylations phosphorylation
and so on that this just judo,
that's all this is because we don't know
no precisely how this happens,
but somehow the experience
of starvation marks the DNA.
Maybe like those methyl things we were
telling you about with the rats. Yeah.
Telling some genes to turn off
now or the genes to turn on.
And the incredible thing is
those marks stick around.
This sperm carries these marks to the
next generation and then the next one
after that, right.
[inaudible]
so somehow by some kind
of chemical mechanisms,
starving grandpa back when he was about
nine to 12 years old turned out to be a
good thing. So it's like, um,
GRANDPA's struggle is sort of jumping
forward and giving me a leg up. Well,
that's the good news. But
unfortunately there's, um,
there is some bad news here. Yeah.
If your grandpa didn't starve,
instead he lived through great times.
He stuffed himself silly nine 10,
11 years old. So he's a happy
grandpa. You the grandson, you then
would have high frequency.
So heart attacks as to
diabetes. It was uh,
a fourfold risk
for four full 400% greater. Yeah.
Can I say this is spooky. This is spooky
because it's like it does get, yeah.
It's like what if GRANDPA has a bad day?
Suddenly you're marked. Yeah. Frankly,
this makes being nine, 10, 11,
12 like a rather crucial and at a time
and you're not making the best decisions
anyway cause grandpa's just
nine. I should add to that.
They have found very similar
affects for smoking. For instance,
if you start smoking when your, you
know, 10, 11, something like that,
you end up having children
with more problems.
I initially felt very hopeful and excited
about this research because it seems
to suggest that that w a body one body
can respond to an environment and change
and be flexible in a way we
didn't think was possible.
But this you're telling me about Sweden
feels very, um, grim in
a certain way. You know,
sometimes that your grandfather's
suffering helps you, even if it helps.
It's horrifying claim
makes me claustrophobic.
You feel kind of hemmed in by what your
grandfather did? A little bit, I guess.
I guess the way I would I
would look at it is that, um,
you can change your environment a lot
more easily than you can change your
genes.
[inaudible]
I think is, what's weird here is
that, is that we started trying to,
to make a difference in our children and
our surprise attack by our grand plan.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do
though. When a meal gets to be eight,
I'm cutting him off. He's not eating it
at all. This may hurt you, my friend,
but I'm doing it for my grandchildren.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
thanks to [inaudible]
reporter Pike Malinowski and
Korean Barbecue is young and I'm a
senior archivist at a national archive in
Maria Bay in Stockholm.
Hello, this is Sam [inaudible].
My name is Jean [inaudible].
I'm a Sam Keynes dead.
Radiolab is produced by NYC and
distributed by NPR. Hi, bye.
And this message.
Hi, this is well calling
from Lausanne blend England.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation and had some
public understanding of science and
technology in the modern world.
More information about
slow@wwwdotsloan.org
hi, I'm Robert Krulwich. Radiolab
is supported by Squarespace.
The simplest way to create
a website this new year,
make your next move with Squarespace.
Whether that's starting a business
or launching a passion project,
no matter what your goals are.
Squarespace's award winning templates
can help you present your ideas to the
world.
Beautifully use offer code radio lab
for 10% off your first purchase of a
Squarespace domain or website,
squarespace.com make your next move.
Make your next website.
Hey, I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert
Krulwich, Radiolab and today inheritance.
What you can move on to the next
generation and what you can't.
Now the sweetened story
from our last segment,
leftists both fill a little strange. Yeah.
Because while you might
have a lot of influence,
no genetically speaking over
your kids and their kids,
you don't seem to have
a lot of control. Oh.
So we're going to leave you with a
story from our producer, Pat Walters,
about one woman's radical,
even troubling attempt to
regain that control. [inaudible]
come on in again. Few months ago,
pat made his way down to North Carolina
to a small suburb outside of Charlotte
to visit this family memos
Dublin. I'd come to see,
she and I snuck away from the
children into our office. Right.
This is nice and quiet.
Um, well I guess, um,
I was thinking we could just start
at the beginning. What year was it?
Where were you?
Okay. Um, 1989.
So this is Barbara, Barbara Harris.
I'm the founder and director
of project prevention.
And in 1989 when the story
we're telling now started,
she was living in California in
Orange County, and I was a waitress.
I worked for I for over 30 years.
And she was a mom to six sons.
She and her husband really
Harris. What'd he do for a living?
Surgical technician, six boys. There's
a lot of boys. But at that point,
just two of the six boys were
living at home, Brian and Rodney,
and they were seven and eight at the time.
And Barbara found herself returning
to a thought she'd kind of always had.
She started to wish again that
she could have a daughter. Yeah.
And by this point, she's 37 years old.
And I knew the only way I was gonna get
a daughter was if I went and became a
foster parent and asked for one
[inaudible].
So she did, she filled
out the forms [inaudible]
through all the training that we had to
do and first aid fingerprinted and had a
background check done.
[inaudible]
and then they waited for the call.
I already knew that if I ever got a
little girl, I was gonna name her destiny.
[inaudible]
and um, that summer it was, um,
July they got the call, I
had asked for a newborn.
So when the social worker
called me, she said,
I had this cute little baby girl
for you, but she's eight months old.
Is that too old? And I said, no,
no, that's okay. She said, well,
she's just beautiful. And she
has lips that like a baby doll.
That's what I remember her saying.
So Barbara and her son got in the car
and drove across town to the foster home
where destiny had been living for
the past eight months since birth.
We went to the foster home and went in.
The lady knew why we were there
and destiny was in the other room.
I'm sleeping or something, I'm not sure.
So we talked to her for a little while and
there's a certain point,
the social worker pulls out a
stack of papers with a child.
They give you a whole folder full of
information. It tells you all about them.
And she told Barbara, there's something
you need to know about this baby.
And she is born and tested
positive for PCP, crack and heroin.
And um,
doctors would later explained to Barbara
that Destiny's mom had been addicted to
drugs while she was pregnant. And
the psychologist who gave destiny,
her first checkup told Barbara that she
was delayed and she was always going to
be delayed because of her
prenatal neglect. Did that
scare you at all as like,
I mean that would seems like a thing
that would be kind of frightening. No,
it didn't scare me because she
says as soon as she saw destiny
and sat her in my lap with her little
dress on and her look curly hair,
she just knew this is my daughter.
A couple of days later I had
already bonded with her so much.
It was as if I gave
birth to her. Honestly,
I think it never seemed like she
was anything but my real mom,
if that makes sense.
This of course is destiny.
She's 22 now and she never
even met her birth mom. No, no.
Barbara says they've reached
out to her many times,
but they never heard back and
destiny says she doesn't really care.
I mean at all.
I got these jeans from somewhere,
but I kind of feel like
she was a surrogate.
Like she carried me for my real mom.
That's how I've always looked at it.
You know, my mom needed a girl
and she got one. It's just,
that's just how I've always, yeah,
and even though they look basically
nothing alike. I mean, for one thing,
Barbara's white and Destiny's black.
They both say that they actually often
forget that they're not biologically
related. They told me a bunch of
these stories. One of them involving,
well,
yeah, so I don't have the
biggest boobies in the world.
You can't see that on the
radio, but it's a fact of life.
And destiny says, one day she and her
mom were in the car and her mom said,
she said, I don't know.
You know, maybe. I mean,
maybe they'll grow picker like
mine, minor, bigger, and you know,
and then she goes, oh wait,
I didn't give birth to you.
That doesn't matter. Nevermind.
You're stuck with small boobies. Okay,
now I just had to accept it,
but we're getting ahead of ourselves
here because even that really sets the
story in motion.
The set of events happened a few months
after Barbara had brought this to me
when they got another call from the
social worker saying that same mother,
Destiny's birth mother had
given birth to another child.
Yeah. The social work call and told
me the mother had given birth birth.
Mother's name was actually the same
as me. So Barbara, really? Yeah,
she has the same name as me,
so I should tell me Barbara had had
another baby and a boy did we want it.
So I went to the hospital
and picked them up.
And you picked him up right
from the hospital? Yeah,
and as soon as she got
there to pick them up,
she could tell that something was wrong.
It wasn't little happy baby because
when a woman uses heroin while she's
pregnant, the fetus gets
hooked on it to two fries.
They're being born with like just
being cut off and he was going through
withdrawal.
Light bothered him, noise bothered him
as a beat it out. This is Smitty again,
projectile vomiting because
he couldn't hold formula down.
He'd fall asleep and just wake up
screaming. And he was just Nyla,
you know, most babies, Ocala peaceful.
He was nowhere really peaceful.
And Day after day, literally for months,
Isaiah would sleep and he would
scream. That was it. It was just,
you know, should have to come
into the world like that.
And nobody has a right
to do that to a baby.
But a year later, the
social worker called again,
Sam, the mother had given birth
to a baby girl. Did we want her,
this is the same birth mother. Yeah.
And again, Barbara, thanks. Come on.
But this little girl is here.
She should be with her brother and
sister and so she should be with me.
And I called my husband
again at work and said,
they want to know if we want to
take the baby and he's a barber.
I'm not buying a school best because we
had already had to upgrade from a car to
a van, from a condo to a
home. And um, so I said, okay,
well this will be the last
one. We'll just get one more.
But a year later, no.
She gets another call,
another little boy. That's how
we ended up with four of them.
These are four kids from the same
birth mother? Yeah. Wow. So by now
it's 1994 and Barbara is thinking,
I just don't get it. You know,
like how did this happen?
How was this woman allowed to walk into
the hospital and drop off a damaged baby
and just walk away with no
consequences over and over again?
How dare you do this? The way she sought
the state, the federal government,
somebody should say,
you're not doing this.
You're not leaving this hospital
unless you have longterm birth control.
Barbara tried to get a law
passed requiring just that,
but it failed and when I found out
the bill didn't pass, I just thought,
I have to come up with something
else. I have to be creative.
And she says one day this idea
just came to her. She was thinking,
everybody's motivated by money.
So
can I offer these women
money to use birth control?
Any other words? Could I pay women who
have drug problems to stop having babies?
I decided to have a press conference
in my front yard to announce what I was
doing and my naive mind, I didn't
have a clue what a big deal this was.
The story exploded.
Barbara Harris, his solution is
simpler than anything else out there.
Instantly she's offering
$200 $100 200 bucks.
It's 300 down to any drug addicted woman
who will agree to have no more babies
and I'm going to go out into the streets
and offer addicted women money to use
birth control. This could
mean sterilization. It
could mean getting an IUD
if she gives the woman a choice.
If you've already had a kid,
you can be sterilized and if you haven't,
you can choose to have an IUD or an
implant put in which will last for several
years. Wait, and when you say
they can choose to be sterilized,
do you mean permanent? Yeah,
permanent like tubes tied.
Wow. Sounds bizarre, but it's a
solution here. It says her program,
children requiring a caring community
or crack crack can prevent thousands of
unwanted births to drug addicted women.
I'd like to everybody to meet please.
Barbara Harris, please
welcome Brian [inaudible].
As Barbara made the rounds on the
daytime talk shows the reaction was split
right down the middle and the one hand,
she says immediately
check started arriving
25. This is 50 from all over the country.
This is 750 and it's 200 all over the
political spectrum from Hollywood to
social
conservatives
together pledge more than $150,000 to her
program. And that number, by the
way, has grown a lot. That 1 million.
Uh, yeah. Over the past five years.
If you look at our tax return. Wow.
But along with the support came attacks,
particularly as drug addicted
women began to sign up.
Barbara Harris says she's convinced
more than a dozen women, 14 women,
25 women have accepted her offer to
be sterilized in return for money.
Right away.
People accused her of targeting women at
their weakest moment and enabling their
drug abuse.
You know what they're going to go do
with that money. You get them $200 each.
I can spend on crack
and that's their choice.
But the babies don't have a choice.
Barbara started finding herself on panels
with women who used drugs during their
pregnancies and that's when things
would start to get out of here.
I feel that they should all be sterilized.
Sterilize, like you said,
you were like your head when you
ran your advice and like she is.
I didn't say I'm glad she asked my
opinion. Okay. This lady right here is,
you know, taking drugs and
try and be pregnant again.
First hear about this. What
goes through your mind?
I think I was really horrified and
terrified. That's Lynn Paltrow.
I'm executive director and founder of
national advocates for pregnant women.
Lynn has become one of Barbara's
fiercest critics and full disclosure,
she's Robert Sisters. Yes.
Well her,
her explanation is that
these women are having,
in her terms,
litters of damaged babies and society
forever will be responsible for them.
She said litters
in this magazine Article Barbara Even
said, quote, we don't allow dogs to breed.
We spay them, we neuter them.
I'm not saying that these women are dogs,
but they're not acting anymore
responsible than a dog in heat.
Are there people whose drug use is so
out of control, they can't parent. Yes,
but creating an assumption that there is
a class of people who don't deserve to
procreate who aren't worthy.
Appropriating the human race leads you
down a path that is is we should have
great concern about that path
is basically called eugenics.
Well,
I mean Hitler thought that if you were
Jewish that you had given up the right to
be mother and he sterilized
people as well. Well,
I just want to eliminate drug-addicted
babies from being born. I mean,
I don't think that puts me in
the same category as Hitler.
What's the worst thing you've been
called by one of your critics?
Probably Racist.
I mean, I'm married to a black
man, so that was just funny to me.
And according to Barbara, the majority
of the women she pays are white.
Do you think like,
but ask Barbara about some of the things
that she'd said because to be totally
honest, they kind of turned
my stomach. I like you.
I get the sense that like you have,
there's a lot of warmth in you.
You're obviously a great mom,
but that feels cold to me.
I was just pissed and what
they'd done to my children.
Now babies I had seen and all the
people that have me and tell me about
their babies that were damaged.
I had everybody's abuse on my back and
I didn't care how he said it or how we
did it.
Just don't have any more children because
at that point I didn't really know any
of them so I didn't see them
as people. I just saw them as
child abusers might be a mixture,
but she says she doesn't
feel that way anymore.
After I've gotten to know
so many of the women.
Barbara has this drawer in your desk
and Ms. Harrison staff are filled with
dozens of letters from
women that she's paid.
I want to thank you for your support
and kindness as always. She said,
thank you so much for the gift. I
bought my son an excavator track,
remote control and some summer outfits.
This is from 2000 to whom it may
concern. I have been doing very good.
I just got custody of my eight year old
son and I'm so proud and I have four
years clean and I anyways,
God bless you sincerely,
Jennifer [inaudible],
have you ever had someone call or write
you and say that they regret their
decision? No,
I've only had somebody call and say they
regret that they didn't stay on birth
control, which I find kind of
hard to believe. But then again,
I must've read at least a hundred news
articles as I was reporting this story
and I didn't find a single case of
someone saying that they regretted what
they'd done.
[inaudible]
how many women have you paid?
We have paid,
um, 4,000, 266. That's a lot of people.
That's a lot of people. Yeah.
She actually emailed me afterwards and
adjusted that number down like a hundred.
Um, and so in the end of, you know,
where do you come down on this?
I ended up finding myself
really conflicted about it,
but the, the,
the like I agree with Lynn that this
program does perpetuate a stereotype.
Tell me what your image of a drug
using pregnant woman is. Who are they?
It will be wrong to assume the women
Barbara talks about on TV and these women
don't just have one and two babies.
They have six, seven eight, 10 14.
All these women who have so many babies
and never try to seek drug treatment.
It would be wrong to think that they
represent all women who use drugs while
they're pregnant.
The women who I've worked with who've had
a history of drug problems aren't like
the examples that she gives. These
are women who loved their children,
who sought help and she says oftentimes
the women who want help have a really
hard time finding it. And
Barbara's not offering that.
She's not offering treatment.
She's not offering counseling.
And there are programs that do that.
But I said this to Linde Bite,
all the things that troubled
me about Barbara's program,
I feel like what she's
trying to do is to stop it.
To stop a kid from getting born into
a childhood that's going to suck.
The fact that you're motivated
by a really beautiful,
important, um,
value that we want healthy kids doesn't
mean the mechanism you're using is going
to end up helping those kids.
Because the truth is you have no idea
how these kids are gonna turn out. Yeah.
Like nobody's arguing that women
should do drugs when they're pregnant.
That is a bad way to start a kid's life.
But that's just the
beginning of the kid's life.
So much can happen after that. Once you
[inaudible] you and for me,
this whole story really
shifted or you and Jesse,
when I started spending some time with
destiny, Barbara, 22 year old daughter,
you know, as you can see, I like to talk,
even though Destiny's mom was doing all
sorts of drugs during her pregnancy and
the doctors told Barbara that destiny
was going to be mentally and physically
delayed, not feeling the way
I'm supposed to, she just isn't.
Could you just tell us like what you
are doing now? You're finishing college,
right? Yes.
I'm almost done. I'm
graduating in December.
It's exciting and right now I'm
student teaching, so that's fun.
But the moment I really felt like, Whoa,
was it when we started talking about the
little baby that we keep hearing in the
background. Okay. Everything.
That's my little girl,
she's 20 months old.
She'll be two in January and so her
name is Kalia and she's a complete nut.
I don't know where she gets that
from. Oh hell yeah. She keeps me busy.
Were you planning to have clean?
Nope. She was an oops kid.
She was totally new skid. See, we'll
just be honest. We just didn't think,
I just didn't think, you know, you know,
they say it only takes one time. All.
Yep. That is so true. One
time, and I'm one fighter,
so yeah, that's embarrassing.
But I believe everything happens
for a reason and I think that no,
I didn't plan on it,
but I wouldn't take her back for
anything because she made me better.
I want her to be able to look
back on her life one day.
Maybe when she's getting interviewed,
I don't know. And be able to say that,
yes, my mom was there for
me 100% without a doubt.
And I'm going to have straight A's and
I'm making it work and I'm going to
graduate with honors and one day I'm
going to be able to tell her, look,
I did this. You can do this. Like
push yourself and you got it.
That's really impressive.
I mean, you're just,
you're saying a lot of things that are
really impressive to her. Like I matter,
like I make a difference to her.
Okay. All right. We can stop.
So we did stop and I packed up
my stuff. It's pretty much done.
And Barbara and destiny walked me
out to my carb. Kaliyah came too.
They had a little basketball for her. My
goodness.
Loving is here and at a certain point
I noticed like over my shoulder,
Barbara is crouched down and she's got
her phone out and she's taking a picture
of this just perfect little scene.
You can get her in here. All
right, you're going to kick in.
And I just felt like I was in one
of those moments that like, look,
I'm going to contains everything that's
good about us as people. You can do one
buddy, you're watching this. I
couldn't help but think that destinies,
very existence is probably
the most interesting argument
against what Barbara is
doing. You're,
I can it back because if Barbara had
gotten the Destiny's birth mom, destiny
CLIA this moment, none of it would exist.
Yeah. And I told destiny I was thinking
about this and asked her about it.
[inaudible]
my situation turned out positive. Like,
I mean as far as you
know, positives can go.
Like I think I hit the Jackpot.
A lot of times that's not the case
and you just had to have to weigh it.
Like is it worth it? Like I could have
turned out like some of the other kids,
destiny says before she was born,
her mom had four other girls.
These were kids that didn't
end up with Barbara. Yeah.
Three of them ended up in other foster
homes and seem to have done pretty well.
But one of them,
okay, well one of them don't
really know what happened to her.
She's somewhere, but it's not
good. From what we've heard
last, they heard she was
living on the streets in La
and that could've very easily
have been one of us. Yeah.
I mean,
yes I might get a great
family but I might not.
The question that was stuck in
my head right then was like,
if you could choose between being born
knowing that your life might end up like
that and not like it is now
or not been born at all,
what would you have done?
Um, not been born at all.
I wouldn't want to put it up to chance
because what kind of life is that?
You mean that I do mean that.
Yeah, I'll check the side.
I know I've been joking a lot in this
interview, but I mean with all that I am,
see
she wants to see it Gaffin
back together. What's she saying there?
Taylor swift's never getting
back to you. You say never ever.
Oh no baby. Be careful
just saying, okay. She's,
do you want to say bye bye. Say Bye.
Aw, you blew my kids. That
was nice. Okay. That was
good.
Remind me this destiny has, uh,
what three brothers and sisters
that also were raised with her?
Two brothers and one sister.
What happened to them?
Isaiah is in college and
Taylor and Brandon W I met
them at Barbara's house and
they, they seemed to be, uh, to be fine.
And what about the four kids
that weren't raised with Barbara?
Do you know anything about the other,
the other four at just a little there?
There were four girls,
and Barbara and destiny told me that a
few years ago they found three of them
and they all either were in
college or had finished college.
So then the one that's in trouble
is just one of one. One of eight.
Yeah. One of it. So I guess
you could say to yourself,
seven out of eight of these kids did it
right. [inaudible] that's interesting.
I mean, that's, that's a different
kind of odds, but it's, yeah.
L Walters.