I'm Robert Krulwich. I'm Molly Webster.
This is radio lab and today today
we've got a guy asking a pretty common
question. Yeah.
But the way he tries to
solve this question is at
first thrilled to him crutch,
then the curse and then it ends up
in an extraordinarily deep puzzle.
It comes to us from producer Andy
Mills. A story is about David Weinberg,
a buddy of mine,
and it starts off uh right around the
time he gets out of high school. Yeah.
I graduated from high school in 2000
and then went directly to university and
then I got kicked out somewhere at the
beginning of the second semester and then
left that town that I was living in and
moved to the town where all my friends
were going to college and
he moves into a group house.
It was a party house, him
and a bunch of his friends.
There was a giant cross in the front
yard that my friends had found wild
tripping on acid and put in a shopping
cart and they put in the front yard.
Our fact checker actually found out
that they were tripping on mushrooms,
not acid, but anyway, a lot of drinking,
a lot of partying. And for David,
like for awhile it was good hanging out
with like the people that I care about
most in the world, I feel incredibly free
because I don't live at home anymore.
Um,
and then I just started to get old for
one everyday when his friends would go
off to class,
David would have to go to work during
the day I was working as a janitor at the
university where my friends went and
during the evenings I would deliver pizzas
and it went on like this for years, you
know, day after day they would party.
But then in the morning when
his friends would go to class,
he would go and clean toilets and then
deliver pizzas all through sophomore year
they would go to class, he would
clean toilets than deliver pizzas,
junior year class
toilets, pizzas. And like,
I think looking back on it now,
I think there was this rage that started
to build up inside inside me because I
mean I was really sick of cleaning the
toilets of kids in the dorms who I resent
but are also,
but I also recognize are able to do
something that I wasn't able to do.
And you know,
all my friends were at that university
and they were about to graduate.
And so I think I was
also worried that like,
well they're all going to go off and live
these lives and I'm going to be stuck
here cleaning toilets. And on top of that,
by the time most of David's
friends were seniors,
he was spending his weekends in jail
for driving on a suspended license.
So my life at that point was like
cleaning toilets in the morning,
delivering pizzas in the evening.
And then every weekend I was in jail
and there was kind of this breaking
one thing that one thing that
we did a lot of like, uh,
we listen to a lot of punk music.
My friends were in punk bands and we
would just like get really drunk and like
yell into the speakers probably like
three or four nights a week, you know.
And One night we were doing that,
it was me and my friend
Danny and my friend mark and
some of them you've snapped
inside me. I just got lost.
It just started like grabbing chairs
and hurling through windows and just
like smashed out all the
windows in our house.
You couldn't see the floor cause there
was just like wreckage everywhere and I
was all bloody and I was just
like, it was intense. It was,
I don't think it hit me until the next
morning when I saw what it looked like,
like a hurricane and like
ripped through the house. Yeah.
And all of his friends, everyone was just
sort of stunned. There's sort of like,
what's going on? And then you know, when,
when you confront a reality like that,
everything just sort of gets stripped
away and you're just left with this
question that's like, who am I like
and what am I doing with my life?
And around that time, David was
driving around delivering pizzas,
listening to the radio and WBZ
Chicago. It's this American life.
Am I right glass heard this story, this
Scott carrier story called the test.
I was hired to interview men and women
in the State of Utah who received
Medicaid support for treatment of mental
illnesses generally die and interest
like stop me in my tracks. So the
story is by a guy named Scott carrier.
He's a frequent contributor at this
American life and it's basically about how
he gets this new job.
He gets this job driving around the
state of Utah interviewing schizophrenia,
people giving them this test. I
took the job because I had no other,
I took the job because I had just quit
my steady job, my professional job,
and this is happening at a point
where Scott's life is falling apart.
What I wanted more than anything was to
put my boss on the floor and stand on
his throat and watching gag talks about
how he hates his boss and my wife moved
out, took the kids and everything,
his wife and just left him.
So I took the job and did the job
and my life will never be the same.
And David says, as soon as he heard
that story, I remember thinking like,
I need to figure out how to become a
radio producer. That's what I need to do.
Why, why does he want it
to become a radio for this?
Well, I think first off,
Scott carrier is really good
at what he does. Yeah. Uh,
there's something about him
that is magnetic, right?
It gets people thinking I want to do that.
But maybe more importantly
in the story, Scott is stuck,
not too dissimilar from, uh,
where David finds himself.
And a good Scott does is he
turns his stuckness into a story.
And in doing so kind of gives it meaning.
So He's, yeah, it's getting, it's
rising above your situation. Sorry.
Yeah. Yeah. And when David
hears it, he thinks like, well,
maybe I can do that too. It
makes sense. It was like, okay,
this is my ticket.
So that summer he lined
up a job at this camp,
this summer camp in upstate New York.
And I bought this mini disc
recorder already. Got himself. Mike,
the little mic that you could
clip onto your shirt and testing.
Recording inside the tent. He and his
buddy mark who had just graduated,
they left Colorado and headed to upstate
New York. My idea was like, okay,
I'll just go around and get all these
recordings and then I'll write these
stories about what it all means and day
one sort of like on the road but with
recording.
Great. On the line, on the law,
you recorded the kids at the camp
[inaudible] step out. Yeah.
We don't meet this bar fight one
night when he was out with the other
counselors. What's going on with
it? Is there keyboarders Huh? Yeah.
We brought the keyboards
flirting with girls.
What do you got these
added for buddy? Listen,
this is the coolest thing in the world.
Put these on. I mean, isn't that cool?
It's a live recording of what's
happening right now. Right now. Yeah.
I distinctly remember just being in
complete awe of hearing recordings that I
had made
where nothing was happening.
The idea,
the idea that I could make a recording
and listen to it. It was like,
like early man sees a mirror, you know,
and just can't stop staring at it.
Yeah, yeah. Actually wasn't it
interviewing people or anything like that?
He'd sort of decided that he wanted
to record moments as they happened,
like to him and he figured the
best way to do that was to record.
Secretly I had cut a small hole in all
of the pants and shorts that I had in the
pocket. So like I'd get up in the morning,
put the mini disc recorder in my pocket,
and then I'd run the cord down my shirt
and anytime something interesting was
happening, I would slip my finger in
my pocket and just press the record.
Well, launching fire at first, just
some, you know, moments here and there.
This is really scary. These
possible little scenes for a story.
Maybe Abraham.
Then we got to Queens, we got
to get to the seven trays. Him,
he and his buddy mark
built in New York City.
Everything sounds interesting.
So he's recording more and
more on the upper middle,
falling there. Then every day
after New York, he and mark hitchhiked
across Europe together. I'm sure, uh,
my name is mark or I'm David.
And at this point David is recording
people that pick them up in Europe,
e n mark and there other buddy
dom on the side of the road.
Well, the rhythm of the
cars on the highway is even,
it sounds almost like waves and the ocean.
No,
every street performer I would run up
to stand next to and record and just
everything. And you're still
thinking to yourself like, man, I am
just getting gold. Yeah. I was
like, you know, this is the,
this is the raw material for my
first grade story, you know, and uh,
I think I tried, like I
separated myself from, it's like,
it's kind of cliche like, oh yeah,
you graduate from college and you backpack
around Europe. And it's like, no, no,
no. I'm not one of those people.
Like I'm actually making a
grants documentary. Like I'm a,
I'm a, I'm a somebody, you know, I'm
not just like everybody else. Yeah.
Meanwhile,
David is accumulating hundreds
and hundreds of hours of
tape and one thing that
you'll hear if you managed
to listen through all of it
or most of it as I did is
just him hanging out with his buddy mark.
He was one of the people like we became
instant friends the moment we met mark
was your older than David. He was really
into music. Sound engineering? Yes.
Magic pocket.
We had this like perfect dynamic
where mark had like enough talent,
like he could actually play music and
like rift these funny songs on the spot
and I sort of like brought
the wrong, boozy ASM to it
and the two of them together that we
would just end up in these crazy places.
[inaudible]
oh yeah. Do you remember this
recording? Yeah, I remember that.
[inaudible]
we were in Croatia and then we
ended up at this huge amazing party.
It was like in this old
abandoned cabin, his building,
which is hundreds of
beautiful Croatian people.
That was such a great day,
but then she didn't want a trailer
slate. Do you want French fries,
veggies or apple sauce?
David and mark came back to the states.
Mark went out to Seattle to record
an album with his band. And David,
I got a job waiting tables at an apple
[inaudible] or salads
or soup before the meal
back in his hometown living in
his parent's basement. Yeah.
And if you guys aren't taking two seconds
to try to up sell and you're taking
money out of your pocket, you're
taking money out of your pocket,
you're taking money out of mind.
This kid did, he hung out with the most
that I worked with was this meth addict.
I would go to his place after work and
like drink beer and play video games and
he would get high and it was just like
really depressing, um, a hard time,
this shitty.
And David has all of this tape like tons
and tons and tons of tape from times
with mark and, uh, in New York, in Europe.
But he has no idea what to do with
it. So he just keeps hitting record.
Yes. Set up for the night shift
the morning.
Yeah. I mean I just, I
just that more, I think
I needed the recording and the
wire more than any time in my life.
Didn't want that.
Like that was the period when I needed
the wireless most cause it was like
raspberry lemonade. Sure, sure.
This sucks. But like I'm gonna,
I'm gonna get through this.
I'm gonna and this will
be a chapter in the story,
but just
[inaudible]
I spent a lot of my time with my finger
gently resting on the mini disc player.
I could feel the disc spinning
when it was recording.
It was just very satisfying
and comforting. You know,
like a pulse in a way.
Yeah. Yeah. I think
it's still going. Yeah.
Excuse me. Excuse me. No,
we should get one of those bells.
Put it right here. So tightening
the meeting or like if I just made
this friend or make it big, you know,
like they made it, they just kept getting
louder and louder until you made the
[inaudible]. No, not
at all. Some bartender
[inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible]
does he have a story? I'm not
so sure he's caught to tell. Oh,
well hang on. Okay. And after
the break, I think you'll,
I think you'll hear an answer. Okay.
[inaudible]
this is Neva bar term from Encinitas.
California radio lab is supported in
part by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
Get more information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
Invisibilia is back for new
season with all new stories.
All out of 22 arrival. Danielle,
everyone get down. This is a robbery.
We have stories about small personal
battles. I didn't leave my house.
I wanted somebody to see me really sorry
about the past and stories about huge
cultural issues. This is probably
gonna get somebody killed. Just evil.
You can hear Invisibilia in NPR
one or wherever you get your podcasts.
I am Robert Krulwich. I'm
Molly Webster and we're back.
And today we're w we're in the middle
of a story about David Weinberg who is
recording almost every day of
his life. And last we left him.
He was in Applebee's, uh,
working as a waiter and living
in his parents' basement. Right.
But he did eventually, yeah,
save up enough money to travel again.
I went to Alaska, things like that.
And he says that, well, when times
were bad, like at Applebee's,
he needed these recordings to make his
life feel like it had a meaning when
times were good,
he couldn't stop recording because
he was worried that he was gonna miss
something. Yeah. Occasionally,
like something would go wrong.
Like I lost three or four recorders.
They broke down over the course of the
years that I was recording and whenever
our recorder broke,
there would be a period where I'd have
to wait for the new recorder to come.
[inaudible] and I just felt like
on edge all the time, you know,
like I need to be, I'm missing,
I'm missing out, you know.
And like in this weird twisted way,
like I felt like I was missing out on
life because I wasn't recording it.
So when you would get the recorder,
it would be like a relief. Oh yeah.
It was like, oh, thank
God I can, you know,
like this pressure would be released
and I could go back to recording and,
and I would just feel like myself
again, you know? But then, hey, hey,
why is Brian ahead of you or behind David
ended up down in Seattle where he met
back up with mark and mark and I got in
some big arguments in Seattle before I
left.
It's something that you
said that with private,
like what is why it is that
you feel uncomfortable.
He just told me when I had the buyers
like I hate the fact that you record me
all the time and you know, I was
recording that conversation too.
I don't want to get to the heart of why
and he just laid it all
out for me. You know,
like he was someone who spent his day all
day in a recording studio meticulously
laying down perfect tracks,
you know, that was his life.
And so to him that idea that you would
just sort of like record everything.
It was wrong for a lot of
reasons. One of which was just,
he just didn't think that
experiences warranted that.
And then he had like
philosophical objections to it
for both
[inaudible]
that like what makes life great and
worth living is that it is this fleeting
thing and it's temporary.
Well I liked my life being
temporal. I don't want him to,
posterity is only good
in like certain doses
and when you are trying to
constantly record it and capture it,
you're just taking away
from that aspect of life.
It's like don't keep trying to capture
like the essence of this thing.
Just be in the essence of the
thing. Right. So here you've got
David saying that you know he's recording
all the time as to not miss anything
and mark is saying that no,
by recording all the time
you are missing everything.
You're missing the important thing.
And it got to the point where he
said he didn't want to be recorded
anymore and it was like really getting the
way of our friendship cause it was like
it like puts a ceiling on where your
relationship can go when someone feels
like they can't open up to you in that
way. That just puts this wedge between
you in a way that's just like awful.
Did you stop recording at this
point? Well, I couldn't stop like I,
that I had just like, I don't know
whether it's OCD or whatever. It was like,
I was just like, I
couldn't stop recording.
And so I was always recording and the
recording was like almost like a uniform
for this person that I
wanted to be. It was like,
it's like you're in a play and
you think you're living this life.
And then when the desktops suddenly,
like the lights go up and you realize
it's all fake, just like face it dude.
Like
you're just drifting.
At this point, David has
around 2000 hours of tape, um,
because he keeps on recording. He's not
really hanging out with mark anymore.
And he ends up just drifting
down to New Orleans.
And this is not very long after Hurricane
Katrina. And it's like, you know,
like, you know, everyone has heard
about the flood and I was like, no.
So I was like,
listen to these people's
like heroin journeys and then
like all these injustices
that they had faced. So he
decided to do something that he,
he never really done before and
started interviewing people.
Yeah, I've been assessed the stall,
but I've been living in New
Orleans east telling their stories.
How has it changed since? Huh?
I will change that much since Katrina
with their permissions, you know,
not recording them
secretly it up, you know.
So where did you do your grocery shopping?
I was doing a daughter jets really?
And then he started getting those stories
onto New Orleans public radio station,
listening to Wwlz street talk stories
of New Orleans cultural rebuilding.
[inaudible]
I'm telling you man, I appreciate that
discipline cause I was growing up, man,
I was growing up, just terrible man.
And then at night, uh, he'd go home and,
and he would listen to audio from
the wire tape of like me and some
bar and I think I am
ready. Everyone in a bar.
I hear Ya. Yeah. You didn't make
very many friends there, like
super drunk. And it's like,
what? Like, why did I think
this mattered? You know, like
why, you know,
and then also this like dynamic started
to change in my mind where like it's one
thing to record your own life
and yes, I mean to be fair,
I was also recording other people but
it was always framed around me and
everyone else was just sort
of like supporting characters.
But then when I started
doing stories in the wounds,
it was like this is not about
me, this is about other people.
And like suddenly it did start
to feel dirty to record people.
It was like all of that sort of came to
a head and I just felt worse and worse
about recording and then I just
stopped. I was like, I don't want to,
I don't want to do this anymore.
What about that feeling you were talking
about just moments ago where without
the recorder recording, what's happening.
You felt as if you were missing out
that an experience was kind of wasted
because you hadn't gotten
a chance to record it.
I mean that didn't go away. That
definitely didn't go away. I mean,
I feel like that still to this
day, I sometimes feel like, man,
I wish I was recording this, you know? Um,
but it just forced me to really think
hard about what moments in life were worth
capturing and what [inaudible]
weren't, you know. So like if
you do try to capture a moment,
then you're kind of out of that moment,
but if you don't then it's gone.
So that has the potential to be
lost. Right. I think that yeah,
we all can relate to
this idea. But for David,
the crux of that tension to do it or
not to do it like that became really
difficult for him in part because of what
happened next few months after he had
quit recording. I used talking
to mark who uh, you know,
still back home in Seattle is very
happy to hear the David wasn't recording
anymore and so mark decided to go down
to New Orleans and visit David and their
buddy Danny who was down there too.
And um, man,
this is hard cause I haven't really
told the whole real story about what
happened with mark. And
I'm trying to think,
I'll tell you the real story
and um, shoot. Um, with, uh,
Dan and today Danny and mark and I
were really close to three of us. Um,
and one thing we would do a
couple of times a year, we,
we would all go out to the mountains
together and just have this great trip
together like as friends. And so we
were going to do that in New Orleans.
And so, um,
we got on our bikes and we
rode down to the river and um,
sat along the river for awhile and then
we took the ferry over to the wet West
Bank, the other side
of the river, you know,
like New Orleans is like glittering across
the water got stoned and it was just
magical, like in the, we were just sitting
there for a long time, just talking,
like having those sort of deep
philosophical conversations
for the first time in a long time.
[inaudible] was not recording,
wasn't worried about
capturing the moment. So
my mind was free to not think
about the recording, you know,
and then I was actually more
present in some way. You know,
and it just felt like it always did when
we were close back in the mountains in
Colorado, you know,
it was just like a great moment and I
wanted to keep hanging out there and mark
was like getting kind of antsy. He
wanted to go explore the city, you know,
he wanted to go exploring
and I was just like,
they didn't really feel like
I was just sort of like,
they didn't want to be
around other people.
I was happy to be there with them and
then mark just jumped up and took off,
like just sprinted away. And we were
like, well that was weird. You know,
like it was very strange. David says that
mark said something in a moment but
he can't like remember exactly what
and so we like got on our bikes
and we were only a maybe, I dunno,
maybe a hundred yards, 200 yards
from the ferry that was parked there.
And by the time we got to the bridge
that connects the land to the ferry,
I saw that Mark's bike was laying on
its side on the ramp. I was just like,
well that's weird. You know, in my
mind am I, when I think back about it,
I feel like things happened very
slowly. Why is Mark's bike laying down?
Why are all those people shouting?
They're looking into the river.
Why are they looking at over?
And then I look in the river and
there's mark and he's swimming in the
Mississippi and he's shouting something
and I can't figure out what he's saying.
And I was just like, Holy Shit.
Like this is really bad. And then I
got really, really scared and I looked,
Danny and Danny looked totally
terrified and he started to,
you know, he was going down
river. Obviously it's the river.
And so there was a point I could see off
in the distance that there was a boat,
like a rescue boat or something
had gotten into the water.
And mark started to drift around the
bend and he disappeared out of you.
David and Danny, they kind of
walk up and down the river, um,
looking for mark and they couldn't find
him. Then it gets dark. Um, and Danny,
Martha, just head home and wait
for news there the next morning.
Still no news. A few days
later, the authorities,
they gave up their official
search for mark and,
and assume that he was dead and week
or so later they found his body he had
drown. And I should just add that there
is no reason to suspect that this was a
suicide. Yeah. I'm sorry the mark
passed, man. That's [inaudible]
it's a tough story to hear.
Yeah. Yeah. Let me ask you this,
okay.
Thinking about this as a lens of
like, you being as someone who has a,
a compulsion and obsession that is
now under control but still live,
lives in you, is there, uh,
still is there a part of you that
[inaudible]
wishes that you had been
recording that day? Um,
uh, I don't know.
The thing is, David says, uh, you
know, not long after your market died,
he started going through a lot of his old
recordings and sometimes he would hear
on them these great moments
between the two of them.
But a lot of times he
says it almost like, uh,
he could hear that ceiling,
but those recordings had put
on his friendship with mark.
Man, I want to fucking take
a boat down the coast, man.
So I was acting different than I would
would've if I hadn't been recording.
You know, like I was conscious
that I was on tape all the time.
I don't know, even if the
boat, even if, you know,
Damien was saying that
he was willing to like,
and I also hear myself in these
recordings often, like stepping over him.
Like he'll say something and then
I'll jump in and, and, and just like,
clearly I'm just like,
I'm on my own like train of thought
and I'm not really listening to him.
And that bothers me a lot.
I'm glad I don't have,
I think I'm glad that, I don't know.
It's just a hard, cause I'm on one hand,
I'm very glad that I don't have to
live with that tape and that it doesn't
exist. But at the same time David says,
I feel like maybe I miss something and
maybe there's some part of what happened
that night that I can't, that
I missed. All I know is that
he just said, let's get out of
here and like jumped up and like,
I don't even remember
exactly how he put it.
I just remember all of a sudden he
was gone. If I had that recording,
maybe I could make sense of it and maybe
something would be more clear about it.
Um, I think about that a lot,
but then I also think of what would have
marked what would mark have wanted. And
you know what?
That probably trumps whatever
clarity. I don't know. I don't know.
Yeah. But I still think about it a lot.
I still think about what I would get
from those recordings if I had them.
And, um, yeah, I don't
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible] a big
thank you to David Weinberg for opening
up his audio archive and sharing it all
with us and sharing the
story and thank you.
And you also produced the whole thing and
listened to all of those hours of day.
Uh, I should add here a
little update on, on David.
He's actually a producer at
KCRW and he's got this, uh,
series that you should all
check out called below the 10.
And if you want to know more about that
or maybe you listen to a lot of the 10,
what it's a series about people, um,
like very one of a kind interesting
people who live in La, a couple of the 10,
if you want to hear it, uh,
find links to it or hear little
snippets from the archive.
You can find all that on our website.
That's the thing you could do.
I don't know if that's the thing we
should say, which is radiolab.org events.
That's it. Still it.