Hey, this is Radiolab. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich. Our topic today is,
goodness, goodness, selflessness.
So we've done the math. I,
the math leaves me a little on the codes.
Why did your, why? So you know what,
forget the math. Forget it. Let's, yeah,
let's go to the people who do the deeds.
People who do amazingly brave
and heroic things. Yeah,
no math required and maybe find out,
I don't know what makes them
different than the rest of us. Yeah.
That question. Lettuce,
Robert Koski to a guy
named Walter Rick Koski.
I'm the executive director and secretary
of the Carnegie Hero Fund Commission.
Cool. Well thanks for doing this.
Can you just give us a little
background on the hero fund?
What is the Carnegie Hero Fund?
Carnegie Hero Fund is a private operating
foundation that was established by
Andrew Carnegie in 1904 and what we do
is recognize civilian heroism throughout
the United States and Canada by giving
an award called the Carnegie Medal.
And the accompanying the Carnegie
Medal is a financial grant. How much?
A lot of, currently the
amount is $5,000 wow.
And how do you guys choose your heroes?
We judged the heroic acts
against a list of requirements.
So then you have to have some
kind of definition of hero,
which includes some and excludes
others. Yes, perfect. Basic definition,
which is a civilian one
meaning no military who
voluntarily to leaves a point of
safety to risk his own life or her own
life or to an extraordinary degree.
Five to save or to attempt to save
the life of another human. Six.
How about seven y, can you hear? Can
you read that one more time? Okay.
I wasn't reading that
just came from memory.
So like what is it that happens in a
person's mind at that pivotal moment when
they decide to voluntarily,
voluntarily leave a point of safety
and risk their life to an extraordinary
degree to save the life of another
human? That's what we wanted to know.
Should we just jump in? Okay.
So the first one we have on our
list is a Laura Shrek. Okay.
That's file number seven three five
four six and the award number is 8,005
I am Laura shrike. I'm
from Matt Toon, Illinois,
and I currently live in
Dubai, United Arab Emirates.
Oh Wow. Laura spoke with our
producer Tim Howard. Okay,
so we're going back a little bit here.
Yeah, 15 years. Yeah.
Back in the, uh, mid nineties, 1995
to 21 year old college students
and I was driving through the country and
I saw a woman getting mauled by a bull
and a pasture.
So she stopped to see what was going on,
jumped out and started yelling
at her to see what I could do.
The woman was on the ground and the bull
was 50 pound Jersey bull tossing her in
the air and back on the ground.
Wow. She was clearly struggling.
And where were you? I was right
on the other side of the fence,
but the fence was electric.
So here's the moment
that we find fascinating. At this point,
Laura can either go forward
through thousands of volts
of electricity toward an
angry bull that will
likely mall her too, or
she can stay safe.
[inaudible]
I went ahead and just climbed through
the fence and I don't remember ever
feeling the electricity.
She says by the time she got through
crazily enough and neighbor had shown up
and threw her a piece of pipe maybe
about two feet long or she approached the
woman who is still conscious the
whole time she's yelling at me,
hit the ball in the face as
hard as you can and don't stop.
So Miss Shriek went up to the bowl and uh,
repeatedly refers two
foot length of tubing.
I think it distracted the bull enough
where she was able to get out from under
him.
And as soon as we were outside the fence
looking back into the pastorate and the
bull was literally right
there at the fence,
[inaudible] ground a few
times and snorted. He was
not happy. He was not happy.
Yeah.
To our question,
when you were there at that fence and
you had the choice either stay put or to
go through it, what was going through
your mind? W was there a calculation?
No, I can't really say that. I mean,
you didn't weigh your options
or anything like that?
I did not know. It was
just, here's the problem,
here's what I need to do. And
something needed to happen.
Huh?
So there was no choice moment?
Not that I recall. No.
If nobody came to this woman's
rescue, she would die. Unfortunately.
This is the usual explanation, says
Walter lobular. No explanation.
Like I couldn't stand there
and not do anything. I would,
I was compelled to act.
I didn't really take the time to
think about what else could happen.
No, I can't say I ever really thought
about my own life at that time. I mean,
I think we just jumped ahead
because we thought we'd try again.
That's the voice of the next Carnegie
Hero that Walter told us about.
Yeah. William David Pennell,
Ames William Panel. Wow.
Who is the 8362nd person to
receive the Carnegie Medal?
I'm pretty sure Lynn Levy tracked him
down. Bill, can you hear me? Yeah,
I can hear you.
William. David Pennell was 37 years
old at the time I faced heroic act.
Was It 1999? Yes. I was, uh,
early in the morning. It was like
3:19 AM in a small town near
Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
Monongahela, Pennsylvania.
We was in bed sleeping.
My wife had a lot fash I actually
didn't hear it in a dog my one dog was
carrying on. So right
away I run down there.
Mr Pennell went outside his house. There
was a very bad automobile accident,
a car crashed head on until utility pole.
She was like rippling up the windshield
off from under the hood and he responded
to the scene wearing only no shoes
or shirt or nothing on their chest
and bare foot. So here we are,
bill standing in front
of this ball of fire.
There are three drunk teenagers inside
that car though he doesn't know it can
either a do nothing
for B. Go in through the driver's door.
Big Fella sloped out the doors.
So I reached in and grabbed the
hold of them around the chest,
pull them from the driver's
seat out to the ground main.
Their car was just like blazer
and my neighbor was there.
She was hollering. There's more of them
in there. So I run back to the vehicle.
We found that the front seat passenger
who was trapped in the wreckage and I
finally got him loose and pulled him out.
Apparently Mr Pennell was aware
that a third person was in the car.
A third young man. Uh, Mr Pennell
entered the car third time.
By then there was tires blown.
I flames had grown to about three feet
above the car's roof. The interior,
like the headline are at the car and
stuff was dripping like plastic Donald my
back. Huh. I mean, I'm in
there screaming, you know,
somebody give me a hand in here,
but nobody, nobody would help. And uh,
I reached in and grabbed the hold of the
kid who was in the back by the scruff
of the neck and pulled him out. All right,
so when you are coming out of your
house and you're looking at that car,
what was going through your
head? Just turn to try to help?
I mean, I, I did what any
normal person would do. I mean,
you know, I just kept saying, this is
somebody who's kids. You know what I mean?
It's a time my daughter was like 16
and I'm saying to myself, you know,
if something, God forbid,
whatever happened to her that I would
hope someone would be there to help.
Do you ever talk to your neighbors and
ask them why they didn't come in there?
Uh, you know what, that's funny you
brought that up because no, I've never,
never brought it up. Never brought it
up. How come? I don't know. I guess,
uh, maybe I probably wouldn't
like their answer. I don't know.
I don't know why.
I've never asked him about what do you
think is the difference between you and
those other people who just sort of
stood by? Uh, I couldn't answer that.
I couldn't answer that.
So our bowl girl, she didn't know.
This guy didn't really know either.
Somebody must be able to tell us something
about what they were thinking at that
moment that allowed them, that gave
them the courage to do what they did.
I can't give you a definite answer as
to what propels people to do this. No,
but we took one more shot with Walter
and he told us about a case that of all
the cases he's heard, this is the
one that puzzles him the most.
It's the case of Wesley James Autry,
a construction worker from a New York
50 year old man who did jump into the a
track that in a subway
station to remove a fellow,
a young man who had fallen onto the track.
The gentleman was a six
foot 180 pounds. He was,
he was an ERT and yet Mr Autry persisted
despite the fact that a train was
coming. There would come a point and
let's, at least in my estimation,
where you would have to say,
I have to get out of here because I'm
going to be killed on, I'm not suicidal,
but Mr Autry didn't think that way.
He and I part in this in this manner.
What he did was he lay atop the victim
between the rails while the train passed
over them in the farthest
reaches of my imagination.
I can see myself jumping onto a
subway track to attempt the rescue.
What I can't see myself
doing is lying at top,
the victim while the train passes over me
making this story even more nuts.
When we finally met up with Wesley Autrey
on the platform where this incident
happened under 35th and Broadway, he
explained to us that his daughters
then when they was okay and uh, how
old lady daughters at that time,
my daughter was four and six and this,
this them there should this
picture, oh my God, super cute dog.
Then one behind me is Shuki
and this the baby Sashi.
So when they're standing there and
this guy starts convulsing and then
eventually falls off the platform onto
the tracks, right as a train is coming,
his choice is pretty stark. In order
to save this complete stranger,
he's got to leave his daughters
behind potentially without a dad.
I'm looking at him
second and going into another seizure
or some strange reason a boys out of
nowhere is that, don't worry about your
own, to worry about your daughters.
You can do this. So we jumped yes.
Runs to the guy. Is he conscious? No. No.
Tries to grab the guy's hand and he start
my grabbed his hand will slip apart in
a, he slipped. I look up, the train is
getting close. I grabbed his hand again.
We'll slip apart, just rained
the skulls up 50 feet, 20 feet,
10 feet, and then it's right there
and all he can do is grab the guy,
get him in a bear hug and flatten
his body against the guy as much
does he
the first train car? Just greys.
My cas train car went right over it
when the train came [inaudible] so stop
quoting five cars passed over us. I
looked him in the eyes. Excuse me,
and you seem to have a seizure
or something. I don't know you,
you don't know me.
So I just kept talking to him until
he came through and he was like, well,
where are we? I'm like, we on a different
train. He said, well, who are you?
I said, I came down to save
your life. So he kept asking me,
are we dead or we in heaven? I gave him
a slight pinch on his arm. He's like,
oh, just I see you. You
are very much alive.
Have you, did you ever ask yourself at
this point like what am I doing here?
He asked it. What am I doing
here? What about you, your mind?
I can hear the two ladies.
We had my daughter standing
the man between their legs.
I can hear my daughter screaming. So
when that training come to a stop,
I yelled up from underneath the train.
Excuse me, I'm the father. We're okay.
I just want to let my daughters know that
that I'm okay because I know that they
are worried about me. Everybody started
clapping. Can I ask you a question?
So the point at which you said
you heard a voice. Yes. That said,
I can do this. I can do this.
What's what's what is amazing to me?
Is it you left your daughters
right here after a guy.
You don't know he was a stranger,
total stranger. But you know what?
The mission wasn't con
completed. I was chose for that.
You felt chose like you were teaching.
I felt like I would have chosen
live for a religious person
though I would wonder why me?
Well, you know what, uh,
maybe 20 years ago I was supposed to be
at a certain point and then he explained
to us exactly why he had jumped.
He was the one guy who could,
he said right before his
feet left the platform,
this one specific moment from his
life flashed this thing that happened.
You know, I had a gun pool
to my temple, but you know,
it was a misfire. So you know, a gun
was put to your head and missing.
So you are almost dead for a
second. Those dead, you know.
So you think you might've
been spirit for a parent?
I was spare for reason after that. Yeah.
[inaudible] he says when the gun
went click and he didn't die,
he always wondered why had God spared
him that moment until he was on the
platform and he saw the guy
fall off. He says, then he knew,
this is why I can do this. I
can do this. I can do this.
That voice when that board said
that you're going to be okay.
I knew everything was gonna work out
you. You know what I think at
the end of the day, what's that?
I don't think that there's an answer to
the question we asked. I don't really,
hero question. Why were you a hero? I
don't think that any three of these here.
I mean the last one had
the longest explanation.
He had been selected for some purpose,
but does he know why he
was not a clue. Okay.
Number three gives me something. What
does he give you? Okay, so the first two,
right? They have no idea. None.
So this is just something in
them that made them act began.
Number three is talking
about circumstances like the
world prepared him for that
moment. Serendipity. So it makes me think,
well what if a circumstances
are just right?
Maybe any of us could do that
again, I'll get a middle man. He,
he used to say to me all the time, he
says, how did you manage to do that up?
Or how did you manage
to pull him kids out?
I don't know if I could've done
that. I said, well, you know what?
I'll say you wouldn't do this or you
wouldn't do that to you're put in that
situation. In fact, when we asked Walter,
how many nominations do you get a
year? Are they hard to find? No,
they are not hard at all to find a, we
are fortunate to be living in a society
regardless of what you hear elsewhere.
We are fortunate to be living in a society
where people do look out for others,
even strangers.
He told us they've even had to up their
guidelines to make it harder to win
simply because of the vast number for
ROIC deeds that happen in day to day life.
All
right.
This is Walter Red Koski support for
NPR comes from NPR stations and the bill
and Melinda Gates Foundation dedicated
to the idea that all people deserve the
chance to live healthy, productive
lives at Gates Foundation.