Uh, okay. Ready? Okay. This is radio
lab. Oh, okay. Yeah. You start saying,
okay, this is radio lab today
we're talking about loops.
I remember Krulwich Gentleman Ron. This
is Radiolab. It's all about loops. Yep.
I'm Jad and I'm in Robert, you're
listening to radio lab today.
We're talking about Luke. I'm Robert.
I'm jet and it's all about Lou gifts.
I'm Jan,
I'm Robert Talking about
loops and speaking of things
that happen over and over
and over again here on this show here.
Hello. Here he is again. Hi. Jad.
Hey Steve. Steven Strogatz. How are
you? Mathematician Cornell University.
How's it going? I'm good. And uh,
Steve told us a story
about a mathematical loop.
The through mathematicians all over the
world for a loop story starts way back
with a guy named got lob. Frager got
lob. Frigo, how do you spell that?
It's not, it's not Gottlieb. It's,
it seems to be lob at the end,
unless it's a Typo in
every book I've ever seen.
Now just set this up
very quickly. God Club.
The frago was a map petition back in the
1870s and eighties and he had a dream
that mathematics could unlock
the secrets of the universe,
that you could maybe even
build a machine, beat it,
some basic mathematical rules, and it
would just start churning out discovery.
Wouldn't even need a human being. That's
how powerful he thought math could be.
But that led him to a question,
if math is the most fundamental
thing in the universe,
what is the most fundamental part
of math? What's at the foundation?
Is it numbers? Is it, you
know, one, two, three. Well,
that's what you would think,
but God lab, he said, no,
there's a deeper thing than numbers.
The deepest thing of all is,
is what today we call sets the
set of things, you know, so that,
yeah, so like what's a
set, you know, you could,
Steve explained it to us using
the wall things. Sesame Street,
really old episode as far
as just to set it up here,
it's two people working
at the furry arms hotel.
There's Humphrey who's got a green nose
and a pink face and his girlfriend or
bike. I don't actually know what she
is. She might be his wife, Ingrid.
And so there are hotel keepers and Ernie
is in the background and so Ingrid and
Humphrey are taking an order
room service order from a room full
of penguins. You know, Humphrey says,
I'll take your order. Mr Penguin,
sir, would you lie? Oh, fish, fish,
fish, fish, fish, fish, fish,
fish. Dan Humphrey says,
let me check if I got that right.
Fish, fish, fish, fish, fish, fish.
You got it.
And then he calls over to Ingrid who's
going to call it into the kitchen.
So he tells Ingrid Fish, fish, fish,
fish, fish, fish. Ingrid says fish, fish,
fish, fish, fish. No number. Good. No,
that's not right because she only says
a five times. But then Ernie explained,
oh, excuse me, Ingrid and Humphrey, I
have a better way for you to do this.
I better where you count the fish fish
one [inaudible] two [inaudible] and six
fish. They both realize Ingrid
and Humphrey, how powerful
this is. And they say,
does work for say cinnamon
rolls? Spark plugs.
Absolutely. Wow. That's
the point that what?
Cinnamon buns and spark plugs and fish.
The sets have in common is
that there are six in each.
I mean if you try to say
what is six really mean,
it's the thing that those sets
have in common. According to Steve.
It's not so much the number six
that's important to hear. Yeah.
That's just the label for
this characteristic that
all these piles seem to
share. It's the pile itself, the
set that is the most basic thing.
So afraid to said, well this is it.
Sets are the bedrock that
I've been looking for. Yeah.
We can build the rest of
math on top of it. Yeah.
And then I can make my math
machine that'll solve the universe.
And I think he published a book sort of
showing how this might work except that
Russell Bertrand Muscle,
the mathematician then found a
devastating paradox that ended up,
well annihilating what
Reagan had tried to do.
Russell's paradox has now become
known as the barber paradox.
It's a little thought experiment. So
in this case, the set is a town. Yep.
A town with people. Yep. One barber
with the following rules in this town.
The Barber shaves. Everyone
who doesn't shave himself,
the barber sounds reasonable, right?
Everyone who doesn't shave himself.
So some people shave themselves,
some people go to the barber.
That's the universe.
We're in a town where everyone who
doesn't shave himself as shave and by this
barber. And now the question
is who shaves the barber?
Who shaves? Remember the barber? The
Barber has the property that he shaves.
Everyone who doesn't shave
himself, so he can't shave himself,
but on the other hand, until
he doesn't shave himself,
then he's one of those people who doesn't
shave himself and is therefore shaven
by the Barbeau. Maybe the barber.
Here's two solutions for you guys.
The Barbara could not shave,
couldn't he just not shave? No.
Or maybe town shave. Maybe he could
set up some sort of mechanical device.
It's sort of like one of those cold
card things that you can't change your
answers sensibly. What happens
to the barber and no one has,
there's nothing to say.
He either does or doesn't shave himself
by ordinary Aristotelian logic because
the barber can't shave himself
and he can't not shave himself.
So, so there's something still it
ruined. That's what ruined them.
[inaudible]
good ruin in the afternoon and you're
going to be late or you're going to have
to wait for a couple of hours like
after lunch, before you go swimming.
But I can't see that like overthrowing
all, all life's work. It does. It does.
It turns out to be very,
very problematic for the foundations of
math because what this Barbara paradox,
the reason it was so annoying
to mathematicians was that
math is supposed to be
this logical thing, right?
Logic is the lifeblood of math.
And yet here you had
this little bit of math.
There was bilogical a
self predicting that set.
But Bertrand Russell, the guy who came
up with all this, he didn't lose faith.
He felt, well, this is just
a problem with Cynthia.
So then spent a long time
trying to make, um, a theory,
I think he called it a theory of
types instead of sets. And these,
he had certain admission rules that he
thought would prevent paradoxes from
happening.
And for awhile it was looking pretty
good under Berkshire and Russell System.
There was no logical
problems, no paradox until
describing a little German guy comes
along and you say his name girdle.
I hear it. I hear it often pronounced
double. I don't speak German,
but mathematicians often say it
like the woman's piece of clothing,
you know from the old days
it sounded like a good good Yaddo.
There's, it is a kind of er or
this is Janna down 11 she has written a
book about goodwill and I am a professor
of physics and astronomy
at Burnett College.
And she says the point at which could
enters our story, it's 1930s Vienna.
Austria. Yeah. Just recently finished his,
what would be equivalent to like a
doctoral degree, a phd. Smart Dude,
kind of a rising star.
It was no question that people
around him understood that,
but he was also maybe a little bit
off. He had real breaks with, you know,
reality. He was in the biographies,
they'd call him a paranoid schizophrenia,
but he seemed more a kind of
obsessive depressive, I don't know,
it was my say my age. Armchair
psychology terms are accurate, but,
but he was in and out of
Sanatoria and, and um,
and he had real difficulties
being sure. What was your real,
the only reality he really trusted was
math circles, shapes, prime numbers,
formulas, axioms. Right? And as a
certain point, he got into paradoxes.
Perhaps it was the barber paradox
that learned them in, we don't know.
But he began to think about and
actually experiment with some of these
paradoxical loops. So he took
something like the paradox of the liar,
the paradox of the liar says,
um, this statement is a lie.
This statement is a lie, right?
Huh? If it's true, then it's false.
And if it's false, then it's
true. This statement is a lie.
If you think about that too
much, you might blow it, right?
So Google was interested in that phrase
and for various reasons he took it,
tweaked it a little bit to come
up with the following statement.
This statement is unprovable.
This statement is unprovable,
which is very important to
notice. If it's, if it's provable,
then it's unprovable. Obviously a little
bit of a word game at Google thought,
forget words. What would happen if I
converted this statement into math?
Because in math things are
either provable or unprovable.
They cannot be both at the same
time. It's either true or false.
And if it's true, we'll then damn it.
You should be able to prove it. Yeah.
So he said, I'm going to
assign a special number,
a unique number to make that a purely
mathematical statement by coding it in a
very clever way into
arithmetic. So to be honest,
we don't completely get
this part very, very clever.
Once he did his mathy stuff,
he had a rigorous mathematical
statement right there on the page.
He looked at it and he realized that
what he just said in math is it the
following statement? This
statement is unprovable is,
it's true because it's actually
unprovable meaning in math,
this statement actually is unprovable
because it is true. The logic of math
will not let you prove that it is true.
So it might be true.
We'll just never know.
Nothing like that is
supposed to happen in math.
Things are supposed to be true or not
true and you're supposed to be able to
prove every true things as Steve,
so if there's something
true that you can't prove,
that means that the math
is strangely ruefully
incomplete. It's always called is
incompleteness theorem. That's the phrase,
the girdle incompleteness Theorem is
that if you have a system of axioms that
are consistent, meaning they
don't contradict themselves,
they're necessarily incomplete,
that is there a certain statements you
can make within that system that you
can't prove or disprove and
all of math has this character.
This is the big shock that this
is not just about word games,
about logic puzzles with barbers.
This is as as devastating for
even just counting for one,
two, three, four. In other words,
math is shot through and through with
these kinds of statements that you can't
either prove or disprove seriously.
The deep thinkers at the
time were amazed at this.
It was recognized as one
of the great ideas of the,
of the 20th century for
sure. It may be of all time.
I mean, maybe I should make
it more concrete there.
There's a question that as far
as I know is still not solved.
Steve gave us this example of a problem,
something called gold box conjecture.
It kind of gives you a sense of
what incomplete is, feels like.
So gold box conjecture says that you can
always write any even number as a sum
of two prime numbers. So let me
give you some examples of that.
Like say 12 yeah, remember first of all,
prime number means you can
divide it by one and by itself,
like seven is a prime number. You
could divide by one and seven,
but nothing else. Okay. All right,
so 12 which is an even number is seven
plus five those those are both prime
numbers. All right, let's try another one.
How about a 24 that's 11 plus 13 right?
Okay.
Or I'm 36 19 plus 17 hmm.
Any even number. Now, this
has been checked out to, I
don't know what, billions,
trillions, maybe hundreds
of trillion soap.
No one has ever found a
counterexample to gold box conjecture.
And here's the thing.
You might think that either
it's true or it's false.
It might be that this statement,
every even number is
the sum of two primes.
It might be neither true nor false,
but what we today call
undecidable undecidable is a
term that comes from girdle
and decide, oh yeah. I mean,
suppose in some ethereal or transcendental
sense like that is suppose that
there's God and God knows that is true.
Then you know what about us here
among the world of human beings,
all we can do is check each even number
and every time we check it's true.
Would that that would never constitute
a proof because we'd never run out of
numbers.
If you then say that to
understand everything,
you either have to defer to God
who does understand everything.
If you believe in God, but
if you don't believe in God,
you then have to live with
mystery and not knowing
[inaudible].
Yeah, that's all you can say. I'm going
to say yes. I'm say, Oh huh. Well,
I think you've encapsulated it perfectly
and I think that girdle himself was,
I think a believer in all kinds
of mystical things. Like for him,
this was very freeing and liberating
because it meant that there were,
that we couldn't be mechanized.
There was profound mystery forever.
Hold, hold on.
I'm on your team here, but let me
just point out something. Google,
when he died, he was not exactly
liberated. He was a paranoid,
like he thought people were trying to
poison him. He starved himself to death.
He wasn't exactly liberated,
but I choose to be,
I believe it's somewhere
in his tortured mind,
and I guess his mind was pretty tortured.
There was a little fellow
humming a song, a song,
because liberation, this problem
themselves, this problems
[inaudible] problems,
unsolvable problems and solvable
problems.
Thanks to Steve Strogatz. He's
currently working on a new book,
which he calls the joy
of x, not sex, just text.
We don't even know what he's
experiencing. The joy of, and Jen 11,
her book about Google is called a
mad man. Dreams of touring machines.
Oh No, it's probably solvable problems.
And finally our last, a
loopy piece. This one, uh,
like the last one involves things
feeding back on themselves. Hm.
Kind of a like your classic
positive feedback loop,
which is what exactly? Well,
it's like when you can do it with
audio. You take a speaker and a mic,
you put the,
you feed the sound from the speaker into
the mic and the backend of the speaker
into the mic. The multiplies
and multiplies and then
then you get something like
payables with horrible,
definitely the painful,
but that kind of feedback loop like in
the case of our next story can also take
the pain away. Comes to us from
this lady. I'm Melanie thernstrom.
She's a writer, author of a book
on pain called the pain chronicles,
which is a book that began as
a chronicling of her own pain,
which has been suffering from
every day for the last 15 years.
And what sort of pain? Oh,
pain in my neck and right shoulder
and right side of my head.
And you're all at once? Yeah, yeah. It's
all mine. Did it start with something?
Did you hit it, hit it
there, or how did it start?
It didn't start with an injury of any
kind, but it did start at a discreet time.
Goes back to 1997 she was New
York at a country house on a date.
It was our first date and
I wanted to impress him,
so I swam across a pond
about a mile across.
Um, was this your idea or was this
his idea? It was my idea. Wow.
That's a different kind of first day.
And you made it all the way there
and back. Yes. And nothing happened,
but that night, what'd you got in the bed?
I was kept awake by this strange burning
sensation in my shoulder and neck.
Um, I didn't get the, the head
pain for like four more years.
Um,
and that particular pain never
went away and got worse over time.
Um, so it was like a
nerve. A nerve was being,
yeah. I mean,
eventually I got an MRI a couple of years
later and there was nerve impingement
in my spine. And so there was, over the
years, she says she's tried everything.
She tried drugs and she's tried physical
therapy. She's tried distraction.
Like I'll go to a matinee
and if it's a scary movie,
I just don't stay focused on that
pain. So distraction can work.
But then she says as soon as
she gets out of the movie,
it's back and it's
angry for being ignored.
And sometimes I'd have
the sensation like that.
That right side of my head was like dying.
Like the nerves were dying dead tree.
And that image would kind of frightened
me and that thought she'd find that that
thought would make the pain worse and
making the pain worse will inspire further
negative fantasies, which will make
it anymore until make the pain worse.
Which one spire morphing? Yes,
it's out of the loop. Positive feedback
loop. Yeah. In a negative sort of way.
Right. And eventually
Melanie's decided, okay,
I'm going to write a book about
this. You do some research.
So I was reading a lot about self
inflicted pain and religious rights
and I actually went to witness a Hindi
Festival type who Sam in Kuala Lumpar and
when she saw it really changed
your mind about things.
And you can see video of
this festival on Youtube.
What you see is a dense crowd of
folks. Even the middle of the crowd,
they write these moms doing
insane acts of devotion.
They literally like thread needles
through their tongues, poke skewers,
do their cheeks weighted fished,
hugs dangled from their backs.
And yet she says when she would look
in their faces, they seemed relaxed.
Like their eyes, guys
don't tear up, they don't gasp
for breath. Like really relaxed.
Wasn't just that they
were tolerating the paint.
It's actually seemed like
they weren't in pain at all.
And I would think, okay,
fifth person here has a skewer in
his mouth. I'm [inaudible] pain.
But that stick, you know,
when you can't become a religious Hindi
in order to experience this analgesics
benefits. I, that's cheating.
But I did feel like, okay,
so one way to describe it, um, is faith,
but for every way that you can
describe and religious terms.
There's also a way you can describe
things in, in scientific terms. Yeah.
And the reality is all of our pain is in
our head, which brings us to this guy.
This is Sean Mackey, chief of the
Stanford Pain Management Division.
And he will tell you that one of the
most basic facts about pain is that it is
not purely physical.
We've got signals coming up from the
body that are sending us a message.
Like if you whack a toe,
the signal shoots up some nerves
in your leg into your spine,
and those signals can
virgin our brain. And before
you even feel a thing,
there are a multitude of what I refer
to as little amplifiers throughout our
brain that turn up and turn down
the overall pain experience.
And these amplifiers are things like your
mood, anxiety, depression, attention,
expectations,
all of these things feed back onto that
signal coming up from the body and make
an either boosted,
but bubba past a certain point
where you get a sensation of pain or
they can deaden it down, down, down,
down, down, down, down, down, down to,
or you don't feel anything at all. Huh?
Point is pain is a conversation
between the brain and the body.
And Sean thought,
what would happen if I actually
let people see that conversation?
Could they, you know,
take control of it? Yeah.
So we did a study in Melanie signed up.
So describe what happens
in this experiment. So you
put in this MRI machine,
we put somebody into a
scanner, a brain scanner,
and you have a screen in front of you.
And what you see on this
screen is something that
normally only the researchers
would see. You see your own
brain in real time. Yeah.
Well you're not seeing the whole thing.
You're just seeing one p called
the anterior singular cortex.
There are many parts of the brain that
respond to pain, but that's the one that,
it's an area that has been shown to
be involved with pain perception,
turning pain up and down. It's thought
to give pain. It's emotional valence,
it's negativity.
And do you actually see an image of this
little piece of your brain right there
in front of you on the screen
and we'd, you actually are,
you're looking at your brain. No,
no. That's confusing to everybody.
So instead we give a, a visual
metaphor. He see an image of, um,
fire claims in an ice cave. I mean,
it is kind of a cartoon flying,
but it looks realistic. So you're
flickering flame do the leap into this.
Do the leap. They leave.
And the more activation
there is in that region,
the higher the plane go.
So Melanie is lying in the scanner
watching her own pain, flames.
And Sean gives her a set of
instructions. We say, okay,
we want you to imagine that you're
sitting in a nice warm, soothing Jacuzzi.
You know, this branding is a warm
bath. This burning is very relaxing.
I'm relaxing into it. Yeah.
But pretty soon it was like
hot, Kinda hot. Skeldon
me how I get to get out.
And before she knew it, the flames were
rallying. So Sean said, okay. Okay.
So how about you're lying
on a beautiful beach?
Yes. You know,
this breathing is a pleasant Suntan and
the sand is nice and warm and pleasant.
Um,
I'm gonna look so good in my new bathing
suit if I just keep getting burnt like
this
sunburn. Alright.
And then the flames
would kind of go crazy.
Her thoughts kept slipping
out of her control. You know,
if every time she would see those
flames rise, she would think, oh no,
the flames are rising. Which
would make them rise even more.
And then more and more until she
had this bonfire on the screen,
you're immediately struck by
the, they look like the flames,
where you're going to the flames,
where you're burned at the stake.
I've been reading a lot of
lives or saints at that point.
But then Melanie had an idea,
she said, why don't I take this,
this negative image and flip it?
And then I started trying to move into
the idea of being a saint or a martyr and
that I, you know,
believe that I would have no cane
and that I was protected by my faith
in his. Melanie started
thinking about this.
She could see the flames
dying down just a little bit,
which is fine cause I, this isn't,
you know, you don't know me,
but this isn't actually like part of
my fantasy life. But she thought, okay,
I'll try this. Let me keep
going in that kind of feeling.
So I was trying to pick one of the
few prayers I knew. I knew. Um,
I mean I didn't, I'm half
Jewish, half Christian,
I was three. I'm not settled in
onto what kind of martyr I was.
You know, I started thinking she's not
really be a Jewish martyr since you know,
if you're half Jewish mothers,
Jews, it's the right side. Really.
I'm Jewish more than Christian.
And then I started thinking about Jewish
martyrs and like what prayers do they
say? And, and as she added and right
advise details that continued to
make the flames go down, okay,
I'm in the right brain state.
Let me do more of that.
So Melanie finally decided, okay,
I'm going to be this one particular
Jewish martyrs names Akiva, Ben Joseph.
He was burned at the stake by the
Romans for teaching the Torah.
And there's a particular legend that just
as the executioner's about to set fire
to the logs right underneath his feet.
Akiva stared the execution or in the eyes
and smiled and the execution was like,
why are you smiling?
You're about to be burned alive and keep
us said all my life when I said those
words, you shall love the Lord your God
with all your heart, with all your soul.
I was sad because I thought,
when shall I be able to
fulfill that command and now
that I'm giving my life and
my resolution remains firm,
why shouldn't I smile?
By the time Melanie had this
fantasy built up in her mind,
she looked over at the flames and
she noticed they were almost gone.
Zero, zero pain for the first time.
She'd taken control of
it. I felt like, wow,
I am watching my brain
thinking my thoughts and I am
changing my thoughts by thinking
and watching myself do that.
So you are looking at yourself, looking
at yourself, looking at yourself,
looking at yourself. Yes.
Peering inside and seeing
the ghost in the machine.
I felt, you know, like someone
taking their first step on the moon.
Like I am watching my brain thinking my
thoughts and I am thinking my thoughts,
changing my thought by thinking
and watching my thoughts,
watching my brain,
changing my thoughts by thinking
and lodging myself do this
well. I needed to establish, I need
to establish this, that once you were,
did your two sessions and you're
in between exercises without this,
all these Gizmos, could you,
could you address your pain? Yeah.
Better? No. Like you think, well, okay,
can't you just get the
feedback from your own body,
but somehow this sensation isn't quite
direct enough that I think that you could
do it without the visual feedback.
Before that moment in that machine,
it was, um, power.
[inaudible] my name is
[inaudible]. I am changing
my last five words
before we go.
A very special thanks to our singers who
joined us this hour from the New Music
Ensemble at LaGuardia High School.
They are Kelly FMU, Julian Sodo.
You like Greenho, Juliet, Eagan,
Ruby from those guys wrote and performed
all the music between the pieces you
guys rock and thanks to the guy who
teaches them and who organize this.
Mr Robert [inaudible].