You are listening to
radiolab radio from W N Y.
S. T. E. N. N. P. R. Hey.
Hi. How are you? I'm fine.
How are you Robert? Nice to speak
to you after all these years. Yes,
it's been quite a few years.
I should let you know the Jad Abumrad
has just wandered in. Hello. Hi Jad,
this is Adrian Knowi.
Last name is N. O. E. N.
I'm director of the National
Museum of Health and medicine.
So you know why we're calling
you, right? Yes. Okay.
So what's the spring
it on the audience? Um,
I don't remember how I
happened to bump into you.
I don't even know how this came
up. I think you and I had, um,
been coke presenters at a
Ted conference with Amy.
That's what it was probably a decade
ago. We may have been talking about, um,
important events in New York
or civic architecture, but I,
but I do remember perking
up at the phrase grants too.
Trains too. So Robert said something
to you about grant's tomb. Yes.
And then you turn to and say it again.
Now you may know who's
buried in grant's tomb,
but I know it's buried in grant's tumor.
Yeah. Yes. He turns it home
at the museum. She works at,
there is a tumor that had been excised
from the throat of president grant in the
1880s actual tissue from grant's tumor.
Yes, that's right. Yes. Here we are.
Crouch.
I've been National Museum of Health and
medicine [inaudible] it is kept behind
several locked doors,
so you guys don't have an inkling of what
you're about to see if we go in there
now, but it's a privileged
area. This is Brian Spatola.
He's the collections manager and he let
us down a long hallway to some doors
into what? Me Back. Oh,
holy moly. Oh my God.
There's like a, they're twin
babies and in formaldehyde look,
Greens heads torsos and majority
of even gotten to the tumors.
Right. So he let us out of that
room and into another one in the,
you're sitting on a table and
waiting for us is this, is this,
the thing about which we spoke it is
was President Ulysses Simpson grant's
tumor. Oh Wow. It was resting in
a box. It looked as it happened
exactly like a cigar box.
Oh. Which is a little ironic.
This was the guy who never ever
stopped having a cigar in his mouth.
He never stopped having cigars.
He smoked as many as 12 cigars a day. Wow.
So it was probably the cigars that made
the tumor February of 1885 tissue was
removed, examined, and his physicians, um,
concluded that he had a
squamous cell carcinoma. Mm.
And ultimately he was treated
for pain and died in July of 85.
That same year. Well, it's pretty fast.
So that's what killed president
grant then it was a tumor. Yes.
I didn't know that.
So you see the staining that they use
to bring out the details in the cells is
the darkness, the tumor, the
darkness is the tumor. Wow.
The very stuff that, even though
president grant got through Vicksburg,
and then even though he came east and
they fight, tried to kill him here,
they tried to kill him
there. They tried to go.
Then he goes and becomes president.
This is what actually killed him.
This is what killed him.
Yeah. Can I touch it? Um,
no.
We may not be able to touch the actual
tumor of the president of the United
States, but we can touch on this
subject. We can grasp this subject.
We can examine this subject coming
up on radio lab for the next hour.
It's totally tumor. Oh, come on.
Don't call back because really what we're
going to talk about are not just any
tumors but famous tumors,
immortal tumors, deviled tumor,
contagious tumors and
tumors that speak up.
I'm Robert Krulwich. I'm about
to be confused. The big one.
And I'm Jad Abumrad this
is Radiolab. Stay with us.
[inaudible]
wow.
Alright. To get things
to get things rolling.
This first story is about something
that we thought was not possible that we
hoped was not possible.
We learned it from, uh,
I'll make it work from this Guy David
Coleman. I'm a science journalist. He is,
I think my favorite in my generation.
I think he is the best writer
that writes about science.
I specialize in evolutionary biology and
travel on assignment to far away places
and interesting situations.
All right, so first of all,
where are you going to take
us to? What part of the world?
I'm going to take you to
Tasmania,
which is the island state off the
south coast of Australia. You know,
you go to Australia and you think of
rock and deserts and red dirt and heat,
but you keep going south all
the way off the south coast.
Suddenly you have these
rolling green countrysides,
lots of wallabies.
One was species of kangaroo that like on
New England countryside with wallabies
that the, exactly with small
kangaroos hopping around.
But our story does not actually
be king in Tasmania. Nope.
It starts in Holland with a gentleman
by the name of Christo Bosh.
Is that bar as in B a r Bosh?
Christo bars is a wonderfully
independent spirited plumber,
a plumber,
plumber guy do to make a living on the
photographing is for me a big hobby.
We don't know just how
great a plumber he is,
but he's a very good wildlife photographer
and he looks for interesting animals
to shoot with the camera.
I mean, so over the years,
very often he puts down his
range and he travels. Yeah.
Well we don't have that many
animals here in Holland.
A little bit of road
deer and sometimes a Fox.
And in the early nineties he goes to
take his latest photography sabbatical in
Tasmania have gone to a Tasmania on boat.
And where you there to take pictures of
Wellby's or Kangaroos? No, no, no, no.
He was there this time to photograph
devils. Tasmanian devils. Yeah.
I quite liked the animals. What
is, I mean, I know the cartoon,
but what does a real Tasmanian
Devil Alexi look like?
Whether are about as big
as a little pit bull,
but look a little bit more like a bear
cub. Huh? White Yolk on its chest.
Big Set of formidable teeth. They'll
eat almost anything. Anything,
anything that could [inaudible] Kelp,
maggots and fish, snakes, garbage cans,
the occasional rubber
boot, you name it. Anyway,
when crystal gets to Tasmania,
he drives up the coast.
He finds dead animals on the
road, you know, roadkill,
roadkill from the road to use as bait.
What sort of roadkill? Kangaroos?
A little devil. Can eat a kangaroo.
Oh yeah. When there are three, four,
five together, ate a big
kangaroo in an hour is gone. Wow.
So he takes the dead kangaroo,
drags it to clearing in the forest,
sets up his photography equipment.
Very close. And then what happens?
Well you just wait
[inaudible] so he waits and as the
night falls little black ships,
we can creep under the,
you can hear them sniffing
on the refine the roadkill.
Ah.
And then I just started eating
and fighting with each other.
[inaudible]
this squad scary. If you
don't know what you're eating
as the crystal Danny at a safe
distance English shadows takes,
yeah.
Over the years he's done
this over and over and over,
but he always sees lots of devil
devil's in front of his lenses.
Sometimes 20 devil's running around,
devil's in his kitchen or come
into your tent. Devil's everywhere.
Let after a bunch of trips,
something happened.
It was Easter 1996 he was in the park
watching a dead kangaroo and waiting for
the devils to show. But only
thing I saw was one devil,
just one. Hey Dadada,
I'll try another spot at another
spot. Tried it at two devils.
They're not gone entirely,
but they're scarce.
And you notice something strange
about one or two of the devils.
It was something on the
faces fasion on the backend,
on their mouth and something
that looked like a growth,
a large, ugly growth. Well, maybe a,
they've been bitten or fighting
with each other and been on that,
but it was really big, you
know, and blood coming out.
And this was the first alarm bell.
So crystal, you were the first to see it.
And this was just the beginning,
like a pie out of hell and dark
death is sweeping Tasmania.
Trouble reporters got the stone fronted,
anything like this and began reporting
that more and more Tasmanian devils had
these lumps on their faces. They fill
the ice sockets, they puff out the lips,
they infect the gums. It's really sad
and hideous and whatever they were,
they turned out to beat lethal.
To jump ahead a little bit,
the effect that it's had in
the population, in some cases,
devil populations collapsed
by 90% died off very quickly.
Scientists looked at the disease and
determined that it was some kind of tumor
cancer, a cancerous tumor. And then
the question was what's causing them?
So what, what, what did they think? Well,
the toxic chemical was guest number one,
some poison or pesticide
from the environment. Yes,
number two was a virus.
So they tested in places where the doubles
live looking for something toxic or
some virus and they found nothing.
And then along comes a woman
named Anne Marie Pierce.
She looked at some tumors close up, um,
very close up from 11 different devils.
So she's looking at the first tumor and
she found that the chromosomes were sort
of mangled, which isn't really that
strange because that's what cancer is.
It's like your genetic
stuff gone screwy. Right?
But then she looked at the tumor from the
next devil and she found not just also
mangled chromosomes,
but chromosomes that were mangled in
exactly the same way as they had been in
the first devils. So now she looks at
a third identical metaphor, identical,
and then a fifth identical 11.
Exactly the same pattern in each
[inaudible] does that I,
I feel the sensation of all,
but I don't quite have these
understanding attachment.
Does that mean that that
these tumors are all brothers?
What that meant was that these tumors
were all genetically identical.
They were all the same tumor. How
can they all be the same tumor? Well,
they can't because,
because that wouldn't mean that these
Tasmanian devils caught the cancer and
from some other Tasmanian Devil.
Exactly. Wait, what do you mean exactly?
You can't catch cancers.
Epidemic of cancer in Tasmanian devils
was a crazy impossible tumor that was
jumping
[inaudible]
that was leaping from
one devil to another.
[inaudible]
raping tumor. Yeah, a leaping tumor.
[inaudible] point in this tale where we
really have to question everything that
we thought. We knew.
No cancer.
Now most people think of cancer as like
a situation in which one of your cells
starts
replicating and it doesn't stop.
It replicates uncontrollably
until it destroys you.
Okay, so that's like the one cell theory,
which is frankly how I thought cancer
worked. Oh Peter, we have to go ahead.
Just start. But then we spoke with this
fellow. Yup. His name is Carlo Maley,
cancer biologists at the Wistar Institute.
And he told us if you really want to
understand what's happening with the
devils, you're going to toss
out the ones cell theory.
Cause cancer is not just not
just a cell going haywire. No,
it's actually many cells
competing, competing for space,
competing for resources and in the
process driving each other haywire.
Like if you were to
somehow go into a tumor,
he says what you would find is between
a billion and a trillion cells in there
[inaudible] these are different cells,
this huge clump of cells in there.
They're all fighting out
cause you know space is tight,
food is scarce.
And what will happen is in the
middle of this mailing list,
the cells are competing, each
individual cells trying
to copy itself, copy,
copy Gabby. And somewhere along
the way you get eventually
a copying error. And
every so often says Carla,
one of these mistakes we'll
give the new cell a new talent.
And in the case of cancer it
usually starts [inaudible].
Just something pretty simple,
like the ability to slurp up food,
Fester nutrients like oxygen and
glucose. Now with this advantage,
that mutant and all of its progeny
will take over that area of the tissue,
but
not for long because now you got all
these beauties and they start until
randomly again, you get
another copy in state
and maybe this second copying mistake
gives the cell the ability to divide
faster, right?
So there it is proliferating faster than
its neighbors and it takes over growing
and displacing the other cells. But yeah,
it just keeps getting worse because
now you've got these double mutants,
they can eat fast, they
can divide quickly,
and they start to fight until you
get a third mutation, then a fourth,
and then you just keep ratcheting it
up and eventually roughly five to 20
mutations, you end up with a cell
that is so gnarled, so mutated,
and so powerful that it can
literally spit a kind of acid
[inaudible] matrix,
metallo protease that allows it to
rip through the membrane barriers.
And this is when you're really in
trouble because now the cell can roam
and so the cells leave the primary tumor,
they've got dissolved their way into
a blood vessel. That's a mutation.
Then they've got to survive in
the blood and another mutation.
Then they've got to stick
somewhere else yet another.
Then they've got it dissolved back
to the RTL heading and another. Yeah.
So it sounds like cancer is always
evolving to be more cancerous. It totally,
yes.
[inaudible]
this also explains why we
haven't been able to cure it.
Why when a person takes chemotherapy
drugs, the cancer will go away for awhile,
but then it'll come back
stronger cause the cells have
evolved a resistance to those drugs.
When I first got into work on cancer,
I was impressed at how malevolent the
disease seems as if it's being designed to
kill us. So here's my question. Um,
this leaping tumor in
the devils [inaudible],
is this a case where the tumor is actually
evolving into a new form like after,
say the 50th mutation or whatever?
Like now it doesn't just have
the ability to travel in a body,
but it can somehow leap out
of a body through the air
and into another body. Sure.
You mean the one that's really scary?
Yes, it is. It is pretty scary,
but,
but this is amazingly rare and according
to Carlo demands some pretty special
circumstances. Oh,
would m a Tasmanian devil would some
tumor get from one individual to another?
What would what? How would
that happen? Tasmanian devils.
God blessing bite one
another in the face a lot.
They're scrambling over carcasses.
They're fighting and biting,
swallowing, crunching.
Yan
males also bite females
during the meeting period. He's
a little bit of a rough lover.
So you have the male and the female
biting each other in the face.
So a devil with a tumor on its face.
Let's say it's meeting with another devil
and it bites that second devil in the
face. What exactly happens at that point?
Is it just rubbing its tumor? Okay.
When you think of these big ugly
tumors, think of Feta Cheese
and when one devil bites another, there's
a tendency for the tumor to crumble.
And to shed tumor cells that then fall
into the wounds on the second devil.
But um, some of your,
I don't understand. Um,
why wouldn't the immune system of the
devils kill those sales prevent those
cells from taking root? Yeah. Cause
that's what immune systems do.
And the latest answer is that,
well Tasmanian devils don't have as much
genetic diversity as you would expect.
Whether that means David explained to us
is that the Tasmanian devil population
has gotten so inbred,
they are so alike at a genetic level
that their immune systems now confused.
They don't know the difference between
their own cells and invading cells coming
in from other devils. Exactly.
Which doesn't actually sound like
the tumor is all that powerful.
So I asked Carlo Maley,
you got a mutation that this is really
the story of a tumor evolving more
adaptive or is it just the story of
a tumor getting lucky them those,
I think those are the same
story. How do you mean?
I mean evolution is all about dumb luck.
The way you explained it.
It's dumb luck that the tumor
was on the outside of the face.
It's dumb luck that they
bite each other a lot.
That a cell could come along that
could shed and fall into a wound.
It's all dumb luck. But that he
says is what makes evolution happen.
That's natural selection right
there. And when you step back,
sometimes the results are just
nuts. Yeah, just nuts.
And this is the point where we need to
talk about a transmissible tumor in,
in dogs, canine transmissible
venereal tumor. This is a tumor.
He says it's evolved way beyond the
one in the devils and way longer.
How long has that been going on?
Well that's been going on for
somewhere between 220 500 years.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. Between 220 500 years.
Yeah. Yes. Unit. Yes. Over
to millennia. Exactly.
And if that's the case then it's the
oldest continuous animals cell line in
existence on planet earth. You
might need to say that again
cause that is just too strange.
It is. It is. Even stranger,
it says David Kwaman.
When a tumor lives this long
propagates itself this long,
you can only really call it one thing.
This tumor is essentially an animal
parasite, not a species of parasite,
but one individual parasite
that may never die.
[inaudible]
David Corbin is the other song
of the Dodo and natural acts.
This is David Coleman
calling from tropical Bozeman
radio lab is funded in part
by the Alfred p Sloan Foundation
National Science Foundation.
Any lab is produced by W N Y C and
distributed by NPR and this message.
Hey, this is Radiolab. I'm Jad
Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
The topic is totally tumor. Of course.
That's my line by the way. Oh No, no,
it's okay. Yeah. We've been
talking about tumors this hour,
famous tumors and thus far they've been
really bad. Terrible tumors, really bad,
very horrible tumors, but because
we are fair minded about everything,
even tumors, let us consider the
that sometimes tumors can be rich,
beautiful and desirable. For example,
well,
George Malley is an ordinary man who is
about to become extraordinary name as
many mammals as you can in 60
seconds. How about alphabet? Are Brock
Bat Caribou Dauphine OHIP
this what is going on?
Or you're taking this 1996
movie. John Travolta plays a guy,
gets a brain tumor and the tumor, the
performance makes him into a genius
[inaudible] into Portuguese language
in 20 minutes. Not all of it phenomenon
the accent though to where
it doesn't give accents,
but it does. It does raise a
feel question, which is like,
is it possible for a tumor
to create something good?
So we paid a visit to a guy,
a doctor named Orrin Devinsky.
I'm a neurologist at NYU
mango and school of Medicine
and Dr Devinsky has had a
lifelong interest in the
beneficial effects of certain
kinds of brain conditions. Right?
I mean I would just tell you,
I think one of the most fascinating
cases in neurology very quickly,
and this one we were not prepared for.
A gentleman was described who ever since
he was a child would look at safety
pins and have an orgasm at
safety pins and safety pins.
The more shiny and the more
numerous, the safety pin,
the stronger the sexual experience. And
this happened from his pubescent period.
He just safety [inaudible] pretty.
He made this association when you looked
at a safety pin, he had an orgasm.
So he got to have been embarrassed by
this. This is worse than being, yeah.
So he would go into pride. He realized
this is not something most people do.
We never talked about it.
And he did it in private and then
he got married after the war.
He was honorably discharged and got
married and then started having less sex
with his wife because the safety pin was,
my safety pins were much more enjoyable.
Sometimes you just had to think about
a safety pin, not even hold it up.
So wait,
what are we seriously making the case
that this guy is getting a benefit from
furiously pin obsession.
But I think actually you could say that
the experiences that this guy was having
with those safety pins gave him a kind
of pleasure that maybe is unavailable to
the rest of us from an odd,
odd source. But you know,
pleasure is pleasure until says Devinsky.
This fellow began to have seizures,
got admitted to a psychiatric hospital
in London and Maudsley one of the big
psychiatric units. They actually got
an EEG. And to make a long story short,
there was a benign tumor.
Oh right in the part that's
called the temporal lobe,
sort of in the middle of your
head, right behind your eyes.
But they took it out. They took it,
they took it out and they cured
him of his wonderful experience.
So he, uh, he never was able to, he
could look at safety pins all day long,
but he would never again enjoy them
the way he had for his whole life.
How did he feel about that? Um,
I think it was a mixed
blessing as you would imagine.
[inaudible]
blue jeans on sneakers and this idea that
from a tumor you can get something in
the not so good, but also something
good. This is an idea that has, well,
there has been a, a novel
written on this theme.
The title of the book is lying
awake by a friend of mine.
My name is Mark Salzman.
Mark is a writer who lives out
in California and he thought,
I'm going to imagine a nun or main
characters, sister John of the cross.
This is a woman who had joined a nunnery
because she felt just lonely for a
relationship with God.
Yes. It's just not enough for her
to tell herself. Yes, God is there.
What she longs for is a tangible
sense of God's presence,
a sense that she can really
feel God's presence in her life.
And um, she,
she begins having what she thinks are
migraine headaches that the regular doctor
that the sisters see tells her that she
seems to be having migraine headaches.
They're coming more and more frequently.
And there comes a point when one of
these headaches changes dramatically and
then everything is different. Everything
is different. What's different? Well,
what happens? Shall I
read? Yeah, go ahead. You,
you kind of have to imagine this scene
taking place in an environment of
profound silence.
Okay.
She's in the cloister.
She and one other sister that
working on a sewing project,
they're sewing an altar cloth.
One of the pins slipped out of her hand
ringing like a miniature triangle
is it bounced off the floor.
She looked down to the floor and saw that
it looked impossibly distant when she
reached down for the pin.
Her hand look strangest of all as
if it belonged to someone else.
[inaudible].
The silence in the room came alive
like the words left out of a poem.
[inaudible]
something buried so deep inside her,
but she'd forgotten it was there.
Rose to the surface sister.
Are you not feeling well?
God was present and sister and
his voice was present in her face.
Nothing was changed yet everything was
changed. God is here. She answered.
You were here all along.
Well this is a field goal, isn't it?
For someone seeking a spiritual
connection. She has one.
That's right. She f this is the moment
she's been waiting for all her life,
but there is a problem because when these
things come from, sorry, just give me,
she has a tumor. Let's just get
the non surprise out of the way.
The show is called totally tumor. A
cost of all with famous tumors. Okay.
Do we do client? Yes. She has
a meningioma, a benign tumor,
small about the size of a raisin in
the temporal lobe area of her brain.
Right in the same spot where the
safety pin fellow had his tomb.
So the problem for her is
should I have the tumor removed?
Give up the most satisfying and
fulfilling experience of my whole life,
or should I sacrifice my health in order
to share with others the experiences
that I'm having? So we
thought, well, Orrin Devinsky,
the doctor we spoke with first.
I think every case is unique, and
individuals see patients like this.
This is what he does for them.
So we took the case to him.
Now here's the question.
If a person comes and says,
I'm having what I want
and you are suspicious that what
she also is having is a disease,
what do you do about
the patient? If I knew
for sure that the tumor, let's say
was benign and would never grow,
and the only thing that person experienced
was this religious feeling that
they've found extremely
enjoyable, I would say,
let's do nothing but do serial scans to
make sure nothing grows and that you're
safe. But in the book, as it
happens, the nun got a little worse.
She had a few more
headaches, the more severe,
and they took the tumor out,
the seizure activity stops.
These experiences stopped coming
and she does feel afterwards
a sense of [inaudible],
blah.
She feels as if she sort of tumbled out
of a Himalayan mountain into a muddy
village.
[inaudible]
this is common apparently in patients
after they've been treated. Right.
So my last question then
is really about the,
it seems to me the deepest question
though, all in this case is that, um,
if someone has a very important
and meaningful experience
and you have a sense,
it may be a abnormality, a physical
abnormality that is triggering them,
do you regard them as delusional?
Like there's just the possibility here
that maybe these people are having an
actual conversation. So yeah,
there's no question there are just,
you not even consider that.
No, I mean, so science, I think
the question you asked and I think you're
getting at is could it truly be that
this is God's avenue to speak to us? Um,
and people in the late 18 hundreds thought
it was through the right hemisphere.
And that's often where these cases
occur in the right hemisphere.
So it may be that. That's right.
It's the more emotional hemisphere.
And when things are in a perturbed state,
you may be more receptive to
experiencing spiritual things.
And I think there probably is some
physiologic basis that allows you to tune
into a broader world and maybe some
states of neurologic dysfunction allow you
to harmonize or tune in or receive
those messages so to speak.
In which case then your
tumor or your would
be the window where the conduit, right.
I do feel like I need to
place an asterix right here.
We are talking about a
tumor in the end. Well,
but understand that every feeling,
every thought you have comes
from cells in your brain.
Yeah.
Any of those cells can produce a glorious
experience than the experienced stands
on its own and sometimes in
very well documented cases.
These are extraordinarily profound,
desirable thing. They're often hard
to put into words. Have you tried,
I mean when, yeah, I mean people,
you know Destro Yefsky is probably the
most articulate person with epilepsy
who's had a religious experience and
who wrote down what he experienced.
I don't have the quote in front of me,
but it's, you know, this Felicity, this,
this a feeling I get
for several moments. He
was quoting his ashes.
I would experience such joy as would
be inconceivable in ordinary life.
I would feel the most complete harmony
in myself and in the whole world and this
feeling was so strong and sweet.
[inaudible]
that for a few seconds of
such bliss, I would give
[inaudible]
10 or more years of my life
even my whole life.
[inaudible]
perhaps.
Hi.
Hi. This is Emily calling from
rainy Vancouver, Washington.
Radiolab is supported in part by the
National Science Foundation and by the
Alfred p Sloan Foundation,
enhancing public understanding of science
and technology in the modern world.
More information
aboutSloan@wwwdotsloan.org
hey, I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich.
This is Radiolab and our topic today
is totally two minutes. Yeah, yeah,
totally. What you call it, what
you want. It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter because
the topic is tumors,
famous tumors and our next and
final tumor related tale is one.
We're wanting to do this particular
tumor story for [inaudible]
forever or after like two years ago,
I think. Oh, longer than that. Yeah.
It's a story that comes from a
friend of mine, Rebecca Skloot.
You want me to talk,
make noise. That's true.
I think we can move me closer to him.
She's a journalist and she
has been wanting to tell
this story even longer since
she was in the womb. I mean, she's been
researching the story for 10 years.
Hello, hello, hello.
And she just wrote a book
called the immortal life of
Henrietta lacks and in the
story, okay, it's about a tumor
that expands and never stops.
Begins in 1950 a black woman in Baltimore
is in her bathroom and she discovers
pretty much all on her own. Did
she has cancer? Um, it's all,
it's a little bit of a mystery
how she initially knew this,
but she knew it was there.
[inaudible]
I'm not, she called it. She
had told to her for a while
that she thought there was something
wrong with her, with her womb,
and she climbed into her bathroom and
she slid her fingers up inside of herself
and found this lump
chapter one
first she went into her local doctor.
I happened to be an
attending at that time.
The guy she eventually ended up
seeing at Johns Hopkins University.
Who is this fellow? Dr.
Howard Jones. I'm 98.
Next month I'll be 99 wow. So
when she came in to see you,
can you tell me anything about what
she was like? Well, she was a uh,
uh, you didn't remember
anything? No, I really don't.
But you remember her tumor,
right? Well, absolutely.
I never saw anything
like it before or after
[inaudible]
and this didn't look like
a normal tumor. It was,
it was deep purple and about as
big as a quarter, sort of shiny,
very soft. That was another
thing. I bet it on examination,
slightly raised when you touched it,
you might think it was a red Jello.
There was something very
strange about the way it looks.
[inaudible]
so doctors took a sample? Yeah.
So they would cut off these little
teeny tiny pieces and see Haley,
small King Dang bite or two,
they would take a piece,
put it in a tube and one would
go to the lab for diagnosis.
And in this case since it was Hopkins,
they would take an extra piece and
give it to the man named George Guy
too. So George Guy was a
researcher who worked at Hopkins.
He had a deal with the clinic that
anytime they got a patient with cervical
cancer, they'd give him a tiny piece of
the tumor. What he really wanted to do,
his main mission, actually, not
just his scientists everywhere,
we're trying to do this.
They want it to find a way to grow human
cells outside of a human being in a
dish, in a dish. George Guy
had been trying to do this,
working on this for decades. And
why exactly. Um, it's sort of like,
it's sort of like having a
little tiny bit of a person in a,
in a lab that's detached from them so
that you can do whatever you want with
them. You know,
you can't bombard some person with a
bunch of drugs and just wait to see how
much they can tolerate before
their cells all explode.
But you can do that in cell
culture. So, oh, so this is like,
this is like the basic thing
you need to study human biology.
You need cells in a dish. Yes.
Problem was anytime they tried
to grow human cells in a dish,
my daughters, they would
die. Yeah, they die.
This is George Guy's former lab
assistant. Can you just tell me your name?
You know, my name is so
and so. My name is Mary.
I'll put my maiden name in there.
Oh sure. Toy Cooper cheque.
Mary lives just outside of Baltimore.
About an hour from where she used to
work with George guys. This is Dr. Guy.
Just show me some pictures and he's
sitting at, at a microscope we can have,
he looks, he's a, he seems like a
really big guy. Like a really tall guy.
He was a big guy. At least six, five
judging from the picture. Yeah, he was.
And in every slide that she showed me,
he had kind of a crazy smile on his face.
Like he's got a, like he's
having a good bear if a man,
that's what I always thought up.
Oh yeah. In any case.
Mary says they were completely stumped
at why the human cells always died,
but they just did. Yeah. So on
the day that George Guy Walked in,
handed Mary a two with a little chunk
of a nameless woman cervical cancer
inside, I knew nothing about
her. No one expected anything.
No. He was doing that. Well he probably,
yeah, ever hopeful. But you know,
I was eating lunch and I thought,
oh the heck with it. You know,
it's not going to grow. I'm going to
finish the sandwich. And that's what I did
three. Then I went in and
she gave the, sell some food,
get my usual turn on all
the machines and left,
came back the next day they hadn't died.
So she came back the next day and they
were growing and then the next day still
growing. They just kept
plugging along in the next through a lot.
Rebecca says they doubled in size
every 24 hours. Yeah, they just grew.
All of a sudden, you know, I kept
transferring them and making more tubes,
transferring them, making
more tubes to transferring.
They weren't very reliable and stronger.
They just kept plugging
along and alone. Meanwhile,
the woman had spawned all
these cells die right?
Officially she died of uremia,
which is a like toxicity of the blood
because she wasn't able to get rid of the
toxic waste. That usually goes out in
your urine log in the log in the wall,
not herself,
and to tell us this story, is it
privileged to introduce Dr. George Guy?
It wasn't long after the
George Guy appeared on TV
holding in his hand a little
bottle.
Now let me show you a bottle,
which we have rolling my fifth
quantity of caster style.
So did you want to look at the photos?
Yeah.
You can't really get a sense of how
aggressive this tumor was until you go to
the Hopkins Archives and looked at
George guys pictures and videos. Okay,
this is Ken here. Halo Cell
Film. Then it hits you.
They use her in large 10,000 times.
Oh my God. Swirling hurricanes of cells,
just like thousands of them,
some small and some very large together.
Kept transferring them and making
more to them under the mic.
It's like something is just
explode. You're going to
[inaudible] just keeps getting
bigger and bigger and stronger.
It's indestructable, it's
indescribable. Nothing can stop me.
Why? Hers just sort of took off and grew
and the other ones that they had tried
before, it didn't is just
a little bit of a mystery.
Nobody really knows fore unless
George Guy knew what he had.
This new cell line was what they'd
all been waiting for. So early on,
right after this woman died,
George Guy sent Mary back down to get
more cancer cells from the [inaudible].
Oh, he sent me down to the
morgue. Yeah. Really? Oh yeah.
So I went down there and the
coroner, I don't know who he was.
Dr. Guy was there too and they were
standing down at her feet sort of. Yeah.
Meanwhile, she's like, she's flying
out there. She's already open.
I got some samples, coroner. We're
taking them out and getting a, Timmy,
what'd she look like? I couldn't look
at her face. I couldn't look at her.
The only thing I looked at were her toes
and they had chip nail Polish on them.
And that was really like,
oh this is a real person.
What was it about the
nail Polish that hit you?
Oh cause it was chipped cause you know
that she hadn't been able to take care of
her nails for a long time if
they got chipped like that.
And it's showed that she
was proud of herself.
Not everyone wears nail
Polish on their toes. Yeah.
Yeah.
Over the next several months while this
woman's body lay decomposing in the
ground,
George Guy and Mary produced hundreds
of thousands of her cells or tumor cells
and he named them the heela
strain. Heela like Heela,
h e l a [inaudible].
No one would actually know why he had
named them that for about two decades.
But what he did with these cells,
you know, we'd be unusual nowadays,
like if somebody now found
a cell that was special,
they'd run off to the patent office
and then sell it to Merck for 1 billion
bucks. But George Guy, hey,
just pass them out freely.
Didn't try and make any
money off it. It was just
nice, nice new thing
that could help science.
It's Mary says that George Guy began
to send Hilo all over the world. Yup.
And pretty soon she was in
hundreds of labs. And you know,
this was in the midst of
the polio epidemic season
when polio was at its worst.
We're talking early fifties right?
Yeah. So there's 1951 52 you know,
schools are being closed,
kids are being kept inside
today's cruel disease. Medical
science still has no complete onset.
There was this enormous effort
to develop a polio vaccine.
Problem was in order to develop a vaccine,
you had to have enough polio virus,
you know enough quantity to be
able to study it in the lab.
And they had no way of making enough. So
whether they do, well, one of the guys,
that guy, one of the guys that
guy had sent the cells to,
this collaborator friend of guys
discovered something kind of amazing,
which was that polio loved the heela sell,
put polio inside a Hilo cell healer
would copy and in the process make more
polio, which the Super Xerox sale, no
matter what you want to do, they'll look,
make a copy, make a copy
and make it a copy. Yeah.
So now they had a way of making polio
that could just be a polio factory.
And so the government made a factory
at the Tuskegee Institute, a real one,
literally a factory. So they had
these big, you know,
stainless steel and have that sort of
culture medium that were sort of rotated
constantly autoclaves for
sterilizing all equipment,
five microscopes, crazy
frankensteinish gizmos.
They had this machine that was like an
automatic settle dispenser and it had
this sort of long mechanical arm in
Squirt a certain amount of this cultural
medium filled with Hilo
cells into it to wow,
this is like the beauty of industry
right here. Yeah, it is absolutely.
The cells that were produced
at this factory. She says,
we're used to test the polio
vaccine back clean to prevent that,
but rather disease. The test
that they were doing in north,
it was the largest field
trial ever done at its peak.
The tests [inaudible]
he lived production center was producing
about 6 trillion cells a week. Wow.
Um, which is kind of inconceivable,
but that was actually only
the beginning says Rebecca,
because this factory led to an even
bigger one that was for profit. Right.
And that second factory was the first
time any human biological material was
commercialized. So this was the first
biotech company? Yeah, basically. Okay.
When they first started
mass producing healer, uh,
what sorts of things
were done to these cells?
What sorts of problems were investigated?
Like anything you can imagine.
So they infected the Hilo cells with
every kind of virus and hepatitis e Coyne
and cephalitis virus, yellow fever,
herpes, measles, mumps, rabies, whatever.
Like you, just any, any
backs. And this was just as,
there's a revolution for scientists
in certain chemotherapy drugs.
He loves sales went up and some of the
first space missions. Really? Yeah.
So they were, Hilo went
into space, into space.
And every time I hear
what I think you'd be like
[inaudible] why?
I mean just because the premise was to
see what happens to human cells in zero
gravity, you know,
if we're going to be sending people up
into space and what's gonna happen to
them up there? No. So Hilo went
up before any humans did. Um,
and then she eventually
went up his, she the cells.
There was actually an interesting
little slip up there. Yeah, I know.
Okay. So let's actually skip forward
in the story to the point where that,
that slip up,
you just heard that pronoun
confusion gets personal.
No. Well it happens. Okay.
It's a late sixties and a Hilo has it
led to a revolution in science and now
there are hundreds of cell lines,
not just he live at hundreds
and somewhere along the way,
scientists discover that Hella is so
aggressive that she's actually been
contaminating and taking over all of
these other cell lines where you just had
she, but I get your point. Yeah.
And she does it in the way it
does it in the strangest way.
Keela cells can, you know, they can
float on dust particles [inaudible]
they can what? Um, they can
float on dust particles.
Yeah. So they can, you mean
they can hop out of addition,
just get on a particle and
just float out the door,
up the stairs, down the hall, and
he'll sell into a lab rops into,
into a dish or cell culture where
there's other sales growing.
And because he was cells, her sort
of powerful cells, they takeover.
So on the heels of this catastrophe,
someone at Hopkins decides to make a test.
Let's make a test that will allow us to
genetically determine if a cell is heela
or if
it isn't. And to make a long story short,
this desire for a genetic
test led scientists and
journalists to ask a question,
which amazingly, for 25 years had
not been asked who was this woman?
And that's when we found out
her name Henrietta lacks.
This is the sound of Rebecca reading.
Henry had his medical
records for the first time.
This is a 30 year old colored woman.
She's sitting with Henrietta's,
his youngest daughter,
Deborah, second November.
So this is again when she was pregnant
with you and Brianna had five kids when
she died at the age of 31 most have
no memory of her because they were too
young. And that's
especially true of Debbie.
That was only 15 months old and I don't
remember anything about my mother.
Yeah. So she, you know, she,
she had been her entire life just sort
of longing to know who her mother was.
And did she like dancing? You know,
I always wanted to know what
she liked to do, what she went,
where she liked to eat.
Did she breastfeed Deborah?
She was really sort of
almost fixated on that idea.
She wanted to know if she was breasted.
Oh, well, you know, I don't know
what I would give up just to,
just to have her here
as hey, just to see her
the whole, Huh.
So in 1973 when a scientist calls the
lacks family and Deborah hears that little
bits of the mother that she never knew
are still alive and oh by the way,
can we take a blood test
from you and your family?
Cause we're having some contamination
problem. We need these genetic markers,
blah, blah, blah. Well,
as you could imagine,
took me by surprise. It really did.
It was really confusing.
I mean, how much is it, how much of
ourselves is out there? You know,
eventually she went online,
did some searches and found thousands
and thousands of hits. Like for instance,
on Heela clones. And
Deborah had heard, you know,
various journalists in the past had
come to her and mentioned, you know,
Dolly the clone sheep and
sad, you know, your mom,
they did this with your mom too.
Meaning that's actually
where the technology started.
The first cells of our cloned were Hila
cells. But that was just cloning a cell,
not cloning an entire being. But
that distinction is very complicated,
particularly for somebody who doesn't
know what a cell is. Yeah. Um, so Deborah,
between what journalists had told her
and googling Henrietta lacks and clone
thought there were thousands of clones
of her mother around. And really,
you mean like a bunch of Henrietta's
thousands walking the streets,
walking around.
And Rebecca says that one
of Debra's biggest fears was
bumping into one of these
clones. She said, you know, she would say,
I would have to go talk to her and she
wouldn't know that I was her daughter
and, and, and I don't know
that I could handle that. Wow.
It sounds so fantastical. Like
how could someone believe that?
Are Copies of her mother walking around?
But at one point 25 years after their
mother died, someone called and said, Hey,
part of her still alive. And you know,
we've grown enough of her so that it
could wrap around the earth several times.
At that point, all bets are
off. Yeah, right, exactly.
Not to mention that it's actually not
that crazy because your DNA is in your
cells. So if your cells are taken
out of you and they still grow,
well, isn't that still
you alive? It's of you.
But it's clearly not you
and the then it's going on.
[inaudible] it's a funny middle
space, that's for sure. Yeah,
so here's what happened is Rebecca
went off in search of Henrietta lacks.
Every so often Deborah would come along
and sit with her as they interviewed,
you know, anyone they could find friends,
family, and eventually over many,
many years, a picture does emerge
of who this woman is. She
was born in, in Roanoke,
1920 Virginia and I think she
was the 10th of the 11 children,
but apparently she was
the one that stood out.
Everybody talked about her as just
being, you know, she was the cat.
Oh my goodness. I don't
think I could top her.
This is Sadie Sturdivan
Henrietta's cousin.
That's a beautiful girl.
I was doing it for myself,
but hit it was very pretty Grana. Oh Hey.
And this is Henrietta's sister Gladys
and completion.
Everyone that they spoke with
zeroed in on the same few points.
Like first she was really meticulous
about her nails, always painted them red.
It's very deep. Red And second
Henrietta just had this,
she was very strength,
forthright, very sassy.
Like yourselves. Now,
the unfortunate thing is that when it
comes to her life, you know how she lived.
There's not a ton of detail.
Totally. So this is when she
crushed my hand with your cancer.
But in that hotel room,
when the two of them,
we're flipping through the medical
records, they did start to get some detail
about how she died. Things
I want to take notes about.
Was she in a lot of pain
when she died? Yeah,
I heard this was the hardest thing that
she was eventually in an unbelievable
amount,
Dean's complains of pain in
the right lower quadrant,
wailing and crying and you know,
moaning for the Lord to help her.
And according to the records,
doctors tried everything. Morphine,
they injected a hundred percent
alcohol straight into her spine.
I the pain spider, the
alcohol injection last week.
And she would have these fits of pain
[inaudible]
to spasms where this waves of pain would
hit her and she would rise up out of
the bed and thrash around.
So they strapped her to the
bed and her sister will,
along with one of her friends,
you know,
one of them would tighten the straps and
the other one would put a pillow in her
mouth so that she
wouldn't bite her tongue.
Yes, if I only just had the chair.
So take care of her.
Now dealing with how her
mother died was one thing,
but the cells made it more complicated.
Whatever apparent her mother was
alive in these cells somehow.
So if that's true, that
left very big questions.
And the first of them for Debra was,
how can Henrietta rest in peace if part
of her with part of her soul is being,
you know,
shot up to the moon and injected with
all these chemicals in a radiated and
bombarded,
painful. No one, you know,
that had her shelves on the back
of a donkey going to Turkey,
you know, in the air planes
just going all over the world.
Uh, uh, I just don't know
if she worried about them. She
worried that it hurts her mother.
When you infect the cells with Ebola,
does somehow her mother feel the pain
that comes with Ebola and a scientist ever
like sat down with her and yeah,
me just explained to her like this
is no, never, nothing cause it's spy.
It just strikes me that it wouldn't
be that hard to explain it.
Like when you take cells out of a body,
it's kind of like when you cut your
fingernail off, it just doesn't,
but your finger nail doesn't keep
growing and living after you cut it off.
It's a, it's really hard.
There is no other example of some way
that you can take something from someone's
body and have it keep living and not have
a person feel it and all these worries
says Rebecca began to build in
Deborah's mind and build and build.
There came at this point, wait,
so we were at her cousin's house.
This is her cousin Gary.
She was broken out in hives and she was
telling him all the stuff that she'd
recently learned. You can almost
hear it on the tape. She says to him,
[inaudible]
she can't carry the burden of these
cells anymore. She can't [inaudible]
okay. I don't want to cut.
And I had been sort of trying to talk
her down and he was trying to talk her
down
[inaudible]
and then just out of
nowhere, he just started
singing
[inaudible] Yo,
no. [inaudible] [inaudible]
Ooh.
[inaudible] no, those [inaudible]
and he started preaching
thing that doctors came,
that he held her head in his
hands and we'd come to you,
not the offer and the
finish of about Wifi.
And we thank you for being awake.
Mic. You make a path in the middle.
You call the Milton's a
skip lego rams and the Luma.
We thank you today.
Thank you all. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
[inaudible] hello? Hello? Hello? Yeah.
Hey Man. Hey Man.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
and she just relaxed. I like it, man.
I feel like, Huh?
She didn't realize it then, but that
night Debra was on the verge of a stroke.
Want to walk up into the
building? My Wall. Okay.
Do you mean he said
it's just up this hill.
One of the most striking moments of this
story is when the two of them, yeah,
visit Hopkins, I feel, yeah,
they'll lots of good and yeah.
Deborah meets her mother's
cells for the first time.
I shouldn't have, I'll show
you the bathroom and I can
show you by itself. Okay.
Because the scientists had finally
contacted. Sure. Christopher Lingara,
the scientist who invited us
into his lab to see the cells,
he had projected them onto a screen.
Big confused. They look green here. Okay.
They're so neon green
in this particular case,
because of the way they were
stained and projected. Um,
so they're very ethereal looking.
They're very [inaudible].
It's sort of there. The glow, you know,
I mean, when you think about angels,
right? You think of something glowing.
Christoph turned on this
screen and she just, I mean,
Deborah just gasp. She just,
Oh, [inaudible]
what was I saying? About 200 times
bigger than what they really are.
The swirling hurricane. Okay.
Did you say all that's my mother.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh Christopher gave, he gave her a,
a vial of the cells that she could hold
in her hand and they came out of it out
of freezer. So they, they're very
cold and she sort of, you know,
rubbed her hands together with the bile
in her hands to sort of warm them up and
sort of blew on them
to keep them warm. Um,
and then she just sort of
whispered to the cells. It was, um,
sort of incredible. She just raised
them up to her lips and she said,
you're famous, but nobody knows it.
Before we close, I want to thank Rebecca
Skloot for giving us her raw tapes.
Her book,
the immortal life of Henrietta lacks is
truly spellbinding everything that we
just did, very, very condensed
version of what's in that book.
You can get more information@radiolab.org
sign up for our podcast there,
radio lab.org before we go, we just want
to give a nod to our producer Layla.
We want to give a waved to her because
she's coming home. She's heading off.
She's leaving us after four and a half
years to go and be a writer at Grad
school. She writes a pretty good radio
piece, and you're gonna miss her for it.
And also for her great
awesomeness all around. So Lulu,
we love you and good
luck. I'm Jad Abumrad.
I'm Robert Krulwich.