Are we good? I think we are. Maybe
you have to get in closer. Yeah. Okay.
All right. Yup. We should do the thing.
I'm Jad Abumrad. I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab, the podcast. Can you just
tell us who you are? Oh, uh, well,
I don't believe I'm going to reveal that
and we're gonna start today's podcast
with this international man of
mystery. Who are you reading? No. Uh,
I'm Ian Frazier.
Ian is a writer for the New Yorker
magazine and he's written a bunch of
wonderful books. I Wilson Siberia and
other books of nonfiction and humor.
And we had Ian come to visit us because
we were working together on a show about
games, which we just aired in that show.
We ended up talking about a baseball,
a football, basketball, checkers,
chess. But the says there was
a game that we totally ignored.
Tic tacs.
Tic-Tac-Toe. All right. So what's the
deal with you and Tic Tac toe? I mean,
you, you learned it at age
five, I'm assuming, like
buddy. Exactly. Like everybody
else. Yeah, of course. But I mean,
as you get older,
it's one of the first sort of levels of
sophistication that you reach is that
you know how to get a draw
on every tic-tac-toe game
and you learn that at about
age, maybe six I would say. And
after that it's just formality.
It's sort of a developmental
milestone. Gaming. It is. It is.
But when you realize you have to be
sophisticatedly bored the game, right.
And you go, Oh yes, I'm
very good at that. So you,
you each the mature age of six and
achieved a certain amount of tic-tac-toe.
Sophisticated. I would
say I was a grandmaster.
Yeah. But the problem is when you
get to that grand master point,
everybody else is a grandmaster too.
And so everything is a draw and
the game basically dies. Right.
And so like the rest of us, Ian
stopped playing tic-tac-toe.
But then when he was well into
his middle life, you might say,
oh, this would have been in, this
would have been about 10 years ago.
He ran into something
that made him think, well,
maybe tic-tac-toe can
still do something for me.
Right, right. What happened?
Well, I went to Russia and I
traveled, uh, all over. And uh,
I was in, uh, Chikota,
which is the part of, uh,
the Russian Far East, opposite, uh,
Alaska. It's not a great distance,
but it's an enormous distance
in terms of culture. Uh,
and at that time my Russian language was
very weak and I was staying with this,
uh, a young couple who had a
six year old son named eager.
And because of the level of my language,
I got along very well with preschool
children and elementary school teachers.
Hello. I am a student. Right.
And that didn't seem like
ridiculous to a six year old.
It seemed great. And he actually
could speak some English.
He had like about eight or 10 words.
And the first thing eager said to me was,
how do you do?
He was just incredibly cute and the
nice kid and his shirts, you know,
red Russian kids shirts are buttoned up
at the neck like that. And he was very,
very serious. And, and,
and so we were just hanging out
and I was able to talk to him.
And then on a whim, really
he said, I said, well let's,
let's play tic Tac toe and why
did you get that idea? Yeah,
cause it was just something
to do with the kid.
I don't even remember
how we got that idea,
but we were just sitting around and I
explained the game to him and he had never
heard of it. Really? So you drew,
you drew the classic shape of the tick
tech to this boy and he stares it into,
so what's this like some
kind of cross or what he did,
he didn't know what it was.
He had no idea what it was.
And I just showed him by drawing
how you do this x's and o's.
And he picked it up. I mean
he understood what it was.
And then we started playing and he
very quickly got the principal, but I,
to be honest, was
clobbering him with doing,
was there a certain kind
of joy? It's just like, ah,
that's not where the o goes.
And then three x's foul,
you're outta here and he would be
quite crushed. I'm like, oh no,
I lost it.
But it's really fun to play tic Tac
toe with someone who doesn't know how,
because you're just walking all over
him and just putting axes. And I was,
it was okay. Technically it was not fair.
I think finally we're collaborating.
Are you talking like, oh,
I mean James or game after game.
And it didn't take very
many moves for me to win.
So I stayed with them before we made
this trip into the Tundra and we went out
into the Tundra. We were there for
a week or 10 days or something.
And then I came back and
stayed with them again.
I do not believe he had been
playing tic TAC toe in my absence,
but somehow he had gotten better.
And so we had very, very ordinary
and frustrating games in my,
for my point of view as became back.
I didn't win as readily at all.
I didn't lose well. But, uh,
you feel a slight urge to
go to the nearby school,
find new, find new weather. Uh,
Siberian tic-tac-toe Hustler
was how in elementary schools,
of course was how I, you know,
paid for for several years have
paid for my New York City apartment.
Uh, I later checked and, uh,
listeners may contradict
me, but as far as I know,
this game is unknown in Russia and
I've asked Russian friends, unknown,
completely unknown, complete
like years old and up and up.
I would send in eastern Russia on the
site in deep Siberian or I was in deep
Siberia. But, um, uh, in the cities,
I have not met anybody who knows
this. Moscow, you want a Straw skull?
Not a Moscow. I've
asked people, I didn't go around these
cities and say, do you know tic-tac-toe?
I mean, what if it didn't
get to a Minsk? Wha what is,
so finish that sentence. How,
how wide is the shadow
of non tictactoe dumb.
If we can establish this
in eastern Russia, maybe,
maybe you could go to Japan and
they wouldn't know how to play it.
I haven't even, I don't know. Well,
it would be interesting just to find out
where tictactoe is elsewhere and where
it isn't. Yeah. Not that I'm
going to do it myself. No, no, no.
It's to be one of these. This could be
one of these crowdsourcing opportunities.
Why is that? Well,
we can ask people to help map it for
us because like what if there are whole
corners of the globe that
are virginal territory.
So you could go to playgrounds and
you could like walk in and say, Hey,
kids wish them come here.
So we decided to test this
proposition. After we talked to Ian,
we put a call on our Facebook page asking
for you people to help us make map.
And we got [inaudible] bosses. Hello.
I am coming to you from
Kwangju, South Korea.
Actually lots in the north of Iran
near the Caspian Sea. Croatia hills,
not in Poland, Istanbul,
Turkey, Christchurch, New
Zealand. I'm here in Seattle,
Washington or Cedric ground.
The Netherlands, Argentina,
Caribbean, Namibia,
Japan, Dublin, Ireland. Gotcha.
In the fall, who's Denmark? Okay.
A typically hot day here in Dubai
and stretches are pretty simple.
Grab a cell phone or whatever you
got that can record. Go out. No,
let's get on with our
business. Take a survey.
So I think we found our first victim.
Who Nice people walking by in the full
show. Miss you. Principal Movie Paul. Oh,
hello sir. Have you heard of
[inaudible] a a game called tic-tac-toe
backhoe. We LMU moving their own doctor.
Who here has ever heard of the game?
Ticktack to tech toe kick tech.
So here are the results, which may
surprise you will go country by country.
Everybody interviewed a lot of people.
So what you will hear is representative
and we'll start with Japan.
Do you know Tic Tac toe? Tic Tac toe?
No. This game? No. No. No.
Japan? No. No. No. Argentina.
No. It doesn't. No.
No. Ireland. No.
Do you know what it is or no one knows
how to play Tic Tac toe? No. Maybe. Yeah.
Yes sir. Nope. No. Switzerland. No.
Turkey. No. Croatia. No
New Zealand pick tags.
Is it a dance? Now it's again.
Have you so you've never played
tic-tac-toe. Heavens no. No.
You're on sir. It is
[inaudible] so amazingly, it seemed
like huge chunks of the globe.
Do not know tic-tac-toe.
Tictactoe hustler could clean
up the key or forget hustling.
Maybe you just want to believe there
are still some blank spots left in the
globe. We'll hear yard,
yes, but just to be safe,
we asked everybody to go out,
not just with their cell phones,
but with a pen and a paper
so that when someone says no,
they could draw them the grid just
to be certain. Let me show you. Okay.
We have x's and we have owes and
things like this, this or this.
So if I am ex and then that a stereotype,
try to stop me and you have to get three
in a row and this is when the answers
change. That's awesome.
Oh, so ex, Huh? Findex.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well you know that, Huh?
Once people saw the grid with the
x's and o's, they were like, oh yeah,
we know that game. Of course,
we just don't call it tic-tac-toe game
has a different name in Turkish. Yes,
in Turkish. It's called peace. All
X, x or x in Serbia, x socks, socks,
socks. Gosh. What's
the name in Peru? Peru.
It's Meechie in South
Korea. What do you call it?
Almost one more homo and in
England, which one is it called?
Goats and crosses, looks and
crawfish knots and crosses,
which is also what they
call it in Ireland.
And we call it noughts and crosses New
Zealand now in Switzerland [inaudible]
it's known. And the French language,
that is what they call it in Polish.
PUCO [inaudible] it's cuco extra jet.
Is everybody in Poland know
how to play this? Yeah.
And to round things out in
Argentina they call it that.
The D in The Netherlands. Both kinds.
And I use them Iran, no corner Croatia.
And in Costa Rica. Gotcha. Gotcha.
Well let's take a little break and look
at our notes. See where we stand so far,
gentlemen, I'm beginning
to get this feeling.
Seven people interviewed seven
new, it had our dream was of glory.
I'll know what take the pill is.
Yeah. We were going to, you know,
we were going to be the Gingiss cons of
tic-tac-toe just may not be supported by
the data.
No. Yeah,
but we got Russia, right?
[inaudible]
well, um, hi, you infringer. Hi,
this is Soren and I work with rob.
I don't know if we have Russia actually,
because as we were conducting our
international tic-tac-toe survey,
I got a note from Ian. It was a, it was
a, it looked like an [inaudible] note.
So I called him up and he told me that
shortly after we talked to him that first
time,
it was maybe even the same day,
he was at a party and
there were some Russians.
And I just thought, okay, let
me just make sure about this.
And I asked and they said, yes,
of course there's tic-tac-toe.
And I said, wow, everybody told
me. And they said, yeah, sure,
everybody knows it. A friend even told
me the name of it, it's Kresky Norske,
which is like processes and zero.
And he said, yeah, it's well known.
And the entire thing fell to the
ground at that point. Um, my,
my dream of Tic Tac
toe conquest, so sorry,
I don't, I'm sorry. I base
this on insufficient data.
And a, I'd say completely
wrong, completely wrong,
because I did encounter, you
know, some people who didn't know,
and this one kid who I really,
I can promise you I just
beat the pants off of, uh,
in tic-tac-toe. He had
no idea, but that was my,
the limit of my contacts
last time. We got
take tax. So we got
[inaudible] tape.
Ian Frazier is the author of
travels in Siberia and Paul,
bunch of wonderful books. For more
information, go to our website,
radiolab.org Oh and before
we go, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you to our international
tic-tac-toe surveyors.
I read it through audio to watch,
actually said RJ [inaudible],
Christina or Vasquez, the hands
target because seen, my name is Mara,
she'll see unreal. This
is Maryanne and Mrs.
Lot by Mr Spanky. Nick Glastonbury.
My name is Humana baseman.
My name is [inaudible]. Mr Guillermo
and my name is Pedram Murphy.
I'm Jad Abumrad and I'm Robert
Krulwich. Thanks for listening.