I don't really know where Tim is,
so we're just going to try am
Jad Abumrad I'm Robert Krulwich,
Radiolab and today we're talking
about truth and facts. Yup.
Facts of the matter. So recently
our producer, Pat Walters and I,
we were trying to get in touch with
a guy, Tim criter. Hello Tim? Nope,
not there. I think if we just shout
very loud, very low up the window.
We wanted to talk to Tim because Tim is
not only is he a wonderful writer and
before that a cartoonist,
he has this essay, uh,
which kind of gets to the heart of a
very different kind of truth and we've
tackled so far and that is,
can you truly know somebody even after
everything you thought you knew turns out
to be wrong. Hello, Tim? Yes. Oh,
there you are. You sound great too. Oh,
we should say this is
a story not about Tim,
but about his friend who he named Skelly,
just to protect his identity. Right?
So let's, let's try,
if it's okay with you,
if we could maybe just talk about Skelly
as if we were just kind of hanging out
at a bar, even though you're
in a tiny booth on the other
beer in this tiny room, that
would be easier. Tell us uh,
how you met this guy. Um, he was
part of a group of friends I made when
I was working at post-collegiate job,
going door to door for
the environment, um,
to knock on doors with clipboards
and get people to donate.
Like vacuum salesman knock
knock kind of thing. Yeah,
you're dropped off by a van in a suburban
neighborhood and I can still faintly
feel the dread of, of having to
knock on your first door the night,
which was always the worst. But you
know like, like being in the army,
it was a bonding experience,
especially because they're knocking on
the doorstep. It's just really, you know,
a few hours a day. Then there is
going out to the bars afterwards,
which became as much a part of the
job for us as, as anything else.
And one of those nights
out drinking with friends.
He got to talking with Skelly. What'd he
look like, by the way? You know, I, I,
he forbade me ever to draw him.
I used to put my friends in my
cartoons all the time and um,
I did that once to him and he
interdicted me from doing that again.
So you don't want to draw him on the
radio though. You know, he's about to, uh,
he had this great mop of
curly hair glasses that were
literally held together by
duct tape. The overall effect
was warmth and intelligence.
But from the beginning he says
basic facts about this guy.
What a little hard to pin down.
It wasn't really clear at first whether
he belonged to our camp on the hippie
young people or whether he
was someone slightly older.
His first life hadn't worked
out. Um, as it turned out,
he was the ladder and he had been a
practicing lawyer and he had quit being a
lawyer for reasons that
remain unknown to me.
I mean, I'm not sure it was
entirely voluntary quitting.
But Tim says at the time he liked
the guy. Yeah. For one thing,
women seem to like him. They
were charmed by him right away.
All my girlfriends always liked
him. And beyond that, you know,
he and I were two of the
readers in the group. Uh,
we each always had a book with us.
So they began to swap books and
as they got to be good friends,
Skelly even showed him his writing. I
still have it somewhere in Longhand,
even beautiful long hand.
He was clearly a sort of kindred spirit.
But then some questions popped up one day,
Skelly told him that he had written a
novel and that it had been accepted for
publication. Tim was like,
wow, I was excited for him.
You probably thought you got published.
That's amazing. I want to do that. Yeah.
So, you know, I kept bugging
him about, well, when's,
when's your book coming out? Skelly would
say, well, you know, in a few months,
and then a few months would
pass. And Scotty would say, well,
they just pushed it back.
It's coming. And you know,
we had a close little group of
friends and like all people on Earth,
we talked about each other
behind each other's backs.
And it may be that someone else sort of
clued me in like, Tim, there's no block
[inaudible].
I mean, maybe he wrote a book,
but it's not being published.
Initially Tim thought, well, there's
probably some truth to it, you know,
even if the truth was only the kind
of truth that's contained in dreams.
But then there were other stories.
One of his stories was about having been
married briefly in France and having a
daughter over there and there was a time,
at least one time when he was on vacation
from the environmental canvas and he
supposedly,
it was going to be in France visiting
his daughter who lived with her, uh,
maternal grandparents there.
And our boss saw him walking on Charles
Street in Baltimore during that time.
Obviously he was not in France
and they were never like, ah,
dude, someone saw you in Baltimore
where you really in France? No,
we didn't say that. And
you know, I, I've met,
I mean I've spent,
I've logged a lot of time hanging out in
bars and you do meet pathological liars
in that line of work.
Um, and, and you know,
I'm always duly impressed by their
stories when I first hear them until they
pile up and they've, they're always
able to one up your story, you know,
they've always met someone
more famous than you,
something more tragic has
always happened to them.
And then they start to
seem creepy and repellent.
And all I can say is he
didn't feel that way.
He just seemed like a really good guy
who happened to lie more than most
[inaudible].
In any case, after they
left the canvasing job,
they both stayed in Baltimore
and the state close.
We frequently ended up crashing
on the same floors together,
closed down the bars together every
night they'd take road trips together,
blasting classic rock.
He loved LED's up on.
And after a while those stories,
like I've published a novel or
I have a daughter in France,
we didn't hear that stuff anymore.
Our theory is that he did not expect that
we would end up being friends for the
next 20 years and he would
have to maintain these stories.
And you know,
we liked the guy so much that would have
been unthinkably mean spirited to bring
this stuff up. So we just sort
of pretended we'd never heard it.
And he says they kept themselves from
asking too many questions like, yeah,
they knew he had a job at the
opera house, you know, fundraising.
But he was always broke, always
hitting them up for money. And he was,
he was,
they wonder why was he
always house-sitting and
spending the night at the
library. You just never
knew. You did have to.
You did have to triangulate from, from
the few facts available and you know,
in a way it was fun.
It was fun to speculate about and fun to
tease him about. Only behind his back.
Of course, for example,
Tim told us about one time he and his
friend nick were up at their cabin near
the Chesapeake Bay, which is
about an hour outside Baltimore.
And we had had a lovely
afternoon eating oysters,
drinking beers overlooking the bay.
And we're supposed to drive to a
train station about 20 minutes,
half an hour away to pick Skelly up. Uh,
he's gonna take the train up there
and join us and so break away from our
pleasant setup on the water and we'd
drive down to the train station to pick
them up. The train comes and
goes, he's not on it. Uh,
and we're both a little peeved at having
been torn away from our afternoon to
come get him only to be stood
up at the train station. So my,
my friend checks his cell phone
to see if maybe there's a message.
And indeed there is and the
message goes like this, hey guys,
this is Skelly. Um, I missed
the train. First of all,
there's the background noises of what
is clearly a bar glasses clinking the TV
on unmistakably the mount
royal tavern, a alone oil.
We just knew. And he says, so I'm,
I'm really sorry about this,
but I was in a meeting that ran a
little longer than I expected and
I tried to catch it, but I was
like three minutes too late,
but I checked and there's
another train seven 20,
it gets in seven 45 we'll
definitely be on that one.
So hopefully you all get this message
and be there to meet me. Uh, okay. Again,
sorry about that. Hope I'll see you soon.
And then there's 30 or 45 seconds of him
fumbling to figure out how to hang up
this borrowed cell phone throughout,
which we can hear the sounds of
the bar clearly in the background.
And I listened to this message and I just
smiled and shook my head and handed it
speechless. Lee to my friend. Nick,
do you give any sense of what's,
when you're not being told something,
do you have any feeling for what you're
not being told or you just think it's
just silly details? No,
you know, I don't, it was,
he was just a very guy
[inaudible].
Um, and we got the sense that, I
mean he told me once, you know,
the less people know about
you, the better off you are.
[inaudible]
I mean,
we weren't supposed to know for a long
time that he lived at home with his
mother. Um, you know,
which is not unheard of,
but an embarrassing thing
when you're a grown man.
And it became really obvious that he did,
cause if you called his house
sometime you got his mother. Um,
and he had a complex
cover story about how, oh,
well if the phone rang
enough times at his house,
it was forwarded to his mother's
to pick up, which, you know,
I had never heard of that.
I didn't know the phone company
and offered that service. So,
you know, we knew the deal,
but we weren't going to challenge him
on it because it's so clearly with
something he was embarrassed
about and eager to conceal.
[inaudible]
I think he probably saw himself and was
worried that others would see him as,
as you know, marginal or
pathetic or loser. And you know,
we didn't see him that
way. We love the guy.
It was just one of us, you know,
there are conditions that
come with every friendship.
People are weird and most of the people
who are really worth being friends with
are weird.
And you learn to accept that there are
unspoken rules in certain friendships.
[inaudible]
until the day comes when the
rules don't apply anymore.
[inaudible]
fast forward a few years,
Tim has moved to New York.
Skelly still is in Baltimore with his,
well his mother had died but he
was living in the same house.
I still saw him pretty often.
He'd take the train up and we get
some beers and some chicken wings.
And one day I got a phone call from a
friend of mine and he sounded very badly
shaken.
Tim's friends said that he'd been worried
about Skelly cause he hadn't heard
from him for a while.
And then he called work and it turned
out he hadn't been there and he knew
something was wrong. So he
went to his house. And um,
you know, I think he was able to get
the door open enough to see inside.
And uh, he called in him
and he heard nothing.
And he forced his way in and
found him lying on the floor dead.
The coroner ruled that that
death was drug related.
So I went back to
Baltimore right away, um,
because I assumed there would be
a, a memorial service and so on.
And for a couple of days,
nothing happened at all because
he had kept his life so thoroughly
compartmentalized that no one knew
how to get in touch with his family.
Although at the last minute,
who, the day before his funeral,
we got in touch with his extended family
and they were able to send some people
up just before they arrived.
It occurred to Tim, well,
maybe we should go through his house,
you know, and just clean up and you know,
find out if there's anything
there that we should, you know,
disappear before his family shows up.
And we were talking to the guy who
first found him and he said, yeah,
well here's the thing. He told them, you
guys, you can go back into that house,
but I'm, I'm not going back
in there. He had warned us,
but as soon as we stepped
in, it was still shocking.
Terrible.
What'd you see when you walked in?
Um,
there are aspects about that that I
will never tell you or anyone else.
But suffice to say that
as soon as you walked in,
you could tell that someone had
ceased living like a human being.
I mean, there were heaps of things heaps
and he'd stop throwing things
out. There wasn't electricity,
there wasn't working
plumbing, no plumbing at all.
No, no, I don't think so.
[inaudible]
and words are gonna fail
me here. I mean, the,
the simplest way to say it would be
to say it was clearly a place where an
insane person that lived for
someone who is mentally ill,
ed left. Um,
I dunno if that's what to call it because
most people who are mentally ill don't
know to conceal their mental illness.
He was just a, a very gentle,
decent, kindhearted guy.
But something horrible had happened. Um,
but on some level he had,
he'd understood that. I mean,
it was a secret that he was keeping
[inaudible] and he kept it locked inside
that house.
Hmm.
And I think we were all appalled to
realize that something had been so
drastically wrong with him all this time.
And the single most upsetting
aspect of it was imagining how
utterly alone he must've
felt himself to be.
[inaudible].
Did you ever have moments of
feeling guilt like I should have,
I should have gotten into that place.
I shouldn't have no.
That I don't think there is anything
that anyone could have done for him.
I mean, he, uh,
he had so clearly determined not to
let people in to that chamber of his,
his life. And,
and the other thing is that he was
so convincing in his dissembling.
I mean, we really didn't think
there was anything seriously wrong.
Yeah.
He was his best and most decent and
sanest self when he was in our company.
But you didn't know so much about him.
[inaudible] and I guess I just in,
in light of that, I
wonder what it means to,
to know someone or what it, who
exactly it was that you think you knew.
Yeah. Well. Um, you know,
the only people I knew of whoever
got mad at him for telling,
uh, what they would've
called lies were women.
I mean he was a guy so he was not above
trying to impress girls and you know,
the,
the things he was trying to impress
them with where his novel is storied
history.
And often when they found out that those
things were not strictly speaking true,
they felt lied to and betrayed and
none of his friends ever felt
that way. And I always felt that
perhaps is patronizing or nasty of me,
but I always felt that what those girls
were really mad about was that they
believed him, they'd fallen for it.
But in a sense you and your
friends fell for something too?
Well, I dunno.
I mean what I would say we fell for was
the thousands of hours we spent in that
guy's company,
which seems to me like a more direct and
reliable form of knowing than hearing
facts either made up or real.
I mean there was a [inaudible]
day one, um,
Skelly and I drove up to my cabin to
check on the place cause there had been a
blizzard, uh,
and there is a grove of bamboo trees
there and the weight of all the snow had
bent them over the driveway so that
they formed a kind of continuous arch.
And we parked and we walked down through
that arcade and we would tug on every
bamboo tree and it would shake the snow
off and it would suddenly spooling up
into the air and fling it's load
of snow 50 feet into the sky.
We did that with every tree walking all
the way down the driveway and it was
[inaudible]
so beautiful and so much fun
that we cracked up like boys.
And I'm the only one
who remembers that. Now
I don't really know where Tim is. So
we're just going to try am Jab. I'm Rod.
Hi, I'm Robert Krulwich, Radiolab and
today we're talking about truth and facts.
Yup. Facts of the matter. So recently
our producer, Pat Walters and I,
we were trying to get in touch with
a guy, Tim Kreider. Hello Tim? Nope.
Right there. I think if we just shout
very loudly, like out the window,
we wanted to talk to Tim because Tim
is not only is he a wonderful writer,
and before that a
cartoonist has this essay,
which kind of gets to the heart of a
very different kind of truth and we've
tackled so far, and that is,
can you truly know somebody even after
everything you thought you knew turns out
to be wrong.
Hello, Tim? Yes.
Oh, there you are. You sound
great too. Oh, we should say,
this is a story not about Tim, but
about his friend who he named Skelly,
just to protect his identity. Right? So
let's, let's try, if it's okay with you,
if we could maybe just talk about Skelly
as if we were just kind of hanging out
at a bar, even though you're in it.