Ruby wax is a content writer and
performer who has lately become known as
a campaigner on mental health issues and
a champion of mindfulness born in
Illinois,
the only child of refugees.
Ruby studied psychology at Berkeley.
They say it right.
Barkley,
and moved to Britain in 1977 where she
wrote for shows such as not the 9:00
news,
girls on pop with doing French and
Saunders.
Saunders and Tracy Omen.
In 2012,
she completed a master's degree in
mindfulness based cognitive therapy,
Oxford,
and in 2014 was appointed an ob for
services to mental health.
Imagine that her recent books include
the number one best seller,
saying new world taming the mind and a
mindfulness guide for the frazzled.
Her new book,
how to be human.
The manual is released in January.
She's been married since [inaudible] 98
88 to her third husband and has three
children.
Thanks for coming.
I could have just listened to you all
day thinking I'd like to meet that one.
She sounds like a terrific human being.
Have much cute.
So Ruby,
how.
What is it that made you transition from
an entertainment based life to one,
based on the psychology,
the spirit therapy,
whatever this is that you're doing now?
What's,
what inspired you?
Well,
I uh,
I went to Berkeley when I was young.
That's how you say it,
but Berkeley and I never finished
because I hitchhike through Europe.
I decided what were you doing in the
first place?
I was doing psychology but I never
finished and I just ended up hitchhiking
one day and I have nightmares to this
day what my locker combination is
because I left all my books there.
So to this day I'm still racking my
brains there.
I am the illusion,
they're still there.
So I wanted to come to Europe to get
away from my parents a and B.
I wanted,
this is pathetic.
A classical actress with no talent.
None,
Zilch.
I mean since high school,
that was like 6,000
people in my school.
I was the only one,
not in the show.
6,000
were in Hello Dolly.
I settled.
I mean I was in production.
It was a full load.
Him staring at 5,999
people in Hello Dolly.
Anyway,
fuck them all.
Can you say that?
My whole life has been,
you know,
where are they now?
And I've tracked them.
Vengeance against Berkeley.
No,
against every township high school.
Then I went to Berkeley to study
psychology and then I thought I'm going
to come to England and become a
classical actress if you knew how
delusional that was.
So I used to watch.
Goes on top.
I liked it.
You were one that was much later.
I really.
Yeah.
Know Evanston was when I was 17.
Then Berkeley was 18,
19 mangoes on top girls on top of way
later.
Way like a century.
Know about.
Um,
I was 17 girls on top.
I was.
No,
I was 30.
Yeah.
That was kind of a gap.
So you knew when you went in
early life in academia that you were
interested in psychology then it seems
like you pursuit some external glamorous
goal and then in Middle East Age,
isn't it?
You're divided between a food for the
brain,
which isn't really on your agenda when
you're 20 and yet a narcissism was
always nagging away.
I mean,
now that I know how my father got out of
Europe,
I understand why I have this insatiable
thirst for things that are impossible,
you know,
because they said he'll never get out.
And now I have this drive to get things
that people say it's impossible,
but I had no English accent.
I had no talent.
That's a tough one.
So I went to Europe.
I just hitchhiked.
I sort of sold some marijuana to get the
plane ticket.
Can I say that?
Yes.
None of these will be handed to the
authorities.
Ruby Berkeley.
So they had.
Anyway,
I sold that and some girl scout cookies.
Got to Europe.
I found myself an acting teacher.
Finally,
it's a longer story.
Um,
I hitchhiked with somebody from the cast
of hair.
This is sort of sad because that was my
first taste of Bohemia anarchism and uh,
about what you feel that it is somewhat
telling that it was a prepackaged and
stage version of Bohemia that you are
Lloyd yourself.
Well,
I was,
yeah,
I stopped him.
So then,
um,
I went with this guy through Europe and
ended up in Israel where I found
somebody to teach me acting.
Then I came back to London,
lived in a bedsit for two years in
audition for probably rod is seven times
and was rejected each time because it
was,
they said one of the most grotesque
auditions they'd ever seen.
She Hunt.
I ferocious drive for success and for
attention I read,
I'm saying new world.
It was a bit in there where you talked
about being in like a like,
you know,
so we know we're famed,
sort of can lead to either it's a
continued upward trajectory or it can
become sort of grimly cataclysmic.
And your anecdote about that shark tank
show that you,
a participant in saying that you know,
that there was a sort of an attractive
woman who was in bikinis,
was the central focus of celebrity shark
tank or whatever.
It was a shock celebrity shark bait shop
that marked the end of my career.
So I like to pick that scab liked it a
lot.
Yeah,
I'm not.
So it was always when it was already,
like Korea was
really fading away,
you know,
there's signs because you ride on that
surf and people give you attention and
you get,
you know,
the fantastic infantilizes you this kind
of career,
you know,
that's why you can't get,
it's so hard to wean off the mother
breast of fame.
And so,
um,
then the car,
you know,
I started getting desperate and they
take the nipple away and said,
oh,
I'll do anything.
Please document my gallbladder
operation.
So they said,
here's something even worse,
getting a shark tank with Richard and
grant and we'll film right?
And it marks the end of my career is
peculiar,
actually receive enriched.
He grown up,
I would say very,
very talented,
bright,
brilliant people,
but the machinery of celebrity will
ultimately deposit you in a shark tank.
So what was it off of them?
The obvious that was particularly
revealing about that.
What,
what was the nature of that revelation
of knowing that we were,
it's over,
this is it,
it's over.
But in the first few years of being
ejected from the central,
the central spotlight is you think,
oh well this is just temporary.
Surely they'll have me back.
But there's telltale signs,
like when I was asked to cut the ribbon
at Costco's for the Qa,
Costa coffee at terminal three,
that's another sign that things aren't
going well.
So Richard and I were joking saying how
awful this show was and really would end
our careers.
And then it did.
It did kind of end around then and they
had a really beautiful babe from
holyoke's,
you know,
who was asked to take her top off to
practice getting into a shark tank.
So they'd say to Richard and I,
you aren't needed it.
Most days we weren't needed.
So Richard and I both bought houses in
Cape Town,
which I still have because we were so
bored in.
The rand was really bad.
So you could buy one for about 10 bucks.
So Richard and I went with a camera
following us because they always liked
to pretend,
Ooh,
this is reality.
We both bought houses and on day 75,
the babe with the breasts had refused to
get in with the sharks.
They had been everyday training or right
making or stand in a frozen freezer to
check that she could take the cold with
no top on imagine.
And she'd say,
do you think I'm being exploded to us?
We go,
no.
A.
Anyway,
the last day she refused to get into.
They said,
get the old ones in here.
Richard and I are now crammed into these
rubber things.
I'm actually,
um,
I've actually got cystitis.
I don't know if you could say that,
but that's not a good thing to go into
shark tank with.
So they drop us in and we're not in a
tank and not in a cage like they usually
do for special occasion.
They put us in a tube,
a see through tube,
which means you're in the aquarium and
the sharks watching and he's magnified.
So he comes at us.
I pissed myself.
So that urine came out of my collar and
then Richard and I started laughing
beyond and they dubbed in screams.
So it ends with,
it looks like Richard and I are sitting
in the bottom of a test tube and I
always say I'm the sharks just swam by
looking for a list celebrity.
Anyway,
that was pretty bloody brilliant
actually.
I know it does sound good now,
but they cut a lot out.
So it was just basically tits,
tits,
Richmond and I screaming and some urine
coming in and coming out of her neck
because credible image.
But like,
so obviously though all she told the
story in a very humorous way,
it's painful.
Agonizing.
So what happened to you mentally and
spiritually that made you want to stop?
Well,
you know,
I had a lot more life before and nothing
sadder than an old celebrity.
Nothing,
you know,
it used to be Panto was the pits.
Now it's one of those reality shows
where you eat a cockroach.
So I thought this ain't happening,
you know,
and people saying,
weren't you?
And I go,
was I who,
you know,
it was never me.
Anyway.
So I thought jumped now jumped before
the party.
The party's over,
you know,
before,
before you're not invited anymore.
So I,
I jumped right out and went to school to
get a degree in psychotherapy,
which was.
People let you know,
drop me and laughed and said,
oh,
it's psychotherapist,
but I just needed something.
I knew I wasn't going to be a
psychotherapist,
but you got me a new group of friends.
I had to wean myself like coming off of
drugs off,
you know,
getting on the tube and nobody going,
oh fuck,
I know who you are now.
I go,
do you know who I am?
And they go,
fuck no,
buy a ticket.
Like everybody else,
you know,
that one.
The arrogance had to be squeezed out
like sweat.
And then eventually I had my new
friends,
I went,
I studied,
you know,
young,
and then I'd study winnicott and then
I'd studied bowlby and I got really,
you know,
I thought this is great.
Tell me about,
did it feel like you were picking up
something that you would describe?
Brain started getting a honed again,
you know,
it started to come to life and then,
um,
and then I had to,
then I had a serious breakdown in my
third year.
That's when everything crumbled.
And I think it like before you invent,
reinvent yourself,
there has to be a death.
I always think of the Phoenix,
you know,
before he rises,
it was death,
you know,
that everything shuts down all your,
everything that was your reality is
taken away.
There's just nothing.
And then some of us,
and I always love this expression,
this is where you either turned into
wine or vinegar,
which coincidentally young did say.
So I started to,
um,
I've,
it was in that institution a long time.
Will Your institution.
Yeah.
And it was so bad that I.
Oh,
this is tragic.
At one point the BBC threw me another
bone and I did a show for a.
It was a BBC Internet,
right?
Not like it is now.
Sex seems like a show called Ruby's room
or something that three people would
hear.
It was about mental illness.
So,
uh,
every week,
three per a person would come to my
house that was the idea with a different
pathology,
so I'd have schizophrenia or,
um,
physical dysmorphia or bipolar,
and then I take them in a way to have
tea and they'd sit with my cat and my
kids would come in and then I,
because I knew how to interview them
because they're my people.
Then at the very end it would say,
here's the symptoms and here's what you
can do about it.
Which I thought was really responsible
and the show was sometimes hilarious by
this time I was,
I couldn't get on tv,
but that was a great show even if you
caught me out.
So again,
I don't want to get better because it
was a blessing that I got kicked out
now.
Um,
and they'd come over every week and this
is how bad it was when I first got the
job,
my first guest was a depressive and I
had 10 shows to go.
So I was in the institution.
Ed had to get me pick me up from the
pick me up from the institution.
I've I put lipstick on.
Everybody in the institution applauded
and said that was so brave.
Imagine you know that's from the cream
of the crop.
I went home.
I'm sitting with a depressive and I'm
from an institution dripping,
dripping in sweat and trying to pretend
you were who you used to be and the
depressed person is looking at me going,
man,
you are more fucked than I am.
Of course nobody can see when you're
mentally ill.
So I did this shaking slightly,
but they think,
oh,
she's being funny.
Finished the interview and then was
taken back to the institution.
So my first show clinically.
What type of mental illness were you
suffering from an the Sam?
I will always have its clinical
depression,
depression.
I don't get up.
It's vanilla depression.
It's not the up and down.
So that was a long time in there and I
tried to.
I had regions.
They said you have to leave because
you're not finishing.
So everything was taken and then
gradually when I came out and that was a
bad time,
you know,
I'd sit for weeks on end in a chair.
Did you ever get this where you'd look
at the shower and think,
oh man,
I had some day.
I hope I can get into that again because
it's not feasible that you could ever
take a shower.
It's,
it's,
it's too confusing.
So the nurse would come and hold my hand
and then she finally take me to the
shower after a month and then eventually
she got me to the door and then
eventually she took me to the park and
so I was saved.
So you were experiencing the,
the despair and that despair fools like
her sort of an absence of any.
Anything,
live force,
any energy.
What have you learned about psychology
or neurology?
These helpful to you in understanding
your own personal experience with regard
to it's an extremist?
Yeah.
Well,
to study the brain is such a relief to
understand the pathology of it because
then you think it's not my imagination
because in everybody looks is feeling
that they're making it up.
Come on,
Mike.
Ruby.
Uh,
everybody thinks they're making it up.
I mean that,
that's that.
So the disease isn't necessarily
depression.
It's shame.
That's what we all suffer from it.
It's like saying to somebody with
Alzheimer's,
Oh,
come on,
you remember where the try harder.
Just think,
okay,
where is it now I've taken it again.
I swallowed it.
Go.
That is cruel.
So let's say to understand it,
you're neurologically.
Same thing as let's,
it's a brain.
I find it even
as a person that sort of personally
knows about mental illness and knows a
lot of people,
I still sort of defined mental illness,
annoying because the name.
Because your brain is an organ.
Do you know what I mean?
If you flipped yourself upside down,
would you call your feet mental illness?
It's a.
do you know what I'm saying?
Oh,
you look physically well.
What the fuck does it mean?
Mental,
mental is physical.
It's an,
it's an Oregon.
It's the only one that when it breaks
down,
you don't get any sympathy cards and yet
it runs everything.
So the ignorance of the world is
astonishing.
Why do you imagine or what do you think
that is?
Um,
there's always been a stigma,
so I'm,
you know,
there's always been women at 55 lose
their jobs.
I'm not naive,
you know,
I,
I'm not one that goes,
it's not fair.
It was always a taboo,
you know,
because people may think they are by the
grace of God,
go,
I,
you know,
it's only a hundred years ago.
I think we were burned at the stake,
so it,
but it will leave,
you know,
the gay movement suddenly now
homosexuals are everywhere in a minute.
The whole gay thing will change again.
It'll be,
that'll be the last taboo.
But where we are now is still in an era
of shame
and I'm not,
you know,
I'm not too,
it's not fair.
That's the way it is.
If you were to examine the template of a
bigotry against a sort of an inverted
comments,
minority social groups such as
homosexuals,
it's because of the sort of,
the costing of the dominant class is
shadow into those groups.
You sort of talking about James Baldwins
analysis of the category of Negro is
because it bears the shadow of the white
dominant class,
so if it is in terms of attempting to
follow the,
that idea that it's a maligned and
outcast group and it's not something
that's essential.
Because when I think about mental
illness,
I think,
well perhaps it's because if perception
itself is warped,
you can't.
There's nothing that you can trust.
There's nothing tangible there.
And when a human being looks the same as
they always look,
but they're behaving differently.
I find it very,
very.
I find it frightening when other people
are in the exhibit in mental illness.
Um,
but from a sort of from a just because
it's not tangible.
And yet,
you know,
my professor said,
I'm not bitching again,
had a bill gates put the money into
mental health instead of malaria.
We would know what it is.
You would be able to define depression
just the way you can down to find
cancer.
And that's only because it had a lot of
money thrown at it.
Not because it's some mystical,
you know,
it's serial disease.
It's just that nobody threw the money
in.
It's as simple as that.
So you think no matter how seemingly a
theorial something might be,
it is on some level mechanical on like
whether it's consciousness,
so consciousness a,
d,
a,
O w.
we're going to continue.
I'm going to bash us 15 minutes every 15
minutes.
Careful what I said about consciousness.
So the mechanics consciousness.
There's a whole nother ballpark,
but disease,
you know,
the way we can look and see how cancer
is formed.
Sure it wasn't possible,
you know,
a thousand years ago.
Now it is.
Everything is.
It's a disease that's mechanical.
Consciousness is a whole different ball.
Park consciousness,
the relationship between consciousness
and presumably the brain is integral a,
the capacity to understand the brain can
understand disease.
It's a,
you know,
it's a technical glitch,
but it can that the consciousnesses,
what the hell is that we just don't
know,
but like,
but is there,
but given the perspective and
consciousness are possibly synonymous.
Then the understanding of mental illness
and consciousness are,
I think integrated,
but that there is a relationship between
mental illness and the nature of a
person's consciousness because it's your
consciousness that is becoming warped,
isn't it?
At least that's what's manifestly
happening,
but we don't know what consciousness is.
Louis Wolpert says,
I'm sadnesses to depression where the
tumor is to cancer.
Meaning that's.
God said.
It is something.
There's something physiologically not.
It's not.
It's a tumor.
That's what it is.
Consciousness is a much bigger ballpark.
It,
um,
I know what you mean is that if you have
a malignancy in your,
in your brain,
abby,
it's gonna Affect your thinking.
But you know,
there are people,
if you know,
I love the man who thought his wife was
a hat.
You know,
all those extreme things that I think I
even put in my book,
people who assumed that their arms are
real,
you know,
are,
are the,
are their enemy.
And so what's that illness?
I have it written down.
They chopped their limbs off other
people,
you know,
see their mother and they see it that
she's a stranger or they see their left
hand and it looks like it's trying to
kill them.
Those are brain diseases.
They can easily be marked as to what's
missing.
What's their consciousness is a,
of course it,
it,
um,
it inflicts itself on how the person
thinks,
of course,
but they're still conscious.
They still,
the moment they wake up in the morning,
however,
you know,
the way we express ourselves as a teeny,
teeny grain of sand on a,
you know,
an iceberg,
the size of Mars.
So how you think and how you talk has
nothing to do with,
you know,
it's a teeny bit of consciousness
because consciousness is everything.
You know,
it's your heart rushing through its
proteins being made.
It's,
we don't even know,
you know,
get,
get somebody who's in physics in here
and I'm,
I'm at his feet with the relationship
between wellness,
mental wellness and mindfulness that
you've been exploring really in all
three of these books.
It seems to me that it's using tools
that have been available for a long,
long time,
Millenia primarily through a theological
means and
the,
these are predicated mostly on the idea
of cleansing the consciousness,
having a relationship with an aspect of
yourself that's not mechanical,
that is not the body is not the brain.
So what,
given that your latest book is a monk
and a neuroscientist and you exploring
mindfulness,
exploring wellbeing,
exploring being a human being.
Yeah,
it's not.
The monk is obviously from the mindful
school,
did neuro scientist is very much,
um,
how,
what addiction is,
how the future works with how evolution,
you know,
affected us,
that,
you know,
how we actually do evolve,
um,
how,
how relationships are formed.
He comes from the very mechanical side
and the other one is the mind and most
of them are married.
They completely agree on every front.
So that's to me really reassuring.
Also,
they're funny.
They have a good sense of humor.
Um,
but to take mindfulness,
mindfulness was made simple,
simple simply for the west by Jon Kabat
Zinn who was dealing with people in
pain.
It wasn't for any mystical experience
and then my professor,
Mark Williams started to use mindfulness
for psychological reasons for people
with depression,
so they're using some ancient wisdom as
young did to everybody borrows and they
put it all in using MRI scanning,
which is only,
I don't know,
it's not that old and they obviously did
a lot of research and it was
mindfulness.
It had the best results.
It wasn't like somebody showed up with a
Bindi and decided,
I'm going to push this one because you
know there's a market in it.
They literally did experiments on the
works and cognitive and mindfulness had
the best results,
but that doesn't mean for everybody.
I mean,
know what's good for me is going to kill
you.
Do you know what I mean?
They say jogging is good.
Well,
the guy got,
the guy dropped dead.
Who'd invented it?
So we.
Part of mindfulness is understanding
where's your tipping point,
how much you know,
how much is good for you,
and when does it tip into sickness?
When is it a habit?
When does it go into addiction?
When am I working in my flow and when
have I tip and now I'm going to burn out
my immune system.
That's what mindfulness is good for,
is that you can check your internal
temperature.
I can't get into the Buddhist stuff.
Tell us what mindfulness in your
understanding of it and how you practice
it means just for people listening to
this.
Well,
I don't do the woo woo stuff.
You know,
that that was not my,
what was appealing.
Uh,
I could give you the scientific reason
which really turns me on how to do it,
how to do it is.
But I like what happens in your brain
when you do do it,
because if I explained to sit up and
said,
will you lie down?
And then you get up and then you lie
down and you get up.
I've got to show you my six pack for you
to actually go,
oh,
I get it.
So if I say,
this is what you do,
you sit down.
I have to explain what the effects are
in your brain.
So when you sit and you have a focus,
when you take your mind to focus,
let me just say,
should I do my spiel?
Usually we're in a high state anxiety.
That's the culture we've created.
You know,
50 years ago it wasn't so bad.
Now distraction is our middle name,
so that means there's a part of our
brain that's primitive called the
Amygdala and its aroused when we feel
threatened and that's what the court is
all out.
Okay?
We used it with dinosaurs or whoever the
enemy was.
As soon as the incident was over,
we got calm again.
Okay?
The problem is it never shuts down and
that's why were so many people are
burning out.
Kids are cutting.
That's the situation is that we're
flowing cortisol the whole time.
That's all it is.
And it leads to every problem.
We have physical ones too,
so stop thinking mental.
Too Much Cortisol Burns causes cancer,
diabetes to infertility,
obesity,
all the problems are because of the
cortisol.
But if you start to focus on one of your
senses because of the cortisol or you
could send me,
those are the conditions that create
causal,
like the cortisone is a,
what's happening everyone one level,
but like also what really needs to
change the conditions of created
conditions that creative,
but because we aren't really thinking,
you know,
not any more,
we're more at the mercy of technology.
Yeah.
Nobody's,
everyone's going,
oh,
let's shut technology down.
What we put it there.
That is our evolution.
You know,
we used to um,
evolve to adapt to climate.
Now we adapt to culture.
It is our culture,
but we don't have the genetic variants
to deal with it.
So now they're having to bring in things
like mindfulness and they'll be in a few
years,
there'll be mental fitbit's a bet you to
be able to test your own cortisol
because left to our own devices in this
world,
addictions out the window,
you know,
I mean at its height,
obesity,
the whole thing.
I mean,
we know what the situation is,
but the result is you.
Gosh,
Cortisol.
So the thing with mindfulness,
when you focus on a sentence,
just go with me on this.
The immediately there are,
you're not thinking anymore,
you're focused on a sense.
So the Amygdala goes deactivates and
this other part called the insula.
I'm making it simple.
Activates,
okay?
Each time you do an exercise where you
watch your mind gambling,
then you focus on a sense it deactivates
the other one activates and the more you
do it,
just like a sit up that insulin gets
buffed like a muscle so that when the
shit hits the fan and you get really
stressed,
it's easier to pull to a focus because
you've got,
you know,
you've done the workout.
And then that,
that,
those voices going,
this is shit,
I'm an asshole.
Why am I depressed?
Nobody else's depressed.
It's quieter.
What sense do you use?
I usually follow my breathing and the
thing is it's portable,
so I don't have to sit on a gluten free
cushion if I'm on the taxi here.
Um,
you know,
rather than see,
they've actually said that obviously
they do scans on people mind wandering.
It turns out that mind wandering makes
us really miserable and also you're,
you're,
you're missing three,
four year life.
You can't,
you can't.
And ordinarily a out of five thoughts
for a negative.
That's just human.
Our proclivity as humans,
and again,
it was for good reason because if we
didn't think negatively,
we would have been eating,
so we always have to be on our toes.
Anyway.
The thing with mindfulness is virtually
you,
you get this,
it's a lion and not a Bush better not to
sing a Disney too,
because chances are you wouldn't be here
in the evolution stakes these days.
Yeah.
How does.
I can see how that works.
Anyway,
I'm jumping around,
but the point is,
is that I met.
I can lose my temper like anybody and
rage is still my drug of choice,
but the,
I can get the cortisol down quicker so
it doesn't give me the heart attack.
How does it work in practice?
Then thought I'll get up in the morning
and to me it's a new habit like brushing
my teeth.
I tried to do it at home,
but all I do is track my breathing.
That doesn't mean there's no thoughts.
People get this wrong.
The only time there's no thoughts is
when you're dead.
That's it.
So you watch the shit coming through.
You know,
the,
you're an idiot every but oh God,
I got and Russell brand.
He's such a genius.
I'm such a moron.
Why did I even do this?
I didn't write this show.
Oh my God,
I'm bluffing.
Everybody's going to get,
you know,
the usual.
Oh,
don't forget to get a toaster.
The toaster.
It has to got to be fixed and you need
more tips.
Don't corn,
Russell.
Show get some cue tips was why wasn't I
a ballerina?
What did my mother,
okay,
this could go on forever.
So they're going,
but because I'm used to watching them,
you know what I'm used to watching.
They're more like a radio in another
room.
I sort of expect them and go,
oh yeah,
that's tracked number 42 there.
Strack number 77.
Of course you admire Russell.
That doesn't mean you're an idiot.
Just let it go.
Let it go through.
Yeah,
but you are still a little bit of an
idiot and he's looking at you like
you're.
You know what I mean?
All that.
So I sort of.
The minute you can watch your thoughts,
you're not a slave to them and some will
be true.
Maybe you don't like me,
but the point is I didn't waste my
energy thinking about it.
If you're an asshole,
then I'm an asshole.
Do you know what I mean?
Whereas before,
and this is where the cognitive thinking
comes in,
you get caught in a habit.
I really thought I was the stooge that
everybody thought I was an idiot and I
can blame it on my parents.
You can blame it on whatever you want to
go on and on about it.
Life is short,
so instead of that,
when I get my normal records,
I can kind of.
If you go to a,
if the minute you go to a sense thinking
lowers your listen,
you listen,
or you could,
you could,
you could focus on some things.
You could use any sensory information.
You could use me re-designated attention
Arab's used those beads.
You know,
if you,
if you focus on the sense of the beats,
it's a very smart thing.
If you're,
that means that there's part of your
body that's not involved in the
thinking.
It's,
you know,
so of course the thinking comes through,
but you're,
you're,
you're laying back a little bit.
So you're going,
oh,
I see what I'm thinking.
It's not necessarily true.
Now let's rethink.
Maybe Russell actually likes you.
Let's just break the habit.
He adores me.
Now what interests me is how many of
these men in this particular technique,
mindfulness east,
found in
theology now like I'm sort of aware like
anybody,
that there is much in a religion in
scripture that is sort of of its time
and is used to underwrite bigotry,
power and establishment.
But why?
Why,
when I become fascinated is when in
theology there are techniques that are
effective in helping us to moderate
control our consciousness and improve
our lives,
which they cannot possibly have had
access to the which in their case can't
have been underwritten by the technology
that is currently being examined with.
So I think,
how do they know in the vader's that
this is going to work?
How do they know?
I don't know.
It's fascinating though,
Huh?
I know they knew that they knew,
but they were uh,
you know,
somebody went bingo.
But the thing is they've also put nuns
in a scanner and the very fact that they
pray also lowers the Amygdala.
Amazing.
So I'm really 30 minutes.
There are,
you know,
there are techniques that are you
feeling okay,
can I get some key tips?
Can Get qtip told me it'll be gone.
It'll be moisturizer.
Don't you worry there'll be something to
replace.
The key tips
are constant morphing need in your
consciousness.
I have this to this thing you say about
three quarters of your time.
This is that my inability to be present,
particularly in pleasant situations
really troubles me.
I've,
I am a,
I need intensity in my life.
You know,
I had a recent,
had an experience where I hung out with
two men I didn't know well,
separate occasions on the same day,
the first part of the day.
Very sort of a lighthearted,
lovely occasion.
And I sort of thought,
why are you not fully present for this
while you were observing this later on
in the thousand situation was quite
intense,
but I was there,
you know,
I felt sort of somewhat threatened,
not entirely safe,
but I was very,
very present.
Something in my makeup means that I pay
more attention when I'm.
No,
no,
no.
See,
that's only because the neuroscientist
was so hip on this stuff.
I would ask questions of the monk,
of the neuroscientists and this is
something he,
he makes me feel better that you're not
the only one if we,
um,
whenever we're focused on anger or you
know,
the negatives,
that's sort of in a way us at our best,
you know,
we were built for danger.
So with this kind of when there's
nothing to think about,
we really like it were,
like you said in your book,
we're all addicts to something,
you know,
it's now it's a lot of thought,
I think I have to have sex.
I think I have to have q tips.
I think I have to.
It's just the chase.
The chase is much easier when there's
something fearful or Europe against the
wall.
It's just like a,
an the animal lurks within us.
So yeah,
it's almost like a chemical stream
that's internally moving that we
subsequently narrativize,
but that's why once the q tips are
achieved,
the moisturizer will be required because
the chemical in both continuous.
What's so interesting
is that we feel the emotion first.
Like I'll feel to drive and they put
scanners on people.
I'll feel it.
And then two seconds later I'll think
it.
So your thoughts are the last to know in
a way.
So if you're driven,
let's say you're in the addiction of
anger,
right?
It'll kick in,
you'll look for people,
you'll make excuses like saying,
oh yeah,
I'll give up smoking tomorrow.
Oh yeah,
sure.
I don't have to eat,
but I think I will eat.
Your brain will outsmart you every time,
but it's your insights.
They get the urge first.
I sort of said in the book it was like a
hive of bees and the queen is sitting
there.
She and she suddenly wants,
let's say a starbucks.
She thinks because she wants it.
You're going to get a starbucks,
but there's a zillion worker bees in
slave bees in valet parking fees.
They're already buzzing with each other
and whoever buzzes the loudest has made
the decision to get the latte.
Then the queen things.
Oh yeah.
That's what I wanted.
There's been a vote in every cell in
your body and before you actually kick
into something and we're.
And the juice of anger and rage is so
much more addictive.
Nobody ever gets addicted to Kale.
I'm really trying to create that.
Don't you won't drinking stuff five a
gallon,
still don't like it.
No.
I once I thought,
you know,
I,
oh,
juice is good for you.
So I made a big thing of it and I went
on the train and drank it the next day I
spent my day vomiting and they,
then I figured out I had drunk the
equivalent of four football because it's
also his stuff for football fields.
I had food in my body
drinking because of the stuff rubin's
don't.
So this,
um,
so the understanding consciousness from
a mechanical perspective,
the mind,
the mind or people in academia so
particular about the meeting,
like my point is these are,
if you have a mechanical understanding
as expressed through that analogy around
the hive mind and aspects of it,
you know,
the sort of the essential self being the
queen bee and different aspects of the
mind being different,
you know,
different bees within it.
But what
these are the consciousness and we only
know about the queen.
So when you say consciousness,
we have no idea
except of course many of the,
uh,
tech,
the techniques that I am interested in
which incidentally are sourced from the
same place as mindfulness.
Just another aspect of it.
They say that we can attune ourselves to
an aspect of consciousness that is free,
is truly witnessing all else.
And I will.
Well,
how could it be because you are
remembering so you know,
you,
but what my experience of my experience
of meditation is that it's only
retrospectively that go,
oh yeah.
Wow.
I wasn't in that moment.
I will just then that's already
happened.
I wasn't thinking and cataloging what
went on for one minute or a second or
for five minutes,
who knows,
because my understanding of time it has
been removed.
Subsequently I narrativize it and go,
oh,
that was what was happening.
So I'm having a different relationship
with in those moments.
I'm not thinking,
uh,
you know,
I want to have sex or I'm not good
enough,
or this might,
I'm afraid of this or a desire that
there is a cessation in that.
So that's it for me.
That's another aspect of meditation
that's important,
which I think can change our
relationship in a more,
uh,
a more total way or a more extreme way
than just using it as a technique to
calm down,
which I think is bloody valuable.
It is.
And you're completely right.
I get very excited about the mechanic
that,
but that's my problem.
You know,
the uncle say,
oh,
get off it.
Come on.
It is,
it is a practice of spirituality and I
have an allergy to that,
but why?
Because I,
you know,
I grew up at the time where I was
rebirthed and then somebody shoved a
crystal up my ass and then,
you know,
religious persecution drove your family
from.
That might be it.
Yeah.
I didn't even think of that.
So if I can't see it or I can't smell
it,
I don't buy it.
But of course the point of mindfulness
is a.
and I have a hard time saying it to
develop.
I always call it the c word compassion,
which now I talk about in the book and
presence.
Those are also the point of it.
But you see my proclivities always go to
the daddy won't think I'm smarter than
less.
I know the,
you know,
the physiology of it.
Daddy will think it's another cookie
stuff,
which Oh,
I've just had a revelation.
We must kill,
must die killing us.
I didn't realize you did.
This is like 8,000
years of shrinkage you just did is the
reasons probably I'm holding on to the
sciences because my dad said everything
I did was cool stuff.
There's not just that though,
Ruby.
This is all our father.
Patriarchy itself is built on
materialism and mechanistic thinking
precisely because it can be commodified
and sold and as soon as we begin to
access aspects of consciousness or self
that are beyond mechanistic and
materialistic thinking,
we begin to dive,
dive voltage,
understand access realms where our role
here is no longer the role of the
consumer,
the civilian,
the citizen,
but something quite different.
And the thing that fascinates me about
your work,
I,
I think that what I think you're doing
beautifully and what cannot be disputed
as you're making it accessible to a p
and people need like,
like you.
People need to understand it in terms of
material and mechanics and patriarchy
and if that gets people to understand
it,
that's brilliant,
but what,
but what I am fascinated by is how will
people accessing this information
without any of these tools.
And what else is there?
Because I think you're monk friend is
right.
It is about compassionate is about
presence.
People have been talking about it for
Millennia.
Knowing that our salvation is in that
direction and the father.
I don't think he's solely and uniquely
external,
but the father like you have just
expressed,
we carry with us.
It becomes all of our father,
both inner and outer and it prevents us
from exploring neurological circuitry
which might give us,
you know,
uh,
say new world to your time back at you.
You should write a book.
Well,
I'm,
I've got a pen.
I've made the first tentative steps into
the chest.
That's a brilliant thing.
And I just had an epiphany about my dad.
Go on that.
You're still trying to press.
I can't.
I can only do one pip otherwise now come
on very.
There are series of exactly what goes
wrong.
Michael Epiphany's is they can do a
moment dialogue.
He gave me multiple,
multiple epiphany's barely even moved
off the chair and the epiphany's carrier
on the train.
She could never walk again.
We're making sport at this rate while
she's.
The woman is permanently.
Um,
so,
right.
So you think that there is an obvious.
Obviously there is an aspect of your own
psychology even in your sort of
enlightened,
modern.
You're right that the,
the,
the father and all of us motivated me to
seek,
but it means it's a very thin slice.
You know,
the mechanics are the thin slice.
The bigger consciousness is the real
mccoy.
I obviously it wisdom.
It's Buddhism.
That's the real mccoy.
I find it difficult to talk about,
even though I studied it at Oxford,
but these guys opened consciousness.
You're right,
they didn't define it because it doesn't
have,
you know,
I think Einstein said,
if we're not conscious,
how do we define consciousness?
You know,
they didn't define it,
but they experienced it.
These guys open up where it's timeless,
you know,
these are the 10,000
hour guys.
It's timeless.
There is no,
um,
you know,
they do tests on these monks the whole
time,
you know,
doing the,
uh,
there's a blink test where most of our
Amygdala with sound,
you know,
because they show really disturbing
pictures.
But these guys,
their Amygdala,
it's more complicated than that.
But they're not.
Their Cortisol doesn't rush language,
you know?
So it worked.
It happened to be that it could have
been people who were astrologists.
It could've been a scientologist,
it happened to be Buddhism.
Would you say that it happened to be,
but they would say no.
We have this technology passed down from
the Buddha who had to stop saying it as
a Westerner.
You know what I'm saying?
They knew who the WHO,
you know,
with our arrogance,
we think,
well,
the fact that I was sitting there,
what was he doing it meanwhile they knew
everything and so what fascinates me is
what else I know and what else they
would teach us if we follow this down.
He's not going to just.
Why do you think I live with a monk
through your different modes?
Well,
he lives in my house but.
But his job is,
he works for Google and he works for
facebook and he works for banks and they
all long to learn this piece,
you know?
And how do is this guy,
by the way,
this monk 10,
he,
he's,
he's the guy at the monk in the book.
I'm using your gas now.
He doesn't know we let the monkey.
I shifted monkey.
And is that bad?
Well,
yes.
I think it is popped a monk in the spare
room.
The kids left.
Right.
And that there was this room and I
thought that is so such a great move.
But I met him.
He was doing a conference and he.
Boy,
can he,
he's articulate.
You went to Oxford because he western?
Yeah,
his mother.
I know this is weird.
You remember the Kumaras not mirror the
other lady,
she's his son.
He said,
sure.
He's the son.
So He's,
he's,
his story is unbelievable.
And uh,
he went,
he was an addict and he went to clean up
many years ago at Sammy link and they
give a,
they,
they give a course,
you know,
for a year to clean up your act.
And he,
he got so into it.
He became the fully ordained monk and
I'm talking five years of silence.
It's,
they don't just pass this card out and I
have to say his vibe in my house.
I called it my air freshener in or the
toilet duct,
you know what I mean?
You can't get a better vibe.
Do you meditate with them?
Yes we do.
Yeah.
Well,
he travels the world,
he's in Jamaica and now with Google I
think because in tech stuff or doing
meditation,
they all long to do,
you know,
to learn meditation for different
companies.
They pay him and he,
the monk isn't allowed to have money,
so he's building retreats.
So he's just built one in.
Um,
I think Southampton and then he's
building another one in Scotland.
They're not allowed to make money.
So he's making the extreme ends of the
country.
He's coming around the coastline
building retreats and he's not allowed
to have money.
It's curious,
isn't it?
The retreats for white people to kind of
go and get it,
get a massage.
This is for,
you know,
Buddhist nuns and things.
It also trade critiques are matching the
retreats and retreats have that thing.
You go to a hotel and there's a candle
in a stone.
So they go,
oh yes or no.
And now this appropriation of spiritual
doctrine and the commodification of it
is something that I am kind of aware of
and it's peculiar when sort of great
tech monoliths such as Google and
facebook recognize its efficacy and
essentially say,
how can we commodify this?
How can we utilize this for profit?
How can we turn the light?
Because you said that you know that your
experience has been that it's increased
your compassion and it's increased your
presence.
Now you may find yourself in a situation
where I presume you still have the drive
that your wife had because it's part of
my DNA.
So what do you,
what you're doing with it and let me
know you're doing this,
but how is it working for you with this?
How is your ego?
How is your sort of self laceration,
self flagellation,
how's that all going now?
Well,
it's got the same tone.
You know,
we don't change skin.
It's,
you know,
I can feel the same qualities,
but as I said,
it's,
I can't think of anything better.
And Jon Kabat Zinn said it.
It's more like a radio in another room.
Like I can grab it and be Ruby again and
part of me so addictive,
you know,
if you show me,
I don't know,
Jon Kabat Zinn gave me a really good
review it last night for the book,
the sides,
you and he's my.
That's my.
He invented mindfulness.
So my next thing was to write John and
say,
do you think I could come over
and do my show for you?
I mean,
he's just the ambition.
I can feel it.
You know,
it's,
it's an,
it's like an animal.
It's,
it's the,
you know,
when I see the alien and I go,
hey buddy,
I know exactly how you feel,
but it's not wild ambition that I,
that made my career with no talent.
I would not have developed talent,
but it in the beginning I wouldn't take
no for an answer.
I just showed a bunch of me.
They said,
but you can't ever TV show.
I said,
I'm showing up.
I'm here.
Turn on the cameras.
They said,
well,
who the hell are you?
I said,
I'm here.
I've arrived.
What about,
so do you think this is something that
can be for really interesting?
You said something interesting and I
went off.
I'm happy with tangent.
Do you think whereas it could be
described and diagnosed neurologically
or do you think there's another
component to that?
This drive,
this willingness,
this ongoing desire?
Well,
it's dopamine.
It's the same thing that gets people
fixed and fixed on approval,
fixed on rage,
fixed on,
you know,
I now from doing.
Who Do you think you are?
I,
I get it.
My dad got out of their country two
seconds before he would've been
annihilated,
but he never shut it off.
When he got to Chicago,
he ate his way through.
He lived in rage.
He became the tyrant he escaped from and
that's how I lived.
I will eat you alive if you get in my
way and now it's just,
it almost destroyed my family,
whatever,
you know,
because I wasn't around when my kids
were young and now because of,
of watching the mind what?
Just watching it and going,
okay Ruby,
but without whipping myself because you
know if you hit the animal,
it gets more violent.
I go,
calm down,
let's use that anger when we need it.
This isn't perfect.
This is my ideal.
Cool.
And then when you know when,
when the man hasn't come to fix your
fridge and it's been a year,
use that anger.
Well Ruby,
go on the phone and do what you do,
but then when you put the phone down
then don't go call somebody up and go,
you know what I did because that son of
a bitch didn't show up and I do some of
this off on it.
Get off and then I've got it on and then
I started picking other things to make
me angry because I want more just like a
junkie.
So kind of understanding that I will
give somebody hell and it's so tempting
because it does taste more delicious
than being nice.
Wba said,
every artist
you must create his own religion and you
are creating your own religion.
Sourced as it necessarily seems to be in
your case from a secular understanding
of modern scientific ideas and it is
working for you.
You're telling us some of your code,
some of your methods for coping with
your personal human condition.
So now you're saying that some of that
source material,
the drive is being repurposed
effectively and have your relationships.
For example,
if your husband and your three children
are they,
those relationships are improving
but they are improving.
But then my kids are.
My two daughters are in comedy now and
the engine starting to were,
you know,
of me and I'm becoming Ethel mermen to
push them and they go back off and I
feel too,
but eventually I do have to back off
because it's your kids.
I can't devour them the way my dad
devoured me this time.
I'm backing off.
He ate me alive and you know,
he died and we were not friends.
What do you mean you live?
He just,
uh,
he overwhelmed me,
you know,
they,
it to mold me like a piece of clay.
They wanted a rep,
they wanted a photocopy and I wasn't it.
So they kicked the shit out of me.
He meant to be.
I was meant to be.
I do know,
you know,
like my mother was perfect.
She spoke eight languages.
She married a tyrant.
Really bad move.
A just a nice Jewish person,
I guess not interesting for them to get
something outside of a d because I was
uh,
I,
I got really,
I didn't get any grades.
They were below the toilet because I
was.
Now I know I was traumatized.
I couldn't think they'd say,
what books did you read it?
And I go,
um,
I couldn't.
So I was putting the remedial class and
my brain was frozen and I thought it was
because I was dumb.
There were traumatized by your father.
They were wild.
I wrote a book way earlier called,
how do you want me?
Yeah,
And Carrie Fisher edited it and she said
my parents were as crazy as hers.
There's nothing else to say because hers
are the a list.
And my parents were as dark as it comes,
as dark as it comes
by that you like.
And this isn't to be diminishing,
you mean sort of ordinary domestic
darkness as in there's not talking
sexual abuse and violence.
Really a lot to do with say,
oh,
but there's violence and there's fear
and there's psychological torture.
Go on.
No,
no.
Psych.
I mean add is a nice man who I'm
married.
He said when he sees my parents,
he wants to take their head and Jeremy
Chapman,
the side of a table because of the
cruelty
and the Philip Larkin talk.
Why they're responding to a sort of
massive social trauma and political
power.
No,
I didn't know where they came from.
They didn't tell me about the Holocaust.
It was never mentioned.
So they passed it to me.
So I had noises of.
I never watched a film about Nazis
because since I was a kid I heard
screaming in my head and that's because
they gently sublimated it and past that
noise.
You think that the law,
I mean that's not genetic.
Is it?
That sort of some sort of manual
psychological transference.
Then I put my hands up,
I don't know.
Torture,
curious.
Mystery remains at the beginning of
psychoanalysis as separate from
neurology.
There's these sort of distinct schools,
Freud who it's too pricey,
dreadfully believing the psyche is built
upon repression and primarily repressed
sexuality and young who maintained that
there was that,
there was a mystery and a,
a collective unconscious and a
transcendent aspect to who we are in
sales on the button to.
I'm into that dude.
So what?
So what,
so you love young so that because for
me,
a lot of it,
like in there like I love this Melville
quote,
I hear a lot of all human sciences but
passing fables,
meaning that if you'll look at and go,
oh,
how cute.
Quantum theory,
you know,
like,
so like w,
w,
w what in the work of young you find
fascinating from your perspective of
someone who understands numerology and
the.
No,
but let me say the answer to everything
isn't mechanics.
It's just I hold onto it.
That's my problem.
I see.
Yeah,
it's not cool.
It's not that reductionist,
but it's me showing off,
you know,
for.
I really liked meditation because it
makes me much prettier.
And um,
and I sit and I sit in front of my
Buddha and I liked,
you really liked me then,
but I think,
hey,
throw that Amygdala.
It's like me tossing my dick out.
Very nice ticket.
Walsall smothered in Amygdala
by law.
So what do you like about you?
You're like,
they're sort of archetype
the shadow.
The shadow is so interested in chorus
because,
you know,
Freud wanted to be a neurologist but you
couldn't find a live brain,
you know,
so he was guessing there is no Edd,
there is no metaphors and similes,
metaphors.
And he was kind of spot on too.
But he went to literal.
Whereas there is something that isn't
mechanical,
that isn't neuroscience of something
that we're,
that lives below as something looks.
I,
maybe it's my addiction,
maybe it's the rage,
but it's something that when the mind
does meet it,
the light shines on the darkness.
There is a kind of piece.
And that is mindfulness too.
It's the dark meeting,
the light,
you know,
it's the,
it's the anima and the animus.
There's a marriage.
And so resident fighting yourself with
those abusive thoughts,
which I accept because if you get angry
at those thoughts,
this is a more mundane quote,
but if you run from the monster,
it chases you and if you face it,
it runs from you.
So there's a marriage and he was very
much about,
you know,
the male and the female side,
the dark and the light.
And that's as far as I can take it.
He was right on the button.
I mean,
if that's not stealing from Buddhism.
And he was into Mondalez.
And of course archetypes is completely
correct.
We aren't one thing.
I'm not just ruby who's like at this age
and I don't feel female.
I really don't.
If you woke me up at four in the morning
and said,
what sex are you?
I'd really have to say I don't know
because I don't feel it.
And we should understand we're not a
stereotype.
This body is a,
is always a cesspool of genes and
experience.
And I could pull a card at any time,
you know,
I'm living proof.
I was a moron at it as a kid.
And then ended up in Oxford,
who the fuck would have thought that
one?
It's just if you let it go and you
really study because it ain't coming to
you.
That brain has got its neuroplastic.
You can really develop this brain.
It's going to be harder when you're
older.
But if I start learning Chinese and I
start,
you know,
whatever I will have the wiring that a
30 year old doesn't have,
I suspect,
but a lot of people listening to this
will suffer from mental health issues
because you know,
I attract them and obviously you do.
Yeah,
my people.
So people can change.
They can change.
But let me just say with the disease,
you know,
again,
we don't know about this.
If you have cancer,
you can't think your way out of it.
Do you understand that mental illness?
Well,
you don't get the fear.
You can lower the fear.
You can with depression,
you lower the shame.
Which means that when I feel the little
nips of the depression coming,
I.
because I have a little bit of an
overview,
I know what to do.
I don't get busier,
which is usually my way to go.
I'm perfectly fine.
I'll show up at your,
I'll say showed a bit of charity for
safe.
The puffin,
like I give a shit last time and I took
up scuba diving at Christmas under
brightened pair to show everybody else
and then you end up in an institution
for five months or take on a lot of work
to get the cortisone,
which is the very thing that's making
the depression about depression,
about.
So this time I see it coming.
I shut everything down because I respect
that disease.
I checked into a little retreat,
no TV and I just sat and bit the bullet.
It hurts like fuck,
but it passed faster because the court
is always down and that's why Kabat Zinn
worked with people in pain.
Focus on the pain because if you don't,
your whole body is the essence of pain.
Focus in on where it is.
Okay.
I'm not completely depressed,
but there is depression,
so that doesn't mean I still take
medication,
but I have a different relationship with
it.
Gosh,
that's really fascinating and really,
really helpful.
And what I'm enjoying very much about
this conversation is the evident
marriage between spirituality and
science.
Uh,
I feel that this is going to play an
important part in our conversation.
I mean,
you and I,
but I mean culturally going forward
because my senses and it's one of the
things we've been looking at continually
over the course of these podcasts.
But,
uh,
you know,
Adam Curtis,
it was that said,
oh my God,
the old thing is dead and the new thing
has not yet been born.
And like we're the age of managerial
politics,
this age of bogus,
institutionalized religion,
all these things coming to a halt and
people are looking for ways to connect
with their essence.
Ways to understand their story.
But it's got to have the right language.
It's got a feel real.
People can't pose through it.
But I sent that.
There's much in this stuff,
but we've talked about are around union
archetypes are mostly because we need a
way to access the mystery and the
mystery.
I don't mean a woo woo thing.
I mean,
there is a terrain that can never be
contained by our limited capacity for
knowledge.
That's why,
I mean I,
I might be pulling this out.
We weren't going in this direction is
this all comes down to it are,
are working to as a tribe.
It all went wrong when we,
when we suddenly went agricultural and
we lost each other and I think in this
world we're too isolated and I have
these.
I have these things called frazzled
cafes were groups of people.
Well,
I didn't mean to swerve.
I just good.
I always the real cure.
The real thing for compassion,
this is the road is,
is that we start to be human again with
each other.
You know,
meeting it's smaller groups maybe and
not doing cocktail bullshit where you
have to say,
how's your kid?
Like I give a shit.
You know,
life is hard enough when you talk to
people.
It's completely superficial.
So anyway,
from my experience in the theater,
I set up these groups.
If you go to Fresno Cafe Dot Org,
put down your name,
we get in touch with you marks and
Spencer's gave me all their cafes.
They shut it down and then groups of 15
meet every two weeks with a facilitator
and all these people,
it breaks your heart.
It's so touching.
They're scared in the beginning,
like little frail humans and they're all
ages,
all colors,
all you know.
And suddenly they start to speak human
to say they're not mentally ill.
They're like all of us,
you know,
they opened their hearts and by the time
you leave they're all holding hands.
They've exchanged phone numbers and
they've.
Some groups have been going for a year.
They have their tried and I know that
that's part of all this is that we're so
alone and nobody's comparing notes.
I didn't like that idea.
I think you're quite right about like.
So you found out Harare.
Come on and just talk to us through the
sort of.
One of the driving ideas in his book
sapiens is how the advent of
agriculture,
which is obviously an economically lead
notion meant a huge.
I'm not the expert mentors,
so if people urbanizing coming together
and people becoming sort of units in an
economy,
as opposed,
I'm losing a certain necessary essential
connection that lucky he explained to
you that book agricultural works for one
Straw society,
but it doesn't work for the majority.
Now bumped it up,
bumped it up,
bumping up and technology works for so
many things just like they needed to go
into the architectural stage.
But we are.
Our brain is still caveman.
We don't know how to adjust to this
population,
but this technical,
this,
uh,
this notion of theological,
continued progress is underwritten by
the same idea as agriculture.
We are progressing,
we are going forward.
And I would say that that requires a
mechanistic and materialistic Veltin to
continue and to you say,
no,
no.
There is a mystery.
All the things that we access through
the senses on by Necessity Limited and
unless we find a route back to who we
are,
who we are as humans,
I've wished something is like I have in
my own life,
a collective eyes to support groups and
community groups where we do talk to one
another and very open,
honest plane.
Why are you lucky?
Yeah.
It's like the gift of a of addiction in
my case,
but I think you know,
but there's nothing to stop us creating
societies based on a different model.
Creating groups on a different model of,
well,
we need an only commune on the economic
circumstances.
Certainly struck me recently how
ridiculous the kids socializing shopping
malls,
that's where they go.
If you're not spending money,
you're not congregate in,
you're not coming together so we can ran
sack and attack religious institutions
or we like and God knows how corrupt
they became,
but it was a place where people went
together to do something other than buy
something exactly when.
It's the same thing if,
when we had churches in a gathering,
again,
we didn't need extraneous methods or a
mental fitbit.
That was a community was being human.
It's a group that's human,
not an individual.
An individual alone is like a finger.
So,
um,
it's the loneliness and know the being
open to saying,
I'm fucked.
I don't.
I need to be contacting people and
saying,
here's what's going on in my mind is
that what's going on in yours?
And there will be such relief when that
happens.
What do you think of this thing that
Yanis Varoufakis said when they were in
their egos?
The individually we exist in like he's
sort of a person that don't really,
like he said that he thinks matter came
before spirit.
So I disagreed with him.
Talking about consciousness must've come
from matter rather than Matt coming from
consciousness,
but he said that you,
that we exist in dialectic,
that we exist in relationship to travel,
you know,
what is self if there aren't other
people to relate to.
So our whole notion of what it is to be
an individual is wrong.
So what do you,
what in your work long.
I mean they,
you know,
the mother builds the child's brain
through her reaction that a kid is just
a blob of fat unless the mother starts,
which was my case,
um,
she tries to keep me up and then dressed
me and gave me these hideous haircuts
and I was sent to school as a blob of
fat.
Yeah.
So,
but the only way a human being is molded
is through the compassion and the
emotion of the mother.
She teaches the kid what it is to be
human.
So we,
I love this expression,
we work like neuro Wifi.
If I was in a rural state,
I pass it straight to you.
So we infect each other,
but we could infect each other.
Maybe with things like mindfulness,
I can only teach you compassion and give
you compassion.
Now I can't do it alone,
but if my,
if the certain and there are chemicals
involved,
then oxytocin switches on chemicals,
chemicals very.
I like a nice bit of Mumbo jumbo of a
morning on a good road,
but a good ball when you get that sexy
thing.
That's the chemical.
I'm sorry to say.
There is no consciousness involved.
Something goes a little bit of juice
goes to the penile area.
I'm not talking about sex rule,
but you did that all in your own mind.
I love Mumbo jumbo means a rhubarb
Halabaloo no,
no monkey business.
I meant the monkey business.
No,
but I'm saying compassion is could be
reduced to a chemical and we do talk
about in relationships like
why chemicals,
where do they come from and what holds
them together.
What invisible grid.
Let's see.
I'm not as smart as you.
That's the problem.
A mess.
Finally we agree on my pencil in
egotistical.
I'm indulgence.
How you going to really be?
Um,
what I'm going to say.
I like that thing you were just ending
on about that.
We find it difficult to individually
rate because like when something happens
around me and my parents,
but I can't see it objectively because
they are immeshed in the self that is
witnessing it.
So thank you very much for that.
You've got go because literally there
I'm wrapping this up,
not because I want to,
but because it's my train produces.
It says you've got to get train in 25
minutes to go to east bumfuck.
I can't imagine why I'm spreading the
joy.
Well,
they need doing these shows.
I love it.
That's fantastic.
I love the show is the show that I came
and saw.
To me it's a meeting of mind and ego.
The perfect marriage.
Yeah.
Who comes first?
Um,
ruby is,
I'm usually the ego.
Surely selfish the mind,
but then mind is sort of all
encompassing.
Ruby,
thank you for coming on here.
Thank you for your letter.
You plug your book properly.
Uh,
Rubin's new book,
how to be human.
The manual is released in January and
there's a very good,
at least one good quality on the front
of it.
Get you can preorder it now on Amazon
because preorders is good for people,
so right now a ruby.
Thank you for coming to talk to you.
Thank you for giving us some time to
look good.
You're beautiful inside cameras.
I.
Oh,
I didn't.
Fuck.
I didn't hold my stomach or you'll be
beautifully unselfconscious.
Ruby.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Thanks.
This show that you've just listened to.
Then using your ears were sponsored by
my new book recovery,
which you can get as an audiobook on
audible.
It's brilliant or you can get it on
Amazon,
which is very good and you can come and
see me or my rebirth to lightly.
You've listened to me.
Come and look at me.
Less stuff for even November,
so we're wearing arranged gigs.
This new tickets come available.
You're going to love it.
Torquey 25th of November.
Imagine seeming into.
Okay.
Imagine what's going to resonate in the
air down there.
Portsmouth,
28th of November.
Fantastic.
What a night to be alive.
Reading on the 29th of November,
which I believe is Churchill's birthday.
Gotcha.
I
go to ww dot Russell brand.com
to get your tickets.
Finally,
if you liked this show,
subscribe to it.
Review intellectual tunes.
Don't give it any less than six and a
five star.
You can't do $6.
Can you put?
Surely the day will come.
Well,
thanks for listening.
We love you and we'll see you again
soon.
Bye.