Sort of like your online voice style,
like through blogging and talking about
Scottish independence.
Now that you're in winter,
more international level of notoriety.
It's talking more about class,
but I'm assuming that when you were
talking about independent class was a
big component.
Can you talk to me about,
I mean that's how I came Kim and our
possession of conflict,
the wife sections of the yes movement
because you know like all movements
there's a disagreement in certain
pockets about what the priorities are
and what posture we should assume
generally saw.
It was the sort of,
for me and a lot of other people on the
Ken of left and the radical left we we
we didn't see,
we didn't really buy into the idea that
independence foster and then we'll talk
about all this stuff later.
We thought,
no,
hang on way.
Got All this trouble of having
independence.
If we've not got a really set up an idea
of what we're,
what I do and relation to taxation,
social housing,
welfare,
drug policy,
education.
Like let's really get into the detail
about that stuff because that may be the
thing that mobilizes more people on the
desk and franchise communities who are,
you know,
usually apathetic towards politics and
for good reason.
So I would be bringing up class usually
on relation to art because I was
creating music [inaudible] eh,
the themes that are thought of Mlg,
no of the independence,
the beer.
And uh,
sometimes I would comment a conflict
when I would go and perform at arts
events that Wa like felt very sort of
student here in middle class.
And there's a certain expectation about
what's appropriate.
You'll notice from your expedience of a
pr as a performer,
although,
because you're more established,
no people will tend to come to whatever
you are or an ass shoes.
But when you're just meeting people for
the fast team and you're using the
vernacular and a lexicon and,
and,
and things that may be perceived as
vulgar on aggressive,
then Eh,
you just feel resistance and for Mina
and reason then testing questions
because one of my premed,
new tress and,
and dependence was that the
regionalization of culture and Bratton
means that a lot of great writers and
artists from different places under your
care who don't have friends and sort of
London bubble that just get ignored or
seniors cain off like firebrands or they
get bracketed in a certain way.
And so our thought independence's
perhaps it'll viscerally,
I fought independence is a way for us to
create our own culture and our own,
uh,
and configure it out and I'll eat it.
Makes sense to us.
Um,
but then there was a lot of self
interest involved as well and hand say,
you know what,
it was sad of being a bigger fashion or
smaller point.
You know,
I've been ranting for 15 years.
I'm very,
I'm very competent.
I'm very passionate about it.
Um,
but even in Scotland,
the idea of wrapping with my own accent,
it's like a joke for a lot of people.
And uh,
and that's even worse when you go,
don't,
so if you're not old or,
oh,
the grain rappers and all the MCS doe
neil's are pervading,
protested the of your key hot port.
So it was just like all of those
reasons.
But then when Al got any further
discussions,
west people who were running these arts
events and I was wanting to talk about
class,
or I had class beast disputes where for
them then they were like,
we'll talk about this later.
We'll talk about this after.
And they would try and play,
keep me in various ways,
obviously underestimate and how
passionate I was about.
So that became a sort of a divergence
point for me and a lot of other people
were for the yes movement.
That still remains to this day.
I would see.
What is the nature of this dispute?
What is the nature of this disparity
between what I'm picking out you're
describing as a more educated or to use
a classical or conventional word or
more?
Uh,
the more bourgeois aspect of the left
and the working class contingencies and
then also this dispute.
Oh,
also a national fooled at the sin and
over always will.
So it's,
it's not,
I wouldn't characterize it as a dispute,
although it does manifest as a
confrontation and acrimony.
I would characterize it as,
um,
things getting lost in translation.
So we currently think about culture as a
sort of continuum where people,
uh,
near the bottom are waiting to sort of
graduate to become legitimate by virtue
of their willingness to either conceal
or renounce those indicate who they
actually are with.
Whereas assay working class culture as a
parallel culture and that there are many
contradictions,
x interest at ease lessons.
There's a lot of wisdom,
a lot of things that are very distinct.
Uh,
I mean,
I've been socially more bail enough and
wife that I've maxed a lot across a
ravine.
So over the years I've built up an
understanding of some of these fault
lanes and that the big donor and
communication often can come from simply
a difference in a sense of urgency or
priority on the watts that someone
newsies.
So what you might see is what you meet
cs passion.
Someone sees it as aggression,
pushiness of what you might see as
polite.
Someone thinks his pattern isn't,
it's the combination of all of these
little instances where people come away
from an attempt to mango across the
ravine,
that that just becomes natural to sort
of recall back to where it's
comfortable,
where people are gritty.
Whereas Alec,
to be on the lane,
I'm more comfortable in the medal.
I come from a working class background,
I'm passionate about it.
But back then in my youth there would be
people trying to police how I spoke that
wants the are years,
the things that I was interested then a
very rigid idea about what a young man
should be.
And I resented that and challenge that.
But then at the same time on the other
side,
then even just the things that I want to
talk about and the way that I wouldn't
if fema is changing,
no,
cause I've kind of been caught saying
the bay,
a few legitimate people notes about
like,
oh this we must have Garvey.
But beforehand it was very,
it was very much a struggle.
I had to kind of manipulate my way into
the middle class,
feels like stop wearing a hood.
They start wearing a blazer,
wearing a pair of glasses instead of a
baseball cap and learn to talk.
Like middle class people were alarmed
that for them that's the sort of form of
currency,
not necessarily being clever but sonin
clever on an amount of that.
I sort of picked up on that.
That's when I became more socially
mobile than perhaps my education with
the valid.
Maybe make some good points there.
One of the things I recently learned
about the way that hedge money is
constructed is with the imposition of a
narrative and have a language within it.
And the way I learned it when I'm doing
this course at university,
they said that the way that the western
world or so called secular work deals
with Islam or Middle East and countries
is with the assumption that there's a,
a narrative for Islam has to go through
that will conform to what uh,
post,
uh,
like I like that,
that create,
that Christian history has been through
lie a prostin ecm and Catholicism is
secularization when as you did when you
were describing working class culture,
the entity,
it's a parallel narrative that there is,
there is a separate Islamic narrative,
there's a separate working class
narrative and you don't have these
things need,
didn't necessarily conflate and
certainly what you would call I suppose
secondary or sub narratives.
It can't be subsumed in the infocomm is
dominant narrative.
Yeah.
So like,
yeah,
I like that mate.
What you said that you have to even on
the level of lighting,
the way that you accessorize pop on a
pair of specs instead of a baseball cap
to be more sort of identifiable.
But then when you do that,
you comment in conflict with where you
actually come from,
you up pop gagan a blazer and people are
like,
well,
your hood there,
who do you hang?
Yeah,
and saw that actually is not as much as
as as that.
That has been difficult at times.
It seem team of kind of like I've tried
to stay true to what I wore one,
and really with the book,
what I was trying to do was engage
multiple people from multiple
backgrounds at the scene.
Tell
you.