This is a very special edition of under
the skin because I'm not even hosting
it.
I am the guest this week under the skin
will be hosted by the Great Welsh
philosopher,
the Dylan have a merchant new
consciousness.
It is Brad Evans.
And what this man doesn't know about
violence isn't worth knowing and I
should are less rate myself and kick me
own editing before I deny his knowledge
of the subject of violence with the uh,
with my book coming out,
Brad has kindly agreed to interview me
on the subject of recovery.
Brad,
I have my very much as a philosopher
over the course of these,
uh,
of this excursion into the subcutaneous
world.
We've become friends and I'm very
grateful for you doing this.
I will now hand over full authority to
you and bowers.
I do.
I'd like to begin by saying,
I've obviously read an advanced copy of
your book and it was actually a real
privilege privilege to read it and I was
actually taken by a lot of the courage
that you put down on the pages.
So that to me is something to be deeply
applauded.
Now,
the one thing I guess,
you know,
I'm also,
I guess kind of humbled that yachty
shall trust in me to do this.
So,
so thank you and thank you for our
friendship.
That's something with,
you know,
a cherishing.
Um,
I'd like to go,
you know,
directly into this question.
As I say,
it's kind of,
you know,
it's interesting being on the other side
of this and the one thing that,
which I kind of think about,
you know,
is that for anybody who writes a book,
they know that it's a whole series of
procrastination.
Sometimes it takes months,
often it takes years.
And I guess the first thing that really
struck me was what compelled you to
write this book at this particular point
in your life?
I felt that anybody that's in recovery
who has this experience where,
what begins is something that you're
using to tackle a particular addiction.
In my case,
initially,
crack and heroin becomes sort of over
time.
Like I realized that the tools and
techniques I was using to one day at a
time not used drugs and alcohol were
becoming utilized in every area of my
life.
The way that I feel about sex,
the way that I feel about food,
all behavior and all forms of attachment
can be tackled,
or at least my perception of them can be
ordered by working the 12 steps.
So excuse me,
coffee mate.
But so what I felt was like this,
I'm like at this point in my life where
I feel like I've gone through so many
layers of disillusionment,
disillusionment with fame,
disillusionment with Hollywood,
this illusion when the sex and
disillusionment is,
I think by and large are bloody good
thing.
Who wants to be illusioned?
You know,
like so you know,
and like,
so I felt like,
you know,
the,
the recovery is the lens through which I
live my life is that my relationship is
conducted through the program that I
described in this book.
Obviously my spiritual development,
the way that I relate to other people,
I by no means do it perfectly,
but it is a technique that makes it so
effective that I want you to expound it
because I've seen it change lives of
people with really serious chemical
dependency,
really serious behavioral problems.
And I think it's a technique that offers
is a kind of counterweight to the
overriding,
uh,
ideology of our time,
which just seems to me to be a kind of
determined an icon and yeah,
conscious self centeredness.
Yeah.
I don't think,
you know,
when I was reading the manuscript and
this call for transformation really
comes through then you can see that as a
very personal journey that you go on.
Um,
I guess I was trying to figure out,
um,
what type of book it actually was and I
know this is bloody ironic or come from
a song called postmodernist right there.
I was trying to label it and classify it
and I think,
you know,
in an affirmative way it's almost like
an anti self help book.
And I think what I of mean by this is I
think the central message,
which really jumps off the pages is that
it's precisely these kinds of traits of
a self centered,
individualistic kind of fuck the world
narrative and all,
it's kind of loving sentiments,
which kind of gets us into this fix in
the first place.
It's kind of just help yourself
narrative.
And I think what really to me comes out
of this is more about a sober in perhaps
more truthful cry for human connection.
Is that where you see the hope?
Yes.
Cause I think our culture and our
biochemistry collude to create a kind of
a chronic individualism.
And I feel that the natural conclusion
of uh,
uh,
kind of a secular rejection of the
mystical leads us to the conclusion that
we are just individuals.
We're here to survive.
We're here to fulfill our impulses.
In the original 12 step literature,
it says like,
we have no argument with those people
that say perhaps man's purpose is simply
to fulfill these bike camp by a chemical
drives to procreate,
to survive,
to dominate the selfish gene approach.
But he says one thing we are certain of
is no one has made a worse mess of this
way of life than we'd at suffer from
alcoholism and addiction.
And like me,
when I tried to live my life as a means
to find personal fulfillment are getting
into sort of a kind of peculiar despair,
I start to feel lonely.
I start to feel disconnected.
That don't mean I don't pick up the
cudgel once again and try to find my way
back to false prophet.
Why I feel qualified to write a book on
addiction.
He's because I've been addicted to
heroin.
I've been addicted to crack.
I've been addicted to fame,
money,
sex,
relationships,
other people's approval.
I see this phenomena emerge again and
again and I'm starting to think that the
label of addiction in itself is too
confining.
That actually this is the human
condition in motion.
You're yearning itself,
yearning and we live in a culture.
I think that usually does is fuel this
will to acquire a know like I thought
it's become,
the reason I wrote the book is because
it seems to me that simple though.
This is an particular though is in
origin.
It entailed within,
it are tools that could people's
perspective in quite a profound way and
what you say there brad about it takes
you from a point of view of going,
Oh,
if only I can get this when I get that,
I'll be cool.
Or if that person understood me or if I
could have sex with that person or if I
could get those shoes.
All of these part being personal
examples from my own life,
like everyone be okay and it doesn't
work.
But if I go like,
you know,
and I don't do it enough because I'm
again,
I every day I wake up,
once again,
bewitched and hypnotized by individual
isn't.
But when I'd go and spend time helping
other people,
sometimes in real blatant sub Princess
Diana,
why he's like going into a homeless
shelter and getting proper hands on and
being amongst it.
Or if just on a basic communal way like
we human being should be taking phone
calls from other people that are
suffering,
reaching out and talking about their
problems for a change,
which you know is odd that it needed to
be full made for me to understand it.
Cause I'm sure a lot of people just
bloody do it naturally,
but it just gives me a different way of
talking to my mates if my mates are
going through relationship struggles or
personal struggles or work struggles,
I think,
oh why?
Well,
this is good cause I can connect to you
here and while I'm talking to you,
I won't be thinking about myself and my
own problems.
And the more I do it,
you know,
I think,
like in Christianity Brad had la,
I want to know what you think about all
this stuff,
man.
But when it talks about when Christ says
it,
get down with a poor,
that's where he's at.
And it's not like,
oh my God,
look at the scars and lesions and like
there's some energy there when you're
helping others and the Chi.
And not only that,
the other people that help others are
beautiful.
So you start to feel a kind of elevated
sense of connection,
purpose,
meaning all of these words that are,
I think being increasingly marginalized,
empathy,
all these things that are being excluded
from the sort of political ideologies of
our time and the social ideologies of
our time suddenly become accessible
fruit as most basic thing.
Right?
Hmm.
Yeah.
There's an interesting point in terms
of,
you know,
I think we can all kind of know in our
lives when human connections seem deeply
meaningful to us,
right?
And we know that these connections exist
and we thrive on them.
And we know that they're kind of really
reciprocal because they're based on an
ethical understanding and,
and that idea of love with one another.
But we often driven actually two
relationships,
which as you say,
we're trying to seek affirmation in the
wrong places and they become very toxic
and they become,
and sometimes society can actually
promote those types of relationships,
which we know what actually deeply,
you know,
detrimental to ourselves,
to our emotional wellbeing,
toward intellectual wellbeing.
And yet we still strive for them.
And even though we know they are
completely empty,
meaningless,
or indeed maybe be nihilistic in terms
of our own sense of self.
And I think that's,
that'd be romanticism.
You know,
I'm not saying that we're at a,
romanticism is a mendacious idea,
but the,
the,
the notion that you can find fulfillment
by being with some aspirational figure,
some dietary,
I'm living God as your own personal.
Jesus,
I'll find salvation if I find them.
One,
you know that that idea,
I think he's highly prevalent but even
more toxic than this I think is the
commodification of relationships that
that happens on quiet the,
as I say,
it's a collusion between bio,
chemistry and culture.
Like it's very natural I think on some
level to meet a man and think,
what can this man do for me?
Can he serve me?
Can he make me feel better?
Can I make money?
Is you're going to be a good ally in a
fight?
What can I do with it?
Or in my case with women,
do I want to have sexual intercourse
with that woman?
Is this person gonna make me feel
better?
I was.
If this is the commodification and the
objectification,
it happens.
In my case it happened quite quite
automatically.
I have to work to not approach
relationship in that way.
So I wonder,
so for me the program is the antidote to
the type of thinking to which I have a
tendency that's all it addiction is,
is a tendency left on my own.
I will go that way unless I intervene.
Unless there is a program and the other
thing breath,
I think he's,
it seems to me to be important is we
don't choose between a program and no
program.
We have a program.
You have the program of your family,
you have the program of your society,
you have the program of your culture,
you have the program of consumerism.
If you don't undo that program,
if you do not be code yourself like
someone leaving a cult,
then that's the program you're living
with the program of I'm not good enough.
I'll never be good enough unless I get
this object or that object.
I won't be good enough on this.
That person can accept me.
Now what I think this offers because it
was designed to tackle alcoholism and
addiction is a way of untangling the
strands that web os to materialism,
consumerism and objectification and
individualism.
All of these things that are based on
the idea that what can be measured,
what can be white is what is important.
See like my um,
it's not like I am anti atheist in any
cognitive,
you know,
I know loads of people.
There are a few is probably you like
that are fantastic and incredibly smart
and compassionate and wonderful people.
My concern is that there's a thread
within atheism that tells you that all
the only thing that matters is that
which can be ascertained and science in,
in,
in all of its main disciplines is
forever peripheral forever on the brink
of new discoveries.
And when you get someone like Elon Musk
saying by like look with the kind of
virtual reality technologies we have
now,
there's no way of proving that we're not
all currently living in a virtual
reality.
And I had a gun,
my mates virtual reality thing,
my little mate Israel is only 11 years
old and a four.
Oh my God,
you can be immersed now in a totally,
totally different reality.
So we elon musk sign,
if we can do that,
imagine what other cultures could
conceivably do.
You can't rule out the possibility that
this is one.
Well,
bloody hell,
that's what it says in the bag of our
Gita,
except it doesn't use the word computer.
You know,
like what is it that you want?
now we're saying it's the material world
is an illusion that's like it's
transmitted into your consciousness,
through the senses.
You reconfigure it and you end and the
inflections of your culture denote what
meaning you attribute to the external
stimuli and the only way of decoding
that I think we're not the only way,
but a way of decoding that is by
impersonal set.
In personal crisis,
you get the opportunity to reevaluate
that crisis could be divorce,
it could be drug addiction,
it could be a heartbreak or some other
existential crisis.
But when you're at that point,
whether as an individual or as a
society,
you can say,
is this the kind of life I want to
believe that I want to live?
Do I believe it could be different?
Am I willing to accept help?
Once you take those are the first three
steps.
Once you take those three steps,
it's possible to have transformation.
After that,
there's a process of inventorying,
a willingness to change,
and then a devotion to conscious contact
and to service,
and then you've got a completely
different way of life
in the world.
Yeah.
I think there's,
you know,
this reevaluation is,
it's,
it's an I,
it strikes me as a really important
thing,
but it's also a very difficult thing to
start to reevaluate everything about
your own sense of self,
your sense of behavior.
You know,
it's often easier to project your
troubles onto other people.
Or are they,
rather than actually saying,
actually,
is this something about my own self,
which I needed to,
you know,
what,
how am I shamefully compromising with
power in a way that's affecting my own
relationships with the way I'm
objectifying things datafication and so
on.
But I wanted to bring us onto the,
with the step that you said,
you know,
because I think when I was reading the
book,
the first kind of couple of chapters was
kind of like,
yeah,
I can go with this.
Right?
It's kind of,
you know,
there's,
there's this step around,
okay,
admit you have a problem,
then go and speak with somebody.
Then you go into this section.
No,
what you need to do is write an
inventory of all the things which really
piss you off,
right?
And then I go,
Whoa,
wait a minute.
Right?
This is where it's starting to get
challenging,
right?
And it's going to start to get
difficult.
And you,
you even say those words at the
beginning,
he said,
look,
you know,
this is not easy,
right?
This is difficult.
And,
and you talk about,
you know,
this,
write down all those things which you
think create a s and you're an assault
on your sense of Salford,
on your sense of dignity and you know,
and the phrase you actually use you as
the uncomfortable confrontations,
right?
So deal with this uncomfortable
confrontations in your life.
And I was wondering how did you actually
feel,
of course,
from writing the book because in many
senses you must have had to revisit a
lot of uncomfortable confrontations,
which you'd already might've kind of
dealt with.
But in writing the book there was almost
like an attempt to kind of revisit those
issues.
And you know,
how,
how did you feel right in this book
because of the efficacy of the program,
Brad,
it did not feel like the resurrection of
their cadavers of my past because they
have been buried.
And even in examine them,
this metaphor is going well.
And for the purposes,
for the purpose of the book,
like a,
it didn't,
they,
they don't bring him back to life now.
Like you know,
sort of,
I have a propensity to return to states
of shame,
you know,
I like that I have that in me is easily
triggered in me is easily triggered like
leading up to my wedding.
Like cause I think like is the way I
sort of have been explaining this.
You might like it,
right?
My Mate Matt Morgan,
he said to me,
keeps climbing up high.
We went down crime up there.
She'll fall on your head or smash open
like an egg.
Right.
And ever since Matt said that a little
boy,
a cutlet and keeps going,
oh no.
My head or smash like an egg.
And Matt said the image is too lurid for
the child about our handle it,
you know,
like it's too potent an image.
Right.
So me getting married,
like I don't think,
Oh,
I'm getting married in the morning,
like standing.
The only way I think,
well what is marriage?
Marriage is a ceremony.
This is a ritual.
This is about the relinquishing of the
ego.
This is about coming together and making
a vow to become a different man and to
live in alignment with new principals.
So on the causes that I'm looking at,
what,
what you know,
inadvertently accidentally,
we've not consciously,
but somehow actually looking at what is
the meaning of a marriage in juice is a
state in me that's the point of ritual
to induce a particular state.
Meredith says,
my friend Meredith,
she goes,
people think that religion is about the
text.
It is about the ritual.
It doesn't matter if you can't
understand the Latin mass.
Better to just hear a lot of babbling
and something.
What is this guy talking about?
You know,
like,
which I'm sure some people identify with
right now.
Like you know,
it's like the ritual induced the state
in me.
The fear was so terrible.
The fear was so terrible,
Brad,
of what am I going to do?
And I had to use this program to cope
with the level of fear.
I thought about getting married the next
day.
Not any fear about marrying my wife
cause I really wanted and really wanted
to.
But something about that ritual,
that ceremony,
it meant something.
It wasn't nothing.
It wasn't,
oh,
it's a little bit of paper.
So I turn up at Church and then a party.
No,
no,
no.
My friends,
there is the unseen.
There is the invisible.
There were,
there is something happened to me and I
had to surrender 100% I had to
surrender.
I said,
what is this fear trying to tell me,
what does the field one,
the fear is communicate in the fear is
talking to me from my own biochemistry,
for my own body,
from our own consciousness,
a message,
a powerful message is being said sin.
And if I don't listen to it,
something bad is gonna happen to me.
I surrendered,
I surrendered wholeheartedly.
And every time I do that in my life
improves.
New States of consciousness are achieved
through the surrendering of these
biochemical circuits that somehow
containers these neurological loops that
we Lao to encircle us and tether us to
low states of consciousness.
I think you know.
No,
no,
I'm those familiar.
Yesterday on the bus,
I'm taking the of this new state of
consciousness and I,
but I want to connect with,
to
back to a question of philosophy
because,
um,
you know,
the trouble is with this bloody critical
theories as we can't read any book
without actually looking for the
political and philosophical
implications,
right?
Go on.
So,
you know,
like,
I'll read Alice in wonderland,
I go,
this is the best bloody book of
political theory ever written,
right?
But often we read books and actually
most,
a lot of them are just devoid of any
significant philosophical significance
or implications.
In other words,
they don't force you to think about a
problem differently right.
Now,
the one thing which I admired about the
book was it's,
it's actually has a very deep political,
philosophical,
philosophical architecture to it.
And the one thing which I was kind of
struck with the book and what I was kind
of excited when I was reading with his
is when you talk about this attempt to
connect about connection,
you also link it to the question.
Of course,
you know,
life is very fleeting,
life is short and we need to find these
connections and a meaningful existence.
And I what the book really
kind of finds almost like a rescue in
for me is an attempt to introduce
something of the substantive over the
superficial and the substantive for you
is spiritual.
And I was wondering how you can kind of
maybe riff,
you know,
talk maybe a bit more about that,
that you know,
what is it about the spiritual that is
substantive for you in terms of dealing
precisely with maybe the philosophy of
the book or is it a standard about the
spiritual to me is its efficacy.
It works when I do these things,
I feel better when I am kind.
When I'm loving,
when I surrender,
I feel better.
Now these things can't be measured mack
and mechanized or monetize,
but they are in fact in fact effective.
There is some truth in them that is
difficult to legislate or iterate.
So that's right.
Works for me.
And I think perhaps the reason that this
program is so good is I didn't invent
it.
It was invented or constructed by
someone else,
like you know,
in the 19 for easy in America,
a chronic alcoholic bill Wilson,
who after like an incredible source of
an epic drinking binge or the type which
are defined his life,
had what he described as an epiphany.
And I believe epiphany to be the
revelation of essence that previously
concealed revelation of essence would
want to feel this way.
What's going on?
Suddenly,
you know why and bill was an has this
epiphany and realize is that he will
never be able to be free from drink and
the problems that result from it unless
he helps other people to not even
realize he's one he can never drink
again one day at a time too.
He's going to have to help other people
that have the same problem in order to
achieve this state and set about it
immediately.
First of all,
traveling drunks in New York,
going up to people in bars going,
let me help you,
let me help you.
And then predictably saying,
no,
get off and leave me alone.
Then eventually it has this sort of a
program,
uh,
an experience which in the myth of the
foundation of alcoholics anonymous is
the significant moment,
the defining moment in their conception,
I suppose.
Or He's in Akron,
Ohio and it worry for a business
appointment and it comes on him.
He's in the hotel that he's staying at
and he sees the bar and he hears the
music and he's tempted to go in and,
but adjacent to the entrance to the door
is a public telephone.
This is the 1930s,
remember.
And uh,
he takes a chance and he rings up and he
calls up a local priest and says,
look,
if you've got anyone or a doctor,
maybe he calls like a,
have you got any [inaudible] have you
got anyone in this area that's been
coming in going,
I'm a terrible drunk,
helped me help me.
And that guy goes,
yeah,
we are.
He goes,
can you put me in touch with that guy
cause I need some serious help.
Like I want to help him.
And he goes,
Oh yeah,
this guy needs a few more phone calls
here and there as they make the
connection,
but eventually ends up with Doctor Bob,
the other founder of alcoholics
anonymous goes around his eyes and he
says to this guy,
listen,
I've got this problem.
I,
I'm unable to stop drinking once I
start.
It's ruining my life.
I ruined on my relationships with my
job.
Opportunities fall apart.
It's destroying me.
It to him,
he's condition.
The other guy starts talking about his
problems.
The two of them having initially like
the bird there,
apparently the doctor Bob Guy was like,
you know,
I'm only going to tell him like he
totally secretary,
come get this guy off the 10 minutes.
Okay.
It seems a bit weird.
I'm getting phone calls out of blue.
When people want to talk about boots,
they end up talking for hours and hours
and hours.
They recognize at the end of the four
hours that neither of them would want it
to drink during that whole time because
the alcohol is not the problem.
Alcohol is the solution to the problem
of living under the false ideals.
Of a materialistic society.
People are looking for something.
They're looking for connection.
Some people just can't live without that
connection,
so they find another solution to living
without the connection.
Booze,
drugs,
sex,
gambling,
and I think we're all on the scale
somewhere.
All of us are one way or another trying
to come up with it.
They're very,
like couple of days later,
the two of them,
they start going to hospitals,
traveling other people.
Oh,
there in people here that are here
because of alcohol related problems.
Yeah,
that dude over in that bed,
he's been a pain in the ass all night.
You can hear him shouting from behind
the curtain and that the two of them go
over there,
hit him up and suddenly,
you know this,
this is,
you know,
as you know,
a lot more than me,
Brad,
within luckily historical terms,
this is only the 1930s we're in 2017
now.
This thing grows and grows and grows.
People realize,
oh my God,
this works.
It works.
Now that it's written in the Christian
language of the time is written in the
patriarchal terminology of the time.
It's also understandably protective of
its identity.
The anonymity is to make sure that Aa as
a thing is protected and that no one
person,
certainly not me,
can say,
Oh,
I'm Mr Aa because I know that I'm really
still crazy.
I could drink or take drugs tomorrow,
send me captains and you know,
I don't know.
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I'm certainly,
you know,
as I've made clear in the book,
it's not written from a position of
authority.
It's written from a position of
experience and I don't know better than
anybody.
Like I don't know what crazy things I'm
going to do.
I just,
but I know that if I work this program,
I'll be all right.
If I work this program,
The only problem stuff for me when I go,
I think I'll take control of this
situation and starting that cause me
then ego,
desire,
pleasure,
fear,
rage.
The other program steps back in.
So the reason the spirit is important
because it's the only thing that can
transcend the material.
It's the only thing that can house it.
It is the crucible of the material
world.
What is consciousness?
Where did it come from?
What the fucking hell is going on Brad?
Like,
and for me,
this very simple tool,
it gives us access to consciousness in a
way that we will not attain if we live
in accordance with our biochemical
drives and a culture that uses it to
turn us into passive consumers.
Yeah,
I think you can connect this to the
politics of the times in terms of,
you know,
on the one hand,
we constantly told that nobody's in
control,
right?
So we have to accept insecurity,
vulnerability,
and that can lead to a lot of people to
be an anxious.
But what York seemed to be saying is
actually letting go of this very
ridiculous idea that we can be in
control of other people's behaviors,
other people's lives,
like bloody North Korea this morning.
If we dwell on these things,
then we're going to live in the
basically,
you know,
in this constant state of anxiety about
things we can't possibly deal with.
And I think that's kind of,
and how do we seek some kind of
affirmation out of this world.
Maybe the turn,
I just said it a different sense of the
consciousness might be the alternative
to that.
But I want to come back to your story
about you know,
this question of confining.
Cause the example you talk about,
you know,
these two guys were speaking and of
course there they are confiding in one
another and that idea of have to confide
in one another.
That of course requires confidence,
right?
To confide requires confidence.
You need to have the confidence to
confide in somebody and it might be a
random stranger,
but at least you have an established
trust around this kind of sense of,
you know,
of the confidence.
And there's a particular passage I want
to read from the book.
Um,
not only I think because it brought a
tear to my eye and I don't to shut on
your illusions people have of me.
I do have emotions every now and again.
It doesn't seem like it.
I did an excerpt,
the trues on suicide and you,
it's like you're reading the side of a
tin of beans.
I know you're very emotional,
but also because you know,
I think it really addresses what's at
stake here and this kind of,
you know,
it says,
suddenly my fraught and frighten
childhood became reasonable and soothed.
My mum was doing her best and so it was
my bad.
Yes,
people have made mistakes,
but that's what humans do and I am under
no obligation to hoard these errors and
allow them to clutter my perception of
the present.
Yes,
it is wrong that I was abused as a
child,
but there is no reason for me to relive
it consciously or unconsciously in a way
that I conduct my adult relationship,
my perceptions of reality.
Even my own memories are not objective
or absolute.
They are biased and they come be
altered.
Now this to me is a really powerful
passage in the book because what you're
talking about is not only can we
sometimes you know,
decide and we do have a choice around
Utah.
If you talk about the things that we
hold and carry along with us,
I'm not saying that we can ever forget
them or we can outlive them,
but we can choose whether they define
our lives are not.
I'm the fitbit central message,
which I think comes out of this as a
very positive message is if you do
confined in others,
that's where the transformative
potential happens.
You cannot simply trans wake up one day
and say,
I'm going to be an entirely new
subjectivity.
You know,
it doesn't happen that way because in
order to change your behavior,
you need to change your behavior in the
eyes of others,
right?
We are human,
you know,
we're not human beings,
we're human becomings right.
We'd always connecting to people in
disconnecting and reconnecting and in
that sense it requires a certain,
you know,
confidence to transform.
I wondering what you think about it in
terms of your experiences,
Brad.
One of the things that recurs lately
since Yanis Varoufakis it on this
podcast was,
you know,
we exist in dialectic.
What is of like,
you know,
seal me in a pod and shoot me into
space.
Like an,
what am I,
what am I without rf Jarvis cocker,
put it more simply without people.
We are nothing,
you know,
like so like yeah,
quite right that it is a collective and
communal activity.
This book you could learn,
you could read it on your own,
you could do the program on your own,
but primarily it's about how you relate
to yourself and how you relate to other
people.
And uh,
the passage that you read from a book,
just to clarify,
the abuse happened outside of my family
and you're,
the thing that I think is important
about,
um,
you know,
the,
the my stance that you can,
one can alter their perception of the
past and if you will alter your
perception of the past,
you will to the present.
Is that there?
Yeah.
As I said there,
there is no objective reality,
but you're right.
This is going to be a state that's
difficult to achieve.
Just sat in the room.
You go to Chondrocyte that to yourself.
It has to be realized in relationship.
I believe.
Yeah.
Um,
I want to connect this then now then to
the social implications of the project
that you've already talked about.
You know,
you see kind of addiction as something
which is not just an individual
pathology,
but it's a social construct,
right?
We,
you know,
society gives you these certain values
and those values in many ways play to
the human desires in a way which lend
themselves to addictive personalities.
And actually we are taught to desire the
very things which could bring us back
down to it.
You know,
on our knees.
And there's something about the tub log
pressing Britain,
which is kind of revealing of this,
you know,
we'd like nothing more than the
celebrity who falls,
right?
Because it's almost like this,
that's not the system failing.
It's working all too well,
right?
Because we kind of expect us,
We want this to kind of happen and you
know,
but I want to kind of connect it also to
your other work on,
and I think you know,
some of the other powerful work and
advocacy work you've done on the war on
drugs and Lincoln,
this question of addiction to drugs.
Now as we know,
historically the war on drugs has been
kind of separated between almost like a
war legal paradigm versus a Health
Development Paradigm.
Now I think,
you know,
the shift towards seeing it as a health
problem is a positive shift away from
the wall paradigm.
But too often when we shifted then to
the health paradigm,
it invariably retreats back into
individual pathology,
right?
It's the person who's just simply a
fault because you know,
they've fallen through the cracks or
whatever else.
And I think what your book is also
trying to do is add another layer onto
this and say,
yes,
you know,
addiction is a health problem.
It's a mental health problem.
But unless we understand the social
consequences and the social effects
which give rise to this problem and
constantly feed it,
then we will not gain a real tangible
purchase on this.
And you know,
I wonder what your thoughts on this,
cause this is to me is I find is really
important in terms of really pushing the
debate forward on addiction and the war
on drugs more generally.
And my question of violence and
everything else which follows the
criminalization of drugs is a useful
social yeah.
In the management of populations.
And this has been explored in films like
13th and the House I live in brilliant
films on,
uh,
how the criminalization of drugs allows
you to,
uh,
portions of the population,
you know,
form of Niekro politics,
creating new economies,
new opportunities for social management
and social engineering,
particularly in the United States
economically requires slavery in some
form to sustain itself.
[inaudible] health model.
You're right,
that's it.
I hadn't really thought of that,
of that.
The implications of a health model is a
determinant means that individual
pathology is the,
is southernly the defining contribute to
the condition.
There is clearly a relationship like a
young man Hari's written about addiction
and he like the example he sites his rat
park where you know rats that were kept
in conditions like that.
You know like cause it's interesting
you'll love this is a a postmodernist
dear brad that there's the assumption of
what normal is in in laboratory
conditions though they with unthinkingly
uh,
have this is normal and they put rats in
cages and got a lot of these wraps.
They much prefer the water bottle that
was full of crack cocaine,
the normal water and then someone point
out,
oh no mate,
it's probably horrible.
Avoid that cage and sorry.
All right let's give him a nice cage
then we've all,
you know,
good shit to do.
And they stopped taking crack curiously
enough.
So you know there is undoubtedly like
addiction can affect anybody but
particularly chemical dependency but it
is certainly exacerbated by economic
depravity.
But there are different forms of
Also emotional depravity is like,
it's not a condition that the,
the sort of the economically deprived
people have exclusively control of hello
be nice from turf exclusive and trolling
or something.
But it's effects are felt more there.
If you can't get into treatment,
if you can't afford to address it is
more likely that you,
you know,
I mean you're criminalized from the get
go.
You're already a criminal.
So now is what degree of criminality is
it that you're going to cop for?
When I went to that,
um,
I went on a police raid in west London
once and it was like,
you know,
it was,
it was a very revelator re-experienced
for me Brad.
Cause like the bad the door in of what
was a crack house.
Like you know,
even the term crack house once I've got
like even me as a person that's been
crack houses,
I've never really sort of questioned the
idea that that's,
that's an Aos,
it's not really a crack house.
And you went here like we went in there
and bought dwelt within the crack house
was not monsters.
It was like beating down the door of the
leukemia ward,
thin,
emaciated,
broken people slumped,
Pale in a chair,
denied sunlight of every variety,
spiritual and literal just holding their
lives together with drugs and that it's
interestingly circular that this program
on an individual level takes from self
obsession and narcissism and deposits.
You are a point of service and kindness
because that is precisely the program
that's required on a social level that
if we have an inclusive,
empathetic,
loving society that that necessarily you
the these you include people,
it would become a more inclusive
society.
I think this model of sacrifice that
exists within Christianity,
the,
the sacrifice.
God for me,
I apply in my life when I ever I see
suffering,
I think that guy's homeless so I don't
have to be a mate of mine.
Got his leg amputated recently and he is
a person who works this program.
Like I met him at a sort of a conference
for drug addicts,
very badly organized and,
and he was on crutches and like,
Oh you white mate.
I'd only met him once before,
you know,
it was a nice guy,
but I didn't know him that well.
You're right.
It's called Pete.
Are you all right mate?
He goes,
Oh yeah,
I go,
what's with the crutches,
you know,
expecting are,
a trip to broke my ankle.
Some sort of minor interest story.
And he goes,
Oh,
I've got cancer.
I'm having my leg amputated at the knee
and I've fucking ill bloody.
And he goes,
no,
I'm good.
I want to live.
I want to be clean.
And I was sort of like some wave hit me
of like the truth of what he was saying
and the beauty cell four oh learn about
this person.
I'll call his number,
stayed in touch with the week leading up
to the amputation.
He's fine the night before.
The amputation is fine for at the
amputation.
I speak to them the next day.
He's on a,
on a bed,
admittedly on opiates because of the
nature of the pain medication.
It were blissfully happy and he
continues to be because with this
program,
this is a program is effective.
He transcends the material condition and
just says,
well,
my leg is being amputated.
I can't control that,
but I can control my reaction to my leg
being amputated and I think about this.
I can't get it obviously out of my head.
How was this guy managing this?
How is he doing it?
Because he's not putting it on and I'm
talking to him every day or at Ross,
some just doing this thing.
Yeah,
I'm doing of recording another thing
today.
So also he's happy and the reason is is
because he's accepted it.
He surrendered it.
He's working this program and he's
getting on with his life.
He's not gone now.
I will be defined by this problem and
that's unbelievable.
That's unbelievable to me,
that is that powerful and it's that
effective.
Now he does this again,
as we say in communion,
in conversations,
so it works on an individual level,
but you're quite right brad.
It's not something that we should
ascribe to individual pathology because
where are these bloody boundaries?
What do you mean an individual?
We're all made of the same stuff.
We're all thinking the same force rules,
feeling the same feelings other than the
variety provided by cultural inflection
and social conditions were all basically
basically the same.
So like if we have systems that
encourage empathy,
if we have systems that emphasize the
Corolla and connection between us,
then we will build a better.
So I think,
yeah,
and I want to push you on the,
the title,
which is recovery.
And I think,
you know,
you could offer almost like a simplistic
reductive reading of the title,
which is almost like,
you know,
how can you kind of go back to a
previous better self?
Right?
So how do I recover myself?
It's almost like the George Best
question.
I,
where does it all go wrong in your life?
Right?
And then if you can pinpoint this,
but as we go,
as you see,
you know,
for a lot of people who are in this
condition,
it's the social forces,
the complex social forces that is no
pinpointable moment in somebody's life
where you can say,
this is kind of what it all goes wrong.
But I think the way I understand in the
way you're using the term recovery also
is also a critique of the idea that we
can live a perfectible life under.
The,
one of the striking things which comes
out for me of this is kind of a humility
with what you're talking about is,
you know,
on the one hand,
not only not to take yourself too
seriously,
although we have,
you know,
we have to deal with serious issues in
the world,
but also this idea that it's okay not to
be okay sometimes and to admit this is
no bad thing.
That's true and this is something,
again,
I've only really found in,
we've been spiritual conversations and
spiritual,
not not in the right word,
but it's like for me,
this has always been framed spiritually.
Like when I talked to Sharon Salzberg on
this podcast,
she said that when you're meditating is
normal,
that you start thinking all the time.
You don't punish yourself for that.
You just returned to the mantra or
return to the breath.
You accept fallibility as part of the
part of the equation of your humanity
that you to a degree relinquish the idea
of perfection but sort of somewhat
paradoxically I suppose Brad,
uh,
the,
the one of the meanings or implications
of the term recovery is that you recover
the person you're supposed to be
supposed to be an info Commons I
suppose,
but meaning that I natural bio chemical
entities that as a human being or a tree
does have in it a code,
it has an intention,
it will grow a certain way if unimpeded
by,
in our case,
social,
cultural,
personal,
familial conditions.
So what this,
the point of recovery is,
is to get you back onto that intended
path.
And it is my belief that the intended
path is not to be a passive consumer.
It just cooperates as an,
as a unit within a,
within a system of sales.
Just as a statistic,
we are engaged.
We must re be reborn until the present
so that we can become really what we are
so that we can become what we are.
Yeah.
So
did of rebirth.
I'm going to kind of try to end then on
a very positive note and go,
and then at the start of the book you
deal with the big impending d or The
death question,
right?
So nothing more positive than death.
Right?
Um,
and as you pointed out here,
the introduction,
the reality of death individually and
yet it's certain,
right,
is something we don't like to talk about
publicly.
Um,
and yet of course we know from Plato
onwards there's this idea that to is
effectively to lay it out,
to die,
I need to learn and to death might not
be a physical death.
It might be the death of a relationship
or the death of,
you know,
an idea of the death of a person you
once were.
And you can kind of more than this,
right?
But I don't,
however think this goes far enough and I
think actually we might need to take it
a stage further.
And there's a quote from David Bowie
when he puts it,
he says,
religion is for people who fear how
spirituality is for people who have been
there.
Now,
I think with this in mind,
I think the question your book kind of
leaves me asking is how can we learn to
examine our lives in a way in which may
be,
as you say,
the addict,
you know,
has a certain experiential value,
right?
Because they have seen rock bottom,
They can look at life almost the example
you give of the people who are deprived
of light,
right?
In this amazing created state,
they know what it means to look at life
from the perspective of death,
right?
The old must already dead,
So I think,
you know,
in terms of then your hopes for the
book,
you know,
and looking at the future,
how can we learn and maybe take the
voices of these people much more
seriously in terms of if we appreciate
we're all kind of knee deep in the mud,
right?
And we know existence is tragic,
but we know existence is also wonderful.
All right.
So how can we maybe learn to go beyond
this question of just simply learning
how to die and look at life from the
perspective of death and become much
more affirmative of what we actually
have in this all too fleeting existence?
Well,
for me,
Brad,
it's become certain,
quite simplistic attitude or north
shifts such as acceptance,
gratitude that I relinquish the idea
that the,
I'm not homeless in a Gob smacked up off
my nut because I'm somehow superior,
but just because of a sort of a random
set of coordinates and events have
deposited me in a comfortable life and
I'm really,
really lucky and gracious so I don't
have a punitive attitude towards those
people.
And I see him in like,
you know,
sort of sometimes he'll write ourselves,
but where I came as repositories,
it potentially of great truves and um,
important information.
Uh,
one of the recovery charities
organizations that do work with it,
Bac O'connor,
they run facilities in Burton on trend
in their United Kingdom and stoke on
Trent in the middle and as those areas.
And I went to an event with them the
other day and like just spoke to that
service users,
which means in this case,
drug addicts and stuff and like to talk
through what they're doing in their
program.
The counselors,
a good number of the counselors
themselves,
people in recovery,
which I think is always very,
very helpful.
And then afterwards,
my wife was there and that sort of sat
in there.
They put on a lovely spread for us.
God loves them.
You know,
some Christian,
maybe something even as far flung as
Bruschetta a,
but the kind of Bruschetta would get in
stoke on Trent.
Yeah.
Catch up.
May have been involved.
I manage,
I can,
it's perfectly nice.
Anyway,
there's this bloke there who was a
proper to glance at like if you can
imagine shaggy from the cartoons,
Scooby Doo,
but he slept outside for a year and he's
had a bloody good kick in and no dental
work.
Like this is what this guy looked like,
fin broken and uh,
like drug addicts obviously.
And I like,
he's sort of,
he's come lay and he's fin is fuck.
And he's like,
ransacking the buffet quite gently,
you know,
just thinking of this food.
Then I'll take that and sort of packing
out and stuff and all goes,
all right mate.
And that goes,
oh yeah,
your urine.
Yeah.
And I'm like,
yeah,
that's right.
And,
and the like,
because I'm like,
when I'm among other people that have
got addiction issues,
I feel like I don't have the obligation
to try and act like I know what I'm
doing or that I'm clever or that I'm in
control.
And I said,
sank too about feeling like,
oh yeah,
like I maybe mentioned fame in some
capacity.
And I go,
yeah,
but I do get like,
get nervous and I get frightened.
He goes,
what'd you get it?
And for you like your,
you're Russell brand and like,
who cares what other people think about,
you know,
if you would imagine there's people that
know you if they don't know you're
fucking right.
Now,
obviously this is highly colloquial,
but like,
uh,
also for me is sort of profound and
beautiful and also the fact that he's
even willing to take that role when
meeting someone who's,
they're sort of visiting in kind of
like,
I'm here as a patron of this
organization,
but that he,
like,
he's not like dumbfounded by the idea
that I'm nervous and fearful.
He accepts,
Oh,
this guy is just the same as me and
there's an honor in that,
you know,
a real honor.
And I think they've awakened people not
only realize it but somehow can live it.
I'm sort of realizing it,
but the challenge is living in,
you know,
like that is,
there is no distinction.
There is no separation between him and
me.
We were all experiencing it.
We're like,
as the Great Bill Hicks said,
we were all one consciousness
experiencing itself subjectively.
And when I realize I'm live,
that I'm not on my own anymore,
I'm not afraid anymore.
I don't have these obligations to prop
up some Avatar of myself that people
might love or approve of or boost up or
make much off to ameliorate some inner
sense of worthlessness.
There is uh,
the,
the solve is in the wound,
the salvage in the wound.
You know,
when someone punishingly says I'm
worthless,
I am nothing.
Is it trying to reach the truth beneath
that that we are essentially not
divided,
separate from and therefore are
everything in the one.
This is not about annihilation of the
self as in the subjugation,
you know,
sort of refer to your work in a violent
and destructive way.
But the recognition that there is no
need for fear and there is no disease
need for desire because we are already
one,
we are already one and that these things
are not just philosophical tropes or
empty mantras.
They are things you can live by
recognizing that your own suffering can
become a tool and the suffering of
others can be an opportunity.
If you can just break out of the
preexisting and imposed paradigm that
you are here to earn money that you're
worth is established by what you've got.
You know,
and like,
oh Jason Segel the act,
so I'm friends with him and he went all
those things we defined ourselves by
like,
you know,
maybe there's a billboard up with your
face on it.
It's just the symptoms of other people
making money out of you.
It's not you,
not you.
And all of that being flown around in a
jet and fate it over like,
cause that's not something to fear not
doing.
That's something too.
We've escaped because,
gosh,
yes,
it's a,
in it's way,
it's,
there is glamour.
They of course,
glamour is a thing.
People respond to it,
pleasure and all of those things,
but there's no real worth in it.
Like I met that homeless guy once and
let not,
no,
he was not homeless.
He was going to what?
It was some homeless people.
I met him in New Orleans and he was off
to go and sort of help out or some
homeless deal,
you know,
feeding homeless people.
And he didn't recognize that was famous,
that sweaty guy.
And he said to me,
um,
a fame money,
all of that.
That's the crumbs I want to be at.
The bank quit the bank,
quit and somehow been tricked into
finger near.
That's what real religious people tell
you that actually,
you know,
you'll get out of wine.
I'm crack on.
We it didn't,
but this is not about subjugation.
This is not about asset as Susan.
This is not about denial.
This is about finding the truth.
And often the material world is
preventing you from,
from getting there,
is preventing you from getting there.
Cause we caught up and you want to
mentation and we can't see that we're
all part of one garment.
Yeah.
So then to kind of sum up,
the one thing which I've take really
taken from the book,
um,
is being alone and loneliness is the
greatest killer.
It's it because not only does it result
in people dying prematurely,
but I can kill your sense of self esteem
and dignity.
And the two,
I guess messages,
which I wanted maybe just reiterate it
for why take from the book is that if
you are feeling alone,
speak to someone or if you see in
somebody who's lonely,
just give them a helping hand because
they probably need you more than you
realize.
And I think that to me is the one thing
that I wanted didn't you know,
to take from the book and is that how,
you know,
do you have any final comments on that
or do you try to remind myself when I'm
talking to people like about,
I'm talking to another human being and I
tried to talk to them with love and
respect and often if the,
if the opportunity is explicit,
like you know,
if it's,
I'm dealing with someone that's got drug
and alcohol problems or some other
problem that I identify with,
this is an opportunity to be loving.
I forget this all the time.
I'm a pretty long distance from
perfection.
But like I tried to remember,
you know like Oh God,
you didn't really look at that person in
the eyes.
You didn't make it an attempt to connect
with them,
but we can come from a perspective of
love.
We don't need to only be coming from
self preservation.
We're not all here competing for
resources.
It's a yes was perhaps there's some
evolutionary truth to that millennia
ago,
but it's not true now what are here to
help one another and in deciding that we
can create it all,
it's a pleasure.
As always,
challenge to Russell and you know,
thank you for the opportunity to get
under the skin with you and turning the
tables around.
That was a bloody good wrap up Brad.
Thank you so much for doing it.
It's really lovely to talk to you.
Obviously a very beautiful person and
you're clever and what?
It doesn't matter what I say.
I could gotten such a long run in like
where I'm referencing Zen Buddhism,
Bloody Jack Kerouac consciousness
itself,
biochemistry and I could,
it'd be good.
Yup.
Okay.
I like your minds three seconds faster
than mine,
which I don't like incidentally.
Thank you,
Brad.
Pleasure.
This show was sponsored by my new book
recovery.
Preorder your copy by going to Russell
brand.com
and if you like this show,
please subscribe and review in itunes
only five star reviews,
please.
I'm very sensitive.