I was fascinated by how particular,
it becomes like juror number free.
She didn't like us by that kind of
thing.
How particular it becomes and that we've
got a sway that person,
she will be swayed by x,
Y,
zed.
And it becomes very sort of bespoke,
doesn't it?
Well,
um,
you know,
as when we're picking jurors,
uh,
the way,
at least I view him,
is there a certain jurors who I consider
to be fillers
just go with the flow.
Exactly.
They're not going to affect
the jury deliberation a one way or the
other.
Um,
so I don't worry terribly much about the
fillers.
Well,
how do you identify a Filler,
uh,
by talking to them?
Uh,
and,
and that's the key attributes of a
filler.
Uh,
the key attribute of a filler is,
um,
uh,
sort of a timid personality,
who doesn't seem to express any views in
any sort of a strong way.
Um,
you know,
just,
just that sort of mousy person who's
sitting in the corner and you just sort
of know,
uh,
that,
if,
if things get rough,
they want
void it conflict of a,
exactly.
Exactly.
Um,
you want a few of them?
Oh No,
I'm happy.
I'm happy to have as many of them as we
can in 12.
I don't,
well,
no,
because you need at least one leader.
Yeah.
You need to leave now with the lead.
And that's what you're thinking,
right?
This guys,
I myself from a bisexual continually
being accused of pushing people down the
stairs I've had just about enough of,
exactly,
exactly.
And,
and generally
we're going to,
you know,
you're going to focus in on and there's
going to be three or four people,
uh,
in any group that gets selected,
have 12 that are not going to be
fillers.
Uh,
and,
and they're going to have various
degrees of,
of leadership qualities.
And,
you know,
this is all sort of armchair psychology
as well.
Although,
you know,
he's strictly enough now with social
media,
uh,
we get to,
you know,
if you,
if you have the resources,
you start looking at people's social
media and you get really interesting
insights into their,
into their,
uh,
ways of thinking
based,
they attended that rally.
Exactly.
Yes.
Um,
but,
um,
so you'll get three or four people who
you think these are people who can
really affect the deliberation.
So there's this whole,
you know,
there's the theater of the case itself,
whether it's the famous staircase or any
case.
Then there's this secondary reality that
takes place,
annexed off over there where the 12
jurors go off.
And in a sense that's,
you can't really can,
you can influence but not control what
takes place there.
So then here's a good example.
No.
So in,
in the Peterson case,
where was one juror in particular?
Uh,
an older black man who we just got the
sense all the way through,
was really skeptical of the and their
theory.
Well,
it's just rolling his eyes.
Yeah,
exactly.
Body language,
right.
Um,
anyway,
uh,
so,
and it was pretty,
I think everybody in the courtroom sort
of got the same sense.
Uh,
anyway,
so the jury goes out to deliberate in,
in North Carolina.
They're not sequestered.
They don't,
they don't have to stay in a hotel or
anything.
They go home.
Uh,
well,
uh,
over that next weekend on a Saturday
night,
uh,
apparently this juror got stopped by the
police,
uh,
and accused of a driving while
intoxicated,
which he claimed he wasn't.
Uh,
he got arrested.
and we went into court that next Monday
morning and the DA stood up and move to
excuse that juror on grounds that the
juror had,
had,
uh,
been,
resistant to the police that he was
going to be angry,
that he'd gotten arrested,
that he couldn't be fair to the state,
uh,
and succeeded in getting that you're,
knocked off the juror who took that
person's place was a white female about
the age of Kathleen,
uh,
who was an engineer,
which Kathleen also was.
Uh,
and we found out later and the juror
was,
the jury was split at that point.
It was I think three guilty,
three not guilty and six undecided.
Um,
and then once a new jury joints,
they have to restart the node,
the,
the deliberations.
I don't know know quite how they do
that,
but they're supposed to do that.
Um,
and that your ended up being the
foreperson of the jury,
the one who came on a and she ended up
leading the charge to convict Peterson.
Um,
so,
and for all we know,
they deliberately arrested that guy and
the whole thing's constructed
that,
eh,
the thought crossed my mind more than
once
because there's a game because it's a
gay member as a game.
There's so convoluted and so much of the
process is not explicit.
So much of it is masked necessarily mask
that you're subject to influences.
They're very difficult to account for to
the point in fact were not only your own
attitude to truth,
which seems very sort of actually quite
gnostic and beautiful.
Like I,
it's not my job to ascertain truth.
It's my job to serve,
which sounds like kind of a spiritual
and beautiful idea.
In the end it becomes like there is no
objectivity at all,
only power and how power can exert
itself.
And
well,
that's certainly true in the criminal
justice system.
Uh,
you know,
we,
we've seen that time and time again with
all these exonerations of people,
uh,
who spent decades in prison,
and then,
you know,
the DNA testing,
uh,
establishes that they weren't guilty.
Uh,
so what,
why did they spend all their time in
prison?
Uh,
uh,
and generally it's because of the of
power is because the police decided that
they knew better.
I knew best and that person was guilty.
Uh,
and then tunnel vision sort of kicks in.
So you have a combination of arrogance
and tunnel vision,
uh,
and,
they ignore the evidence that's
inconsistent with their own theories
because they're arrogant and they have
tunnel vision,
uh,
and they inflate the importance of the
evidence that is consistent with their
predispositions.
Oh,
it's called confirmation bias.
We all suffer from it.
It's just particularly pernicious in the
criminal justice system
in a sense.
Power kind of admit to its fallibility
extensively without undermining its
foundations.
Exactly.
I mean,
if,
uh,
if the authority is not infallible,
then it loses its authority and then
we'll just choose some other,
okay.
[inaudible] right.
This is infallible and
yes.