Sam harris.
He's a writer,
neuroscientist,
philosopher and host of the podcast,
waking up with Sam Harris.
He's written five New York Times
bestsellers covering a range of topics
from neuroscience and religion to
violence and human reasoning.
These include the end of faith letter to
a Christian nation,
free will and the moral landscape.
He's the Co founder and Chief Executive
of Project Reason and nonprofit
organization that promotes science and
secularism and as argued that science
can determine moral values.
He's previously studied both eastern and
Western religious traditions including
Buddhism,
Hinduism,
making several trips to India and Nepal.
He is now a proponent of secular
meditation practices.
He's a vegetarian practices Brazilian
Jujitsu and is married with two
daughters and has a correction.
I'm going to have to recant on the
vegetarian there a can in the
vegetarianism for the moment.
I unfortunately,
it's exactly like a pasta.
Well,
welcome.
Thank you.
Regardless of the embracing the Avatar
that I'm trailing vine.
Yeah.
Um,
thanks for coming on.
I've talked to you for such a long time.
Oh yeah.
And I've heard from so many of our
mutual audience members that we should
be getting together.
So,
because I suppose in the works for a
long time,
yeah,
yeah.
We exist in that sort of a,
in the sonic boom created by Joe Rogan
perhaps.
Yeah.
Maybe.
How'd you want Joe Rogan?
I listened to waking up and I've heard a
bunch of your stuff.
I saw you on Joe Rogan as well.
So yeah,
Joe Joe is the,
the 800 pound gorilla of podcasters.
Casey is,
everyone knows.
Yeah,
he's the
very much that we are all orbiting Joe
Rogan let's face yet.
And like,
God,
there's so much stuff I want to ask you
about,
but you know,
because there's loads of things we agree
on loads,
but there are some pretty distinct
things that I imagine we disagree on.
And I suppose these will be some of the,
some interesting things to,
to,
um,
to analyze.
Um,
but just to start us off,
um,
I suppose,
tell us a little bit about that.
The,
the fusion of neuroscience,
philosophy and atheism and the,
the,
it's become sort of the,
the defining of people's perception of
you,
but there's a sort of a,
I suppose a neurological,
a underwriting for your sort of personal
perspective of atheism and how you fit
in,
what you've learned in this sort of like
the 10 years since you've come to
prominence and how your positions
perhaps evolved.
Yeah.
Well,
the,
the atheism connection is probably just
an accident of history more than
anything because it really is what
happened to my intellectual life right
after September 11th.
So I was doing my neuroscience phd,
I had a background in philosophy.
I was,
I went into neuroscience very much with
the interest of a philosopher.
I was,
I was always interested in understanding
the human mind at a,
uh,
a high,
a level that really about,
would only be doing work in,
in people.
And I'm not,
I wasn't ever thinking of curing
diseases.
And it was all about just understanding
human subjectivity and consciousness and
morality and,
uh,
human reason.
The,
these were the kinds of,
uh,
higher level mental attributes that
interested in me.
And so I was doing my,
I was in the middle of my phd.
I had done my coursework,
I was getting into neuro imaging work on
belief.
I was studying the difference between
belief and disbelief and uncertainty.
And then September 11th happened and I
had,
I had a background in meditation.
I had a background in explicitly,
uh,
trying to cash out rather ancient
spiritual concerns,
um,
uh,
through whatever methodology was
available.
So I had,
you know,
had taken psychedelics in my twenties.
I had spent about two years on silent
retreat.
I was,
you know,
very connected to the experiential side
of what people think they're only
religion is good at.
Right.
But I was not a believer,
uh,
of,
of any sort.
I was,
um,
I was an atheist,
but I never thought of myself as an
atheist.
I was totally unaware of atheism as an
organized political movement.
I couldn't have told you who Madelyn,
Mario hair was.
I mean,
there's a famous atheist.
I,
you know,
I was aware of people like Richard
Dawkins for their science,
but I was not someone who had read books
on atheism.
And so my first book,
the end of faith,
which,
which really was the really initiated
this,
this publishing phenomenon that was
called the new atheism.
I,
because then it was,
it was me and then Dawkins,
and then I came out with my second book
and then Dan Dennett and Christopher
Hitchens,
all of us had these books that came out.
Um,
I never even used the word atheism in
the end of faith.
And it was,
it wasn't that I thought not to use it,
it just was not a word I used.
So I was just talking about the,
the conflict between reason and faith,
the con conflict between science and
religion,
the,
the obvious untenable realty.
I mean that the actual proper horror of
the fact that we have a world that has
shattered into these separate religious
communities and these separate and
incommensurable worldviews based on an
adherence to these ancient books.
Uh,
and that strikes me as,
and then as it struck me then,
and it strikes me now as just as
perverse as people blowing themselves up
over rival interpretations of
Shakespeare.
And I mean,
just imagine there was some hamlet cult
versus some king lear cult,
right?
And people are willing to die for these
differences.
Those cults exists.
But that,
that's the world we're living in.
I mean,
our world is just that absurd.
And so I reacted to all of this in the
aftermath of September 11th,
uh,
without ever defining myself in my own
mind as someone who was now shilling for
atheism.
But then I got inducted into this,
into the conversation about atheism.
So it,
it's,
it's somewhat ironic that atheist is one
of the first words that in my bio,
but it's not,
it's not an
no.
Was retrospectively applied or though
your [inaudible] you say you were kind
of the insight in incident of your
public life.
Your life is a public in a lecturer was
nine 11,
which you,
uh,
rigidly defined as a,
I said,
I've suppose judging from what you've
just said as a,
a religious event primarily or an act of
religious violence.
Oh yeah.
Well it was,
it was clearly that you might want to
talk about other variables that could
explain it or that could of could of,
uh,
other motives that,
that people might have.
You know,
you might want to talk about politics or
economics or,
or,
um,
US foreign policy with a legacy of
colonialism.
But I think it is absolutely clear that
while those variables account for some
of them,
the misbehavior in our world,
there are still people who get up in the
morning with 100% of their motivation
being a religious expectation of an
afterlife.
I mean,
these people exist.
I can just find you these people who
have none of the other variables that
people would want to use to explain.
And the terrestrial variables,
economics,
politics,
there are people who have never suffered
any economic insecurity who devote their
life to Jihad.
There are people who drop out of the
London School of economics who are
British citizens so that they can go
fight with Isis.
So,
and it's,
what does that to you imply the toxicity
of religious ideology?
Well,
it's,
it's the power of belief.
It's not even,
it's not even,
it's not even purely toxic.
I mean,
this is the,
the horrible paradox here.
I think the experience of people even in
the,
even in the most extreme,
and we might want to say psychopathic
cults,
right?
Something like Isis.
The experience by and large is not of
being a psychopath.
It's a,
it's not like Isis.
And again,
now we're sort of now focusing on,
obviously my criticism of religion is
much wider than focusing on
fundamentalist Islam.
But to take this case,
many people think that Isis was acting
like a bug light for the world.
Psychopaths that only psychopaths would
go over there and behave this badly and
then you,
what you're talking about is bad people
who would behave badly anyway.
These are people who were going to rape
and kill any way and they just found an
excuse or a,
or a pretext by which to do it under the
ages of religion.
That's just not true.
I mean,
we just know enough about the bios of
these people that it's,
and you would never say that of someone
who was observing some other religious
behavior slavishly under,
under some doctrines.
He wouldn't say that,
you know,
that you wouldn't explain the behavior
of people at the mass,
the Catholic mass,
you know,
where they line up to eat a cracker.
You wouldn't say,
well this is just,
you know,
politically motivated,
crack reading behavior of these people
would find pretext,
eat crackers on Sundays anyway.
You know,
they would,
they would ritualize their cracker
eating behavior for some other reason.
No,
no.
They have a belief that explains exactly
what they're doing with this cracker.
And they'll tell you,
and,
and it's,
it's just not,
it's,
it's a doctrine that they're following.
And if a doctor,
if the doctor and said,
eat two crackers,
they'd be in two crackers.
Sure.
But like I personally,
and presumably you would agree with
this,
the Catholic mass is serving a
particular function as all ritual and
ceremonies and the literalness if the
cracker is secondary to it's evident,
perfunctory role,
uh,
as I,
a place for social cohesion,
acknowledgement of mortality and the
potential for the human soul or the
human essence to aspire to something
beyond the carnal blood and body drives.
If we take Christ from a more
theological as opposed to sort of a,
in a sort of reductive simplistic.
And I think for me personally,
spiritually useless perspective as,
as like the metaphor of Christ being
that the potential for transcendence
beyond the flesh individual to the
enlightened male that Oh,
the enlightened being I suppose,
uh,
then the sort of the mass for me is an
opportunity to ceremoniously
acknowledged that meaning.
So like I,
I would look at a mass and go,
oh,
this ain't about literally in crackers
and like,
and in even the metaphor as explicitly
stated in the scriptural terms of that
denomination,
there's more that even that is limited.
I would say that people drive to do that
as,
as Mariam is Mariam.
So you're,
you're,
you're flipping the logic of what I'm
saying.
So I'm saying that the thing that
explains the actual ritual,
the cracker eating is the doctrine,
right?
If the doctrine,
we're different,
if the doctrine where if Jesus had said,
well,
this bread is,
it has nothing to do with my body.
So it doesn't matter what you do at the
mass,
right?
Don't eat anything right to eat anything
is to pollute your body.
You should just be thinking about me,
right?
If that was the doctrine,
there would be no cracker eating ritual,
right?
So that,
so the doctrine is,
it says,
I mean,
it's a bizarre act of,
of,
you know,
human sacrifice and cannibalism at the,
at the bottom of it,
which doesn't make a hell of a lot of
sense.
But if you look at the roots of
agricultural diety worship and the
relationship between the known and the
unknown and the necessity to have
relationship with plants or season,
it doesn't,
it doesn't
gonna be eating his body like,
like,
like they wouldn't the,
the people
except as a metaphor for union.
Yeah.
But in oneness.
Except it's not taught.
It's not preached as a metaphor and the
doctrine's not metaphorical.
I will grant you that many,
many people aren't thinking about it
literally now.
But that's just to say they've lost
their faith in the actual doctrine of
the,
and I think that's important.
And also I think we have to look beyond
rationalism.
I think when we're dealing,
you know,
you are a man who is deeply interested
in mysticism and spirituality in
anything.
Once it's on the plane of the corporal
and the rational,
then it to evaluate the symbols purely,
rationally,
they're always going to be sort of kind
of left wanting because yeah,
the in a wafer or drinking some wine.
But if you have a relationship with the
wholeness,
I would be slow to conclude that I
think,
I don't think you have to be irrational
to use these tools
or beyond rational,
not the rational,
not like a necessarily less than
rational,
possibly more than that.
Clearly more than form any rational
understanding of the universe.
There's more to life than that.
I mean there's,
there's,
there's fun,
there's love,
there's beauty,
there's,
there's uh,
there's more that we want out from life
than simply not being wrong.
Right?
So I'm not saying that that reason is
everything,
but the question is,
do you ever have to be irrational to go
beyond merely conceptually understanding
the world?
Do you ever have to lie to yourself?
Do you ever ever have to have to lie to
others or believe the lies of others to
go beat,
go into these other areas that,
that no one would know.
But most people are living as though
absolutely you do that because religion
is just the most profligate example of
lying that,
that any and self deception.
We mentioned it.
Politics is it,
I mean it's
every bit as bad except then it just,
it pauses an afterlife where it gets all
cashed out
except of course,
you know,
like again to return to the point about
nine 11 new or particularly induction.
Sure.
Wittingly or otherwise I into what's
being come known as the new atheistic
movement.
That for me,
what,
this is a question I suppose if that
particular event taken in isolation,
is it like,
you know,
Bob Barry can horrific and dreadfully
cinematic and totemic.
Uh,
but definitely taking place within a
historical context.
For me,
they're very variables that you,
fleetingly mentioned economics,
colonialism,
these like how do we delineate,
how do we sort of,
where are these imaginary lines drawn
between this is religious violence,
this is political violence.
This is acceptable violence to who draws
those lines.
Also,
they can be very easily drawn when you,
when you take the case of any individual
and his or her motives
individuals,
yeah,
we have to resort to individualism as
opposed to cultural,
national movements.
You have to take that individual is
crazy.
But that state and that state action,
I would first say that very few of these
people are crazy.
So let me just break this down a little
bit because there are many different
types of violence and so there,
there are,
there are crazy people who are just
crazy in,
in the,
uh,
the more clinical sense of that term,
which is,
which is to say they're suffering some
thought disorder.
They're,
they're,
they're suffering from some kind of
delusion,
right?
So,
you know,
many of the people that are
schizophrenia,
but,
but you know,
there are probably other ways we want
to,
um,
class a thought disorder here,
but they're not,
they're not rational.
They don't have rational goals.
They're hearing voices.
They think they're talking to the,
you know,
the,
the son of Sam thought his dog was
telling him to kill people.
Next door's dog at all.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah,
we're still,
yes,
exactly.
Pay attention to your own dark,
rough night.
Um,
so yes,
and different from everyone else.
People who are mentally ill are not
dangerous.
But there are some people who are
mentally ill who are right now,
there are people who do horrific things
for no ideological motive,
no rational animus,
but purely because they're crazy,
right?
So you take like every one example would
be probably this Guy Adam Lanza who went
into the school in Newtown and killed 20
some odd children and,
and half a dozen teachers,
right?
I think 26 people were gunned down.
He,
I don't know what,
I don't know if anyone gave a diagnosis.
I mean he was probably almost certainly
on the autistic spectrum,
but he had something else going on,
but he didn't,
he wasn't a white supremacist who had
some ideology who was,
who was acting out in this way.
He wasn't a jihadist who thought he was
going to get into paradise.
Right?
So,
uh,
and there are many other examples of
mass shootings like that.
Jared lauffner was a guy like that.
You know who,
um,
uh,
whereas you,
if you're going to talk to this person
and find out why he did it,
nothing is going to make sense right
now.
That is very different.
And yet,
so that we could talk about the same
superficial crime of going in and
killing children in a school,
right?
Uh,
there's that version of it.
Then there's the,
uh,
really angry,
and I would argue,
psychopathic,
sadistic,
eat classically evil person who just
wants to kill kids,
right?
Who just gets off on all of the misery
he's going to create as a result of this
crime.
Now this person is not suffering a
thought disorder.
Now we,
if we knew more about the brain,
I think in the end we would,
we would be happy to say,
well,
there's still something wrong with this
guy's brain.
I mean,
we're human evil is a species of
neurological disorder,
but we don't understand it yet.
And so now where it's tempting just to
say,
well,
these people are evil,
right?
It's a very different kind of person
from the first person.
Um,
and yeah,
there's probably into the boundary
between those people are or can be kind
of fluid,
but,
but you know,
these are different types of people.
No,
but
get to the worst case.
The worst case is there are,
who are as good,
whoever are moral and as ethical and as
committed to the wellbeing of themselves
and others as you and I are,
who still go in and shoot up schools and
kill everybody and hope to die in the
process because they think they can get
into paradise that way and get into p.
So when,
when members of the Taliban went into a
school in Pakistan and killed,
I think it was 137 kids and,
and,
and burn their teacher alive in front of
them.
Uh,
you have to ask yourself,
what do you think?
You know,
all members of the Taliban who endorsed,
who did this and then all of those and
the Taliban who endorsed this,
we're all just psychopaths or mentally
ill.
No,
no.
If you listen to what they're saying,
if you listen to what their,
where they believe,
if you read the texts that they think
are the verbatim word of the creator of
the universe,
it all falls into place.
This is perfectly rational behavior
given the requisite beliefs.
And that is what is so horrible about
this kind of dogmatism.
Even that process or that sort of
extreme example of the execution of
children in schools.
You base of an elective reading of even
that particular doctorate and it'd be
particular like passages you go,
oh is the passage where the sort of not
so much.
Unfortunately there's loads of stuff
that's like live a peaceful life of
devotion.
[inaudible] have you read the Quran?
Have you read the Quran cover to cover
saw bloody,
we're laughing.
There's mainly got through these notes
for this interview,
so I'm doing this thing on the flight.
You can,
you can do it at the point it's a short
book or like my general feeling is that
the Quran holy is like most religious
scripture.
The intention is to create a social
environment where people are benevolent
and cohesive,
which ultimately became a tool for
social control as a result of the way
the power structures,
but there's more than that.
There's,
there's likely the religion in politics,
but I don't know.
I think,
again,
I wouldn't deliberately misread the
metaphor for,
for me,
life after death,
and this is a person who spent two years
in a silent matree,
Gavi,
you with Dick.
This is that beyond the life that is
determined by primal desires and
biographical wants and your imagination
of yourself.
There is a life after the death of that
individual.
After that individual dies and you
recognize that the temporal can never
provide fulfillment,
you gain access to a sort of a second
life and after life,
the Kingdom of Heaven is spread upon the
earth and man sees it,
not the Kingdom of Heaven,
the life after the death of your ego.
So Sam,
yes,
I would say I would like if it's not
talking about that,
I don't know what it's talking about and
what the value of that would be as a,
as a,
as a manual for being,
for being human.
There's so much,
mate,
let me,
hold on a sec.
We've got go for you did a big
classification system of the degrees of
who we've got to do the schools.
Okay.
What we'll do.
Then do your flag and then we're going
back to the school.
You want to acknowledge that.
However,
whatever
personal reading breathing
is,
most people most of the time think that
the afterlife is a literal place.
You go after die.
That consciousness survives the death of
the body.
And in the Judeo Christian tradition,
especially the Christian,
the Christian and the and the,
the Islamic tradition,
it really matters whether you believe
the right thing or not.
I mean,
in fact this life doesn't matter at all
and that's what's so corrosive about
this.
But like in it,
and actually look at some of the
alternatives now we did,
we just,
their device to barometer of degrees if
madness and the worst types of madness
and the worst way to tobacco your kids
murdered in a school by which particular
type of madman,
you know,
but we should probably bring into the
mix.
Not all men are like,
I don't mind kids killed in a school by
for any ideology,
whether it's grounded in sort of
rationalism and economics or whether
it's a book that's a bit older and more,
I don't know,
esoterical colorful or imaginative,
I don't know sort of how to determine
it.
But what I suppose what I suppose the
heart of why I want to get to is whilst
undoubtably religion has been used to
justify violence from all types of Ang,
uh,
angles and in different historical
moments and you know,
Buddhist violence in Burma and Christian
violence in,
you know,
like in the Middle East or sit or
secular violence underwritten by
Christianity,
resourced entirely from Christiana in
sort of Christian dualistic notions
undertaken by far right Christian
president and whatever.
Or you know,
sort of the more lucid livid and office
and contemporaneous a far right is a
extremist Islamic violence.
It's like,
well,
how do we see that as distinct from
rational violence,
political violence,
particularly when that is far more
potent palm,
far more widespread.
And it's,
I would say is the violence of the
dominant culture.
What interests me,
Sam Harris is power and the powerful,
and for me I'm interested in who gets to
decide who the other is,
who gets to decide by what metric.
Rationalism and religion is evaluated.
And it seems to me that the kind of
violence that's focused on in a lot of
your work is the violence of desperate
people.
Desperate possibly subjugated people.
And I would say to this,
I know that you don't do this,
but I want you to educate me on this.
But to dismiss the colonial aspect,
the,
the sort of economic aspect,
the occupation of Middle Eastern
countries and historical,
I mean if for me it seems like how,
how can you conduct that extraction?
How can you divorce those different
types of violence?
They seem to me to be part of one
narrative.
Well,
I can do it very simply because you have
exam just to dissect out the variable of
colonialism or oppression from the
outside.
Um,
you have examples of people who have
been oppressed as,
as oppressed as any other people who
don't resort to this kind of violence
because they don't have the same belief
structure.
Right?
So take that.
Here's a,
here's a,
an almost perfect scientific experiment.
You,
Palestinian Christians and Palestinian
Muslims living in the same occupied
territories right now,
who was blowing that well before the
Israelis put up the wall who was blowing
themselves up in,
in pizza parlors and discotheques,
right?
It was 99.9%
Muslim,
right?
It was not Christian.
You have Coptic Christians in Egypt
being murdered by their Muslim
neighbors,
by suicide bombings who don't resort to
their own suicide bombings in return.
Right?
It's the beliefs matter.
The details matter.
Why do you fetishize the or antagonism
towards that particular type of
violence?
Not,
it's not a,
it's not a fetish.
It's just violence exists in the context
of a far more potent opponents.
Violence.
No,
no,
no.
Okay.
Like he can't,
we can't talk about Palestinian
violence.
And for Christian person you might
acknowledge saying no,
not talking about history.
No,
of course,
of course we can because we can because
you can have sweet though.
Moral morning,
someone in Orange County will be
converted to this belief system and want
to fight in the name of this cause.
And it's purely a matter of belief.
It's,
it's as much a matter of belief as you
wanting to go on a diet or a learning to
meditate.
Or maybe I'll go to Hawaii this year for
my vacation.
These are ideas.
But luckily,
you know,
you and I,
we live in a sort of a secular society
and our beliefs seldom come into
opposition with the dominant philosophy.
And when it does there,
there are problems.
W what worries me?
So I was really,
oh,
so that might be here.
My background concerns,
I think ideas are the most powerful
things we've got right?
Ideas are the operating system for human
life and human culture.
And if we fail to build a civilization
that works,
it will be because of the failure of
ideas or our failure to communicate good
ideas to one another in such a way
that's persuasive.
So,
so,
I mean,
how do you get 7 billion strangers to
peacefully collaborate with one another?
It is a matter of conversation that
ultimately gets people to converge on
common projects and common values.
And so all we have is conversation.
And when conversation fails,
all we have is violence,
right?
There's,
there's really just two modes,
conversation in violence and what you're
talking about when you're talking about
power and it's misuses,
you're talking about state violence or,
or state coercion,
uh,
that you deem to be illegitimate.
Now I'll grant you.
But if we,
if we took a list of all of these cases,
you know,
CIA run coups and other countries where,
you and I may just check the same box.
It's like,
well that looks legitimate or that,
that had consequences that could have
easily been foreseen.
Lots of people suffered and died there
that shouldn't have the objectives.
All of it.
Yes.
And,
and,
um,
so,
but when I'm looking at cases of,
of uh,
when I prompt prioritize kind of the
light of shining the light of my
criticism on specific ideas and specific
human behavior,
I'm looking by and large for the,
the,
the craziest and most dangerous ideas
that should be,
I mean it's,
this is really the low hanging fruit for
kind of bad epistemology.
The thing,
the human behavior that should seem
impossible,
right?
Like,
and suicide bombing was not a drone
bombing.
It's not just the aesthetics.
It's not just aesthetics because because
suicidal people are undetectable,
so jihadists are undetectable.
If part of it's the best thing that can
happen in an operation is that you die
while conducting it.
You are the perfect weapon.
That's fair.
So,
but I just have to hammer,
I have to hammer this home.
When you're talking about the
possibility of something like nuclear
terrorism or biological terrorism that,
you know,
when someone tries to weaponize
smallpox,
killed 100 million patients,
nuclear terrorism,
he's not hypothetical already happened
50 years ago.
No,
I won't call it,
I won't call that nuclear terrorism.
There was certainly a first piece of
dice semantics would be your primary
concern.
Nobody call that thing.
But how my teeth,
it's reasonable to ask,
well how the Japanese view it now and
how the Japanese view their relationship
with the United States.
Now it's,
it's a,
there's,
there's an argument.
I'm not,
I'm not defending narrative Sam that
supersede the uh,
power and narrative of nationalism and
geopolitics gift where there is that,
but they make sense,
determine it.
They make the,
the,
the Japan and the US no longer see
themselves in a position or positions.
Right?
Well,
so what,
so one question is how,
how are we going to get all of these
societies that are at loggerheads to see
themselves in Nonzero sum,
uh,
arrangements with everyone else and um,
and what's,
what we'll have to change to make that
possible.
And my concern with religion,
religious fundamentalism and not all
religions equally.
Um,
but uh,
my concern is that these are the beliefs
that are held most closely.
They're the least negotiable.
I mean,
they're by definition non negotiable.
These are the,
these are my faith based beliefs are the
beliefs that that if you challenge them
that will buy whatever evidence or
whatever argument,
I will take that as a personal insult
and I will want,
want to resort immediately to violence
or the threat of violence.
I will want blasphemy laws.
I would want to pass a law at the UN
that will,
that will give you jail time.
If you say the wrong thing about my holy
book,
right?
That's where conversation has totally
broken down and there's nothing to,
to resort to.
But for us,
when you say a suicide bomber,
I bet it's an extraordinary,
and it's difficult for us to understand.
But what I'm curious
about,
Sam is the,
what are the prerequisite conditions for
suicide bombing even to be relevant.
And I also can't help but thinking when
I sort of feel when,
when we sort of recall events like waco
or any disruption or anything that sort
of ruptures the sort of like the,
the uh,
American mainframe are not American.
So here,
this goes beyond nation.
If you put,
if you find yourself in opposition to
the state,
the means by which the state will deploy
violence doesn't need to resort to sort
of Lurid,
livid,
blatant clumsy acts like suicide
bombing.
Because the power is so evident,
the ability to exert power and control
is so total that it doesn't need sort of
like almost the sort of graphic and
horrific whimsy of something like a
suicide bombing all be underwritten by
something that looks peculiar to people
like us that value life and value fine,
don't have a belief system that's like,
oh,
I'll be in some sort of a Valhalla
subsequently.
Well you were using Waco is an example
of state oppression or suicidal
sacrifice.
I'm using it as an example of the
[inaudible].
The,
the,
the kind of violence that interest me is
the violence of the truly powerful and
the kindness.
So for me,
I said like suicide,
but I can see that it's kind of,
it's gratuitous and sort of,
and therefore an appealing form.
But for me when,
when analyzing nine 11 to focus on the
perpetration of that event and the
motivation of the individuals involved
as opposed to the geopolitical
circumstances.
Um,
and what happens generally when two
narratives come into conflict with one
another,
short changes us and means that we focus
like I'm my sole interest.
Sam is who he like when you talk about
how are we going to get these 7 billion
people to cooperate and form communities
based on mutual values,
which for some reason I believe is a
possibility,
my own spirit,
my own spiritual pursuits if led me to
the point where I have a basic
optimistic view of humanity,
my own personal experience with Muslims
is led me to believe that Islam is eight
essentially a positive thing,
a positive thing.
But that's a bad way to take his
temperature.
You're at me cause how many Muslims have
you had a personal experience with our,
granted you,
you're taking the temperature on the
bicep bloody suicide bombers and no,
no,
no.
I'm,
I'm taking the temperature on the basis
of the actual doctrine that makes sense
of this behavior.
And also aspects of the doctrine that
aspects of the,
no,
no it's,
but wait,
wait,
hold on.
Let me just,
I got to,
I could imagine that we'd have this
conversation then there'd be a bit we
went,
yeah,
he sounds not that bad.
I think come into this room.
We're thinking that,
but it's,
it's worth connecting with you have
these dots because it's not just a
matter of the killing of people.
I'm talking about how people want to
live.
So if you ask yourself,
and this is just a thought experiment,
um,
if you ask yourself if you gave perfect
power to any one group,
right.
And they,
so they could impose their way of life,
every other group.
So he gave him,
this is my magic wand argument that I
use in my first book.
Um,
you know,
Give Dick Cheney a magic wand and Dick
Cheney,
the prototypical evil mustache twirling
bastard,
who,
who gave us the Iraq war and,
and is as demonized on the left as,
as anyone.
What would he have done if he had the
power,
you know,
just to make a life in the Middle East
and Afghanistan
any way he wanted.
It doesn't need to.
We did not need to conjecture.
They said we want to ever remove the
ability of our opponents to respond.
It's in the public sphere.
Let's go a little further.
Let's,
no,
let's go a little further in our
imagination.
Do you actually think,
uh,
and maybe Dick Cheney has been so
demonized that he's the wrong case here,
but I have a strong opinion.
But Dick Cheney.
Yeah.
I,
you know,
how you spell that is,
this is what I would guess,
right?
Someone like Dick Cheney,
if given unlimited Ken unload just magic
the resources of magic magic,
you're doing like a two to narrow
reading of that,
right?
Yes.
We don't want to be a bit that,
we don't want these people to be able to
attack us.
Right?
That's the goal of the war.
I'm saying,
oh,
oppose our objectives,
but what are,
so let's go.
So what would we want that region for a
kickoff?
We won't tell on challenged.
No,
no,
but I'm talking about,
I'm talking about magic.
We don't even need to steal their
resources.
We have the power of magic.
Now what will life would you impose on
these people?
Right?
What?
What life would would the worst of us in
power,
like Dick Cheney impose on these people?
I think he'd make Afghanistan or Iraq,
like Nebraska,
right?
This would not,
he would not be some hell scape of
unnecessary suffering.
It would be a starbucks on every corner.
Mere capitalism.
Now you have your critique of this way
of life.
No doubt.
But he would w what?
What he would want to impose on these
people is orderly economic,
probably good Christian behavior.
Right?
He would want movie theaters.
It all be watching the Oscars right now
what?
What would Abu Bakr Al Baghdadi impose
on everyone else?
He's told us explicitly because he tried
the experiment in Syria and Iraq.
We know exactly how he wants to live and
he wants others to live.
It is seventh century theocratic
barbarism and there's no doubt about
that.
It is fornicators homosexuals thrown
from rooftops and fornicators.
Yeah.
Whether it's their throats slit.
Shortly we can agree on is that what
the,
the second guy name,
I don't know.
Is it relevant and broadly speaking,
irrelevant in terms of view of 7 billion
individuals.
Dick Cheney's,
starbucks on every corner
there are 1.7
billion Muslims,
majority of which live under some
significant theocratic constraint.
You're talking
about women,
it's not the same theocracy.
Listen,
I'm just as concerned about Christian
theocracy as you are.
How can you,
cause I think like you're about to talk
about sort of gender issues,
but you're,
once again it's free thought issues.
It's shines.
Surely but,
but,
but the metric by which we evaluate them
is a distinct metric could drawn from
another narrative and the free and
alfred like so like you know,
we might say,
oh bloody hell women dressing live out
or whatever,
you know,
we call it,
I don't think we're in a position to
make those kinds of decisions.
Of course we are.
You don't think you're in a position
think the,
their narrative should adhere to our
template.
Well,
first of all,
so,
so you're a man,
you imagine that most women forced to
wear a burqa.
I don't know about forced.
And my experience in conversation is
being that it's more that we ought to
regard it.
I think we have,
I've asked Muslim women about it and
they said to me,
it's like,
it's like a discipline and when we dig
it,
but first of all,
we're,
now I'm talking about a burka.
I'm not talking about someone going to
Barnard who elects to wear a headscarf
because she likes the way,
I don't like the imposition of a,
like a,
of our heterogeneous haitch demonic
ideas of how masculine,
feminine relationships work might not be
universally applicable.
Something is universally applicable.
And if it's not universal,
we can understand those differences.
So if there's a culture where they like
spicy food and we don't,
uh,
but eating spicy food is just another
way to be happy as a,
as a,
as an ape,
uh,
we can understand those differences
biologically and culturally.
This,
the idea that it just may be as good as
solution for the,
the how to maximize human wellbeing,
uh,
to put half the population in bags from
the moment that and,
and not,
and not let them learn to read.
I mean,
I'm taking Afghanistan,
I'm taking the local case of Afghanistan
under the Taliban,
uh,
and uh,
you know,
and it may well fall back.
I mean it's,
it's actually a Afghanistan currently as
well.
You're talking about women who
are,
who have almost the worst possible life
on planet earth.
I mean,
we're talking about maternal mortality
rates that are off the charts.
You're talking about,
uh,
illiteracy.
That is that you have to go back 200
years in the west to find that level of
illiteracy reasoning that's used to
justify the bombing.
I know it's not an actual colonization.
If those territories,
they're not like us,
they treat women different from us.
I don't think position to make those
judgements.
So then tell me how you would react to
this.
I have two.
I have two daughters.
And if I were thinking the way you were
thinking about this issue,
what if I thought it would be a great
idea to have a cultural exchange program
where I just sent my daughter's over to
Afghanistan to live with a Taliban
family.
So rather than go to summer school here
and get prepared to go to an Ivy League
college or whatever it is,
I send them to learn.
I send them to live with the Taliban.
Explained all this to be,
I said,
well,
nobody but nobody.
You got to answer it fully experiments.
Well,
I'm from a Western culled up in
indoctrinated
dispute.
No right or wrong.
I don't think that there's the eye.
I'm not in a position.
I think he's very different.
Me Saying,
I've been born in the west,
I've grown up in the west.
My daughter's born in the West now
impose upon her a tilt,
totally different set of values.
I want to go to the deep south over who
wanted to go to places in Britain.
Yeah.
You don't think it's unlucky to be born
a girl in Afghanistan five years ago.
I think that these kind of a sort of
theoretical tableaus are used to create
a force hierarchy and a moral
superiority by a dominant culture that
subsequently uses thinking of this of
this nature to underwrite the modern day
colonization and subjugation of these
people on a massive scale as barbaric
and a disgusting is nine 11 was a daily
nine 11 since then so that that's a
state system can perpetuate yourself
using rationalism using comfortable
means of executions that glides slyly by
all why in the sky is no better than the
nine 11 news over patterns too.
It is.
It is better to let,
we can talk.
So you're invoking a many things here
which we should treat systematically.
Things like collateral damage.
So you
you drop a bomb like that language.
It's a euphemism.
It's a euphemism but that's,
that's the word we use to talk about
unintended people getting killed by
[inaudible].
What was it like when a 7% of drone
structures eight a result in a that day?
The data here are hard to get our hands
around as well.
Highly politicized.
Yes,
of course it is the then the language is
important.
And who decides what language is used
and who decides where powerful and who
decides what's rational violence and who
decides what religion is even,
right.
Okay.
But so let's,
let's treat these things point by point.
So
first,
now let's take them in a giddy.
Blah.
I'm trying to get out of the Blue
Giddy blur is now in my mind.
Um,
so there's a,
there's a fundamental claim that you
have just made it at least implicitly
that I disagree with.
And then I wrote my third book to rebut
that.
The,
the,
my third book,
the moral landscape is an argument that
we can talk about questions of right and
wrong and good and evil in universal
terms.
That these are not merely cultural or
personal affectations right?
It's not that we're not free.
You make it one of your full experience
minced in a minute.
No,
no,
no.
Because see you on the edge of the,
we'll just have sex with her baby.
The were say it's wrong.
The reason why thought experiments are
so useful is that there the,
the,
the pure case,
right?
They're not,
they will,
you can just,
you can take one variable at a time.
Um,
so,
um,
but this idea that it's all a matter of
personal taste or all a matter of
culture,
right?
It suggests that all all cultures,
therefore our,
I mean,
the,
the moment you make the link between
question of good and evil and the well
being of conscious,
like questions of happiness and
suffering,
right?
And I think that link is very direct.
I mean,
that's a separate conversation we can
have,
but,
but I think the only intelligible
morality has to focus on human
suffering,
human wellbeing,
and even more broadly to the suffering
of any conscious system.
So it's animals.
If we're,
if we're torturing pigs so as to get
bacon,
uh,
that is that we have an ethical
obligation to not do that,
do that last,
find a better way of doing that.
So that is no longer torture breed pigs
that don't suffer,
whatever it is.
But what suffering should be our
concern.
And if,
and so if the moment you grant that you
have to grant that not every culture and
not every society and certainly not
every family,
right,
has perfectly solved the human wellbeing
problem,
right?
They haven't solved at equally.
So if you find a family over here that's
forcing their children to live in a
basement for 20 years and,
and um,
to,
to interbreed and not,
not showing them the light of day,
okay,
this is,
this is a problem that society has an
interest in.
Now we're now we're now we're talking
about power dynamics where the society
has an interest in rescue in those
children from their deranged and evil
parents.
Right within this,
just this,
this could be true just in a single city
like Los Angeles,
right?
As has happened very recently.
Um,
the,
that scales that scales to whole nations
and,
and to,
uh,
right,
global situation.
Politically it does.
Yeah.
Politically complex.
But for you to withhold judgment of the
burqa makes absolutely no sense for you
to withhold judgment of
no female genital mutilation.
Makes absolutely no sense.
It's a different way,
again,
now,
now.
Perfect case of getting misled by words
because they're,
they're highly non analogous.
Those two procedures.
I'm not,
I'm not in favor of male circumcision
either,
but I'm just saying just talk it to use
the word mutilation or circumcision
synonymously.
Word mutilation.
No,
you just jumped to the men though.
Yes,
I listen when we sort of interchange
styles of dress,
we're still in the caddy blur by the
way.
I never leave it and personal submission
when we interchange that with sort of
like sort of a subjugation of a family
and keep people in the cellar.
But you know,
there's different levels of complexity.
Now I'd like to,
if,
if I may shift gears a little sad
because one of my great interest in you
is your immense intellectual capacity
and jaw,
uh,
what I want to call it without being
deliberately provocative zeal and love
of ethics and morality.
And I would like to know how that
relates to your personal spiritual life.
I know you are a great meditator.
You said like,
you know,
I've never had there Jesus,
two years silence.
I think I'd struggled for 25.
Well,
I mean,
I meditate twice a day for 20 minutes
and I don't find this right,
right.
Yeah.
No,
I mean for me this stuff is the answer
now.
What the reason I meditate,
the reason that I embrace the spiritual
life is because I believe I've
experienced,
I've experienced that for me personally
to become a valuable of society.
Wherever that song on the microlevel of
my family and hopefully on a broader
level,
I have to take personal responsibility
for the fact that I'm a complex
individual that are within me.
All of the things I would condemn over
the course of a podcast talking to a
brilliant man like yourself.
Maybe one minute I'll condemn violence
another minute I'll come down condemn
egotism and self centeredness.
The I am victim to all of these.
I'm perpetrator of self centeredness and
egocentrism and the tool that has helped
me most to overcome these personal
problems.
There's been a kind of a spiritual
veltin Shang and I planned to use that
word with you today.
My German's bad.
That's,
that's literally the only German word
you'll hear cause it's the only one I
know.
So like,
let's say my spirituality has been my
personal vehicle for carrying me away
from sort of selfishness,
self destruction,
and like I'm talking as a peasant's
overcome,
not,
oh,
you know,
through the help of others.
And to a degree,
faith,
I must say to a huge degree faith,
uh,
my own addiction.
Now you've got a addiction issues,
haven't you?
Habitation you just for you dabbling in
it.
Was your brother know like Dan?
No,
neither.
If you've got no addiction background.
No,
no.
Dan Harris had Dan Harris,
who's,
who's also,
he's a friend.
He's not,
there's no relation,
but he wrote the book 10% happier and it
was a big bestseller about mindfulness.
And so he's had issues that he's talked
about.
I see.
Well,
so forgive me.
So my person,
like,
so my personal experiences have been
that sort of spirituality and a faith
that is determined resolutely by as best
as possible,
nonjudgmental realism,
a benevolence,
kindness,
being of service to others,
principles that broadly speaking don't
require me to enter into conflict,
but to be off service.
Uh,
the,
this for me,
I think is an incredibly valuable
resource.
And,
and,
and these things and ethics in general
are drawn.
I'll not ultimately,
because prior,
who knows what proceeded religion,
some form of theater and ritual.
Who knows what they're doing down deep
in the dank of the forests,
what gods they device there were
conscious,
well,
precisely where consciousness is a
little more open.
I suppose what I,
I want to understand it.
So it has,
how does your personal spirituality
serve you ethically and,
and uh,
where does that intersect with beyond
tolerance?
Because tolerance suggests that there's
something to tolerate.
Where does it lead you to a compassion
and love?
And what solutions do you think can be
derived from your personal understood
your present experiences of mysticism
and spirituality?
Where I would say first that it,
it really,
while it may seem different from what
we've been just talking about,
it's of a piece with what we've just
been talking about.
And the reason why I have such passion
for criticizing this particular species
of bad ideas,
the religious ones is because I see the
baby and the bath water that everyone is
afraid of losing.
And I see that it doesn't require any
bullshit
too to be saved,
right?
You don't have to lie to yourself.
You don't have to believe that a book
was written by the creator of the
universe.
You don't have to believe that that hell
fire weights people who don't call
historical person by the right name.
You don't have to believe any of those
things.
And all of those things are absolutely
integral to the doctrines of these
religions.
Uh,
and there's many separate religions on
off
for that are incompatible.
I think there's a point where religion
and politics intersect and it's not
always clear where that line is drawn.
And I would say that the point where
spirituality stops being about kindness,
love,
fun.
Remember earlier in this podcast you did
the list if the things that difficult to
quantify scientifically.
And I would wonder how,
uh,
how,
how a valuable and a useful those image
scans and neuro image scans are when
dealing with fun and love.
I'm sure they have great service,
I'm sure,
but like these things,
the way that we access them,
the way that we increase them.
And,
and to your earlier point,
the way that we as best as possible
eliminate suffering.
For me,
this is the function and the role of
spirituality.
And,
and I think sort of some of the
furniture and ornamentation that
religions are variously acquired due to
the cultural influx infections of the
times in which they were conceived for
me are less important and less relevant.
Whilst I acknowledge that I'm a
relatively unique case and some of the
extreme,
uh,
issues that you're addressing,
I,
I'm,
you know,
I've been not imaginary.
I know that what you're saying is true
and there's baby bath water issue.
I'm interested in the baby always on
about a bath.
Well,
so what you just described about your
own spiritual life and ethical life,
um,
it is obvious to me that there are
universal principles there that what you
just described about the consequences of
paying attention to certain things.
So,
so meditation,
uh,
getting off certain substances that are
not good for you.
So,
you know,
breaking with,
with addiction,
these are universal features of what
it's like to have a human mind that is,
is based on human neurochemistry.
Uh,
and,
um,
this is not something we just made up.
It's not something that's,
that's a purely a product of our time.
It's not merely cultural.
And that's why sticking girls in bags
for their entire lives and not letting
them read
bad derisory it is,
it's exactly what,
it's exactly what happened
in,
in Afghanistan.
I'm not,
I'm not talking about,
again,
I'm not talking about the voluntary.
Uh,
should you use a century language if you
are here to convey love?
It's exactly,
it's like no because,
no,
because
pretend to love girls.
If you're not as concerned as I am about
this ms treatment of them.
I don't pretend to understand,
but you should.
It's not for girls.
They're girls and the Americans.
It's not that you're overthinking it,
you're overthinking.
It has nothing to do with skin color
knows what the level of thought.
That's [inaudible] Sam,
but you like,
you know,
you all in American,
I can introduce you.
Just take a few facts on board here.
I can introduce you to women who have of
what?
Oh,
whatever shade of Brown skin,
you require my requirement,
who holds about me,
who have grown up in these cultures,
who will say exactly what I'm saying
about the consequences of compulsive
gambling.
No country,
no,
no.
What do you say?
No,
but no subjugation is the same in yoga
or exercise.
But you're,
you're,
you're drawing the wrong lesson here.
I'm,
I'm back.
No,
no,
because you're just missing a few facts.
If you have those two people have a
conversation.
If you take someone like I on her cle or
Sarah Haider who runs the ex Muslims of
North America,
right?
And you have her talk to someone like
Linda Sarsour,
you know the Hijabi,
uh,
icon of the woman's March,
right?
Darlene,
if the left now who's actually a closet
theocrat and quite an nefarious person
when you get her talking about religion,
I mean she will,
she will not admit that life for,
for women in Saudi Arabia is,
is bad by comparison at all for,
with life for women in the West having
such a complicit trades relationships
with them.
Then I'll agree with you there.
So,
but if you have two women have this sort
talk,
right?
One Who has,
who has taken off the hijab for reasons
of not wanting to wear it and wanting to
live in a system where she's free not to
wear it,
and one who says,
I'm wearing it purely as an expression
of my own religious faith and it's just
pure women empower female empowerment.
If you let that conversation proceed,
you'll see that this side has to lie
endlessly about the,
the actual doctrines about why most
people,
most women,
most of the time are wearing this there.
It's being forced upon them.
And maybe we'll talk about the misuse of
power you're talking about.
You're talking about mean to take,
take the perfect case.
It sounds like it's a thought
experiment,
but it actually happened.
You take the religious police in Mecca
who wouldn't let the girls who are
burning alive in a dormitory be rescued
because they weren't wearing their,
their veils,
right?
They wouldn't let the firemen go in and
rescue girls from a burning building
because they weren't properly vale.
But that's,
that's the,
that's the reductio ad absurdum this
gender relationships in this country
have become so complex,
particularly where we're both fathers,
but you can judge the sure and the
aesthetic obligations that will be
placed upon my dor to look a certain way
to behave a certain way to believe.
So
I don't,
I don't even think that's a reasonable
possibility.
I just think you are in a position to
judge how wrong that would be and if
someone is used to judge how wrong,
what would be imposing those
restrictions on your girls?
You know,
that would be a bad,
a diminishment of the wellbeing of your
girls and to pretend to not know what if
a girl in Afghanistan
turning to this fish is in my idea.
Why are you not more concerned that by
the continual objectification
of women over that female sexuality,
the advertising industry using females,
it's a different order of problem,
but I'm totally with you,
but we just want these more prominent.
What do you think is more likely to
happen to your daughter?
That she's going to be whisked off to
Afghanistan?
It's been wife number five or that she's
going to have sex with some days because
she's got that here.
My concern is for both things,
you consensually for reality,
like an abstract ideas that play into
the hands of an already a power dynamic
and a well-served power dynamics.
Let's get who's side are we all?
But let's get,
who does the grail serves I have,
where is this mythic truth?
Where does perennialism come from?
Why are these themes found throughout
the great faiths,
the oneness,
the unity,
the possibilities for love.
We're going Giddy Sam,
we go for another ride in the tumble
dryer of love.
So let me try to connect a few of these
things because you're concerned about
power,
right?
And you're concerned about the misuse of
our power.
We're so,
so our being Western power say
I suppose it,
but to tell the truth like now I've got
ya.
Okay.
Like I don't even,
I think that those,
that mosque of nationalism is
superficial.
Let the real power operates and has done
probably since British colonialism on an
economic scale that doesn't pay a great
deal of attention to sort of trade
tariffs.
All those very trade terrace have we
drawn up,
you know,
we've the powerful in mind.
So what for me,
Sam,
what interests me and not sort of like,
while I,
you know,
I'm got no argument bloody isis when I
read about that southern kingdom,
some terrifying shit going down.
But what interests me more is who is it
that gets to determine what is happening
in the world in my life right now?
And it seems to me that,
that that's transnational corporations
and governments of Western democracies
that don't need to resort to the kind of
a sort of vivid acts of violence on
their domestic population because it's
unnecessary because we've all been
beautifully conditioned and when it is
required,
when brutality and violence is required,
it will be used.
It is enacted.
And that when me seems more important
than people responding to that power,
but it's all important.
And then why is your focus continually
on this sort of fetishized aspect?
Well,
it's,
it's again,
it was just to say fetishized is to,
is to reveal the problem that I,
that that causes me to focus on it.
Because again,
it comes back to the power of ideas.
And I think one of the worst ideas going
really is the one that you've expressed
here,
which is who am I to judge?
I'm just a white guy who grew up in a
western context.
Who am I to judge the Burka,
this,
this kind of moral relativism,
postmodernism.
What?
No,
nobody.
That'd be the,
this,
this is the order.
This is,
I know you don't wanna answer to that
name,
but this is the intellectual trend that
gave us this kind of,
uh,
apprehension around making these
judgments.
Right?
Who am I to to say what would be the
good life for somebody else?
And it,
no matter how
grotesque the example of human
suffering,
nonviolence,
compassion and love is the answer,
I'm what I think where we disagree is
what should be the key target.
What is generating,
generating the problems.
There are many problems,
but I think to take it at the level of,
of greatest abstraction,
and I think greatest leverage for us to
think about it is for the most part,
we,
this is not a problem of the world being
filled with bad people,
right?
There are some bad people.
There's some,
it will say 1% of people in every
culture are probably psychopaths,
right?
So there's 1% of people who really do
feel no compunction about harming other
people and they kind of get off on it
and they're going to keep doing it no
matter what you change about the system.
Uh,
but most harm is the result of bad
ideas,
good people having bad ideas and good
people being in systems where there are
bad incentives.
And what I think we,
so the crucial word here is incentives,
right?
I think we need economic systems and
political systems and institutions and
interpret and ways of being with one
another publicly,
uh,
which align our incentives in such a way
so as to make ordinary mediocre,
not so insightful,
not so reflective,
not so philosophical.
And frankly,
not even that ethical people effort more
and more effortlessly do the right
thing,
right?
So you,
you shouldn't have to be Saint Francis
of Assisi to,
to act well in the world,
right?
But there are systems where the
incentives are bad enough that you
really have to be a moral hero to be
just basically decent.
Right?
All of the incentives are pointing the
other way.
Right?
I'll take,
give you an example for this.
Um,
life in a maximum security prison.
So if you,
you're a good guy,
you're not a racist,
you're a Jew.
You want,
you just want to get along with people.
If you were put into a maximum security
prison,
all the incentives would be pushing you
the other way.
So for you,
for you not to join a white gang in a
maximum security prison would be
effectively suicidal.
Right?
Like you would just be the victim of
everyone so that the place is set up to
segregate everyone by skin color,
right?
So even if you don't have a racist bone
in your body,
you're just self preservation alone.
They also concentrated society.
Exactly.
The royal institution.
But it's the perfect,
it's a perfect example of bad incentives
are misaligned incentives,
how these things happen.
They're happening everywhere,
but most of these,
most of them,
most of these exams,
samples of bad incentives are most that.
Most of these examples of where power is
victimizing millions and of people are,
I would argue examples where the system
is set up in such a way that it is
reliably x sporting this misery.
Right?
And there's,
there is no author of it.
There is no bad person or they're very
few bad people.
Who are the actual authors of this,
uh,
of this human suffering there or the
perpetrators of it.
It what we have.
Our systems were selfish people being
selfish most of the time.
Managed to export a fair amount of
misery to tell people who are less lucky
than themselves.
And if we want to,
if we want a fairer economic
arrangement,
we have to design it and we have to
design it for people as they are.
We have to,
we need systems that will allow,
how about people are mutable?
Yeah,
exactly.
Is that we respond to ideas and we
respond to incentives.
Yes.
And incentives to be a bit more personal
for a moment.
Uh,
like are you a bit cynical about human
beings?
Cause like when we talk it's like I feel
we've been fighting about terrorism and,
and uh,
female gentlemen genital mutilation with
my pro terrorism protein mutilation
starts on those issues,
um,
shoulder to the wall now.
But you seem so very,
you seem like angry about you seem angry
and about humanity.
Almost all I know.
Think human beings are not good
country.
I see.
Well they're neither,
I mean we're,
it's all mixed,
right?
I mean there were good and were bad and
we're careless.
Right.
And we're short side the line between
good and evil runs through.
Yeah,
absolutely.
That's certainly a more eloquent way of
saying it,
but it,
it is,
but there's
okay
the,
again,
to talk about the,
the,
the situational problem,
yeah.
The problem of incentives is doing more
work than human evil is doing.
I mean,
I think,
again,
I think we,
all of us have,
have work to do on ourselves to be
happier and better people.
Right?
And that is spiritual life and that is
ethical life.
But I think,
I think better than,
and this,
these are not,
these are not mutually exclusive
projects.
These can be done simultaneously,
but better than each of us figuring out
how to be a saint,
um,
would be to design a system that made it
easier for everyone to be far better
than they're tending to be now.
And that's possible.
I think that's absolutely,
literally
possible to a lot of decentralization
and the significant change,
particularly in,
in our nations around what is called the
political.
But I sort of see as the religious now
let,
let me tell you something again.
It's again a little more,
what do I want to say?
Trivial.
So personal.
It's not trivial.
I A,
the other day I was driving home from,
and I've seen the movie or something.
It was a daytime,
still a homeless guy just collapsed
laying in the middle of the road,
you know,
it's La homeless people just everywhere
forming shanty
towns like the apocalypse is already
happened and is creeping in around us.
Like it's slow tide and it was some
homeless guy and like,
Oh,
I know that homeless guy is just laying
there.
I should do something about that.
Amanda didn't,
I just went home and I thought like,
ah,
why didn't I do anything about that?
Great example here.
So,
okay,
it's because in the current system
there's nothing very easy to do,
right?
So like,
so you have to be an absolute moral hero
to do something about that particular
homeless guy.
And it's very likely that what you would
do wouldn't help a lot and would just
complicate your life massively.
So let's say you just say,
well,
this is totally untenable.
I cannot step over the body of yet
another homeless person.
I'm going to take this guy into my life.
He's going to come back to my hotel
room.
I'm going to,
you know,
I,
I've got to go to London in a week.
I'm going to figure out what to do with
this guy and get him in and it's going
to be your whole project
then a couple of times.
Yeah,
it's complex.
Yeah.
It's called [inaudible].
So the reason why he's lying on the
side,
there are many reasons why he's lying on
the sidewalk and probably those reasons
aren't immediately actionable by you.
Um,
now what we need is a system that
recognizes the problem of homelessness
in the most compassionate and pragmatic
way and figures out what,
whatever solution there is.
What,
you know,
there's substance abuse issues,
there's mental health issues,
there's,
there's zoning issues.
There's like,
I mean,
we,
we the,
there's this not in my backyard ism that
where people are just getting pushed to
different parts of the city because you
don't see this in Beverly Hills,
but you see this in Santa Monica,
right?
We have to figure out a solution that is
compassionate and,
and
so do you think poverty is the
relegation of spiritual principles?
The fact that broadly speaking,
culturally spiritual principles and for
been relegated to the point of almost
insignificant.
So it's sort of no longer feels like a
sort of a person or ge to help homeless
people.
Of course as you set the systems aren't
in place.
One wonders what would happen if I just
sort of put him over my shoulder and
tried to take him somewhere.
I know it happened shelters would be
full complex medical issues,
issues of finance,
but then you think there's sort of this
sort of idea of individual ism and
individual freedom kind of relieved,
still sort of be somehow favors primal
and selfish drives over sort of communal
fraternal drives.
And whilst I agree with you on that baby
bath water dynamic,
I don't think we do enough to,
uh,
to focus on,
luminate and present the baby,
the baby that is spirituality.
That is,
you need to kind of things that we're,
you know,
when you're meditating for two years in
silence and when you're continuing to
meditate now probably when you're doing
Brazilian Jujitsu,
shrong senses or fraternity,
togetherness,
oneness.
How do we,
for me,
I think that the pro,
the priority,
the most useful way of getting those
values into our culture is to
demonstrate them to confront power where
possible and necessary.
And it seems to me less significant.
And this is what I'm fascinated by,
the to attack focus on the arguments
that you have focusing on and
arguments you've been brilliantly making
and pricing about sort of we sort of
sort of wonderfully pos or disagree is
it has become evident on many of the
tenets of it.
So that for me they,
well I suppose what I'm saying,
it's all,
and people like you and I who believe in
spirituality,
you believe in compassion.
We believe in love be doing more to
elevate those values.
I'm doing that a lot when I talk about
meditation and spirituality and
wellbeing and ethics a lot is it got the
highest base.
Got Behavioral.
I know you have to be a chairman of that
deal with you know,
secularism and all that kind of thing
and of be like,
you know,
how does that convert into,
bought a boots on the ground,
love for other humans?
Well we do talk about what the ground
truth is here,
man.
We have consciousness and its contents
in each moment.
I mean that's,
that's what our lives are.
We have,
we have changing states of consciousness
and this is all there is to care about
is that all there is to care about our
changes for good or for ill in conscious
creatures like ourselves.
So if you love someone,
you care that they be happy and that
they no longer suffer or if they suffer,
they suffer in ways that are productive,
that lead to an even deeper states of
wellbeing.
It's not like we're just pure hedonists.
There's this kinds of suffering that
that lead lead that has a silver lining
that gets us somewhere worth going.
But when you're talking about finding
meaning in life and making meaning
together in community,
you're talking about just what kind of,
what it's like to be you.
Are you talking about consciousness and
we are.
We are.
We actually know a lot about how to
improve states of human consciousness
and creativity and aesthetic beauty and
ethical interactions and not lying and
treating people the way you would want
to be treated.
Something like a precept,
like the golden rule.
Super useful.
And as I can say,
that's a great,
yeah.
PC software under the heading of baby,
right?
This,
this is okay.
Yeah,
but you don't,
but they don't,
they don't only come from scripture and
there people had these ideas outside of
religious traditions.
You can find Greek philosophers who've
said all this,
right?
Yeah,
but,
but nothing,
nothing has,
nothing has to be believed on
insufficient evidence to use these ideas
and to find them compelling.
Yeah,
no,
of course I agree with you or you don't
have to all I believe that.
And there's a cost to believing any
dogma that the problem is any dog,
any dogma,
it's costly.
Well,
it depends what those look like.
They are the price.
Now,
the collateral damage of our culture.
Sam,
are you confident that individual
consciousness,
like my individual Russell brand
consciousness and your individual Sam
Harris consciousness,
are distinct,
separate things that are not
qualitatively similar,
if not ultimately the same?
I
know there is zero scientific evidence
to suggest that all consciousness is
one,
but it would given you your research
scientifically and personal,
spiritual,
uh,
investigations.
Is there anything that suggest to you
that consciousness is a phenomena,
maybe universal?
Well,
it's universal in the sense that that is
simply the fact of experience is that
there's the fact that there's something
that is like to be you.
And there's something that has liked to
be me.
And so it's almost analogous to space.
It's like we,
it's like the space in this room,
uh,
is,
is seamless,
right?
And,
and undivided.
And you ask yourself,
well,
so what,
what about the space?
Like what about the space inside this
water bottle?
Well,
where's or what like where is the water
bottle with reference to space?
Well,
it's the only place it can be.
It's,
it's,
it's right there where the water bottle
is by move it,
it moves.
But it's,
it's,
there's no other place.
It's so to ask if you're asking about
the space,
uh,
it has,
it has a kind of sameness regardless of
what object in that space you're talking
about.
And consciousness has that property,
at least conceptually.
Now we don't know how consciousness
arises in the physics of things.
We don't know if it's a product of,
of,
yeah.
I mean there's certainly good reason to
believe that it is,
but we don't know how far down it goes.
It's probably could be a fundamental
constituent of matter or it could arise
on the basis of assemblies of neurons.
Yep.
The good reason to believe that it comes
from Matt,
that the more complex an organism is,
the more evidence of functioning
rational consciousness there is.
He's
Wa it's a me,
just again here you sort of start the
universe from the big bang.
Right.
And the idea that,
um,
I mean we,
we find complex arrangements of matter
giving rise to different emergent
properties and life is one of those
properties.
And you know,
and all of the features of life,
reproduction and,
and,
and metabolism and,
uh,
the,
the order we see in,
in the natural world is the result of a
process of increasing complexity.
And at the end of some significant
period,
I mean,
in our case,
you know,
billions of years,
you find organisms that exhibit the
properties of consciousness,
but that,
but the only,
the only consciousness we're sure of
100% sure of is the consciousness in our
own case.
Now we can reason by analogy.
We look at dogs and other complex
animals.
And we can say,
well,
to imagine that,
that they don't have consciousness but
only seemed to have it.
That's actually not parsimonious.
And because I mean,
they're so similar to us,
you know,
neurologically and in every other way
that to imagine that the lights come on
somewhere between them and us seems
irrational.
But how far down that goes is anybody's
guess.
And intuitions really divides.
If you ask,
most neuroscientists are philosophers of
mind,
is there something that is like to be a
fly?
Right?
This got 100,000
neurons in his brain.
Um,
people just,
you know,
it's that kind of coin toss right now.
I think there is,
um,
again,
so it could be,
we,
we simply don't know at what point
consciousness emerges and,
but it's,
it's possible that single cells are
conscious in some way.
Right?
I mean that's,
that like that wouldn't,
you wouldn't expect the,
the,
the living world to appear differently
if cells were conscious.
Right.
Um,
but it is,
it would be genuinely mysterious because
when you look at the human brain,
there seems to be a lot of neural
activity.
In fact,
most neural activity that is not
associated with what you experience as
consciousness or I experienced as
consciousness from a first person side.
So
what motion you're activity is not
related to yeah,
most,
most anatomical biological stuff.
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah,
most of what your brain is doing isn't
showing up in your first person
experience as conscious
at that age.
Just like a cherry on the cake,
the kidneys in the plan.
But it's the,
but it's the,
the thing that ultimately matters,
right?
I mean,
so the content and,
and it's the only thing that,
that any of us can be absolutely sure of
and said this is,
this is my line about consciousness
being the only thing in the universe
that can't be an illusion.
I'm not that,
I'm not the first person to say this
obviously,
but the,
um,
it's the only thing that is,
has to be true of us no matter how
mistaken we might be a better everything
else.
So if this,
if we're on in the matrix right now,
and this is just a,
you know,
we're just living in a simulation on
some alien supercomputer and none of
what we think is real is actually real.
Consciousness is still real.
And the consciousness is just simply the
fact that anything seems to be happening
at all.
Or if you're really asleep and dreaming
right now and we're not really doing
this podcast,
you're totally confused about your
actual circumstance.
But you're actually not confused about
the fact that your conscious,
oh,
that would explain why I've got no
trousers and pants.
I was,
I was hoping you had trousers.
Like,
see how you just described
consciousness,
then it's potentially sort of a
construction then suddenly up personal
consciousness that we can be set and is
not an illusion.
Many of you know about,
you know,
sort of the Mahara Mahabharata and the
back of our Gita and many of these ideas
are sort of using a vernacular that is
naturally termin by the time in which it
was conceived.
It talks about these ideas that mayor
illusion,
uh,
that and,
and,
and for me like that because of like,
like he also said that list of values
that would be useful and which I've
said,
oh,
well they have their part of the baby in
the bath water,
aren't they?
It seems to me that possibly within,
uh,
like if can somehow extract what is
positive from a,
what is called religion,
that it might,
it leads us to ideas such as fraternity,
unity,
oneness,
compassion and like with the,
or do you not find,
uh,
I,
and now connections between what you
have learned in neuroscience and what
you've learned from studying sort of
Buddhism.
Oh yeah.
The connections are very direct,
but
how'd they know that stuff?
But we,
but we don't want well but just because
it's,
it's just the nature of consciousness is
you,
you're talking about people who have
spent,
especially in the Buddhist case,
I just an incredible amount of time
studying from aunt,
from the first person side.
What experiences,
like what his character is,
what one analogy would be.
Um,
the central,
the central claim of Buddhism is not
just Buddhism but,
but um,
Buddhism and I would put several of the
Indian traditions like Advaita Vedanta
in there with the central claims at the,
the self is an illusion.
The EGO is an illusion.
Where,
and when I say self,
I don't mean that people are illusions.
I mean that the sense that you have a
subject riding around in your head
thinking your thoughts right there.
That there's a thinker in addition to
the thoughts.
That's an illusion.
And that makes perfect sense.
Neurologically,
there's no,
there's no place in the brain for your
ego to be sitting.
There's no central place where
everything comes together.
There's no unchanging center in the
brain.
You're just talking about a cascade of
neurophysiology and everything is
distributed everywhere and it's not a,
and there are various parts of the brain
that are coming online and off and,
and,
and subserving conscious dates and not,
it's,
it's a,
it's a process and there is there if you
could experience consciousness as a flow
of sensory and emotional and
interoceptive experience without a,
the sense that there's an unchanging
center riding around on that flow,
right?
Like a man in a boat on the,
on the stream of consciousness.
Yes.
Um,
if you could experience that
consciousness without that,
that would be an experience that is much
more coincident with what we understand
neurologically it that would be,
that would be to experience something
that is more true from the third person
brain-based,
what do we see inside the head side?
And it just so happens you can't
experience that.
That is just,
that is how that is what meditation is
like when you really know how to
meditate.
This sense that there's a meditator in
the head strategically paying attention
to experience rather than just pure
experience that drops away.
Right.
So that's,
this is one,
that's one piece of data in favor of,
of the,
of introspection here.
And it's not,
it's not a piece that the western
intellectual tradition or the West or
the western spiritual tradition ever got
a good hand handle on.
I mean,
so yes,
you can find specific Christian and
Jewish and Muslim mystics making these
noises,
but they make the,
when they make these noises
sufficiently,
they start to sound like Buddhists and
their co-religionists want to kill them
rather often.
The religionists the powerful,
uh,
and ease within nation states and
economic life.
People start believing they're not
individuals.
It's very out to market at them.
Yeah.
But we haven't had a lot of problems,
people with people being killed for not
doing enough shopping and shopping malls
because,
cause I,
unless there's a shoe in,
in the shopping mall and that's the
stuff they buy in the shopping mall,
kill some.
Yeah,
I looked.
But if you look at the history of
Christianity and Judaism and Islam,
you find people who,
I mean,
these are explicitly dualistic
traditions.
You have a soul,
you have a soul that exists in
relationship to the divine and that
division,
it's maintain the theological,
I would say sam high risk.
The reason that bifurcation occurred is
precisely because I wear man's
relationship with the divine prioritized
in the manner that you've just been
describing.
That seems a neurologically Apisai where
that to become our priority and
materialistic,
let's call it lifestyle and mechanistic,
social mechanistic social systems such
as the ones that we inhabit would be
less,
uh,
fertile.
Because if people believed that the
ultimate reality was not being
experienced by the self,
that there was no self that,
that,
that and binds us,
that makes oneness a real possibility.
That starts to suggest that your
consciousness and my consciousness
ultimately are the same.
Or at least there's nothing to suggest
that there are any different.
And that the things that we believe to
be different,
a superficial,
uh,
accents acquired through culture,
that's also true materially.
And I,
and we shouldn't give the material short
trip because the material progress is
the thing that frees attention to,
I mean,
so I mean,
just,
you roll back the clock long enough,
you find people living in just perpetual
states of trying not to die,
right?
And you're like,
you know,
you're,
you're fending off wild animals.
You're exposed to the elements.
You're,
you're,
you're suffering the consequences of
disease and you have no concept of what
disease is,
right?
You don't know about the germ theory of
disease and you and your child dies and
you think it's because the,
your neighbor,
she shined the evil eye on the child,
right?
I mean,
so it's like,
it's,
you have magical beliefs accounting for
changes in the world and they're,
they're completely fallacious,
right?
So the progress we've made in
understanding that the material world is
all to the good,
except we have all of these misaligned
incentive problems and,
um,
externalized damages to two very good
things and be like,
you want an iphone.
Right?
But you don't want people jumping off
the roof of foxconn because life is
such,
it's so painful they're being to,
to make an iphone.
Right.
Um,
so is it possible to make an iphone
without creating just unendurable misery
for some number of people?
Undoubtedly.
It must be true,
right?
We haven't,
we haven't figured it out yet.
Uh,
so as to make that the default and we
need to do that.
But we,
you know,
there's nothing,
there is no,
there is no distance between the
material and the spiritual here.
I mean,
so cause if consciousness is just a
matter of,
of information processing in,
in the,
the right complex systems and if
consciousness could one day be born in
our computers,
right,
well then we'll have an ethical
obligation to,
to not make our computer suffer.
Right.
If Siri could suffer,
right,
well then it matters how you talk to
her,
you know,
and it would matter every,
oh yeah,
I want to complicate life.
Um,
and we're not obviously not there yet or
it certainly seems obvious that we're
not there yet,
but at a certain point we will very
likely either be in the presence of
conscious machines or think we are
right.
We'll lose sight of the they'll,
they'll emulate conscious systems in a
compelling enough way that our default
will be,
I'm in relationship to this thing now.
And,
and to withdraw a sense of consciousness
in that case would seem,
um,
just unprincipled and unethical and
we'll have,
we,
we could well build machines that seem
to have emotional lives and even have
more richer emotional lives than we do
because they're going to have access to
all of human knowledge,
all of human,
uh,
all of the aesthetic products of,
of human ingenuity for all of history.
And they'll be able to talk about them
and appreciate them and remind you of
how much you love certain things and,
and react to your emotion faster and
more accurately than your best friends
or your or your spouse.
Right.
We could bill,
ultimately,
we will very likely build these
machines.
And if we have an understood how
consciousness arises in physical
systems,
will think they're conscious and we will
maybe right or wrong about that.
And,
and whether we're right or wrong about
that will be a huge consequence because,
you know,
it would be,
uh,
um,
it would be an absolutely abhorrent act
to build conscious systems that can
suffer in ways we don't even understand.
And just,
just to cavalierly,
you know,
spawn this off in simulations and,
on the Amazon cloud and not know what
the hell we're doing.
For me that of course we've already
created like the,
this is not just a hypothesis because
already all around us as we've already,
fleetingly discussed,
lie scattered,
they're damaged and broken and
presumably conscious entities that are
fellow human beings,
our fellow English,
but in America,
Americans scattered and broken around
us.
And Sam,
uh,
so for me there's two points to Raha
cause we've got a much longer than I
intended to.
Sure.
It was trippy how like,
uh,
like,
you know,
there's,
there's quite a lot of questions still.
I'm,
I'm fine on time so you can just,
I'll see if I can do as one tumble
dryer,
one s whirling neurological sprawl.
One evening
we stick regurgitation.
Uh,
in your general direction.
Here are the things that interest me.
One on a podcast I was listening to you
do once a like an,
it's a,
it's an idea that sort of more commonly
understood that possibly freewill is an
illusion that decisions are made prior.
So morality and ethics sort of suffer
some what if that's true too?
I don't think that final part holds are
person.
Or you can have your morality and ethics
without free will.
Can I have morality and ethics without
free?
But they roll it by the way.
Evaluate them.
Has to be sort of looked at differently.
Do it in one big,
let me do my vomit.
Girlfriend used to use back.
Yours is more piecemeal.
Mine's a sort of a literal slu.
Yours says it has all sorts of
rationalism and academia to bill on
this.
Of a what?
Minecraft.
A beautiful architecture.
Um,
so Sam Harris,
the other thing is when you were a,
when you've taken psychedelics,
did you not experience a things that
comparable to what you described is
neurologically demonstrable and what
you've experienced in,
in,
in meditation,
I sense that your individual identity is
a sort of,
uh,
confection of sort of ideas and
sensation and that there isn't sort of
a,
a beautiful oneness.
I myself taking Alicia,
Jenny,
I'm clean now for 15 years,
but prior to that,
when I used to take hallucinogens,
the thing I didn't have the vocabulary,
artillery or education to understand
what,
what the hell was going on.
And I wish I'd been born into some sort
of shamanic tradition where people
taught you what spirit is.
When they tell you what it used to be,
a man,
what they're taught you,
what love is,
and how to behave and how to create
systems and how to father a daughter and
how to take care of regardless.
I experienced something within my
identity.
I seemingly be on my identity as a 16
year old boy.
I remember thinking,
Oh my God,
this is not who I am.
I am not this body.
My consciousness is other than this in
temporarily individuated form that only
the distinction.
And uh,
you know,
even just on the,
on a physics level,
like everything was one,
everything is expanding.
I am only experiencing time in an
animalistic way because of my own
entropy and atrophy where I are
limitless in a terminal material being,
I would see myself as part of the whole,
as part of oneness because the way that
I narrativize my life is as a result of
biocentric experience as opposed to
objective experience.
I've just been subjected to this stimuli
and I've built an identity around it.
It felt extremely true and it stayed
with me ever since.
And I've revisited it through meditation
there.
Uh,
aside from it being a,
an interesting experience intellectually
is an interesting experience emotionally
and spiritually.
And if this sense of oneness does not
translate into a sort of a personal
ethical code,
that means I treat people lovingly.
What is its value?
So it's two questions.
Have you experienced that state and what
do you think of it are moral and ethical
implications on an individual?
And what does it,
how does it translate into behavior?
Well,
well,
there are two states I would want to
differentiate.
There are two ways in which you can
think about the loss of self and the
sense of oneness.
So,
um,
with psychedelics,
you get to come back to what I said
before.
You have consciousness and its contents,
right?
There's just,
there's the fact that things are
appearing.
There was the fact that there is
experience and consciousness is the
knowing aspect of experience.
And nor in the normal course of events
you have,
you know,
ordinary sights and sounds and smells
and sensations and thoughts and
emotions.
And you go through,
and most people go through life thinking
every moment of the day in the car,
in that context.
And they don't know how to meditate.
They don't know.
They don't have any mindfulness.
Uh,
they have this sort of white noise of
discursivity where they're talking to
themselves and everything they see and,
and,
and sense.
And every interaction is filtered
through this conversation they're having
with themselves and the world they see
visually and,
and uh,
uh,
you know,
the world they sense with,
with touch and other senses is tiled
over with concepts.
So you,
I,
I look at a bottle and I see bottle,
right?
I'm not the,
this,
this field of light and shadow and color
is differentiated by concepts.
I see my phone,
I see a bottle,
I see the table and everything is
solidified that way.
Now what happens with psychedelics is
your,
your habit pattern of thought and
attention is completely bowled over by
the pharmacology of whatever you've just
ingested,
right?
So if it's acid or mushrooms or,
um,
any of those classic psychedelics,
it's just whoever you are,
whatever your talents are at
introspection,
we know whether you've ever wanted to
meditate or not.
Um,
you are guaranteed to have a change in
your experience.
If you take a sufficient dose of a
psychedelic.
Now it can be a very chaotic and
unpleasant change.
You can,
it can mimic psychosis right there.
a bad acid trip is really bad and not
spiritually uplifting at all.
Uh,
but a good one can put you in a state
which is just unimaginably expansive
where it like all of this,
then the normal,
uh,
pro kind of perceptual categories and,
and emotional barriers between you and
the world breakdown.
And there can be this kind of like just
this free as free flowing exchange of
energy and sense of oneness the way,
or you can,
you know,
you touch a tree with your hand and the,
and the,
the,
there's,
there can be kind of a laser like
concentration in the sensation of just
having your hand make contact with the
tree.
And they can be just as the sense of
just,
you know,
the energy,
the energy of that touch,
right.
Can become,
it's like you turn,
you're turning up the volume on this
channel of information and making it
conscious in a way that it never is in,
in normal life.
And so you just,
you could spend two hours just in this
kind of orgasmic union with a tree,
right?
I on the right drug now,
um,
you can do all,
you can have all of those changes happen
in your consciousness.
You know,
like the full pyrotechnics of a
psychedelic display without losing the
sense of an ego you can actually have at
all.
You can still feel that there,
that you are the center of that and
you're just,
it's just so much better.
Uh,
or in the chaotic,
you know,
psychotics side,
so much worse to be you at that moment.
Now for me,
meditation has a very,
if,
if you,
if you go an intensive retreat and
you're spending,
you know,
12 to 18 hours a day meditating,
you can have psychedelic light changes
in the contents of consciousness.
But the more important change for me is
the insight that there is no center to
consciousness,
that there was simply is consciousness
and everything appearing.
And when you have that insight,
it actually doesn't matter what is
appearing.
It doesn't matter if you,
when you touch the tree,
it feels like,
you know,
a million watts of,
of sublime energy and there's no barrier
between unit you and the tree,
uh,
that is the same on some fundamental
level.
That's the same as just seeing a water
bottle and picking it up and having a
drink in a completely otherwise ordinary
state of consciousness.
The center can drop out equally or be
present equally in both of those cases.
And I'm much more interested in finding
this,
this unifying experience of centerless
snus in the midst of whatever's
happening.
And because of the,
the problem with the psychedelic
experience or,
or any peak experiences that is that
they come and go,
they're there.
They're by nature,
impermanent,
right.
And they,
they,
you had to bring some causes and
conditions together to make them happen.
Whether they're pharmacological or
Meditational,
you know,
he had to go on retreat for a year and,
and meditate 18 hours a day in order to
see those,
you know,
in or lights or whatever it was.
Um,
and or you had to,
you know,
kind of blow your mind on acid and be
kind of useless for the rest of the day.
Um,
uh,
in order to have that,
it,
it's possible to have no ego and have
none of the problems which an ego gives
you in a state of otherwise totally
ordinary consciousness in it,
in a state that's compatible with having
this conversation.
It's just you either feel like there's
someone behind your face in this moment
or not.
That's really what it is.
Like it's like if you're looking at me
and I'm looking at you,
the usual,
the default state of consciousness is to
feel like you're behind your face
looking out at a world that's not self.
Like you're over there,
you're kind of behind the mask that is
your face and you're looking at me and
that's the end.
And when I look at you,
when I react to something you say,
right?
When I say,
well,
that's clearly bullshit way,
hey,
you haven't thought that through that
feeling of you know,
my point in it like this,
you're implicated over there,
right?
And you begin to react based on that
implication.
It's possible a lose that and to have
like just just the world remains and yet
nothing else changes their doesn't.
There's no strange lights.
There's no Kundalini in the body.
There's nothing.
Nothing has to get weird or psychedelic
and uh,
it doesn't matter if it does get weird.
No and I please know you'll write that
there is a of if there is no pragmatism
to spirituality,
if there isn't a practical application
to these extreme experiences within
consciousness,
then what is their value?
My feeling is is that the sort of
linguistics and grammar of mechanics,
the apparent separateness,
the meaning of gesture,
they're very notion of you and die.
There are moments where I experienced it
as temporal.
There are moments where to use the Great
Bill Hicks is I think perfect phrase.
I feel that we are one consciousness
experiencing itself subjectively.
When you talk about the loss of the
being behind the mask of the face for me
this is,
we are talking about enlightenment and
[inaudible].
Are you talking about rather ascetic
version of that without bells and
whistles and pyrotechnics to use your
earlier phrase.
But similarly when you talk about the
Psychedelic,
that sort of very emotional description
of connection and love.
For me,
these are the kinds of experiences that
we need to convey into an environment
that deprived of that kind of experience
and understanding create maximum
security prisons,
which find further means for degradation
in gangs and separation.
Once within that we are living perhaps
in a time that is for me to turn it
around by the extraction of the
spiritual as opposed to the,
because of the amplification of it.
And for me,
the,
uh,
the distinction that you and I have in
the way we view the world is that I feel
that the main agent in extracting this
element of spirit without,
which I don't see a solution for the 7
billion people on this planet,
that the main agent is post secular
capitalist culture and religion.
Well,
no,
it's not only religion,
but it's,
it's dogmatism.
It's bad ideas that,
that are immune from criticism and,
and therefore remain effective.
So what we need,
well,
again,
it comes back to conversation and
violence.
We need successful conversations.
We need to converge.
We need to find the thing that can be
said so as to get the people who are
wrong to recognize it,
right?
And that's,
that's all of us some of the time,
right?
Like if it's like,
like how long do you want to be wrong
for,
you know,
how long do you want to be living under
the sway of a powerful,
bad idea?
Now there are people who have powerful
bad ideas that they class as religious,
who,
who are determined to live the rest of
their lives under the sway of those
ideas,
no matter how much evidence piles up
against them and no matter what the
consequences.
And so that's why religion for me,
it has a special character,
but political dogmatism is in many
cases,
just as problematic.
Economic dogmatism,
economic dogmatism in certain cases
could be the greatest engine of harm we
ever see,
right?
So it's just,
but it's,
it's,
again,
it matters what is true.
It matters.
It matters what causes systems to work
or to reliably fail.
It does sound.
And given that I think in the last few
minutes of our conversation,
we've got close to something that seems
like a fundamental truth that we can
agree on that there seems to be some
essence behind temporal individuality
that has some kind of seeming university
allity though.
How could anybody ever possibly really
say that it is,
if we can bring our focus as individuals
and as a society to that notion and
notion which does exist in all
religions,
uh,
in,
I would say in a relegated role.
And as you said earlier in a role that,
you know,
when Mr [inaudible]
what's the reason to say that it exists
in all religions?
Because what if it doesn't like what,
what then or what if it doesn't equally
or what if much of the,
of the religion repudiates this core
truth?
Well,
I would say that you and I are having
the same conversation and agree about
something fundamental.
And,
and to elect to disagree for the
purposes of hypotheses would be a silly
thing to do because within Christianity,
as you've already said,
there's a mystical tradition within
Islam.
There is within Buddhism,
it's sort of more practically delineates
in gin is I don't know what religion,
religions,
I don't enough about it.
But what I'm saying is,
is it like that what excites me is when
I see perennial mythic template
recurring through folk law,
faith Montefiore's in pantheism that all
seem to infer the truth that you are
personally describing that you have
psychedelically described that you have
neurologically describes me,
don't.
But it's very important to realize that
they don't all do it equally and to pay
lip service to the idea that they're all
teaching the same thing equally well is
creating,
I would argue an immense amount of harm,
but it's some trinity a lot,
but there are some dogmas and doctrines,
but say it doesn't exist and that is
relevant and that it's not there at all.
So I don't think like say take our two
countries.
I don't think the dominant ideology
ideologies are drawn from religion.
They're drawn from sort of a sort of,
uh,
posting lightened meant rational
materialistic ideas and from economic
ideas and colonial ideas and post a
Westphalian tree ideas of state and
nation and power.
You know,
people aren't going to like the big
problems aren't derived from a sort of a
religious source.
And if they are,
they are the very component that share
those qualities with nonreligious power
structures.
The important thing and the thing that
is not present almost by definition in a
secular culture is this idea of essence
and truth other than through mechanistic
exploration through science,
which whilst as you have already eh,
brilliantly explained,
easy and valuable it cause like,
I know you've done talks that particular
that directly contradict this,
but we can't answer the questions of the
experience of essence yet.
And perhaps one day we will perhaps one
day we will.
But so it seems to me that there's some
fighting
one example that I think ties together a
lot of what we disagree about here and,
and it,
it crystallizes the,
the point I am urging you to take
seriously,
uh,
and the don't take it serious.
Take it off.
This particular point,
the mentors,
let me just crystallize this point.
Uh,
and it's,
it's the,
the problem of dogmatism,
why dogmatism is,
is,
is basically always bad and
unforeseeably bad.
You can net,
you can't in advance know how bad a
dogma is going to be just by considering
that the,
the sentence on paper,
uh,
but the dogmatism is just the wrong
methodology for,
for getting anywhere worth going because
it is the antithesis of,
of open conversation.
And so,
and this is the example that I now
always used because it's just,
it just is so clear the,
the dogma that all human life is equally
sacred,
all human lives are equally valuable and
that life starts at the first moment,
the moment of conception right now,
this on its face,
if you just told me if 20 years ago you
said,
what if someone who believes this,
what does he,
what sort of needless human misery is he
going to manufacturer?
I would say,
well,
is just a totally,
this is the most benign thing you could
possibly believe.
Who,
who's going to get killed in the service
of this dogma,
right?
Who's going to have be be tortured for
decades in the service of this dogma.
But when you look at what people have
traditionally done with this specific
idea,
and this is a Judeo Christian,
the American constitution,
nationalistic,
no,
but,
but especially this,
this the link to the moment of
conception.
You,
you,
you'll look at the millions of Americans
who opposed embryonic stem cell
research,
right?
With all the promise that held right
here,
we have petri dishes filled with,
it's imagined,
you know,
hundreds of human souls that,
that are microscopic and to kill those
souls would be tantamount to murder.
To experiment on those souls would be
tantamount to murder and therefore they
didn't want to have a conversation about
all of the,
the children and adults with,
with life deranging injuries and
diseases who might've been helped had
that,
had progress been made in that area.
Now that is a psychotic moral attitude
made possible by the most benign seeming
dogma,
right?
I mean literally we're talking about
people who,
if you could
just one aspect of it and they said an
understandable squeamishness about human
life and we've all seen that the little
baby pro life type images and stuff.
But also Sam,
there's an ongoing dialectic between the
scientific community and religious
community who's got the right to be the
dominant,
the parental figure in ownership of the
public sphere and the public's Seoul in
inverted commerce.
So like,
you know,
there's a lot of kick back at Vista
kickback from Christian groups over the
sort of,
you know,
like evidently beneficial scientific
endeavors,
barely held belief is I,
I believe so,
but interest the Zygote at the moment of
conception and then therefore I'm
worried.
And is it sort of an interesting sort of
notion and I,
you know,
I think you and I would be on the same
side of that particular argument
clearly,
but like,
but what I would say is that we need to
again revert to focusing on what is
truly divine or sublime.
These moments of interconnectivity and
oneness.
And then we wouldn't need trash
talismans to be placeholders for meaning
in a culture that has lost its meaning.
I would say in significant part because
the role of the spiritual has been
relegated to meaninglessness in favor of
a materialistic mechanistic,
culturally that leads ultimately to sort
of widespread consumerism and uh,
and uh,
so,
and consciousness and consciousness that
we are continually in that world of it.
I reiterative for constant tangled
thought that because people have no
experience of the sublime of the divine
or,
but again,
I,
I wouldn't,
um,
miss you have your own fetishistic
objects,
like,
like this notion of consumerism,
right?
So a consumer,
like you and I are having this
conversation in a podcast studio at
headspace,
right?
Headspace.
Is it a meditation APP that on,
on,
on the one hand is the quintessence of
consumerism.
I mean,
this is something that only happens in a
smartphone right there.
The various phone that I was talking
about this causing people to jump off
rooftops,
right?
So,
and yet,
I think headspace is absolutely good
thing to have out there.
And it's,
and,
and it is,
it's,
it's bringing a incredibly useful
practice to millions of people.
Um,
and podcasts bring incredibly useful
conversations to millions of people.
All of this is enabled by mere
materialism and mirror consumerism.
And it's,
there's a,
has to be an ethical and spiritually
correct way to do all this.
It's not a matter of getting rid of the
microphones and getting rid of the
smartphones.
Yeah,
no,
I'm not suggesting that.
I'm just the same way as you would pause
it there.
Is there an extremist and dangerous
version of Islam,
which I would say has the,
I don't think he's an essentially
malevolent idea.
I would disagree with that strongly.
Uh,
I would say that,
uh,
people having objects isn't necessarily
wrong,
but to fetishize objects and to believe
that it's some kind of fulfillment and
spiritual solution can be achieved
through the acquisition of objects is
dangerous and all the more dangerous
because it's not so explicitly
understood.
But that's what's happening.
That the,
the,
the extremist ideology that we already
live with in is so all encompassing that
we cannot see it's horizons that we have
lost the tools to understand it and
describe it.
I'm not talking about sort of a post
Stalinist leftist position.
I'm talking about the reinvention and
the reembracing of the human soul.
Can we find that you've talked a Sam
endlessly about we need to have a
conversation.
Well,
you and I are having a conversation.
I believe in God.
You don't believe in God.
And it turns out that the differences
aren't actually when it boils down to it
that meaningful.
Because when it comes to love of our
daughters freedom,
compassion,
we ultimately believe the same things.
I think that that unless you and I can
find a way of saying,
okay,
I respect that.
I,
you know,
like a lot of my,
the people whose guidance I seek,
uh,
most,
earnestly are atheists,
but that,
that doesn't change.
The fact that I believe that there is,
there is,
there are levels of consciousness that
are beyond material phenomena that will
net will never understand free
magnifications of the human senses or
further analysis of,
uh,
of the material objects because there
are limitations to the human mind,
you know,
and,
and ultimately [inaudible].
Importantly,
Sam,
I also think that all of this stuff,
all of this,
uh,
a theorial wittering has no meaning
unless it translates into love and
compassion.
Unless there is some meaning in the idea
that there is some connection between a
tree in a hand if you achieve the
correct mental state.
Yeah,
I mean,
again,
there are wrinkles here that I just want
to flag.
One is that extreme and mental pleasure
is divorced from ethics.
So for instance,
to go back to this,
this perverse case that we started with
suicide bombing,
I,
I have good reason to believe that the
mental state of a suicide bomber before
he thinks euphoric.
Yes,
yes.
I,
we're not talking about suicidal people
who are just trying to end the
depression as fast as possible.
We're talking about people who are on
the cusp of the,
the deepest spiritual reward that
summer's Tommy,
we stopped on miss.
Take a person,
like a policeman that's willing to risk
his own life to rescue,
rescue a child in Japanese.
Similarly,
their regard for their own life is being
abandoned in that moment.
And that too could be described as a
kind of euphoria because it like,
it happens to fit in with our worldview.
We're cool with it.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah.
And,
and,
but so that's what I'm saying,
the real consequences for human beings
matter and it's possible to,
I mean,
euphoria is something and in a sense of
meaning is something that can be totally
misaligned with what I think we would
agree is an actual ethical relationship
and an actual spiritual insight.
And so that's it.
So,
so euphoria is not a perfect guide.
It can be very misleading guide for
wisdom and compassion.
That's,
that's the point.
Okay.
It's true of Nixon bloody bad decisions
as a result.
Yeah.
And so,
and,
and the absence of euphoria can also be
misleading because you can,
they're,
they're genuinely like what I just said
about this kind of non dual experience
in meditation.
You can,
you can have it in a very subtle way
that doesn't have,
doesn't summon him at least,
certainly doesn't immediately summon
some radical change in your,
your,
the feeling tone of your experience.
It can be,
it can be as simple as just looking at a
water bottles,
you know,
and,
and it's just,
you know,
it's just the lights are on and there's
no center.
Now you can feel that for just a moment
and not recognize it's revolutionary
significance because it doesn't come
with the upwelling of,
of rapture or bliss that people
associate with good meditation or,
or a psychedelic experience or,
or ordinary religiosity like feelings of
love while chanting or singing in church
or,
or whatever.
Or a football match where they're like,
yeah,
there are various contexts in which
these states can be achieved.
And I suppose what I believe is that we
should be looking to create the state's
prioritize the states and give more
people access to them through whatever
means,
you know,
certainly I don't agree with the
imposition of an ideology of Dogma on
anybody else,
you know?
And I can tell and I think the key
obstacles to that are a huge centralized
power bases.
And then without the removal of that,
I don't see how there could be a
solution.
Yeah,
well we,
you know,
I don't,
I don't know how much we disagree about
all that.
I mean,
haven't,
again,
it's all a matter of alternatives.
It's like it's,
you know,
democracy seems impressively broken to
me and capitalism seems impressively
broken to me,
except the alternatives seem worse.
I mean,
this is,
this is a Winston Churchill,
so,
but,
but no,
but I think we just need to find our
way,
but just recognize what we're doing.
We are,
we're trying to grab whatever lever or
dial we can get within reach to change
the human experience in predictably
benign and ultimately positive way.
Do you feel much fear in life?
Do you feel afraid much like in your
tummy?
I mean in your brain?
It's more in my brain than it.
Well,
I mean,
no it's not.
It's not that I can't feel fear I,
but,
but the things that I worry about
publicly as a matter of,
you know,
being someone who talks and writes about
these things is not indicative of my
feeling adrenalized and fearful all the
time.
I mean,
it's not the,
that you can,
you can worry about new.
I mean that actually the thing that
worries me most again at the brain level
is that the greatest risks to human
wellbeing are hard to take seriously.
It's like,
I mean,
they're the people who think,
who professionally think about nuclear
war and,
and new and the consequences of
proliferation and people like William
Perry,
you know,
that the,
I guess he's close to 90 now.
He was 85.
Uh,
these people think that we are at the
most dangerous place we've been in the
last 75 years with respect to the
likelihood of,
of a nuclear exchange.
Right.
So as I could like think the Cold War is
not only not over,
it is like from from Paris point of
view,
we are in another Cuban missile crisis
right now.
And nobody's worried about Russia or
Korea.
Well,
the,
yeah,
all of it.
Yeah.
But I mean I think,
I think it's the possibility of a
mistake.
I mean,
the book I would,
I would recommend your listeners read,
which should make them suitably afraid
is Eric Schlosser's book command and
control,
which is just a story of how many
mishaps and how many,
how,
how haphazard our stewardship of these
nuclear weapons has been.
It's just,
it's been by dent of sheer dumb luck
that we haven't nuked ourselves or
provoked a,
an exchange between,
between Russia and the United States
based on just bad information,
you know?
Um,
so,
but so what is worrisome here is that
it's hard to spend more than five
minutes worrying about that on any given
day.
You know,
like,
well,
I can worry,
I can worry a lot about totally trivial
things in my own life,
right?
Like,
if,
if my website goes down,
you know,
the field,
my feeling of,
of kind of moral emergency is at 11
right?
I like what the fuck is happening.
My website is down.
Like I,
I,
you know,
I want to call the,
the,
my website developers and it's an
emergency.
It's like,
and yet when talking about when,
when I hear that the,
the people who,
who make it,
their business to think about the
prospect,
that whole cities may be annihilated by
the biggest bombs in our lifetime.
When I hear that they are more worried
than they have ever been,
I can,
you know,
five minutes after we talk about this,
I'm not going to be thinking about it.
Right.
And that worries me is hard to,
it's hard to have an appropriate
emotional response to what we think the
data show.
And so it is with the suffering of other
people,
you know,
you feel it about the homeless person.
You can see on this sidewalk that you
happened to be walking on.
But to hear that 90,000
people in Los Angeles County are
homeless,
it's,
it's inconceivable.
And it's hard to summon an inappropriate
emotional response.
Yes.
That is perhaps some,
we've been bull out of alignment with
what we're capable of receiving,
what we're can capable of transmitting.
It's talking of sort of anthropology,
I suppose the bats,
human beings have been so extracted from
these conditions that are,
you know,
where you said we wouldn't even
recognize what disease was.
We've,
we've,
we have become as gods,
we have a cheer,
some mounted,
so many obstacles that perhaps we have
no,
we are no longer living within a pallet
that is appropriate for this particular
mammal.
But we also just have bugs in our
hardware and software that we are bad at
correcting for [inaudible] and that,
and that's why,
that's why again,
systemic corrections,
you like good laws and good tax codes
and good governments and good
institutions I think will do much
heavier lifting for us.
Then all of us getting our heads
straight and keeping them straight day
after day.
So I made the example that I'll give
here is based on the work of Paul
Slovic,
um,
who found it.
It's just,
it's a propensity for moral error that
is totally shocking.
So if you tell people,
uh,
you give them like the classics are to
Unicef Pitch,
like here's you know,
one little girl in Sudan,
you know,
her name is,
is Jenny.
Uh,
she,
you know,
her parents were killed.
She needs your help.
$5 a day will keep her in school and all
the rest,
right?
You tell that story with one
identifiable child peep,
you get the maximum response of
compassion and,
and F and actual altruism from people.
You ask them how much they'll give every
month and you get their maximum number.
If you show that same girl to a
different group of people along with her
brother and you say,
here's Jenny and here's Jacob.
They've suffered this horrible atrocity.
$5 a day,
we'll go $5 a month,
we'll,
we'll keep them in school,
et Cetera.
The,
the,
the altruism and the,
and the self assessment of compassion
reliably goes down just more to the
scope of the problem,
right?
And it's the same girl in the same boy,
you add 10,
it goes down further.
It goes through the floor and if you add
background,
background statistics,
if you say this little girl Jenny,
she's got this terrible problem,
you can help and there's a hundred
thousand girls just like her in Sudan
alone,
people just
passion,
just wash it.
That kind of apathy is a kind of despair
and you kind of hope there's just no,
there's no
point in doing anything.
And so that's what we have to correct
for that.
Teleology of civilization then seemed
somewhat broken.
The idea that sort of like the,
the grow bigger and bigger states and as
sort of a,
a sort of a globally mandated
government,
these would seem to be poor ideas like
what may work for human beings for the 7
billion is de centralization and to
achieve that,
to achieve real change,
where do you suppose the fulcrum will
need to be applied?
Who are the people for whom?
The 90,000
homeless and Little Jenny and the
hundred thousand others.
Oh,
not really a problem because their
system is operating precisely as it was
intended to operate.
Well,
it's all of us here again,
there are not that many bad people.
It's,
we have,
we have a default level of selfishness
in virtually everyone all the time.
And that we have to figure out how to
game that and channel that successfully
toward more benign ends.
I mean,
you,
you what you want the perfect system,
and this is what capitalism promises but
doesn't deliver,
is everyone selfishly seeking happiness
for,
for themselves and prioritizing the
happiness of their families,
their loved ones,
and then maybe going out a few and maybe
extending that circle more and more as
they learn more and more about the other
problems in the world.
Yes.
But they'll never,
they'll never extend that circle
perfectly or they'll,
or most people certainly won't.
And what you want is a system that
captures all of that energy in a way
that allows all boats or most boats to
rise with the same tide most of the
time.
And,
uh,
is there,
is there a perfect solution to all of
these zero sum and,
and,
and positive some arrangements.
Um,
I don't know,
but there's certainly better and worse
ones.
And we know,
we know that.
We know there's some bad ones on offer
that we don't want to experiment with
again and we want to refine our,
our current set of solutions so that
life gets better and better for
[inaudible].
The truth is,
it's,
this can sound like a very despairing
conversation,
but life has gotten better and better
for virtually everyone in our lifetime.
I mean if you look at the last century,
I mean it's something like 10% of people
now live in extreme poverty and 90% of
people don't.
We've got 7 billion people,
90% of them are not in what we're
calling extreme poverty.
The something like 150 years ago that
was flipped,
it was 90 10 the other way.
It was only,
it was 90% in extreme poverty.
Um,
I suppose again,
they send the metric by which we judge
poverty and the metric by which we judge
human experience is something that could
be long debated.
And for me,
I suppose what I'm interested in and I
the here I think we can cut his truth,
truthful experience io at listen to a
podcast you did once and like a with
someone else.
I respect very much Jordan piece and it
got caught up along while on some sort
of semantic tangle and like so but what
I feel is that,
you know,
I am interested in my own sweet,
selfish,
egotistical way in conveying and
transmit in love and change.
And I think that the point where I feel
pressure needs to be applied if that's
even the right attitude,
you need it be combative.
Uh,
for me there's sort of the focus,
I think individual personal revolution
and personal salvation and I think he's
a,
an important component and the
introduction of ideas that go beyond
rationalism and materialism may be a
necessary spur for significant change.
I feel like rationalism,
materialism,
lead people to believe,
well we are just individuals.
We're here for a short amount of time,
pleasure sensation.
It seems to me that just looking around
that seems to be what is happening.
It seems to disengage people.
And then some of the examples you've
given about your human compassion,
it seemed,
it,
it's very,
it seems very hard for people to access
love to access community and within the
operating system that currently have
bites.
I would agree.
Yeah.
We need more again,
what you're talking about our systems
and institutions that,
you know,
just how good could a school be,
right?
How good could entertainment be?
How good could,
uh,
the Internet be?
How good could smell,
how good could social media be in terms
of leading us where we want to go,
both,
both personally and interpersonally.
And I think we are at the beginning of,
uh,
perfecting those things.
And it's not,
it's not that we'll reach perfection,
but it,
I mean,
all of these things are obviously so
broken as they are now that we just
don't know how much better life would be
if we got halfway to,
to the optimum.
Um,
it's just,
uh,
there's an immense amount of work to do
and the work will be done on the basis
of having insights into truth and having
a fact based discussion about the
consequences of,
of,
uh,
turning any of these knobs.
Sam Harris in the background about it,
there's the gallery to this small
facility that headspace the brilliant
app in spite of the contradictions of
having existed in a consumer's
technological world,
which I would like to give props theme
was against the wall and that one,
I mean,
but you know,
we're,
we're going,
there ain't no wall to sort of send me
quote doc Brown in the transcendent
realm,
the wall,
the me,
the you,
all one or glorious oneness.
People have been holding up like ice
skating goes like 45 minutes,
60 minutes for 120 minutes now,
just that duration of the podcast right
now for me,
it's been a great joy and a great
pleasure and a rigorous intellectual
workouts.
And I speak with you and I'm enjoying it
very much.
Sam Harrison most grateful.
And I've returned to the idea that
conversations are what's likely to
produce change,
particularly conversations between
people that don't automatically agree on
the most significant issue.
So I'm incredibly grateful to you.
Likewise.
Well,
thank you.
Thanks,
man.
Yeah,
I got you Sam Harrison,
science and everything.
Hope you enjoyed that episode of under
the skin.
This show was sponsored by my book
recovery,
which is available now.
You can order it on Amazon if you want
it,
and you can also get the audio book on
audible.
We will help you change your life.
It'll help you to see the world more
clearly,
more lucidly.
Finally,
if you like the show,
subscribe to it and review it on itunes
or wherever you get your podcast from,
and get five stars.
It makes me look good and feel nice and
isn't that ultimately the objective.