You are listening to under the skin with
Russell brand.
Today I'll be speaking to rupert
sheldrake.
Rupert sheldrake is a biologist who's
been called the most controversial
scientist on,
uh,
his research strongly challenges the
paradigms of conventional science.
And he's the author of multiple
scientific papers and 10 science books,
many of which have been best sellers
worldwide,
which developers hypotheses that
traditional science has difficulty
explaining,
such as he's popular theory,
morphic resonance.
It lives in London with his wife,
Jill,
and they have two sons.
He's latest book science and spiritual
practice is out now I'm holding a copy
of it in my hands.
I'm looking at Rupert Sheldrake,
who's been,
we've been in the studio and matter of
minutes,
you've challenged the setup of the
studio many ways,
the positioning of the microphone,
the positioning of the camera.
It seems to me that you are a man who
continually flies in the face of
convention.
Have you always been like this rupert?
Um,
well not completely,
no,
but I have always heard her kind of
contrarian streak,
I suppose.
How were your,
was your,
your early experience,
your early professional life was
conventional academia?
It's that,
right?
You were like uh,
Oxford researcher or dawn dawn at
Cambridge.
I did a phd at Cambridge knows that
Donna.
Yes,
I and a sort of a,
I suppose a conventional biologist.
Well I was doing unconventional sounds
under the guise of a conventional
academic appointment as a research
fellow.
So um,
I was actually,
when I was at Cambridge I was trying to
see how we could expand the frontiers of
biology go beyond the framework of
thinking.
But at that stage I hadn't published
clarity as on morphic resonance and what
I did was relatively within the limits
of acceptable science.
It's interesting the Dogma and doctrine
that it exists within the scientific and
academic communities and yours is an
interview that I feel that at the front
of obligated to say that your
controversy is that I think that people
like on the sort of I posing side of the
argument kind of regard you as like,
cause I'm interested,
very interested in spirituality.
I'm very interested in science.
But what you've already said about
challenging frameworks is where my
particular academic interest lies.
I know there's much about convention
that I've have to learn.
Of course I do like most people,
but I'm very interested in pushing
frontiers and boundaries.
But like there's some of the criticism,
oh yeah,
that's it.
Like,
but what you're accused of is like
pseudo science and stuff that's not
backed up by proper evidence.
And I feel like that if we had neil
degrasse Tyson on,
and I hope we do one day or when I've
had people I had on a sort of a,
uh,
the head of philosophy once from Oxford,
he was like a Christian theologian.
And it's interesting,
isn't it?
Because once you're dealing with
mysticism,
which Christianity must be referred to
as to a degree like that,
there's a kind of,
there's a hierarchy and there's hedge
money within those fields.
Why are you controversial?
What is it the have said that makes
people think
of you?
Is that a phrase that I particularly
hated them sometimes if anybody,
Woo Woo Frou Frou band Ted talk.
You've got banned Ted talk,
that elite club,
which I think is somewhat admirable.
Tell me like what your detractors say of
you.
If you don't mind?
Well,
first I have to say why they think it's
heretical.
Um,
what I'm doing fundamentally is
challenging the materialist model of
reality,
which sounds his based on has been for
more than a hundred years,
which is the doctrine that all matters
unconscious.
The whole universe is made of
unconscious matter.
Um,
which then leaves the problem.
How come we are conscious?
And that's called the hard problem.
The most scientists assume that
consciousness exists only in human
brains and possibly in animal brains to
um,
you know,
the liberal ones.
So maybe as far down as worms or
something,
but,
um,
anyway,
it's all only in brains and the rest of
the universities unconscious,
purposeless going nowhere.
Evolution is just a matter of blown
churns.
There's no god out there.
There's no spirit heart there.
There's no creativity out there is dry.
It's just chance.
Um,
and that because they believe are
mindset,
nothing but our brains,
then anything that suggests the mind
extends further than the brain must be
pseudo scientific.
So for example,
I've done a lot of research on
telepathy,
um,
where people,
and indeed dogs.
I wrote a whole book on dog to and
animal telepathy called dogs that know
when their owners are coming home.
Um,
based on evidence that dogs can tell
when their owners are coming home.
Millions of people have had this
experience.
I've done experiments and sure enough,
at least some dogs really can know when
people come at random times and
unfamiliar vehicles we film at All.
We have all this objective evidence.
But the very,
the very fact that I'm suggesting to
laugh with you might be real is
something that provokes this kind of
hysterical response that it must be we
were pseudoscience because my opponents
believe it's impossible.
So they don't think they need to look at
the evidence.
So you think it's impossible,
therefore this stuff must be fake or
phony or fraudulent.
Um,
and what I do is start from the position
that these things seem to happen.
Millions of people with dogs have notice
their dogs or cats pick up their
thoughts,
millions of people who've had the
experience of thinking of some who then
rings on the phone,
telephone,
telepathy.
And I've done experiments to show it's
not just chance.
It's not just guessing.
Um,
so anyway,
these are the kinds of,
what do you think that let's say,
hey cause you know like listen to me,
I'm all about God and consciousness and
changing the world and a model that
expands beyond material is,
and this is where my particular
fascination light,
but wouldn't they say that those,
firstly,
those examples about,
you know,
cats and dogs,
they seem sort of somehow hum drum and
every day they seem anecdotal and w and
wouldn't they say members of the
mainstream scientific community know
we've done tests around that.
It's down to random chance dogs don't
know when their owners are coming home.
We've can demonstrate this in scientific
laboratory conditions,
double blind testing,
et cetera.
I wouldn't,
isn't that what they would say?
No,
no,
they don't see that.
Well first of all,
this,
it turned out total.
But what I searched there too as well.
If lots of people,
I hope more than a thousand AU database,
I've got more than a thousand studies
your case.
Hundreds of dogs that do this and 600
cats.
Well I would say the plural of anecdote
is data.
If lots of people notice something then
to say this is rubbish because lots of
people say or they've noticed it isn't
the right starting point for science.
It's meant to be empirical,
which means based on experience.
So my response to this is to say,
okay,
well let's test it.
Well it wasn't that they'd done the
tests and shown it didn't happen.
No one had ever done a test before cause
they assume it's rubbish.
So when I do the tests then with the
dogs,
then you involves filming the dog,
the place,
the dog weights.
Having people come at random times come
in unfamiliar vehicles.
So there's no possibility of the two.
It's a routine response.
They can't smell people from many miles
away.
They can't identify the signed for
unfamiliar taxi or other vehicle.
Um,
and these dogs still do it and it's all
on film.
So I would say this is evidence for
something which lots of people believe
exist.
And the reason that,
um,
I'd concentrate a lot in a lot of my
work on what I call the mysteries of
everyday life,
what you call humdrum,
um,
is precisely because these phenomena are
classified by most scientists as
paranormal or para means beyond.
They're saying that paranormal,
which means they're sort of spooky or we
were,
my point is they're not paranormal at
all.
Their normal everyday experiences.
For most people.
What's paranormal is the claim that
these things don't exist.
A claim made without evidence on purely
ideological grounds near the beginning.
Ribbit you said that that basic model of
mainstream science is a materialistic
one.
That material,
that Mata is not conscious and
consciousnesses at some point in a way
that we don't understand a merged from
matter.
What do you think is the motivation for
the defense of Dogma?
Why is it so,
why is rationalism and materialism so
rigorously defended and alternative
views?
Uh,
so vehemently opposed?
Well,
it's kind of political.
Originally it was political in the 19th
century,
beginning of the 19th century,
materialism was quite a small minority
view within biology.
A lot of people were fabulous.
They thought there was a life force or
some life.
It wasn't just matter.
Organisms weren't just machines.
Um,
but the material is wanted to believe
that because they wanted a universal
that's just matter cause such a universe
would have no god in it.
Why did they want that?
Because particularly in France where
atheism got going in a big way,
much more than an England,
the old regime that was overthrown in
the French revolution was very closely
allied with the church,
the Roman church.
And they thought that to get rid of the
king,
you got to get rid of Cha,
the church too.
And the best way to get rid of the power
that the church was to say,
God doesn't exist.
So the whole thing's ridiculous.
Sharman pretends.
So in the French revolution in 1793 they
abolished the Catholic Church in France.
They closed the monasteries,
they guillotines tens of thousands of
priests and they proclaimed the cult of
reasons as the state religion notradame
cathedral was turned into a template of
reason.
Now in Russia where you had a similar
massive growth of atheism in the late
19th century.
The Bolsheviks in whose revolution
account or missed a hundred years ago,
1917,
um,
wanted to get rid of religion because
they thought religion supported the SAR
and,
and the state,
and they wanted to destroy this
religious underpinning.
So science was an ally for them in this
militant atheism.
And in Russia in the 19th centuries,
they had about 5 million people belong
to an organization called the League of
the militant godless.
That went round a bit like terrifying,
terrifying bit like the League of the
militant godless.
They went around and trying to stamp out
everything to do with religion in
Russia,
a bit like the red cards in China.
And so atheism was essentially political
in the 19th century.
And for much of the 20th century,
and many people who are atheists wanted
materialist science to back up their
views because it meant they could reject
organized religion,
particularly Christianity,
uh,
in favor of other ideologies.
So it was a necessary tool in
challenging hatch mini that religion at
the idea of God and man's relationship
with God was tied up in power
structures.
These power structures were corrupt and
oppressive,
needed to be overthrown.
I mean no one's saying the French
revolution or the Russian revolution
where bad things necessary but
unnecessary revolutions,
but in order to underwrite those
revolutions,
you had to attack the idea of God,
which was the main stay of the hedge
money or the sort of the basis of that
power.
Now,
earlier you mentioned this idea within
biology of vitalism,
there in a,
in a a hundred years ago in biology that
the idea that there was a sort of a
super mechanical component and element
that couldn't be tracked was present.
I'm learning much about vedic philosophy
where they talk about the idea of
Brahman,
Prana,
Atma the idea that there are essential
non-mechanical energies.
Now is this,
what is this connected to your idea of
morphic resonance?
How does it relate to it?
When you talk about,
well,
what do you mean by morphic residence?
What do you mean by non mechanical
energy?
Even though it wasn't,
you said that it was me.
Well,
morphic resonance is the idea.
This a kind of memory in nature.
You see contemporary science,
one of the dogmas which was established
in the 17th century at the scientific
revolution is the idea that nature is
governed by fixed laws.
And the idea was in the 17th century,
God is the maker and ruler of the
universe.
And God is eternal.
So God's laws are eternal.
And then,
um,
the idea was that everything in nature
has to follow these laws because God is
omnipotent.
So God was the universal law enforcement
agency.
That was the metaphor.
Yes.
Um,
so,
um,
it was a theological consumption and
they didn't have the idea of evolution
then.
And it's very anthropocentric metaphor.
The idea of the universe that nature is
governed by laws and only humans have
laws.
Yes.
So when you think about it,
it's not a very appropriate metaphor to
start with.
No,
they were just patterns.
And I like this idea of metaphor and
it's,
uh,
the fact that we are necessarily dealing
with metaphor when we're dealing with
science.
Uh,
that it,
even the mechanistic model was contrived
at a time when industry and
mechanization was happening in human
culture.
So it would have been an attractive
model and accessible model when
mechanization was happening socially.
Oh,
humans are a bit like a machine.
Nature's a bit like a machine that was
in the language.
It was in the ether here became
inappropriate metaphor for
understanding.
Is that correct?
It is,
yes.
So he sort of nature as a kind of
mechanical system made off of
unconscious matter based on forces at
work,
by pushing and pulling at mechanical
forces.
Um,
and the idea that the laws were fixed at
the beginning,
uh,
you see,
was it made sense when they thought the
universe didn't basically change.
But when the idea of evolution came
along first in biology with Darwin in
1859,
but then with the Big Bang Siri in the
whole of nature,
as late as 1966,
we got to radically evolutionary
cosmology.
If everything's evolving,
then why not?
The laws of nature and in fact laws of
nature.
As I said,
it isn't a very good metaphor.
Why Not Habits?
Why can't universe have regularities
that are habits and then as it kind of
memory in nature that sustains them
instead of some kind of external
transcendent mind with fixed laws in it,
which is the eternal eternal God idea.
I've nothing against God,
but I've got a lot of against the idea
of God making laws of nature that are
totally fixed.
Yes.
It's almost like the requirement for
fixed laws is that a requirement in
order to conduct study.
If there are no fixed laws,
it's impossible to conduct study,
so you need fixed laws.
There must be fixed laws,
but in a way it doesn't make sense.
If you're moving through limit the space
which is continually evolving,
it's more likely that there are patterns
that seem like laws when observed from a
particular perspective but are going to
be subject to the continual evolution
and change that all other phenomena
appear to be subjective.
Absolutely.
It puts it very well and you'll see
things that have been going on a very
long time,
like the crystallization of salt or the
formation of hydrogen atoms are such
deep habits.
They behave as if they're changeless,
but when you look at new things,
new forms of learning,
new forms of behavior,
new chemical compounds,
then you see the habits build up and the
evidence for morphic resonance comes
from looking at new phenomenon,
seeing new habits build up.
For example,
if you crystallize a new compound,
a new chemical compound for the first
time,
it takes months or even years before
crystals form.
But then once you've got it going all
around the world,
they form more easily.
If you trained rats to learn a new trick
in London and rats all around the world
learn the same thing quicker according
to actual evidence,
this disputed evidence,
or is that stuff that's like,
we're down with that?
Well,
the evidence was done years ago,
Harvard and in Edinburgh and Melbourne
university's,
no one's disputed.
The evidence,
the disputation is about how you
interpret it.
And most people thought at the time,
well,
this just shows some weird effect that
we don't fully understand,
so let's forget about it.
Um,
I think the evidence for morphic
resonance,
you see a lot of phenomenal already
there.
Um,
that people agree about fit with morphic
resonance.
For example,
Iq scores have gone up more than 30%
since Iq tests were invented in 1918 and
I predicted this would happen myself,
not in 1918 obvious too,
but in the 1980s,
um,
because the tests have remained more or
less the same,
millions of people have done them,
millions of people of salt,
these problems,
it should be getting easier to do the
tests.
Those calls would be going up.
The average scores,
not because people are getting smarter,
there's no independent evidence.
They're getting smarter,
but the scores are going up because so
many people have already done the tests.
I see is that there's a shared icloud of
consciousness that we're all uploading
our results into,
that we will have access to access to
that.
Consciousness is not wholly housed in
the brain,
but consciousness has some other
component.
That's one aspect of the theory of
morphic resonance is it?
It is.
It's a kind of collective memory and
that idea already existed in this
psychologist young.
Yes,
with his Jerry was the collective
unconscious,
um,
had the idea that we all tap into a kind
of collective memory,
but he was thinking just in terms of
human psychology and I'm saying that's
the way that all nature works.
It's not just us.
When you talk to this,
he saying because of patterns in dreams
that people dream in a kind of
consistent language in set and Casey's
that motifs appear across cases,
across continents that have a continuum
to them.
Joseph Campbell's working comparative
mythology suggest that indigenous
cultures produce patterns within their
myths that are identifiable.
That the s,
uh,
an African myth or an Icelandic myth can
have templates that are comparable,
which suggest that consciousness
communicates or at least has some
essential quality.
There is not determined by material
reality or geography,
but has some other form of connection.
I mean,
I personally don't have a problem with
this idea because I see that the sensory
realm is accessible by the instruments
we have.
If we didn't have a sense of smell,
I wouldn't be able to understand
conceptually what you meant by a sense
of smell.
I know that different animals have
different ranges of hearing,
have different ranges of sites.
So it seems to me possible that energy
can communicate and travel in means too
subtle for my limited instruments to
ascertain and receive.
So for me,
it's never been a problem.
But it is necessarily difficult to
demonstrate when it's transferred back
into the language of mechanics material
and identifiable evidence,
isn't it?
Well,
I mean,
not in principle.
you can do experiments to test this on
chemicals,
on crystals,
on ranch,
on humans.
So in principle you can test us with the
scientific method.
I mean,
I'm totally pro the scientific method.
I spend a lot of my life doing
experiments.
Um,
so,
um,
in principle there's no reason you can't
test it.
And in fact it has been tested.
Um,
it's just an unfamiliar idea for most
Westerners.
Now you're studying eastern philosophy
and eastern philosophy.
The idea of a memory in nature is
completely standard.
Uh,
you know,
I lived in India for seven years.
I worked in an agricultural institute.
Um,
and the,
so I sort of got fairly familiar with
Indian philosophy.
I was in much influenced by it.
I had this idea before I went,
but when I talked about this idea in
Cambridge on high table of my college
career,
college,
you know,
the looks of blanking comprehension or
in the tea room of the Biochemistry
Department where I worked,
um,
when I got to India I would explain this
idea to Indian friends and colleagues.
Even people I met on trains.
And you sound test.
They,
well they do.
They are,
they asked me first,
I didn't,
you know,
in India,
if you sit on the train,
uh,
what is your name?
Where are you from?
Ecentra and then give me some of your
theories.
Yes,
about three questions in,
you know,
after,
what is your salary?
They ask you what is your view of the
world?
So I really wants it.
So I explained this and the general
response I got from Indian friends,
colleagues,
and even strangers with,
there is nothing new in this idea.
Ancient Rishis have said there's
thousands of years ago.
What's the,
what's the,
how,
how is that vedic?
We understood the idea that there is
this a memory in nature,
but it's basically part of the
philosophy of Karma,
which in in it's limited form is about
reincarnation carrying over memories
from one life to another.
But in it's more general form,
um,
can be seen as a theory of cosmic
memory.
And in some forms of Buddhist and Hindu
philosophy,
they have this idea of a cosmic memory.
The Sea Asopus took this up with our
idea of the akashic records,
which is a kind of cosmic memory bank.
Um,
so I didn't know all that.
When I thought of these ideas in
Cambridge,
I came to them through thinking about
biology and plants and you know,
it was coming.
How did you come to when I was working
on plants,
how do plants grow?
Plant morphogenesis the development of
form.
Um,
how does the leaf become a leaf?
How does a rose fly become a rose
flower?
Why is an oak leaf different from an ash
leaf?
Um,
I worked hard.
I was working on the plant and hormone
auxins supplant a hormone that makes
cells grow and makes roots form and
makes would cells form.
And I worked hard at how it was made and
how it was transported run the plant.
But the thing is it's transported round
to all plants in the similar way and
it's made in a similar way in all plants
and yet they have different shapes and
so everyone was trying to sell.
You can explain form in terms of
chemicals and this was the main
chemical.
Everyone thought was the important
influence,
but I realized actually it won't explain
it.
They've all got the same one is and it's
like trying to explain what goes on in
different shops and factories and
schools because they will have the same
kind of money.
Are you an end to it?
It's,
it's the,
it's something that's part of the
system.
Take it away in the system would
collapse,
but it doesn't explain why they're
different or why they have that form.
And an idea that came up in the 1920s in
developmental biology was the idea of
morphogenetic fields,
fields that shape form.
I got interested in this,
but then I realized these fields have to
be inherited somehow.
They can't be inherited through genes
were changing code for proteins.
They had to be inherited by some kind of
direct link.
And then I run out,
asked if it was a kind of memory across
time,
a great deal of biology would make
sense.
Not just biology but a lot of nature.
So I had this kind of flash of insight
and for three or four days I was kind of
manic state when I first came up with
the idea of morphic resonance because
more and more things made sense.
And then I got worried,
you know,
it's a kind of theory of everything and
I ought to be worried about there.
So I didn't publish it for another eight
years.
I thought I've really got to think about
this hard and look at the evidence.
And when I finally worked through a long
process,
it made,
it really did make sense after thinking
it through.
And that's when I published my first
book,
a new science of life.
The idea being that there is a memory
that is beyond material that is
traveling through time.
Can you give us some examples of that?
Well,
the one example would be the,
the thing I mentioned with rats.
If animals learn a new trick then ranch
similar rats faced with the same trick
somewhere else on the basis of
similarity resonate with those rats
before morphic resonance is about
similarity in patterns of vibration or
patterns of activity.
Um,
so um,
what I'm suggesting is there's a kind of
resonance across time that um,
just go,
Ma goes across time without falling off
with time and across space.
I mean this is a difficult idea perhaps,
but the alternative is laws of nature
that are outside of time and space
altogether and yet somehow present
everywhere.
It's not as if the conventional
alternative is absolutely mind boggling.
My mind bottle factor free,
it's just we're used to it.
That's right.
You're quite right that to suggest there
are objective laws that exist outside of
time that is an unusual and as you've
said already,
it's a,
it's analogist to the idea of God
anyway.
Yeah.
That there is an absolute template,
a sovereign,
uh,
a sort of a monolith of truth that
stands beyond the,
that's in a sense as a paradigm that is
the same as saying,
God,
there's these rules that are in charge
except for material is scientists.
The rules are supposed to have come
about spontaneously by themselves.
They're like things in a mind but they
say there is no mind.
So they're completely paradoxical to
have laws that are in material,
that are rational,
that have no material being and yet no
non material substrate is incoherent
belief.
And yet that's what most scientists
believe.
How and why it is,
I mean what more of obvious example I
for obvious that you know,
that famous example of the four minute
mile as in the film,
chariots of fire though no one could
break the four minute mile,
someone breaks the four minute mile,
then people break the four minute mile.
It's took a very poor public
identifiable idea.
The once he's identified that something
is achievable,
it becomes achievable.
It comes sanctioned,
accessible.
Somehow.
What I'm interested in rupert,
ease,
how dogma behaves and how heresy is
regarded in control.
Now one of the things I enjoyed in your,
let's call it,
um,
uh,
like I,
I like to have a band,
a Ted talk is a cool thing.
I think like in your band
a Ted talk is,
uh,
when you were talking about how
mainstream science protects it,
uh,
dogmas through denial of variation.
For example,
what's the,
uh,
the speed of light?
Yeah.
Well,
I gave an example of the speed of light
that between,
I got interested in this because the
idea that the speed of light,
it's totally constant and all the
constants are constant as part of the
fixed law dogma.
Um,
so I thought,
well,
I'll just check out.
I had no particular,
I don't work on physical constants.
So I wasn't a particular thing where I
had a personal interest,
but I just thought I'd look at the data.
And when I did,
I was amazed to find it varied quite a
lot between 1928 in 1950 or so,
the speed of light dropped by 20
kilometers per second or around the
world.
And then it went up again and they were
all claiming that they're accurate.
They have little error bars on the
graph.
So you showing very small arrows that
the Arrow was like plus or minus 0.1
of a kilometer per second and yet lose
20 kilometers per second difference.
And I just couldn't understand what was
going on.
So I went to see the head of the
national physics laboratory at
Teddington,
um,
the man in charge of measuring
constance.
And I asked him and he said,
well,
it was constant.
Don't even need him,
your laptop mate.
It's always the same.
So he said,
don't,
well,
um,
he said,
I know it's a very embarrassing incident
in the history of our science.
And I said,
well,
does that mean that everyone was fudging
their results?
So in,
in,
during the whole of that period or
around the world to get the expected
result.
He said,
we don't like to use the word fudging.
I said,
well,
what do you call it?
And he said,
we prefer to call it intellectual phase,
locking certainly rate.
They then,
then it went up again and then they to
resolve this problem.
They're just defined it.
They by fear,
they invented the speed of light,
the closest value.
And they said,
that's it from now on,
it's defined.
And then they defined the meter in terms
of the speed of light.
Um,
so that even if the speed of light did
change,
you'd never notice because the media
would change in length.
The same time in the unit of measurement
would also alter,
I'm reminded of the Melville quote,
all human science,
but passing fables as we learn more,
everything that we think of as being
absolute will necessarily evolve because
we are only looking at a small portion
of all of the available evidence.
What do,
uh,
revelations in quantum physics in your
opinion,
mean about the nature of consciousness?
I know that they're double slit theory
is an area that,
uh,
people like myself who are of a
spiritual bent,
uh,
Lee Paul over as evidence that
consciousness impact,
uh,
mattel matter and the behavior of waves
and particles and physicists say,
no,
you're misinterpreting this in your
drawing conclusions that are erroneous,
but what does it tell us without us
being too sort of quick to leap on our,
um,
you know,
our chariots of fire and start blasting
out the silver trump pits and
proclaiming the lord?
Well,
I think the main,
most important thing about quantum
theory is it tells us that nature is
probabilistic,
but there's,
there's no rigid determinism.
You can't predict things exactly.
Um,
and there's a kind of inherent freedom,
right?
Even at the most fundamental put in the
most fundamental particles of matter,
I think the staff freedom.
Yes.
Do you mean that just because the
behavior of particles and waves
apparently altering under observational
and under observation?
No,
the the,
if,
if you measure the take a single photon
going through a double slit for example,
you can't predict which way.
Whereas lend up which bit of the film
that you're filming it with it'll land
on.
But if you send thousands of single
photons,
one after another,
you get a kind of average pattern,
which is like a wave pattern.
Um,
so it follows a kind of probability
distribution,
but you can't predict any individual
one.
If you've got a radioactive uranium
atom,
you can't,
you can say what it's halflife is.
We've got millions of them by how many
years will it be before half of them
have decayed.
But this individual atom,
you can't tell if it's going to decay in
a million years or in the next second.
There's nothing that enables you to say
that.
So there's an inherent freedom at the
very foundation of matter.
And what chaos theory has shown is that
even bigger things like the weather
systems have a kind of inherent in
determinism or freedom.
And the same is true of the way the
nerve cells in our brain work.
And many of them are on a knife edge.
They could go one way or another.
So all through natures as this kind of
in determinism.
Um,
that means there's a kind of inherent
freedom at all levels in nature.
There's certain strong habits,
but when you get things that are
changing and they're on cusp points,
there's,
there's this kind of in determinism.
Now I don't think the observer stuff in
quantum theory,
I think it's overrated.
The,
you know,
the consciousness thing.
Well basically what it says is that the
kind of observation you make in quantum
theory depends.
It depends on what you're observing.
In other words,
your observations depends on the
Observer.
But the philosopher Schopenhauer pointed
out exactly that in around 1800 you need
the whole of science.
He said all observations depend on
observers.
It,
it's not as if nature is out there,
just sort of passively observing itself.
When we observe nature,
we come to it with our frameworks of
thought,
preconceptions,
measuring apparatus at Centra.
Whenever we ask a question of nature and
an experiment,
the answer we get depends on the
question we make.
So that's a perfectly general point
about all science.
It only came to sort of pump pillar
consciousness through quantum theory,
but it's not specific to quantum theory.
Yes,
I see.
Now what do you think on a more
practical level,
the imposition of dogma normally
protects the interests of the powerful.
Is it important that much of what is
regarded as a sanctioned and valorized
science is corporately funded?
Is that important?
I don't think that's important.
Actually.
Not the most important thing sake.
The dog moves of science got established
before corporate funding became very
important.
I mean this dogmatic materialism was
already well established by the late
19th century when,
you know there are a few German
companies making aniline dyes and things
about them,
early chemical companies making aspirin
and stuff.
But long before this sort of massive
corporate involvement,
it was an ideological movement.
People like th Huxley here in England,
um,
we're basic material and that they
wanted to spread the message about
materialism cause they wanted to destroy
the power of religion and make
scientists as it were,
the new priesthood.
If you have a culture where you destroy
the old priesthood and where science
reasoning and progress of your ideology
and every government now being converted
to it,
economic progress through science and
technology,
every government in the world,
it's a dominant paradigm then who are
the priests of this new culture?
Obviously as a scientist.
And Th Huxley wanted the scientist to
become a kind of priestly caste,
um,
professional scientists who would then
be the go to people for governments.
And in many countries there's a
separation between church and state.
But in no country is the separation
between science and state.
So I would say the power base of science
is much more state than,
than corporations.
They've come long later.
What is their gospel?
Well,
the Gospel is,
is we'll save the world through science
and technology.
You know,
where the saviors of humanity,
um,
religions have screwed it up.
People just fight each other.
But we come along and we'll care.
Diseases,
reduce infant mortality,
provide abundant consumer goods,
uh,
prolong life.
And many of these promises of come true
after all.
It's not just ideology.
It's a very powerful,
much less what is not empirical.
Well,
it's not imperia clears the metaphysical
belief system that nature's totally
mechanical,
that it's all unconscious,
that the laws are fixed.
All these,
in my book,
the science to illusion,
I have these 10 dog,
most of science memories,
a stored in the brain.
That's another one.
Um,
they believe that because the
materialist,
everything must be matter.
So all our memories must be inside our
heads in some way.
A memory must have a material component.
It must on some level be measurable.
Exactly.
And therefore when you die and your
brain decays,
all your memories were wiped out.
So every religion that believes in
reincarnation or an afterlife or
purgatory or whatever,
any form of transmigration,
any kind of access to connections or
anything like that must be rubbish.
Because memories in the brain is
impossible for any aspect of them to
survive.
It seems to me the rational conclusion
of rationalism is that we are
individuals.
There is no meaning,
therefore consume.
Yes.
And that's why the word materialism has
two meanings.
And in science and philosophy,
it means this worldview I'd been talking
about and we've been discussing in
ordinary everyday language.
It means people who go to shopping malls
all the time and are constantly
consuming things.
That connection is telling that and you
think,
oh,
I think so.
Yes,
very much so.
I think that it's not a coincidence.
We used the same word for both.
Can we talk a bit about psychedelics and
uh,
you taking psychedelics?
I don't want to talk too much about it
since most of them are still illegal,
but should we talk about how you've
never taken psychedelics now it's
illegal and wrong today.
I'll tell you why.
I'm very interested in Terence Mckenna
and you were friends with Terence
Mckenna when you,
in fact,
I've heard him talk about you and you
and stuff.
We were great friends and in fact we had
with our friend Ralph Abraham,
who's a chaos theory mathematician at
the University of California.
We had about 40 or 53 way trial logs and
we produced two books together and it
was about 20 or 30 of these try logs are
on my website in streaming audio.
So,
you know,
for 20 years nearly we met every year.
We spent several days just talking to
each other cause that's what we most
enjoy doing.
And um,
one of the things we were interested in
was indeed psychedelics.
And one is terrance had many interests.
Psychedelics is what he's best known
for.
But he had an extraordinarily wide
ranging mind and he was also incredibly
funny.
Um,
well for me,
um,
just to,
I suppose if it's a long time ago and
talked about it,
for me a great revelation was in about
1971 when I took lsd for the first time
and everything.
I had been taught about the nature of
minds.
You know,
I studied this stuff.
It Cambridge as an undergraduate,
you know,
nerve impulses,
neurotransmitters,
hormones affecting sanctuary,
sexual characteristics,
all that kind of thing.
Suddenly and the immediacy and the
incredible power of this visionary
experience.
I just felt something very,
very important to just be left out from
this world view.
So for me it really was what the term
means,
psychedelic means psyche,
revealing mind,
revealing.
It revealed a Roho realms of mine that I
had no experience before noon at told me
about.
Um,
and opened up an interest in the nature
of consciousness.
So for me,
it was a transformative experience.
Do you experienced during this period,
long time ago that was so
transformative?
Describe it please.
Well,
the first thing that happened was I took
it with a French annotating it once or
twice before.
We thought it took an hour to come on.
That's what he thought.
So we took it
to wrap the site that we can hear police
sirens.
So we took it,
we thought we'd have a meal while we
came on.
So we were in a restaurant and it came
on during the,
in this restaurant,
food started looking distorted,
the whole theme.
Okay.
So I want you to get back to my rooms in
college.
I was a of cloud college at the time
too,
that suddenly this journey became a kind
of,
it went on forever,
going through streets and everything
distorted.
And when I got back,
I thought I must have taken a massive
area of days.
And I thought,
cause I felt completely out of control.
My whole ego was dissolved.
I didn't know what was happening.
It had come on sooner than we thought.
So I thought this must be a huge
overdose.
I'll be insane forever,
etc.
In fact,
I thought I must be in hell.
And then neon signs saying hell that
I've all around me,
which proved it.
Um,
then a friend,
um,
my friend sort of talk to me and I sort
of came to my senses as it were,
and he's not really a census,
but suddenly I felt so if I was floating
up towards,
I saw the light above me and I broke
through like the surface of the ocean.
And suddenly I was in the realm of
transcendent beauty.
Um,
music turned into forms and patterns.
I had the sense of connection with the
one at all and everything.
And,
um,
kind of mystical experience.
And I later came to know that Stan grof
and other people describe this as a kind
of death and rebirth experience like
that going up through the darkness to
the light.
It's like being born from the wound,
coming out through the birth canal into
the lighters,
kind of like a birth or rebirth
experience.
So for me it was a kind of
transformative moment of a whole new way
of understanding consciousness and my
connection with the greater
consciousness.
Yes,
the very idea that one's conscious
experience can be chemically altered.
That one's perceptions are not um,
rigid.
For me.
It demonstrates the plasticity of
reality and our relationship with
reality.
Terence Mckenna,
one of the things that fascinates me
about Kim is the conclusions he draws
from these experiences with regards to
the way that power operates,
the control of substances of this nature
in me as a person that's in from drugs.
You know,
I don't take drugs.
I'm not taking drugs for a long time,
but what I,
what I personally in chew it is that
there real so many vested interests in
keeping people behaving in an orderly
manner and if you have access to
mysticism,
it one tends towards challenging
structures and like we said at the
beginning of our interview,
Rupert looking at frameworks and asking
simply why,
why does my life have to exist within
this framework?
Why must I behave in this way?
Why is this convention being observed?
I think it's interesting.
I know when you,
what you said about revolutions earlier
and the necessity for to challenge the
idea of God because of the way that God
was operating in power structures prior
to the two revolutions that you
mentioned you use to underwrite those
power structures.
I can see the necessity for challenging
hedge money in that form,
but the removal of God to give you a
professor the full niche and quote you,
the God is dead and we have killed him
and there's not enough water in the
world to watch the blood from our hands.
The idea that when we lose God,
when we lose a way of accessing and
understanding the mystery,
we prevent ourselves.
We have prohibited from being fully
human,
continually evolving and connected.
We begin to regard ourselves in the
material model as components that have
to have a mechanical function to be
valuable.
We become a tool of consumerism.
We become either an asset or a deficit.
We don't have inherent value.
So I can see the politically why these
power structures are perpetuating.
And even if,
as you say,
they existed prior to corporatization,
I would say the power behind
corporatization is mutated and was
present in some other form prior to
that.
And that it's about the preservation of
power structures and always has been.
And that's why it's so vehemently
opposed.
Whenever anyone says,
Hey,
there's another world there.
Love is real.
We're all connected.
Yeah.
Whenever that message starts to come
out,
people don't like it.
It gets dampened down pretty quick.
Right.
I agree.
And I think that the suppression of the,
there's a reason why these revolutions
occurred.
And,
um,
but what,
what it leaves at the materialist
worldview where from which God's been
removed or relentlessly St Kilda society
leaves people alone,
isolated and the privacy of their
skulls.
And um,
and is it's a well,
it's meaningless and depressing and
that's why depression is the endemic
disease of modern societies.
But that's exactly why I think that in
the secular age,
when many people have lost contact with
traditional religions and spiritual
practices are so important.
And that's why I my most recent books
called science and spiritual practices
because,
um,
the,
the paradoxical thing is the sort of
ironic that people think of science as
against spirituality when if you
actually use science correctly and use
look in an open minded way,
you studied spiritual practices
scientifically,
like meditation for example,
then it turns out the evidence is
overwhelming.
This is very good for people.
People who do it are happier,
healthier,
live longer.
Um,
you know,
people have figured out which bits of
the brain changed during meditation,
lowering stress levels sleep better.
Um,
the scientific evidence suggests these
are very,
these practices are very good for you.
In my book,
how I deal with a number of other ones,
like um,
connecting with nature,
which is very important practice for a
lot of people,
including me and pilgrimage.
There's an amazing revival of pilgrimage
going on in Europe at the moment.
And um,
I think this is probably the one that
most clearly expresses.
Um,
the fact that so many people feel
they're on a journey,
they want to go somewhere there
somewhere that connects them with
something bigger than themselves.
It's the physical journey of a
pilgrimages and expression of that such,
um,
for teleology,
yes,
there's a purpose to the,
the,
the journey and the,
if you're getting an a pilgrimage to the
holy place,
then you're going to a place which holy
and healing come from the same root.
So you're going to a place that can have
a healing effect on you.
You think then that
we live our lives extracted from these
kinds of principles until they are
somehow scientifically verified that w w
what you said about meditation,
it's something that I've thought about
quite a lot that you know,
mindfulness and meditation and now
spoken or from a perspective of
wellbeing,
but it has been necessarily secularized.
Uh,
it's something that I find it kind of
irritating I suppose because meditation
is,
it was being present and suggested and
proposed through religious ideologies
for Millennia.
And was it,
and these conclusions were reached not
by impure at wouldn't work perhaps by
empirical means,
but we're not by scientific means.
I wonder what other notions found in
theology would be similarly beneficial.
I don't query the need for change as in
the examples that you've already given
the revolutionary changes.
And nor do I dispute at how religion has
been used to support power to,
uh,
to,
engine bigotry and oppression.
Those are like,
but,
but like a,
in my belief system,
uh,
there is,
a line be quick to see where religious
people are,
right?
And this mindfulness example,
and possibly what you're saying about
pilgrimage,
about purpose,
and when w w it anecdotally,
my experience of the world is even when
I'm talking to people,
they feel lost,
unhappy,
disconnected,
you know,
like,
and you could arrive at these
conclusions for Marxist theory that
capitalism would lead to alienation and
people feeling that their only function
is an economic one or a productive one.
So as you're saying that these group of
literally these traditional ideas such
as pilgrimage,
is it a new way of reengaging with
aspects of our consciousness that will
be neglected?
Absolutely,
yes.
Well,
I think it's re-engaging because it's
going on a journey to something that is
bigger than you.
Um,
you know,
for example,
every year I've been doing this,
I have a Godson who's a teenager and you
know,
I feel as a godfather I should do
something for his birthday.
And I think,
and it stopped giving stuff to people
because I think everyone's got too much
stuff.
So I give experiences.
And when he was 14,
I offered him,
I said,
my offer is a pilgrimage to Canterbury
rewalk,
the last eight miles through fields on
footpaths and words.
We go to the cathedral,
we light candles at the shrine of some
Thomas go to choral even song,
which this beautiful service and um,
have a cream tea and come home on the
high speed train.
And I said,
would you like to do that?
And slate?
Just to my surprise,
he said yes and we had a blissful day.
And we do that every year.
No two different cathedrals.
Beautiful.
How do you,
uh,
not that you need to,
other than in the context of this
question,
I align your anglicanism with what
you're saying about morphic resonance.
You know,
like a very,
what would people would deckard is
conventional faith?
Well,
I mean,
it's not very conventional to be a
Christian and modern Britain and you've
got 5% of people go to church regularly.
Um,
so it's definitely not the power
structure and nunes in it for the money
anymore.
So,
um,
morphic resonance actually fits very
well,
particularly in my book on science and
spiritual practices.
One of them,
I discussed his rituals and all
religions have rituals and secular
cultures do as well.
And what are some rituals of secular
culture?
Well,
the American thanksgiving festival for
example,
so national ritual rituals,
reenact and original seminal moment in
the history of a group.
So Jewish people for example,
reenact the Passover dinner that
happened in Egypt when they fast
foreman for ancestor worship and
connection.
And to demonstrate that we exist beyond
our individual selves and the connected
to our lineage.
Yes,
the back to an original event that sets
the lineage in motion.
And so Christian holy communion is a
ritual celebration of Jesus's last
supper with his disciples itself,
a Passover dinner.
Um,
so it,
it's a kind of ancestral connection
across time.
And the point about morphic resonance,
it depends on similarity.
Now if you have a ritual where you use
the same language,
the same words,
the same gestures,
the same incense,
the same whatever,
um,
you deliberately create things as
similar as possible and you set up
perfect conditions for morphic
resonance.
So in all cultures,
people believe that by doing these
rituals,
they connect with our ancestors.
Have done them before,
right back to the first time it's done
and it means the individual individuals
much more than just me.
I'm part of a whole long tradition that
went on long before me and we'll go on
long after me.
And this whole tradition in any case is
about something bigger than us because
Jesus,
his last supper,
the Passover,
it was about more than just those
people.
It was a in their own terms of an
intervention of God into history.
Well,
I like that.
So my individual consciousness is just
temporal,
but my consciousness has existed before
me and my consciousness will exist after
me and my consciousness is part of a
vital energy,
a continual pranic flow existing through
all forms existing beyond and through
time and space,
time and space themselves being just
referential points from this biological
organism or this species of biological
organisms that would be entirely
different if we had different senses.
That consciousness is somehow reflecting
onto the screen of reality rules that
are apparent to its own understanding
and its own interaction with the
external and through these rituals we
can demonstrate it,
recreate it,
connect with it in a different way and
see how we have existed like waves
passing through time.
I like that.
But somehow stripped of mystery.
These things can seem like,
I imagine that some of our out there
rather than more radical a listeners my
thing,
you know the whole cause to me it sounds
bloody delightful going for the cream
tea and the pilgrimage to Canterbury's
or sort of thing I might do actually.
But like a lot of people think,
oh I ain't doing that.
Oh I want to do ios guy with a flick
knife.
Buyer would so like you know,
so like it doesn't it seem,
it seems conventional.
Whilst you said it's like 5% day seems
like,
I don't know,
what does it seem,
does it seem radical?
It seems,
but what is it?
That thing that I'm feeling,
it seems somehow,
I don't know,
safe like it's not going to change the
world.
Like it's had its moment that it's
nostalgic.
Is that what it is?
Well,
I think there's an element of that
connection.
Well,
anything that connects,
I don't consider it nostalgics connect
with tradition in the past.
I mean here in Britain for example,
we have incredible cathedrals and those
were produced in the middle ages when
virtually everybody who believed that
they were part of something bigger than
themselves and the whole society,
I mean 3 million people with ox carts
and ropes and pulleys created all these
incredible cathedrals.
Cantor breed our own wells,
Salisbury of Centra,
Westminster Abbey.
They thought they were part of something
much,
much bigger than themselves.
And they're still here today.
And I find them incredibly powerful.
Um,
I don't think it's just nostalgia.
I think they have a living presence and
anyone who goes into them,
um,
especially if you're getting listened to
this evening service even song where
everybody is it as this beautiful music.
It's an extraordinarily beautiful and
transforming experience.
Now I've nothing against Iowasca and I
wouldn't like to say this is,
it's either all you see for me it's not
either or.
I think all the spiritual practices are
part of what we can do.
And there's many,
many spiritual practices we can take
part in meditations,
one rituals or another.
And I was,
Kara has done as a kind of ritual as a
kind of sacramental communion where the
participants,
especially on these psychedelic churches
like Santo Dima.
MMM,
that sounds good.
This is a Brazilian,
there's a very big psychedelic church in
Brazil.
It was two actually more than two,
but the main ones are called sent who
die.
Me.
And when you went to Fsu,
tyler,
which means union of plants and these
are churches I have been,
I suppose I suppose I should add a long
time ago.
Um,
to services these churches in Canada
actually watching the,
so the one they liked be psychedelic
charities.
I'm fascinated why they've got good
murals in them.
[inaudible] they don't know the,
these not,
they didn't have buildings.
I mean the wellies they may be doing in
Brazil,
but this is sort of in a room where they
rent rooms and things.
So what they are at Inosanto,
maybe men are all dressed in white on
one side of the room,
women on the other.
And it started to my surprise with
everyone reciting the our father and the
Hail Mary.
And um,
and then there's the kind of community
where you all go up one after another
and drink from this chalice of Iowasca.
All right.
And then the whole group is traveling
together and the person leading it says,
you know,
this isn't just personal tripping.
You know,
we're all in this together and we're
traveling like in a boat together.
And there's periods when you sing
together extraordinarily beautiful
songs.
And then periods when everyone sits in
silence and has kind of visionary
experiences.
In my case,
for the first time he did,
and I was sort of zooming out of the
earth into the cosmos,
through the stars,
and it was astonishing experience.
Um,
and then you come back and there's
another song.
And as the country was very strong sense
of group solidarity.
But I don't see that that is is um,
you know,
I see that as a perfectly compatible
with lots of other religious [inaudible]
sat around having your cream tea.
I sounds much more radical to me.
I went to this church repat in ladbroke
grove quite by mistake as a matter of
fact.
I like I wonder then and it was,
I like to discover Eritrean Christian
folk.
They had like a,
like a screen at the front.
They will listen to pretty crazy
keyboard music.
Everyone else sat me with Airtran and a
little kid at the back and a tiny
plastic chassis was,
seemed to be there in some sort of
administrative up the front
was the pastor and a couple of other
guys.
It was pretty uh,
intense,
you know like um,
let the,
it was like a feel Jesus type levels of
stuff and a guy like,
you know,
everyone was going out the front and
having like proper,
it looked to me like speaking in
tongues,
out of body kind of experiences.
While I was watching this all happen
from it,
from the midst,
from the congregation,
which was only about 30 or 40 people in
this church.
You know,
I was thinking how,
how are we going to go home afterwards?
You know,
how are we going to pick up our coats
now?
Car Keys and be normal again like after
we have letting ourselves go after we
have dispensed temporarily with our
identity is hello there cnn.
I suppose this is what I mean while
you're having a cream tea or you're
walking in a field is still essentially
you,
but while you're shooting through the
cosmos on Iowaska,
you asked if physically experiencing
that you are not just your identity is
rupert or Russell or whoever you happen
to be listening to this thing right now
and watching these Eritrean people in
congregation of watched them having a
group experience that was clearly
transcendent,
which was clearly outside the accepted
social rules.
I've thought how will this sees,
how will it comes to cessation?
I went to the front of my cell phone
that the pastor did some ritual on me
and where my set killer mechanical
condition mind would say that it was all
Brouhaha and nonsense except for when
like he offered me the healing.
The place in my stomach that you grabbed
is exactly where I feel the pain when
alone anxious and full of doubt.
The place that you grabbed that was the
place where I feel the pain,
you know?
And then at the end things did resolve
quite perfectly and beautifully and
people just chat it afterwards and went
back to their jobs.
In these cases,
I'm thinking a lot of these people were
cab drivers and doing pre low pay,
minimum paid,
we'll jobs,
but they had there a communal experience
and and I and a I transcendent
experience.
Certainly it was beyond the accepted
social norms of how are you,
what are you going to be doing next
Wednesday?
Did you see spurs the other night?
People were,
and I feel that if you exclude that
experience from your life,
if your life does not include that,
then what are you doing?
What are you doing?
Hmm.
I agree.
I think that without that kind of
experience,
we lead very impoverished lives.
Yes.
And that's why I think like you do that
spiritual practices and awareness of
that dimension is so important.
What should science,
how can science,
which you know no one disputes that
without science?
No technology without science,
no medicine.
All the things that you listed,
you know,
the experimental method.
Absolutely vital.
But is there a,
what do you,
what would your biggest hope be for
science?
I think first of all,
going beyond these narrow dogmas,
hold it back.
My book,
the Science Delusion in America is
called science set free and it's really
the idea is that if we escaped from this
dogmatic prison that it's in at the
moment,
it could become much more positive and
life.
And I think that if we switch from a
view of nature as being dad,
unanimous and mechanical to a view of
nature as a living cosmos that's
evolving with habits and that everything
in nature is being alive.
Gaia,
the earth,
the sun,
the solar system,
the galaxy,
plants and animals,
not machines,
but truly alive.
We'll find ourselves in the living
world,
which has a kind of purpose is not clear
what it is,
but it we'd feel much more connected if
we feed ourselves part of the living
world.
And then the kind of spiritual
principles that give rise to that world
or the creative forces that underlying
would become,
we'd feel they were more relevant and
closer to us and we'd see God in nature
and God in us.
And,
um,
uh,
and I think then when that happens,
our lives become much more connected,
much more meaningful and much happier
too.
Yes,
that's very,
very beautiful.
And I can't see why that would be
controversial at all to regard the world
in those terms.
Rupert sheldrake your book,
I'm telling you this,
but really,
you know it,
your book,
just going to let you know in your book,
science and spiritual practices is
available now.
I,
uh,
I thank you very much.
I really enjoyed talking to you.
I really enjoy listening to you.
I find it incredibly valuable and
beautiful and to invest the world around
us with love and not to feel that we are
just components in a,
uh,
a mindless and purpose less machine for
me.
This is not just,
Oh,
this cheers me up on,
you know,
on my road to the bone yard.
No,
it also just feels like it has truth.
When I think of nature,
when I think of my experience with
psychedelics,
it seems to confirm that there are
forces beyond that which can be
understood through the limited senses,
that there is information available that
can't be understood within the existing
template.
It seems to be bloody obvious as a
matter of fact,
and that nature does seem like an uh,
uh,
um,
in motion,
a living beautiful thing rather than a
mechanical resource.
But if you start looking at nature as
something other than a resource,
a lot of economic interests and
political interests would be strongly
challenged.
Yes.
Anywhere.
It's a great pleasure to don't try and
wrap it up.
I'm the host of the thing.
Well,
all right,
but I think you're getting signals.
You're meant to be wrapping it up.
Refresh your drink.
I want to go bloody Cathedra with yeah,
it would take us in all about one.
Yeah,
I word yes.
I'd love to go with you.
We'd go to a cathedral would walk
through a field and like weird.
Let me just have a cream tea and then
we'd go work aphasia.
Which ones?
The best ones?
Dharam cancer.
Well we could start with Westminster
Abbey,
which is quite spectacular and amazing.
Really?
Yeah.
And they do choral even song practically
every day.
Even song.
You mentioned it all the time.
You're not the best.
It's the best way.
And I mean I've,
you've done done this empirically know
what works for people.
Um,
if people are committed Christians,
holy communion is the best way.
And,
but if people are not used to that,
then choral even song is something that
can include everybody.
And um,
it's extremely beautiful and it lasts 45
minutes and it happens every day.
In all know cathedrals.
What's,
there's a website that I helped set up
called choral even song.org
where you can find out when the next one
is,
what they're singing and what kind of
choir too.
I'm gonna investigate what it was like
for those people.
We've ropes and policing.
Awesome.
Current building them cathedral up.
It was the right bull lake erecting
them.
Dragging great stones around norritch.
Exactly,
but what they did is endured to this
day.
Whereas what people do by buying things
and throw away culture,
lenny juror in rubbish.
Heaps for the for centuries to come.
Thank you.
More cathedral fueled s iphone though.
You're probably not listening to this on
the Cathedral.
Thanks very much rupert sheldrake.
Thank you.
Thanks gs.
That show was sponsored by recovery,
which you can buy now on Amazon or you
can get it as an audio book or you can
buy it on your device and you could see
me read most of it basically on my
facebook feed them or I'd read it out.
Great Chunks of at can't shut up about
the damn thing.
Also come see me on my rebirth till we
had to reschedule some dates.
So I'm in Coventry,
eight for November.
Less stuff for eat for November.
Stoke for even.
November is a great show is live.
Fill in the survey.
You will have a wild,
wild time there.
I signed books in the interval.
I come right out.
I'm very,
very available.
Go to Russell brand.com
for your tickets.
Finally,
if you like this show,
please subscribe to it and review it and
get your friends listening to form
little groups where people gather and
perhaps build churches to it.
Why not?
Are you listening to this in the future
after I've passed on,
right?
Why not canonize me and make me a sane
in a proper all rise too much or just
give it five stars.
You don't have to start a religion.
I know how difficult that can be.
I'm trying to start me own one right
now.
It's knackering right island,
right then.