Gary Young is a British journalist,
author and broadcaster.
He is editor at large for the Guardian
and a monthly political columnist for
the nation.
He lived in the United States from 2003
to 2015 and his books include stranger
in a strange land encounters in the DC,
United States,
no place like home,
a black Britain's journey through the
American south and his most recent
another day in the death of America.
A harrowing account of children's lives
cut short by the ubiquity of gun
violence in the u s Gary,
thanks for coming.
Thanks.
You've been really keen to get you here
for a long time.
I particularly enjoy your journalism and
your commentary on the subject of
violence.
What are you,
I mean,
we know that you're here to talk about
another day in the death of America.
Where did you,
where the devices that just in one 24
hour period you,
I suppose elevate the depths that take
place on that day until their stories.
Did you really just choose the day at
random?
I did.
It was the first day I could do,
I've been in,
uh,
London promoting a previous book in
October.
And then I came back,
I had a seven month old babies.
How did a little bit of work to do to
get in the good graces of my family then
it was thanksgiving.
Um,
my family is American,
my wife is American and this was the
first Saturday after thanksgiving.
So it was the,
it was literally the first challenge.
I mean,
what's awful about,
um,
shapes his book is the reliability of
the statistic.
So every day in American seven kids on
average a shot dad.
And that statistic is sufficiently
reliable that so long as you're choosing
a weekend cause more do done at the
weekend or in a,
and what more do die the weekend even
more dire in the summer when kids around
and playing and all of that,
um,
that you could do any weekend.
It would,
it would work horrifically.
So you could in the most brutal
manifestation of it,
you can sit down and wait for the kids
to die.
They will donate.
It's reliable.
It's a perfectly reliable statistics.
I haven't seen the stance,
but I can almost guarantee you that last
weekend on average,
seven kids would have at least seven
kids would've died on Saturday and
Sunday and next weekend will be the
same.
Why is he in particular about these
deaths that goals you?
Why are you fascinated by this?
It's more that they all go me and that,
um,
if America pays attention when it's a
mass shooting or some kind of spectacle,
not every time,
but most of the time,
but on a daily basis,
these deaths are just like the white
noise around you that everybody gets on
with.
And you do almost in year two,
it,
you know,
you're watching the TV and it's,
um,
after this,
well before the sport,
you know,
and on 68th and Harrison,
a 17 year old boy was shot dead last
night when Blah,
blah,
blah.
And then this is a show of his mum
crying,
saying [inaudible].
And um,
after a while that just becomes the way
things are.
And um,
I do think in this center helping
British and thinking,
well,
it doesn't have to be like that
actually.
And so what I wanted to do with this
random day was pick,
let the day pick the kids.
And then you know,
there are,
if you pick a different day,
you get a different book.
Um,
there are,
uh,
every,
twice a week a toddler either killed
themselves or kill someone.
Um,
you know,
there are,
there would be other days it would be
more compelling.
Maybe the order would produce more
compelling stories.
But the point is this was like the day
choose the kids and then I will follow
them up and find out who they were
because they just statistics methodology
has the,
because it is random,
it gives you access to the horror of the
randomness because it wasn't selected on
the basis of it being,
as you say,
a compelling story.
It's just like you could spin a roulette
wheel and that will land on a tie where
there's devastation and unnecessary
death.
That's right.
And,
and many of them are compelling Ansley
all of them are compelling in their own
way.
But what was important to me was not to
kind of game it in order to try and draw
out some,
you know,
to draw out a specific emotional
response.
So I was also very determined and went
back with some foods with my editor
about it.
Um,
um,
that the,
the order of the death should come in
the order that they were shot.
Not like Hilda Story.
Yeah.
Not the best one here.
And so the first child to be shown,
he's in in some ways the most terrific
and there is a problem there for,
for a book,
which is that you pick up the stories
about,
you pick up this book.
The first child is the youngest child is
nine years old.
He answers the door and his mom's ex
lover shoots him in the head and then
runs off and he's,
you know,
ends up getting shot by the cops
himself.
And it's really the story of this kind
of mums,
unrelenting grief and her struggle to
kind of get back to some kind of normal
life.
And ordinarily you wouldn't w you know,
people of,
you know,
I read the first chapter and,
and I had to put it down for a week,
you know,
um,
but I thought it was important.
Um,
if,
if that's the order in which they came,
then that's the order in which,
you know,
they should be written if I was gaming
it out or put something a bit easier
first.
Hmm.
Okay.
So obviously what you're saying is true
is important to you and a kind of
practical truth as I posted the
different kinds of truths that emerge in
these times that are to do with,
you know,
deliberate construction of stories to
engender a feeling that some people
would argue even from an artistic
perspective,
you know,
not necessarily a journalistic
perspective.
I'll know,
but,
uh,
it will be more true,
Gary,
if the,
if it ends in this climactic moment,
more people,
you know,
they've got the kind of way that we were
asked as creative people to,
uh,
compromise is usually a or regional
people.
It'll be easier,
isn't it?
Ultimately you want more people that
read the book.
So why did you have a kind of a,
an almost puritanical determination to
commit to truth?
And it is,
there is something a bit Brechtian in
about it in that sense of just kind of,
you know,
just here is I guess what I felt was
how's that Brecht interests as well in
terms of kind of,
um,
uh,
not going to try and manipulate your own
motions here.
Uh,
although I mean the subject matter is
emotional enough.
I want to engage your critically and one
way.
I'm not saying that this is what I say.
I have to do that I made a pitch for
Brett in book about China.
So I didn't build the way that you
described it.
I thought that sounded a bit like that I
met kind of,
um,
uh,
on the one hand the stories are so
horrific and I feel compelling in their
own rights that,
um,
that I'll need to be gamed.
But that also there is some power in
saying this was the day,
this was how the day progressed.
This is,
this is what happened.
And I mean,
it's still my book.
So there's still things I left out and
things I put in.
It's not like I didn't edit and it's
also not like I didn't desire response
from people,
but that,
um,
to the extent that the premise starts
with something random,
I wanted to keep to keep honest to that
as much as I,
uh,
as much as I possibly can.
I can see why you would,
it's a very,
very confronting idea just to say this
day happened and this is how the day
unfolded in the react.
This is the reality of that day.
So if you feel like that was a brew or
an unbearable,
well that's simply the consequences of
looking at reality,
not the artistry of a creative person
with get you over interesting
position to analyze what's happening in
America with violence more broadly.
I read something that you wrote a couple
of days ago about what trump means in
terms of hatred.
Um,
man,
submerged ideas becoming explicit.
Do you,
is there a relationship between the
ideas you're exploring in this
particular book?
Are there,
are we seeing something that's important
and unique now?
Eh,
do you think in America?
I think we are.
I think that,
um,
it's important to recognize that trump
didn't invent racism or bigotry,
you know,
he's button,
there's never been someone at such a
high level who's prepared to be so
brazen about their bigotry.
And that is new to have that lead from
the front.
You know,
you can have George Wallace in Alabama,
a segregationist running for president,
but nobody thought he was going to whip
me.
It was a protest candidate.
And instead you have trump going to
Alabama,
which only removed at state ban on mixed
most managers in two thousand two
thousand.
I mean,
this is,
you know,
you're talking some serious kind of
Taliban Nael,
right?
Yeah.
You're doing them going all right.
And um,
s um,
trashing these black athletes who,
um,
are making a protest about black lives
matter now just they fill in the
listeners.
That's the,
this is the protest were nfl players are
kneeling during the national anthem
because they're saying this,
this anthem don't include me.
Is that the idea that this anthem,
until he's handsome,
represents the ideals of the country,
are not going to stand up for him.
And,
um,
and I guess relating that to the themes
in the book,
I mean most interesting in the book is
none of the kids,
all of the shootings that we know of
same race,
which is usually in America,
America is segregated to death.
So white people kill white people.
Black people kill black people.
That's why the,
the,
the term black on black violence doesn't
mean anything cause it's just violence
as how American violence works.
And um,
um,
and none of them are killed by cops.
But the date,
the November the 23rd 2013 comes in
between,
uh,
when George Zimmerman is acquitted for
shooting Trayvon Martin Dead in Florida,
which was when the black lives matter
Hashtag was coined and Ferguson,
which is when it really took off.
When Michael Brown is showing back up in
broad daylight and this and some Louis.
So it comes in between those and it
doesn't come.
None of the death conform to that kind
of,
uh,
that morality play of white cop,
black kid.
Um,
but there are two ways in which it
relates to the broader theme in the
first is the way that the police treat
these deaths for the most part,
which is well,
you know,
that's the kind of thing that you know,
happens down there.
So they don't,
very few of the deaths are um,
solved.
You know,
very few of the murders are solved and
most of the parents think that becomes
on even trying.
And then the other thing is the way that
they're treated by the press,
which is,
that's not news really.
If a kid gets killed down there,
that's where kids get killed.
You know.
So I didn't actually do this in the
book,
but develop this kind of notion
subsequently that when I went to
journalism school,
there was,
you know,
there's this thing when,
uh,
when dope by some man.
And that's not a story when a man bites
dog,
that's the story.
But sometimes you have to ask yourself,
why do these dogs keep buying people?
And why the same people keep getting
bitten and who controls these dogs.
Sometimes the fact that someone keeps
happening in a place is a reason to
investigate it and no reason to ignore
it.
That's very interesting isn't it?
Because I suppose that the normalization
is an important part of the
intoxication.
That this is normal.
Do not question it.
Leave it alone.
Even that well known journalistic trope
isn't it?
I suppose a way of establishing what
normal is.
We surprised at what is acceptable.
I learned because I,
I'm a part of it is that these podcasts
of cancer to university now and I wanted
to learn more and uh,
I learned this thing about net crow
politics,
like who it's okay to kill can and I
suppose in the normalization of the
deaths of these children in these
particular regions,
what you're saying is what the more that
in the state in that it doesn't matter.
You are indicating that this is,
you're continually broadcasting.
It doesn't matter that they're dying.
It doesn't matter.
They're dying.
Exactly.
The black lives
don't matter.
And there are these assignments and
these assumptions come,
uh,
come out.
So one boy in Dallas,
he's,
um,
he gets just 80 words in the Dallas
Morning News,
um,
saying that he was shot dead while he
was walking with his friend.
And then the first comment after this 80
words is this a woman saying,
well,
I don't want to blame the victim.
And then of course,
that's what exactly what she'd done.
Right.
Um,
but you know,
where were the parents?
You know,
I wouldn't let my kid out at 1130 at
night.
This is,
you know,
um,
uh,
parents have taught us some sales,
more questions and that the first thing
that raises is what time should have
kicked me out and not get shot.
You know,
when's curfew for kind of child,
you know,
don't shoot after time.
Children can be shot exactly.
Side when they say he was a,
he was an a student and it's like,
well,
what grade you have to get b plus,
you know,
fortunately that a child wasn't doing
that well academically,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
If only you just pulled his,
you know,
just,
just trying to bet barry Algebra,
maybe he'd still be alone.
It's a big,
big rights.
But then sneaking me,
this woman knows nothing about his
family,
this family,
cause it's not like they were
interviewed.
You want to go 80 words and you find out
that his mom knew exactly where he was.
And that night it had been with his
friend who was over because he was going
with his grounding to church the next
day.
No word of a lie.
And this is why it's useful to have
these other things where you're saying,
I'm not saying yeah,
because it just sounds so idealic.
They drank cocoa,
they watched,
we're the millers and they played two.
Now,
the worst thing that Samuel Brightman
did,
he's the kid who was shot that night was
cheat at now.
And he was a very,
very persistent cheetah who know by all
accounts.
Then he decided to walk his friend,
the six minutes bank to his granny's
house.
And during that six minutes he was shot
dead.
Nobody knows why Samuel that only moved
that quite recently.
Some you didn't hurt anyone.
He's quite a sweet,
quite fragile kid actually.
Uh,
by every accountable,
the people that knew him.
And there's lots of kids in the book
where nobody says that about them.
Um,
and um,
uh,
and then you got this woman saying,
well,
you know,
I blame the parents and you went,
well,
no,
you know,
you don't know the parents.
But there is an assumption if you're
black and working costs and you live in
some of these areas that it's not just
like,
well,
we don't know anyone like that.
It's that they're kind of almost a
different species where the parents
don't love their kids and the kids
doesn't love life and the pennants and
negligent and the kids are feral.
I understand.
It's like it becomes permissible and
inevitable.
So I learned a few things they had like
the black lives matters is a necessary
response to the assumption black lives
don't matter.
The unstated blank lives don't ma'am.
I see also that your commitment to truth
is a requirement because what we're
dealing with is the management of
narrative in order to facilitate a
particular response.
That in a sense that the first comment
after the iee word a eulogy was,
uh,
like that's almost like a reflex that
that person had.
Well,
what do you say when a black person is
killed in that era?
Oh,
right,
well where were the parents and it's
been late at night,
you know,
I mean,
we couldn't have a result of
conditioning.
I was in America when a trayvon Martin
was murdered and I like this.
Even the sort of grammar of news is
obvious gone an intensity to it.
There's sort of,
you see the police cars you've seen over
at helicopter shot of a law and it also
seems a bit like it's all merging into
crime and gang.
Even if those words aren't explicitly
being said,
because those tracks exist in my mind
already.
So all we need to do is far a few little
triggers and I'll go,
yeah,
probably that kid was sort of a criminal
or some value,
you know,
like it's,
it takes effort to unpick my
conditioning is a why English person in
America having already been
indoctrinated before my arrival.
Yeah,
I mean it,
it takes everybody method.
Actually even the email,
um,
uh,
I mean different efforts with different
kinds of people,
but the condition and the dominance,
that kind of hedge many of that
narrative is so strong that the parents
of the kids who die will say to you,
he hadn't been in trouble with the
police.
He didn't do drugs.
And what they're doing is listing the
reasons why he shouldn't have died.
A high end listing.
The reasons why they charge shouldn't
have died every single,
so there were 10 kids got shot dead that
during that 24 hour period and they
weren't all black,
seven were black to Latino,
one wine,
every single blank parent.
When you ask them,
did you think this would happen?
Did you had,
you know,
was this on your radar to a person?
They all said,
oh,
oh yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
Samuel's mom and Samuel,
you know,
he didn't get in trouble in school or
anything and his mom said,
well,
I didn't think it'd be a,
my thought would be his brother.
Yeah,
the data new Eric just said,
did not doing your job properly.
If you don't think that your kid could
be short in this city,
just email you.
So there is this kind of,
what did you call it?
Macro,
macro politics.
Politics is kind of,
it's not just for the dominant forces
in,
in terms of who should be show a kind of
encompasses all of us are thinking,
well I have two American kids and we
were living in America when I was
writing his book.
Um,
that's when you realize,
yeah,
that's the,
that's the fear I have for my child.
I'm walking around with that too.
Um,
there was a weird thing in the reporting
of it cause people went on about
parenting.
So manage,
so I saw it looking to see if there's
any documentation about parenting and
race.
And I found out that,
uh,
this was a government study,
that black dance,
well,
first of all,
more likely to be single dads and any
other race,
but secondly,
we're more likely to buy.
They've read to help their children with
homework,
uh,
have breakfast with them.
A whole range of things that black dads,
while they were least happy to live with
the mother,
they were the most likely to do all
these things with their kids.
And I just thought,
well,
that can't be true you.
So then I'm looking at a range of black
that,
well now this is when I'm looking
through,
you know,
um,
trying to find someone who's written
something to amend.
I think,
well,
what the hell are you doing your black
that you do all those things and somehow
you kind of,
you know,
the,
the idea is so dominant that you just
said,
well,
you know,
obviously no,
but it was,
it's more powerful than our own mind.
Like the Groucho Marx quote,
who are you going to believe me or your
own eyes?
And that voice becomes so dominant in
your consciousness,
they use zips reality.
Oh,
that's what I say.
Now I see the importance of the device,
that truth,
like if the commitment of the simple
truth expose these narratives,
uh,
so a visceral Starlin,
an erv ethic,
it reawakens asked from the
normalization of the death of children.
So in your book,
it's like older than a minute.
Children die in isn't a thing that you
just isn't,
it's not an Aae word,
a bitchery and then just roll your eyes
and say,
it must be parental responsibility.
Now I can sort of see again,
the idea of parental responsibility and
incorporation of crime and stuff into
those stories is a way of enhancing both
the idea that these somehow culpability
of the victim,
your responsible and that has,
that that plays a big role in American
culture in that it's part of the
general,
this is an individualized culture.
If there's some terrible bad thing
happening to you,
it's not because you're this color or
from this economic class in trial.
Yeah.
He should have tried to be artist to not
get shot and like,
you know,
so like in this all to be it a different
hue.
So,
um,
it's based,
that's an actually,
that's a sort of a vital fred in perhaps
it's the defining fred of,
uh,
the,
American ideology is individualism and
personal culpability versus any kind of
connected collective or national
responsibility.
That's something that's continually
being eroded.
How this gun culture participate in
this?
Why is it like,
given that you're a person who tells
stories in the way that you do what you
like,
it's not an like we saw other people
just like guns.
Why is this idea so a irresistible to
American people?
Why,
why isn't it like that?
You know,
like you see sort of like a Bama speech
after sandy hook or wherever and he's
like,
oh right,
that's the day now where we don't have
guns anymore.
It's just like,
no.
Why,
why is this fall so powerful?
What does it mean to their unconscious?
Which is which?
It's an excellent question.
And,
um,
I guess one of the best ways to explain
it would be,
and you touched on it there in terms of
tapping into some core things about how
America feels about itself.
They've got nothing to do with guns but
work quite well with guns.
So,
um,
when I used to go to the NRA,
I went through a couple of NRA
convention,
the National Rifle Association,
which is the gun lobby.
Um,
what's the vibe?
Like?
Weird,
weird and kind of,
um,
it's a lot of white guys.
That's the kind of 90% of the
demographic,
probably more,
although they're trying to push gums in
more in women's direction,
said lots of now pink guns and Nice
things that you can carry your gun in
and kind of ways to look pretty with
your gun and stuff like that.
But,
um,
lots of white guys and I almost kind of
almost sexual relationship to these,
to these weapons.
You know,
they kind of the stroking them and they
kind of,
you know,
the,
that pouring them basically.
And I would really play up my
englishness in these things.
I mean,
first of all,
cause it,
you know,
it helps and second because it mitigates
the blackness,
but we throw me now and I'm down to my
becoming out of your mouth from Steven
is really,
and I've got puff Daddy,
I'm looking at Puff Daddy,
but I'm hearing them.
If I could explain stevenage to then
that would,
so everything else,
everybody,
Steven,
you can continue with your prejudices in
Essex to Steven Itching.
Um,
and I signed that.
Understand this,
I don't understand this.
Explain it to me.
And to a person,
they were off to the races.
They'll say,
are you married?
Do you have children?
Imagine someone broke into your house
and they wanted to rape your wife and
kill your children and take everything
that you worked for what you're going to
do.
Uh,
you can,
uh,
wave a stick sticker them,
you're going to call the cops and wait
for the cops to come or you're going to
defend your family and defend what
you've learned.
And so it speaks to kind of masculinity,
homestead,
um,
a small government individualism,
a notion of kind of my being right
defend what's yours.
Now the reality is,
well,
there are several kinds of facts that
contradict that.
Firstly,
most people who are shot dead killed
themselves.
Secondly,
you must often that you're much more
likely to be sheltered by someone you
know,
did someone you'd done so well I should
say is,
are you married?
Yes.
Well,
watch out for your wife.
And so,
um,
they are,
survey evoke these very primal yes,
things in the culture and when
confronted with that,
if you start talking about background
checks and um,
you know,
bamming semiautomatic weapons and stuff
like that,
he's not really a match for these basic
ideas of American individualism,
small government masculinity and so on.
You're talking about tinkering.
We think so they have a powerful
narrative that they can tap into and the
gun control people done.
It's brilliant isn't it?
Because it doesn't seem like it should
be important enough.
A national rifle association and he's
like,
you imagined the English version and I
have just been a bunch of cases in
Berber jackets hanging around in the
shyest that wouldn't be,
you wouldn't think affecting policy of
that.
I'm sure we have our own sort of
uniquely bizarre equivalent within some
of our,
more to temik issue in our own culture.
But what I was struck by Gary there was
like it shows you the limits of the
rational mind,
which is curious when we live in what is
a pointedly a rationalistic of
materialist culture that's based
primarily it's least explicitly on
economics that people's drives are not
being sourced from rationale.
Cause if you hit them with none,
I know you're most likely first to kill
yourself or be killed by someone that
you know.
So the best thing you can do if that is
your fear,
if fear is your motivator,
he's do not have a gun.
It doesn't just stay in.
Yes they endorsed that go out.
But that is the ultimate solution.
Just atrophy in a cupboard had the
brilliant the solution wasting away in a
market space.
So like it just shows you the truth
again is irrelevant.
It's irrelevant because they must know
that they must know they must have been
hit with those stats.
Do you think?
Well they have
and what what they do is they deflect
them to other things.
So you're talking about the hood,
Adam [inaudible].
That's where these things happen,
you know.
So if you say to them,
which is true,
you're much more likely to be shot.
People who have guns in the house,
I'm much more,
I used to be shot than they basically
deflect that too.
Now you're talking about black people
really.
So when I was promoting my book in
America on the radio,
uh,
it was a Conan Chow and one guy said,
um,
if you just took out a few cities in
America,
then that whole average would be kind of
way lower.
And I'm saying,
well yeah,
but if you took half few seasoned in,
wouldn't be America would do.
I mean America is a hot wallet take out
Chicago,
New York,
La,
Detroit,
where you can get cars from where you're
going to get your blues from,
where you know,
wait,
he believes from,
so that's again,
it's in its coded like that this is a
get even mentally,
there is ghettoization happening.
Why that statistics and nation is
regarded incorporates a [inaudible] oh
this is terrible statistic.
But fortunately as white people that
live in a suburban area,
it's irrelevant.
And that cause I,
that's facilitated by an individualistic
idea,
isn't it?
Or an individualistic perspective of,
of,
uh,
of yourself and your country,
I suppose,
of their country.
So like this,
um,
oh,
your kids are American.
So listen though,
uh,
the other thing you mentioned,
this is like everything in that national
rifle connect a convention seemed like
it was primal,
you know,
their sexual connection,
the idea of power,
the idea of fear.
So when we're talking about guns,
we're not really talking about guns,
we're talking about power and fear,
sexual energies,
Leighton impotence,
sense of social breakdown,
rampant individualism.
Uh,
so it's a very,
very difficult thing to unravel because
you,
it's very hard for people to get,
like I wonder what would literally app
like why is it that it's no president
can countenance or no government can
count and it's,
listen,
we're just doing this thing cause it's
playing with the right thing to do.
Consequences.
Yeah.
There's probably,
there's a fatalism about it.
So when I asked every family that I
spoke to,
so what do you think is going on here?
When I ask them open ended question,
none of them mentioned guns.
Wow.
Because I figure in the book it's like
if your kid got run over,
you wouldn't say,
well traffic,
we'd have to get rid of traffic cause
you can't imagine a world without
traffic.
Um,
so,
um,
you know,
imagining the world without God thing I
mentioned poverty that I mentioned
racism because it's like,
well that's everywhere.
So kind of Ha you know,
so I'm going to go with now parents or
that Kid's dad or this is a rough
neighborhood.
But no,
the kind of
uh,
bigger thing.
It's brilliant.
I also think that kind of,
um,
uh,
guns a big business and so there is,
that's what
they have to be bigger than that
wouldn't it?
Cause like they're statistically give
financially is not enough to have that
kind of potency.
It must be serving something very,
very powerful.
And I think that what you said there
about the people can't imagine it,
we just can't,
that's been taken off the table.
The idea that we could moderate Shafiq
the idea that we could moderate guns,
all of these ideas are excluded and we
accept that this is a,
this is reality.
And I think probably all of us are on
that scale somewhere with what we can
conceive of and how radical a change
we're willing to countenance how
beautiful the world we're prepared to
imagine.
None of us are willing to start.
Like so like what kind of conclusions
does this lead you to in terms of power
structures and the way that power
operates,
if you sort of,
if it seems literally unimaginable to
know Afghans?
Well,
the,
I miss as you suggest,
this can work for almost anything in any
country that if you are able to kind of
swamp the field in a way,
if you are able to kind of,
okay,
if you were able to remove something
from public discussion and remove it
from public countenance,
then um,
uh,
then there's no reason why I shouldn't
go on forever.
So I kind of,
different example would be nuclear
weapons are used to be quite involved
with cmd.
I used to be on the National Council of
CMV and I went away for kind of 12
years,
15 years to,
uh,
to the states.
And when I came back and Coban and one
of them he talked about getting rid of
tried and I kind of thought have you
still got tried and true domain is that
people to stop talking about it?
It stopped being,
you can just tell him it stopped being a
thing.
And you know,
I thought,
God,
how weird.
I felt we were supposed to be afraid of
the like young men from the North West
with backpacks.
That's right.
And we've got this kind of lumbering
kind of weird who's,
who are we supposed to be firing that?
Yeah.
But kind of it had been removed from
discuss.
I'd just kind of stop thinking.
And you were a president was ncn be
obviously a breast of these ideas.
So that's very interesting.
It's always a code to be,
we you're talking to their mate was that
we operate in,
in a time where the powerful,
now I have a master data and the
historical knowledge of how public
consciousness and the public sphere
works.
So they almost know you only got to
manage this for a little bit of time and
we're all going to be cool.
And I think an obvious and pertinent
recent example is grand felt and the
management of the deaths around the toes
just keep,
just keep distracting,
don't talk about,
don't clarify any information.
It will dissipate as surely we'll know
like one of those totemic events that
scars are national consciousness because
it's almost too perfect.
This sometimes happens.
I notice in current affairs were
symbolically many,
many Fred's come together and there's an
indelible connection to truth.
You can't,
you go,
oh no,
this must be because we've long regarded
poor people as dispensable and we've
been making terrible financial decisions
and we'd be ignoring it and all of our
social infrastructures,
a paper tigers and there's nothing set
up to protect people and we actually
don't care.
So now we're going to have to stare it
in the face.
Even in that,
when that kind of emblematic event
occurs,
there's a sort of sense that just ride
this out,
they'll stop caring.
Other stuff will happen in a while.
This will seem like an obsolete concern,
like trident replaced with a newer,
more novel kind of fear.
Yeah,
I met,
I mean your point about Grunfeld cause
I,
I do remember thinking at the time,
um,
cause it happened a week after the
election and we count the election and
that effectively what had happened June
now election was that Labor had
introduced a series of ideas that were
once considered mainstream.
And actually in most of Europe are
considered mainstream,
barely had been removed from the public
square.
We're going to tax rich people a bit
more.
Um,
uh,
we've done and not have tuition fees,
which when I started at university
didn't exist.
Um,
we are,
you know,
we're gonna,
we're gonna move to a reality that we
actually have within my,
you know,
living memory.
I'm 48,
so it's not like,
you know,
I'm loud.
And they,
um,
I'm,
I made called austerity,
what it was.
And so there was,
when grenfell happened,
I do think there was a price for people
to put it,
that we've just had this moment.
And then Graham felt happened and there
was a kind of like,
that's kind of something that we've been
talking about.
You don't have that.
It was that it was part of the
constellation that kind of brought those
threads together.
And I think,
and um,
uh,
and I saw it in on social media where
when things like this happen,
there's always a group of people kind of
who I'm sympathetic too who want to draw
the border conclusions and say,
you know,
look,
this is part of something bigger.
You know,
if it's nine 11 or whatever.
And then there's always a group of
people who seem to be more dominant and
in any case have the power of the media
behind them who say,
you're exploring this tragedy for play
command.
Stop talking,
stop talking about all the serious stuff
and respect for the victims.
And they tried that on social media and
we've grandfathered,
it didn't work.
People were like,
no,
this is exactly the time to talk about
this.
What else should we be talking about?
And I do feel that,
I'm not saying,
you know,
Jeremy Corbyn made that happen,
but that um,
coming out of this election there was a,
there was a price to go,
there was a language for it and people
were kind of achieved to me.
And um,
and it's one of those examples where
people,
you know,
people go,
well,
they'll neighbor didn't win,
you know,
and it's like,
well actually they won quite a lot of
arguments and they change the national
conversation and yes,
they are not the,
you know,
they have not formed a government,
but let's not pretend they didn't win
anything.
It didn't change anything.
A slight,
there's an identifiable disjunct because
the sort of proceeding media noise was
so much about condemnation and ridicule
that the fact that in the face of that
there was a positive reaction in a
positive result,
it starts to demonstrate this fissure
that exists between this is the reality
we are telling you and this is the
reality you are experiencing now.
The efficacy of media in dead Indian and
a mosque in our own reality.
Even as you said,
like,
yeah,
I was thinking like that.
Even me as a person that I like to
think,
oh,
I'm really up for change and sort of
radical ideas.
Like I feel like a giddy school girls,
they might get rid of this tuition fees
go bloody hell.
He's like,
you're right.
I mean like,
but in my lifetime,
that free education,
he's already that the way that it is
situated.
Now what this suggests to me,
mate,
and given that we sort of started off
talking about the way we tell stories
and you elected with your most book to
make a commitment to truth,
even if that costs you in a structural
sense,
like,
oh no,
the best terrible death occurs too
early,
or whatever it is.
You know?
So one thing I think that seems to be
occurring is the outcome.
Then what?
What are we doing?
If we've got true for on our side,
broadly speaking,
by which I mean,
you know,
collectivize breakdown.
Powerwall stopped telling me stories of
the individual stop ignoring how the
influence of the powerful ways,
having a devastating effect on ordinary
people's lives.
Stop separating from one another,
finding reasons to hate each other.
They are how,
why are we not able to tell these
stories in an effective way if we have
true for now side.
Why is this dominant story continuing
dominate?
Um,
I mean I think there are a few reasons.
There's probably millions,
but just,
I mean,
pardon me,
I fear sometimes we don't quite even
believe those stories are sales,
right?
That we want things to be true.
But,
um,
we,
we don't know where the album we quite
atomized.
So there are these moments when you
realize,
oh my God,
everybody else has been seeing at the
telly.
[inaudible] tell me who else,
six months as well.
I didn't realize.
So this is that moment jumie election
where it was one of the questions times
when a young woman says this discussion
about nuclear weapons and disarmament
and she says,
I'm just wondering why so many people
want to bomb everyone and there's a big
cheer in the audience.
Like,
yeah,
what,
what are we,
why are we having that conversation?
Who Do you want to Boehm.
And so there are,
we've,
we all feel like,
well,
maybe it's just me.
There's a lack of confidence.
I guess Dennis is also true.
I think that we are,
um,
uh,
for the most part,
not withstanding social media,
we don't run stuff,
you know,
we don't own a large media corporations
and things like that.
We are still kind of quite marginal in
terms of the means of distribution.
And then certainly in a country like
Britain or America,
you have the kind of weight of this kind
of awful history,
which to some extent,
um,
could damn the people within it.
So if you want to talk honestly,
say about British racism or about
Britain,
then you'll have to talk about empire
and slavery and murder and a range of
things that kind of people feel
implicated him.
If you say,
um,
you know,
people say,
well,
um,
people will say we want a wall,
or even though they didn't fight or we
won the World Cup,
even though they didn't play,
but they'll never say we own slaves
stole stuff that just not going to do
that.
They're not going to claim that.
And so having kind of honest
conversations about who we are and what
we've done,
um,
people kind of shy away from that.
So in more powerful countries,
people kind of,
um,
the more honest conversation and the
more truthful conversation is also kind
of a more difficult conversation,
put too much into our shadows.
We've allowed this to be a kind of a
repository of truth where we don't look
at,
oh no,
this is what Britain mean.
So be careful when you talk about
Britain,
this is what freedom,
this is what we have done,
this is what we missed out.
So true.
Like we've become,
and of course there are many,
many troops,
but there are so many unaddressed
aspects of our reality that I suppose
I'm a constructed reality is that we're
invited to participate in seem more
tactile,
more attractive because we're a sort of
an unwillingness for us to embrace our,
the,
the truth of who we are culturally own.
I would have to argue who we are
individually that there's been,
there's a reluctance like I,
so it was,
I think Gary,
like is it like,
you know,
like I hold these ideals,
but if say like in a perhaps because I
don't like it when people go me,
well,
why don't you give up all your money?
Then I always think that's like,
oh fuck off and leave me alone.
Stop cutting me out of the argument.
Right.
My Leica,
I do some I think would it like,
right,
okay,
what happens if I go,
these people are going to cut.
Anyone who needs a house is can come and
live in my house.
Now what's that gonna do to my
consciousness?
What is my resistance to that idea?
Easier?
A personal thing.
Now I know I've got limited power as an
individual,
but is my unwillingness to commit.
You say,
man,
willingness to look at what in my
shadow,
my own selfishness,
my own capitalism,
my own love of comfort,
my own love of prejudge village,
my own prejudice,
my own ways of garnering what I am and
who I feel about myself,
the participant.
Like,
I am a participant in this system in
these ways.
Yeah.
I'm also kind of,
that is a,
um,
in a way we kind of have to keep those
two things in our head at the same time.
Right?
So we are,
we are people,
we are flawed individuals and we live in
a capitalist society and we,
you know,
we want houses and we wants things that
are going at my,
my w,
you know,
we want things,
we want comfort.
And my personal feeling about all that
stuff is do what you have to do so long
as you don't screw anybody else over.
Um,
you know,
if you can point to a time or a place
where I've actually done something,
you know,
actually made somebody else poorer or
worse off than that's one thing.
But that,
um,
you giving away your money doesn't
change capitalism.
It just makes you poorer.
And,
um,
uh,
I'm interested in changing the system,
not in,
you know,
seeing you in,
um,
uh,
seeing you in,
in poverty,
but also just kind of linking where we
are as individuals to kind of more
collective things.
And this comes back to the gun thing
actually and and children in particular
that we talk about personal
responsibility a lot with guns,
but there is also with children,
particularly a collective
responsibility.
That's why we have sexual services,
child protection services,
child courts,
all that kind of thing.
There was an awareness that they're not
fully responsible and so there is this
general way of understanding things.
I think that like I am not a state,
I am not a society.
I'm an individual.
So when people say,
well say someone did that to your kid,
wouldn't you want to just go out and
murder them?
So yeah,
I would.
That's why I'm glad there's a code
because I know want to be responsible
for kind of,
you know,
how we respond to these things
personally that I would,
I would rather,
there was some independent reasons why
of doing these things and I guess,
yeah,
we all have certain privileges.
We live in the west,
we all have certain privileges,
so we have to be aware of them,
but we can't let us have them disable
us.
What can we learn from the particular
distinctions between these two,
the studies of violence that you've
undertaken in the United States and
England?
What are the differences say about those
countries do you think?
Well,
um,
so I've been doing a series this year on
knife crime in Britain,
could be on the blind,
um,
looking at tracking over deaths of kids
19 and under,
um,
from um,
from stabbings and um,
which kind of mirrors in a way what,
what was happening in the states.
Uh,
I think the broad,
the broad lesson that you,
one can learn from path of those things
is that,
is that there are reasons why this
happens that are not,
people kind of feel like this falls out
of the blue sky or dark sky,
that kind of,
it's evil.
It's,
you know,
bad people is,
and it's really,
you know,
in America if you take segregation,
poverty,
racism,
kind of underinvestment in,
in communities,
and then you put on the top of that big
pile of tinder I violent weapon that can
kill people really easily.
What do you think's going to happen in
Britain?
Um,
if you cut child and adolescent mental
health services,
youth services,
um,
slash c,
you know,
social services through kind of a local
councils,
um,
then what do you think is going to
happen?
Something's going to give,
but of course it's going to be the
poorest people.
It we're to suffer.
So there are a nobody,
I I s the last piece I did for the,
um,
beyond the blight series was an
interview with the mother of a child who
had killed someone who'd been sentenced
and she had written to her mp saying,
please save my child.
She had taken parenting courses.
She had told a local social services,
either my child's going to be killed,
all this going to be a body bag.
She had asked them to move her because
their child was struggling.
She had tried all of this stuff and what
she said was,
did my child did the local authority,
a knife in my child's hand.
Now he's responsible for what he did.
They don't try everything I could.
Yes.
And where we found yes.
And it's possible to keep all of those
things in your head at one time that
everybody has to take responsibility for
what they do.
And that includes us collectively as a
society.
I understand we've been overly biasing
towards narratives that are about
individualism.
And the reason I think we're so
susceptible to that idea is because we
live in our own heads,
we are individuals.
So that seems where people go,
you know,
oh well he did each and at that made you
think,
Oh yeah,
oh I'm me and I didn't do it.
There's immediately a sort of a fertile
ground for that to flourish in and
they're almost,
it requires of us a little more work to
see us,
the invisible Fred's between us,
the collective connections that our
culture is made up of.
And if that story is not articulated and
beautifully told,
we forget it.
Cause it's almost like I feel like I've
return like [inaudible] to the my self
as an individually driven on my own.
Those kinds of psychological memes,
like they're,
they're effective in my own Ed.
So it,
it takes an effort to feel like I'm
connected,
I'm part of this and we are all one.
It's a difficult story.
So it's in a way we live in a culture
that tells us the stories about
ourselves that are the worst stories and
neglects to tell us the positive
stories.
And it seems like,
I mean,
Gosh,
economics is one level of it,
but I,
you know,
sometimes I wonder if there is more than
just entropy or uh,
you know,
like inertia at work behind it because
it seems like such malice.
It seems like it can this be as simple
as the attainment of profit behind all
of this suffering behind all of this
pain is just people going,
no,
no.
It's better off to sell stuff if people
think they're individuals and that
they've got buy things to feel better
and if their lives about it's their
fault that go after we will use.
It's,
um,
it's,
it's more about neglect.
It's more about these going back to the
black marks mammoth thing,
these people don't matter what happens
to these people,
it doesn't matter.
Um,
uh,
and if we can convince ourselves that
these people don't matter and what
Hamson doesn't matter,
then all sorts of things come into play.
And so what this,
what we've been trying to do beyond the
blade and why I was so keen to interview
them,
the mother of the boy who killed was to
make the point that in order to solve
these things,
we have to humanize everybody.
We actually,
we have to,
it's not a killer.
It's a child who killed,
is a child who did something monstrous.
He's not a monster.
That people are more than their crimes.
That in a world where some of these
people,
anybody in ms story isn't human.
All sorts of things are possible to
neglect,
to forget to dismiss.
And so we have to start off from the
basis that even the people who are doing
things that we hate Nancy's,
we're humans.
And that actually is the problem.
What are they not human?
We could plug that somewhere else that,
that period and all of the other
periods,
it was similar.
It was Armenian genocide.
It doesn't matter.
They were committed by human beings.
That's what scary about it.
Once we start pretending that they're
not human beings,
then we found a way to kind of um,
uh,
park this stuff somewhere else.
So people do,
people can do very bad things.
They can also do brilliant,
wonderful,
beautiful things.
And um,
um,
either way and,
and,
and then comes the problem of saying,
well,
Nelson Mandela,
he was a saint or saying that people are
doing wonderful things and sanely now
the still they're people,
they're people.
And that is a very inspiring notion
because it means it could be you,
it could be you doing that.
Yes,
yes.
I see the necessity of it.
And I see now I understand your
commitment to truth because you're
within truth.
There is complexity.
And in the complexity though,
there is a revelation if you sort of
finish off,
uh,
if you allow the threat to finish where
the conventional narrative ends,
then you are didn't your denying
yourself truth.
Just beyond that is where the
explanation is.
If you allow the story of it was this
time of night in this community with
this,
within this demographic,
then you are not participate in,
in real truth there.
I understood,
I understand the importance and
significance of that.
I also recognize how important it is too
broad to firstly,
I dunno,
identify different stories.
Uh,
I think,
uh,
another relatively recent,
an interesting example where that was
it,
when was that?
There was sort of the riots around that
police custody,
murder sort of around north London.
Oh yeah.
That old though.
The peculiar way they sort of bloomed
like some sort of continuum of
consciousness was of regionally
awakening what they do.
What did you think about that,
those disturbances?
Well then no,
far from,
uh,
where I live and um,
you know,
I s I thought,
well,
yes,
you know,
a young person has been killed and uh,
what kind of world would it be where
people were angry about that?
And you can try and manage the anger,
but the real way to kind of,
I mean,
there are two things that you have to do
to actually confronted.
The first is tell the truth about how
that happened to make sure somebody is
accountable.
And then the second is make sure it
never happens again.
And anything short of that,
well one dissipate their anger,
but people have a right to be angry.
Not least when people,
you know,
there is this sense whether it's
[inaudible] or or something like this,
it's like,
well that's not a way to kind of,
you know,
saw that out,
writes a letter to your mp or what,
when people feel that system has failed
them and that it didn't just fail them
like our now you know,
it's going to be another week before you
know,
my,
my toilet's fixed.
If found them in a way that meant
somebody died,
that it was existential,
somebody died or in case of grant from
loss of people dying,
then anger is a very least you can
expense.
And um,
um,
there is some sense for those people who
could never imagine that this could be
them,
that there is some sense of decorum
missing some sense of propriety.
And you know,
I'm always struck by remembering Michael
Heseltine's pamphlet.
I know you didn't see that coming.
Did Michael Heseltine's report after the
IC one riots were,
which was entitled?
It took her a riot and he's making the
point.
Yeah,
I know.
Weird that like what else would you have
listened to?
These people have been saying all sorts
of things for all this amount of time
and nothing's happened.
So what if not days,
I don't think this was entirely his
argument,
but it took this for you to pay
attention and um,
um,
as society as to ask yourself when these
things blow up.
And I said,
well you know,
we have to kind of get back to normal.
We have to get beano Cole Cole's for
calm cause it was cold for calm and it's
like how come can you be when people are
being shot dead in the street?
How come can you be when people are
being made about the state?
What kind of piece existed before these
rise?
I'm sure you've felt very peaceful,
but I don't feel peaceful if I think
that my child to be one of those.
And there is coming back to the book.
There is this sense from that,
that letter,
the woman who kind of wrote,
you know,
to send me Brian died.
This could not be my child.
This could not be me.
I cannot imagine I single way in a world
in which this could be me.
So this is happening to a different
species.
This is like in James Baldwins phrase
about or at least analysis of the
creation of taxonomies,
the necessary other that if you can have
a demonstrable you different and uh,
hopefully visually different other then
there's a sense that,
oh,
I'm not culpable,
but like it doesn't require such vivid
demonstration.
Like I know the way that I think of
people that are a rough sleepers as,
oh,
that's not me.
And I was like,
that couldn't be me.
Oh.
Like I said,
once you recognize that these
distinctions are merely superficial
stories,
veneers over the truth,
suddenly we are all vulnerable.
Suddenly it's all of our children.
Suddenly we're all at risk.
Suddenly change becomes an absolute
necessity within which we must all
participate.
And I really appreciate the way that you
tell stories.
And the way that you communicate for
aluminate in through truth ideas that
may otherwise not have been revealed.
So I'm very grateful.
Thank you for coming on under the skin
mate.
Well for having me.
It's good.
Good show.
Wasn't it splintered?
Nice one.
We are,
you've got mark [inaudible] before we
go,
as well as your own book.
What other books would you recommend or
sometimes we ask people to recommend a
few books that we should read.
Um,
uh,
I've
just been reading no is not enough by
Naomi Klein,
which I think she's been on the show.
She's good.
No is not enough.
Um,
um,
copy of that book from the ground around
roads,
um,
by Colson Whitehead,
which is a brilliant book about,
um,
a abolitionist.
It's a,
it's a novel,
uh,
which is,
um,
which is really good if you've got kids
under the age of about four,
so much.
I really like.
It's just a story about this little kid
and everybody's coming around because
they're having a surprise party for his
dad and it's kind of every kind of slice
of kind of Caribbean life,
I think in amount of salaries.
Uncle dd looks like a baby player and
his Auntie,
whatever,
who looks like she probably works in
local government and he's got two hours
and one's really fat and one's really
skimming and then his mom.
Anyway,
let me start,
comes home from the office and they will
have a big pies.
It's good.
I mean,
I did not ruin the plot there,
Gary.
Yeah,
it was quite a lot about Simon.
well the kids ended up going to bed.
They go,
I'm going to be analyzing the next week,
so I'm pretty sure this is subtext to
that.
Thanks.
Thanks very much,
Gary here another day in the death of
America.
That's out now here I've read it.
I like the,
you've got these air,
1950s white people in the cafe got coke
or shout because as I said,
very clear semiotic indicator there.
Call it.
Cheers,
mate.
Thank you.