Hello,
you're listening to under the skin with
me,
bro.
Nah,
y'all listen to me,
Russell brand and I'm talking to
Professor David.
I'm assuming professor can drop the
professor.
I don't like it very much.
Oh,
professor.
Hey.
I've come up in the world.
Professor David Harvey.
I'll be talking to as if we was equals
that David Harvey Professor David Harvey
is the world's leading Marxist thing.
Go.
That's what it says.
See,
I've just,
I'm just reading the script might,
I'm just reading the script.
He writes extensively on Marxists,
geography,
social justice,
and the political economy and is the
author of over 20 books including 17
contradictions in the end of capitalism,
rebel cities and the new imperialism is
a distinguished professor of
anthropology and geography at the
graduate center of the city,
University of New York and has been
teaching Marx's Kapital for almost 40
years.
His new book is titled Marx Capital and
the Madness of economic reason.
Professor David Harvey,
Frankie,
very much for being our guest on under
the skin.
You'll hear somewhat to promote this
book,
Marx capital and the madness of economic
reason.
Why you,
why have you written this book?
And now?
Well,
I'm,
I've been involved over several years
now what I call the mark's project,
which is to try to explain to people
what it was mark's was talking about and
to do it in terms which are simple
without being simplistic.
It's been quite a challenge to do that
has this marks is kind of a bit of a
hard read when you first read him.
But a lot of academics spend a lot of
their time trying to make marks more
complicated than it already is.
So I'm trying to make it simpler so that
people can grasp it.
And I had a series of books which have
come out.
And this is uh,
the last one and it may not be the final
one,
but it,
uh,
I tried to put a lot of things together
in this book about what the,
what's going on in the three volumes of
capital,
how will they relate to how the three
volumes relate to each other and,
and how coming out of that you get a
picture of capitalist society and the
essence of what capital is about.
Uh,
so that's what I'm trying to do in the
book and I'm hoping that people will
pick it up and read it and give a good
shot at understanding it.
Given your stated objective of making
capital more accessible,
perhaps we'll start this conversation
with a paps illuminating a few simple
terms and ideas.
So I'll go through these questions
because this is an important topic and
we've looped into this cause are
preemptive chat.
I was really getting off on,
but I would like to make sure that we
build sufficient foundations.
Firstly,
why you're not calling it das kapital
like how you're supposed to,
um,
well I'm using the English translation
so I usually English language to talk
about it.
There are some problems about the
translation and obviously now that's
what I'm working from.
Hey cause it I suppose because of that
brief to simplify it.
Firstly why he's based book so
important.
I mean capital and though your book and
think is important as well.
I'm not trying to belittle your book.
I said why is capital and then why is it
an important book?
What's in there that's relevant to
people today in 2017 after we have in
jewelry,
their idea,
their negative stories about communism.
Why is this?
But why is capital one important thing
for us to understand?
Now,
you know,
capitalism book is not about communism.
Oh it's a,
I was about as a critique of capitalism
and there's not even a critique of
capitalism and every respect.
It's a,
it's a critique of how,
what I would call the engine of
capitalist development,
uh,
works.
Uh,
how the laws of accumulation of capital
work cause capitalism expansionary
system is constantly expanding.
And how does it expand and what kind of
stresses does that do that does that
create amongst working people?
What kind of stresses in relationship to
cultural evolution,
what kind of stress is in relationship
to environmental questions and,
and,
and the like.
And we're surrounded obviously with all
of those questions about the
environment,
about cultural preservation,
about even the definition of what it is
means to be a human being.
They having a big debate about that and
the United States right now because
everybody looks at trump and says,
is that the future of what humanity is
going to look like?
And the answer many people,
there's no,
we got to think of something really
different.
So,
so with all of those questions around,
uh,
you need to know what it is that is
driving capitalism,
uh,
to do the kinds of things it does in
relationship to exploitation,
the environment,
social inequality,
cultural transformations,
the production of new wants,
needs and desires,
all of those sorts of things.
We need to have a theory of that.
And Mark's is the first person,
and we're ready to come to terms with
what that theory might look like
in the 1850s mark's was able to identify
in this critique of capitalism,
what likely trends and what the result
of capitalism would be.
Even though this is like,
you know,
150 years ago,
that's when the reasons you've written
the book,
isn't it?
Even at 150 years ago,
it was able to predict what was it about
capitalism then that made it evident
that this economic system,
well,
first,
and it has to grow.
It has to grow with the,
what we call a compound,
right?
Which is kind of a 3% per year is a
small amount of,
uh,
new commodities and so on back in 1850.
But by the time you get to 2000,
it's a huge amount of new commodities.
So it's got to grow and at some point,
or rather it's gonna hit limits to that.
Yeah.
In the end.
That's quite a simple observation.
Yeah.
And Mark's made then,
because if you change the word
capitalism to the word elephant,
then
in [inaudible] it is the elephant has to
continue to grow.
It's going to fill the room and kill us
all.
Like you just pointed out.
Yeah,
no,
it's a,
it's a growth machine and it has to grow
because that's the only way in which you
kind of show a profitability profit is
an access.
Yes.
And they have to produce the access in
order for capital smart and then you
have to use that access to produce more
access.
So they say it's endless.
Accumulation is one of the rules of the
game necessarily and essentially
impractical filling.
A practical need is about creating needs
that are not there order that it might
continue to have compound growth.
So how come that that observation was
made in 1850 how covert and then go,
oh yeah,
that's a good point,
right?
Stop this capitalism then.
Well,
because there's plenty of room to expand
back in 1850 I mean the rest of the
world was there and of course we are to
colonialism.
We had imperialism,
we had all of the expansions around the
world,
so there's plenty of room for that
growth to occur.
Uh,
there was a,
what I call a capital was getting into
what I call a special fix a lot of the
time,
which is what we're capable of doing.
Super amount of commodities,
uh,
and,
and capacity and Britain.
So I wouldn't know what to do with it.
So,
uh,
the British would lend to Argentina to
build railroads and the railroads will
be produced in Britain.
So yeah,
so Argentina gets caught into the kind
of the circulation of capital.
So,
so there were plenty of places like that
for capital to grow into.
But now there's no place left.
I mean,
maybe Africa still is not completely
gone,
but pretty much everywhere in the world
has been caught into it right now.
So growth from here on out is not
feasible when it was feasible back in
1850.
All right.
So,
even if someone has said out in a
minute,
if we have to,
if we have to indefinitely grow this
ideology,
it will necessarily bring about
destruction and the responses I was now
bie cheese,
no one was bothered.
Well you know,
back then,
uh,
you know United States was only just
beginning and and yeah they all United
States,
continent sort of and the North American
continent to get to occupy.
Would I be right then in asking David
and beyond dry and more importantly than
right.
Bloody clever in asking that uh,
that capitalism a sourced from
imperialism and colonialism is an
economic model that fits the proceeding
ideology which had been a rather more
obviously in ethical system of
domination.
Yeah.
I ran a capital has always been about
geographical expansion.
Now,
whether you call it colonialism or you
call imperialism,
I actually prefer to call it and even
geographical development because
sometimes imperialism makes it is too
simple a term cause cause right now if
you look at the way in which commodities
are made,
you know,
one piece is made in Taiwan and one lady
says made in South Korea and other
pieces made in Mexico and then it's all
put together in the United States and
you say,
where is capital in all of this?
So right now it's a much more
complicated kind of story.
So I kind of saying,
well where's,
where's,
where's all this work going?
But she's producing the commodities
again on our table.
And one of the questions I always like
to start by geography classes off with
was questions of where does your
breakfast come from?
And it was kind of really interesting.
People can't go,
oh I never thought about it.
And they,
they kind of say well it comes from the
supermarket and you had no,
no,
no.
I want to feel aware there's all this
stuff come from.
And,
and after about three weeks of asking
the same question and people will say
things like,
I didn't have breakfast this morning,
it's now telling me this question but I
don't like this question and I'll let me
my breakfast and no,
I'm not hungry.
More of a puzzle that rain.
When did that crowd the cloud accumulate
and why was that card that I'm not
coming to your classes anymore.
No,
that's exactly right.
That's how I,
I got a lot of dropouts from my
geography class cause I kept asking that
question.
But in a way a capitalism is a vehicle
for a particular type of mentality,
which is kind of about what,
well it's uh,
you know,
the famous kind of statement,
the greed is good.
There's that kind of a side bar about
Ashley.
The mentality now is shifted a bit
because I think a lot of capitalism is,
is about a complicated relationship with
the data's and I,
one of the things that are talking about
in this last book a lot is the way in
which the future has got foreclosed by
debt.
Bad debt is a claim on future labor.
And it's a claim on your future library
and if you heavily in debt,
you've got to pay it off.
So the incentive you have right now is
not took on is is getting rid of the
debt.
I said
I'm supposed to be rich and I'm in
slave.
Yeah,
well this is exactly,
this is exactly right.
It's about foreclosure and it's about,
it's about not emancipating you at all.
It's about imprisoning you in a network
of a debt relations which have become
very different.
That's why,
you know,
student debt,
I'm in states now,
we've got these horrible amount of
student debt,
which really full close is the future
for people for new in remarkable ways.
If you couldn't remove morality from the
lens of analysis in a source of
ingenious in it's mendacity in a number
of ways in which he dominating.
Yeah.
By the way,
Mark's does not make a moral argument.
No,
it's not a really,
essentially a moral argument they'd
seize.
It's about the inevitability of
mendacity.
Cool.
[inaudible] bearing might like then,
this is still the simple bit of the
podcast for me and one to z,
but that is the difference between
socialism,
Marxism and communism.
Is there a quick way of doing that?
Well,
socialism I think is generally spoken.
Alvarez,
a transitional a system and which
capitalism has put down a sufficient
constraints so that you have social
democracy and it's,
and I think traditionally it was seen as
a stepping stone to full communism
where,
which would lead to the abolition of the
class relation between and labor and the
abolition of class privilege.
And eventually of course the abolition
of the capitalist state apparatus.
So communism is seen as something,
a further stage going beyond,
uh,
we're,
whereas under socialism,
elements of the capitalism would still
exist.
The market system was still be their
money of the sort of what we use.
And cumulate was still be there,
but under social,
under communism,
a lot of that would then disappear.
Marxism,
for me anyway,
is,
is a mode of analysis as a way of
thinking,
which is a critical way of thinking.
And,
and it,
it says to you when he,
when he got some sort of situation and
you want to try to understand what the
hell is happening,
you don't get to see by surface
appearances,
you don't get to see it by ideological
kind of bluster.
You get,
you could do an analysis and for
yourself and you come up with an
understanding of what's really going on
here.
And when you understand what's really
going on here,
you can then act against what is really
happening in a,
in a deep way rather than simply deal
with surface symptoms.
I see subcutaneous analysis,
not just observation of symptoms.
When you observe the symptoms,
you're necessarily confined by the
argument.
The Arthur.
Yeah.
One of the things mark said was if,
if,
uh,
you know,
if everything was as it seemed to be on
the surface,
there will be no need for science.
So we look at the,
we look at the sun and it looks like the
sound's going around the earth,
but we find out,
well it isn't,
you know,
it's rotating.
So I'm just another business.
Write that down.
This is Iowa.
So that's why,
that's why mark's means by appearance,
uh,
and,
and then the reality behind it.
So it's,
uh,
and,
and you know,
most scientists,
I think we recognize there's a
difference between symptoms and you
know,
what the underlying causes and those
medical practitioners would,
would recognize that difference.
And Mark's is trying to do a kind of
constantly trying to do a forensic kind
of inspection of a capitalist system to
find out what these symptoms which you
see on the surface,
like increasing inequality,
where,
where those symptoms are coming from in
terms of was producing them.
Yeah.
I see.
Um,
may I ask when a law recently we spoke
to Al Gore,
we spoke to Al Gore about climate
change,
Al Gore,
uh,
talking to us about like how,
you know,
in a sense,
I suppose he's a raise on debt sre and
explicit mission,
which seems to have some nobility about
it is to galvanize and enthuse people
about being sort of responsible.
But when I was talking to Al Gore are
kept thinking and in fact saying,
yeah,
but hold on a minute.
If you need that to stop,
can't you do the best and they've got to
be sort of some stern,
I'm definitive regulation of that.
Otherwise it will just carry on like an
then this guy's regular like defy in an
absolute regulation of energy companies,
certain kinds of traits,
certain kinds of labor.
So in in the capitol,
is it dealing with my same,
well it's no point just asking.
People have you know,
turn the tap off,
are they clean their teeth?
It's much more important than say,
well you can't have that amount of
profit.
You can't operate in that way.
He's that way.
He's that Crista does that critique?
Yeah,
that does.
That's a very good point.
I mean what my view of a Al Gore is he
thinks that you can actually solve the
climate change problem within the
parameters of a capitalist system and
that he doesn't want to do away with
capitalism and we spray is trying to
protect capitalism from the consequences
of climate change.
Whereas I take the view that a,
the main producer of climate change is
of course the driving force of capital
accumulation.
And until you've dealt with the driving
force of capital accumulation,
you're going to get all these promises
about new technologies which are going
to solve the problem and so on.
Uh,
but you're not going to get a
fundamental kind of a solution without
challenging capital itself.
So it's kind of futile,
isn't it?
And it's sort of sort of using the means
of a kind of a contemporary consumer
society in that it's about your
individual choice and usually
individually recycle and individually do
they make these kind of choices?
Um,
there's a thing I'm very interested in
and I keep asking people about it and
they don't know.
So I'll ask you,
there's this thing I read.
Gandy said they went,
this is him that point ass kicking out
the British and then ash just doing
their job for him.
Uh,
what India is a country of 70,000
villages that's built on craft economies
where everybody works all the time.
We have to focus less on mass production
and think instead of production for the
masses,
and to do this,
we're going to have to break out spell.
We've commodification as long as people
are thinking we've got to get more and
more stuff,
we're going to be in trouble.
Now that is where it starts to interface
with the individual bottle.
Like this thing he said about 70,000
village each one or to po it,
autonomous,
independent and trading only in access
and being where possible.
Self-Sufficient.
What's he saying there?
Candy is this,
is that
it's,
it's a utopian vision in some ways and
I'm not against Utopian visions.
You need that water if you were right
utopia.
Oh you do?
Oh,
I know.
I kind of like a little bit of Utopian.
No,
I love it.
I don't,
I don't entirely lie on,
I own
it.
And,
and I think that that,
that,
well,
well candy's saying is that there is a
way of organizing production and
consumption,
which is radically different from that,
which is given by the industrialization
model.
And he was faced with a,
you know,
Nairu and develop mentalism which was to
bring in factories and solve the problem
that way.
And a Gandy saying no,
there was another kind of solution where
I think there's a,
there's a problem with that is in a
situation of very strong population
change and population growth.
Yeah,
the 70,000
villages were all but the growing and
then,
uh,
and there are other issues which arise
like,
uh,
how,
how do you,
how do you deal with local famines under
circumstances,
that kind of man,
if you get crop failures amongst say,
20,000
villages in the said part,
and how do you support,
uh,
what happens there?
So the,
the haze assumption is that they'll
never be a crop failure.
Whereas historically there are crop
failures because of climate issues and
her malpractices and things like that.
So you need to have,
uh,
an organization that can deal with the,
with the possibility of crop failures
and,
and can redistribute wealth between the
villages when it's,
when it's really necessary.
And the other difficulty is when they're
independent and autonomous villages,
some of the villages will start to get
very afterward and very rich and some of
them will get very poor.
What are you going to do about the
inequalities of income is between
different villages.
Gandy didn't think about those sorts of
things.
And I,
and I think you have to think about form
of organization will put all those
village economists together.
So you've believed that in Arcos into
Elysium,
Eh,
I suppose a version of what Gandy was
talking you could go to and our coasts
and colorism from,
from,
from what he's talking about.
I don't think he would want no bad at
all,
but,
but you could move in that direction.
And of course there's a lot of interest
these days in solidarity economies and
autonomous development and this place
and uh,
you know,
and as a coach,
it's a great faith in autonomy at the
seminar.
Our autonomy is going to be the
solution.
Am I answer to that is,
I think autonomy is a good thing when
you know what you're doing with it,
but it's not the solution.
Because if you don't have autonomy
relations between autonomous groups,
you're going to get a great deal of any
quality.
You're going to get the famine problem,
you're going to get all sorts of issues
with this kind,
uh,
which have to be sold by,
by integrating a local economies with
each other in such a way that they can
some mutually support each other in
times of difficulty.
And so it is a,
it's a,
presumably what you're agreeing for Wa
capital is arguing for is that the,
the role of the state,
but the state has to have a benevolent
and redistributive role and all that
done.
There has to be,
well put it this way,
they have to be mechanisms of a
redistribution and,
and,
and the like and,
and mutual support.
And that has to be organized.
Now when he used the term state,
we often think about the capitalist
state and I don't like the capitalist
state,
but we do need a form of governments and
governmental inter interventions.
And I like some of these things where
they talk about,
you know,
[inaudible] for example,
and this idea about municipal socialism
or,
and,
and local socialism days,
you'd have autonomous,
uh,
assemblies.
But then there will be a super assembly
that we would start to deal with the
relations between and,
and then he'd have a super,
super assembly in which,
uh,
yeah,
what's happening in,
say North America gets connected was,
was happening in South Africa and,
and issues like climate change are
addressed because you need an a,
a global organization to deal with.
The climate change problem is going to
be dealt with simply by everybody
changing behavior,
as you mentioned earlier.
So you need,
so you need some form of,
of governmental structure of
coordination.
Uh,
and I,
and I think,
uh,
the autonomy argument is,
is powerful up to a point,
but it needs to go much further.
When I say that,
then people say,
oh,
you're in favor of the capitalist state
and you just want to,
you can get a state power and we know
the state is a disaster and yes,
where the current state is a disaster,
it's an instrument of capitalist
domination.
I'm also,
I think now that it was even in the 19th
century and we see it being a militarize
so it can suppress social opposition and
social movements and,
and so,
you know,
I,
I'm,
I'm really against the kind of
capitalist state,
but,
but that doesn't mean I'm against some
sort of form of government,
uh,
look and deal with these much broader
global kind of problems.
How will do you,
how would we ever arrive at that?
How would they,
how would we have a form of state that
was benevolent and acting in the
interests of its population?
And can you now answer a question and
you must be continually called upon to
answer that,
where like I'm glad that you did this
distinctions between socialism,
Marxism and communism and it,
how do you address the great failures of
communism in the last century?
Well,
first off,
I don't think necessarily the communism
was a great failure.
Uh,
I mean,
I called her,
you know,
style and is good.
Lacks.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
there were some very,
very bad parts of that history.
Uh,
on the other hand,
I think what was interesting was after
the collapse of the Soviet Union,
life expectancy in the Soviet Union went
down in Russia know enormously.
A lot of people,
they're suddenly found all their rights
or disappeared.
I mean,
so,
so I think we are wrong to kind of say
everything that the communist dead was,
was,
was terrible.
Mostly I've been propagandized to live
there.
My perception of what happened in the
car communist union,
that century has been totally realized
and I don't really understand it cause
it does.
I mean cause I don't know.
Yeah,
look at,
look I'm not,
I don't want to get in a situation of
saying everything was great and
wonderful and a no criticism.
But if you look at a place like Cuba and
you look at the health care delivery in
Cuba,
it's fantastic as well.
Education,
you know,
and,
and so there's some very good things.
Awesome,
good things.
And,
but like I think we have to address
that.
Some of the things that seem like I was
always good fan on the telly once with a
woman that was doing a documentary said
it seems that communism in Soviet
communism unconsciously or inadvertently
mimicked this,
the social structure that immediately
proceeded it czar Islam in the,
in spite of its declared objectives,
it has a hierarchal structures and did
lead to oppression and persecution of a
cliff.
Yeah.
No,
I mean I mean I don't,
I don't deny that a lot that,
but I do think that,
oh we have to give credibility to some
of the things that happened on the
commute or something.
The other thing I have to say is this a,
the reason that most of us have the
standard of living we have today is
because of the communist threat.
If the communist threat and not being
there after 1945 you know,
we wouldn't have had the delivery of the
welfare state such as it was and all
those kinds of things which allow us
increasing life expectancy.
And it's interesting.
They are,
over the last few years,
life expectancy has been going down in
some of the major capitalist countries.
Britain,
for example,
Cameron,
I think as the first prime minister to
leave with a lower life expectancy,
the money came in.
Well I think he's,
he's gone up,
you should say the armed guards outside
his house.
Nothing's happening or that gazer let me
tell you,
it is how bill crawling around
everywhere and there's an ambulance on
got.
I can't,
that was having to anyone else elaborate
grove.
I must be terrified.
All hell bill or outside one else.
Right.
But Look,
David,
this is a thing and it goes on basically
my position and more first though,
it may be,
I need substantiated as it will continue
to be,
is this,
that we need radical change.
Yes.
And part of that does seem to be the
dismantling of a capitalist state and a
new system based on sharing.
But when we even appear to have an
allegiance to like,
hey,
like anything,
an umbrella under which she had stolen
is a more,
and like,
you know,
me,
I'd love a bit of Shea Guevara,
but you can't,
you've tried saying that in Miami
people,
the kickbacks pretty fierce in her life
because like,
because of the floors and because of,
you know,
like we've been,
I grew up in the 80s and Cold War,
which is,
you know,
see a,
a town of two,
two sides.
I've,
I find it very hard to unpick that.
And anything that seems revivalist are
nostalgic about communism,
that's already happened.
I think people were like,
no thanks mate.
You don't want to do that.
I mean,
I,
I'm,
I've been interested in some of these,
uh,
programs,
for example,
uh,
in,
in northern Syria,
the Kurds have reorganized things along
a kind of a assembly structures,
uh,
partly inspired by the,
an alternative notion of democracy.
I think that right now some of the
progressive mass in Spain or trying to
come up with a way of creating more
democratic assembly structures.
So I think there's a lot of
experimentation that needs to be done on
things like that.
I think the big problem with communism
was they had us and what I call a single
bullet theory of social change,
which was put in classic Marxist terms
that the productive forces that is,
if you could command production,
then you'd really,
the rest of society would take care of
everything in a proper kind of way.
I think we have to work on,
on,
on a whole range of different issues
including sort of culture relation to
nature.
And we have to deal with a problem right
now,
which is fundamental to me,
which is what I call global alienation.
The alienation of populations
politically from their jobs,
from their daily life possibilities.
And,
and you've got alienated populations all
over the world who then do crazy things
sometimes,
you know,
that can be passive for a while and then
something happens and you get these sort
of seemingly irrational outbreaks of,
uh,
of craziness and they erect elect Donald
Trump and do things like that.
So I think alienation is one of the big,
big issues.
And when you have populations that are
alienated then then you can't address it
by sort of sign obote communist at that
cause there was there as Eileen a pillar
is I as alienated from political parties
like the Communist parties and so on as
they are from anything else.
So it's hard then to rebuild some sort
of a trust with Eileen knighted
populations and that's a lot of
political work to do.
And I think there's an interesting
distinction for me between uh,
what might be called a social media is a
form of communication and social media
leading to forms of organization.
The communicative forms are very good,
the organizational forms are very bad
right now and we've really got to think
about how to,
how to construct organizational forms.
And I agree with you entirely.
I'm not nostalgic about,
you know,
what the Communists did except that,
when it comes to healthcare and that
kind of thing,
I'd say,
well we should look at how the Cubans
did it and no one an education.
We should look at the,
yes,
I understand you're in now matched by
the beauty of the original idea,
the veracity of the critique and the
possibility of components of it.
Cause you said that great.
It kind of was how many take that down,
how it looks.
That's what I'm interested is it will be
recorded is open or causes.
Okay.
Thank you.
I've seen endorsement that's going on
the poster.
You say to that,
great,
I'm going to give that in as a thing.
As my phd,
I'm not doing a phd.
I'm doing the math on that begins with
them.
I'm really going to have to start
listening in those lectures and that is
yes that you like that and uh,
I have a compliment.
I'm so ego led.
If someone's nice to me,
it takes me about an hour to recover
from my graces because I've been given a
compliment that's just take a while to
reflect on the compliment and the move
on with the interview.
And my point is,
is that w let's say what's needed is
something that whilst it may be derived
from or capital or capital or booklet,
I've only just learned to say correctly
and now you've made can be,
I'll do it like that.
I suppose David,
the thing that sort of interests me,
the reason I'm doing this podcast is I
sense that change is possible.
I sense that we are being lied to.
I S I can feel I the,
the,
the argument that you made about
alienation,
it's so,
it's so in evidence.
Um,
and I,
I went to that Cuba when I was quite
young,
22 and it was magnificent.
I was there of all things to record a
chewing gum commercial.
It should the most vacuous product
imaginable,
not even nutrition,
just the act of mastication as a ritual
and an idea while people,
staff.
And while there,
luckily I'm a drug addict because of
that.
It was then,
I'm clean now.
So that means that wherever I go,
I have to go and find for people that
know where the drugs are.
So that means you'd have to get off the
rails.
You have to go down the rabbit hole.
So I found myself in these things called
Barrios in Havana.
I liked it,
I liked the people and I liked the
murals.
And there was a sense of Julie and glory
and potentiality and caused from the 50s
wine,
not just streets painted by people in
this presence of people and people's
creativity.
And as you say,
the absence of that set alienation that
comes when you don't participate in your
city,
when you don't participate in your
culture,
when you know you have no power,
when you know you have no meaning,
how lost you feel.
I felt something different then,
but I was on drugs.
So you know,
all of my experiences were being
filtered through trucks,
but I,
you know,
and that was before I knew that they had
bloody good then.
Okay,
you know,
live here and you know,
all of that.
But what I feel like when we are posing
an idea to people now,
I think what like w in there,
what,
what did Lenin,
Trotsky,
the Bolsheviks et Cetera,
take from that book capital and use in
the revolution in coal museum.
And how did it become that,
you know,
like,
uh,
the,
the failure that it became,
even if you take as failure,
either the fall of the Berlin Wall,
the end of the Soviet Union,
and what has happened in,
in Russia now.
Yeah.
See that,
that's a question I often get asked to
my back away from.
I kind of say,
look,
uh,
yeah,
Lennon and trust gay and Bacara and all
these people.
I read Capitol and I took certain things
from him and I did certain things from
him.
Our job right now is to read capital and
find out what we want to do with it.
What shall we did?
Yeah.
Well,
well,
first off,
you gotta learn how to read it,
you know,
and,
and that is not initially an easy thing.
And that's horrible.
I hope some of those things I ride help
people get into it.
That's going to be vital.
It,
you're going to have to do that as
really important.
And,
uh,
you know,
and I have these things on the web where
you can do the,
you can,
there's a course on Marx's kapital
volume one and volume two on the web,
but you know,
and you can take it on the web.
Um,
so,
so yeah,
open it up.
But in the process,
making sure that we understand what it
is that,
that,
that miles is really teaching us about
the nature of this system and know that
it comes back to this is not what it
appears to be on the surface to can we
develop a way of critique?
So I want,
I want to educate people if I can,
not necessarily to regurgitate knocks
cause that's not the point,
but to use his mode of an analysis so
you can start to see,
okay these populations that alienated,
why are they alienated?
Where's the alienation come from?
Once it got to do with the nature of the
Labor process,
why is it labor process the way it is
these days?
Why did capitalist technology decide
that they wanted a labor process which
disempowered the Labor?
Yeah.
Why is,
why is that there?
Why is it,
as [inaudible] says,
it's wonderful thing where he starts off
one of these chapters and he kind of
said,
John,
Stuart Mill has this problem.
He says,
look,
we have all this labor saving machinery
right now and you've ever thought this
labor saving machinery but lighten the
load of labor and John Single.
But the funny thing is is it seems that
it doesn't,
the actually,
it makes it a lot of the labor of worse
and Marxists,
but of course it does because the
purpose of the machinery's not delight,
lighten the load of labor is to extract
more value and more surplus value,
a more profit from the labor.
Of course,
if the machine can help you do that,
and then that's what it does.
So this is where there's,
so this gives you an understanding of
capitalist technology,
which evaded Don's do at mill,
but we smog sees very clearly and we see
very clearly and say,
actually the purpose of technology could
change.
There are all kinds of person,
but it was military and all the rest of
it in there.
But one of the big purposes of it is to
disempower the labor.
Yes.
And and when the Labor is disempowered,
guess what?
They become alienated.
Yes.
Guess what?
They start behaving in an out of the
united way.
You know when you go at least things
sort of going on,
you're kind of saying,
well these are the kinds of insights
that come out of reading Marx's capital
and you kind of go,
wow,
no.
Once I've got that insight,
I can't look at any discussion of
technological change and imagine it's
got some,
some socialist utopia attached to it.
As you know how some of the people who
are writing these days do the artificial
intelligence is the new socialist utopia
now.
Well you see what happens.
Uber,
Uber starts as a kind of sharing economy
and the next thing you know it's become
capitalized and somebody become a
billionaire out of it.
You got high,
you got the ability of the system.
Is capitalism good morally,
ethically it's,
look,
it's very big obstacle.
Anything.
You can take anything like I,
I,
my understanding of it is it primarily
over the way that it interacts with
culture and creativity and how you can
see mimicked in its narrative.
The,
uh,
central floor iee for example,
take hip hop,
which begins as sort of very defiant
then goes through a stage of being
Utopian and beautiful and then oh,
becomes commodified,
becomes clearly a product and to some
degree about products and about commerce
and about acquisition and about like
he's,
if the ideology is so endemic,
it's so all encompassing that it becomes
invisible.
So you say that part of capitalism's DNA
is it its own concealment,
it's own consuming is a primary
function.
Once it's concealed,
his self care can continue.
Now what I think is,
you know,
when people talk about lean,
the system and the floors were the
system who obviously when you say you
know about technology's role is to
technology,
you know,
John's mills all baffled by it for marks
goes,
no,
it's doing its job perfectly.
Or is that not true of bureaucracy and
systems of control for someone?
This system for some people,
for some groups I'm institution,
this system is brilliant,
is working 100% effectively.
We have all about climate change.
No problem.
Whereby alienation,
inequality,
riots,
death,
murder,
that's the best summation.
No problem.
So who is this strata for whom this
system is beneficial?
Who are they?
How do we influence,
control,
diminish,
limit oppose them.
Phd.
That's what you got to do.
So she could have sold out.
No,
I mean I could give some preliminary
salary answers to those questions.
Write this down.
Yeah.
Well I'm in,
it's an it's,
I mean you're in a great position to
take that sort of stuff on big time.
Yeah.
Because I mean it's very important when
you're doing a phd to be in love with
the no matter you're doing,
you know,
cause otherwise also brand myself by me,
which is,
which is fine because here's why you
should be about in some ways.
So I think it's a,
but yeah.
Who,
who benefits while you can see who who,
who extracts wealth from it and how
wealth goods I guess.
Yeah.
How Jeff Bezos gets his money and now he
is the guy rounds,
Amazon,
right and good though on my Amazon.
But they're part of the problem.
I didn't pay the bloody tax a t bloody
Begley controlling everything.
So that would have to go and how Google,
and I know elise,
I love monopolies are kind of been set
up so they'd been set up in such a way
and,
and actually,
you know,
I use use a minnow,
definitely awesome at the same time,
value is being extracted from us,
kind of rent is being taken away from
us.
Uh,
and,
and so we've got these,
these,
these systems now which,
which,
you know,
and,
and I think particularly in the cultural
field and so on,
the,
the forms of exploitation and
appropriation are,
are,
are becoming and are pretty,
uh,
pretty,
pretty chronic.
I mean,
there've been that way for quite a
while,
but it seems to me right now,
particularly given the problems that I
mentioned earlier,
the capitalist running out of places to
go for new things to do,
just geographical a geographically,
uh,
and,
and actually it's increasingly relying
upon,
you know,
culture,
the production and commodification of
culture.
What does that mean?
What do you mean by that?
Is the commodification of culture.
For example,
if,
if we want to have a short turnover time
or something,
then,
then the spectacle is instantaneously
consumed.
It's gone.
It's not like my grandmother's knives
and forks.
It doesn't ask 150 years,
this is the Olympic Games or something
like that.
But it becomes,
becomes a big mode of capital
accumulation.
Vast amounts of money goes into
rebuilding the infrastructure and doing
all the things that the construction
interest wants to do.
And the Olympic Games or 10 days,
it's all gone.
And there was an x games that running
track round out pink and,
and,
uh,
how many,
Biennale
is,
are there now and every city has a bnr.
Yeah,
he's a patient with a cultural,
you know like Venice exhibition or the
Shanghai exhibition and the and and so
and so you suddenly find though the
whole kind of cultural realm is being
used as a,
as a sort of commodification real estate
development kind of a scam.
Yes.
So okay,
I see.
It's like that there's a,
a matrix of commodification.
It's applied to everything and you can
see it's prints,
fingerprints,
if it would have anything that's
organic,
his fingers on everything.
Like football being a great example.
How like,
you know,
if you listen to talk sport,
which is obviously I think now owned by
sort of sky and stuff,
this is the sort of delicious,
cruel irony of like what everyone is
talking about all the time is I was just
all goes about bloody money.
So goes about money and like the way
that sort of like the way that football
looks now and of course in our players,
amber,
I mean that's one of the few ways that
working class person as a chance to vent
in any money is to become a world class
football.
So that's what I,
that's not my point,
but my point is that somehow the essence
of the game is surviving.
This process of commodification,
how the experience is being turned into
a product,
how even age roots in community is
tribal roots,
its roots as a congregational activity,
a spice for union.
And togetherness is basically layer
after layer of commerce wrapped around
it.
The players appearing in the adverse
adverse on the shirts.
You know,
how long before the pitch has adverts on
there,
how long,
you know,
it's obvious say it's creeping through
our consciousness.
It's everywhere.
And one of the things I think as well is
I feel like you're growing up.
When I did,
I commodify people,
I think I,
I have to uncork I have to consciously
unstitch my tendency to look at people
and think,
well,
what are you going to do for me?
What are you going to give me something?
Can I have sex with you?
I'm not thinking of this now,
David.
I'm trying to,
I'm married now.
Like I try not to look at people as
commodities.
That's one of the things,
one of the floors,
you know,
you talk about on one hand,
the alienation that people understand
it.
Oh No,
I'm absolutely expendable.
My role is meaningless.
I am only a piece of this machinery and
organic piece of matter in a machine.
But the other side of that is that we
start to look each other as commodities.
That we could lose the diff,
the lens of humanity.
She said to me,
you know,
was a central kind of pull up politics.
Uh,
I'd like to see,
tell you what I want to politics of
decommodification.
That is what's happened over the last
30,
40 years.
Education has become more and more of a
commodity,
but should stop being a commodity.
It should be a free good to everybody.
Health care is a commodity.
In other words,
we should start a de commodified whole
sectors of the economy.
Now that's this socialism.
That's not communism,
that socialism,
that's a,
that's a socialist or a project and
you're right.
We should also stop the,
you know,
start the commodifying others so that we
start to look at others as people
instead of instruments of our own,
you know,
uh,
our own activities and trying to exploit
fair economic ideology requires that it
does things is sort of biological and
psychological is stimulate limitless
need and desire in order to perpetuate
itself.
Then here's also colonized the
consciousness and the lives of the
individuals beyond their economic role.
Cause it requires their spiritual role
be beholden
to be the ideology.
No,
no.
I think the decolonization of the
decommodification,
those are the kinds of general food
fields of endeavor which we can start to
do things on right now.
I don't do it well,
you know,
we couldn't even get the Labor party to
start to go really strongly.
I mean abolished student debt for
example.
There was talk of this.
There's talk of it.
Yeah.
Well stop having talk about it.
Don't do that,
you know,
do the same with uh,
making sure that there's enough money
goes into healthcare.
So it's really a non commodified set and
we,
you get rid of the secondary kind of
privatized thing,
which the get,
get us out of the conservatives,
you know,
want to use that as a way of sort of
chewing away at the National Health
Service so that you're done.
Uh,
you know,
so there's a,
there,
there are real politics,
uh,
that can have short,
even in the short term,
or you can imagine sort of a radical
beginning.
And if people start to think in terms of
decommodification just over something
like education or health care,
and then you can extend it a bit more to
housing and then actually the basic,
uh,
food,
which,
you know,
the Cubans you did by the way.
Oh yes.
With a ration book on a ration book
every year.
Certain basic amount of rice and sign,
and it's not working too well right now,
but,
but it was a basic food kind of
allocation that everybody had.
So do things like this and,
and,
and uh,
we could do it,
you
know,
when people come out of a cult like
scientology or you know,
they have to sit him down with someone
who goes to all that stuff you've been
wired up with is not true when they come
back to your mom and dad or whatever he
is.
And how are we gonna unstitch the
conditioning generation generation deep.
When I like sometimes just to make
myself feel better,
I really go and talk to the young people
and like,
you know,
give him Ben there he is about my views.
One of the things that's very difficult
for me,
uh,
as someone now,
you know,
I'm in my forties now and I tried to
feel like I'm a person that has access
to the young and I feel like I can
affect people is to recognize how light
they are indoctrinated by they want,
right.
The phone don't tell them that they
don't want the phone because they want
it.
You know,
how much she learned.
They said they think about money.
Why would they not?
How could they not,
how do we begin to see this thing you
said?
The thing you like most of our marks,
his analysis is these ferocity and its
ability to deconstruct,
critique and reveal essence,
epiphany,
that revelation of essence,
the revelation of real truth,
right.
How are we going to wade through the
layers of inculcation lacquers their
mind?
I you started at
various in various ways.
I mean I think marks has asked answer to
this is first off he says it should
start to try to identify certain kinds
of practices which are very simple
practices over things like you know,
using people who in instrumental ways
instead of relating to them as human
beings and that that these,
these,
these changes can,
you know,
so the realm of practices is very
important and that can be all over the
place.
The second thing is to start to actually
have a political movement which kind of
says,
you know,
we don't have to actually create human
beings of the sort that we're creating
right now with a kind of neo liberal
aesthetic and all of that.
And,
and we can do things rather differently
and get people to read.
I mean you mentioned Gandy,
people sometimes read Gandy and get very
transformed by it in terms of starting
to think about the world in a different
kind of way.
And so there's an educational process
which then gets embedded in a political
movement.
And I think that is then starts to be
important.
And uh,
that political movement can start to
have effects by orchestrating new forms
of governance and democracy and the,
like,
for instance,
if you look at what's going on in
Barcelona,
you've got a radical mare and she's
trying to set up a kind of a new forms
of democratic consultation within the
city.
Yes.
She's only just started a,
they only just started working on this,
but this is one of the projects they
have.
So,
but that,
but that project comes out of a bunch of
people who started to develop a small
practices on the ground who got together
and kind of said,
look,
we need to do something.
We are radically different.
I mean,
the mayor comes out of the
anti-foreclosure movement.
She's,
she very,
very progressive.
When she's got a bit of a progressive
alliance behind her.
And so new things can be be set up.
And it's very interesting to me,
and I'm interested in urban,
this is not a radical males around the
world.
I mean even places like Seattle and Los
Angeles have radical councils.
Now we're starting to do things that are
very different.
The local level,
just to the local level.
And I,
this is the way in which this political
movement can't be taught from the top
down.
It's got,
are all going to get sort of,
it's got to develop organically somehow.
I agree with the People's daily lives.
So you're not thinking that that means
to a degree then the power has to be
closer to people and the yes.
And then the essay,
the idea of state power,
even if apparently they never,
lynn is always going to seem somehow
abstract.
Yes.
And,
and,
and then you then,
then,
you know,
to me it's more a dialectical kind of
relationship between some sort of
centralized state power.
So somebody like who's a mayor of a city
has a certain kind of centralized power,
but I rest very much upon,
you know,
local neighborhood movements.
Then what happens is I was movements try
to do certain things and they get
support.
They need crucial support from an
American do.
So if you want to develop a new house in
complex,
which is a non commodity housing
development of affordable housing and
you probably need the city to help you
acquire the land and,
and if the city helps you acquire the
land and the procedures doing this job.
So said I relationship of certain kind
between these different levels
of shame because you've gotten the most
recent text messages from John Rogers
cause he's talking about some people
they're trying to buy some house.
My mate John Rogers,
he said First Communist,
I've met when I was young man.
He side fairly my head with thirdly
dreams.
Okay.
Yeah.
He sent me something recently about some
campaign where people are trying to buy
their own life by their own land and,
and develop it.
Do you think then that what you're
saying,
is it curious,
do you think David,
that they serve sort of forms of more
localized or at least see wide
government?
For me,
I would take with my particular code
that that's an indication that we,
what's required is decentralized,
more decentralized power and perhaps
this is the end of the nation state.
I mean when you sort of look at what's
happening in America and him,
certain strands of British politics,
like can you see pipe perhaps a within
the brexit impulse,
a sort of a,
a certain positivity in that people want
to unpick themselves.
I know there's many reasons for brexit
waiver on some level to a kind of
decentralization power being closer to
people,
people having a degree of authority in
their own lives.
But I don't believe in a decentralized
fashion as a,
as an absolute.
I mean because a,
actually it turns out of the,
one of the best ways you can orchestrate
centralized control is through
decentralization.
Uh Huh.
But you think about it at the market is
a very decentralized system.
And of course this guy,
it's a,
it's actually compatible with incredible
concentrations of political and economic
power.
So,
so I don't think decentralization in
itself is the answer.
I think that some level of decent in a
situation where there's not any
decentralization,
we'd go for decentralization and then
lies by its ideology.
There is in the air has such a clear
mandate.
It's such a simplistic mandate,
extract profit,
extract,
profit.
Like you know,
that that itself is right
geographical.
It's be like,
it can't be contained.
You can't,
you and I suppose any attempts to
regulate,
yeah,
national level or local level are always
resisted.
Now another thing is say that for a
moment when you said they're like the,
if we had a political pie that wasn't
login overtly committed to say,
you know,
sort of,
uh,
like,
you know,
some of the basics.
Um,
how do you think in governance in
government such as a nation and it's
such an ideology would survive one we'd
like after weapon.
Grace?
Well,
you know,
again,
that's one of the big issues.
So you've got these pretty progressive
movements when they get political power
and then they find political power is
constrained in certain ways,
and the finances are such that they have
to do things.
So they'd become just like,
you know,
everybody else.
And we've seen that,
you know,
the history of the Labour Party when
they came into power,
he started to be very much more pro
capitalist.
So,
uh,
so I,
I think,
uh,
at that point,
the whole kind of revolutionary impulse
has to be taken,
uh,
most,
most seriously and decide a reformist
party,
uh,
should look to create what I would call
revolutionary reforms,
those reforms,
which opened the pathway towards
further,
if you know,
what does reform,
what would you prioritize the
establishment of like benevolent state
institutions around how often education,
I can see how important that is,
but is it not equally important given
what we've discussed that to have
powerful,
draconian regulation of enterprise?
Yeah.
No,
I'm not in a,
I'm not against a regulating what a,
the capitalist class is doing a,
I'm very much in favor.
What does that sound like?
Well it did,
it sounds like,
uh,
for example,
you put strict rules on pollution and a,
you put strict rules on things like
occupational safety and health
conditions in factories and the like so
much regulation around their behavior
and actually those,
those
around pie as well.
Well,
I,
yeah,
I mean,
I would like to see,
uh,
I mean,
it wouldn't,
what,
what kind of world would it be if Ashley
sign liker them on drag on a principle
of which was we started out,
well,
it was a big cooperative that became
bigger and bigger and bigger originated
in Spain.
And the rule was that the salary
differential should be no more than one
to three.
Oh yeah.
That's cool.
Yeah.
Now,
recently it's gone to one to nine.
So you see the kind of pressures on it,
but one to three.
Imagine if all corporations had to work
under the,
under the rule that the writer return to
people in the corporation should a not
be more than one to three right now.
Big Corporation heads guess,
I mean like 300 or 400 times what the
average height down it.
Yeah,
of course running millions,
but you legislate it and so kind of say,
okay,
here's the,
here's the situation and we will be,
we'll be living in a radically different
world if we,
if,
if alcor if,
if hey on right now is a scandalous,
I mean you have this scandal going on
here about how much the heads of a
university is a paid oh,
they're scandal.
Yeah.
There any [inaudible] earning huge
amounts.
Yeah.
May.
And at the same time that cutting,
cutting back on on,
on a number of faculty,
they hire you now because yeah.
It's very seductive isn't it?
Yeah.
Everyone gets loaded in.
Become a,
become a little dry in.
It's very difficult not to get lured in.
Yup.
It's like you sort of like,
you know,
like I knew it was wrong prior to having
money and I knew so that it wouldn't
work as well.
And then when you said the comfort,
you see the seduction of comfort.
I confess I have some of that too.
And that's why I thank you very much.
That's why that is that there's a
component to this.
I always harp on about whether,
and the only way to engender real
change,
deep change isn't not through,
I don't think he's through analysis and
critique because I think people sort of
know.
I think they know,
but like uh,
for to understand that change is
possible.
I think you have to make people feel
differently.
Yeah.
And like,
you know,
they sort of the antithesis of the
alienation that you just described.
Now there's a moment in any kind of
revolutionary process with where,
yeah,
you're right.
If people don't feel differently than
okay it's gone.
Yes.
So I wonder how,
I mean do you mentioned as well there is
the possibility for mass communication
and there are some seats.
So I was,
one of the things I was trying to do
when I like,
and it was more overly involved in
political conversation is I was trying
to find grand stand flash,
obvious,
blatant,
bland things that people thought,
oh my God,
you could do that.
Like,
and the one things you that group
quarter ad busters.
Okay.
They would sort of say things like
Cuellar Corporation and is there
something about it made me sort of
tingle with excitement is that they
would say identify a corporation there
is not popular dumb a campaign lips of
almost like when we campaigning for
hospitals or on behalf of unions it
sort,
it exists within a million that they
know how to manage.
Like I feel like a target campaign,
there's like our role is we are going to
crash,
collapse,
undermine dissemble apple was a
difficult one because we've all got them
and they're so bloody popular.
We've all got them.
We were all tacked up in it.
Right.
But like get it.
Do you see like that there could be like
the these ideas or is there any
potential for that?
I'd like to introduce these kinds of
ideas are like in it cause it's hard for
me to look at Google and Amazon with
animosity or you know like even though I
know why don't they pay their taxes?
Why won't you know it?
Because I like those logos,
those brands and those stories that
convenience,
the comfort.
It's so seductive.
David,
how do you like,
you know,
like people went,
like when I talked to black cab drivers,
you know,
and like,
and so I'm like,
yeah buddy.
Yeah.
One of the few ways that working people
can have an on his job and then like,
you know,
Uber,
so creepingly convenient,
right?
What do we do?
How do you ask people,
you know,
like how do you get people to change the
way they see the world without some sort
of different vehicle into their hearts?
Well,
you can
boycott is better or something like
that.
Uh,
that would be an interesting way.
In fact,
they did get boycott in New York City.
It was very interesting.
Yeah.
Uh,
it was a day when a trump declared the
no Muslims are allowed from those
countries and they'll,
everybody's rushing out to the Kennedy
airport to sort of,
you know,
lawyers and all this kind of stuff for
turning up there.
And,
uh,
the regular cab drivers,
went on strike for an hour.
So I actually arrived at Kennedy airport
where,
I mean,
they,
all this was happening.
I was impossible to get out because like
the cab drivers.
But Uber broke the strike and Aruba came
in the next day,
uh,
social media was of out of says boycott
uber next day Uber lost half its
passengers because,
cause I,
cause I undermined the cab drivers
striker,
uh,
over the immigrant population.
And I thought it was very interesting
but that,
that,
that happened.
So there is the,
there are ways to go with it.
So the communities with their eyes
illustrate
these points.
I think sometimes these symbolic things
are very important and that I am all in
favor of,
you know,
any kind of symbolic action.
I mean,
I think the occupy movement was a
symbolic movement and I think it,
it actually changed the discourse about
inequality,
uh,
introduced the concept of the 1% and
everybody I was down at.
And so we are,
a lot of people were in the occupy
movement and so it was a terrible,
terrible failure.
And he said,
no,
it wasn't a fire.
I mean it did some things which were
terribly important too soon to tell.
They say,
yeah,
right.
I May,
I may I run through like a,
the proper questions myself and make
sure that we've covered everything
because you're so fascinating.
Well,
no,
I'm enjoying it too,
so,
yeah.
Yeah.
I love,
we love Pricer Marx's capital.
One of the most important text in the
modern era changed the destiny of
countries' politics.
People across the world.
What are its key arguments?
We better pick that up.
I feel that we carry a pair,
but you think we've covered that?
Yeah,
I think we all have and that there was
about this,
about commodification is about
accumulation of capital,
circulation of capital and how it has to
grow and technological change and
dynamism and all of that understood
that.
Do his ideas,
the ideas if that's capital of capsule
continue to resonate today and if so,
what do they still offer?
Well,
I wish we talked about that too because
we said,
you know,
capital is more prevalent around the
world now and it was back then.
So in some ways marks is more important
now because the terrain on which it
operates is much bigger.
That socialism,
Marxism,
communism definitely done that.
Considering the degree to which
technological,
economic and industrial changes occurred
in the last hundred and 50 years,
how might marks his analysis and its
application need to be modified.
You want to do it a little bit more of
that?
I think that the answer to it is not
much.
Uh,
it's very accurate.
It's a good,
no,
the thing is that Marx,
yeah,
Marx wrote a lot about what was going on
in the 19th century and that's dated
what he's writing about,
what he's writing about capital is
writing about a system which still
exists,
which is even more powerful now.
It wasn't his day,
so possibly we can now see how it's laid
out.
We got bloody,
Oh,
he said that was going to happen.
Now there are some aspects,
uh,
the,
the marks never got around to finishing
doing on,
for example,
finance and the role of finance where he
read that,
he wrote some very fascinating stuff,
but he never completed it.
But we need to do that right now because
the financial question is a much bigger
question now than it was in his day.
Yes.
Thank you.
Your work is said to be appreciated by
Anna Case and the outcome and the occupy
movement as much as it is by Linden is
party organizers.
Why'd you think miss is?
I have no idea and you should ask them.
Yeah,
that's right.
Well done with not being vain.
You should've put that question in their
cow that makes us look sycophantic or
cross that out.
Right.
I believe in the shadow.
It makes us look how authentic.
How has your anthropological and
geographical background informed your
teaching of marks?
That's really good.
Yeah.
I want to know that it's actually,
it's,
it's a,
I mean I,
I have a,
I call a different take on mark's taught
our people and the is a m prime,
not primarily interested in mark's.
I'm primarily interested in
urbanization,
uneven geographical development at world
scale,
a local scale and things of that kind.
And I,
and I,
the only thing I like about marks is it
helps me understand all of that.
Now when there's somebody in marks,
it doesn't help me understand or that I
kind of push it to one side and say kind
of,
I think this is probably a useless bit
of marks.
My religion,
I'm very much about,
I'm very much about mark's a as a,
as a practical guide rather than as a
grand theory Tisha and who's a pure
theory got fest.
And so I uh,
I can't because you come from different
disciplines in anthropology and
geography are right now.
And thank God I'm not an economist.
Yeah.
That stuff's boring isn't it?
And it's a made up and it's not a
science and he's all just pretend.
Now what about,
um,
I like that breakfast thing that they
say,
where's your breakfast come from as good
in it?
Like,
cause you said no,
these beans.
So it's probably been prevail and like
that.
A cold,
no,
it's all sorts has gone on.
Put your fit mind the cocoa pop where to
sugar come from?
Yeah.
Titan Lyle,
that capital of Rab scallions.
When trust as far as I could from,
I still got the whip marks in their
hands.
So it's been,
it's been said,
we are entering a post capitalist era.
Do we still live in the country side?
How can I say one just after,
of course we do.
It's got worse than ever.
Always something that's worse than
capitalism.
Maybe some sort of terrible,
terrible behemoth.
Some sidewalks.
I'm horrible monsters.
Always pretty horrible monster size,
so it's,
it's a monster that has some good
effects.
Sometimes beyonce,
I don't know.
Quickbase complying with beyonce.
Will the current system ultimately
proved to be fatal to us?
I wish
could say yes,
but the trouble is the capital can
continue under the most dire conditions
if people don't change it.
And I thought,
what's the point that people who have
got to change it because I ain't going
to change because I ain't going to
change it.
Resounded Gourd.
Right,
and I have to change.
What are some of the main contradictions
at the heart cath is we really covered
that with the growth and the dynamism.
Garraffa car believed that they could go
after the,
he does all of these.
The producer,
he's been reading it very hard.
Could you ever love me,
Kara?
Thought,
where are you going?
Really?
What about the argument that says
capitalism's contradictions lead to the
innovations?
They may do it resilient.
That's good.
Where'd you get that from?
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
look,
and there's a lot of reinvention going
on at the capitalism and it's very
useful.
It's very useful.
I mean,
why would we do without velcro and
things like that?
No crowd.
I see an example.
It's trivial things like that.
But on the other hand,
if you're struggling and you've got a
broken arm and you need to fix it up and
he'd wear Velcro,
boy is it good?
Ah,
I said my stuff wanting to cut over
giving.
Given this entire interview,
you write about how cities are both the
heart of capitol and class struggles are
cs.
You rubber has cities of both capital.
He write about how cities are the half
both capital and class struggles.
How am I cities be reorganized in Moss?
Actually just an ecologically saying
ways.
One of
the big projects I think though we've
got to have is how to redesign cities so
that they're much more,
uh,
available to the population where they
count the island nations,
which currently exists to bound urban
life.
And actually it's interesting if you
look at it over the last 30 years,
most of the big movements gone around
the world have been urban movements.
And I gazey park about what happened in,
in Brazil,
uh,
and,
and uh,
2013,
uh,
you know,
so,
and even occupy was a much from a lot of
it was about housing and urban questions
and not about what's going on in the
factory.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
I wonder what that means.
It means that actually the people are as
concerned about the qualities of urban
urban life as they are about the
qualities of a,
their employment.
Yeah.
They've always,
they've always been involved in both,
but one of the things that marks was a
bit of bias towards is he biased towards
production and not necessarily because
the timing is right.
Yeah.
So,
so I would always want to correct that.
Have it in March
perhaps.
Because now the kind of economies in
which these movements were occurring,
there is no longer sort of mass
production in a manner in which there
was men.
Marx was writing now,
okay multiverse.
And in many parts of the world,
the working class in the sense of
factory libraries,
there's disappeared as being central.
And if it's not in China or Bangladesh
and so on,
but uh,
in North America traditional working
class,
it's been much diminished.
Yeah.
He separately say Paul Gilbert was,
he pulled up,
he said,
ah,
land yard of land,
yard class,
the needs of working class.
Really interesting thing we had when
we're doing interviews,
sounds of dance capital capital's we now
call it of course now that d and making
that kicking,
oh,
curly curly have sought sensitive as an
eight crash is Marxism on the rise.
I think there's a much greater interest
in it.
And I think a,
it,
the [inaudible] idea was in the 1990s
when it was very hard to get anybody to
have a look at Alex's capital,
but I think,
uh,
since 2000,
it's,
it's gradually come important.
And then the crisis of 2007 2008 yeah.
Hey,
some of these big arguments against
communism in the 20th century has been
directly responsible for killing 100
million people.
Did it?
Yeah.
This has a lot of things that can be
very negative things,
you know,
religion in and of course mal made a
huge mistake,
which led to the great famine in China.
About 20 million people died focus,
you know?
But,
but on the other hand,
it also saved a lot of lives.
I mean,
the interesting thing about even about
the China case,
when people get mad at me when I say
this,
yeah,
okay,
20 million people probably died in the
famine,
which was unnecessary bad policies and
all that stood on the other hand where
mal came to power life expectancy in
China was 35 and when he died and life
expectancy was 65 so he did something
right as well as,
yes,
I see.
You feel like it's your personal role to
address much of the propagandized
information was taken as
another photo of the public eye on it.
It emphasizes all the negatives and it
never says anything about what the
positives were.
Balanced propaganda.
On the other hand,
I understand one capitalist economies
are based on free exchange.
This is a popular claim of capitalism.
Is that true?
Is it made up?
Well in principle it is,
but in practice a lot of it is monopoly,
power,
monopoly,
power plus even people's and the role of
the consumer and they've been stimulated
into a terrible state of desperation.
Um,
I think we've covered it.
I think this is such a thorough
interview I've done now.
It kinda just before,
I mean not,
not that we let you go,
your continued to be free,
but my mate John Rogers sent me this
thing,
check out this and see if it makes
sense.
Uh,
like a blah blah blah.
I meet out in Malin you in respect of
this project we are hoping you could
speak to Russel about here.
I'm Russell and probably close to his
heart.
This is a number of people in Harringay
have formed a company with the aim of
buying a large bit of land that would
otherwise be sold to a private
developer.
They will want to build loads of
expensive housing and a part of
Harringay Tottenham,
I mean just as call it north London,
it's not antagonize.
Most of the other people in London where
I'm just a big football insights were
local people can't afford them lost
gentrifying the area and kicking out
local people.
What we want to do is build 800 times.
They're all genuinely affordable for
local people and the site controlled by
local people or low,
I could go on,
he says,
but if you need more info you can go to
the websites,
start hiring guide or Co.
Dot.
UK.
We are actually serious about this as a
funny paragraph to put this late in.
Uh,
we've got,
we've got solicitors,
architects,
we've been speaking to the mayor about
blah blah blah blah.
We need to pry pile on pressure and
publicity.
So what do you think about project like
that where essentially I suppose their
project is to have sort of a,
to acquire some land to build 800 times
and sort of govern them.
So again,
he's going to be operating within like a
metropolis that's got other systems of
government aid his heart.
Um,
uh,
you know,
I'd love to know more details.
Like you don't just make snap judgments
like a [inaudible] support,
this kind of thing.
I mean,
in the states we have something called
community land trust,
which takes,
which means that people who are in those
houses can't sell them.
So I don't know whether that's in that
proposal where the people are the
easier,
they can't turn a quick profit on their
host.
So,
so,
uh,
you know,
if,
if people come in and they live there,
then if I leave,
then they just get back what they put in
and I,
there's no kind of speculation on the
land.
So anything of that sort.
I'm in five fiverr off.
Yeah,
people were,
but people have authority and power in
their own lives and the ability to
govern themselves with possible.
But if they,
but we sometimes find in those things
where people look at the situation and
say,
well,
under the rules of the game,
I can't sell and,
but if I could sell,
I could make mega bucks.
So therefore individuals tried to then
turn those collective things into things
where they can speculate and come out.
I mean,
isn't it cause in a way capitalism,
like most and observable phenomena as
somehow sourced from the,
our inner lives of fear,
greed.
Well,
it's partly that,
but then,
you know,
if,
if somebody is living there and I see
that if they could make this better,
turn this back into a market
proposition,
they could make a lot of money out of
it,
then,
you know,
and they got pressing needs,
medical needs or something like that or
well then,
then,
uh,
they want to go market.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
I see.
So
greed and,
and,
and an ideology and so on.
People have real kind of needs.
I suppose that's why you,
uh,
I insistent on there being some kind of
state roles so that there is some sort
of overarching principle.
So legal apparatus there that prevents
them selling out at a market rate.
That's some free advice from David
Harvey that you've got there from you.
And you know,
there are some called Tony [inaudible]
who's a friend of my mate,
John Rogers.
And finally what five books we've got to
read.
It's a terrible,
terrible,
terrible.
Um,
but yeah,
you should get an reading this stuff
from any,
all kinds of different perspectives.
Uh,
and,
and the sorts of things I would so say
is,
uh,
you know,
if you read a clr james on a black
Jacobins,
uh,
you know this,
I mean this is a common understanding.
It's an understanding of marks.
It comes from,
from the colonial experience,
put it that way.
And so anybody is coming from that
background I think would immediately get
sucked into sort of appreciating the
marks is standpoint from that
experience.
I say the same thing about something
Sunday like Silvia Federici who has a
book on Kaliban and the witch and,
and another more recent one called 0.0,
which is about the experience of women
and the whole history of capital
accumulation from the very origins to
two today.
Again,
you know,
people who will get into that and I
would get a person and perspective on
the marks,
his position,
which would come from,
from that.
And then I,
you know,
for a,
a humanist position,
I'd say read Terry Eagleton spoke on,
uh,
why Marx was right.
Uh,
wear marks where he actually goes over
the whole history of,
uh,
of,
of Marxists humanists positions that he
took on,
why he was right and corrects a lot of
the bad propaganda that we've talked
about.
And then I leave for it.
And then I,
then I'd say,
actually,
I'm going to give you a couple of mine.
I think you should.
You should take a this last one,
which is uh,
uh,
yeah,
Marx capital and the madness of economic
reason,
eh,
but then I will it by reading the brief
history of neoliberalism,
which is about the history of capital
accumulation from an 1970s onwards,
but it got out to about 2005 so it was
before the crisis,
whereas the new book has a final chapter
which updates the neo liberalism.
Bocomez happens in neoliberalism since
2005 so I would say,
you know,
you would get into get into things that
wise expedition of learning.
I'm going to start with yours professor.
Thank you so much for coming on the air
for having me.
This has been great.
We did you say I've been great.
Always been great.
All right,
brilliant.
Thanks.
Hey,
we,
why don't we go on?
You read in this monologue from
Shakespeare that you've concluded that's
right out of King John.
How come you saw king John saw King
John?
Because a friend of mine took me there
to listen to it and it's not a great
place.
You're on the other hand,
there's this great speech in the middle
of it.
It goes like this mad world,
mad king's mad composition,
that's smooth face gentlemen tickling
commodity commodity,
the bias of the world,
the world who have itself is pasted well
made to run even upon even ground to
illicit vantage.
This vile drawing by us,
this sway of motion,
this commodity makes it take heed from
all in different see from all direction,
purpose,
course intent and this same bias,
this commodity,
this board,
this broker,
this all changing word and why re ally
on this commodity but for,
because he has not wooed me yet.
Now that I have the power to catch my
hand when his for angels was sort of my
palm but for my hand is an attempted yet
like a poor beggar ray Ellis on the
rich.
Well wiles,
I'm a beggar.
I will rail and say here is no sin but
to be rich and being enriched.
My virtue then shall be to say there is
no vice but beggary since king's break,
faith upon commodity gain be my Lord for
idol worship Thee.
Yes,
it's a great quote.
And of course,
the first line of Marx's Kapital is,
I'll look to me for that.
You're the first line is that the wealth
of the world in which we're looking at
here appears and have greater
accumulation of commodities.
Ri Shakespeare,
Karl Marx,
professor David Harvey,
thank you very much for joining us on
under the skin has been a great
component in a wonderful education for
me to chase.
Thanks mate.