Oh,
very interested in mental health.
Why is that mate?
Are You mad?
I say this,
looking back on your feet?
Um,
I,
I wouldn't have called myself.
I used to have severe,
severe anxiety and depression about 10
years ago and I'm now the anxiety and
depression free for 10 years because of
I've got a rigid mental health system.
I've got to self care system.
Mainly.
I was lucky like I never suffered from
mental illness.
My issue was mental health,
which to me means that my view of
myself,
my view of other people and my view of
the world was excessively negative and
fearful.
Oh,
that's a good definition.
So I just basically tested it.
I wrote,
I read reappraised how I felt about
myself.
I've heard about other people and I do
that on a daily basis and mental health
regime really,
to be honest,
it's no different to exercise.
Could you first of all,
before we hear that,
and I'm sure I'd like to hear what you
do for your sort of,
your regimen for mental health.
Could you describe the depression and
anxiety as you experienced it 10 years
ago?
What was it like,
what did it feel like and how did it
impact your life?
Um,
what have been about 18 or 19?
He,
the thing is my main thing would have
been anxiety and the thing is with
anxiety,
anxiety can result in quite a lot of
shame because my anxiety kept me from
leaving the house,
so I would,
I'd get anxiety attacks in a certain
place like in the pub are in a
supermarket.
So the natural thing for me to do.
Then the logical thing was,
oh,
soup markets given me anxiety attacks,
I can't go there anymore.
But before newest I was kind of stuck in
my room all the time.
Afraid to leave the house in case you
get an anxiety attack that then brings a
ferocious amount.
The shame would it because then I start
judging myself,
going on my friends,
okay,
we'll go into the shop.
What's wrong with me?
That then resulted in depression.
So it's this really shady,
so eager.
And I think the road of my,
like I was just afraid of being an
adult.
I was terrified of being autonomous,
you know,
do,
what would you say you were taking out
the cause and that was going to be my
next question.
I don't know why I want you to know that
that was gonna be my next question.
Like as if I'm psychic,
but was there some sort of trauma would
you say?
Or like what do you think precipitated
it?
I mean I understand this thought,
that cyclical idea of feeling ashamed
and not feeling like you can do with
other people.
I can still get a little bit like that
now as a matter of fact,
but like how does like do.
But I would now relate that to oh this
is because when you were a kid,
this happened and that happened.
Do you have that kind of awareness?
Or like my parents were quite old and
when I was borrowing a fairly bad
asthma,
but my fucking enough for job back on
your fucking.
I know,
yeah.
It says on the plastic,
but I do not put this on your end.
I might add if they were going to put
something out,
especially not if you've got asthma.
Amazing in a very mythic sense,
my mother first to point out because I
want some to.
No,
no,
no one is pointing to that particular
one.
I guess.
Thanks.
Bonding around of applause with
someone's opening up about their
psychological history.
That's the level of narcissism we're
dealing with.
So like your parents were older and you
had asthma.
Very bad asthma and my dad would have
been quite anxious.
He and I can actually trace my father's
anxiety back to the famine.
He,
he learned how to be anxious off his
manner and his men.
I learned how to be anxious.
I've heard Matt who was actually
starving,
so patterns of of anxious behavior and
depressive personality types will pass
through and sort of amazing,
but it makes sense.
It's true.
There will be a generational trauma is
an idea.
You know quite a lot about
psychoanalysis.
Don't you have a degree in it or
something?
I studied,
I did like three or four years training
to be a psychotherapist and then it
stopped so I could wear a bag in my
head.
Brilliant,
good decision.
Good decision.
The psychotherapies last is plastic bags
game,
so we may like,
so would you say that idea of
generational trauma does that you've
just been quite frivolous,
but two ways like there,
there,
there is actual research now being done
into trauma being been passed on
genetically.
They're looking specifically as how
people in the Holocaust and how
genetically trauma is passed on.
Now that's a very new field,
which is quite hard to get your head
around,
but the simple one is behaviors get
passed on.
If you're a young child and you,
you're around.
If your parent is excessively angry or
if you're a parent naturally looks at
things in a negative fashion.
The child knows nothing other than to
look at the parent as the authority of
truth.
So we learn these things,
but the beauty of being the common,
an adult psychotherapy and self help is
that narrative you learn as a child.
Once you to become a fucking adult,
you can go,
Holy Shit,
that's not the way it is.
I can rewrite my script,
so yeah,
for me,
my dad used to.
He found out that I had asthma.
He,
the doctor would have said,
well,
there's a slight chance of death,
but you know,
and then my dad would have ran out of
the hospital going,
oh,
he's going to die.
So when I was about three or four,
if I was to want to play soccer with my
friends,
he would just start going,
no,
you'll die.
Do you know what I mean?
And that was off putting.
Yeah,
it was like,
he,
he man on mark him,
you're going to die.
So me being being four or five,
it's like the adult is telling me I'm
going to die if I do normal things that
my normal friends are doing too.
And it was to protect me.
But then when I got older and normal
thing meant going to fucking school,
going out things that were adult
deepened way unconscious,
it manifested itself as a severe fear of
a debt.
That's good analysis.
Good self analysis.
How Japanese narrativize nation.
There we are on this show.
We upload self awareness kind of new
age.
Um,
but like yeah,
that's,
that's pretty interesting that they
finished in Nevada or isn't.
Do you not think that?
Could be,
in a sense the,
uh,
central definition of adulthood and
ability to control your own narrative to
say,
I am no longer my trauma,
I am no longer my past.
I can recreate myself.
Absolutely.
That is the key to being an adult I
think is like,
it's,
it's first off,
it's understanding the intrinsic value.
Um,
I am no better than anybody else.
Nobody else has better than me because
I've got an intrinsic value that can't
be taken away.
The other thing is to understand that no
aspect of your behavior can define your
value as a person.
So for me will say like my,
my creativity,
like my mental health is very much
attached to my creativity.
If,
if I'm creating,
then chances are I'm in a good mental
place,
you know,
if I'm procrastinating,
that's what I ended up down the anxiety
land.
Do you know what I'm saying?
But for me,
the crucial thing is tonight,
horrible theme park.
Yeah.
Anxiety.
So I,
uh,
I just,
I make sure that my creativity,
like if,
if I released a fucking short story or a
podcast or whatever and it doesn't do
very well,
I have to be very cautious around how
much I beat myself up over that I can't
allow my,
an aspect of my behavior such as
creativity to define my value as a
person,
as important as very interesting because
I,
you know,
as a person that sort of toyed with the
celebrity,
like I find it extremely difficult and
that model that I just described of
attachment eeg with pornography or a
substance misuse,
if I start becoming overly attached yet
even to our list podcast is done well,
this has been unwell.
Then suddenly,
yeah.
Then are googling your name,
Google your name.
Do not
who yourself write up the name.
No good ever.