So your perspective and your motivation
is an optimistic one that you
essentially believe that people that
have extremist beliefs,
however,
those beliefs are resourced,
whether it's a fundament fundamentalism
from an Islamic perspective or ethno
nationalism.
Yeah.
You think that these are almost
temporary few bugs that human beings
passed through,
that they are not essential states as
you said,
that you are interested in in meeting
the human being behind the,
the,
and you believe that human being is more
truthful,
more real,
better than their group identity.
And each of these cases
I do because what I've found in,
in doing all the films that I've done at
this point is the,
the whatever the,
the window do I always call it sort of
window dressing or whatever the brand is
that might be different,
you know?
So on the surface of it,
it's going to look different to most
people when it comes to a jihadi versus
a neo Nazi.
Well,
these are completely opposing
ideologies,
completely different people and
therefore should be treated completely
differently.
But what I found is that the type of men
that are attracted to these movements
and the type of vulnerabilities that
those men possess that are being preyed
upon by people in a position to misuse
whatever vulnerabilities that these men
have for their own political gains.
Um,
all the same,
the psychological,
the emotional,
the social makeup of the,
the guys across the spectrum.
I have found actually to be really,
really similar,
whether it's,
you know,
a matter of,
searching for meaning,
searching for belonging,
searching for a sense of purpose,
searching for a brotherhood,
camaraderie,
searching for just a way of coping with
a very,
you know,
quickly changing world,
um,
finding themselves to be insignificant,
powerless.
Yeah.
And then you have recruiters and you
have these movements that are filling
those voids actively and cynically
actually filling those voids,
not by accident,
but actually by design.
And I find that really troubling.
But I also find that quite hopeful.
Um,
because I think that these basic human
needs,
I mean,
I am searching and have been searching
for all of these things that I've just
listed as well.
You know,
it's just,
it manifests itself different for me
than it does for these guys.
And it's just for me,
it's a matter of figuring out how do we
satisfy these,
these needs for young people?
How do we satisfy and address these
vulnerabilities that that young people
have?
And also how do we confront the feelings
of shame and humiliation and
powerlessness that so many people feel
before they become instrumentalized by
our politicians and by populism.
So you found a group regardless of yeah.
How it superficially polarized the group
identities
of white supremacists or jihadist may
seem that there's a kind of uniformity.
Absolutely.
So,
absolutely.
Because,
because the,
the,
these movements are meeting these young
men,
predominantly men.
I mean,
obviously there are some women that
that's important.
I do,
I think gender is a tremendous part of
this.
I think,
I think a sense of masculinity or a
sense of sort of toxic masculinity I
think is absolutely,
absolutely essential to this,
to both movements or to any kind of
extremist movement.
Um,
and I think that's also systematically
overlooked.
I think the way that our media addresses
extremists,
and I think the way that all politicians
address extremism in,
in general,
I think is not very helpful.
They constantly want to make it
something exotic,
something so impossible and monstrous
because surely we can't do anything
about this.
These people are just hideous.
They possess these hideous views and
less just sign them all off.
And that's not the truth.
The truth is they're all operating out
of really basic needs and those needs
are not being met in their life,
in their immediate family life,
or in the wider society.
That says more about us as a society
than it does about these men.
And so I'm interested in that.
I'm interested in,
in,
in finding an excavating what those
needs are,
what those vulnerabilities are,
look extremists of any kind of stripe
and,
um,
any form flourishes in,
in vacuums,
right?
So you have Hamas and his wool line.
All these kind of,
you know,
big names that we've heard of.
They provide in,
in circumstances and environments where
social services do not exist.
Education does not,
you know,
uh,
does not exist.
Uh,
uh,
healthcare does not exist.
They are filling those voids.
So whether it's political voids,
it is economic voice,
or it is social and emotional and
psychological voids in the lives of
people.
These extremist groups,
whatever their brand is,
are fulfilling those,
knowing what these lax and these voids
are in people's lives.
So why do they know that while they
doing that,
and we are not,
why is our political system not
addressing the social and economic and
the political grievances that our young
people have?
Yes,
it does.
And again,
it doesn't excuse the way that they're
choosing to express that.
I think we can say at the beginning that
no one's is seeking to excuse the
behavior of extreme.
Yes.