[inaudible]
not under the skin with Russell brand.
My guest today is Frankie Boyle.
Frankie,
I'm really,
really happy to have you on the show.
I love you a bit.
I think I told you in our email exchange
that I saw a sensitivity in you that
much belied and contradicted your public
persona even when you were sort of more
[inaudible] than me in the public
sphere.
I thought there's something about that
man is incredibly sensitive and tender,
so this is a suppose and disarming
introduction is what I'm doing I think.
I think it's pretty close to see who's
most of telephone from the head by head.
Yeah.
I know with both had our fair share.
Heavenly of public vilification.
How do you do,
do you feel like that you,
now that you're back on,
I mean do you still consider yourself to
be back in the mainstream television?
Not me.
No,
not taller.
Considered myself to be like less secure
than ever.
What did you mean that emotionally and
personally or professionally or both but
also professionally you just sort of
think the minute you're kind of out and
doing stuff in a very can amend stream
field,
the minute you step out say what's
acceptable,
you would just be completely destroyed.
So I feel like I'm kind of dancing on
the edge of a cliff or bet you feel that
day when you're doing something like the
autopsy or tv autopsy your are you
centering yourself?
Cause I had it for example,
that monologue you did about threes in
May on in fact a cliff edge and the
gail,
I thought one of the things I've had,
my bad,
you're right in is the poetry and your
succinctness it conjuring images that
are humorous.
I potent and I've sort of thing.
Oh that will stick.
That'll bark people that that has been
said about him but now you do you find,
are you centering the saying you're
dancing on a cliff edge,
do you feel it was that self censorship?
I don't do it,
but like there does it for me usually
and a out like writing for the Guardian
as well.
It just ended up being like a real
horrific,
just trying to get prey common or garden
stuff in there because I think if the
education can education system can uh,
please select for conformity.
You know,
that idea that you know,
by the time you reached the top in any
institution,
you've already gone through so many pre
selections for your conformist while you
fill in the test where you turn up to
skill every day,
that everybody's a conformist,
where like sometimes in entertainment I
think that can appease leg for neurosis.
So like if you're kinda going through
several peoples what he's about,
what other people might think,
and by the time you were scrapped riches
and they're just kind of freaking out
about nothing.
Yes,
I think you're right about that.
But there is a degree of neuroses and
indeed sensitivity that is deeply
prohibitive.
But there's so about like the
creative process that is,
it requires like a connection to what
you actually believe.
When we were corresponding for a little
while and email like I'm member,
we talked briefly about the idea,
like my somewhat more romantic idea of
the comedian is shaman and like
accessing new realms of consciousness.
And you said something about,
um,
that there was something about that,
about describing of a world that you
felt was somewhat dangerous and that
what needed to be done with the frosted
describe accurately the world are
actually in.
Was that just the past in Forza
philosophy?
Philosophical mainstay?
Yeah,
totally.
I mean,
I,
I think there's,
in some of the most interesting ideas,
there's a lot of,
um,
there's a lot of danger isn't there?
The,
you know,
shamanism and,
um,
particularly quite shamans.
There's a lot of kind of,
Eh,
how'd you mean?
There's that whole thing of like
cultural erasure and stuff like that.
And us just being at that as we see it
at the top of some tree where every,
every idea in existence is part of our
mid board for our personal philosophy.
Can,
it dictates against them
the standard stuff.
So do you mean white there as a synonym
for power?
That it was sort of like a there that we
are,
we are selecting for like all culture is
a mood board from which were selected
strands and obfuscating or ignoring
their cultural origins.
Yeah.
I almost think you don't need to use
white as a synonym for power justice.
It's a Nim.
Yeah.
Ah,
yeah.
I see this interesting thing with it at
the minute and we're no,
some people talking about Ah,
you know,
you don't,
you're not white privilege doesn't
really exist.
You know what if you're,
you know,
a white guy who was born in this century
action and all that kind of stuff and
you think the thing about real
oppression is those people don't need to
fantasize.
You know,
if you really oppressed to that whole
thing of like,
you know,
you get that from,
from white people,
particularly white people was a platform
and they're sort of going,
well,
what if it's a paralyzed white guy and
he works for Oprah?
You know,
you just know like,
Whoa,
if you know,
if you were black,
you wouldn't need to make a fantasy to
have your depression.
I know you would just go out on the
weekend.
I started the taxi,
you know,
I'm an empty white,
white people come up with imaginary
oppresses like the Illuminati and you
know,
we've got to,
we've got to create something because we
don't,
we don't have it in the same way.
Is your general worldview optimistic?
Frankie?
What's that happened to you after like
working in media fire don't for maybe
it's 15 years.
Is it that you've been doing this kind
of stuff like that it still feel
positive and optimistic about change?
I think you solved domestic but most
people heat in it would think it's
incredibly depressing.
It was mistake.
I could lay it on you quick quickly.
[inaudible] I think like um,
maybe a whole reality is like a math for
a and the materialism and
commodification are mine.
Keynes way of trying to express in
metaphor the fact we are trapped in
motto that we are sped.
It now has to live in Martin and die and
go through all that kind of stuff and
perhaps the,
perhaps the actual facts of life is
we've constructed it.
I simply sort of metaphoric responds to
that.
And there's some people may think that's
incredibly depressing bias.
I think of it like when I was a teacher,
I did teach her training for bet.
It was an alcoholic.
I remember like seeing my arm writing on
a chalkboard one day and thinking,
Oh fuck,
I'm a teacher,
my teachers and I almost had an body
experience and could see myself doing
this thing that's,
I've got to,
I've got to go to this job.
You know?
And that's when I started doing comedy
and I almost think,
oh,
metaphor of existence,
materialism is sort unsurvivable that we
have to go over it.
That was sort of almost half to
transcend mater.
So I think that's a really positive
thing.
Yes,
yes,
I understand.
So in this sort of transcend ben or
moment there at the chalkboard art
teacher training,
you add a pithany,
which I've heard described as the
revelation of essence.
Suddenly the essence becomes plain tee.
They all know that that's a teacher's
arm.
I'll know it's all.
So Maya on where they are one and the
same thing.
I liked this idea,
the on some level we are conscious that
we are spirit traps in Matt and
materialism is merely the metaphorical
expression of this.
One of the things that I get
continually,
um,
what I want to say,
frustrated by irritate by an almost,
I'm on the,
uh,
on the precipice of a hysterical toddler
tantrum about is that invoke comments.
The left lacks a kind of mythic
imagination that in opposing austerity
there's a kind of an austerity of a
room.
I would want to say vision that it seems
sometimes a little bit flat and a little
bit droning the for me,
if,
if we're just talking about your
transactions between bureaucracies and
different type of imagination,
then what is the point?
I want some vivid,
lucid dream.
I want people to talk about different
realms.
I want basically to take Ios Iosk and
experience machine elves dabbling with
layers of reality,
but I can't drink or take drugs.
So I caught so it's no longer open to
me.
Black.
I agree.
Birds,
there's also this thing for,
it's like sometimes that slightly
humorless leftist thing also turns
itself to critique.
Oh the other people's attempts to find
narratives and metaphors and things that
resonate with people.
So it's okay to be boring but to sit
there and go,
I didn't like that one.
Well we don't just try it.
I think metaphors can be incredibly
powerful site in the 1968 riots in
France.
That was partly to do with society of
the spectacle and get the ball and all
his slogans were choked on the walls and
stuff like that
just exploded because you do know a bit
more about that cause I'm into that.
I think that [inaudible] I'm into him
cause he said one thing I read about him
the other day was saying that the media
and technology at south deeply
corporatized the old data within it is
necessarily imbued with,
it's your agenda and you can see that in
social media that even if people are
sort of going,
hey that's me in this square and riot,
the an advert for trainers may very well
accompany and the he's,
he's procube age than the medium is
prohibited by its origins and by its
ownership.
So has it.
Hazel was saying was like this bag,
the cool,
um,
as you know,
when it says just the site that you can
escape the spectical so every ton,
and even that's what we're doing,
talk hummus is high in this back corner.
Podcasters book ended by adverts.
He would love that.
Yeah.
He signed that.
They'd be,
it's inescapable that our role while
we're at work,
we are workers when we're at home with
consumers with designated roles that
prevent us from having an authentic
interaction with reality,
an authentic experience of ourselves.
So don't you like it?
It's interesting for me to watch from
the outside how your role at least
externally just as a fan and a consumer
of your work is like,
it seemed like,
oh,
frankie boyle initially is this mood
like sort of a fella.
There's making shocking joke working
class Scottish person making sort of
pre,
uh,
would want to say,
see hearing jokes,
sacred cows to topics and all that.
And that seems to be a reemergence of
political commentary,
uh,
as a sensitivity and an a real depth of
analysis and deep cultural understanding
of you.
On the gone,
some sort of personal epiphany,
or have you always been like this and
just felt emboldened more recently to
express yourself more truthfully?
Oh,
I think I've always been like late us,
but it's like you will never see little
fragments of it slit most people,
if we think about how we relate to
things,
so I was reading an article yesterday or
start to read an article by Roger
mcguinn turf.
So,
so regimen golfs on the Guardian website
as I fucking hate vagifem of golf.
And I started to redesign a call and I
thought to myself,
wait a minute,
what should I actually been to this guy?
And I think it seemed like reading some
poems on a children's show 20 years ago,
if I was totally honest with myself,
just so dead.
It isn't an intellectual exercise.
I didn't like his glasses and he seemed
a bit smug.
That's sort of the level that most
people relate to you.
And to be honest,
if you ask most people to relate to you
more than that,
you're a bit of an egotist and people
are perfectly,
it's perfectly fine that they can hear
one joke they don't like and hear you.
I'm quit don't with that.
Right.
But you know,
I've always done like political stand
up.
It's just like people tend to take it
one way or another.
I don't see,
you didn't choose whether his edits and
they show the best thing.
Yeah.
Wow.
So you don't think that you have
essentially change?
Do you think you've been categorized and
pieced together differently?
There was a time where it was convenient
there for,
it was frankie boyle,
shocking comic and now it's convenient
because everyone's a bit more bruised
and anxious to have frankie boyle voice
of uh,
the off authentic voice of the people.
Well,
maybe I think everybody matures as bad,
but there's,
I mean there's also that thing of,
I think I do tasteless stuff other than
kind of like offensive stuff.
So it's the idea of like the
distinction.
What would it,
what would it be?
Late we say civility because civility is
a bit of a bore really now it's fine.
That bet.
When I first meet people of getting
beyond the niceties to be Beva can a
chore and then use it later.
Passenger are you doing,
you know,
um,
and I think in society we have that as
well.
But part of the problem is if you're a
comedian and you've got working class
background,
you've got regional accent and you're
dealing with tastelessness taste is a
social marker.
Is he cute?
This is the main social marketing brand.
So then immediately it's like,
oh,
you're just didn't fucking jokes and the
Jimmy savile or you know,
and you're like,
well I'm not really,
but that's all you can hear.
And I'm sort of time Messiah.
I don't really need the people who,
who can get it to come to the shores.
So you'll say,
and again that that's about like forms
of taxonomy.
That is it,
because like if you make a joke about
Jimmy savile row in a particular accent,
they won't be seen.
Same way as if that,
that same joke was made in a different
accent where we are.
This is interesting cultural critique
review.
It's just,
oh,
that's crass.
And Bolga did you ever see them
documentaries,
Grayson Perry done about taste and class
and it was actually exemplified
brilliantly the point that you've just
made because class is quiet class and
taste.
I suppose whilst they're systems of
categorization,
there's a tendency from be a bit or more
first like,
well he sort of said like,
uh,
you know,
it was,
it was a rough,
you know,
in some ways it was reductive,
Barbara,
but it was really articulate and clear
for as far as I could see,
like you been lucky in working class
communities,
uh,
Welfare's exhibit it.
So like,
you know,
you get Larry Tattoos,
Goldie loud,
noisy cars where materialism has to be
expressed because necessarily because of
scarcity middleclass it gets sort of
like,
you know,
it becomes more sophisticated.
The coat and the signals become more
discreet.
It was talking to interior design,
fashion,
all of those things.
And then you send an f class.
People were just like,
dress like I'll ratbags new motto of
Tech.
Like he was sort of like a polo
mattress.
I make everyone come in some bad old
Volvo or Jim Morris miners with bits of
wood on them and like,
you know,
they were proper,
proper loaded.
And if I see an interesting that,
cause what you know,
that taste is sort of the art of the
every day,
the stuff that you're wearing,
the way that you decorate your house.
Hey,
a great story.
He went around and he's like working
costs woman's house and it was like,
Oh look a these horse brassieres and
this poor things I need.
It was a very goldie and elegant,
beautiful.
So kitsch display of taste.
And if anybody was interesting how it
was an almost exact like how you could
move,
oh this is an interesting marker.
This is real.
You can use it as a barometer is
legitimize me is genuine.
Yeah.
I mean I that's interesting.
Must Watch that.
Um,
I think is w as well.
There's a kind of further stage two,
which is if you middle class,
the only the only people who can really
impress other people with purchasing
power or really poor people and really
rich people.
You know as if you really pair,
you get a nice car and if you really
brought you get and your and your,
your social group or impressed.
If you middle class people would pretty
much,
you know,
in a place where they can only express
themselves through the test.
So you taste becomes incredibly
important.
And I think when you align that with the
fact that we didn't necessarily,
but it's very difficult to live morally.
So if my taxes are going to bomb sedia
tomorrow,
if my taxes are going to lakeview slide
front page of the times to the nacs
death squad,
you know how you I live a moral life or
maybe it's to my tastes.
You may want to pay lower taxes,
but how on earth are we to fund our sas?
That's exactly what you want.
Correct.
Sas Dead Scott.
No,
you're right.
Good.
I do a fair enough.
You're quite right now,
but I wonder how that relates to what
you were saying about materialism and an
endless commodification and the fact
that you know,
like you're right,
we sit here and we make this pot of
podcasts now.
Autodidacts though we may be,
we're evidently adept at pontificating
and doing it as you know,
in some cases on some occasions though,
not this one for a hunt,
some living here by like where,
where is it that,
where are you resourcing your sense of
purpose now?
What is it that you won?
What is it that you want to do as a
comic?
Cause like,
uh,
one of the things is I still believe in,
I do believe in the possibility of
change.
I believe in a evangelist sees him.
I believe that you can enthuse people
probably in ways that a rather
dangerous.
In fact,
when I was just interview Noemi Klein
there,
she went,
you're this part of bloody problem.
Yeah.
You Miss Lunatic.
Well I said,
I think I was struck by this thing at
rate and a grant,
Morrison comic musical one good mine can
make a difference.
Was it just the end of the story
archive.
So I don't think I'm trying to
evangelize to people in general.
It's just that thing of if you do
something and test in that has meaning
to,
it can be that one person I could not
watch and things like Alex Cox is say
video or maybe drama or whatever you
called it.
What did he just show his favorite
movies and BBC two but she wouldn't even
get that kind of thing now.
But like just just things like that had
a big impact on how I see the world,
you know?
And if you can change how one person
sees the white old not might've been off
I suppose.
So I mean if we don't really understand
the true nature of being there so or off
the manifest world,
I'm I suppose to sort of even to suggest
that there is a global narrative that we
can interact with an intersect with
Ralph for them.
Sort of endless,
infinite subjectivities,
all tangled up and occasional narrative.
Fritz memetically sleeping across the
Internet.
But I don't know.
I suppose like when you find it,
you know when you get an interview bio
and Jones,
a person who has a much clearer,
I like,
I mean and like I said,
have a clearer idea of narrative to sort
of a traditional idea.
In terms of respect of the left,
how do you think like someone like you
that's talking about talking about the
spectacle took her out in the nature of
consciousness,
talking about that sort of like,
sometimes you sound a little bit
nihilistic if I may say so.
I think nihilism is quite a positive
thing is it?
Yeah,
go on.
Starts off is like existential nihilism
of going well.
You know,
there's,
there's nothing else you might as well
make.
This is as good as you can,
you know?
So it's a kind of a branch or
existential ism.
Originally I think it's only since the
90s whatever that people have started to
see it as a death cult.
Hmm.
Because it becomes a bit decadent and
had any stick,
oh well there's no purpose.
Why as we'll stick this out and Obama
and kick that falls over.
Yeah.
I think as well,
you have to be careful about saying,
let's have a narrative and let's have a,
a thing where we,
this is a thing we're like,
Eh,
Alan Mirror the comic book rate,
I'll talks about m r is propaganda for a
state of mind is really [inaudible]
cool.
Yeah,
it's cool.
But at the same time you've got to be
careful with that because who do you
propagandize too?
You don't propagandize Tutti calls.
It's not persuasion.
It places you in a [inaudible] of a week
and a design a narrative that you know,
poor people are going to fan too.
And this is gonna make the world bear.
And the thing with that is people can
see it if you don't,
if you don't approach it from a
possession of equality and going,
well,
how can I help?
Then you know,
you're,
you're suddenly putting yourself in a
hierarchical possession of hey,
that create a story that's going to
work,
which is what most political parties are
doing and what most really politically
motivated commentators are doing.
And I always,
I think people see that.
People see that you're trying politicize
things.
I say I'm a bit grandiose of course.
So like I'm always thinking,
oh,
I've got some letter about like,
I don't know Frankie,
if it feels like it's an essential part
of me,
I say sometimes to my counselor.
Like I know it's much of what I do is
driven by ego.
I know it is,
but it's not only that,
there's something else there is,
I admit that there's the ego.
I admit it.
There's the grandiosity I've met,
I want the adulation.
And in the past I wanted this more
audit,
uh,
all vs anatomical manifestations,
carnal manifestations.
But like all of,
of all of these,
I have now been stripped,
stripped,
and landed in domestic city and don't
think I've ever been happier than being
a father and a partner in a recognizable
sort of way,
but still this yearning.
But it seems to me to be not perhaps
these systems of categorization and
these delineations are also arbitrary,
but seems to be more than he goes.
Super Ego,
Ego plus something of the mistake,
something of the magical,
something that I'm still craving.
I think you'd find this reductive or
nihilistic,
but it's not,
I think this is a good thing,
you know,
like David Eick cool side too,
right?
So like David Dykes,
so beer in a minute.
Do you know you need things like,
because a lot of people are less,
it's a lot of various people in power
and sort of country western singers for
somebody who's in our lessons,
right?
I see.
Like David dykes kind of like a
religious figure.
So he's like a guy who's had a religious
experience,
but it's a goalkeeper.
Right?
So you can,
he frames it in a particular way.
I'm an,
it's kind of like the guy who wrote the
Bible has to believe the metaphor is
real.
Yeah.
So like that's why it has its power of
David date has to believe like the,
not ramp tales,
but it's a good way of thinking of them
because they'd behave like red tail.
That's right.
And he does have to,
as you say,
because I like you,
you've met everyday,
like haven't you?
Yeah.
We,
we,
I,
I've named several times and I,
you know,
I'm obviously fascinated by David dike.
There's that,
like,
I so much voices,
I mean he preempted to hold off the off
the knee like zones of things that he
said we're going to happen.
It's not,
not,
there's not mince words,
pedophile rings,
you know,
like David,
I've said this all be it within the
entertainment industry.
That's he swept paid.
If I run it,
it runs deep people in children's homes
right now.
But yeah,
admittedly that was book ended with a
love of lovely stuff about lizards.
But like I agree with what you're saying
is that he's almost like unconscious
metaphor labor.
Cause because David Eick you've pushed,
we've got,
no,
it's funny,
but see,
I think that maybe the messianic thing
isn't that,
so you have to understand that as a kind
of,
oh I can totally change the world by
doing this,
but to have an actual effect on whatever
as a few thousand people that you
energize.
Like you have to believe that to be
true.
Like A,
like a like go see if Hitler suddenly
had there sort of a moment of going,
oh no,
this is mental.
I'm not Hitler.
It'd be meant to be metaphorical.
He's like,
no.
Can you see the death camp that they are
a bridge too far for you?
Come for all tying.
Let Nick Crow politics played to kill
it.
We've built one.
Oh No,
no,
but perhaps he had a frankie boyle
moment of looking at his own sieg
heiling hand and like you writing on a
chalkboard.
I haven't hit La.
What have I done to myself?
You have to believe them.
You know?
Do you have to take the metaphor out of
it?
It has to be absolute and real.
Yeah,
we're not,
we're not sure.
We spoke to David [inaudible].
I am loved so many of the stories and I
love,
like some of them are well vivid.
If you read some of the ones where it's
like Hillary Clinton and going down on
someone and all of this,
can you fit?
Oh Man.
Y'All could go in for this stuff.
You rental it.
The Queen
Mother tongue isn't at giant [inaudible]
laser.
[inaudible] there's one that what she
like changes in the SPEC quite lizards
and stabs the kid up the arse.
Oh.
And it's like just to start over chat,
go from there.
Where are you going to go?
Never explained,
never complained and had that same catch
phrase.
The Queen Mum never apologize.
Never explained or something like that.
Right.
Well surely you should after you've
taken it.
What?
Bloody Great John Elvino Lizard and
bumped someone.
Particularly if it's an underage person
you couldn't possibly have consented
mom.
Yeah.
Lucky had some rich to some rich,
rich stuff in there.
Some interesting things.
What did it come in and what else did
you,
what did you think when you met him?
And I was like in Portsmith and you've
just seems like a pretty normal dead,
but there's definitely my ad fan had
kindergarten backstage.
A Ne was like talking to me and like
David Aic was stuck behind them in the
corridor looking at me like this bloke's
and nuts.
Let's get away from this Weirdo right
now.
Then the queen mum bombed another kid.
She was a phoenix.
That's one.
Like,
I'm,
yeah,
well I've found fascinating is as like,
you know,
as I say this like,
I wouldn't like to be mean about David.
I was just,
it's so colorful.
Some of this imagery that like when I'm
him,
I was just surprised by actually quite
how,
how sort of ordinary,
he was almost some drum members that we
watched football with him and we went
out of the white right.
And like,
I think it was like a FAA Cup games to
sort of like a couple of championship
level teams and him and his,
no,
no.
They need to be playing a bit wider and
so Saturday drinking tea and being sort
of very ordinary while sat on this,
uh,
you know,
this sort of great volcano of lucid
imagery and powerful mythology.
I think it's like the mundane is hugely
underrated because like,
they've got stuff to sell us all the
time.
Um,
but,
you know,
imagine how much better
honey part would be,
uh,
a comprehensive,
you know,
if it was just a bad kid,
then his teacher,
how many get a bus to the edge of town
to face some demons or some stuff.
I had just all been a real chore
and then having to top up their oyster
cards are much better.
You think that he in the ordinary,
in the real,
there could be somehow more potency.
There's really good.
Then those children's books.
Um,
Alan Gardner,
wheatstone of pressing almond and nine
my right,
there's a trilogy in it.
So first one is called [inaudible] and
they're all,
but he's,
um,
children,
a brother and sister who are fighting
against this watch.
Um,
and you know,
the go through the old maths,
can I say calls Colin?
Challenges like that and it,
and then he'd rates a sod one like of,
it's 30 years later,
just before he dies.
And it's like the boy grown up going to
his therapist and he's not able to
really remember any of it and they just
think he was like nuts as a kid and his
sister disappears at the end of the
second book,
famous watch.
And he just never really finds out
whether she dead there,
whether she does or if he's just lost
his mind.
It sort of normalizes it and it was
great.
It was really good.
Oh,
I'm going to check those out.
I liked that Frankie.
All right,
so let me think about it because I spent
out a little bit while we were talking
about I can,
uh,
became a bit untethered from myself.
So one of the things I had to talk to
you about,
like on sort of a,
perhaps a more or ordinary level,
these moments of disruption that we seem
to be experiencing that they're sort of,
uh,
the terrorism,
the Grenfell Tower,
which you spoke to own Jones about like,
uh,
what do you,
what do you think is revealed by these
events?
What do you think is becoming a parent?
What is becoming manifest?
And it's been previously concealed.
I think people are more widely
recognized and just high letell.
This system that is supposed to
nominally care for them can't even be
bothered to pretend.
And for some reason there seems to be a
deference between a government is
supposed to pretend to care and a
government that can't even be bothered
to pretend the care,
you know?
So the idea that the grand for residents
got their rent,
the doctored this month for example,
you know the idea they could,
they tried to throw them out of their
hotel,
you know,
they're in a holiday inn somewhere and
they tried to split them all up and,
and,
and also there's a can immediate lag.
There isn't no.
So they don't know that.
They can't get away with that anymore.
In the days of social media.
They don't know that they can have a
council meeting.
There isn't film the all because
everybody's got a camera now,
you know.
So there's,
there's a,
there's two things and I think,
which is like social media for which
alone for a long time is seem to be like
quick can it depressing seesaw of good
and bad.
I seems to be like a net gain in protest
movements.
Um,
and,
and just also the fact that we are
really in classes or are way more out of
touch than we'd imagined.
Yes.
I see.
So they sit in a way is like,
is it s a revelationary symbol of joy
that that brings together numerous
Fred's this connection,
total lack of concern.
And then the unawareness in fact of how
quickly things get changed.
I fought,
one of the things that was notable,
uh,
struck me was the,
on the black sort of a Monday or
whenever our,
after the fire Jeremy Corbyn was on tv
going,
you know,
repossess ours is give them luxury flat.
And that would have been a couple of
years ago that would be mental and
visible.
And then by Thursday,
Friday,
that's what's happening.
So there is it almost that there is a,
there is a necessity to respond to a
different kind of uh,
discourse.
It's also just like how it's almost
novelistic,
I mean it's how can have cartoonish and
the whole thing has been so at the head
of housing,
m Kensington and Chelsea,
Eh,
council is a guy called rock fielding
mail and it's going to stay down.
But he's like part of this like honesty,
cratic family who his mother is some
kind of modeled happy who ran a couple
of times and for this party called tree
panning for the national health and try
and persuade everyone to like tree pine
themselves to drill a hole over here.
The drill to hell in a hand to help you
relax.
Yeah.
So she's good taste sons.
One is rock fielding melon.
The can a straight Arrow and then
there's cause cause it,
cosmo fielding malins done several
documentaries about acids and they live
in this like Jacobean Mansion.
Right?
And it has the Breton or maybe the
world's largest gravity phone,
tim.
So it has literally this enormous 300
feet high powerful jet of water shooting
up like 24 hours a day.
The one thing that could have
extinguished is in the grains of has an
ancestral home.
If only there was some way,
some way to control the confrontation,
one eyed man would've needed something
absurd like a gravity defying press
conference over the solution was laying
about in their garden.
And the the straight Arrow is the one
that's called rock melon rock fielding
Mellon.
Amazing.
So yes,
there's,
it's interesting when you talked before
about like perhaps materialism and
commodification being some extraordinary
metaphor for ourselves,
understanding that we are spirit trapped
in matter because more and more I'm
seeing a kind of dumb poetry in current
affairs.
Like so if we're emblems such as the
tower itself and then sort of Ludicrous
sub narratives about fountain is in the
garden as if somehow now the is
appearing
just beneath the veneer of superficial
reality.
But something ulterior is trying to
realize itself,
some dreadful beasts slouching towards
Bethlehem to be born,
but that is there some optimism in this
lucky in,
in events like this on a sort of,
I don't know frankly this deep into the
conversation,
but on a practical level,
do you think that this could precipitate
change?
Absolutely.
And there's loads of things to be
positive about.
Look at the incompetence of your
enemies.
Look at like the tardy carbonate,
like something make or fallen.
I can of living side I sent out to just
sort of saw cup shrapnel or something
and he's just,
you know,
tied onto a bus and driven at the media.
May Cook Golf.
Um,
borders is like there.
I mean they're just,
they're just saying,
who do we,
can we replace this in competent cunt
with a massive cunt?
And all we can do is I can see that
there's cause for optimism there.
What about you on a personal level?
How has it been you,
you all right it happy in there.
You've got love in your life and
children and stuff.
Hey,
I've got children I've been doing in
London doing this TV show on BBC two so
I'm just like,
I'm messing my kids at the moment and
feeling about like how much longer can I
do this?
How long have you had to do so far I've
been here for like months.
Oh really?
What does it,
it makes you feel what?
A little bit disconnected.
Yeah.
And also it just makes,
I think it makes you write in a bit kind
of automatic cars instead of like,
you know,
Oh I really want to say something about
the subject.
You're kind of going to,
I need 10 jokes for this week to try and
get through this thing and get back
home.
Yes.
I say it breaks your relationship or
fucking be grand for a moment.
With the idea of the mute.
My life has changed a lot,
you know,
like sort of,
I felt like when before I would just the
philandering womanizing,
like sort of professional,
loose cannon person,
there was sort of no consequence.
There was a kind of delicious
rootlessness accompany though.
It was with a deep sense of personal
despair.
Over the intervening when we,
a hotel I was in would immediately turn
into sort of a barren multistory car
park bereft of all life bereft of all
light.
It was just the trail of underwear
traipsing out of the door now like they,
you know,
this era is over and I live in,
I mean people I have peace and harmony
and love and all these things that I
sort of never like in it.
For me,
family was a kind of,
uh,
an idea that was nervous about because
of what the connotations that word had
because of the one that I've grown up
with,
you know,
and now I'm learning a kind of a new way
of living and one.
How'd you,
how'd you feel to them and does that
take you away from that?
I don't like when I,
if I go like I'm doing like touring in
an intelligent way,
right?
I do like so free shows a week
and like if I have to stay away,
my girlfriend and my baby and my dog,
all of us go up in a car like traveling.
People might as well have a banjo like
we were sort of like yeah it's a really
good way of doing it because the center,
the nucleus of my life has moved from
this kind of limitless.
We sort of like driven kind of
performance ego goal or they was upset
to you already.
That in itself has been in a woven with
other stuff to oh no I have a home.
I'm a person.
I'm a
great if you can do that man cause I've
just had to stop to them cause I did a
50 date to it or something last time.
I just couldn't handle it.
It's too much
aren't you?
Were away a lot.
And what happened to you
as she used to weigh too much and
there's also like you know the thing you
get at the moment,
there's a lot of criticism of comedians
about Oh you,
you want comedy to be a protected space
and a special place where you can see
nsn and use.
I think it's the fun,
this space away from that in the world.
I mean if I could just stop them fucking
yelling or trying to claim on this stage
are lik explosive sales.
However,
do you know the idea that we have this
aspirational idea of it's a protected
space,
you know,
just cause you need to think that when
you're writing but in practice,
you know,
standing up on afraid and I in Blackburn
to people who've been drinking him and
he stopped drinking it like fucking five
o'clock.
Oh you and your protected space.
Yes.
I see.
And that as a,
aside from that you find it personally
difficult.
Yeah.
D M yeah.
Just find it really hard being away from
home for the amount of time.
And also,
I mean I like the [inaudible] tif didn't
stand up so you write a joke,
he'd go and try it works is in the
shore.
But the idea of then taking that shore
and like a hundred times,
I mean as it gets less relevant to you
in them.
I can't,
I'm never doing it again,
I don't think.
Wow.
Really?
He didn't think could do it again.
No.
My technique,
I think he's all right.
This is three days a week thing.
I was here.
I see how it goes now.
I read both of your biographical books
or other thing your brother said like,
uh,
you're always going to be worried about
something.
Even when you're,
like I said,
always be worried about something.
You're worried about something.
And even if that thing goes okay,
there'll be a new worry.
So basically you're always do white
about some things.
I didn't like that thought very much and
I've had it myself.
Yeah.
A hierarchy of like what is that we have
and all we ever really was replace the
one at the top.
Yep.
Yes.
This is jostling league table of angst.
Do you have some kind of like have you
do think that that sort of dynamic of
you already life,
which seems to have pretty fraught to
me.
So it sounded like it's quite difficult
and obviously you were an alcoholic for
a while or is it the uh,
in,
in this of pop popular style
understanding of the condition will
remain one like that.
You don't drink no more tech drugs of
any kind.
No,
I don't do anything.
No.
Yeah,
me neither.
And let's say like,
what do you like,
how do you find solace?
Have you got some sort of spiritual
program or something?
No.
African across a decadent to work across
the Dixon can catch about your
work.
I,
I don't really get obsessive about it,
but I just do too much or it did more
than makes me happy.
Just that part of that can a Catholic
guilt thing of,
oh,
that's good.
Am I happy?
No,
it did so much.
Might not be that's,
that's what it,
who's supposed to be.
Yes.
All right.
Do you know what you mean by that?
I didn't know how you got lack of vision
for what you want to do.
Does it,
do you see yourself becoming more
involved in like more directly involved
in activism?
Do you see yourself ever wanting to be
in a position of any authority or power?
Does that idea sort of soup simply be
unpleasant here?
Oh No,
it seems incredibly unpleasant.
Uh,
you've heard that thing?
Um,
the once and future king t h wait,
no,
but I mean it's like there's Keds Berkey
but king asa,
but it's like,
it seemed as a 12 year olds or
something.
That's where they took him,
the sod and this door and Cuttin from
and kind of where they took monty python
and the holy grail they expect from it
as well.
But it's all access.
There's fairly jolly can a kid's book
Cubo Eh,
you know,
young arts and meet Marilyn and they,
they,
you know,
the spins and fork stands on a table and
all that kind of stuff.
And then a few chapters,
then we start to get bit darker in
Maryland.
Tons.
I'm into fashion consumer lives lake,
it's a fashion,
he swims around in the mall and he meets
this peak and the peak does this speech
about power and it goes like a love is
just an evolutionary track and their
pleasures the same.
All the rides,
his power and he does this free speech.
Right.
And as I can remember reading that like
12 or something.
But it's just that,
I mean that's the assessment that's
going on and people that want power of
wellness is all their ads control.
Do you believe that?
Still the,
that pike saying that there's only one
emotion and love.
I don't believe it.
I reject it completely.
You believe in love?
Yeah.
Yeah,
totally.
me and not believe in love.
Right.
I remember
planes,
my son one day and he was,
he was pissed off a bone and he was
like,
Oh,
you know,
you don't even like me do you?
Or something like that.
It's,
we're going to bed.
And I was like,
he to step in front of the bill it for
you.
And he was like,
why?
He was just like this what it is very
little cat.
He's maybe three or four at the time.
And you try and explain that or impact
that.
Tim is very difficult.
We're really didn't have an intuitive
understanding of that.
You think of overwhelming love?
I don't think they do.
I mean I think Ted's are quite,
um,
it depends on your bra I suppose.
But selfish little bastards didn't know.
Like this one I've got,
it's only seven months old.
At least just I,
I'm diluting it will.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
and they have that.
They're really centered on themselves
for the first few years aren't there and
then that's like that.
I think it would kill me for amusement.
I don't think there's,
I mean she's glorious and so beautiful
and it's caused me to plumb new fathoms
of love within myself.
But in return I have received little
butt grabbed chest hair and
hair,
but I think the best thing in my life is
that important.
I'm uses my son the most,
is some misfortune be falling me in
margin in me,
frustrated.
Then I'm stuck in some place.
It's like,
what?
What he finds funniest too.
Anytime anything bad happens I think
with,
I tell him this,
I mean he's going to kill himself.
Oh,
he loves it.
Yeah.
He loves nothing more than to hear you
being trounced.
One of them things that you hadn't
started.
Fuck.
He said when he come in here that bloody
Yanis Varoufakis he came in here.
Tell us about the dynamics of path and
you're,
hey guys,
I'm like,
those people,
they've got no power.
There were there,
I've only got power within their
systemic role.
Like even somebody said like wolf gang
shall by the German chancellor.
He said out loud to that Yanis
Varoufakis democracies.
Right.
As long as you don't change anything.
And he was not ever being ironic nor
dismissive or anything.
He just was state in some data,
democracies are right.
As long as it doesn't change anything
and that,
that he within like the,
the,
it was sort of like you answer a fuck,
he said from his flirtation,
we've actual power structures that
people were in,
it would just inhabit in particular
roles.
And these were these,
they knew that.
Okay.
Yeah.
I think we make the mistake sometimes of
going on from that obviously knows a lot
more than me,
but I think I sometimes think we made
the mistake of going on.
So the real power,
it's somewhere else.
The real powers that Ross child's or
wherever,
and the real power is the system,
you know,
the real parents systemic is within the
institutions,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
so you mean it is not a human power,
it's sort of superhuman or on the human?
Yeah.
It's like corporations,
you know,
that idea of,
oh,
we're going to make corporations liable
for things you can,
there's a blueprints for making money.
You need to look at ways of reducing
their power,
you know?
Yeah.
That is actually one of the things that
has come up from talking to people.
Let you know these,
you know,
the s and the Yanis Varoufakis and name
and now yourself is that as long as they
are there,
as long as they are our hubs of power,
centralized power,
it's always going to behave according to
the motif of that pipe.
It's always going to perpetuate and
sustain itself.
So the only way of changing it is to
dismantle it even like it.
So I do think that in like on a personal
level,
are you willing to make big sacrifice?
Do you think the Andy and do you think
that people genuinely generally are?
I mean,
I don't think I need to.
I think it's like there's this,
there's,
there's a kind of equal to that.
You know,
I like that whole thing of lake.
I saw a documentary once to build that
habit,
edge general,
all gays who pin on rocks and they see
something that's really all,
it might be a thousand years old.
And I go,
oh,
I'll just redo the eye,
you know?
And this researcher was seen it,
one of them I want you to not for,
you know,
let's say and I'm antique essentially.
And the guy's like,
no we don't just part of the same gate
in hand that does this.
And I think if you think of yourself as
oh I'm doing the eye,
it's much healthier for you than going,
I'm going to create this thing that
lasts for 2000 years.
Do you know what I mean?
Well it's a very wise,
very wise soul there sat there.
Frankie,
what was that thing I was thinking about
everyday you might like here it is.
What's thinking about them Amanda?
Laws like in other people take ages and
ages to manufacturer them,
right?
Like,
you know,
sort of sit there ages than they are
with the sand and it's bull lake takes a
week and then they just sweep it up.
And like obviously like me as a person
that's likes permanence,
like oh no,
no,
don't,
that was brilliant.
Fuck.
But of course the pop point of it is
Dean Jews.
That feeling cause you can lose your own
body yourself.
Everything's gonna fall apart.
[inaudible] kind old coat that poem you
again.
But that even a thing like
Michelangelo's David,
it's just a temporary thing.
The moment we'll come with,
you know,
so whatever death cult looms up out of
Christianity,
if,
uh,
if the,
if the right demographic becomes poor
enough,
if they rise up against idolatry,
chisel in hand to decide to smash away
the renaissance in the Isis inspired
frenzy.
Like you know,
that the Michelangelo's David is on its
way to destruction and deterioration as
all of our individual bodies are on
their way to destruction and
deterioration and this sort of sense of
oneness.
This idea that this aboriginal aborigine
exhibit eight in our bad just duty,
I,
that's a no,
no revere.
The deer on the rock.
That's that that is a better type of
connection.
But that,
but that idea of a sort of an an it did
indigenous connection beyond our
individual understanding of time and
space.
It's bloody hard to get that out.
There isn't,
it may,
I mean,
but that's not how people are really
looking at the world.
Yeah.
I mean it is incredibly hard.
I think there's always that thing where
like I was quite interested in this idea
for awhile.
Culture is like every resistance to
civilization.
Do you ever had that?
Yeah.
So it's like this isn't my idea,
but it's like the idea is that what we
call coach for now is kind of comes up
in the time of like Fredric [inaudible]
in Germany and it's sort of for,
for what became Germany and it's kind of
to resist the French idea of several
eyes and through institutions.
So you know,
France has all these different academies
of the arts and so on.
And that partly that was a kind of soft
power way of making everything very
French,
you know,
and culture can arise is up to
[inaudible] and I kind of think we're in
a kind of late stage in that know where
part of our problem is we work within
institutions,
try and produce culture.
So the reason it's difficult to do a
stand show on the BBC is that the comedy
clubs,
part of the reason comedy clubs exist is
to resist things like the BBC.
Mr,
go on.
Have you seen that?
Fucking sure you know that part of the,
that's part of the reason for them,
you know?
So,
so where do you go from there?
I mean,
do you democratize institutions or do
you try and dry the clothes institutions
in some way or make them more
representative or something?
But it seems like,
you know,
we'd all stuck in some sense within
institutions that are kind of Pristina's
yes.
As oppose.
So a ref to refer back to that idea that
this,
we have ourselves become
institutionalized.
Who is thinking our thought?
Who is prescribing the stories?
What is it that I'm thinking of when I'm
thinking of myself?
One of the things in our email
correspondence you talked about was,
I can't remember the correct words,
but you talked about the idea of
language being a sort of an effective
agent of virus in the mind.
Talk me through that again.
I like that.
That's nice.
Here's my idea.
So the idea is like Kim,
Eh,
you know what kit toxoplasmosis is a
disease that cats or catch it gives to
mace and it clears tiny little scars in
and may spins,
Eh,
that never heal the,
makes them nice,
behave in an uninhibited way.
So Eh,
when they're on inhabited,
they're more likely to be caught by the
car.
Sort of like toxoplasmosis has a
podocyte seat.
Brainpower piracy performs a function of
changing behavior to mace.
What if language is that for humanity?
So what if language has been seated here
to make us behave,
maybe just behave loader so that we can
be phoned and consumed by some cosmic
entity or maybe it's simply something
that's watch and it makes us more
amusing.
The fact that we're able to relate
through language.
Is it really
beautiful and extraordinary idea?
I like the point of origin that cat
shit,
cavalier mice,
but they go fucking the shit that makes
my submit.
Cocksure buccaneer yeah,
the live fast die young mice population.
And you think that language could is
this is really sort of a quiet,
beautiful,
beautifully complex idea.
This isn't an occupying force because
what is it manifesting all his metaphor,
all this symbol,
what is being expressed?
I mean,
I suppose it,
it denies the supposition that language
is a reference to some deeper essential
self.
It's,
it's,
it is.
It's own vessel made a minute done.
If we get into trouble with trump's skin
linguistics anywhere along the way.
Yeah.
I think Chomsky be on our side on that
thing turns Mckenna and bill for it.
Terence Mckenna and nice,
great pioneers of DMT and Iowaska.
That'd be well up for it.
But chompsky I mean he's a,
he,
he seems quite dour at the best of the
Times.
[inaudible] I like,
uh,
yeah.
Well Russell,
Frankie,
I don't think that that's of plausible
at all.
Like,
if the ice suck,
you suck my life out at deal.
Oh No.
What was my other thing there?
Okay.
This is interesting.
I think he might bring me to the
precipice of my awareness.
So think like,
cause I never lose the tendrils and
threads that are required.
Oh yeah.
Iowaska and DMT Doni above you as a
person in sobriety and recovery,
whoever is you determine your abstinent
lifestyle edge that you can't take our
WESCO cause like you referenced Terence
Mckenna there that grow cosmonaut of the
brain.
Like I listened to those.
I watch youtube seems to borderline
fetishistic Stickley of people talking
about,
you know like the describing their
journeys on dmt and DMT even more than
Ios guy because you smoke in,
it's such an obvious black crack as a
hallucinogen,
but I think,
Oh God,
I can't get away with that.
I can't sell my cell phone.
No,
I'm only doing this for spiritual
reasons of research.
If I find myself with a pipe in my hand
fast,
no good look.
Yeah.
So like are you not fascinated by having
the,
some of these metaphors made literal?
I'm fascinated if you've ever read the
breaking open the head Daniel Pinchbeck.
Yeah,
I liked Daniel Pinchbeck.
I know him.
Do you know what is,
I'm second bit was called go on.
I am quit so quarter.
So he did all this for me that don't
know.
He did other stuff.
Like we experimented with drugs and he's
a really good book.
He talks about,
you know what it's like to take hold of
various,
can I listen to tunes?
But like by the second one he saw,
he was in Mexican guides quiz who
quartile
he crazy cold,
some feathered serpent and some inter
dimensional traveler scarf.
Good job.
I took all these drugs actually cause
I've discovered up quick.
It's a cot.
Oldest a separate thing.
You don't think that was the drugs?
It wasn't quite the court took the drugs
I'm good at.
Yeah.
There's the drive sometime self in the
critical using drugs.
Um,
but like this for me there's something
beautiful about this mystery in the it
people have archetypal experiences.
Well I find that exciting when it works.
That terence Mckenna stuff,
he's holding a minute people to drop in
its acid and their flood plot of
plunging inward into inner myths and the
truths and this syntheses is that the
word we'd like different sense.
He's representing themselves in sort of
different media like you're able to see
visually the zeitgeists trends.
For me that's a sort of a,
that image matrix suggest to me that my
own consciousness is such a tiny
aperture of a total consciousness.
It makes me start remembering my own
experiences and I said,
and it makes you want to do it more.
Yeah.
There's something to be said for that
wipeys.
We get older,
we won't care.
Yeah,
because we like as the material form
disintegrate,
you'll stuffing out of might as well
just like dive within,
let it fall apart.
I knew this girl,
he was on acid every day for a year as a
waitress and she was obviously having a
bad time and eventually she said to the
people running the restaurant,
look,
I've been on like a heavy dose of acid
every day,
and they were like,
you know,
I'm going to leave.
I'm going to go get therapy,
whatever.
And they're like,
don't leave.
You're like the best.
Come on just for your brilliant.
Tell us more about that winged serpent
thing that you are.
Yeah,
lots of it didn't affect her job as well
because like acid,
like the first time I sort of heard of
it was like people at school with them
in it and how can you do score and it's
like,
cause I didn't take it to a couple of
years.
I was like 18 first time I took it and
forgot you can't do this and school like
oh but everything just completely shut
down my whole reality shutdown of love
because my sense of self,
I remember that like in my 18 year old
understanding of what reality was
realizing oh no,
there is no such thing as self.
This is just a composite of biography
and biochemical data and it probably
wouldn't have known where it's like
biochemical data.
But I remember feeling that.
I remember looking at my own anatomy.
Allah,
you and Hitler not done saying good.
The same thing like I,
I'm thinking these hands,
what is this occupant force?
What is this energy?
That's not my thinking but is,
is,
is my consciousness and my anatomical
awareness.
But there seems me that there is some
truth in that.
Some truth in being able to uh,
add,
transcend my conventional ideas of self
and like that sometimes a material life
with its prescription.
It's not that I don't feel wonderful.
Moms are transcendent love,
such as with my little kid and even
decide the l May,
I just went on a bar,
drove that day for 24 hours and a fought
God.
Life can be so different.
I'm a man on a barge.
Obviously I can work.
The bar's probably so I have to keep
getting out and why he didn't through
shallow waters.
You're not mean it though,
but it seemed like such a renunciation
of ordinariness for me to be this bloke
on a boat with a family as much as it
was to be a dad in a loft,
putting the crib up there when a baby
got too big for it.
I'm at that dinner loft.
I'm a man on the board.
There was blood.
The Indian now go to normally around the
corner.
I've called up and got Indian from the
place.
I always get it.
Life hadn't changed that Marshall
wouldn't,
we weren't dances with bloody wolves,
but it just made me realize this life
I'm living,
this is not it.
This is a selection.
This is a confection.
I'm the curator of this reality.
I'm not like a promethium and trapped in
a sick.
He'll call moment.
I kind of any moment abandoned all this.
I remember once you have a girlfriend
going to like,
she goes,
no,
y'all don't like the way you do that
because,
well listen,
let me know because I can let go of any
of this shit for you.
None of this is real.
I was just flung this together on the
off to get myself out of where I was to
where I wanted to go.
Let me know what you don't like this
gone.
So I've been absolutely denounced the
ECENTRA south.
That's great man.
You're not bow hex thing about um,
Eh,
we all one consciousness experience in
itself subject.
Well,
yeah,
I keep wanting to say it and then by
every time I go to say it on the stage
before big Cavaday,
I don't say that Russell,
that's Bill Hicks.
I'm actually just say that now because
that is one of your favorite bill Hicks
space.
But he's like,
because it's so true.
I keep arriving at it while like while
riffing,
it hangs above my,
a toilet in my bedroom.
Picture poet x.
But that cool.
This is live at my publisher gave me is
what he would do his point.
He would have one too.
Have you ever told you that thing?
A bit.
Gay told me I should go hex for these
invasive but comedy,
no,
go on.
So it was like,
call me.
Do you know Tom Rhodes?
No,
he's not an American guy who I met
bizarrely on nine 11 and our Gig got
canceled or in Dublin,
but eh,
Tom and wrong.
I choose when he did it off.
Now I'm that,
but we were there.
Um,
eh.
He said,
Eh,
he met biohacks when he was blake
plainly the texts they suck or whatever
he was at the time when he was like a
really young guy and he's,
he pastored bell hacks for his advice
over a couple of nights and biohacks hex
eventually said,
look,
if you want to notice decrees,
always be nice to the new guy.
And for a few years I thought,
oh,
he's having a joke,
Tom,
you know he's going to in the new guy,
pester me and I'm being nice by fobbing
you off with us.
But now I kinda think in this better
have been now,
but engineer working on the eye that has
kind of a bike that is realizing that
you are not the be all and end all.
There's the next generation along from
that and the next generation along for
my,
and you're just,
you're just filling in a little,
you know,
stuff on this stone.
Is it powerful?
Is Transcendent id just so together the
aboriginal,
I have a beautiful Bill Hicks story and
if punctured,
just for a moment,
my narcissism,
but hold on,
I'll get it back.
Wait a minute and it must be some reason
why I'm important.
The eyebrows,
MTV awards was married that time.
Come on,
you can do it,
but have you ever lesson they join it.
John Lennon talk about it.
No,
Lennon tastes like thousands of trips
and say he's like eventually Lizard
Cortana and talking about it.
He says like he eventually just realizes
he's dissolved his whole legal,
he doesn't experience life as a can a
narcissist anymore and he can't rate and
some friend comes to visit him.
I guess someone from England and say
it's Luke.
Remember that time that you wrote that
song?
You mean take then that was in like all
the,
all the different staff that is ego has
helped him to do and Lennon of
eventually arrives at the point before
he has just come back of going do need
some ego to get stuff done.
You can just
well in Nail Bhagavad Gita,
they're pretty clear about this is you
are here,
you are in the material world,
but God's got nothing against material
we did not denounce material with.
They're not favor,
absolute asceticism and totaled
announcement of this accenture,
you will experience it.
I mean there's a for luck joyousness in
Hinduism that I robbery enjoy.
Yeah.
Above the austerity or for some other
faiths that I know equally lethal about
and like sort of,
um,
what I like about that is the,
the,
the ego is an artifact that is not just
this sort of product of commodification,
commodification and capitalism by its,
it can be this glorious expression in
that Bill Hicks way of their
consciousness experience,
limitless consciousness.
The experience in itself,
excuse me,
subjectively that it in a kind of like
an an aesthetic idea,
like a while to like,
you know,
owner,
wearable work of art or be a work of art
that we can become like,
you know,
the,
it needn't be,
excuse me,
fuck it.
Now I think I'm going to actually vomit.
It's like I'm drunk high west Scott.
Cause somehow just by virtue of talking
about it,
but that we can become the realization
of this beauty,
this facet of the limitless that the
whole can be experienced in the
individual.
That's the problem.
I'm curious at this thing goes,
the genie's out of the bottle on
individual ism.
You're not going to tell people you're
part of the parish.
Come on this,
get together and be a collective.
There's pot on a boiler suit.
I said,
that Shit's over.
You know,
people are gonna want to be individuals,
but that's why I'm,
I forever find myself banging on about
the importance of religion because I
think it's the only way to transcend the
prohibitions and limitations of
materialism that you've got to somehow
engage the mythic imagination of people.
But you're right that it is a sort of a
form of propagandizing people and it
does require that you yourself believe
in the metaphor.
And that's,
I guess why I'm interested in
hallucinogens and psychedelics because
it's a way of make the dream real.
I heard this thing frankie about like,
um,
like I think it's apocryphal,
but it's a nice little thing like I was
that when the settlers came,
the settlers,
they shamed the hunter gatherer
societies and most notably the Shaman,
the shaman,
they said your rituals are bullshit and
meaningless.
Your dances,
your spells and your silliness,
Eh,
out on the edge of the village and the
Shaman became clown,
lost the visa ability to be mythic and
potent.
The Shaman becomes the clown earth and
profane nothing but each jokes to guard
him against these new d as the settlers
drag him down.
You know,
and this is what we've become now the
shaman.
Okay.
I've often thought at the center of
every joke scandal,
you can see why shamans left on the edge
of tone.
You know,
you've got to make a quick getaway
sometimes
didn't like that one stick.
Nailed mosques on that same thing.
My backpack and off I go,
Hello Wickham people,
you know that got feelings.
Yeah.
So like what do you feel when you're in
the midst of some Brouhaha?
I wonder if the things I most enjoyed
about you is watching on line,
how you beautifully articulate it.
The scandal around where the joke you
made around about Harvey and Katie
Price.
I thought it was such a beautiful
rendering cause I would obviously from
a,
a sort of a like a humanist,
I suppose if you want to word
perspective God k prize wouldn't class
woman Harvey Meant Leo.
But like,
you know,
like,
but I obviously first and foremost it
enjoy it,
the joke,
uh,
and secondly,
your analysis of it,
it was quite beautiful whenever I've
been called upon to justify the,
and my Andrew Sachs saying,
ah,
I've always got angry again.
I've always got angry because I'm like,
it's not even real.
It's not even fucking real.
They weren't even offended.
It's not this just because of the
collision of the BBC,
this mainstream media because they saw,
you know,
like I've got an re engaged reenergized
by it.
How do you feel about sort of like
justifying your own jokes,
scandal stuff?
I don't believe it.
I've never tried to really justify
anything.
Um,
I think sometimes like that thing you're
describing there,
it's just that fact that you understand
at the center of something that is much
more complex than what has been boiled
down to in a tabloid.
You know,
and you're like,
well that routine starts a certain way
and it goes a different place and when
the night is different every night and
blah,
blah.
And why am I getting hoisted for this?
So does that say to,
but there's also the same,
but it's like how many people have
really got a sense of humor for this
kind of thing.
So like if you look at like what we
would call a of comedy,
we'd guess we'd see ourselves in that
tradition,
wouldn't we've,
we watched probably all the same comics,
like when we were kids.
Um,
the back was the biggest alternative
comedy.
Sure.
Like an hour over the period of our
careers,
maybe the office or something.
So the office maybe got two and a half
million or something.
3 million people and says maybe 60
million viewers in Britain.
She charitably you're thinking like the
biggest desk can go is about 5% of the
population is going to be untethered to
get more than that.
You've much caught to be like,
come on and a dress.
I'll do it.
So most people aren't into this.
I know a lot of the problem is like
you've been asked to justify jokes,
which is okay,
but not to people who don't particularly
like or even understand like what you're
doing.
You know?
So that's a huge part of it.
Is there the papers in particular author
by relocation,
they're taking something that you said
to one audience so that you said at nine
o'clock on a Friday night in Newcastle
and showing it to people over their
breakfast and their home,
county and Gomez,
that's acceptable for them.
Yes.
CSS.
Yeah,
that re contextualization is such a
vital and neglected component and what
I've always found it also annoying is
the disingenuity of the papers when they
do the repositioning of like that.
I don't think that they are ever,
he said what?
Oh Man.
Oh No.
Come on.
We can to have to
journalist of all people.
Someone who let,
Shirley goes through other people's
fucking Ben.
They sitting there like horrified that
someone's dressed up as the twin towers
at Halloween or something,
you know?
Oh my God,
us to people who feel any shock.
I had one that was like I did a joint is
years ago.
The guy who did the speaking clock died
and I did something to call them or
something that said hopefully died
after,
sees a small strokes and I got an email
from the journalists or the Daily
Telegraph who said,
well actually miss through whatever his
name is,
dead die from a series of small strokes
and I'm a bit to foreign his family.
Oh if you can make him ask him if he'd
find your joy commuters and is there
anything you'd like times can just don't
the money fucking joke.
Then it's you joke,
you telling them that joke they'd never
have hair day.
If someone projects upon movie on the
side of a primary school that police
don't erase Ron Jeremy for
the old throne children over there.
Oh No,
I'll get off on it.
Yeah,
you're quite right.
Yes.
You'll see that it's brilliant the way
that they've extricated themselves,
that people's sort of shock impulse is
so readily available.
The bypasses their bill,
they go,
oh hang on a minute,
why am I being even told this now?
It's like cause all of us on a personal
level,
no,
that there's things that we would say to
one another that now if I'm with my
girlfriend's parents,
I'm not going to go.
I'll just reframe you boil.
We had a real laugh about the med Taleah
I recognize it and also doesn't it like
it's a language that has a sort of a
like exact got codes in it that I know
that mine are,
my actual attitude is to mental illness.
I know my actual attitude is to death
and sadness and grief.
Didn't we not permit ourselves a bit of
fucking latitude and a bit of relief?
Well,
there's comedic license.
I guess this is what we're seeing.
Ultimately there's a comedic license in
the same way that there's artistic
license or poetic license.
No,
it's just a poet with the fucking sun
coming up in the morning.
Isn't it like a lion?
We cannot put the fuck you talking
about.
Yeah.
Clinics lives.
Waking Up Sifford I happen to just say,
okay,
could happen any time.
It don't make a good point.
The screwed up.
It's rubbish.
But you know we can,
why don't we get this in license because
I suppose it's,
well let me look out like,
cause I've often thought of that,
that that that profanity being a sort of
better nation of territory.
Like I enjoy doing comedy that is like
disgusting and rude and raw and raw
curse I suppose get off in it and some
very in various ways.
But I think what it also does is it can
sort of act as a kind of explosion that
gives you access to different
territories that people are a little bit
shaken and then you can sort of say
something beautiful or whatever.
But I think that that people would like
to keep the consciousness,
the common consciousness,
the public consciousness in existence on
certain neurological pathways that exist
on an individual level and on a
collective and dialectic level also.
And that if you can untrammeled those
circuits,
those grids with explosive behaviors
that that's dangerous.
Sure.
I mean I think there's three things
going on.
One is you level late,
what comedy can do,
because if you're not allowed to shock
and you're not allowed to do something
at the start,
because often those jokes they get most
offended about or things you do to open
up other subjects,
right?
Yes.
Then that levels out what you can do.
The other thing is they want to print
the jock.
You know,
they want to put in the jaw,
they're look of Victorian freak.
Sure.
I look at the depravity but they want to
show it.
But he does have perfectly formed to
janitor tools from,
I'll just give me a quick give a wag
their cake and eat it.
Yeah.
And I think the other thing is just a
general thing they want to promote,
which is the idea of Eh,
public opinion as synonymous with press
opinion.
You know,
so it ended up the public would rage but
us,
we looked on twitter and we find some
people at Ridge,
you can literally find anything if you
want to prevent the in from either side
of an argument,
just the tape and to twitter.
There's people who say,
I hate yellow,
yellow.
Um,
so what they want to do is make their
opinions synonymous with public,
the public domain,
which is,
you know,
yes,
it's to,
to validate and mandate there.
I'm going to say it,
Veltin showering I there,
there I've said to allison showing it's
been said now,
hmm.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
So then you think,
ah,
that bears sort of,
that when we're talking about change,
social change,
there's kind of an,
uh,
an obligation to reimagine in ways that
a role for bold and may initially seem
sort of a bit mental in their boldness
to,
yeah.
That's what I think as well.
I don't know quite how to do x.
The problem is,
is because people have been so
beautifully schooled in,
I thought that,
you know,
it's in rejecting radicalism of
associating it with the other nurse is
the exotic,
the feminine,
the mysterious,
the sort of,
what do I want to say,
the,
um,
orient or to reject it,
to reject that.
Now,
whenever you say that,
why don't we just sort of break down all
superstructures and live in small,
manageable communities.
Like chimpanzees naturally works.
We can't handle them on 75 relationships
and just municipal infrastructure where
required around transport and energy
systems and not have power that exists
for profit at all.
And that we'll get our kicks and not
from consumerism,
but by interfacing with the limit.
This beauty of the cosmos that we have
access to for our consciousness.
Vote for me.
I think you can like there's that thing
isn't there?
What your seven stages away from the
public there or would you imagine the
general public car,
but then you try and do that like when
you're rating.
So I was trying to read a thing this
week with the British empire and the
idea of some people see the British
empires,
you know,
it was okay.
It was a mixed bag and it would just
empirically untrue,
you know,
and,
and for some reason it's not okay to be
creationist,
but it has all care to,
of maybe then poems.
It was massive excess deaths and it's
all in paddock.
Provable.
And I brought some jargon with something
along the lines of,
um,
there was a tray somewhere who said a
stranger is a friend that you haven't
met yet and I can't imagine who quite
clear they died out and you know,
so you,
you sort of approach,
you learn that,
how do I gradually,
it's through five stages may when I'm
right and had a good actually bring
people to the idea which is main,
which is instinctively reject,
you know,
ideas of empire.
Yes,
that's right.
Because it's difficult isn't it,
to ravel and discard centuries if
indoctrination like,
uh,
I mean I myself when abroad will sort of
like,
I remember the royal wedding was on when
I was in la and I was like,
oh,
it's good.
This,
I don't remember.
So I like got swept up in it.
Know there were things where they sort
of got it.
This is sort of a broad desire and,
and sort of possibly the wrong place to
explore it,
but they showed how many,
like members of that congregation that
day were dressed in literal Disney
costumes if you ever seen that.
But they kept going,
look,
here's this person that's a Disney
costume.
Like they found it,
but loads of,
I'm not that pepper middle turn.
She's dressed like someone at butte in a
piece.
There is that one.
Hang on a minute.
This is bizarre.
There's this sort of blending of the
world of Disney and royal weddings,
but regardless,
my point was that that a little bit of
pageantry and I was war,
right,
whooped up and you know,
I love a World Cup.
I love a bit of tribalism.
Well,
the electrically bro,
all that end as if the lost power,
the royals,
so they didn't use to harm huge royal
weddings.
It's a fairly modern trend,
but also they're going to need to like
stopped shooting the cameras that can
lead to stop turning the cameras,
render in their audience eventually.
So unrepresentative of brand and it's
like [inaudible] Sanchez funeral.
You know,
you're just like,
nobody needs to see those people.
You're going to need to just focus on
something else,
right?
The revelation you can no longer,
I suppose now with the ability to
disseminate information is more and more
difficult to control the truth.
And while social media is still a
corporate spear and controlled by those
kind of,
you know,
interests,
it's that just the information itself
starts to have an impact.
I said Ronins like I went two years ago,
did a pace,
were interviewed Keith.
Richard took about 10 minutes.
We've met to write 5,000
words like so for Rolling Stone Gig and
like they,
the stones themselves carefully manage
the letting you see their audience
because that's the elderly now altamont
no more.
And I suppose all empires,
myths,
emblems brands are held together by
saying no,
no,
we are the populace.
We found one person on twitter who said
that that just funeral was a lovely
event.
Yeah.
Laser flowers and consuming,
I need a week so badly now I can sort of
feel it sort of coming out amidst my
organs.
So,
so before I came reject more urine and
some people would say that's all of the
broadcast has ever been a hemorrhaging
of micturation by a man floundering,
looking for something to cling to.
Thanks.
No thanks for having me,
man.
It's really brilliant to talk to you.
I really enjoyed it.
It was a bit where it got really,
really,
uh,
I zoned out,
zoned out,
glitched out.
Like where I feel the flexing of the
glass,
of my understanding.
I would quite like that.
Sure man.
Enjoy that.
What would we do now?
Well,
that's the end of it and we go back to a
normal life.
So classes it isn't,
it just have to accept this was a little
paddock of time that existed.
I can't live with you now.
Is it?
Oh,
I've got children.
You've got children.
That's it.
We just carry on with our lives.
We're all going to go have some ice
cream.
It's going to be okay,
Frankie.
Thank you.
They go one shift.
That was russell brands under the skin.
The show is sponsored by my rebirth to
go russell brand.com
for information on tickets.
But you may particularly want to go to
Richmond on the 17th for July,
Cambridge,
aim of July.
We're it on the 25th of July.
It was brand.com
if you'd like to show,
subscribe on whichever meaty Aa or
medium you receive these things on and
give it five stars,
please.
Just for the simply so that when I'm
glancing an average,
I'll feel good about myself,
which believe me,
it's no easy.