My guest on under the skin today is
doctor Robin Carhart Harris,
the head of psychedelic research at
Imperial College London,
and he's not even 37 years of age yet.
He's already been described as the whiz
kid of psychedelic research and imagine
how competitive that field is and the
cooler,
the younger brother of Brian Cox,
who we are,
and they'll hopefully have only the
university did a lovely thing,
isn't it?
His research is as exciting as it is
taboo.
He investigates the brain effects and
potential therapeutic uses of
psychedelic drugs and as such,
as the first person in the UK to have
legally administered doses of Lsd to
human volunteers since the misuse of
drug act in 1971.
Dr.
Robin,
thank you for coming on the show.
Pleasure.
Yeah.
Nice to be here.
Thanks for inviting me.
Oh,
you're so kind to say,
can I call you doctor?
Sure.
Although I'm not a medical doctor is
going to banks.
I don't think of any of that.
Anyone that's not a medical doctor I
think should be stripped of that title,
unless you're wearing a white coat and
putting your fingers up people's bomb.
I don't consider you part of our system.
Thanks Dr.
Robin.
I'm still have a sufficiently did wish
to find titles at lowering doctors,
professors,
all of that stuff.
I'm buying into it and tell me,
can you tell me what that means that you
are the head of psychedelic research it
the empirical what,
what's going on for the last few years?
I suppose about,
uh,
eight years now.
I've been doing human research with
psychedelic drugs.
Um,
I've done a number of brain imaging
studies looking at how these drugs work
in the brain.
Uh,
most recently I've transitioned into,
uh,
giving a psychedelic for a particular
psychiatric disorder to try and treat it
as depression and we give psilocybin
which is found in magic mushrooms.
Um,
so now the team is transitioning more
into looking at applications and how
these drugs can be useful,
not just how they work.
Yeah.
Presumably if you're moving to the point
of application,
some of the efficacy of these substances
have been established.
Now I'm ragging.
Before we get into that,
I'd like to learn how someone growing
up,
you're a British person.
I how,
how,
how did you get into psychedelics?
Because there's,
it seems to me like a broad and
interesting field.
Tell me about your academic
background and how you became interested
in.
Well,
let's kind of two aspects to the story
and perhaps the latter one which is
easier to talk about.
Happened around my early twenties when I
was studying psychoanalysis,
so freud and yoga and um,
and I was absolutely fascinated by this
topic and I couldn't get enough of it
and I was,
you know,
any opportunity reading whatever I
could.
But I also felt little dissatisfied with
where psychoanalysis sat in terms of
mainstream psychology.
Um,
it felt Kinda clickish it felt that's
not scientific enough.
It didn't seem to have convinced people
of the validity of its main ideas,
like the existence of the unconscious
mind,
for example.
And I was a believer in some sense,
but I didn't want it to have to be that
way.
I didn't want it to have to be a kind of
leap of faith.
Um,
I thought we could maybe demonstrate
that certain principles of
psychoanalysis a true.
And by these principles you mean
primarily the existence of an
unconscious on an individual level,
yes,
but also a collective level.
So that would be called Young's work,
that there's aspects of our psyches that
are shared ena,
certain themes,
certain ways of being certain aspects of
the human condition that are enough or,
and this is demonstrated what through me
motifs and archetype.
Yeah.
Why did you find that so interesting?
Well,
I think because it felt true because it
resonated with me and I think you can
see it in culture.
You can see it in religion.
Um,
and,
and so I,
I kind of wanted to demonstrate that,
you know,
that there was,
that there's real meat here.
It's not just,
you know,
fantasy or the product of our or young's
and others,
you know,
wild imaginations that these things are
kind of real.
For me,
this podcast,
the reason I do it is to educate myself
and to educate others and to try to in
some way translate the gap that exists
between academia and what you would call
normal people or everybody else that
doesn't have access to this sort of
privileged,
a nomenclature of academia of which the
word nomenclature is undoubtedly an
example.
Like,
so like when you talk about Freud and
young and the psychoanalysis and some of
it's like key ideas.
Like what is the,
it was this distinction between Freud's
view of the unconscious and young's view
of the unconscious,
for example.
Yeah.
So Freud put most of the emphasis on,
on sex,
I suppose,
and sexuality and also,
um,
uh,
the unconscious,
the Freudian unconscious if you want,
had much more to do with our own lives,
our relationships with important figures
in our lives and particularly our
parental figures.
Um,
whereas young kind of transcended that
level and talked about the unconscious
mind with reference to culture and
religion and mysticism and so it was a
kind of,
if you want a sort of deeper aspect of
our minds,
our unconscious minds,
if you want.
The young was particularly interested
in.
He also,
there was a bit of a spat between the
two figures and young felt.
Freud put too much on sex and the
personal [inaudible] I can pretty funny
marriage or don't get about sex and stop
thinking Freud and young does it come by
me gasoline?
I'm like,
so Freud for everything was coming down
to sex and your individualized life for
young for that there's enough evidence
to suggest fruit archetypes and
recurring motifs and themes through
religions culture to suggest that
there's some sort of interconnectivity.
Although in Freud's work on like totally
museum and to bu they're an indication
there that if sort of certain taboos a
recurring for about cultures that that
in itself is an indication of some sort
of collectivized mind.
I think I touched on it and I think it's
a bit of a slightly,
you know,
oversold differentiation that I just
made,
you know,
and,
and Freud was,
um,
would refer to to kind of collective
aspects of the unconscious.
Freud was more mechanistic,
um,
all the young ones as well.
I think the difference is a kind of
emphasize perhaps too much because of
this personal spat between the two and
because they kind of emphasize the
differences,
they emphasize the differences because I
suppose we take for granted the things
that we share in common and so the
differences start to become pertinent
and Germane.
So from this early interest in
unconsciousness,
somehow or another,
she started to think it was all right to
sit around doing drugs,
justify yourself.
It wasn't really quite that,
it was more that,
you know,
how can we test this stuff?
Um,
and,
and I was in a seminar one day and,
and they were the seminar leader and the
people in the group,
we're talking about all the different
ways that psychoanalysis had to access
the unconscious mind.
And the best that it could come up with
pretty much was dreaming,
you know,
and dreams are brilliant and
fascinating,
but the quite unreliable and minor they
are now,
they are a crap from one page to the
next absolute codswallop becoming out
of.
Okay.
So this is the tools of empirical tools
for accessing the unconscious,
our dreams hypnosis,
that sort of like the recognizable tools
and what a new thing that those tools
are a bit lame.
Yeah.
Basically.
And you're and you're not,
you know,
and has been proven really.
You're not gonna convince enough people
with those tools because you know,
people have said a dreams that they're
just chaotic.
The noise,
they don't mean anything.
I'd actually disagree with that.
But yeah,
that's a popular view that there's,
yeah,
a lot of young's work on like say for
I've written every day about sort of
compensate every dreams that they're
like,
that the unconscious mind is at least
trying to narrativize your life or we're
trying to communicate with you.
And you've talked already about the idea
of archetypes.
It seems that when we were like,
you know,
in some senses when we're referring to
the transcendent over referring to her,
a potent,
an all encompassing being,
it could in fact be regarded.
The,
our own unconscious is the repository
for great information,
great knowledge that we have a kind of a
peculiarly unceremonious and
inconsistent relationship with these
aspects of ourselves.
We're absolutely,
and this is where psychedelics come in
because I stumbled across,
kind of stumbled across some literature
on lsd being used in psychotherapy in
the fifties and sixties.
And um,
I was just blown away to discover that
the main rationale for using LSD and
psychotherapy was that it would lower
ego defenses and then allow access to
this,
you know,
far vaster a realm of our minds,
the unconscious mind.
And I just thought this is true.
Had you taken psychedelics by that time?
I'm a bit embarrassed about talking
about.
Not Embarrassing.
It's just a sensitive one in I think
because the stigma,
stigma,
stigma of being a scientist studying
these and the mainstream scientific
community,
homicides,
what?
You're doing drugs and then they think
you're a hippie.
You're not a scientist,
she's,
yeah,
it's interesting,
isn't it?
But it's in itself a taboo subject and
it sort of,
its origins,
what,
who are the early pioneers around
psychedelics with Timothy leary or like
our oldest Huxley,
Ram Dass,
that there were a few people who were
looking at Mescalin early on in the
early 20th century.
Uh,
but really a breakthrough happened when
the Swiss chemist,
Albert Hofmann a kind of slightly
serendipitously came across lsd and
synthesize the lsd while looking for
drugs.
Um,
uh,
more to do with,
with,
with blood and um,
and,
you know,
the blood system,
he synthesized it.
So for,
like go,
like,
so he,
he's working away on drive some sort of
circuitry trial and these gotta mean
drugs or what are they related to?
Uh,
um,
these fungi that grow on certain
grasses,
he's working with mushrooms and stuff
and how,
what is it you come to mushroom related
and,
uh,
one of the compounds that we synthesize,
one of quite a few was Lsd,
25.
Um,
and uh,
the story goes that he got a bit on his
skin and somehow you know,
ingested it and had this like mild
psychedelic trip and then I think the
next day he went back and thought,
well I'll take a tiny little bit just to
see if,
if it was this lsd 25 that made me feel
so strange.
So we took 200 mics,
which is quite,
I think it's 200,
250 is quite a big dose of Lsd and he
had a full on,
you know,
mind blowing a trip full of nightmarish
visions and such like,
Oh I like that cause it sounds a little
bit like the hulk.
Then it,
he got a little bit on him by accident
and then it becomes sort of basically
whole course vitamin,
whoever,
because they all follow that template.
Some encounter which is bloody union
idea.
Okay.
And encounter some sort of a mentor
encounter and then it becomes another
person and goes back next day,
next 250 or whatever of it.
And he goes into some form,
some sort of transcendent realm.
Then what am so between the twenties in
the sixties and you don't start here,
right?
So again,
really to what fifties and sixties
started heating up in the fifties.
People started using lsd in really
psychoanalytic psychotherapy,
which kind of dominated psychiatry.
Then the kind of Freudian model really,
um,
and then into the sixties,
things got a bit more colorful and
people started taking it recreationally.
And then Timothy leary came on the
scene.
He took some magic mushrooms after
reading an article,
um,
about these tribes in,
in Mexico who were taking mushrooms.
And then he took lsd and everything
changed that he kind of,
he was an academic originally.
He was at Harvard.
He's some sort of Harvard fuddy duddy
with Dickie bow tie and a suit on.
And before you know it,
it's tuned in.
Dropout,
have a nice relaxed.
So this is very curious that like all
these substances or substances,
this idea seems to exist in indigenous
cultures.
The idea of,
I don't know,
sort of shamanism or plant based
transcendent experiences is an old idea
and perhaps in an original idea and
indigenous idea,
possibly one of somewhere in the
crucible of civilization,
we will find this idea where man becomes
religious.
Were man begins to believe.
Do you think it's as important as that?
Is that,
what is the basis of your interesting in
personally interesting psychedelic?
I think there's part of it.
So yeah,
the therapeutic side and there's a lot
of,
um,
you know,
very,
um,
deep wisdom to those cultures that use,
that have used psychedelics for maybe
thousands of years.
Um,
and in a way we're just kind of,
to some extent,
we're rediscovering what those cultures
always knew,
but we are bringing something new to the
table.
I think we're bringing a,
you know,
um,
for all our flaws as sort of a western,
you know,
secular people,
uh,
we,
we do have an ability to break things
down,
to deconstruct them and to try and
understand the mechanisms underneath.
And that's important is it to have an
understanding of the medicinal and
mechanical operation of these chemicals?
I think so I'd say,
um,
I think it's important to understand how
something works,
you know,
some people would argue that it,
it makes no difference to me to,
to have that knowledge,
but I think sometimes there can be some
differences,
for example,
in where people ascribe the locus of
action of a drug.
So for example,
indigenous people might say that it's
the plant
that holds an intelligence and we tap in
through taking the plant.
We,
we surrender to it and allow its
intelligence to guide us that that's the
mushroom or the Ios or wherever.
Yeah,
exactly.
Or they may say that it's the songs,
you know,
these eco rose that sharman seeing these
kind of chance that is sung to people
while they're under the influence of,
of say,
I want this jungle psychedelic,
um,
whether it's wave or a particle
somewhere or another is affecting
consciousness.
Whoever is the wave or the vibration
form of the chance or the
particularities of the substance will
one way or another consciousness is
being shifted this way versus particle
argument.
That what is the essential element?
What is it?
Is it that there be light?
Let there be matter.
What is it?
What is it about?
What happened?
View Mate,
when you net them bloody drugs.
I want to know all about it clearly
sounds like you know me.
I'm in recovery.
You don't know me.
I don't take.
I've not had taken any drugs at all and
had a drink one day at a time,
14 and a half years.
Curiously,
Bill Wilson,
the founder of 12 step fellowships
himself,
became very interested in psychedelics
for a brief while after he got clean
from alcohol and I think hunger your
man,
Tim leary there for awhile and he wanted
to integrate lsd into the 12 steps,
which would be an interesting addition.
Imagine just kind of finding,
finding God,
isn't it?
Finding really in a sense.
Yeah.
The twelfth step is having had a
spiritual awakening as the result of
these steps.
We made a decision to turn out life and
will over God and to practice these
principles in all our affairs.
So eventually I suppose a life of
altruism,
philanthropy and service based on this
realization now like me,
I like,
even though I work in media and write
children's books,
I am prepared to say that like,
um,
I've taken lsd when I was sort of the
first time.
I think I was 16 and something very.
I mean,
it seems.
Well,
I essentially,
when you say like that,
it was used in therapy to break down the
ego.
I can see what people mean because we're
the most obvious.
The most obvious,
most immediate and most tangible thing I
experienced was,
oh no,
I'm not me.
I remember thinking that.
I remember thinking,
I'm not me.
I'm not what I thought I was this idea
because what I personally felt was very
chained to my identity.
I'm Russell.
I was born at this time.
This is what I believe in.
I support West Ham united.
I like Morrissey,
and I remember feeling all that stuff's
dismantling in a mirror and like the
feeling somewhat afraid.
I can see why they would need to be
caution,
several mini mentorship and guidance
when dealing with that.
And I suppose in a secular society,
clinical conditions is what replaces the
idea of ritual or ceremony for Shaman
guidance,
that sort of businesses.
We're taking it laboratory.
I'm not doing this in a park with Glen
and dean doing assay and staring at the
clouds of framing up in a calypso.
I slowly made a bloody laboratory.
No,
I mean in a way.
And we take borrow
from what's gone before and um,
uh,
in terms of the sort of semantic model
in the sense that we do change the
laboratory,
you know,
we get rid of the fluorescent lighting
and there's low thank God and we have,
um,
we have some nice ambient music in hype,
some bloody Pam Power,
what you created
in the laboratory.
Laboratory conditions for psychedelics
means what taught me through what the
process is.
So,
um,
we'll um,
we'll bring in some,
some low lighting,
um,
will a compiler playlists that,
that has a certain structure to chat
someone up.
He'd be there tonight.
Um,
and,
uh,
it's gonna sound worse now,
but we built a certain relationship as
well,
so of trust.
It's lovely.
Yeah.
And we try and get to know each other
and kind of lay things on the table and
we changed literally romantic objects or
no,
say in it,
an atmosphere of trust and open
communication.
How many people were at one time in
London,
England,
and just you and one person.
How does this work?
Uh,
usually two people we call them guides
or sitters and people are on the level
they have not took nothing.
Uh,
usually they have that moment,
that moment.
And I know they're sober that the sober
guides so visitors',
um,
and uh,
you know,
particularly compassionate and,
and encourage a,
um,
uh,
an atmosphere of openness,
of a willingness to let go,
uh,
to explore,
um,
to surrender that analytical mind,
uh,
that I was talking about earlier and to
trust and to kind of go with the flow of
the experience.
What substances have you been working
with?
Psilocybin?
Magic mushrooms.
So solid.
Simon's in magic,
mushrooms,
lsd a.
Now dmt.
And I have my colleague next to me,
Christian woman who's studying dmt at
the moment.
I'm an MC as well to help me to
understand dmt that's based on that show
coming song.
I'm quite childish.
A hello a Christian woman or you were
introduced as a phd student.
What you do,
Chris.
Hello.
Welcome.
What you're doing your phd in mate in
the Phd currently leading a study on
trying to find out what are the effects
of the brain and kind of like licking
experience and brain.
You're trying to work out that what
have.
So tell me what that involves.
What are you doing,
Chris?
Um,
so we're basically giving the empty to
um,
a number of healthy participants.
So this young people,
students at imperial college
primary,
not necessarily,
I mean you have a wide range of
interests that people in our studies and
you can have from 20 to 50 years.
Fifty year old people.
Yeah.
Okay.
And talk me through the process.
So,
um,
we have to kind of like main phases of
the study.
So on the first one we wanted to,
you know,
address,
can we give a nice dose of dmt without
inducing anxiety,
you know,
it's such a strong drug that you want to
do it in the best possible way,
but you want to get the effects that
you're after,
you want to get to those far out sort of
experiences in the best way and safest
way possible.
So we first did a pilot phase,
there was no brain imaging being done
and you know,
just people were just sitting there and
the nice environment just chilling and
we gave them different doses of the
empty,
a nice setting.
We saw what happened during the
experience.
We kind of like a,
did interviews,
questionnaires kind of like address that
in the most detailed way possible,
trying to map these effects and
experience.
Um,
and with that we characterize it,
will find the right dose.
And now we're moving into actually brain
imaging,
like proper,
you know,
how many people did you trial to
establish what you consider to be the
right dose?
12 people.
So what did you find across these 12
people?
Uh,
we found that,
um,
you got,
we tried out three different doses,
right,
the right dose,
the experience characterized,
but by the right dose for those kind of
like these stages that were,
you know,
we think are very interesting.
So the first one is this kind of like
bodily rush,
you know,
this feeling that people are actually
expanding outside of their body somehow.
Uh,
then this kind of like entering into a
geometric sort of space,
a very kind of like wonderful,
beautiful,
colorful,
moving geometrical patterns and then
pushing through into this kind of like
different sort of space,
you know,
this feeling that you're entering some
sort of round that it's not coming from
inside,
but it's actually,
you know,
you're visiting somewhere else and in
this space,
you know,
many people in Canada,
entities presences that engaged with
them,
communicate with them.
Some receive very meaningful
information,
some received lake cosmic stuff,
spiritual stuff.
Other others have like personal insights
on their lives.
They felt that they were being carried
by someone through messages of
importance and stuff like that.
I'm curious,
the Corolla Murray,
I'm Chris Rather Robin in what Chris is
describing in what you said about your
interest being triggered by the work of
young and Freud and that there is a
commonality of experience that people
are describing and that one of the early
phases of it is transcendence.
Would you please just tell me a dmt?
What does it stand for?
They methylate tryptamine die methyl
triptolene.
Yeah.
From what is this substance derived?
It's found in nature and seriousness
like plant sources.
You can find the actual drug.
Uh,
we,
you know,
we buy it from a lab that synthesize it
for,
you know,
a experimental procedures itself,
but you can find it in nature.
You can find it in the body as well.
The human body has the substance in it
suggest anything to you there some
evidence on it?
Yeah.
Well we have very,
very small amounts so we don't know if
it's,
you know,
if it actually plays a role into any of
these naturally occurring spiritual
experiences,
uh,
or if not,
or if just maybe some sort of like out
product of the system just happening by
accident scene.
And nonessential,
I suppose what we're interested in is
consciousness,
isn't it?
The nature of consciousness,
what is this that's happening to us?
What is being,
what is it to experience the information
conveyed to us through the senses and to
see ourselves as the sort of participant
in and all three of our own reality.
So anything that can significantly
disrupt the manner in which we
understand reality has potentially
profound implications for us as a
species for the way that we civilize,
socialize an organized one can see why
it's a substance that's been heavily
controlled since its inception in the
sixties when people were working with
Lsd,
there was a point where it began to be
sort of quite heavily policed,
controlled a band.
Is that true?
Yeah.
And in,
in the late sixties,
um,
a number of states in the US started to,
to make it illegal essentially.
Um,
and uh,
the research was effected by
implication.
Really it was,
it then became not impossible,
but very difficult to do the research.
And actually at one stage it did become
impossible.
Then I'm a regulatory.
People were coming round and
confiscating psychedelics.
And so there was a very rapid,
I'm about turn in,
um,
Rooney Society's perspective on,
on psychedelics,
what was happening in America in the
late sixties,
maybe of interest with regard to
controls on a experimental hallucinogens
in soccer.
That takes mean there was a lot going on
culturally in terms of the counter
culture.
And I think there was some fears that
maybe lsd was fueling some of that
political.
Yes.
He's quite likely,
isn't it?
If there was a sort of a civil rights
movement,
Vietnam War,
the emergence of counterculture,
the ideas of the beats start to become
in a sense politicized like these,
like the eastern mysticism is now like
goes through the conduit of American
literature and poetry and starts to
become a kind of socializing and
politicized form is whether it's an
artistic form and one can in a perhaps a
not intubate but conject that if society
is an agreement,
if people start looking at society
differently,
more consciousness differently or
themselves differently,
that potential for change is suddenly
dramatically enhanced.
Do you think that that's possibly why
these substances were controlled rather
than people are worried about,
I don't know,
dental care or whether or not people are
all right?
I think so.
You know,
in some ways you could characterize it
as the,
the youth becoming more conscious and
less conformist,
more questioning.
That's exactly what they were doing.
Whether they were doing that anyway or
whether the psychedelics are actually
fueling those changes because of this
idea that psychedelics broadened
consciousness.
There's an interest in.
I'm a fan of Terence Mckenna,
who's,
I suppose like a,
they're one of the great pioneers,
isn't he?
One would say of sort of this sort of
plant based studies,
but also like for you guys who are
academics,
he must be sort of a controversial
figure and one of the things we have
this podcast is I become aware that
there are sort of sanctioned academics
and then these people are like,
oh yeah,
right.
That guy type people.
And like,
uh,
an.
Even though I'm a great admirer of
territory medics,
I think he so lucid and vivid and
brilliant articular imaginary sort of
for profit in a sense like that.
I've picked up that there.
He's on the side of the fence of what
let's not British types of stuff.
You know the thing about Terence Mckenna
is he.
He's a fascinating personality,
a great speaker at with incredibly
interesting ideas.
Now,
whether that's true or not is another is
another question and my view is that the
jury's out really on a lot of his ideas
and what the meaning of truth is and
Bill Hicks,
like one of the Great Comedians have a
20 a couple of decades ago.
Like he sort of.
He said,
okay,
I think,
I'm guessing maybe got this from a or
maybe from your field this way you guys
are experts for like a shaman is a
misery sort of psychedelic plants are
like an agent of evolution in that is it
has an impact on consciousness and our
conscious experience.
Now I'm guessing Chris,
mate,
from what you're saying about like these
experiments you've done,
that you've had a little go at that dmt
yourself now if you don't mind,
can you tell me exactly what happened?
His face because I'd like to know all
about it from the process of how it's
imbibed to what happens to your mind and
if you can describe the experience using
so blunted tool as language.
I'd like you to do it so,
so just going through it again from when
you get a hit on the pipe and then what
happens in your brain and not like from
a screen from,
from experiencing it.
Yeah.
So it all begins with this intense,
very,
very intense rushing the body,
you know,
there's this kind of like it feels like
this very strong flow of energy going
through.
You know,
what people describe how much she piping
and say you're putting it on a foil on a
bottle and go,
hey,
people usually do.
Yeah.
How you doing?
Because he's in a university.
Does it look a little bit less under the
bridge?
Uh,
well yeah.
I mean I can,
but rather not.
You think the mechanics of it are
worrying,
are they,
it worries you guys to talk about it?
Not really.
No.
No,
but we give it intravenously so it's
not,
it's not like a needle in a needle.
Yeah.
Okay.
And then so you like,
so you give people a little and if you
take it,
do you take it intravenously or do you
smoke it?
If I would have to take.
Is there an eagle you're worried about
illegal stuff or professional stuff?
Oh yeah.
Okay.
If you hypothetically,
let's say hypothetically,
you know,
how would you define it?
Smugged would be the easiest.
I'd worry about the old lungs on that.
I'd probably go straight for the
straight for the old main system brought
into the brain and to the nape of the
neck.
I'd like it.
I'm like,
no,
but I don't do drugs and I think,
you know,
like as a person in recovery,
I think you have to be very careful
though.
There's a lot of talk that psychedelics
can influence addictive behaviors and
issues around dependencies.
It's a very,
very interesting area when it comes
because I,
my personal belief is the addiction
stems from trying to solve a spiritual,
emotional,
psychological issue for external mean to
have that sexual behavior or average
extreme behaviors around food or
gambling or but most notably and
obviously dependency and reliance on
alcohol and drugs.
Now I don't see how someone could become
dependent on this experience where first
of all,
you feel a tremendous rush on the body.
Then you have some experience of
geometry suggesting that geometry is one
of the archetypal things that exist.
I didn't Greeks were on to something
that geometry is actual ways of energy
and shapes and performing and then after
that you go into what some domed realm
where there appear to be entities
communicating with you and what do
people say these?
Tell me about that bit.
That's a very interesting thing.
I mean there's this kinda like there was
this transition from the space of the
geometries into this actual kind of
like,
you know,
different sort of space,
different realm that feels alive and it
feels very true as well.
For many people.
I mean,
if the dose is high enough,
you know,
people kind of reliably go into this
space and this space can be full of
color,
different objects.
Not necessarily.
You will get the same sort of like
shapes NTT.
Some people speak about alien,
so people speak about Goblin.
Some people don't even speak about
visual evidence entities.
Just something being alive around you.
Yes,
because I suppose that would be
interpretive.
A friend of mine,
he's been on this podcast,
Simon amps still using a British
comedian.
He said that when he.
He like with his experience with Ios guy
that he said that he's described that
the different people in the group,
he was in a group out of six people,
he said and like,
Hey,
as a sort of a secularized Jewish
person,
a experienced these guiding psychiatrist
and there was a Hindu person who hadn't
experienced with Ganash and a Christian
person who had Christ like divinity
needs an Avatar.
The divine comes to you in the form of
a,
of an image,
which is really just a form of geometry,
I suppose,
loose geometry,
but like everyone's having the same
essential experience of there is there
is an authority,
there is something accessible to
consciousness.
Which you said there Chris and you said
also Robin,
maybe external may not be.
Yeah.
Well of course you're seeing Jesus.
You just took it.
You just injected yourself with a big
arm full of delicious.
What?
Demo method.
Triptolene
they methylate tryptamine.
Yeah.
Say what?
What is this?
Why do people think it might be external
because of the consistency of the
experience.
It's an.
It's an interesting.
Definitely an interesting question.
I mean,
the thing is that it's always a drug.
You know,
it's an actual thing.
Entering your body,
you know,
costing these experiences,
the feeling,
the experience of your wheel.
I mean feels three wheel and it's.
I think it's definitely something to
respect people.
People feel there's some authority.
There's something external,
something that you knew or bow down in
some sort of way you respect deeply.
That being said,
I'm not necessarily,
you know,
it is something real or that something
that exists to actually outside of realm
of personal experience,
we don't know these things.
It's difficult.
It's difficult to access them from a
scientific point of view,
you know,
most,
most things around.
Yeah.
Inside of us,
you know,
most,
most things,
most objects,
you know,
most entities are outside of us.
And even when we dream,
we think we're in a world where things
are outside of us,
you know,
but we know that,
that um,
uh,
you know,
play if you want is being played out in
our minds and we know that there are
changes in brain activity that account
for it.
And it's a similar thing with
psychedelics.
I mean,
we know,
you know,
with very high reliability that they
work on a particular aspect of the brain
that they work on a particular
neurotransmitter system,
a particular receptors,
serotonin receptor,
if you block it,
you don't trip,
you don't see the entities to really all
the evidence is that it comes from the
brain.
It comes from the mind.
But there's a thing that humans do,
which they,
they have an inclination to do,
which is to kind of externalize,
know to project and say it's out there.
The realm is,
is real,
it's another dimension.
You know,
these entities are actually aliens that
come from wherever.
So we've become certainly in a way
overly sensual and overly materialistic.
It becomes our main interpretive tool is
to regard phenomenon is external as
opposed to internal possibly could
continually go to bias to see things
have this bias of externalizing and
materializing.
Why do we have this bias?
Why do we have it?
Alright?
And I'm interested in so many things
here.
Mostly getting out of my neck,
I'd always have to be very,
very careful.
I've got
great deal of respect and indeed fear of
drugs because of the way that it made my
life go or really,
really badly wrong.
But like what I'm interested in,
I sort of thing I think is the
exploration of this world now.
When you would,
under these clinical studies,
if illusions in the studies that
yourselves,
that you were conducting and in previous
studies,
what part of the brain is being impacted
and what can we learn from that?
Yeah,
well it starts with the serotonin system
and the molecules come in Serotonin,
where else would we see that effect?
But there's loads of it in the gut.
Um,
but we've got a lot of,
in our brains.
There isn't such a massive,
you know,
there's a kind of relationship with
those,
with those systems.
And people talk about visceral feelings
this or is.
Yeah,
exactly.
Gut Instinct.
Um,
so yeah,
so serotonin is in the brain and it
modulates arrange range of different
things,
states of consciousness,
sleep,
mood,
the way we think.
And psychedelics kind of hijack the
serotonin system in a certain aspect of
it.
And then kind of pickle a particular way
it seems,
right?
Cheeky little devil doesn't it again in
there to away on the systems.
And uh,
and then at the kind of broader level in
terms of the whole of the brain that
changes networks in the brain.
And that's the way we tend to think
about brain function these days.
We don't think of all this bit here does
this,
you know,
it's like this distributed system that
often encompasses the whole of the brain
with bits at the front and bits at the
back.
Yeah.
No.
Does something like know vision or
movement or.
Yeah.
This model of compartmentalization
likely come from the period of
industrialization.
That of which a lot of these discoveries
were made in when we saw mechanistic
models as being compartmentalized and as
we realized a time where our technology
is understood in terms of cybernetics,
that we start to look at consciousness
and the brain as a comparable entity.
It's unlikely that he was looking out
the window button,
go to the toilet tree.
Instead,
the,
as DMRC would say,
just the mind rules the body.
Does the body roll the mind?
I've done a little bit circular.
Yeah,
right.
There's one.
Where are these?
Where are these boundaries?
Where are these lines?
Who's drawing them in and for what
reason?
Okay.
So like one of the things that happens
is serotonin transmission and reception
starts going all I knew real well,
and that that creates a conditions of,
of plasticity or a potential for change.
Um,
and you know,
in those kind of looser conditions,
the constraints on brain function,
the way the brain's working,
um,
are,
are sort of lifted and the brain can
operate in a much freer away.
And what happens under those conditions
is the brain networks that we know,
that we know serve different functions
like vision,
like moving,
like,
like high level things,
like even consciousness.
They begin to break down,
they begin to dissolve and disintegrate.
And when they do that,
another interesting thing that happens
when you look at the whole of the brain
is that these systems become less,
uh,
different from each other.
They kind of start to blend in to each
other and those two things.
So the disintegration of networks and
the kind of coming together of networks
and the sort of blending relate.
Uh,
so we've seen.
And so we think to some of the kind of
most abstract aspects of the experience.
So one of them is a,
these reports of ego dissolution that
you were talking about earlier,
you know that that sense that your
narrative self,
you know who Russell is,
is being compromised and you're just as
awake just as consciousness,
but all of a sudden that narrative self
destruct away and the other one is that
you might feel when that happens,
first of all,
a fear,
but also if that's transcended a sense
of connecting to something bigger in a
sense of connectedness,
a sense of oneness.
That's interesting.
So the ego one's idea of a narrative it
self as sort of a physical entity with a
story and a life in a perspective.
When that dissolves,
there's a sense of connection and relief
and release that I do remember I took it
I think quite a lot for a while and
sometimes it felt very brilliant and
beautiful and I enjoyed it.
But remember I wasn't taking it under
laboratory conditions.
I was taking it under the probably the
worst conditions you could take it under
ethics in the first case is.
And then sort of like hanging out in
like sort of people's bedsits in new
cross gate and like with people with
themselves,
just young men and like you know,
that sort of 18 year old lads and for
example,
it's not the worst thing that ever
happened to me and check this out.
Like everyone sort of got a load of
acid,
like sheets of the staff and I obviously
as a very keen young drug user for that
are left that and went and swapped my
bike for a good sheet of it and like
everyone pretended one night that they
were all doing some and they all just
get a little bit of paper which is the
form that it was delivered in and I took
real acid but they only had a bit of
paper in an hour in as Mike tripped
kicking in.
They all go,
guess what?
We didn't take acid.
So I'm now on a trip that requires,
as you said,
in laboratory conditions,
trust release and all of that.
And I'm told that none of the rest of
them are doing it.
Man.
I was not happy that day.
I didn't like it because I was starting
like,
you know,
my,
again,
I'm a,
yeah,
I'm an adolescent male so my identity is
forming.
My ego is a fragile thing.
Anyway,
coming from the background that I came
from and you know,
I remember like feeling very,
very disruptive and very,
very frightened and very afraid.
I mean so that these psychedelic drugs
and not things to be toyed around with
lightly.
But I think there's sort of this general
awareness and sort of.
I'm a big fan of Daniel Pinchbeck.
He writes
a lot about sort of taken different
plant by plant medicines and stuff and
different cultures and stuff.
Uh,
I think that there's important and
potentially revolutionary information
held in these plant substances.
I agree with that and people have said
the psychedelics are kind of,
you know,
there are kind of apart from other drugs
and there's a bit of evidence to support
that.
So for example,
this big population study in theU ,
s looked at united some 200,000
people and then looked at patterns of
drug use and the relationship to mental
health and found the psychedelics stood
out like a sore thumb because all other
drugs,
the more you take the worse your mental
health.
But psychedelics,
the more he took the lower was
psychological distress and the lower was
suicidality.
The two measures that they looked at.
So people have questioned whether you
can even call psychedelics recreational
drugs because at least in principle they
should have been taken for recreation.
Maybe self exploration or therapeutic
work but not,
you know,
not a party or
whatever.
Yeah,
because I remember black,
my impulse in taking those substances
when I was in fact in all drugs,
I want it to get out of myself.
I've felt like trapped and him sort of
in pain and like also the other thing
curiously that felt is what we're
experiencing is reality is not the
ultimate reality.
There's something else I wanted that.
So I kept puffing loads of weed then
drinking loads and doing enough for
drugs and eventually I'm going to crack
and heroin addict,
but the thing that had this odd
transcendent and what do I want to say,
sort of like uncanny,
almost macabre.
I feel it even when we're talking about
it,
when I start to feel this,
the tendrils that connects me to my
personal self flexing and being tugged
because something in me knows there is
another world and it's difficult because
it's the domain primarily of religion to
say that the material world is an
illusion.
None of this stuff really matters.
We're all one.
These tropes are found in religion.
Now what you're doing is bringing these
ideas are exploring these ideas in
academia and in chemistry and he,
and it seems it's sort of somewhat laden
with taboo and prohibition.
Even within your field I've sent you,
you're both cautious about talking about
it in a personal way.
Why?
Well,
it's a lot different aspects there.
But uh,
you know,
uh,
I guess,
um,
I mean the stigma is a massive thing.
And uh,
and it's like we're kind of
walking a very thin line,
you know,
you've got the enthusiasts,
so on one side the psychedelic
enthusiastic that might look in and say,
oh,
these guys are so dry,
the such,
you know,
such scientists,
they're boring or whatever,
and then you've got the way that I like.
Yeah.
And then we've got the,
you know,
the mainstream,
on the other hand,
you look in and think,
oh,
they're not real scientists.
They study psychedelics,
they must be hippies.
I bet they'd take closer psychedelics.
So there's a really sort of difficult
line to walk and personally,
you know,
a major motivation is to try and broaden
that walkway in a way,
you know,
to kind of eat into some of the mystical
aspects.
And although people won't like this kind
of secularized them and,
and I don't see that as a threat,
although some people will see it as kind
of bridge building,
um,
and translation like it really needs to
be a Rosetta stone of the spiritual
experience to the material experience
because materialism is our dogma.
How are we going to get information
over?
Yeah.
And if you make it dogmatic,
but,
you know,
personally I wouldn't ever want to
depreciate things like an entity
experience and I think something,
but sometimes people are threatened by
it and think,
oh,
you're trying to explain away this
experience that changed my life or
whatever,
and,
and say,
you know,
you want to say it's all brain activity
and I don't personally,
I don't want to do that at all.
I'd rather allow that way of looking at
things to just sit.
I suppose,
you know,
motivation would say.
I think it's interesting to understand
how the hell it happens,
you know?
Um,
and so for me it's not explaining away,
it's just explaining.
It's a bit like,
you know,
the wonder of nature.
It still is magical and beautiful,
you know,
um,
whether you understand how,
how a tree grows or whatever.
That's right.
And regard and however far one goes
materialistically mechanistically for
whichever scientific discipline one is
still left with the question of,
well,
how,
why?
What's motivating this in,
what is it Ctda what in thrones this
procedure?
And I think you're right,
I agree with you entirely that the more
that there can be description and
translation of these ideas,
the more it will benefit it's advanced.
What's your personal motivation in
carrying out these studies?
What do you want to do?
What do you want to achieve?
Education is one thing.
Like I'd like it to be more normalized
and,
and less,
um,
I don't know.
Easter terrick,
you know,
the unconscious mind that it be
something that's taught to kids even,
you know,
I think that will help to broaden our
population's consciousness.
Talk about unconscious unconscious in a
way.
You know,
we were talking about indigenous
cultures.
Maybe they have some of that,
you know,
and often quite healthy cultures.
Um,
you know,
it's,
it's less taboo and maybe some of that
kind of parcel eating is something that
the western people have done,
you know,
particularly sort of,
zealously.
Yeah.
Uh,
and so there's a motivation to normalize
A.
I don't want psychedelics,
the vso esoteric.
I don't want the unconscious mind and
psychoanalysis to be so unusual and
taboo and stigmatized,
you know,
there is a motivation to,
to bring it into the mainstream and to,
you know,
get people talking about it and thinking
about it and I think in being more
conscious for ourselves,
we're less likely to perhaps harm
ourselves and others.
God,
that's a very beautiful and important
idea.
I'm intrigued by it because I feel that
we are all to content to dismiss
activity that we all experience,
like we all do dream every night.
This amazing thing that happens in
everyone's mind most days and just go,
oh,
crack on.
Pay The gas bill.
I'll know mortgage rates have gone up
for let's have another foreign war.
And every night all of us tumble into
some glorious world of wonder where our
own life is rerender there's a myth and
that the information that's in there is
somehow ignored.
And that the fact that there is
obviously sort of potential to
understand ourselves differently.
A book that I have written is it about,
you know,
sort of is about how my method of
recovery that I was given the 12 step
method was a way of recognizing that the
model I had of myself was ineffective,
was an ineffective way of living and
that I needed to go on a journey of
being a different kind of man to succeed
in the world.
And my sense is that prohibition around
philosophy,
prohibition around substances.
I know I find it very difficult to
regard the state,
particularly when you talk about this
period of inception in the sixties,
is as parental and loving when so many
of its aims and objectives have been
subsequently revealed to be the
mendacious.
So is there like it's likely that
prohibition around psychedelics shares
that objective,
but if more people experience this and
it was probably like shamanism,
culturally is not for everybody.
Not everybody in the tribe goes off
every bloody day and wanders around in
theory,
all realms and in the unconscious mind
and is expected to interpret it.
Different types of people have different
types of abilities,
but some people should be experiencing
different aspects of the unconscious and
all of us should have a different way of
relating to ourselves in totality,
not just,
oh well I'm just this boat.
And then like deathbed lives,
I should have done more by.
I'd love me.
I just simply couldn't cope.
So like,
um,
like what is the,
tell me,
what is the ongoing,
ongoing intention for these studies?
What's going on?
Well,
we do more clinical work.
Um,
we're looking at psilocybin magic
mushrooms as a treatment for depression
and we,
we've done that already and got an idea
that it works and some idea of how it
works,
but now probably.
But that serotonin stuff,
right?
It's Serotonin and it works on those
networks I was talking about earlier.
Um,
and um,
and,
and sort of reset mechanism as well.
It seems to be going on,
you know,
that's curious what like the narrative
can be interrupted thing.
No,
I'm not,
it's not happening now.
I'm not being abused now.
I suppose you can kind of scramble up
and dissolve
it,
but it comes back,
you know,
but it comes back like a malfunctioning
computer is rebooted and it comes back
and it's functioning again normally.
Um,
yeah,
that's something to test more as we go
on.
But it's a,
have you had some negative stuff then
having to have somebody go proper
crackers?
Yes,
absolutely.
Well,
um,
it can be nightmarish.
We,
you know,
we can have patients whaling during the
session when they're literally,
you know,
facing demons and,
and you know,
our,
when they come back and they go,
oh,
it was terrible.
This thing got me where I was abused as
a kid and that just really lived it.
I know that,
that kind of thing.
Um,
and uh,
and so they need to feel like they can
go there and this has literally happened
that killed himself or anything mad.
Yeah.
No,
no,
not,
not that,
but the experience itself is incredibly
challenging.
I can imagine it being traumatic.
I've experienced it to be traumatic
staring around in your own unconscious.
It's going to be traumatic.
There's all sorts of crap mine around in
there and addressed,
but like,
you know,
just someone having a traumatic time
ain't necessarily a negative thing
because at least you're living it and,
and there can be breakthrough and so
this is a thing and we encourage the
patients to look the demons in the eye
and sometimes those demons are kind of
manifestations of an abuser say and when
they do that they get this curious like
shift in perspective and they'll see the
abuser as a,
almost as a victim,
you know,
that they can sort of see the chain of
causality that led to them,
you know,
being so you know,
damage that they would do something
damaging.
These results can be achieved
therapeutically.
Also,
sort of the reframing in sort of say
neuro linguistic programming would be
about like looking at the perpetrator of
abuse as themselves.
As you say a victim like that,
you know,
that you cook,
but I'm imagining you could probably do
that a lot quicker with a healthy dose
of psilocybin.
People say that,
you know,
famously said about psychedelics that
they can be like years of therapy,
you know,
in a few hours.
The danger is you always feel like we
should put a caveat on it because we
talked a lot about the environment and
the context and I do think it's true
that you know,
in,
in the wrong context,
psychedelics could be harmful.
Person was mentally unwell in inverted
commerce is probably not a good idea to
take any mind altering substances alone.
And I think my personal belief is that
the addiction phenomena is a result of
people medicating themselves in a
society that doesn't know how to treat
them and has no real desire to take care
of the mentally ill.
I was smoking weed,
I was drinking because I was in pain and
I couldn't cope.
And curiously the other thing is I
already said was I had a powerful
curiosity about what was going on in my
mind,
my experience.
A colleague of mine,
a Rosalind Watson has done some nice
work around this theme of connectedness.
You know,
in a lot of mental disorders and
probably addiction.
You know,
people suffer from a feeling of being
isolated and being disconnected from
things and they might be disconnected or
say for meaning
united does a sense of meaninglessness
and what seems to happen with
psychedelics when,
when there is a breakthrough,
is that people feel this strong sense of
reconnection.
I'd like to know on a personal level
what experience used to have of people
in recovery taking these subsidiaries
because I'm in recovery.
I'd like to know about people with five,
10,
15,
20 years plus in recovery from drugs and
alcohol using these substances and
they're not going off and relapse in and
holding up a gas station and kicking
over some bins on their way out of the
lab there.
There's no evidence that psychedelics
promote relapse.
And,
and like I was saying earlier,
they're,
they kind of are sort of,
uh,
you know,
drugs apart from other drugs in a way,
they're not more wish than not addictive
in themselves.
In fact,
after psychedelic experience,
people often say either never again or
not for awhile.
You know,
even if it's,
if it's transformative and euphoric,
um,
they usually have to go through a tough
time to get there.
So they're not hedonic drugs really,
you know,
they're not hedonic.
Right.
Cool.
Hi.
Tell us some of your greatest hit.
Some of the things people have seen,
some of the things people have come back
with.
Gosh,
Chris too.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
okay.
I have one of our last participant,
uh,
she,
you know,
she was going through the pace of the
place of the geometry you see pushed
through,
but she couldn't push through any
further because there were some,
you know,
is not letting her go by and somehow a
bit kind of like punishing her because
of the audacity of going into this
realm.
Right.
Um,
so that was quite scary for her.
Right.
So this kind of like first entity
encounter,
but then slowly,
slowly she started,
you know,
kind of like going through this haze of
clouds.
Uh,
and then they were entities like
chanting all around her and healing her
as she came back from the experience.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
No.
Unless the clinical conditions and the
clinical conditions.
I'm still undecided because I live my
life one day at a time.
Wow.
That sounds pretty good,
doesn't it?
I mean even just the idea that there's
things in your unconscious mind.
I mean dreams are in themselves.
Evidence.
You don't need to take drugs to see that
there's stuff going on in your
unconscious mind that you don't know
about.
In fact,
just look at your own hand right now.
Some things pumping blood into it in not
conscious mind isn't deciding,
so we're.
We are continual evidence of our own
unconscious activity.
But for me,
the idea of these narratives and this
idea of external phenomena being
experienced not via the material world
or the central world,
but via some kind of other tellier
journey.
Is that the right word?
Some other teleology like there is
momentum and receipt of data without
going through the material world.
I liked the sounds of that very,
very much because that seems like,
you know,
like people say,
the reason the world's not changing is
because of a lack of vision because no
one's got a better idea.
You know that we live in a political
age,
risk forms of management and shift of a
percent here or there,
but the things that are interesting in
politics or about kindness and love and
compassion and oneness and socialism is
just,
we're all one.
We should look after each other and I
suppose capitalism is just do the bloody
best jacare where water got so like the
idea that there could be new data,
new information and empirical.
So that's what I think is important that
you're building material,
mechanical,
empirical bridges because the idea that
there is another vision within each of
us,
another way of being,
another version of yourself waiting to
be realized.
That's pretty exciting,
isn't it?
Anything else?
If you've got anything else for me and
you have stories of stuff you've seen.
What about when Terence Mckenna is
saying that he's seeing and like,
I like this idea about like some of the
things I heard two things on youtube I
liked.
One was a Peruvian Shaman who like,
uh,
you know,
obviously I've worked with plants in his
capacity as a shaman being given dmt in
clinical conditions.
And he described exactly as you did that
like,
you know,
bodily sensation,
the sensation of fort speeding up.
Then the idea then thought stopping then
this sort of personal sense of death of
like,
Oh my God,
they've ruined the,
messed up the dosage,
I'm gonna die.
And then realizing like that,
that's in fact personal death or death
of the ego.
And then sort of encountering other
entities.
I love that.
I love the sound of that to me.
Absolutely.
Bloody terrific.
One of the things he talked about is the
loss of time that he said that on his
way back from the experience,
if it goes off,
probably been gone for thousands of
years.
Hope there's some of my descendants
alive came back and he sort of said to
the conditions or anyone alive and.
Well yeah,
everyone's been gone 10 minutes mate.
So like a dmt experience is what,
like this is 10 minutes or something.
Yeah,
there's actually much less intense but
intense Buddhist like five minutes or
even three,
five minutes.
You are in a realm where sort of the
rules of the material world and the
physical world seemed to abate and you
experience things that are beyond your
own understanding,
beyond your own limitations of
consciousness.
One of the things I liked that Terence
Mckenna said,
if,
uh,
if you,
if those were to land on the White House
South Lawn,
it will be less impressive than what's
happened happened in your own
consciousness.
Your own consciousness on dmt reveals to
you.
But everything.
We understand the limitations and
prohibitions as the material and
physical world are,
but one frequency of being but one modem
of reality within us all.
There's this sort of different
potentiality.
An interesting interesting.
We don't have,
I don't have a Bunsen burner or the
beaker full of alkaline think.
It's interesting.
It's like this break down enough to
where you're seeing the world.
I mean this
is a really interesting thing and you
mentioned that at some point.
I mean this idea of transitioning into
another mode of being can be very
healing in itself as well.
And I think this is something that's
really striking about the experience and
why,
you know,
people build this very intense narrative
around them as well.
Yeah.
You know,
you could tell already that,
um,
we've got a slight bias,
or at least speaking for myself,
I have the,
you know,
the,
it even though it might feel like you
transcend the physical and material,
uh,
I'm not sure what to do because there's
no real evidence for that.
And what is the physical material in
these terms,
you know,
what would it mean to transcend it?
Maybe it's just the experience of
totality that the idea,
even the paradigm or the template that
suggests material and transcendence of
material,
is it materialistic or a limited idea?
I suppose psychologically things have a
psychological reality that in a way,
um,
you know,
or a different way of looking and
understanding things.
Then then looking at the biology and
know,
looking at the biology is a,
is an objective perspective and you look
at,
yeah.
Whereas,
you know,
this other perspective of feeling of
experiences inherently subjective and
it's hard.
It is hard to reconcile those things.
So they're,
in a way,
there is a sort of started to get a bit
philosophical with terms,
but like an inevitable journalism,
you know,
that there is a psychological reality to
these experiences that you can't,
and patsy shouldn't try and explain a
way with biology,
but you can let them both sit next to
each other and say when I,
you know,
I do know what maps onto that feeling
and that experience,
there's not,
you know,
and then you know it and if you want to
try and,
you know,
shatter a present sort of paradigms in
science and,
and,
and you have this belief hypothesis that
actually these breakthroughs into
another realm are actually literally
true and that you know,
that there are other dimensions and such
like,
then you've got a hypothesis and you can
go ahead and try and test it.
You know,
we haven't,
we haven't done that yet.
Leave something in there and I bring
something back from it.
Um,
yes,
that's interesting what I'm talking a
lot.
We mentioned at the beginning the idea
of a collective unconscious.
One of the,
perhaps the defining union idea is there
in the work that you've done with
psychedelics over your professional
lifetime,
is there an interesting consistency
across substances and of course
experiences that suggest that there is a
commonality to the conscious experience
of people using these
substances?
Wow.
Um,
yes,
but I'm,
and I guess one unifying,
uh,
um,
aspect of the experience is this feeling
of,
Oh my God,
you know,
myself was a construction,
that it,
that it was built up that it's not
absolutely real.
You know,
I think that's one thing that's,
that's common to everyone and then when
that is transcended another common
experiences that,
um,
the role,
wow.
No one wants that drug.
The,
Oh,
we're all one drug.
You better go to work.
I'm afraid I'm not going to pay your
mortgage.
Why you need to achieve more.
For what reason?
I mean,
it certainly presents a lot of questions
that might be challenging to keeping a
population behaving in a certain way.
Is it very,
very.
There's a lot of interesting stories and
I don't think they're a ttl,
uh,
under the skin.
A name of this show has ever been more
pertinent because a subcutaneous glance
at these inner world suggests the
potential for huge,
huge change.
I'm so grateful to both of you,
Robin and Chris for coming in and
explaining,
albeit in some cases tentatively,
but importantly very professionally and
I think still within the confines of
academia,
something that sounds like a wonderful,
wonderful mystery and when the Great
Brian Cox talks about physics is the
mystery and the wonder and the glory and
our attempts to understand and explain
it this fascinating in all forms of
discipline,
but when it comes to consciousness
itself,
not just one more phenomena,
but the crucible of all phenomena is
deeply,
deeply fascinating.
So thank you both of you very much.
Been a pleasure.
Really cool.
Who's got a syringe that you understand
you've been listened to under the skin
with Russell brand is.
It's not ironically with all sincerity
sponsored by my book recovery,
a new way of looking at addiction and
new way of looking at consciousness,
a new way of managing your own feelings
and your own life.
Go Russell brand.com.
We've had the website redesigned,
looks really good,
and all of the episodes are under the
skin on.
They're completely free for you,
as is the truth,
completely free for you,
completely free.
There's the message on the skin.
Thank you.