My mind is an award winning Canadian
writer and comedian who's performed sent
out seasons in Australia and Britain,
London nominated for best show at this
year's Edinburgh Festival.
Her current show,
Dope,
examines a lifetime of obsessions,
fandom,
and addiction.
She has appeared on BBC two live from
the BBC and comedy central,
and recently presented her critically
acclaimed series,
may Martin's guide to the 21st century
sexuality.
They wouldn't be an article before that
may mountains guide to 21st century
sexuality on BBC Radio Four.
May.
Martin,
thank you for joining me on under the
skin.
Thanks for having me.
I'm a fan of.
You seem like a pretty advanced person.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
You're an addict like me in recovery for
ages now.
I'm maybe 10 years.
Yeah.
How did you know that you,
uh,
had a problem with substances and that
you needed to change?
It was all kind of.
My teens were kind of explosive and I
started doing comedy really young.
I think you did.
It didn't,
you know,
as young as you like.
11 warning has.
Well,
when I was 11,
a comedian like got me up on stage and
made me be his ventriloquist dummy so I
wouldn't count that.
But when I was stand,
even though seeing that pioneering
experience,
yeah,
he,
uh,
I was in the front row,
I always loved comedy and then he got me
up and he said I'll squeeze the back of
your neck and you open your mouth and
I'll make you say stuff.
But he thought I was a little boy
because I was in like a three piece
suit.
And so he's making me say like filthy
stuff.
And Anyway,
it was fun and got lots of laughs and
then got obsessed with it.
Um,
yeah.
So then in my teens I started doing
drugs and I got kicked out of my house
and ended up,
my parents were,
well they read my diaries.
Actually I'd,
I mean rookie mistake had been keeping
these like meticulous diaries and they
found out all this stuff I've been
doing.
And then I guess their reaction was some
level of anger and they were doing tough
love.
So they said he can't live here anymore.
And then I think that was a 16.
I was very,
very young.
Yeah.
That's in Toronto.
Is it?
I suppose that's the age when I first
moved out when I was 16 or so.
Kind of in pursuit of addiction.
Yeah.
What made me leave except the addiction
itself.
Thinking about it now,
the reason that you're a fascinating
guest,
of course,
your within the field of comedy,
you highly respected and you're doing
brilliantly.
But also I suppose topically you're
doing stuff that's kind of defining of
our time.
You'll show before your last ones about
gender and gender identity.
You most recent shows about addiction in
a sense like in anglophone and can
possibly non anglophone countries.
These are determining ideas like whereas
people look to understand evolving and
dissolving forms of categorization.
We look for different ways to understand
ourselves.
Can you talk us through whether or not
that question is clever that I've just
or observation.
It wasn't really a question,
was it?
It's very clever,
very flattering.
Um,
but yeah,
I think uh,
when you hear the word spectrum a lot
and I think,
well with addiction anyway,
I think if you've had a problem with
drugs and then you've acknowledged I'm
an addict,
it can be quite isolating and you feel
like you're part of this kind of small
subsection of the world who just can't
handle their shit.
And then it's been,
I mean this is a really recent thing for
me just reading about it and learning
about like the biochemistry of it and
recognizing addictive behavior in other.
All this stuff you've been talking
about,
but I think you're further along with
it.
The man still like my mind is blown and
suddenly you're like,
oh,
it's a spectrum of behavior.
And I think it's the same thing with
sexuality.
You can think on this weird,
you know,
queer person and then you think,
well everybody has a sexuality and it's
a spectrum.
Yes,
it's extraordinary actually.
It's something I've only been learning
about because I'm probably substantially
older than you and I'm probably educated
in different way had difference of
cultural references.
When I see something like 40 percent of
people under 25 don't identify with a
sort of a homogenous sexual group in a
more interested in fluid of a,
you know,
even though I think of myself as sort of
a countercultural person,
I'm sort of.
Oh,
I know me too though.
I mean I'm 30,
I think of myself as pretty like cool,
but then I do gigs at universities and
like freshers wigs and there I don't
know the right terminology and I'm
putting my foot in my mouth and they're
so tuned into it.
They've got all gender neutral toilets
and they're all have crazy terms for
themselves and it's awesome.
That's great.
In a way it sort of makes sense,
I suppose at what you know,
someone of my age and older.
Is there a very clear identity?
Roles are very clear.
Social Roles and I,
I've been questioning a lot lately what,
how I would identify it and how I've
grown up if the conversation had been
more advanced in my own adolescence
because you know,
what the main feeling I had growing up
in a normal,
ordinary Essex home,
suburban home was not like the other
boys,
but turns out that the other boys
weren't like the other boys.
It's just that we're all magnetized to
an imaginary category.
And whilst there is,
you know,
I don't know,
Canada is one of the most sort of for
most places in there seems like there is
a biochemical basis for at least some
sort of biological and anatomical
aspects of gender.
Uh,
but,
but beyond that,
the way people identify,
demonstrate and represent their
sexuality seems like something that we
need to examine a look more closely.
What was your observations on that?
I think it's so
interesting.
I think all the way we're talking about,
it's all still in its infancy.
I think in 25 years it'll be so
different,
but it's so hard to sort of disentangle,
um,
cultural influences and stuff in terms
of gender roles.
And what's normal for men and women,
and you're right,
there is a biological thing,
but this also I'm in,
it's so hard.
Undo those early influences about what,
you know,
masculinity and femininity.
So yeah,
that's interesting.
I think if we can disentangle those
people be a lot less stressed,
I think
we're both sort of androgynous looking
people within our sort of basic gender
group.
You're quite a beautiful man.
Yeah.
I've been told I'm a handsome woman.
I get that a lot.
Yeah,
you're beautiful.
Like when I've been doing this,
when I've been doing this book,
stuff like,
you know,
when young people are coming to like
sort of signings into my show,
I've been having sort of conversations
that have really opened my mind up.
I was speaking to a young person and God
now we're gonna have to say they said,
you know,
identify as binary.
I don't identify with any particular
gender.
And I really felt myself on the
precipice of my own understanding,
my own linguistic abilities or my own
prejudices.
I.
What do you think is going to be the key
component here?
Because one of the things that I've
noticed around identity politics is
people that are sort of our traditional
or conservative often feel,
I think a lot of shame and a lot of
confusion and it can become quite
opposition or quite quickly.
Totally.
Um,
yeah,
I think it's easy to experience like a
real sense of vertigo about it because
it's just happened so exponentially
quickly and,
and there's all these new words and it
feels like I don't,
I don't know how you are at math and
stuff,
but I,
I used to get this panic and math class,
like when they would introduce things
like Algebra and I and I'd be like,
it just doesn't,
it's too much information and you just
dropped out of school pretty much
because I was like.
And I think people have that feeling and
I think the main thing is just asking
questions and then there's the
responsibility and the people who are
using these new words to explain
patiently and we can all just be
patient,
you know?
How,
how did you look at these themes in your
standup show?
Where are you personally on these ideas?
Identification I am,
I had,
my parents were real hippies and um,
yeah,
so growing up they were always,
this is,
I mean I'm only just realizing and for
moving to England,
like how unusual this is that when I was
a kid they would always say,
you know,
you'll grow up and you'll meet a man or
a woman and it always,
they just presented it as an equal
option,
but I saw who knows if that's by the.
I've always been bisexual,
I always dated men and women is,
I don't know if it's because they said
that or maybe they were like,
well she keeps wearing suits and like
we should have that three piece suit.
You added onto that magician show first.
You were overdressed for any gender
identity for a magic.
So tie and suspenders.
Yeah.
So I was lucky in that area,
so I've always been bisexual and that's
been great.
But yeah,
what I found surprising as a new father
have a female child grant.
Thank you.
It's blowing my mind like it's really
vacillates between this sort of
spiritual sense of Oh wow,
new consciousness as a merge glory.
Glory that she exists and kind of little
passed it out.
Get off me.
Like I said,
it really pendula experienced because no
control,
no off button,
extraordinary.
But I've become very sensitive in a way
that sort of surprises me around
identity.
Like I guess my wife is more traditional
than I am and puts like,
you know,
sometimes puts her in dresses and things
like that and sometimes I'm like I want
to just the way things are practical for
someone that can't walk up.
Right.
So she should just be wearing little
pants and stuff,
you know.
And,
and like I don't know because in a way
you could look at this is that very sort
of conventional,
an old fashioned idea that perhaps I'm a
man who sort of unconsciously wanted to
have a male child.
I don't feel that at all.
I don't like the,
I don't like any ornamentation of
femininity are now because it feels like
something's been put on her that's not.
She's not choosing.
Yeah,
they did this experiment.
I was get experiments wrong,
but I think this is where they had a
baby in neutral clothing in the room.
Have you heard this?
And then people would come in and play
with the baby and sometimes they'd say
it's a boy baby,
and then when they said it was a boy
baby,
everyone was like bouncing it really
aggressive,
not aggressive,
but really physical and always faced the
baby looking away from them.
And then when they said it was a little
girl,
they all turn the baby towards them and
just sort of cuddled in like,
yeah,
that's sort of.
So yes.
We're not really conscious of how I talk
to parents.
One of the things you hear a lot when
you become a bad as people say,
oh yeah,
but you know,
they just do start playing with vacuum
cleaners and if they're a boy they
immediately signed up to be in the
marines and he said,
no,
you were not aware of the unconscious
cues that we have achieved and I'm doing
that thing already.
Have a lot when people go,
because this is a question people like
to ask me on chat shows,
I like to go where you being such a
womanizer,
how are you going to feel when you do a
$6 industry?
Brings home a Russell Bronco.
She might not bring home a and she might
be a gay person.
You don't know who she's going to come
home with.
Such questions worked.
I did that too and my friend has an a
two year old niece and they came back
from some baby thing where they do.
Does your daughter do this trick monkey
music classes and stuff and all the
parents are like,
they're so talented like that.
So they.
They bring the two year old back in.
Then I hear myself going,
I guess in this smarmy way,
like do you have a boyfriend yet to the
to like I'm saying that.
Why am I doing that?
Yeah,
right.
Look at us.
We're not unaware of our own
conditioning,
so this is some like continually within
your standup comedy,
is this the kind of perspective you try
to have as a comedian?
Tell me a little bit about your process
of conception.
Like how did you come to the idea that
you were gonna write your very
successful show?
Dope.
Um,
I,
I guess it's like we were saying like I
always,
I've always wanted to talk about drugs
and that period and in my life,
but I guess I haven't felt like I have
enough distance from it or perspective
on it to do it in a way where I can keep
it really light and be in control of it.
And then I had a this breakup like two
years ago and it just felt
so similar to getting off cocaine.
Like it was.
I was like,
oh,
I know this feeling.
Exactly.
And then started reading about it and
then had this,
you know,
started seeing these patterns in all
areas of my life.
So then I started improvising it onstage
and it was way too dark and then just
slowly adding punchlines.
Is that what you do?
You do like a work in progress and it's
like too serious
and then you add,
you start off your development process
is to start with just being very,
very honest and personal uncomfortably.
So how do you feel what that stage of
development?
I really enjoy it.
I don't know what that kind of
masochistic sometimes isn't it?
Especially when you're like,
I know there's no punchline coming so
it's quite intense,
but I liked that and then every other
year in Edinburgh I do an improvised
show where people write down questions
and then I answer them and then it comes
out of that too because you get to know
what people want to hear you talk about
and yeah,
that's.
Yeah,
I like that idea.
I have a similar process for me,
my access point for comedy is to start
saying things that are truthful often.
Actually one of my guiding principles
is,
does this make me feel a bit ashamed?
Totally.
Your ears get hot.
Well,
I don't want people to know that about
me.
That's awful.
And then.
But that there's something about that
exposure.
So what,
if you don't mind me asking,
what kind of revelations were you making
about the breakup?
What kind of realizations did you have?
Just like,
I mean they've done,
they've compared brain scans,
haven't had like a coke addict and
someone who says they're madly in love
and it's so I just think the hormones
and things are insane and during the
break if I just,
I felt so not like myself and there's
such a.
So the right thing to do to end up with
a relapse and it just,
I was using all this terminology that I
was like,
God,
this is.
Yeah.
And,
and not the healthiest relationship to
love and how can you lose yourself so
completely in it.
Yeah.
So a damaging relationship.
It wasn't the best.
Yeah,
it was great.
And in a lot of ways,
but not,
not the best,
but yeah.
Alright.
Right.
They were punishing components to it.
I've only recently started,
you know,
like something sometimes I think I'm
really clever,
but then I realized,
no,
you're not clever,
you're like an idiot because everything
takes much too long to realize and
really sort of like,
I think like a convoluted,
complex neurological root to make the
most basic observations.
Like for sure it's healthy and nature is
healthy,
but I'm still working on nature is
healthy.
Very long thesis of examination of
grass,
the color green photosynthesis into
connectivity,
the role of oxygen.
I mean,
I'll look at that for ages before I
said,
well,
why don't you just go for a walk in the
woods you said,
so you know,
like it's taken me a long time to come
to terms with that.
But I noticed that my own tendency in
relationships without being disparaging
about the particular individuals I was
in relationships with was set up,
um,
dramatic situations,
producing situations.
And then it's so euphoric when you sued
that anxiety.
It's this weird cycle.
You see the agenda and obviously a
analogist to addiction that if you
continually find yourself at a place
where I'm not good enough,
they're never going to call.
I'm brilliant.
I'm fantastic now to maintain this.
Oh No,
fucking only pretend to be someone else
for another five years.
I believe we can have a child.
Exactly that.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and that is a little.
I mean sometimes I think that substance
addiction is the most rational form of
addiction because it's a direct route to
the good feeling instead of the other
ones are quite convoluted.
Yeah,
you're right.
and easier to control.
I mean,
as long as you have sort of a reliable
hookup,
access to cocaine and heroin or whatever
drug is young people take these days is
can be much easier than the sort of
giddy all for a vertiginous experience
of being in love.
Yeah.
So that's sort of what your show is
about is it is about how your drug
addiction as a young person leading,
you'll be expelled from the family home.
You found those patterns repeating
themselves in romantic situations.
Yeah,
I think I always just thought I got
addicted to drugs and then I went to
Rehab and then I've been clean ever
since and I never really thought about
it with much more depth and then now I'm
thinking or I mean early on when I was
about six,
I had mad obsession with Bette midler.
Like really?
I saw the world through this lens of Bet
Midler that just everything's in
relation to bet midler.
I was so obsessed with her.
Every is in relation to pet mate.
Yeah.
What would bet?
Think about this.
What's she wearing today?
Like I loved her.
I mean my grades were slipping at school
because I was just sitting thinking
about Batman and then comedy and then
drugs and then relationships.
Midler was your gateway?
Yeah.
What was it about?
What was it beat?
She's Hocus pocus at that.
The one where they are,
right.
So you're a little kid in Canada,
you're in a little three piece suit.
Literally this went,
I think I saw it 12,
13 times in cinemas and it just,
I mean it must've been at a sexual.
I must've had a crush on bet midler and
I just lost my mind.
I said,
she's so,
what is innovation capacity that she's
Sassy,
strong woman.
She'd take care of us.
Wouldn't she?
Like,
she tells us like it.
It's going to be okay.
Exactly.
Then hold on a minute.
It's getting a bit sexual and she'd sort
of cut you down quite cruelly,
but then you know what I mean?
It would be a benefit flash and then
beck goes,
what are you going to do with that
little thing called me out and she goes,
oh,
there you go.
Oh God,
actually I'm getting into like,
you're looking at her lovingly.
And she's like,
why don't you take a picture?
It'll last longer.
Oh,
come on and off for you.
Like,
um,
once I saw her accepted an award at the
Golden Globes and she said,
how about these couple of Golden Globes
gesturing to no breasts?
Yeah,
that's her style.
And some food went all unusual in me,
but something glitched eman.
I've felt a feeling feeling in my tummy.
All unusual.
Now,
do you think this is something
essential?
Because obviously bet midler isn't gay
icon.
Yeah.
Odd.
Before you would have had any over or
cultural sense of a gender or sexual
identity that you would automatically
found yourself to sort of some sort of
quintessential figure within the
Pantheon.
Yeah,
you're right.
I mean maybe it was just into witches as
well though.
I any kind of design,
which is a bit.
There was another one when they were
metal street,
one of the others or something.
Sarah Jessica Parker could have gone for
that yet.
Not into it.
Just because she was the most evil I
think.
Um,
and her voice and.
Yeah.
No,
I don't know.
Yeah,
it must've been.
That happens a lot though.
I mean I was obsessed with scary spice,
so as a child and then now I'm like,
well,
she's kind of a gay icon to look at
that.
So it's weird,
isn't it?
Because I think a lot about constructs
cultural,
whether or not we're attaching to these
things or if there isn't a central truth
in a way this crosses over with some of
young's ideas of synchronicity that
there is something happening on a
psychic level that is relating to the
objective world.
Whereas of course the materialist will
tell you know,
these,
these are just over patterns that
signify nothing.
Things are there,
material value.
But if you as a little kid into Ron,
I've somehow happened upon gay icon,
not in a particular content and I know
you are.
Your identity is more complex than that,
but it's just interesting that,
that figure is she.
Because I've never understood.
It's not like Bette Midler,
she's not gay or anything.
Is it a particular person?
Yeah.
I think it's her,
her confidence and,
but yeah,
you're right,
I guess.
Um,
yeah.
When,
when people in huge numbers respond to
the same thing quite emotionally,
then yeah.
That there must be some universal.
Yeah.
Youngian thing that you're responding to
it.
It can't be just that there's a great pr
team or whatever.
There must be some central resonance
now.
Where did you graduate to a after Bet
Midler,
not necessarily in terms of crushes,
in terms of your,
uh,
what would you feel like your next
attachment and then comedy.
So yeah,
when I was 11 and 13 niche comedy and I
started doing standup when I was,
I had braces and I'd be in my school
uniform and come from school smoking
this weird sort of circus act and um,
did it every night of the week.
And,
and that's a highlight.
Any other isn't it?
Very much,
but what was your APP like?
You say,
well,
you've got some props,
I'm guessing.
No,
I just,
I was,
I mean I went through so many different
just imitating people based because I
didn't know who I was.
I was,
I wonder phase where I was just doing,
but basically bill Hicks and then
smoking,
smoking three piece suit,
a little kid like character knighted
character stuff and just tried all kinds
of things.
All so terrible.
Thank God.
Like no one had smartphones.
Isn't it interesting?
One of the things I identify with the
May is this idea of being a little kid
and not feeling particularly connected
to the place where I was and feeling a
little bit lost and adrift and for,
for me,
like,
you know,
when a first sort of via my cousin's
heard the smiths and then sort of looked
into the character of Morrissey,
so I'd think,
oh,
okay,
this guy and let you know that they're
someone that's beautifying outsiderness
and vulnerability and that's,
that can be a bit of an access point.
And then like through Morrissey you get
to learn about,
oh,
Morrissey's interchange deems you start
getting into that type of cinema and
Morrissey's into Oscar Wilde.
You start learning about Oscar Wilde and
you know,
then you get into aesthetics is
interesting,
isn't it?
How sort of,
you know,
like as opposed as a person.
My framework for understanding reality
is spirituality and specifically
spirituality through the Lens of
addiction.
So it's about understanding how I form
attachments,
but culture does have a great potency
and can be a way to understand yourself
in a situation in the world.
It has great beauty in it,
so and like Bill Hicks again was a very
significant figure for me because like,
you know,
in I suppose slightly more sophisticated
way and perhaps a more mature way,
I don't know because I was an adult when
I first saw Bill Hicks and thought,
Oh my God,
that's how you're supposed to do stand
up comedy.
I've been very curious to be a tiny
little kid and trying to appropriate
that kind of stuff.
Yeah,
I guess I must have.
I mean it's hard to remember how I felt
at the time and I must've felt a sense
of otherness and then especially in high
school and probably feeling a bit gay
and then go in and find in a comedy club
where people were not only like
declaring what was different about them
and weird,
but then being applauded for it and
yeah,
that's probably pretty mind blowing.
Is it true here?
I'm just looking at my notes that you've
turned up smoking a cigarette like quite
early,
like you were smoking cigarettes on
stage.
I just thought comedian smoke.
I thought that was that scene,
like Richard Pryor and stuff.
So I,
I,
uh,
yeah,
I went on with a cigarette and people
were just,
I mean there were so it was silent,
but they were,
it was like concerned silence because
they were like,
who has allowed this to happen?
Who should we,
should we notify and yeah,
there's some notification so that you
will,
it was the famous
second city of the second series I
started in Chicago,
but it's sort of like a byword for sort
of improvisational brilliance and sort
of the sort of vanguard of comedy.
Right.
So you were involved when you were
little kid in that world.
We're,
yeah,
I started.
Um,
yeah,
I started out there for a few years and
then,
uh,
and then eventually when drugs kind of
took over and replaced comedy,
then I got banned from second city for
two years from.
And that was devastating because I loved
it and idolized all those people.
And I think suddenly everyone twigs,
oh,
this person is too young to be so high
all the time in this building.
So then I got banned from there.
But what we're doing,
I mean everything like mostly coke was,
it was the big one.
Yeah.
I was disposable cash from comedy to.
I think I just don't give a teenager any
money.
I know it's a very natural conclusion to
have reminders attended.
What are you going to do?
Can't do what?
Buy Models and factory.
And even then there's the clue.
So you,
you're going to find your way to
substances.
If you've got cash you can pay with cash
in hand for gates much.
Yeah.
And then it's around and,
and then I guess I obviously had this
predisposition because a lot of people
to coke and never want to do it again.
That's right.
Yeah.
We have the predisposition.
Are you doing drugs with adults?
Yeah.
Big Time.
That's weird,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Looking back,
I think it's weird.
At the time it felt so natural because I
wouldn't give a child drugs not going to
come out on a limb.
Yeah.
But so I suppose thinking about it,
the first time I got heroin it was often
children,
like they really.
So far,
I mean I've got that now.
If they were Turkish,
I've always assumed they were Turkish,
but that's just my personal bigotry
because they were so young,
dark skinned,
glads in Hackney,
19 myself,
but they were possibly 13.
They're adorable,
jared guys to skinning up with heroin
and I've got some off of him.
Absolutely.
Terrific.
Because you might imagine,
and really that's of it is
interestingly,
so you've,
you've had the access to the world of
comedy now,
but you sort of blended headlong into
the,
into diction,
I suppose you were dealing drugs as
well.
Yeah,
I was very,
I think I was with these adults who were
doing drugs.
I think it was very convincing about not
being a teenager.
I mean they knew I was,
but I was.
I think I really did my best to put
everyone at ease with doing drugs with
me and,
and it's not a big deal.
And so I don't,
you know,
they weren't villains,
but there are definitely some
inappropriate behavior for sure.
Yeah.
That's not judge them.
What about the,
uh,
the drug dealing in any good at drug den
and we're now tell me the key problems.
Just it just terrible at it,
bad at math,
but at selfcontrol I'm sort of going a
lot of people,
a lot of money gets quite scary very
quickly.
Um,
yeah.
Probably you broke biggie smalls.
He's golden rule.
Don't get high on your own supply.
Learned from biggie theaters.
I did a small amount of miserable
measly,
unsuccessful drug dealing myself.
Yeah.
My mate mark gave me quite a lot of
amphetamines.
He said sell that your school and you
couldn't make some profits and this
business model.
But the problem was is that I was
friends with a couple of bigger boys and
like took some of those drugs and I
couldn't keep charging them because of
just,
it was like they was too much fear in
the relationship and I ended up swapping
my bicycle and I took too much of them
amphetamines and it ruined my
performance was macbeth,
if I may say so I think I'd feel a lot
better.
I would pay so much money to see you
doing macbeth as a teen.
He wouldn't have liked it maybe because
it was regarded as a failure when you
were at drama school.
They divide up a play into all the
various,
you know,
like,
because everyone's got to have a go at
being macbeth in it.
I was just doing one bit the bit I was
doing this,
it's just murdered king down Kinedyne.
I feel familiar with the play and he
comes out with the DAC is right or sort
of he's just done a terrible murder and
it feels awful about it and I shouldn't
have done it.
But because I wasn't the type of actor
would do any prep instead of crap.
I fought speed.
Right.
So I've done some speed instead of like
learning about dockers and murders and
stuff like that.
So I come staggering out as a kite.
We've got butter knives out of the
canteen.
But.
So the fact that you wouldn't be able to
murder a king with those butter knives.
Richard.
And did you had you learned the words or
not?
Oh yeah.
I learned those words,
but I think what it would have been like
an amphetamine drug.
It's going to make you.
I think it doesn't put you in the pit of
your belly.
It takes you into,
puts you into the upper Chakras,
whereas I think doing a murder,
you'd probably be really in your guts.
It's very earthy thing,
isn't it?
To murder someone,
particularly for your ad out to do it
with a butter knife.
You'd been plunged into those ribs.
You'd have.
I mean,
your pupils are dilated to be sweaty,
but yeah,
you're right.
I know I fought that while I was doing
was a good job,
but you know at the end when they tell
you whether or not you had done a good
job,
the teacher said that was not a good
job.
Unanimously.
Only one lad in the year below said off
what you were good the way you've done
that.
It was mental.
I said,
thanks.
I'll clean mark where he was not a
person whose opinion could be relied
upon and it doesn't have any Kudos
within the school system.
Certainly I couldn't use it to press,
you know,
that loud in the low year for I was
good.
Well,
whereas when I was in year four,
I guess maybe I was eight or nine,
I did Charlie Brown and I played Charlie
Brown is like my crowning moment in
school and uh,
I took it so seriously that I did this
monologue in it and I cried real tears.
Like I really went for it and there was.
So,
I mean,
it's like,
it's a comedy.
Everyone was horrified.
They thought something had gone wrong.
And why was it about Charlie's monologue
that made you think tears would be
appropriate?
My,
well,
I'll tell you,
he's sitting at lunch and there's this
girl over there and she's ignoring him
and he just wants to share his peanut
butter sandwich and then he,
he's like,
oh,
nobody likes me.
And that I really went for it.
I got a really felt that my parents were
like waving at me,
crying a little ice age,
floods of tears.
Charlie Brown over what some would think
of as a minor misdemeanor,
but I think in that were the seeds of
what would become a great career as a
performer.
One of the things you've talked about in
your show a dope is sort of neurological
and scientific representations of what
you've experienced personally.
Just a little bit about that.
Well,
I mean,
I've watched some Ted Talks I've read.
I definitely will get it all wrong I
think,
but I think there's this some addiction
specialist called Gabor metallic.
Do you know him?
Yeah.
I'm fascinated by him.
I was reading this book last night and I
think we're going to get him on this
podcast.
I interviewed him for him and he's like,
he could have a cult.
He's so amazing.
His voice is so deep and he'd be.
He'd love to speak to him.
We interviewed him.
Tell me all about it.
Well,
he,
he talks about dopamine levels and I'm
like,
uh,
if you.
One of the theories is if you have a
dopamine deficiency,
then when you do get a hit of that
pleasure chemical,
it's so overwhelming and then the
cravings really intense.
So that's what he talks about and about
looking at the origins of addiction and
in early childhood where your brain
chemistry is all getting wired up and
stuff like that.
But that can be quite uncomfortable.
I think looking at your own early
childhood,
I don't know.
I.
It's hard as an because you want to take
full responsibility for all your actions
and you never want to feel like you're
casting blame,
especially on your parents who you.
But everybody.
I mean we're so fragile and we've all
got weird.
You know,
one of the challenges I think my,
if the logical model of addiction is the
kind of places people that are addicts
in the position of a kind of sufferer
through anything about it and we'll
Poli.
It also lets the culture of the hook.
You know,
where there is sort of so many cultural
forces that you want imagined and it
seems to suggest exacerbate addiction
inequality,
poverty,
persecution in talking particularly
about within America.
But it's true.
It's interesting to note the theories of
the dopamine deficiency could be the
biochemical root of what we identify as
addiction.
And it would also make sense of the idea
that the patterns are replicated
regardless of the object,
whether it's a sort of a crazy
relationship of substance,
a career in comedy or Bet Midler who
sort of chasing the same thing.
Yeah,
exactly.
And I think,
um,
I'm also been really interested in.
I didn't realize how like how malleable
we are and how your,
how,
how you can affect your brain chemistry
with just things like your social
environment.
I mean even now as adults and you can
boost your dopamine levels of exercise
and things.
I just didn't know.
We were so malleable.
You're right,
you had a sort of a fatalistic model of
just like,
Oh,
I'm just this,
this is how I feel.
This is something I'm learning that now
go and live in the country.
Don't stimulate yourself into a frenzy
to meditate twice a day,
do exercise,
don't look at pornography.
Like sort of like very sort of simple
rules of how to create a spice in your
consciousness.
That's pleasant.
I'm still getting there.
You've.
Yeah,
everything he said.
That sounds so nice.
Why?
What's your life like now?
My mind just running around,
I'm on my phone a lot.
I don't know.
I probably drank too much.
I mean,
but I,
you know,
I exercise,
I eat,
I eat really well.
I'm trying to like,
it's balance isn't it?
I know I should live in the country.
I should live in the woods,
but it's hard,
isn't it?
Yeah.
It's pretty hot down.
Then would say,
well why haven't you got embraced an
abstinent model if you've identified as
an addict's quite early in your life?
And I'm going to be a really puritanical
and judgmental now for a bit.
It's a good question.
I mean,
I don't,
I,
yeah,
yeah.
I've never,
I don't drink every day.
I look good.
I know you're right.
I think the next thing to go probably,
but um,
your foot a,
you're successful.
So.
But it,
what is interesting when you in that
position,
because I had these weird little rushing
early life.
I was like 24 and I was being on MTV and
I had a radio show on Xfm.
Maybe it was even coming out of one of
these bloody rooms,
like this one was certainly this
building,
but I'd like at that point was
escalating as a drug addict,
you know,
when you sign,
when you,
as a young person you had access
suddenly to ready money,
like just addiction fuel,
what they must have paid me.
Heroin saved me the exchange,
you know,
so like now that you're,
now that you're at this position,
you're becoming successful,
you're on the precipice,
I would imagine have a sort of a
different kind of success,
that tipping point where we're probably
going to get your own TV show soon
possibly,
or make a film and those kinds of things
we're probably going to happen.
So like what are you going to do to stay
stable?
Straight and narrow?
I think,
um,
I mean I,
I've practiced pretty rigorous,
um,
you know,
therapy and things.
I go to Ebay and I and I surround myself
with really good people and yeah.
So you're in support groups and during
therapy I go to support groups and I'm
also in fair Ipi and I'm always,
what I'm continually looking for is what
is the most recent,
you know,
like or covenant rather,
what is the current manifestation of my
addictive behavior and that's when it
starts to give them the,
as we've talked through your root in a
sort of a seemingly innocuous and
culturally recognizable and acceptable
forms of addiction,
right?
Until he eventually necessarily in fact
deposits you if you're an extreme.
Addicts were right in the ass end of
chemical dependency or if you'd have a
less severe strain,
one can hover along,
you know,
sort of in banal forms of mental tyranny
through addiction.
Me,
what I have to do is sort of like look
at like the thing that I like about a 12
step recovery,
the top recovery I believe in is it
brings you to a place that's
recognizable from other forms of
spirituality.
I stay in the moment trying not to be so
self obsessed.
Do Service for other people,
like things that like,
oh,
this crops up in every bloody religion.
This doesn't,
it sort of really,
really works.
That stuff keeps cropping up.
It's got to be the route to the solution
for sure.
I think,
um,
yeah,
being vigilant and uh,
I got to get into nature though.
I mean it's,
I'm really bad with technology.
How are you with that with your five?
Like if I like what I've done now,
my friend over there,
Jenny who works here,
I don't have my password no more for um,
for twitter because what I do is I tell
myself I'm just because I'm on a book to
just having a look for business reasons
for long,
you know,
you get too deep into it and those,
all of those apps are designed now.
People that have been there come from
Silicone Valley and works and those
projects are saying,
you know,
that will deliberately designed to sort
of trigger a response.
It's not painful.
You might decide that they're attractive
and appealing.
That's what you do.
You're not going to make an APP.
So it's bloody bullring done to do that,
isn't it?
It's crazy.
And everyone,
I mean everyone kind of casually says,
oh yeah,
we're all addicted to our phones and
it's like,
no guys,
we are all addicted to our phones.
It's quite,
it's quite bad guys because like one of
the things I've said in this article
that was written in the Guardian the
other day was that like,
is something that your attention is
being continually competed for.
You don't.
You don't know how to come down.
But sometimes the desire to look at my
phone is so overwhelming.
It's ridiculous.
Things like light and the guy,
this guy that designed the like button
for facebook before that,
it had been some other type of button.
He came up with it.
It's just some sort of 13.
I don't know how he does it,
drop it.
I can't even conceptualize my mind.
But you came up with a light button.
He says he don't even bring his phone
upstairs no more.
He plugs it in,
in the kitchen at 7:00
PM and that's it.
That's the end of it.
He's like it.
He's had his personal assistant deep
like take all the child proofing on his
phone.
So he himself can't download apps,
so the people that know the score about
tech saying watch it because David
Foster Wallace perspicacious Lee 10
years ago or whenever he sadly died was
saying we're going to win this before
handheld phones.
Really,
I think,
you know,
suddenly smartphones,
he was saying we're not far away from a
society where you're staring at a screen
all the time and the people on the other
side of it don't love you and they just
want to sell things to you.
And now we are living in that.
Yeah.
And it's also worrying with parenting
and stuff.
I mean you see families out and there's
this screen between the child and the
parent and uh,
yeah,
that actually,
that doctor talks about it,
about gap or does,
he says it's because it's not a physical
separation with the child,
but it's proximal separation because
you're not making eye contact,
you're not connecting.
And that stuff is so crucial for brain
development.
What does that mean?
Proximal separation?
I have no idea.
I think it means not physically
separated,
but you're separate because you're in a
different space.
Ultimately like approximate
approximately proxy.
Yeah.
Right,
so the little kid in this case,
my little kid in the night garden on
this bloody special ipad that bought for
children because a like the thing is is
that the child does prefer in the night
guard than to us.
It's like given the choice,
like if you asked it,
it was you want to live with in the
night guards or your parents would go in
the night guard and I don't even care
about them.
They're idiots on board,
particularly if that one with the beard
been like that is what people might call
it,
a cheap joke,
but it's a joke nonetheless to be
encouraged in my ongoing quest to make
up jokes.
Yeah.
Come in and my mindset is you identified
as an addict quite quite early in your
life.
You're a person that's on the periphery
and precipice of interesting cultural
ideas.
You're old enough to understand it and
to present it.
You've been working from lived
experience,
mirror,
important,
fascinating.
Figure.
Tell me what you're going to do now.
I'm about to go on tour.
Oh yeah,
but it's my first tour of dope.
Yeah,
it's a very different tour.
The show called dope.
Yeah.
And it's uh,
I'm getting untrained,
some stain and ibis hotels.
I'm doing it tomorrow.
Yeah.
No,
I mean they got like a machine in the
corridor that sells food.
Yeah.
And it's even be in the bed and also
washing your hands at the same time.
There's like a little sink like the
bathroom is within.
That could be convenient in some
circumstances,
but mostly it's troubling.
Yeah.
My best hotels.
I'm an Ivus hotel option bird.
You're washing your hands in the sink.
You're laying there in the bed.
You're on tour.
How you started?
No,
I start tonight.
I'm going to Oxford and then a local
playhouse,
a glee club.
Glee Club.
Ready for this?
The glee club for your whole touring
life?
Yeah,
I think so.
It's not that crazy.
It shows a week.
Something about 18 shows in total,
so it's pretty cash.
I think I'll get friends to come visit
me and I think it'll be fun.
And then I meant to be writing a book
about,
um,
for,
for 14 year olds about sexuality.
So.
And write it while I'm on tour.
Hold on.
Let's quickly promote properly the main
mine in a standup show.
Dope.
How do people get tickets for that?
Um,
I think they're on May,
Martin Dot net.
Go on my mind.
Don't net buy tickets to see my mind.
What can I anticipate in this show?
I hate that question when I'm asked it.
Let me see if I can pose it better.
Tell us something about your show
please.
That's good to promote it.
I mean it's everything we just talked
about,
but with them jokes kind of.
What kind of meetings do you go in?
Are you mostly in this type of mood or
do you sometimes go jacket and Matt or
shouty or like,
you know,
your Charlie Brown performance?
I mostly like there's,
I guess I guess I get a little more
energetic,
but I'm mostly like this extremely
affable banks.
I think I'm,
I think I'm affable onstage.
I'm,
yeah,
you're likable,
aren't you?
I tell you what's good is,
um,
while dealing with this complex new
language around identity and,
and people,
the older people having to reexamine
their unconscious prejudices is nice to
meet people that are potentially able to
explain and convey that information,
but don't press buttons that you know
decade or so ago would have prevented
progress.
I get loads of people.
Well,
one more when I talked about sexuality a
lot on stage,
I'd get people bringing their parents
and then coming out to their parents in
front of me.
Like they'd,
they'd wait to meet me and then they
choose that moment to say to their
parents,
actually I'm,
I'm gay.
And I'm so not equipped to kind of
mediate that exchange.
But it was amazing and I guess they,
the parents had just seen the show.
So they're feeling of,
you know,
they were in a positive mood and,
and then one time a girl said,
I'm data,
I'm bisexual.
And then her dad said,
yeah,
me too.
It was crazy.
I know.
And then they asked if I wanted to go to
ga,
why our CEO Bisexual?
And he was fucking every night he's
like,
why do you think I have this earring?
He literally said that.
That's my boss texture.
Leering that are way out.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
Because you go like the priest of a
coming out into sort of a modern gender
fluidity and sexual fluidity and freeing
yourself from previous paradigms.
I'm more,
I feel like I'm a ill-equipped
sometimes,
but I get people off and confessing
their gay things to me.
Like people going,
my wife is in the toilet,
but I just need to tell you.
I did give a blow job once and I'm like,
okay,
cool.
Yeah.
I'd love to show that just using you as
a sort of a vessel for their shame about
their sexuality is a great pity,
isn't it?
That we've become unable to live our own
shadows.
That our culture has taught us,
that there are aspects of our sexual
self and identity self.
They're unacceptable.
I don't want to live feeling shame and
stuff and nothing's going to come see
your show.
God knows what the post show river.
I don't know what was going on.
I kind of stuff.
Do you get,
I'm now talking about addiction.
Do you get loads of people coming after
shows and talking about their own
experiences?
Yeah,
there's been a slight hiatus in.
It was.
I've been deliberately and studiously
promoting the book.
I've not gone back.
I'm back onto,
hey,
this is good.
I'm back on tour,
so like I'm going to be like Ross
brand.com.
I'm on tour again for the next six
months.
Right?
Yeah,
and as you I'm sure are aware,
I do my level best to appear messianic
and romantic while on stage.
Go into the as even in the intervals to
solve swan about like some classes with
ccs of all like,
oh,
you'd really like it.
Like I imagine it's the end of old show
now.
You're going to be happening now,
right?
Y'All could be off somewhere.
You should be enjoying your maltesers.
Oh No,
I'm just wandering around in the
auditorium.
Positive my top off looking all I'm sad
about something on the age of my mind
about saying he wouldn't understand.
It's too deep.
Then people come up and like maybe get.
So my friend Matt,
or do the radio show,
we've.
I've seen too many folks are on
instagram looking at your to impressing,
walking through touching babies and the
dash.
Right.
I'm doing a lot of that.
Yeah.
Just very entrepreneurial.
Like I said,
like why don't you try a bit of that
walking around.
Yeah.
I'm very available to available after
the show.
Are you a single person currently?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh,
that's dangerous on tour,
isn't it?
I mean people.
Yeah.
I do get a lot of couples actually.
That seems to be my niche.
Like we want to have a go.
That's the propositions I get from that.
I think.
I don't know if it was because of the
old inculcation and acculturation early
in life,
but I've never been that at ease around
males and sex.
I've been at an orgy where there's been
men and I was a younger man.
I was involved in a few free sums that
had to man in them.
I don't need the gentleness.
A nurturer of femininity very much
resonated with me.
When you talked about Miss Midler's,
Po Matriarch,
some of the energy I'm going for,
of course,
that sort of literally a married man
with a baby and incredibly happy now,
but if we're going to talk about one
sexual brand,
is that stuff but you couples,
is it?
I get,
I get.
I get propositions from couples.
Yeah.
Post your show.
It sounds amazing.
Blow Job Punch.
Hey,
I'm going to go.
Why do you want to come home with us
right now?
Coming on May.
It's pretty exciting.
Yeah.
I mean I just get straight back into
bloody cabin.
Back to the MYP.
I spoke to a manager.
I'll be slamming that vandal shut.
Locked me away.
And the Ivus.
Yeah.
Is that really an Egyptian bird?
I think so.
It sounds like that might be true.
It's probably some sort of store
probably deliver of new life.
I mean why would they have selected that
word will work out eventually everything
reappropriated by the corporate world.
Everything rebranded.
So do you ever take up these couples on
their mat,
officer,
Mr.
wildly inappropriate personal question,
isn't it?
Why would you answer that?
Um,
I ha,
I have but not post show.
Yeah.
You got to meet up any good or do you
get sort of caught up in the social
dynamics?
I think if I think,
I wouldn't mind if it was three
individuals who just met my favorite
days because with a couple they've got
their own thing.
They keep telling each other.
They love each other throughout.
Oh yeah.
Newer on the age.
Nobody loves me once as a younger man in
freer and more liberal type day from
love.
Share your beautiful say that.
Uh,
like I,
I was sleeping with two humans and them
to humans really liked each other more
than me,
but I just thought it was nice that they
found each other via me.
If they weren't,
they were very happy together.
So it was quite amazing because it
crossed over from carnality and it was
the thing that sort of interests me
about sex.
Actually.
I've never been an overt mechanized ca
conventionally mail person.
It's actually,
I do enjoy the opportunity tunity for a
kind of transcendent union that can
occur that there is even in the most
promiscuous in fleeting encounter as a
kind of thing that feels like love very
much and it can't be sustained in a
relationship,
but you're not asking it to do that if
you're just banding about the hybrid.
I'm banding about.
I agree though.
I think,
um,
those.
I mean,
you're just getting a hit of those
hormones.
That's the same feeling of just as A.
Yeah,
temporary.
that's right.
I sort of want said like the,
uh,
well,
why is longevity?
The key component?
You can fall in love with someone just
in a moment and that's enough.
In fact,
George Orwell writes,
and I quote this a lot,
it's on the first page of homage to
Catalonia,
one of the few pages of homage to
Catalonia that read it goes like he's in
line to sign up for Poom or some
anarchist group to fight in the Spanish
civil war.
And the bloke in front of him was this
Italian gazer with ginger beer.
And he said he loved him and he knew
that he could love him,
like just in that moment and he's never
sort of saw him again because there's
something about the man that was very,
very beautiful and you know,
these sort of senses of solidarity that
can occur in crisis.
This thing that we are looking for is
connection.
Definitely.
I think.
Wouldn't it be nice if,
because I hate breakups.
I hate it.
I don't know why we do it,
but I think I'm imagining if there was a
two week time limit,
so you meet someone,
you fall in love but you both go
microchip or something.
But if you after her weight,
I haven't thought it through as much.
I'm done with this.
It make someone two weeks months,
two weeks haven't like euphoric and then
you both know after two weeks you got to
never see each other again.
This is all good.
It's good because it prevents any
attachment.
Yeah.
I don't know to be heartbreaking if I
got two weeks.
The one thing about like marital life or
not one but one thing.
One of the many things we might listen
to this,
she won't,
she don't care about my career,
one of the many things just in case one
of the many things that I like about my
old life is the sense and I had it this
morning when I got out of bed.
It's like,
oh please God,
be going to bed with this person again
tonight and I don't have to worry no
more and hopefully this life will be a
continuation of going to bed with this
person and then one of us will die.
That's terrible.
At the end.
Will building in your version yams in a
fortnight too much,
too quick.
I know you're right.
I mean my,
my parents are.
I'm madly in love.
They'd been together.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
Having that model of monogamy there,
there.
I mean crazy.
Like talk about their sex life all the
time and just you can just see it there.
Hang on each other's words.
It's crazy.
So I guess that can happen.
Also,
it's given you,
it seems like you've been developed in a
crucible where you've been able to
embrace yourself outside of what was
formerly known as convention.
Now what about this book you're writing?
That sounds quite fascinating.
Tell me a bit more about that.
Well,
that's tricky.
How do you,
how do you do it?
How do you hit deadlines and be
disciplined about it?
So tricky.
I'm trying to write it now because it
was a day.
What's the total 50,000
words a day?
You've got to make that commitment,
but it might be hard for you to do it
while you're on tour,
but it flows out of you.
I'm like typing like this and uh,
I um,
yeah,
but it'll be good.
It's the,
the idea is to write the book that you,
that I wish I had when I was 14.
Brilliant about sexuality.
It's a sort of fluid sexuality and so
cool.
And then how's it going to work?
So I don't know.
Oh,
I had to write it.
You're not the pragmatic.
What is this?
What did you wish you had when you were
14 year old?
You?
Um,
well I guess I had a unique experience
that my parents were amazing,
but it's,
um,
it's a combination of pr,
embarrassing personal anecdotes about
sexuality,
want to do and embarrassing anecdote to
one to one do an embarrassing anecdotes.
I mean,
I think I'm going to tell this story
about my brother when he was a toddler.
One underneath the.
This is not embarrassing to me.
So it's easy to volunteer people.
We all heard about an article titled
Under the Table And my dad was like a
nudist.
He's always naked and uh,
has an enormous penis.
My father and he is sitting there and my
brother toddled under the table and bit
that the tip of my dad's Dick.
And um,
my dad,
I forget what the punchline of the
story,
fine one because of the story is your
profit.
So if we don't find some conclusion,
we're all left with the image I know to
do with helping 14 year old come out
with gender fluidity.
Now so far what we've got massive willy
little profit goes onto the Typo by
showed that on the Willie and we've made
the wrong choice with anecdotes asked
for an embarrassing one.
Well that was challenging.
That was a challenge though.
I think.
What the.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's the only dirt I have in my brother.
He's lived the cleanest life and I
remind them of it.
So that's good to keep me with your
property is just trying to get on with
his life as a professional person.
Here I am doing this.
That on the tape.
So that's before you start judging me
for being at the vanguard of new
identity politics and being a book
geiling and Roger in this one.
The finger up on the stage,
there's never forget that day were you
bit down,
but they all got new.
Stopped bringing out when he says,
Oh,
I've never done anything with the guy.
And I go,
well,
dad's massive deck and the emphasis of
the size,
which in a sense the story didn't need.
No,
I know you did that,
which I think gave the story real sort
of white.
He never watches this here.
Is it a brother or your dad?
Either.
We don't want anyone and that it was
meant to be an embarrassing story about
you may.
Yeah.
Where is that story?
Um,
I,
uh,
I talk about,
um,
I,
my first boyfriend was called Ian Peach
and uh,
that was his real name and then um,
we,
he broke up with me and um,
and then years later I was doing an
interview and they said,
why do you think you're gay?
Which is tricky question and I'll also
just a lot of assumptions in that
question,
but I,
yeah.
And I just panicked and said,
well,
maybe nph.
But they misquote him in.
They heard maybe eating a peach and so
it was a bizarre and they refuse to
change it.
They're like,
that's what you said.
No,
he page.
Look here,
we're using the yearbook.
Yeah,
no,
that doesn't make sense.
I'll put page,
but he in a page that was half,
let's face it,
powerful potent undertones,
which seemed to have been present
throughout much of this interview.
And occasionally they spike into
awareness in some ghoulish familial.
The image of you in an ips bed.
My mom has a google alert set up with my
name,
you know,
anytime my name comes up,
she gets an email,
so then she got an email with that
interview about eating a peach was I got
this phone call like it's really how you
feel as if we gave your brother the same
peaches.
I don't know what there was so stressed
about it.
And your father must be a man that's
constantly on the precipice,
worrying about the tip of his John
Really off fall under the offspring,
but yeah.
Yeah.
Extraordinary and magnificent person.
You are.
Let's make sure that we've covered
everything that we need to cover.
Right?
You're writing that book.
Can everyone please calm down?
Right?
Is that you're definitely going to call
it.
That one's not going to be out.
I don't know if you've got other ideas.
I'm coming out and calm down.
Sounds quite good.
Quite good.
Might be too long,
but I quite like it.
I'm not very good at titles.
Quite good.
July comes out.
Good.
Brilliant.
And also,
you're on tour now and we should go to
my mind.net
to get our tickets when I'll come and
see you.
I'll come and see you somewhere.
That'd be great.
Maybe we're in the same place at the
same time,
right?
I mean that'd be confusing for the
audience.
Be Very silly.
That's the second joke.
In an hour timeframe for a man calling
himself a professional comedian,
charging money.
Zero jokes.
But I've had a nice time.
You're very beguiling and charming after
a book signing recently,
this person identifying as binary and I,
we ran into each other in the park and
we perched on a bench together and I
said,
explain this to me.
Will you then as we're here.
And they explained to me,
well what it is is like I don't feel
like I want to identify with either of
those categories.
I'm an actor and now we're going to go
to this school and learned about acting.
And I felt lucky.
I felt sort of both old and young
simultaneously as I reached across time
to this person and they explained new
grammar,
new words,
and I realized that the important thing,
the thing that all of us have to learn
is a kind of nonjudgment and a
willingness to let go of our systems of
categorization because not only are they
impeding others,
they're probably impeding ourselves and
facilitating this bizarre tendency we
have as human beings to cast our shadow
outwards,
whether that's as individuals or as
whole societies.
You see the role of many,
many oppressed and persecuted groups
being to bear the hedge monies,
inability to look at it's wound,
the inability or the power base of the
United States to own its own wound or
currently what we would term as
Islamophobia or many of the things
emerging from the various forms of
identity politics.
So it sort of.
I can feel something shifting in my head
that are kind of quite.
Is it good?
Yeah.
That's so good.
That's so exciting.
Same though.
Yeah,
and it's changing all the time.
It's.
Yeah,
it's.
I think it's an exciting time.
At least that's a positive thing we can.
I mean I think a demonstrably positive
thing that that these things are
shifting and there's so much badness
going on that's a really positive thing
that people are changing their thoughts
on labels and identity and I think that
we're headed in the right direction then
that's a pretty simple thing we can sort
out as humans.
You think like we could,
should be able to do that overhead is
making a lot of people a bit cross,
but I think they're are going to be
ultimately.
All right,
I've,
I think it will be very freeing and
liberating for a lot of people that sort
of come scrambling up to you after your
show.
Don't worry me.
It's going to be all right.
Yeah.
Oh my mind.
That's been a really,
really wonderful interview.
Let me make sure that I've done all my
proper jobs,
done proper jobs than Promo Promo Dad.
There's no way my is bisexual.
That's what made my thinks.
We need to reframe the way we think
about sexuality and refers to the
Statler of scent to be 125.
Don't identify as gay or straight.
I like that because that for me seems
like the evolution of consciousness,
like young people coming through,
they're smart and now our awakening,
they're not gonna accept the old ways
and the old old codes,
brilliant friends in Canada who,
I mean I guess they're straight like
they've only ever been with the opposite
sex but they're just not going to call
myself that because what if I meet
someone tomorrow and then I have to come
out like that's stressful,
so why not never say anything and then
he never had the stress.
Do you know much about what's going on
in affiliation with users?
Is around sort of no platforming,
particularly within academia within
Canada.
Do you know anything about that sort of
stuff?
Not really.
I hear that phrase.
What does that mean?
It means like some people can't talk at
colleges because I've said something in
offense or something offensive often
around identity politics,
but I don't know much about it,
but I know it's affected eg.
Jermaine greer around gender identity
and Pete attachable around lgb hold on a
second.
LGBTQ issues.
So if you're my age,
both of those people standard sort of
great civil rights giants.
So it's sort of interesting.
Curious.
But it's no reason why you have to be.
They're gonna afford.
I've no idea,
but it is so interesting.
Yeah.
I don't know where.
I don't know.
It's tricky.
Yeah.
With freedom of speech and then also you
don't.
I'm in,
you don't want to incite hatred and
violence and stuff.
So it's very.
We're in,
we're breaking new ground.
I don't know if there is a right answer.
I think we'll do.
Why?
Up to student bodies I guess to take to
sort of discuss it amongst themselves
and have a majority.
I think you're right.
I am a student.
Did you know that?
I go to.
So as university I'm just a young
student making me wait for it.
I'm just lucky kid with a dream.
I suppose my learning very little
because I can't focus on that so as.
And I'm doing religion and global
politics and I think today or tomorrow
I've got to go to a new module,
which is the origins of Yoga in India.
I think last year I was doing lots of
stuff about,
Gosh,
secularism.
The role of religion,
rationality versus irrationality.
Beats for advent of protestantism in
this.
Oh my God.
So much stuff.
West fading tree in my mind is full of
stuff.
Michel Foucault.
The brain's just brimming over with clap
trap.
So good though.
It is good,
isn't it?
Toward Yourself.
Up with the old bit of cleverness.
Just in case you in an argument one day.
Definitely reach into that little
cupboard and knowledge.
I love all that.
I mean it's a whole other conversation,
but I'm big into Joseph Campbell and
stuff.
So good,
isn't it?
I would.
I'd like to go back to school.
Maybe I could do that.
Listen,
you malleable kid.
You're wondering around you wanting to
move to the country.
Your family members are fighting each
other on my big frigging try to
university to learn more about
perennialism and myth,
which I am also fascinated by because in
a way we have to become the hero of our
own lives.
It's not actually about empirical
evidence is about belief and faith and
becoming a sort of a journey of becoming
a becoming a hero in your own existence.
We,
I can certainly say that you seem to
have been.
It's been very difficult for me to not
come over there and cut a little bit too
hard because I'm planning to do first
opportunity.
Okay.
My mind,
thanks for coming in.
Thank you so much.
People can come and see you.
I think you're wonderful and charming.
Thanks.
Thank you so much for having me.
Thank you.
So exciting.
Been good,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Really good.
Couple of darlings.
Thanks.
That show was sponsored by recovery.
You can get recovery by going to Amazon
or Russell brand.com.
Com,
or you can get the audio book,
the audio books.
Very good.
Getting older,
but imagine this voice now,
but reading a book at you.
Love it and come and see the rebirth
tour leads.
I walked over tickets for that.
It's going to be great night.
London,
Apollo.
Fear flow first of October,
first of November or so.
A lot of stars are coming that night.
It's going to be a loss of labs there.
It's going to be a big night,
not in a second of November,
probably a bit.
I don't know who's not in a nitrile
cliff might be their coventry,
even November,
locking,
less stuff over in November.
Jamie vardy.
Finally,
if you liked the show,
please subscribe and review in itunes or
wherever you you download stuff from an
only.
Give it a five star review.
As you know,
I'm very sensitive.
You also might like the radio x podcast.
Check that out as well.
Thanks for listening.
If you know what love is,
you'll know that I love you.