What point is the distinction occurring
between sort of a living,
vibrant earth which we participate in
psychically,
spiritually and totally and the earth as
a resource and I wondered if that day,
I wonder if that occurs in the
transition from Pantheism,
paganism to monotheism,
which were the sort of sacred endowment
of plants,
animals,
et Cetera,
becomes these things are,
as you say,
instrumental.
Do you think that's so significant?
I think.
I think it's both a cause of this shift
and a symptom of the shift,
but the more distance we are from
nature,
the more it seems that God is not in
nature but is kind of the external
overseer of nature and and actual beings
of nature lose their being ness.
A lot of the things that we blame as
cars are actually symptom.
How do you mean?
What do you mean by that?
I mean,
I'm seeing it a lot in,
in climate change and environmental ism
now.
I hope it's okay to keep referring back
to that because my mind is kind of in
that space,
but that,
for example,
one of the most alarming things
happening is what I'm calling the insect
Holocaust.
Have you noticed that there's less bugs
splatter on the window then when you
were a kid?
Yeah.
That less a good covering of Split
Telecon Nice of a Steven Spielberg Sky
splatter.
Yeah.
It's not your imagination like there's
been approximately a 75 percent loss of
flying insect biomass over 30 years.
So confronted with anything like that or
forest fires or hurricanes.
This mindset of fundamentalism,
of money,
of war has a jump.
Excuse me.
Have some water from this little baker.
Thank you.
It has us jump to the cause.
What's the cause?
Oh,
insect die off.
It must be climate change.
Forest fires.
It must be climate change,
um,
to,
to find an enemy is one of the deep
programs of our culture to solve a
problem.
Like I.
So my son who's five,
got this book from the library about
superheroes and it has all these little
anecdotes about the avengers or
something like that.
Uh,
and each story in there,
the template was the same,
a bad thing is happening,
the cause is a bad guy,
and the solution is to defeat the bad
guy by force.
So this,
this is an example of a reductionism
that also has us reduced the living
complexity of earth to a single cause,
which is why I'm wary of putting all of
the environmental eggs into the basket
of climate change and seeing if we only
solve this one thing,
then everything else will be fine.
And then what do we not see in that?
Reductionism?
Reductionism always leaves things out
and in this case it leaves out the
repeated dousing of the entire landscape
with pesticides over the last 90 years.
It leaves out habitat destruction,
it bleeds,
it leaves out deforestation.
Which one thing that came out of my,
my research for this book is that that
deforestation and land abuse is a much
bigger cause of the flood drought cycle.
Forest fires and other things.
Then greenhouse gases.
Well
advantage does the climate change
narrative give the powerful that is not
in their deforestation habitat
destruction narrative in order for the
climate change narrative to be favored,
it lends itself to quantitative
solutions that you can make money off
of.
It's always bad quantatative.
What will you explain what you mean?
Well,
you know,
if it becomes a matter of,
of say increase increasing carbon
sequestration,
then you can plant biofuels plantations
across Africa,
Asia and South America,
which is happening that the numbers look
good.
The metrics look good,
but what's happening on the ground is
subsistence peasants are being forced
out of their traditional lifestyles.
Um,
pristine ecosystems are being leveled to
plant fast growing trees.
A communal land holdings are being
converted into titled The property.
Um,
indigenous people are getting evicted
from their land,
like when things get monetized and
reduced to a number,
the things that you cannot reduce to a
number get left out.
So the,
in general,
the,
when we quantify things,
they fit into a society that is built on
measurement and quantification and
ultimately the conversion of all things
to the number called value.
It's dangerous.
And I mean,
I could go on and on.
I met our goal and he was talking,
as you might imagine about
environmentalism and climate change
while I was meeting him,
I felt this feeling of deep frustration
at not that alcohol might not be a nice
guy because it's sort of documentary
about him once and I saw he's capping
and it did seem like a nice guy and he's
captain with pictures of his dad up and
stuff,
human and uh,
but what I felt was that everything he
was saying was invisibly caveated with
the phrase,
unless it affects the interests of the
powerful,
we must do something about carbon
emissions unless it affects the interest
of the powerful.
Then we went day.
We must decide unless you energy
concern,
unless it affects the interest of the
powerful.
This thing that I instinctively felt.
It feels like it maybe relates to what
you just said and maybe have even more
information on that.
Yeah.
I feel a little suspicious of the
dominant climate change narrative
because the powerful are so willing to
accept it.
I think it's a lot less disruptive than
the alternative narrative that I like to
work with,
which is the living earth narrative
which says that the earth is alive,
that it's health depends on the health
of its organs and tissues and what are
those.
Those are the forests,
the wetlands,
the seagrass meadows,
the mangroves,
the elephants,
the whales,
the fish,
the corals,
everything that is destroyed by
development is necessary.
If you are in the carbon mind fret
frame,
then even if you value a forest for its
carbon storage and sequestration,
once you've reduced it to that number,
you could cut it down if there's say
gold to mine underneath it or oil and
plant another for somewhere else to make
up for it because it's just the numbers.
Right?
Or You could cut it down,
but install lots of solar panels to
offset that.
That carbon.
We're not treating Earth as alive and
and precious and sacred by operating in
that quantitative mindset,
and I don't think that's a big enough
revolution.
I don't think that's why we're being
initiated into a new kind of
relationship to earth.
Not initiated into let's be a little bit
more clever in working the numbers.
Yes.
All right.