Curiously,
I've been listening to a lot of George
Orwell audiobooks,
and it's amazing because there's these
huge passages where he thinks,
oh my God,
what incredible foresight,
how amazing.
And then there's I'm a bitchy thing.
Oh no,
that's not how it turned out.
Oh,
like Hitler has not yet kicked off in
that the road to Wigan pier is going,
I don't like to look at,
they sit at the bloke,
I think he's going to be trouble.
Yeah,
I've got quick George do something.
But then there's like a speculation
about like how other things are going to
pan out and it sort of a,
you know,
like this is the necessity for
socialism.
He does point out that like that
socialism's requirement for
mechanization and a mechanized utopia.
We'll foul and I can't help but return
to something that Gandy said prior to
the Indian revolution throughout the
British.
There's no point in overthrowing the
British in order to simply replace them
and their systems.
And Gandy failed and disrespect.
I mean,
Gandhi had a vision of turning India
into this collection of Agrarian Turkic
Utopias.
And the only thing left of Gandhi's
vision in the core and Indian economy is
his image on these rupee notes.
That's the only thing left.
And this is partly because,
you know,
Gandhi's analysis,
uh,
was inappropriate for the 20th century.
You couldn't,
I mean,
it's a very nice vision to have India as
a collection of agrarian utopias.
It's just irrelevant to how the economy
functions in the late 20th century.
When you say functions,
you know,
functions in order to suit the needs of
the powerful,
it would have functioned pretty bloody
good for most agrarian Indian villages.
It just wouldn't have functioned well
for the capitalist relationships that
needed to be maintained.
Whether or not it was the British in
charge or the Indians that were in
charge.
Um,
again,
I,
I don't know what exactly went wrong,
but from the very beginning,
uh,
certainly Nairu and the,
and the leadership did not try to
implement Gandhi's vision in a serious
way,
largely because they also realized,
I mean,
it's,
it's not workable because most people
want power.
Ultimately.
First of all,
they want food.
I mean,
you could narrow that food,
you know,
narratives never discussing whether or
not he was going to have food.
He's getting food personally,
the Indian people.
But when you have,
you know,
we have a one point something billion
Indians to feed,
then,
uh,
you don't have a lot of room for errors
or fraud maneuvers in the economic
field.
Now,
the amazing thing is that today in
India,
more people die from eating too much
than from eating too little.
Even in India,
it's not just in the west.
So for me,
that's just a perversion.
Like that's just,
well,
that's mental.
We need to enough full system.
Yeah.
And so if there's not enough so then we
can abandon the idea that scarcity is
the problem.
Organization is the problem.
There's too much food here.
There's not enough food over there.
Why is the food not gain over there?
It doesn't suit the interest of the
powerful to the food for the food to go
over there.
How do we affect the interest of the
powerful we organize ourselves,
we challenge the interest of the
powerful.
Who are the powerful is these companies
here,
these governmental organizations here?
Key question to know who are the
powerful world power is in?
How does it function?
It's very complicated.
You mean the power is concealed?
The true power without getting too
conspiratorial?
Yeah.
I mean certainly the modern world for a
couple of centuries,
one of the main functions of power is to
conceal power.
There is kind of a low of history.
If you don't have a lot of power,
you try to exaggerate your power.
If you have a lot of power,
you try to conceal it.
If you're a king in England in the 12th
century,
you don't have a lot of power,
but you tried to conceal your weakness
by these extravagant displays of power.
So you go with like a pile of gold on
your head and you were all these furs
and pearls and every now and then you
tell people,
okay,
cut off his head and that makes people
feel,
oh,
he's very powerful.
But actually he's very weak.
Uh,
because the state is fairly weak.
Then you move to the modern age and
leaders in governments really have
enormous amount of power but they won't,
don't want to attract too much attention
to it.
So you know that they dressed plainly
like an ordinary person and uh,
they,
they live in a much lower light.
They don't go about telling people,
okay,
cut off his head because they don't want
to draw attention to all that power.
So in point,
it's very difficult to know where power
really lies in the 21st century.
Pageantry conceals ordinariness our
flags out precessions all these,
all this pageantry,
all this ritual,
all this ceremony helps us to believe
there is a United States of America.
There is an,
England is not just a sort of an
economic idea and a bit of land and some
powerful people exploiting the
vulnerable.
It's a thing.
It's a flag.
There's an eagle,
there's a symbol,
there's a history.
It's real,
but bit by bit who am picking you on
stitch and you discover there's nothing
there except some powerful people
exploiting some people without power.
That is your America,
that is your England,
that is you're Israel,
you're Saudi Arabia.
All just myths and stories so that the
powerful can continue to exploit the
powerlessness,
whether it's a crown on her head or some
stars and stripes on a flag.
So first thing that people have to be
disabused of is their myths of
nationalism.
Or then whatever method it is that's
preventing them from acting in their own
interests.
It's more complicated and complicated
and that cause I'll get people moving.
Take for example the,
the,
the Arab spring.
So it all started off very
optimistically,
like wonderful.
We have a democratic revolution of the
people.
The people now gain power and it was
hijacked and the collage,
the curves were turned in the wrong
direction.
And we now have a much worse situation
than before.
I mean Egyptians and Syrians and people
in,
in Yemen and in,
and they look back and we said,
this is not why we had the revolution.
Something really,
really failed.
Yes.
Because I think they had no idea.
The Islamic Brotherhood have an idea
whether you liked the idea or you don't
like the idea.
This is our idea.
This is how we see society.
This is our vision.
The people that are on twitter don't
have a vision for the site.
That's why I think it's,
it's dangerous just to go out,
say on twitter and tell people,
okay,
go to the streets,
take out the Kalashnikovs,
fight against power.
So it,
it,
you know,
you can,
you can have a week off revolution,
but then if you don't really understand
the actual palace structure,
then your revolution will be hijacked
and directed in,
in,
uh,
towards goals which are not necessarily
the best goals in the world.
For example,
like Spain in the 30s,
brief flicker of an Arco Cinder colorism
ultimately becomes,
fascism,
becomes neo.
I know so many examples of neo is a
century ago in Russia,
you heard the Bolshevik revolution,
and within a very short time you heard
stallion and the gulags and,
and,
and so forth.
And um,
you know,
by within two or three years,
the Bolsheviks were firing on the
workers and peasants that they were
supposed to represent.
You have the,
the famous case of,
of the crunch dot sailors in the garage
dot workers,
which in 1917,
we're kind of the avant garde of the
revolution.
And by the end of the revolution,
the Bolshevik government was massive
caring.
They're very same workers in crunch dot.
Which in the beginning where the big
heroes of the revolution,
it depends on whether you have an
optimistic perspective or not.
There's some days where I feel human
beings are capable of creating this
utopia.
I believe it.
I believe that this technology can be
harnessed to create,
uh,
more,
in a world of justice and liberty then,
then I'll hear like about some terrible
refugee crises in Burma and think,
oh Jesus,
let's just leave it as it is now.
And this is I,
you know,
I don't know cause I didn't want to
travel then when the aggravation,
but to return for a moment to the
optimistic perspective,
if you can identify the powerful and you
can,
and you have a vision of a society that
could be differently organized.
This for me is to ingredient.
That's a big if,
I mean,
if you look today the world,
what strikes me most is that nobody,
as far as I can tell,
nobody in either the left or the right
has any serious,
meaningful vision for where you monitor
will be in 2015 most of what you get is
nostalgic fantasies about the past.
Yes.
But you don't have a serious vision,
which takes into account a I and
biotechnology and climate change in all
that and really looks clearly at what,
where can we be in 2015
wow.