Part of the documentary that actually
I'm,
I'm glad is there though.
You didn't want there,
but you know,
I wasn't the producer and I gave all the
rights to,
it's the only way to be fair with it.
The producer,
after I worked with a young woman,
you may remember who was this woman,
she was in a cult where they abused as
children,
number four,
Dev sex.
It was
yes.
And that blew you away.
That that was a really,
really,
cause it was moved by that.
And I was at,
when I say the bit where you see you in
the room when you've got a little bit of
downtime and you're like,
that really blew you away.
And that's how I was going on.
So people don't see that in me because
if I'm crying,
they're helping her,
which I did the two with good.
But if I,
I won't be able help her.
So I,
it comes through me and then afterwards
I would go and I feel the grace of that.
And to me that's often tears when it's
so beautiful when someone's life has
been touched.
And then I figured out what I did so I
can do it again or teach someone else.
Are you going to sage with that energy
when you're like,
uh,
like fucking hell.
That was a bit heavy but that our new
feeling,
so I love what I do for anything.
It's not as intense for a start.
I'm a comedian or entertainer.
So I'm up there for an hour and a half,
two hours.
I'm like,
I,
all I've got to do is make him love and
I fucking love doing it.
But afterwards,
like I come home and I sort of crawl
into bed and just like,
you know,
I'd want to be told they're there.
You're all right.
You're a good boy.
Oh cool.
That's what I need to be told.
Like you know,
like sort of is that like if you got
access to that level of vulnerability in
yourself?
I like this cause it seems to me,
this is my love bug me.
Like,
I mean,
what do I have only seen a documentary
and had a bit of a chat based things to
me that you will very,
very traumatic job and we're not
nourished in the way that you should be.
So you had to turn yourself into your
own nutritional source.
Yes.
And now you're trying to solve all of
the world's problems.
Well,
not one individual at a time.
I've been in rooms where there's 10,000
of them,
but like,
uh,
that's a lot of intensity because it's
sort of actually,
even though,
you know,
prior,
in the earlier chat you told me like
that they put all that athletic
monitoring equipment on you and said
that you burned 11,000
calories in nine hours and your heart's
doing this and your house.
And they're like,
yeah,
I believe that in the ability of
consciousness and we'll to alter anatomy
into a material to a degree.
But the simple fact is it ultimately
that you're,
um,
a man,
where are you going with that
vulnerability?
What are you doing?
Have you got like a mentor?
Someone that you can call?
Not many.
I've what's really beautiful,
my life,
the grace of my life is I've been called
to help others and they look at me as
their coach,
but I'd be an idiot.
The kind of people I have the privilege
of coaching to think I'm just coaching
them.
I go there just like I did with you.
I wanted to interview.
I reached out to you.
Unfortunately you want to chat with me
too,
which I was grateful for,
but I wanted to reach you because I feel
you have a very special voice when it
comes to recovery that I have not seen
anywhere else.
So you have a passion and a truth and a
vulnerability and I have a lot of that,
but I'm only one person,
so I'm good at finding brilliant people
and then helping to pull out so other
people can see at least the people that
I have an audience for,
you know,
20 million people on social media and
they talk to people,
so hopefully it reaches even more.
So I'm always on the hunt for human
excellence.
I'm on the hunt for someone who's real.
My vulnerability is absolutely there.
But I've trained myself like an athlete,
like the most common question I've been
asked by the media my entire life,
it always makes me laugh is,
well,
don't you have bad days?
Don't you have days when you're like
fresh state and desired and pissed off
and you watch TV and eat cheetos and
watch pornography?
And I said,
well,
I do some of those things.
And of course I do.
But what I,
it's like an athlete.
I built muscle over the years so that
it's not that they don't have feelings,
I don't get hurt her of the side of the
pie for all those things,
but they're not the dominant force in my
wife.
It's a muscle.
The mind is a muscle emotion as a
muscle.
I mean,
I think the most powerful muscles are
the invisible force muscles.
It's your spiritual,
emotional muscles like courage on you
doesn't grow,
shrinks.
So I put my ass on the line regularly so
that it grows and what keeps growing.
And pretty soon the stuff that used to
make me crazy,
it doesn't touch me.
It's not that I'm so great just I'm well
trained.
I trained his mine.
I get up every morning in my life.
You're talking about rebound,
her more crazy shit ideas everywhere in
your life.
If I'm near,
if I'm near any of my homes and some
places I have,
I have cryotherapy but my homes,
I have these coal punches and our 56
degrees and the first thing I do is jump
on their coal point so there's not a
fucking morning where I want to jump in
that I can't remember.
More intact could jump on that thing,
but I don't negotiate with myself.
I do it for two reasons.
One,
there's a physical health component
moves your lymph system ever.
The blood flushes through your whole
body,
but the main reason I do it even more
than that is when I got up there,
I don't get how people negotiate.
Well,
I'm able to tomorrow I'm going to do
this or oh,
let me like two more minutes till I'm
ready Earth.
None of that shit with me for decades.
I go,
I say do.
I'm not here to discuss the shit with my
mind,
their mind and their soul and spirit and
soul and spirit.
My Soul fucking knows.
And when I say jump,
you fucking jump.
I'm not here to have a discussion with
you.
Now,
does that happen with my water every
day?
Yes,
because I've conditioned it.
Does it happen every of my life?
No.
And when I find it's not working and I
stepped back up and condition it,
and unless I'm willing to take a hundred
percent responsibility for what I feel
and what I experienced,
then I'm always going to be a victim to
someone.
Cause there's always going to be
somebody's upset in the world we live in
today about something you said or did or
didn't say or didn't do.
Go.
There is no victory in the world where
everyone has a voice and not everybody's
voices necessarily designed to make
somebody feel loved.
It's designed to meet whatever their
needs are in that moment,
they might want certainty and you're
being a certain way makes them uncertain
or they think you're significant.
You may think they're totally
significant,
but they don't.
So they're mad.
So I can't live my life that way.
So I live my life where I keep learning,
I keep growing,
I keep loving,
I keep laughing and I'm trying to leave
a decent legacy of a meaningful life by
constantly looking for ways that can be
helpful.
And my prayer,
simple prayer before I walk on at every
stage is use me,
use me Lord.
And,
and when you do that,
it's like if you get out of the way,
my greatest gift is getting out of the
way.
I know that sounds silly to some people,
but it's really true.
I'm not an ultra religious person,
but I'm extremely spiritual and I
believe the force of life comes through
me.
It comes through,
comes through all of us,
and the only gets in the way is all the
beliefs we have of how it's supposed to
be.
All the expectations we have.
And I have them too,
but I keep leading them out.
So I'm not,
I don't want to give you the impression
that I'm,
uh,
I don't have challenges and things that
nature,
but I have a hell of a lot fewer.
It takes a lot more.
When something happens like this happen,
I go,
oh worthy opponent.
Because in every story of a person's
life,
they have what they want and desire.
And then they have these needs that
they're unaware of,
you know,
character things that need to be
developed.
And how do those get developed?
Well,
if what you wanted,
you just took action happened.
Hey you'd be bored.
Be you've never developed spiritually or
your character.
And so what happens is opponent show up
and the opponent can be you with
yourself.
The opponent can be somebody close to
you that feels like a bone or it could
be an external force.
But if you do battle with this,
eventually you badly with yourself.
Cause if you can solve it within
yourself,
you can what we're to what happened to
the outside world.
You can have that sense that your life
is meaningful.
And so I've been battling for 58 years
and I'm going to keep doing battle the
rest of my life.
But I'm,
I'm doing better cause I've done battle
so often.
It's like why is Lebron James who he is?
It's not because he's lucky,
you know?
How do I say?
Yeah,
he's lucky.
He made have certain physical factions
where Michael Jordan,
I remember I interviewed him years ago
and I said,
what makes you the best in the world?
Is it skill as a town is that ability is
a backward,
is a training,
and he was so awesome.
He said,
Tony,
I can tell you the truth that it won't
sound like hyperbole or false modesty.
He said,
I didn't even make the high school
basketball team my sophomore year.
I was cut.
He said,
what it is is every day I demand more
from myself than anybody else could
possibly expect.
I don't compete with other people.
I compete with what I'm capable of.
And it's just like that kind of standard
is inspiring.
They see.
It reminds me a lot.
I had this conversation with Tom Cruise,
right?
It was like another Americans have great
square jawed superstar and like he was
sort of saying about how he made his
success himself.
I goes,
no,
but you were born with the Tom Cruise
Shit like you had that.
Even the will,
but the will,
you know there's not a,
you might as well.
Where do you think will come through?
Where did you will come from?
I don't know.
Where do you think it comes from?
I think that would be better or
something you have to push against or
you don't develop it.
How do you build a muscle?
You don't build muscle because you were
born with it.
We're all born with muscle,
but events developed.
You trained it and that means you got to
find something that you valued more than
your pain.
You got to get beyond your pain or you
got to use your pain and say,
I'm going to use it to become more.
That's what my life's been about and now
it's no longer driven by pain is driven
by the joy of seeing people lit up.