Kenny is a psychological therapist,
counselor and broadcasts though who's
training and experience in areas
including eating disorders,
ptsd,
trauma,
surviving abuse and relationships,
has seen her become a familiar face on
British television.
She spent 17 years working with people
in crisis in some of the toughest,
the states,
and runs her own therapy clinic as well
as a free healthy social network that
aims to help people find balance in
their lives.
She has two children and lives in
Manchester.
Emma can eat welcomed onto the skin.
Thanks for coming on.
Thank you for having me.
Oh,
well,
that's.
I suppose to understand your background
a little bit,
so could you tell us a little bit about
the therapeutic work you do?
I guess that my background begins when
as an adolescent I was sent to the
psychological system,
so I was a regular truant.
They have problems at school and when I
kind of went and saw a psychologist,
what I found was I just couldn't engage.
I didn't feel like they listened in a
way that progressed me and I kind of
remember thinking at the time,
why can't adults speak to young people?
In a way that respects the fact that
they are intelligent and know who they
are to some degree,
so I kind of thought and ruminated on it
and even though I had problems at
school,
I decided that was the direction I
wanted to go in to actually be able to
transmit my own experiences into some
way of understanding of the young
people.
So that's what got me into therapy.
I did a psychology degree initially and
then moved into therapeutic context,
so studying more client centered didn't
necessarily fit me because I'm quite a
challenging person.
I like to use challenge in therapy what
it means and so your a therapist,
but it sort of conventionally inferior
p,
the therapist is what managers listen
and you stick your in there and go,
yeah,
I mean that's the type.
One of the things that I've tended to do
is to feel that even though there are
therapists that are challenging,
but certainly client centered isn't so
egan and Roger's aren't necessarily egan
and Rogers or just to have the kind of
God so client centered therapy.
But I think purism is an interesting
area.
Full stop because I kind of really
struggled with it and I was training and
I was really lucky at Manchester
University that they kind of allowed me
a bit of a freedom to express my own
beliefs in what I thought I wanted
therapy to be and I kind of argued that
I couldn't ever be either of those types
because I'm not that person.
And even when you watch therapists and
action who claimed to be pure,
often you'll see they're not.
They're doing something kind of
different.
So I learned in the long run the best
thing I could be in therapy with me,
just me,
so that I felt that my presence and
conversation and experience with the
client's journey that really authentic
and that's what's effectively worked for
me.
You think that part of the role of
therapy is to discover a kind of truth,
a truth of the client's experience.
Is that so do you think it's necessary
for you to be authentic in that?
Absolutely believe that authenticity is
key.
Full Stop.
I think that we talk about authenticity
as if it's quite easy to achieve.
Just be yourself is a classic example of
things that people say to you when
you're growing,
go up and when you're an adult,
just be yourself,
but actually being yourself takes a huge
amount of courage,
a huge amount of self discovery,
a willingness to be wrong,
a willingness to learn all the time and
it's quite scary.
So I would say that I try to be as
authentic as I can be all the time.
I'm sure at times I get scared and that
makes me wear a mask or I'm convinced
that somebody needs me to be or
authority,
so I'll put one of those and I have to
work against it,
but I think that's human nature to some
degree.
Went at Stanford,
that was in there a couple of weeks ago.
He's like an explorer survivor.
Yeah,
I know.
He's like a bit like bear grylls.
I think he's the grunge bear grylls.
That's how I see him.
It's like a shelf stripped back bear
grylls who said that when he spends
prolonged periods of time on his own,
the uh,
what do you know that that is the
aloneness itself is more challenging
than the survival aspects of what he's
doing because he said that when you're
in relationship with another person,
you're constantly refining yourself and
adjusting.
And he very interesting.
They used these guys like even now as
I'm looking at you and I'm seeing if you
approve of one sign and was really sort
of quite fascinating.
So when you're talking about when it's
talking about like having an experience
of an authentic self,
it must be a difficult thing for anybody
to achieve because we responding to such
a lot of stimulation.
So sort of stimuli.
Absolutely.
I mean everybody seeks approval.
Everybody to some degree wishes to be
liked.
But at the same time I think my journey
began when I started to feel like it was
actually me wanting to police the world
and get liked by everybody that was
possibly making me exhausted.
And I wasn't really reflecting on what I
needed.
And there was almost like a desire to
just accept that it isn't selfish to
concentrate on the self,
it's self full,
and to actually strip back what I
thought people wanted to know about me
and wanted me to be like,
and to just be myself and to some degree
in my therapy,
I think that's what works.
That I don't feel that firstly I need to
be judged by my clients.
And conversely I don't judge my clients
either.
The,
when we experienced that thick
conversation that kind of occurs as a
thickness in therapy,
I know that people.
Who Do you mean by that thickness?
I think practitioners who may be
listening to this or get it and probably
people the falling in love or having
really,
really intense relationships.
It's almost like there's a northern
context to the relationship and other
feeling in the room like this.
Something bigger,
wider,
more cerebral,
but almost touchable.
Even though it's not that.
It's like a sense of knowing that this
is where we're meant to be in that
moment and just feeling completely
connected and almost like within a
bubble of something good.
I'm not saying it isn't with pain or
that there isn't challenged,
just that it's good.
You can use the role of the therapist
then to somehow recreate what sounds to
me like you're describing there may say
is a kind of spiritual experience that
people perhaps to do.
You know,
the example you used is like when you're
in love with somebody.
I like that like in a non romantic
context that it that would pop pop
possibly a person with a mom or a rabbi
or a priest or a shaman where you feel
like I am being myself.
Here I am present kind of dangerous
place to go with people,
isn't it?
I think that throughout history,
wherever you are and whatever culture
and society,
they'll always be people who,
as you talked about then have different
definitions but essentially help to
navigate.
I think that my job in my therapy is
navigation.
I'm not saying I absolutely direct the
journey,
but if the truest waters ahead or if
people keep making the same errors,
it's my job.
I feel to help them engage with that
process,
learn,
move forward and not end up in the same
position so to speak,
so I don't think it's my job to tell
people what to do,
but I certainly think it would be
without courage to listen to people
constantly making the same mistakes and
not encourage them to explore different
avenues and to see different vantage
points and that's something that I stay
true to within my therapy and it's
something that I think my own therapy
when I was training was always the
frustration.
I always felt like I wanted this person
who was sharing the space with me to
kind of fundamentally feel like they
were with me.
I know that if you've not had therapy,
you might have experienced that with
your parents or your friends.
That might be moments in your life where
you just feel that that person is with
you.
You don't even need to have words.
There's just a sense of being.
And I used to feel a frustration that I
never felt that.
So potentially if I'm looking at it on a
psychological level,
you know,
there is a level of me wanting to create
that experience for my client because I
think that everybody in life needs to be
able to replicate that.
I think true happiness comes from
feeling that you find are those that
share that space in that way and then if
you have had that in therapy,
you can go out and when you feel it
elsewhere,
you know it's good and you want to stick
with it.
And that's something I think it's really
important to almost transplant that
experience into reality for the client.
I'm going to say some bold things now.
He'd come those bold things.
I think it's difficult for me to make
grand statements because I only know
what it's like to be America like in
America or in or broadly speaking,
so privileged western democracy type
places,
but it seems like there's some sort of
mental health crisis going on.
Addiction epidemics,
self harming,
a in disorders.
It seems to me like sort of a.
and you know,
I know there's more information
available.
I'm sure there's all sorts of social
factors and various contributors leading
to this statement.
It seems like people are crying out for
some sort of connection to nature.
One of the people are very much respect
to early guests on the show.
Adam Curtis says that politics is as
lost its ability to talk about feeling
the way that people feel that politics
has become sort of managerial.
That people say,
well,
we'll manage this for you.
There's no real vision of where we're
going and what sort of the great sort of
like in the last century,
sort of the,
the great religious institutions have
been challenged politic,
the great sort of experiments of fascism
and communism broadly.
We know once again we can say kind of
failed or certainly fascism revver level
look at that and so like,
you know,
like mental,
like psychiatry therapy,
sort of like in a way a relatively new
science and its relationship with
neurology was an anatomy.
It's going to be ongoing as these
connections and observations and new
maps and merge.
But excuse me,
I feel that the,
the work that's being done in
understanding how individuals feel in
how groups feel it's going to be vital
in reforming the way that we see
ourselves,
the way that we participate in,
in society.
Um,
so emmy,
Emma,
as you have indicated,
a lot of people don't have the privilege
of engaging in therapy.
So how do people employ these
principles?
What should we be looking for?
I mean,
I think that therapy is the ideal where
you don't need it not wanting to get rid
of my job,
but ideally communities,
societies and neighbors,
friends,
people who are around you,
they can be the thing that you actually
need.
And it would be my ideal,
you know,
the Nirvana would be that we support
people without the need for any of that.
I think the medical model in the UK and
in Western world is something that
obviously has benefits to some degree,
but I think we're missing this vital
link.
My feeling is that when I'm working with
so many people who are maybe suffering
from really,
really severe depression and anxiety and
people who have manifestations with
eating disorders,
for example,
when I'm hearing their stories,
I feel that compassion and empathy and
time,
a nurture and a real engagement with
getting to know the dysfunction and then
recognizing the function from within
that dysfunction is what's required,
but that takes a huge amount of time
when we're looking at it in the
therapeutic context.
Money as you noted,
because the NHS is really burdened.
You know anybody out there who thinks
that practitioners aren't trying to do a
good job.
It isn't that it's just the amount of
people who genuinely need that care
aren't receive and get and when you get
that practitioner they're working with
high level crisis,
do you not kind of doing the early
intervention.
So for me the bigger question is how can
we as a society start to be more
compassionate to people around us?
That's the big thing for me.
I always make an effort to get my note
to know my neighbors.
It's a northern thing.
It's a working class thing,
right?
I'm going to be living in now.
Let me interfere in your business.
I'm also a trained therapist.
Now,
notice you're not communicating very
well when you live on.
Yeah.
Obviously that would be one way of doing
it,
but you know that kind of thing that I
think we have.
These are measurable opportunity in
society to make ourselves more healthy.
You said things like going outside and
even when you're working with people in
despair,
one of the big things that you want to
do is look at their diet,
looking at their exercise regime,
look at how often they get outside,
look at who they socialize with because
human beings are human and they're
social animals,
and if they haven't got access to any of
those things are they're not eating
efficiently and they're not exercising
at all,
that's manifesting more problems.
So helping people to deconstruct is one
of the things I would say.
You don't need a therapist to explore
how to impact on your life more
positively through food or through the
amount of exercise you give yourself or
the white light that you get on your
skin or the Times that you knock on your
neighbor's door and ask for a cup of
tea.
There are things that are within reach
to everybody.
Even people who have low socioeconomic
standards can still afford to eat
better,
if that makes sense.
What interests me about the work that
you do is you see that on this podcast a
lot.
It's very cerebral now know your sort of
a qualified clinicians,
so like you know,
like not like I recognize that you can
also communicate on that level,
but say you know,
when we're talking to people that are,
as it were,
conventional academics,
it's likely you feel the weight and
freight of their experience and study.
But when I'm like for,
it's like one of the reason I'm doing
this podcast because I do a degree
religion in,
in global politics.
So as university,
when I'm sitting in someone's unpacking
the upanishads for me or vedic
literature,
what I'm always thinking and probably is
affecting my ability to learn is how
does this relate to me now?
Like you know me now out,
do I apply that if this doesn't apply to
my experience of being human than a,
I don't care.
You know.
And you know,
like I know a lot of people will listen
to this podcast where mental health is
probably the thing that's uppermost.
I know there's a lot of people listen to
these things for self betterment.
They want to learn,
they want to know more stuff.
But I think a lot of people that are
like,
right,
yeah,
I'm not happy and like sort of self
harm,
eating disorders,
drink too much.
Thanks so much.
Drugs,
feeling alienated,
feeling lost and like something like in
a guy in her next door neighbor and ask
for a cup of tea says something about
the kind of society we're living in that
that's bloody sounds like quite radical
thing to do.
It does feel like that for lots of
people because we've kind of become so
disassociated from to some degree what
makes us happy.
I also think we spend a lot of time
trying to avoid difficult feelings
because we've been told that difficult
feelings or something we should run from
or feel ashamed of or challenge in a way
by using alcohol or drugs or sex or
anything that helps us escape those
feelings.
For me,
I did that the years,
you know,
I run away from all of the feelings that
essentially I needed to confront so that
I could work through them and find why
feel is a piece with the part of me that
I think I felt was dark and it's not
dark.
It's just human.
But before I can reach others,
I have to reach into myself.
I have to feel that connection with
myself.
So the reason I can ask now and I asked
people for what I need if.
Because I know that I have enough
resources within myself to manage
whether they reject me or otherwise,
and that's something that's given me a
real freedom average to get there
through accepting that I was never ever
going to find what I wanted through the
avenues that I was seeking in the man
you know,
had an aneurysm and having all of those
areas of my world that I thought were
bringing me happiness,
but that was so temporary and moment or
a that they really gave me,
I suppose what you were saying earlier
on like that spiritual connection,
that sense of.
I like the fact that I think I'm really
this tiny little.in
infinity,
but that that's amazingly miraculous and
the this moment is blink of an eye of my
consciousness is mindblowing and taking
it and reframing it from that
perspective has been incredibly helpful.
Firstly,
because it gives me a humility where I
know that as long as I do as little
harm,
I hope I've done
a decent job and go on,
go on,
go into a therapy session with as little
damage as possible with fuck every one
smack in the mouth.
How does.
See.
I understand what you're saying about
sort of like a,
you know,
the sort of miracle being and acceptance
that is difficult to resolve yourself
outside of yourself.
How did you get there though?
How did you get from being an adolescent
who was a truman and inferred that
heaven is him played its part of your
journey.
How did you become disillusioned?
We've had aneurysm and is it that
reached you because you said you were
initially,
you were not a lot.
You didn't feel satisfied with the
therapeutic experiences you had as a
teenager.
What you must,
I'm guessing,
have had some kind of satisfying
experience with therapy at some point.
A lot of it was to do with the self work
that I did so many years ago.
Not that I do this now.
I kind of became quite intrigued with
things like the runic alphabet and using
things like an overview of a runic.
Every day I started writing to myself,
journaling myself,
learning that actually it was okay to
make mistakes.
One of the big things that I used to do
is go to bed and over analyze every
single conversation that I'd had for
fear that I would have offended somebody
and then everything.
Honestly,
every day it was exhausting and then I
learnt that actually,
you know what?
It really,
it doesn't matter unless there was
intent there late.
I might offend people.
I might upset people.
I might at times hurt people,
but my intention is not to accepting
that I can't always be responsible for
another human being's pain or resolve or
journey and instead the all I can do is
be with them on it.
Even if they reject me or if they accept
me.
That's the journey of life.
That's it.
That's what I'm here for.
I think having children was a big
awakening.
When you say,
what was it?
No,
15 years ago I had a baby and everything
I thought had meaning just totally
transformed like all I believed.
Until then was that though as this book
search in life that there was this huge
search for something,
if anything,
this thing that filled this gap,
I'm not suggesting that everyone runs
off and acid.
Yep.
But the minute I held him like I'd had
no maternal experience or feelings,
I got pregnant because I was told I
couldn't have children,
so one I'd always lived a life where if
you told me I couldn't do something,
I would find a way to do it.
That's still a philosophy I kind of live
my life by,
but I had fertility treatment.
I had a baby.
I held him and I was blown away because
there was this magnificence of being an
ordinary,
ordinary miracle.
Just an everyday thing that people do
all the time,
but he changed everything.
Like he made me the best version version
of myself.
He made me realize I was far more
compassionate and patient that I even
knew I cut those resources to be.
Both of my children have consistently
reminded me that I have an abundance of
love that I never even knew I could tap
into and everybody finds something.
Eventually.
Some people find exercise,
some people find nature,
some people find friendship for me.
Motherhood.
Motherhood was it.
You did thank you that you have.
Oh well you,
you said some things that are about in a
way embracing convention and identity
because I've had a similar experience or
I'm having quite new for me,
still a similar experience as a parent.
This like certainly disrupting myself.
Centerdness trying to stick to the self
centered but as someone.
Several people in the house.
But you also earlier in it you talked
about sort of like.
You know what again,
as I say like often when I'm talking to
like academics and stuff in here,
if like runic letters or the itching
come up,
right?
People would like you clear off because
this is like,
like you know,
we live in a that don't really like to
recognize sort of folk.
I guess.
I don't know.
Folk history and something I'm becoming
more and more interested in and I know
that sort of,
again,
given that you are a psychotherapist,
like that is interesting,
isn't it?
That I'm fascinated by Carl young.
I'm fascinated with.
He's intrigued with like Kundalini Yoga
and the itching and ways of dealing with
the mystery because let's face it,
the unknown is where we all get to.
I was listening to,
um,
sort of a debate or a conversation I
suppose between Sam Harris,
the atheist,
that neurologist and sort of pundit and,
and Richard Dawkins and they were
talking about how,
you know,
it's like the sort of the beauty of the
theory of evolution and it's certainly
sort of his magnificent.
The way I'm packed.
Our understanding of sort of material
evolution of,
you know,
it's a great masterpiece in determining
ideas of like,
of all time.
But like of course it says that,
you know,
we,
we can,
we don't know how it begins or how it
can begin this moment of inception.
So at some point,
you know,
like we all have to interface with the
unknown and,
and I,
I suspect,
and I sort of feel like I know that
there are limitations for our capacities
as human beings to hold knowledge,
but knowledge is potential for
knowledge,
is infinite capacity for understanding
is fine,
that there's going to be faith is going
to be required,
a way of dealing with the unknowable is
going to be a requirement now like when,
if we have a type of culture that
prohibits that because it's seen as woo
woo or sort of like.
I think actually one of the things that
I'm sensing is it sort of a part of this
is to do with Patriarchy and misogyny.
The oppression of the female principal
of the flow of things in a male nurse is
a kind of a self contained idea in a
way.
The female femininity as it relates to
creativity,
both biologically and socially is a sort
of a.
It I sent down,
I'm being very basic here,
but this is kind of a flow to the idea
of femininity.
I wonder,
uh,
how this printer,
how men can embrace their own femininity
and how,
uh,
the feminine principle being bought into
life and it like as sort of these,
these ideas of connectedness that you
talk about,
uh,
how,
what do you think is the significance
and how can we learn more and how can we
enact them?
I think that the men this modern age is
a confusing one.
I think there have been so many changes.
There's so much more androgyny.
Women obviously,
and rightfully so,
at least getting to a point where there
is more equality,
certainly not equality,
but in the western world there is more
equality.
I think that the thing that men need to
acknowledge is that firstly,
the human
animals and the need for connection is
absolutely instinctual.
It's not about them being weak because
they need somebody to support them.
When they vocalize their pain and men
just don't vocalize their pain as often
as they should.
That's why it kills them.
That's why suicide is such a high rate
in men under 40 for example,
we know this,
but actually taking that step,
that brave step to say,
I'm in pain to say I don't know what to
do,
to say I'm confused with all these
stereotypes and schemers about what a
man should be.
To me.
When you become at one with yourself,
male or female,
you recognize the very thing that you
need as a human is to just say,
I'm a mess.
I'm a mess sometimes,
and within that mess is something
incredibly beautiful masterpiece based.
I tell all my clients and particularly
in the man who struggled with the
authenticity and the ability to just say
I'm in pain and to not know what to do
is to acknowledge that that's a
completely generic feeling.
That's the human condition.
If anybody tells me they know exactly
why they're here and they know exactly
what they're doing,
then I think that they're not being
honest with themselves.
I think,
in fact,
it's the wonder of not knowing that
makes life the journey that becomes the
potential to make everything that you
experience in this world feel that it
has something more guttural,
more cerebral,
as you said,
like there's something more,
I don't know what that is,
and it's okay.
It's the not knowing of knowing to some
degree,
so what do men need to do?
I think they need to trust themselves
more.
They need to trust that you don't need
to have the answers to find a way and
that there'll be people around you who
will offer you that spark of support and
that the only way that we can start that
is when we give permission to each other
to follow that through.
So for every man to give another man
that permission for every woman to meet
that permission with care and compassion
because it's not just a male thing.
If we want our men to be protective
leaders,
then it's very difficult for them to be
weak and vulnerable.
Likewise,
women want to be leaders as well,
but at the same time the androgynous
confused and,
and I think that that's why we're having
so many of these problems because it's a
very simple process.
Acknowledge how you feel.
Tell some day,
vocalize it,
received the support,
work up,
support a move forward.
It's not an atb experience,
but it's certainly a place that begins
the change we need to connect more.
We choose not to is a choice.
Everything's a choice.
That's what we're choosing to do,
which using not to.
We're in a tender world,
a throwaway world,
a world where actually deep connection
is something that's almost becoming
avoided just because there is so much
able connection that isn't really with
those things are compromised and goes.
As human beings,
you know,
we used to be this kind of really small
group of people as you would know and
you know who did use things like
divination,
things that kind of made sense to them
and in that community that worked
effectively.
We see that in the past and yet for some
reason with materialism and capitalism
and as you said,
the politics and let's be honest,
the place where it doesn't serve us to
care for people because that's the wider
discussion,
isn't it?
It doesn't serve people who are doing
well to some degree to care for those
who are not.
And yet the answer is that that's the
answer.
And everyone who really thinks about it,
I can see that.
It curious how on a sort of a very basic
level,
things like eat the food that's in
season in the place where you're living
is like a sort of good for you because I
like,
they're sort of like,
there's a sort of a little code that's
all there.
So if a food's known season,
it's haven't been transported,
it won't be good for you.
Like,
so I wonder if there is an analogy with,
like you said,
with compassion and um,
and sort of a subtler forms of feeling.
And I wanted to ask you about sex and
sexuality both as a therapist and as I
am mother of both your sons,
teenagers,
two teenage boys.
So how do you.
I'm like,
you're a therapist.
You produce,
so like gender and sex.
They were recovered with time where all
of this stuff is being repoed and
reexamined.
And so like as a mother of two sons who
are presumably at a point where these
kind of ideas are integral,
how do you,
uh,
what kind of instruction,
what kind of work do you see your role?
Um,
in my role as a mom since day when it
has to have conversations with them
about everything.
And I mean it,
I don't care who judges me for that.
I don't care who judges me because at
the end of the day I'll talk to them
about porn.
I've talked to them about what a girl
will want on the first day and what she
definitely won't want.
I talk about the political standards
that are given to women as far as their
objectification of their bodies or
sexualization of young girls.
The expectations young girls put on
themselves.
I constantly tell them that they are
essentially the future generation of
young men and that they have to
consistently accept that women girls are
equals and I'm absolutely honest.
I mean we'll still,
I'm so honest,
you know,
they know what porn is.
They know why porn exists.
They know what that does some degree to
women and they accept the things that
they see if they see them.
That's not real.
That's not what we're looking for in
good relationships.
Whatever you want in a relationship is
great.
Whatever suits your fancy,
that's okay in a loving,
committed,
connected relationship or at least in a
mutually respectful relationship.
Mr.
Do you think then that the porn is the
sex?
What our action movies to life and,
and,
and if so because I've started to think
of porn is very sort of toxic and
dangerous thing and I have a
relationship with it.
There's a bit like,
you know,
I find it hard to not look at
pornography and it's one of the things I
think that shouldn't look at porn.
Porn is bad,
but like if you like,
but you also are you less puritanical
kind of thing?
I don't think that porn is necessarily
bad because I think that it has a place
in chain Cina.
We're obsessed with bodies.
We like watching people have sex.
We liked the fact that people have
different interactions and fantasy is
really important and particularly for
men and women who like to have visual
stimulus when that happened to
masturbate,
that can be really,
really helpful for them.
What I don't like about porn is it
consistently places the woman on the
whole as a submissive and it also
suggests that women like certain things
that I've never met a client
particularly who likes the fact that 15
men are going to come on their face.
I have to say that's not something that
the average one wants,
but that kind of footage is viewed again
and again and again.
Do you think that must be the men when
looking at pornography?
The fear must be a component.
I'm getting if,
if,
if Paul needs to demonstrate men as
being powerful,
it seems to move it.
It might be catering for the fact that
men feel impotent and powerless trying
to redress that,
so there's a an a bias in pornography to
men being powerful because in effect men
feel powerless and impotent and afraid.
I think that's a really good way of
describing it and when I feel almost
like there's an underlying rage within
porn when I see some of it,
you know,
when I constantly look online to see
kind of what is being mirrored out there
at the moment.
No.
So what expectations would be informed
on 15 year old boys and girls are
looking at the expectations and what
they should want in relationships or in
one night stands or whatever.
I feel this like rage that it's almost
like we have to abuse her.
We have to destroy her to some degree.
She has to enjoy it even though it's not
clearly enjoyable and that concerns me,
but it also suggests that there is some
kind of change in the way that we are
playing out our sexual fantasies.
I want people to realize that whatever
your fantasy,
that's okay.
As long as it is respectful.
As long as the other person is premium
party to that,
I'm willing to be within that fantasy
itself.
I don't think anybody should be afraid
of exploring it.
I constantly teach my clients that shame
is the worst thing you can have in sex,
and one of the things about porn is I
think that's a big part of it.
That same rage and shame that we almost
play out these things on screen that are
uncomfortable.
Why is shame find its way into
sexuality?
Because we're shocked because we're
ashamed of our sexuality early in life.
I think that we are taught shamed so
much in our society.
I think from day one you are told that
sex is bad.
You can only do it at this age.
You should only do it for this reason.
You should only do that with this
protection that you kind of have this
rhetoric already,
but then at the same time,
because we don't just have these really
open,
honest conversations when kids are
growing up,
you know,
how often does somebody go into a
classroom and talk honestly about sex?
Talk honestly about relationships.
So honestly about how good it is and how
bad it can be so that you've kind of got
rid of any need for the shame and you've
engaged with everybody in a way that
they can acknowledge they don't need to
feel stupid or embarrassed or
humiliated.
We formed those norms because our mates
at school are kind of making us feel
that what we're doing,
if we're having sex,
it's promiscuous or what we're doing if
we don't have sex,
frigid.
Those kinds of conversations occur
because adults aren't guiding them.
Like how do we help kids grow into young
men and women who love sex and embraced
it for what it is and feel no shame.
We do it by just being honest with them
and people are horrified about that.
I'll talk about on tv,
I'll say,
let's just start educating them from day
one and people think you're stealing
childhood,
but you're not stealing childhood.
Your creating solid allard.
Adults who can become well adjusted in
the way that they feel about sex.
How can you do that sort of with a
group?
Because I suppose the reason that
there's the,
the,
the suggestion or you're still in
childhood is because it's like these
children are not interested in sex and
your imposing it on them,
you know,
so there's an argument of normally like
around in a way enforcing and
establishing norms around types of
sexuality.
Isn't it like in clause 28 being a
famous example of like,
Oh,
don't teach kids that are almost
sexuality is normal because otherwise
they'll find out that it's normal.
So,
uh,
so I suppose the,
how do you teach a group like a group of
children because presumably there are
children that have different
expectations,
levels of curiosity around sexuality.
How can,
how can you teach it?
I think that you teach it early,
really,
really early.
And when I say honestly,
five years old onwards,
I'm not talking about having sex at five
years old.
I'm talking about what sex is,
how you arrive,
why your born.
That starts the beginning of the
conversation by when kids.
Because presumably what,
when,
when I was thinking about it before he
was answering,
I was thinking right when I would teach
my kid about sex will be when the kid
asks.
No,
I wouldn't talk about when they ask
because children are full of fear
children.
I think that so many adults forget to
look back to how it was,
you know,
I can remember clearly when I was four
and five years old,
I used to suffer from really terrible
ticks as a child.
Like I had really,
really bad touch which have been
twitching about our terrible,
terrible techs have every single one of
them from linking.
Next let's try to getting.
And um,
it was anxiety.
It was a physical eyes.
I didn't want to feel anxiety.
So I use text to manifest that.
And it was because I was so aware of
everybody else's judgment around me.
People would say things to me and open.
Like I remember a guy saying to my dad,
oh,
she's such a funny girl that was there.
I was far.
I was five.
And I've looked back on those times and
always transplanted the recognition that
these kids out there that everyone
thinks it just these naive little
players in life,
they're hypersensitive,
hypersensitive and they're having these
conversations and they're worried about
friendships and they haven't a clue why
the world's working the way that it's
working.
But you know what you can do.
You can make them feel so safe.
Adults can make kids feel so safe.
When I was working on projects where the
young people had had no education,
where they were involved in the criminal
justice system where people had
completely given up on them.
The first job that I had was to make my
boys and girls feel safe because it was
a feeling that everyone assumes people
know,
but very few people really know how to
do it.
By being authentic is number one.
By reassuring them that they're okay.
Even when some of that actions are not
okay,
that fundamentally within them there is
an okayness that we can find that and we
can manifest it and that they can move
forward.
My boys and girls and I say my boys more
than my girls because my 80 percent of
my boys came to the projects,
about 20 percent were girls.
So I run um,
crime concerned projects.
I run college projects.
It was Pru,
pupil referral unit.
So when kids had failed in mainstream
education,
they would come to me,
but they would come to me after that
failed in a mainstream pru.
So I got the Pru,
Pru,
kids and I remember that.
I remember my life that are low.
That's wild though.
Yeah,
well I remember like those times with
summer,
I honestly in my head,
um,
I still keep in contact with some of the
young people if I'm honest.
It's a long time since I worked on those
projects,
but what I recognized immediately was
that they hated me when they first
bought,
they hated me.
They were like,
one called.
I was called posh batch was number one,
even though I'm not working class,
but my accent was different to theirs,
but it was okay.
So there's a scowl.
If you've been kicked out,
the thing that you go to when you're
kicked out or things you might feel like
audrey hepburn after rex Harrison is my
fair lady,
but you know what result,
that was the key.
The key to me was one,
always being myself,
always using the opportunity to inspire,
not to take away my boys particularly.
You had had their self esteem eradicate
it to such a degree that but nine years
old,
they weren't in the classroom.
They were sent outside to play.
They didn't know how to read and why at
13,
14,
15,
16.
If you can't read and write,
you don't feel like you belong.
You don't have access.
Shamed.
It's horrible and that's the other thing
when you talk about academia as well.
Academia is amazing.
People are really bright.
They seek out and suit themselves with
that area of expertise and it's
brilliant,
but at the same time it creates a elite.
My boys would look at people in
education,
even people with gcse is let alone
doctorates and professorships.
They would see an us and them.
My whole experience in life with my
clients,
with the young people I had the
privilege to work with,
with my children,
I want it to be as an author.
I want it to feel like there is no
difference.
We are human,
therefore we're equal.
I may know this and you may know that,
but there is something intrinsic.
I say to every single client that I have
when they're questioning themselves more
than nature,
as you brought up nature before and
everybody has their own opinions on
this.
Personally,
I think nature has an answer for
absolutely everything.
I think she's incredibly bright and she
knows exactly what she's doing and why
she's doing it.
Whether we see those solutions or choose
to ignore them,
whether politically we're allowed to
have those solutions or have them with
help from us.
That's the difference in that
suggestion,
you know,
but one thing I know is that every
single human being out of all these
billions of people have one thing to
print.
I don't for one minute believe that
mother nature decided to give every
single human being a marketing so unique
to them that that wasn't reason and
purpose.
I teach every single child that I ever
worked with.
Every client you were marked,
you were marked with something that
stands you out from every other person.
Finding it is the issue.
Finding it of beautiful.
I think that that word communicate.
It means create community.
Create connection.
Absolutely.
So you're good at doing that.
Then it was this thing up,
so add to get rid of them.
Terrible ticks,
which is a phrase that when it first
came out,
I'm sure called Constellation in an
audio medium that might be a new teller
for show.
Actually terrible ticks presented by Mr
Kenney with several ticks,
but do self down.
I'm higher,
I terrible texture.
I am still happy.
Where's your,
where are your tie control them?
How sometimes I go to the toilet and I
go back for a bit.
I still have my texts I have is um,
it's physicalized anxiety.
So I'm quite,
I would say I don't really feel low.
I don't really feel anxious,
but I'm aware that like anybody,
I have a certain amount of stresses and
strains in my world and my life,
so my brain kind of just go,
ah,
just give yourself a bit of a twitch
that's better than twitches and I do,
you know what?
I can still remember my mom when I was
seven years old and I was quite a cute
little kid with blonde pigtails,
but mum was working class,
but you know,
a really,
really great mother and she would put my
hair in pigtails.
She put me in a red coat.
She always coordinated everything.
We didn't have a lot,
but she made a real effort.
Me and my sister would look like we were
kind of quite well to do kids,
you know,
walking down the road and then I would
cough,
do my neck,
do molag,
throw my shoulders out and she would
just look at me with absolute despair.
There was a correlation between those
two things with what Darwin you up or
nice and you twitching eye out like some
little punk.
Back in the day.
I didn't know how to verbalize my pain
and at the time there were certain
things in my life that felt painful and
that was a way of using my body to
express my sadness.
I'm only learning now quite late in
life.
How muck of it being a person too much
or in the intellect and the body is
where so much happened.
So you go get into your body.
Yes,
yes.
That's a big thing for me.
That has been a huge learning curve for
me.
I used to analyze everything I used to
feel that I had to work out every
intrinsic piece and cellular experience
that I had and it created so much noise
and volume and what I've learned to do
more recently is find this acceptance of
silence and switching off and allowing
myself to kind of meditate on how my
body feels like how my body feels,
not how my mind is and it's been so
soothing and so helpful.
Pop Mindfulness of course,
isn't it?
I'm like,
I,
um,
like do Jujitsu and I'm probably one of
the best people ask it in the world by
one hour a week,
one hour,
where are like body.
Yeah.
I'm in my body and like sort of I'm
physically close to another man
wrestling.
It's sort of like,
it's our love it what you said before
about sex that is probably a really good
way of describing how the perfect sexual
encounter is.
It's when you're not in your head is
when you're fully engaged with your
body.
When you see yourself as playing and
having pleasure and getting pleasure and
having no shame and just allowing
yourself the experience whether that's
in a one night stand or a longterm
committed relationship and it's possible
and it's practical,
but you have to work through all of that
volume and get to a position where you
accept your body before can move forward
or how do you block the territory.
It's a return to a point that we,
uh,
like we started.
But then you sort of terrible ticks.
And then for meditation like,
you know,
like introducing the subject of
sexuality of children.
You said don't wait for them to ask
about it.
Start introducing this one.
W,
W how?
Just have conversations with them.
You know,
from a very early age,
I started to talk about the anatomy of
my body,
my children.
I was a single mom for quite a long
time,
so as a single mom I had one bathroom in
my home,
which meant that my children always saw
me naked,
so I started to have conversations with
them about my body so that they
understood what my boobs were,
what my vagina was.
They still laugh at the word vagina
because we really had fun back in the
day discussing all of those things,
the differences about that bodies then
how they came about,
why they existed,
then what sex was and why it was and why
sex is something that they should one
day enjoy and always feel that I'm the
person they can come and converse with
the barrel,
that both my boys are 13 and 15.
I don't know how I created them.
There are a lot better than I probably
deserved if I'm really honest.
You know,
they're great kids,
but one of the things that strikes me
about them is their emotional
intelligence and they do not have fear.
They do not have the fear that I had
about asking,
you know,
my son will talk to me about porn.
He'll talk to me about the fact that his
friends are talking about sex.
He'll have conversations with me about
them and it's so,
so reassuring because it was simple.
It was simple.
I just made the communication clear that
there was no shame,
no embarrassment.
It was open.
I think it's because you want imagines
that it will not,
you know,
that child's going to go into an
environment where,
like in a moment ago,
we were talking about the kind of what
exists in the world of porn,
the kind of access but young men,
boys,
girls are going to have to pornography.
But he's giving them some given a
curious,
um,
usual on my assumption is dangerous
messages are,
how is your life,
how do you feel as a therapist?
Is My prejudices Mr Kenney human being.
But how,
how is like a sort of a natural
understanding of sex,
sex,
Julie consensual,
loving adult play where we communicate
how like how's it going to survive that
kind of institutional a deviation.
I fully believe that human beings know
how to find that way.
I have a hope consistently.
People say,
how'd you work in certain circumstances?
For example,
with sexual abuse or with murdered
children,
you know,
things like that that people would
really struggle to work with.
How do you work with it?
And it's because I always have a sense
of hope.
My belief system is hope orientated.
I think that no matter how much you
present people with these caricatures,
these characatures of sexuality,
these characatures of having sex on
screen in such a way that very few
people would ever want to encounter.
In the end,
we don't want it.
We desensitize ourselves to it and we
move on.
I hope that women,
if porn continues to hold itself in our
society as it seems to be doing,
I hope that women start to feel that
they should be involved in directing and
creating because fantasy is lost.
There is no fantasy in that.
It's so physical and mechanical.
There has to be something deeper.
Can I ask a question like,
because we hear this idea of like,
of course that is a one vision of female
empowerment is women being involved in
the creation of pornography,
but in a sense isn't that a sort of
coopting of femininity into a mountain
bike because like you know when you sort
of say,
you know,
to raise a May being prime minister,
is that good for feminism?
Was Margaret Thatcher being present?
And of course it's good that women are
in politics,
but I feel like like it's not actually
doing the job that we're trying to do.
I have a second.
I would say,
don't get me wrong,
I would much rather what we have in our
society is a far better relationship
with sex.
It's as simple as that.
I wish that every young person growing
up and every adult could learn early on
to feel that their body is an incredible
tool that something they can really
relate to.
They can enjoy that.
We could have experiences in society
where people can go to lessons and
actually have sessions with people where
they can really construct an identity
with the sexuality,
whether it was correct help for people
who unfortunately have horrible sexual
experiences.
You know,
the statistic is harrowing.
One in six children are sexually abused
before the age of 16,
one in four girls,
one in eight boys.
That's real.
So people are growing up with a
dysfunctional identity towards sex.
So a lot of it is the unraveling.
And when you say about porn,
porn kind of volumizes the negatives as
well.
And I kind of wish that there was more
regulation around that because I think
you're never going to get rid of porn,
but I'd like to see women as equal
players because you get these really
kind of stereotypical vibes about what
women should want and it's turning the.
I always thought,
I know this sounds awful by.
I say to people when I'm talking about
sex,
you never been talking to younger
people.
Don't expect anal sex and fisting when
you have sex for the first time.
That's not what women want and it's not
what you should feel you're pressured to
do,
but if you're watching this kind of
stuff and that's your learning
experience,
you absolutely think that that's a
potential in the room scenario.
What pressure for guys,
what pressure for girls,
so to some degree it's the regulation,
but will that ever happen?
Of course not because it makes a lot of
money and money will always be the
bigger winner in life is extraordinary.
The way we have to incorporate these
external influences on what is governing
the flow of what is normal,
what's determining normality.
It's interesting when something comes up
as a a,
a,
a bowl.
The word in a podcast as listing.
No,
not at all.
Please don't apologize for it.
Of course.
Like I record,
like I once heard about when there was
earlier attempts to regulate the
pornographic content for fisting was one
of the things that they looked at
without considering the role that that
plays in nonheterosexual communities.
I'm like,
sorry.
So regulation can often be used as a
tool to normalize as opposed like when
we're having open conversations about
what sex is,
what sex should be,
but it's very important that that
remains open and inclusive and
nonjudgmental about different types of
sexuality and the thing that I heard
that made most sense to me was consent,
consent,
and who can't give consent,
children and a more mentally ill people.
Yeah.
I think though that the whole porn area,
it's one of those places that could have
purpose,
if that makes sense.
Could be something that could inspire or
it could be somebody that could free
years and allow us our fantasies,
but to some degree the fact that a lot
of people feel intense.
Shame watching porn plays into that dark
psyche anyway.
So I would like to see more people just
normalizing the conversations around
sex,
about talking about that preferences,
about expressing their fantasies without
fear.
I think there's so much fear built up
within the sexual arena.
And Kenny,
thank you very much because I think
communication is going to be vital in
all areas of mental health,
all forms of human expression.
Verbal and sexual and it feels to me
like the way that we relate to our
feelings,
the way that we relate to forms of
expression is vital in this time of
disjunct,
in this time of Fisher separation
conflict in so many fields like you
know,
to once again find union,
but between people that no matter only I
suppose start with communication.
What an incredible journey it's been.
It seems for you from a great
communicator to communicate.
I think you should have your own podcast
and that should be the strap sex talk
obviously will be the title wherever
Kenny,
but the strap from what was that a true
and it's a congruent communicator.
Brilliant.
Listen,
thank you so much.
Thanks for coming.
Thank you.
This show is sponsored by my book
recovery,
which is a good book and it's available
now.
You can order it on Amazon if you want
to.
You can also get the audio book on
audible.
Do it makes good Christmas gift,
and I do a Christmas gift from.
Think about your family.
Oh,
what should I get 'em get 'em that or
maybe or Muslim,
or should I get them just to show that
I'm participating in the seasonal
festivities whenever never get them that
or maybe you're an atheist,
get,
um,
that doesn't even actually matter what
you believe in.
Also,
come see me or my rebirth to Brixton.
December the 19th,
Wolverhampton,
December the 20th.
Go to Russell brand.com
for tickets there.
Finally,
if you liked this show,
please subscribe and review in Itunes or
wherever you listen to it and just give
it five stars because it's good for my
sense of self or well.
Bye Bye.
Thanks.