Krista tippett is here with us today,
which is just absolutely amazing. Um,
I'll read a little bit about her first
and then we will just dive right into it.
Um, Krista Tippett is a Peabody
award winning broadcaster,
national humanities medal list and the
New York Times bestselling author she
founded and leads the on
being project hosts globally,
esteemed on being public radio show
and podcast and curates the civil
conversations project and emergent
approach to conversation and relationship
across the differences of our age.
Her books include my
favorite becoming wise,
an inquiry into the mystery and art of
living and Einstein's God conversations
about science and the human spirit.
And I think literally even
just with those two titles,
you see this beautiful and vast
spectrum that Christa covers.
And that is so kind of
perfect for us here at Google,
literally from mystery and spirit to
the human spirit to Einstein. Like it's,
it's just so perfect to have her here
in conversation here. We're so lucky.
And I think really we were talking
the other evening about, um,
what it means to inquire and the
idea of asking these questions,
these fundamental questions,
questions that get to the essence
of what does it mean to be human?
What does it mean to be human together?
And kind of what are the lessons we can
learn in this practice with everyone.
So we'll look at that today.
But first I'll just share a quick
funny little moment, which was,
as I was preparing for this,
I've been listening to Christopher years
a couple of years ago as I was actually
founding the lab, I found myself
listening to Krista. I'd, I'd, uh,
I'd discovered her then rediscovered her
and the project. And every day I was,
it was kind of over break. I was
listening to one a day or even two a day,
sometimes her podcasts.
And what I found is they
were so enlivening and they
really helped birth the
empathy lab. So I feel like I
wouldn't be, it wasn't for her.
So it's a treat to have you here.
But what was,
is thinking about preparing for this.
And I was like,
should I go back and listen to every
podcast and find my favorite moments? And,
and then it just would have been like
this incredible mountain of beauty that I
would have,
you know,
clearly like fallen under because
there was just too much there.
So what was beautiful was
actually reflecting on the
thing that touches me most
about her conversations
and these beautiful moments
that unfold between her and
other people even across distances.
Um,
or just this in the moment that you're
listening, what comes alive in you,
what echoes in you in
the days, weeks, months,
years to follow and how these
kind of sparks come alive in us.
So that leads us to this form of listening
that I feel like I really learned to
listen even just in being presence
with her before knowing her.
And I feel like we're all so lucky to
have her speaking to us about listening
today.
And so I'll just start with one of her
quotes that really I feel touched as the
core of what this art is all about,
which is listening is about
being actively present.
It's not just about being quiet.
I meet with others with a life, right?
I meet others with the life I've lived,
not just with my questions.
So let's welcome Krista with open minds
and hearts and of course our ears and
share more for gracious wisdom with us.
And of course we are trying something a
little different today with this kind of
intimate gathering. So what we'll
do is crystal, we'll share a bit,
we'll probably go back and forth and
then we'd love to open it up as a real
conversation for all of us to live in
together. So if you have any questions,
definitely listen.
Don't think about them the whole time,
but as they rise up in the room,
please feel brave and courageous.
This is what this moment is about. So
thank you and welcome Krista. Yeah.
[inaudible]
well, it's exciting to be here. Um,
I love this invitation. I feel like
I made too many notes and so we just,
so Danielle and I just liked, cause I
really loved our conversation and I,
the more I do this, the longer
I live, the more I trust that.
And I liked being on both sides of it.
So I've just said to her,
I want her to interrupt me and ask
questions and that I really would like to
open it up and be in conversation
with you. Um, the question,
the kind of requests was to talk a little
bit about the art of listening and you
know, I'm a person who listens
for a living, but you know,
one of the things what you were saying
about that experience of the podcast of
listening to the podcast,
I mean I
listening is about presence,
which I'm going to say again,
but what's so fascinating and you and
I talked about this the other night,
is that, I mean, I am usually
not in the room. In fact,
I'm often halfway across the world from
the people I'm in conversation with.
And, um, the technology
of radio of podcast.
I mean, so, you know, these are
not physical experiences but,
but my conversations,
um,
because of the topic and then because
the medium allows for this are very,
very intimate and they're intimate between
me and the person I was speaking with.
And then it's an intimate experience,
you know,
one of the kind of the magic of radio
and of course that's just the old
fashioned word for podcasting, um, is, uh,
is that it is profoundly individual and
also absolutely communal at the same
time. And there's also kind of a
time shift that goes on, right?
It defies time because,
because in the moment that you listen,
you're in that room when it happened.
And you know,
I think of a conversation,
what I hope for every conversation I
have is that it is an adventure and that
something will happen that
will surprise both of us.
And if you, as a listener, you also
are there for that moment of surprise.
Um,
so that's,
I was thinking a lot about that actually
as I was thinking about being here
because, because we're talking
about human presence and,
and there is this miracle,
but it's absolutely possible with
and through and in technology.
And I think that what you're about is
figuring out how to amplify that and to
explore all the possibilities in that.
Um,
so I think of listening
as a basic social art.
Um,
I think of social art and virtues
as spiritual technologies.
Um,
and that assists to just a tool for the
art and craft of living and have it for
a deep end more generative,
which is a nuance on productive father.
It can be productive,
but a more deepened generative,
higher quality human experience. And, um,
the interesting thing,
so it is a basic social art.
I think it's something we know how
to do or we've known how to do,
but we've actually unlearned. Um, uh,
I think that growing up in this culture,
we learn to that listening is,
or the experience we have,
which we internalize to be
about what listening is about,
is to be quiet while the other person
says what they have to say until it's time
for me to say what I have
to say. But actually, um,
listening is not about being quiet,
being quiet as a side effect.
Um,
listening is about being present.
and as I just said, interestingly,
you can be present online as well.
Um, and so because we've kind
of unlearned this thing, um,
I think it's interesting
to think about what era.
It's really basic component
parts. Um, for me,
um,
listening
brings a quality musters equality
of generous generosity. You know,
and in a spiritual technology is always,
is always working in two directions.
It's inner work as much
as it's outer work. Um,
so especially in this world,
we can have it now and there's so many
things we're fighting about in so many
things were fearful about.
Um,
this is not as easy as it sounds. Right?
In fact, it's not very instinctive.
Um, you know, to me a generous listener,
it definition of that would be wanting
to understand the humanity behind the
war,
the words of the other.
So it's not just about the words that
are going to pass between us and wanting
to bring your own best words and your
best ideas into the conversation you have
to muster.
Also in yourself.
A real curiosity to bring that
kind of generosity to bear.
And again,
this is really kind of a wizard muscle.
The thing about curiosity,
you can't actually fake it.
And again, whether we're
online or offline, um,
we add an animal level when we
encounter another human being,
absolutely know whether they're really
curious or whether they're just asking us
a question. We know
that in our bodies. Um,
so really like even just this basic,
this basic component of the art
of living, of being curious, uh,
becomes kind of a spiritual discipline.
Or if you don't like that language,
it becomes a muscle that we need to
flex and flex so that it again, um,
starts to feel like instinct
starts to feel natural. Um,
listening involves, um, vulnerability.
I mean one litmus test,
um,
about whether you have actually gotten
yourself to a curious place that you can
ask whether you go into a room, whether
that's a virtual room or a physical room,
is are you willing to be surprised?
And again,
we walk into all of our spaces these days,
so guarded,
so clear about what we have to say,
what we have to present,
what we have to protect.
And also so clear about what we
think those other people stand for.
Um,
so to,
to be willing to be surprised as
it is an unnatural move right now.
And then,
and then the final piece of this that I
want to add is that we actually have to
be that actually in,
in many of the spaces we are currently
working with and living in and meeting
each other.
And it wouldn't actually be reasonable
to ask other people to surprise
themselves, their surprise us. Um, so, so,
so there's a piece of this I
think that get the, that the,
that the social art of listening is
intimately connected with the virtue of
hospitality. Uh, another
spiritual technology.
One thing I love about hospitality,
it's kind of a gateway to
all the other great virtues,
compassion or love.
Um,
you actually though it's much easier.
It's an easier entry point.
You don't actually have to love
someone to be hospitable towards them.
You don't have to agree with them
to be hospitable towards them.
You don't even have to like them
But we know in our analog lives,
um,
and I think maybe we're learning in our
online lives that have the space you
create,
um,
absolutely limits or expands what
is possible that will happen there.
There is a difference between creating
a space with a welcome and an ethos or
just opening the door so
that anything can happen.
Um,
something that's very clear to me that
I think a lot about that it's fun to say
in this room is that,
uh, you know, to me, uh,
the,
the digital world is just a new
canvas for the old human condition.
There's nothing that happens online
that doesn't have an offline,
although things can absolutely
get amplified. You know,
it's the good, the bad and
the ugly we're encountering,
you know, but trolls, like we have,
we all walk around with
trollish places in our psyches.
Now they have this public,
this public room to run around and write.
Um, that's like visuals, just like,
um, but so, so, so there's this,
so this has always been true, um, that,
that the quality of the encounter of
the listening, of the relationship,
of the possibility of what
can happen between two people,
whether they agree with each
other or don't or similar don't.
It's very much effected by the, by
the spirit, by creating the space.
Um, and so, and I think
there's just a real need it in,
again,
in the physical world,
as much as in the online world
to create alternative spaces.
And I'll say it again,
where it would be reasonable to ask
any of us to walk in and bring our best
selves and, and be looking for
the good and the other, um,
and be willing to surprise ourselves
and be truly inviting other people to
surprise us. Um, so that's, those are,
I guess the other thing I would want to
just mention that I absolutely think of,
um, in terms of a companion
to, to listening is the,
um,
the art of asking better questions.
Um, in, in American life, we,
we mostly trade in the answers and we
actually mostly trade in competing answers
and a lot of what,
uh,
calls itself a question or
presents as a question is actually,
or is actually art,
not questioning.
It's kind of tools or weapons
to incite or corner or catch,
you know,
or at least entertain.
And this is certainly true in
my field of journalism. The,
the question is often about how it
makes the journalist look and not really
about what it's going to elicit.
What I want to point out
and that spectacle, which
we're all very familiar with,
is how powerful a form
of words a question is.
Um,
the way I've come to experience it as
that questions elicit answers in their
likeness,
answers rise or fall to
the questions they meet.
And in then in the negative,
uh, expression of that,
which we're very familiar
with from media. Um, you know,
it's very,
it's almost impossible to meet a
simplistic question with anything but a
simplistic answer.
It's almost impossible to
transcend a combative question.
But the positive,
the positive side of that is that it's
almost impossible to resist a generous
question.
And we've all had that experience that
there is something life giving about
asking a better question.
Um, can I ask you? Yeah,
yes, yes, yes. You May. Yeah,
I know, right? You're like, if it's a
good one. Yeah. Cause it generous. Yeah.
So what I'm hearing is you're speaking is,
um,
is there's this sense of an opening
that happens when there is a generous
presence.
There is an opening in the question.
There's an opening in the space
between you or things can be put there.
I'm so curious.
Um,
you mentioned that the other night with
the word you set an intention before you
go in and the listening before the
listening and I'm just curious how,
how does that work for you? How do you
cultivate that opening in yourself?
That invitation?
Because it is that first
step of hospitality is open
the door and come into this
space that we can be in together.
I'm just,
when I'm having a conversation
or an interview when you're
having a conversation.
Yeah. And when you're figuring
out the right questions,
the questions that have the
opening in them. Yeah. Um,
well I do actually think in terms of
hospitality and the work I do so and,
and so I think of the preparation
I do for an interview as inactive,
as work of hospitality.
Um, because you know,
again,
we,
we so much is determined about how an
encounter is going to go in the initial
moments before words are spoken.
So just kind of like setting that table.
MMM.
Which is an image of a certain kind of
hospitality, but it's the same idea.
MMM.
When we don't do that,
then the most obvious things about us
that we're all carrying out front right
now just to define what's,
just define what's possible.
And so what I'm interested in is how can
we not solve all the problems or make
it that way?
Because I really want to be in rooms with
people I disagree with and who are and
who I, who I need to learn from and
who I know I want to share life with,
even if I really don't understand them.
Not Violent people,
but most people aren't violent.
There's this huge swath in
the middle where those, those
fellow humans are there.
Um, so what I want to do is
create the space so that,
so that the things that we
already know are problematic, um,
are certainly present that they don't
define what becomes possible between us.
Um, in my interviews, you know, when you
just asked me that intuitively, you know,
what comes to mind is I get excited.
I'm just excited about the
conversation and, and the,
and I want to prepare,
um,
because I want them to be able to relax
as quickly as possible so that we can
really go deep.
And one way I do that is by,
by knowing about them,
by honoring them,
by reading their books, if they've
written books or knowing what they do.
Um, I mean I do a lot of, you know,
I will also read other interviews they've
given. I would say. So I think of my, um,
interview preparation mode as the
Vulcan mind meld mode of interview
preparation. It's like, you know, um,
my mind to your mind,
your thoughts to my thoughts because my,
my goal in preparing, it's not that I, um,
no what,
what they think as much
as how they think and,
and so that then,
and again this works if they're halfway
across the world and I'm in a studio in
there, in a studio that we all
know what this experience is.
If you meet someone new
and you know very quickly,
if you're going to have
to explain yourself,
defend yourself,
be on guard,
and then that's what your
whole body gears up to do.
And then that just write that,
then you're, then you're off. So,
but what I'm aiming for is this
other experience we've all also had,
you meet somebody and you're
just know that they get you.
And even when I say that to you right now,
like my body relaxes and there was a
lot more possibility and it's a much,
it's a soft right.
It's a soft space in which
just going to happen.
And I think it's a more playful,
adventurous space for the same reason I
interrupt to do with my question. No, no,
I love that. I, I didn't, um,
I did want to, you know, um,
one of the things you
said to me is that you,
you also wanted to invite me here at
Google to just say whatever was on my mind
that, that I would want to stay and, um,
to you. And, um, actually, I mean,
I have a fair number of
conversations about, you know,
not about technology per se,
but about our lives with technology and,
um, and do think about this
a great deal. And I, I mean,
one thing I want to say is that I,
um,
and I know you all are, you know, we're,
we're now having this kind of reckoning
culturally with the civilizational
effect of the work you do,
the work that happened in this
industry and we've all created that
civilizational effect who we've all
cocreated it and it's so new and these
technologies, there's so much
in their infancy. And, uh,
I think one of the messages that's
come through so clearly is, um,
with wise people in my
conversations is that, you know,
that we forget that all of this is in
its infancy because it is so powerful and
it has so quickly kind of feels
like taken over our lives. But,
but there is the opportunity and
the challenge is, is to continue,
is to shape our lives with technology
and the technologist to human to human
purpose. And, and I'm also aware of, um,
I do think this is also true
in journalism. Like culturally,
we're so much more skill
that sophisticated analysis
and criticism of what is
flawed and failing and destructive
and terrifying and catastrophic,
right?
Like,
we're really good at that and
we're not as sophisticated at,
at seeing and analyzing and working with
and they're buying nurturing what is
generative and beautiful and humane.
And,
and I think that you, I know,
you know this cause that I,
there's so much that it's human and
beautiful at humane and generative in our
lives with technology as well. Um, just,
I would just say one of the things that's
so clear to me in the sphere I'm in
is, is the abundance
of poetry, um, that is,
that has this whole new life online,
um,
and how people are making
poetry and, and, and,
and putting it up there and sharing it.
Um,
and I think this is also a
civilizational move. I mean, poetry does,
in fact in human societies rise up when
we are in these moments of cultural and
political disarray. It
does. Um, it's, it's,
uh,
it's something we are turning to as our
official forms of language and discourse
are so broken and failing
us so badly. And it, it,
it gives us ways to give voice
to the best of ourselves.
And actually also it
gives us ways to throw,
to put questions into the room.
And I just,
I mean the room and a
very expansive sense,
the public room that aren't,
that we,
that are there for us to live
rather than answer or fight about.
Um, uh, one of those,
and one of those questions by way of
poetry that I work with a lot is from
Elizabeth Alexander,
who was the poet of the
first Obama Administration.
And she has this poem which ends,
you know,
poetry is the human voice and are
we not of interest to each other.
And to me that is,
that is a question that refrains like,
can we get along or are you
a Republican or a democrat?
Like if that's a question
that could help reframe,
are grappling with all the things
we want to grapple with. Um,
and then I'm sure many of you are aware
that Mary Oliver died last week and I
was so,
so privileged to have,
I think the last big interview she
gave in 2015 in which I will share,
she smoked the entire
c only interview I've ever had where my
producer texted me before I arrived and
said, she wants to smoke.
Are you okay with that?
It's like she never gives interviews.
Of course I'm okay with that.
But it was so perfect because I knew
it wasn't remote smoking.
It was in my face and it was,
I was privileged.
Um,
and she was wearing a new England
patriots sweatshirt and, and it was just,
it made her so much more perfect that
she's so three dimensional because,
you know,
very Oliver,
her critics think that she's like poetry
light because she writes beautiful
things about the natural world.
Um,
and I think some of the people who love
her most put her up on a pedestal and
turn her into a saint.
And the truth is like if you think about
a sophisticated analysis of goodness
and beauty,
but you know,
she fled to the woods and started writing
poetry because she was living in an
abusive household. And the poet, you know,
she spent years in young
adulthood gathering berries
because that's what she had
to eat.
And it was that three
dimensionality of her and that,
that's what gives her poems about
beauty and goodness, such heft.
And actually I took,
you know,
so here a question she put out into the
world that is now rippling through it
again. And it's one of these
transformative questions
we can live. Tell me,
what is it you plan to do with
your one wild and precious life?
And something, another gift she gave me
in that interview was to just, you know,
bring the six plus is the,
the phrase,
I like the phrase generous listening.
Mary Oliver used the
phrase convivial listening.
There's like a bubbling and that's
really I being the protests that she is.
I'm glad you brought Marriott
because I actually, um,
when I saw that and I thought immediately
of view because I listened to that
interview and um,
the thing that touched me the most in
that interview with Mary was how she
talked about her poetry
being being a moving thing.
That she would walk to have the poetry
come through her and then she'd have to
run home and get the,
and what I loved about that was just
that it was the living the questions.
It isn't the,
I sit down in this things come stuffs
and I think something that you were
talking about a few minutes
ago with journalism,
which is the nature of
the questions again,
you can go so easily to the
places of, um, you know,
the darker spaces, the shadow
we spaces because it, it works.
There's a lot of edge there to work with.
I think design and journalism is
very similar in terms of there's a,
there's a curiosity. It's, it's funny,
you can almost say like search poetry
and replace like design or art or all
these things. It's all
inquiry into that, that thing.
At the core of something that you're
going to bring out and make felt and move
everything else away.
And when I look at design or journalism,
I think about this deep curiosity that
rises up into us and do we want to just
look for the problems we want to solve?
The itchy seems that drive us crazy or
the things that feel like they're not
right. Or is there actually
something even deeper than that?
It's more kind of unifying them
that that is this place of beauty.
And the way you describe beauty as,
actually,
I don't want to misquote you
like right here. So let me,
let me make sure I get this
right. Um, in my notes,
I literally have the hippies code
on beauty, which is always my,
like my touchstone, which is state
of the world is hopelessly reeling.
Stay close to the sounds that bring
you alive. And your quote is beauty,
is that in the presence of
which we feel more alive.
So this vitality or speaking
about, yeah, and that was,
that's actually a language of John
O'donoghue was another poet and theologian
and philosopher. Um, and I, so he,
he was talking, we were
actually talking about, um,
how a lot of the words that we need them
most and love the most also get ruined.
Um,
and I think that's true of words like
peace and justice and love, you know,
and kindness.
They get on bumper stickers or they get
partisan affiliations and, and so we,
so I think sometimes we have to,
we have to put them to one side and use
them less and kind of say what we're
saying and use a universe of words,
um,
and not expect those words
to do the work for us. Um,
but sometimes we just really
have to claim a word and say, no,
we're not gonna let this die. We
have to resurrect it. And Yeah,
I'm trying to do that
with the word civility.
But he used the word
beauty and I said to him,
well,
you know, beauty is another one
of those words. I said, like,
if you just throw the word beauty and
to many conversations, I said, you know,
maybe were where my mind would go is
to the flawless face on the cover of a
magazine. Right? And he
said, no, no, that's glamour.
And they said,
beauty is that in the presence
of which we feel more aligned.
Okay.
And what you just said,
um,
about,
you know,
the inquiry.
Okay.
If we're,
if we're focused on solving the problems,
do we then end up being
orienting towards the problems?
And I, and I, and I,
and you know, I think,
I don't think we have to do one or the
other, right? I think we can, I think we,
we do to some extent need
to focus on the problems.
Um,
and
it's also just as serious
and robust a question to ask,
uh,
what do we want to amplify?
Because it is good for us
because it,
because it speaks to and elicits the
best of which our species is capable.
I think that's so much
of the conversation.
Just make her Google
not to speak for myself.
And as part of the community of Google.
Um,
I think that's part of what's so
fascinating about this braces phase,
awkward adolescent moment we are in
with technology right now. You're right,
the power is what has brought
us along so far, so fast,
but there's so much more to be done.
There's so much expansion,
there's so much support,
there's so much positivity.
It's easy to focus on the fear part
of it because that's real and that's
happening and things must shift.
But there's so much potential if you
focus on what are the things that we want
to expand in people,
what are the ways we can support,
how can we look not just at the
functional and productive needs,
but at the generative spacious needs of
people. How was the whole person welcome?
And I think what's so curious and part
of why this listening conversation,
it's so wonderful to have everyone in
the room here is we are really trying to
go back to these core skills that are
so easy to forget what the speed with
which we all live and,
and remember what does it mean to in our
process open up moments where we have
spaces for better listening,
where we are practicing some of
these skills in a different way. Um,
working with the design
process so that it's not, um,
it's not kind of the normal
way that we make things,
but that we ourselves more
of us as welcome in that
room and at the white board
that there is kind of,
you know,
for the humans on this side and the way
that it touches people on the outside
and the way that all kind of circles,
um,
what does it mean to work with new models
and open spaces and these places that
we all create in this. Also
kind of where, you know,
you think about that as an intersection
of design and the hospitality virtue.
Absolutely. Yeah. Um,
I'm very clear that as much as we are,
again seeing the,
the dark well,
we're seeing the dark side of
ourselves on this great big canvas. Um,
and we're seeing this very young industry,
which one of the things I've learned here
is it's not really an industry, right?
It's a bunch of companies
competing with each other,
but the world actually needs
you all to be an industry. Um,
um, this industry that
ha that it, you know, I,
I spent my twenties in divided Berlin and,
um,
I keep thinking about that this
out here in silicon valley because
as much as we are riveted by what's
happening in Washington DC or in London,
um, your, the, your company,
these companies are the
superpowers of this century.
And that's huge now.
And I,
and we're all now aware of the
perils of that and all the,
all the pieces that need to be in place
for that to be true and to be good for
humanity.
But I also see that,
uh, you know, every,
every generation,
every century has had it's life
altering technologies, right?
The railroad changed everything.
The telephone changed everything.
Electricity Change, everything.
Fire change everything. But,
but what is new about our technologies?
Of course the pace is different,
but I don't think that's really it because
I think in other generations the pace
of those things was,
was equally completely disorienting.
It is the intimacy,
our technologies are woven
into the fabric of our days,
into the fabric of our lives.
They are shifting the way we
make and lead and learn and La,
they're woven into the human enterprise.
And,
and what I also see is that
these technologies and the
interconnected world and
economies they've given us have actually
given us the tools for the first time
as a species to think
and act as a species.
Yeah. We are not anywhere living
up to that right now. Right.
Like that's not the picture
that this is the reality.
This is the potential.
I love articulation of it.
I've never heard it quite like that,
but indeed it is. Um, the, yeah,
the ability to be interconnected.
It is actually, when you say
woven, it's interconnected.
Not just in kind of our humanity,
but actually in the way
that we are connected.
And I think the inside and outside,
yes. But that inner and outer is,
is so critical. And actually
it's, it's perfectly, you
said that because there was,
um, there was a moment that
you had, that you reflected on,
in your book with Dr Rachel
Naomi [inaudible] Rehman
where you talk about Tikkun
Olam and, and what's interesting
is I actually had a moment
where I was like, oh,
shall I talk about spirituality had
Google and I was like, absolutely, yes.
This is the human heart we're talking
about. The language is almost, you can,
you can use whatever language you want.
The thing that we were speaking about,
the thing that breeds all of our hearts,
the thing that connects all of us is
always the same. So that is what this is.
But, um, sometime early in the life of
the world, something happened to shatter.
He knows origin myth,
the light of the universe and the
countless pieces they lodged a sparks and
every part of creation or highest human
calling is to help repair the part of
the world that we can see and touch.
And I just immediately thought,
what if everything we designed had that
beauty and service and your version of
beauty, you and John's, um, to it,
this idea that we can repair the parts
of the world that we see in touch,
that is a pretty incredible fabric when
we think about what filament is at our
fingers here at Google, what
a great mission, you know,
to organize and organize
the world's information to
light it up and repair it as
well. I think that's where no one else
gets. Also at the one in the same time,
it's audacious and it's doable, right?
Because that, you know, that's the,
that's the Jewish, the
story behind the, it's,
it's called the birthday of the world
and it's behind the moral commandment to
repair the world.
And I really love,
like that's another piece of
language that I think is so useful,
so much better than save the world,
which was what the 20th century was about.
And so much damage was done in
the name of saving the world.
And it also made people, it
actually alienated people
from their sense of agency,
um,
but repair the world and you know,
ever since 2016 it's just like all the,
like all the images that come to mind
about what we have to do in our countries
like weaving, stitching. So
these mending, repairing,
you know, one and, and the
thing is, it's a big picture,
but it's one relationship at
the time and the at a time.
And that's what she said
to repair the world, um,
is the highest human calling. But you
start with what you can see and touch.
That's, that's what you're called
to. I love that pragmatism.
And it also, um, what I feel like is
rising up in the conversation too,
is this save the world.
It made me think there is this really
beautiful intention we have in the valley
and in technology. Um, how can we
solve these audacious human problems,
these large scale massive things?
How can we,
the intention of that is so beautiful.
Um, the results of that are not always,
um, when you speak about intentionality
and hospitality and this whole space that
we've started to kind of
unroll in our conversation,
what's your advice for
us with that? Um, yeah,
well that's, that's all I'm going
to know it. Solve it for you.
But what I, what I will say, I think the
intentionality, your question is so good.
You know,
that's my highest compliment that
it is my birthday. And I thought
that was officially the best friend.
Um,
we all know,
we know in our lives,
we know in the lives of
companies and organizations,
um, the intentionality at
the beginning of something,
the intentionality that's embedded in it
has this mysterious power to be in the
DNA forever. Right? Um,
but culturally and I think especially in
the realm of like productivity of every
kind,
we really privilege the what and the when
questions and not the how and the why.
Hmm.
And I actually think if,
um,
actually believe that if we are going
to wrap our arms around these big
civilizational, these intimate and
civilizational challenges, we have,
um, you know, the end, the
problem is as we also know,
if you,
if you rush to do something,
if you rush to a solution,
you often waste time.
You often end up setting something loose.
The didn't have the
intentionality that it needed,
that you then spend time rolling
back and dismantling and solving for,
um, which is, which is
all by way of saying, um,
it would be who of us now.
And I,
and I mean in every aspect of our
lives and in everything we do,
whatever our work is, um, because,
because this is a critical moment,
um,
to really invest our time,
our creativity,
um, our attention, uh,
a sophisticate,
the sophistication we would give to,
to solving a problem to, to, to
this, to the, to the why, the,
and the how of it.
Um,
yeah,
and what that means and it,
but that has some trade offs that
are culturally, uh, difficult.
Right?
That means you would spend a lot more
time on something that doesn't look like
you're being busy.
So like there's a culture shift that
has to happen around this though.
Langue language I love
that actually comes from,
from spiritual traditions is
the language of discernment. Um,
you know,
I mean,
I know like these industries you're in
are all that innovation and we actually
have to hoist in that a
lot of the problems, mag,
the massive prompts we're dealing with
now are the result of innovations,
you know, and, and also just like
what we did with food 50 years ago,
um,
where we created convenience and
we have actually like w I mean,
could,
do you know what an innovation it was to
have food coming out of boxes and cams,
like, you know, life changing,
amazing, so bad for us,
very lucrative,
so bad for us.
And so now we are like h and then the,
you know, our, our, our
government policies followed it,
agriculture followed it,
all of these things followed it.
But now we're now are implicated in
this massive complex of things around
climate and and Helson and economies
that we have to like take apart and saw
four,
right?
So innovation is not in itself a good
like innovation is not necessarily
progress.
And so that's something to ponder.
And I think if you say
if, if, if these, if,
if our technologies and our lives with
them or in their adolescence, if art, if,
if these super power companies
are also, you know, very young,
I think that discernment
muscle like you know,
of course innovation
has been a core value,
but in the next stage asking
will it be good for the world,
will it be good for humanity?
And that's going to look like
wasting time being discerning. Yeah.
You use the word imagination
a lot to describe that
generative, spacious process.
And in the end I think imagination and
discern my go really beautifully together
towards that.
I must pick up.
So you mentioned that civility is a word
that means a lot to you now and just
talking about these civil,
I love saying that these are civilization
level problems because it includes the
humanity and the culture and you
can just all things at once. Um,
please share your definition.
No, I'm disability. Yes. Um,
well I know it's a problematic word
and I always add other adjectives,
like I say, adventurous civility
or muscular civility. Um,
it's not about, I think we have to
get past the idea that, uh, you know,
it's not, to me it's not,
again, like what is it not,
it's not being nice kind and tame.
Um,
those aren't big enough
qualities to need this moment.
I'm not saying there's
not a place for them,
but that's not what civility is about.
I want to say,
I want to say that civility,
that the intention,
the intentionality behind it is
this repair of our lives together.
Um,
I think,
I think there are these, um, kind of,
there's the questions that have,
um,
that had been with humanity and animated
humanity and I think animated at us,
at us, at our best, that are
ancient and enduring or you know,
what does it mean to be human
and how do we want to live? Um,
and the third question is
who will we be to each other?
And that question across history
has been optional in many settings.
And I think actually the technologies
you created make that question
inextricable now for,
for humans.
It inextricable from the question
of what it means to be human and,
and how we want to live.
Absolutely. And civility,
civility in my mind we're,
we're also like,
there's so many different
things happening at once,
which is part of what
makes this moment dizzying.
And we're very focused on
what's going wrong, but
there's so many ways that
we're understanding the
fullness of what it means to
be human. And, um,
understanding our bodies and our brains
in the interaction between them and also
in,
in our,
in culture fit fully in,
perfectly to slowly.
But,
but gaining a sense of
the fullness of like,
you know, I wa I want, I don't, I don't,
I think these words like diversity
and tolerance are like way too small
inclusion like still is.
There's an INCIRCL but I think
we're really moving beyond us.
We want the full array of humanity
in the room to have its place.
I mean we,
we have such a newly robust understanding
just of the matter of identity.
We are the generation that
is redefining gender. Um,
so I think, you know,
one of the things that happened with the
notion of civility that was that it was
about like these, these phrases like
we would all get on the same page,
right? Or the thing we do
like the democratic instinct,
well you've got some people that think
that smelled like take a vote, move on.
But these intimate civilizational
questions of how we're going to live,
we all have a stake in them.
So to me,
civility in this generation
is about knowing that we
walk into the room or ended
the discussion with deep,
profound differences that are
meaningful and important to us.
And the point is not agreeing.
Um,
the point is getting into relationship.
The point is coming to know each other
and that thing of opening up what is not
letting those things we disagree on
define what is possible between us opening
up a new space where perhaps what
we have in common are questions.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And in that opening of the space that's
a bigger than the differences. Yeah.
It allows for all of the
questions, all of the voices. Um,
something that you were speaking with
Pico I hear about and that recent
interview was, um, how
he talked about how,
what was it in the
institutions of skepticism.
He's kind to all of these
incredibly decorated universities,
which he refers to as the
institutions of skepticism.
And he says that we learned how
to talk but not how to listen,
how to put ourselves forward,
but not how to actually erase ourselves.
And so much of that is this
the living of the listening,
the living of the questions.
If we do that in an artful way,
there really is space for all of that.
Whereas the way kind
of currently it works,
like maybe there isn't always space for
it because it feels like there's not
enough space for us because all
of us isn't there. Um, but this,
this idea of seeking,
I think he also said that everything
important he lived or everything important
in his life that he's learned has come
through his heart and not for his mind.
And I think that's something
that we, um, you know, as,
as good souls here at Google doing,
you know,
what we want to do good
work for the world.
There's this tension between the things
that we feel and the things that we know,
the things we can prove and
the things that we intuit.
And I'm just curious as well in this,
in this listening and in the allowing
of all things for this greater sense of
stability, um, how does one navigate that,
navigate the, this, this space?
And I think he'd do it so beautifully
with your work because you sit with,
you sit in conversation
with everyone. Yeah. Um,
well we were going to have to innovate
some new forms for that, right?
Because we don't reward
the time or the energy
or the, we don't, we, you
know, we don't, yeah. We,
we reward what comes from the mind and
not from the heart. Unless you can cry,
you can pitch it as somebody they can
write. And that's what we do actually.
Cause most of it is,
you know,
all this language we've always
used about your gut, you know,
and now we basically learned that
what they're calling the biome,
the second brain, right. Like we've
actually known that we knew somewhere.
So I don't think science is our,
in being able to make a rational,
serious argument about this.
MMM.
But yeah, that's, and so I think right
now all of the structures we have,
mmm.
They're, they're inadequate. I mean, I,
and I mean that in all of our workplaces
and all of our institutions. Um,
they haven't,
they're behind on what we're learning
and actually they're behind on how
actually the world really works
and how change really happened.
MMM.
And on the difference between what is,
you know,
innovative and transformative
generatively transformative.
Yeah. So that's part of
the task. And there's no,
there's no one size fits all solution.
Like,
and I think that that is one of these
things where the repair is going to have
to be, everybody's starting like
very close to home. What, you know,
what you touch the immediate
people and structures around you.
How do you make space for
that to be rewarded? Yeah.
That's interesting. The idea of, um,
of how to reward the how
and the why. Yeah. Um,
if anybody has a question for Krista,
uh,
my question is what is your thought
behind always asking someone at the
beginning of your podcast? Yeah. Um,
what is something from their childhood
that is spiritually important to them?
Yeah.
So,
so almost always as some version of
the question of what is their religion?
Was there a religious or spiritual
background, your childhood? So, uh,
the truth is that just about everybody
has a really interesting story there. It,
whether it's a story of
absence or presence or
something that was good or bad,
but, but, um, the reason I, the, the,
the strategic reason I ask it is because
of where plants the question. So again,
it's like the beginning is everything,
right? If you get the beginning right,
uh, you can go places and if
you don't, you're working,
you're always working really hard
to get it, get it on the rails.
What I,
so what I've learned about that place,
it's true of other questions about
childhood or origin. So sometimes I'm,
if I'm in a, like a, uh, if I'm in
a particular setting with a theme,
I might ask,
uh,
let's say it's a conversation about
compassion or I don't know. And I,
I might say, can you, what,
can you remember the very
first time that you did that?
That word meant something to you? Or
what, what is your memory of the earliest,
earliest understanding of what
you think of as compassionate?
Now the thing about asking somebody
a question that takes them,
um, what I don't want to do is
start with the, where we all always,
how we present generally we in with our
credentials and what we know and what
we've done.
And it's very chin up and it's,
and it's performative and the, and
that's what we're asked to do. Um,
that question takes it plants people.
It's not a question that anybody feels
defensive about because I'm not asking
you also, and I would never ask somebody,
tell me about your spiritual life.
Like are you religious? I mean that
question would be designed to just,
uh, make everybody uptight, including
me. If you ask somebody that question,
it takes them to a very soft searching
place and their memory and therefore in
their body. Um, it's also interestingly,
as much as we think of religion
culturally as a matter of convictions and
beliefs that answers, it's a place
where beautiful questions reside.
And it's,
it's interesting to me how many people
when they start reflecting on that part
of their life,
it turns out that there's some question
they asked when they were four,
seven or nine that they end, that it ended
up influencing the rest of their life.
Like some of their life has been some
trajectory on the course of that question.
Um, so, so that's it. It's
where to start so that,
and then everything follows from there.
I can get,
if I can invite people to be soft and
searching right up there and then,
then we probably are going
to stay soft and searching.
Um,
I used to work for the wealth bank as
an economist and you talked about saving
the world and um,
then I moved to Silicon Valley and here
people have the same intentions and it
seems that the intentionality is right
and speaking for the world. Thank you.
Wouldn't believe that. But it's
the same. The same is true.
People truly believe in what they're
doing is doing good in the world.
So if it's not intentionality,
why did we go wrong?
Is it that we think it's intentionality
is right, but it's really not an,
it's our ego or what is it?
Where do we go wrong and how can we
fix this that we start off with good
intentions and end up with bad
results? Right. Well that's
a good question. I mean,
maladies,
not everything.
I think then I would want to come
back to this discernment piece. And I,
and I do think that, um, yeah,
the question of ego,
which is often this very often is,
you know, and of course we are,
our egos are part of us. It's
not you get rid of that, but, um,
it resides so intimately
with intentionality.
Um, and so I think part of, um,
spiritual life of interior of
a cultivated interior life,
um,
is to grow in knowing the difference.
Because if they often do feel like the
same thing and actually to grow these
other muscles around discernment and
asking the how and the why question. And,
and, and I mean, you know,
the scale of what the World Bank is
working with or the scale of what Silicon
Valley is working with is tremendous.
But
I do think that there's something
we're waking up to a little late,
um,
about how,
about how disconnected our view of the
problems and therefore the solutions is.
Right. And the, and this
is something about the post
enlightenment world. I mean, I,
I, we, we, we, we turned, we were
fascinated with the parts, right?
And then we created this world of parts.
So in every discipline,
there's this challenge in medicine,
there's this challenge. We, you know,
we have specialists for
every part of your body.
And we didn't learn how to see the
whole and all the interactions.
And there's a corollary to that in
everything we do in, in the economy,
in politics, um, in social policies. And,
um, so in some ways,
like this is kind of a,
this is kind of a civilizational,
uh, muscle of discernment, right?
Like we actually have to start to think
outside the frames that we inherited,
um,
and see in a new way
that I think I,
you know,
another piece of language that's really
important to me now is thinking about
having, not just imagination,
but moral imagination.
MMM.
Yeah. And then again, like discernment.
Yeah.
Is there's, there's no prescription.
It's going to be different in every,
in every setting.
But I think,
I think there are muscles we can build
up and also ways we can help hold each
other accountable. So in my role here, my,
I served the manager and leader
community and my intention and goal is to
support them through,
um,
actually through asking them
questions rather what community,
the community of leaders
at Google. Okay. And, um,
so I'm always on the lookout for really
solid questions and of course your full
of them. Both of you are, and I,
it's obviously very difficult time to
be a leader here or anywhere, but I'm,
I'm seeing,
uh,
leaders struggle with how to listen to
questions that are sometimes just they're
so loaded,
right?
And the leaders don't have the answers
necessarily and they're not necessarily
responsible for the causes and they have
their own questions about what's going
on and the struggles. So,
um, my question for you is,
what advice potentially in the form
of some questions do you have for our
leaders to, for how to
listen, respond, be with,
with what's being asked of them right
now? Yeah, you're right. I mean,
I think when you're talking about loaded
questions then are not really questions
right there. Their arguments
that are presented as question,
I mean that just feels, feels like a huge
responsibility to answer that question.
I, I, I do,
I do think that
what the world needs leaders
in this sphere to be asking is
how will we shape,
um,
these technologies to,
to human purpose,
um, to be, to be good
for us. And, and if, if,
if I say audaciously that,
that these,
these are the tool you
have created the tools to,
um,
whereby we could just start to
think and to act as a species and,
and we must, if we're going to
tackle something like climate change,
just to name one of our big challenges,
but perhaps the one that
had the ultimate one, um,
how can that, I mean, how to rap like,
I don't want to say it as a problem.
Like how to rise to that challenge.
Let me take that on as a design question.
Um,
disrupt our,
all the compartmentalization,
disrupt all these barriers and walls
between all the different disciplines.
We need to be talking to each other to
wrap our arms around some of these big
challenges.
I think I'd add to that as well
cause I just wholeheartedly agree,
um,
is we tend to think very fast and we tend
to be very reactive because there's so
much at stake and it's all happening
right now and there's a lot of them,
you know,
to kind of say the steak thing,
there's so much on the
line and really this, the,
the listening aspect of silence aspect,
the patient's aspect of this I think is
how do we know there are things about
humanity that will never change.
They are,
the things that are wired
inside of us are always be true.
How do we think is a slow as we can to
the things that never change because
that's where the real responses will come.
The fast answers are so challenging and
loaded as loaded as the questions and is
dangerous for individuals too.
There's just so much going on in that
moment when really when we stop and think
about the way that we are as people and
the way that we are as people together
and what it means to live in a particular
way that we can all be proud of.
And it feels like it is
about human flourishing and
civility and the space that
includes all of us. Um, those are harder
questions. Those are feeling questions.
We're not all necessarily in the
practice of that. Even personally.
Just encouraging and having those
conversations here, making space for that.
That's the beginning of all of it.
So I thank you for doing your
work and for asking the questions,
you know, somebody else
or might say is, um,
given that like,
I don't think anybody who started any of
these companies want it to be changing
human nature,
like interwoven into people's bodies,
brains and psyches, right? I mean,
that's not what anybody set out to do,
but that's what's happened.
Um,
a lot of the,
the terrible reckonings we're having now,
even around things that we thought
we'd make great progress on socially,
like racial dynamics and,
and,
and gender dynamics.
You know,
50 years ago there were beautiful
movements and a lot of laws changed and we
kind of came into the 21st century
thinking we, you know, we cracked this,
we can keep getting better at it,
but we basically did this and we hadn't.
And one way I analyze that is that we,
you know,
we have this idea that like if
you, you know, if you know history,
it won't repeat itself,
but the truth is actually that history
always repeats itself until you know
yourself.
And,
and we changed laws but we
didn't change ourselves.
And now again, with science as our
companion, we learn about implicit bias,
right?
Like we learn how our brains were
hardwares and we didn't know how to affect
that.
The beautiful thing.
So it's terrible to wake up to the
fact that we were so much farther,
less farther along than we,
than we thought.
But the beautiful thing is we actually
now, no, we have not knowledge.
That can be a form of power.
And you are working in a sphere that
is actively engaging our brains,
right? Actively involved in our inner
lives as well as our outer lines.
Um, so again, I would say take
that as a creative challenge,
a generative challenge, and
it's uncomfortable, right?
I know it's not what anybody wanted,
but there it is.
I'm going to sneak a question in between
you and Peter who will be our last
question.
Um,
one of the things that's come up a
few times here is like the poetry art,
the space of the heart,
the wisdom traditions.
These are things that I think live very
much in the spirits of many people that
are in all of these places.
Um,
what do you think that we all have to
learn from those traditions explicitly?
Not necessarily in our own homes
and the doors of our heart.
That's where it all begins.
But what do the wisdom traditions,
what do all of these ancient
human languages of our souls? Um,
ha ha. What place do they have in
this space? How can we invite them in?
We'll there potentially or they're just,
they're there.
This is the part of the
human enterprise where we,
where we tried to think about what
our soul is and what our heart is and,
and actually what the fullness
of argument consists there.
Also the parts of the human enterprise
where we were actually honest about how
complicated and messy we are,
right?
Like are the technocratic 20th century
wanted to think that we could just
bracket those things out and you could
check your personal life at the door and
you know,
we wouldn't bring messy things into the
public sphere and it didn't work that
way. Um, and now all of that, you
know, now we're in this moment,
I think this has something to do also
with technology and the just how rapidly
things have shifted,
that everything that we have been
thinking was such a rational discipline,
our politics,
our economics data,
these are just the thinnest of
veneers over the human drama.
And again, it's really messy and
uncomfortable to say, oh my God,
that's what we have to do.
But I actually think that we have to
address in order to do all the other work.
And these are the parts of the
human enterprise where that has been
investigated. And we're, again,
spiritual technologies have been
developed and that's there for us.
Whatever, you know, there,
there are these great institutions
which came out of that.
There's the history of religion,
but that's not all it is.
I love how in, um, in
your book he's habit. Um,
it was comforting to you as you spoke to
all of these kinds of great scientists
in minds to know that everyone is equally
as like are basically the black holes
are easy and humans and
the human condition is
perplexing and astrophysicists
will tell you that are nothing
they're working with. Um,
no black hole is as complex
as any living organism,
not just human beings that
love that. Yeah. Peter,
when I take us home,
thank you so much for sharing and being
generous with your wisdom experience.
There's so much what you said.
I'm a, I'm a disciple of, um,
uh, actually strategy to look at how we
can use the lens of empathy and emotional
intelligence and behavioral science to
help guide perhaps a better future. Um,
but on that note, like there's the things
you're saying like repair versus safe,
which I thought was
wonderful because that's it.
It's a admission that we were
responsible and you have to admit that to
participate in the healing.
So I think the stuff that you're giving
us and partying us is really going to
help us. Um, I asked, I
wants to ask because um,
you have in your own sense the mastery
of listening and interviewing and you say
you prepare and you do the ritual
of being a spendable and, and um,
vulnerability. All of these
things are very to your point,
dynamic study in gender, uh, uh,
reciprocal of vulnerability
and generosity. Um,
but when you prepare, like you, you
kind of stopped the person, right?
And so you,
you come and,
and then you say you're creating an
atmosphere of, uh, a safe place. Yeah.
And it's interesting cause I'm curious
about the correlation with things like
trust and how what you believe in
genders trust and what you believe are
actually builds rapport.
What are the human things that
you've found that the report,
because Google knows stuff about
you. In our next session. Yeah.
So why aren't you creepy essentially?
And what makes your art form of
Rapport Building essentially?
I'm curious.
Okay.
So interesting. Well, yeah, and I have,
I have actually thought about, um,
how the Internet has changed the work I
do because actually when I first started
15 years ago,
I was spending a lot of time in libraries,
just like public libraries.
Um, and honestly,
I don't know how else I was
finding things. So it was possible.
But of course now it's just,
there's an abundance of
information on anybody as you say.
And I can also find things
which is sometimes find like
I can find things people
said 20 years ago that they
totally forgot that they said.
And that is a really great moment in an
interview where you kind of take them to
a place in themselves they haven't
been for a while. Yeah. Yeah.
Why does it not feel like stalking?
Because it's appreciative.
It's appreciative and um,
such an interesting question.
I mean,
people often say or sometimes say
after our interviews that they,
that death, that it was kind of like
a, gave them a gift of themselves.
Like I gave them an opportunity to say
things they never even said to themselves
before. And I, and I, that I do that by,
by being, by knowing so well
kind of how they think and uh,
and honoring that,
that then we can start in a really
deep place and go from there.
I think the,
maybe the honoring word is
important and that deep,
that deep place that you hold for them
to return to and share and open up
themselves.
I think that that human
quality of creating that space,
that genuine curiosity,
that that authentic moment that's
being created out of hospitality,
like she said it,
it would be curious to see what changes
when those values come alive in the
space with technology.
Yeah.
So we will see that is all of our work
to share here today. Thank you so much.
Thank you.