By welcoming a very
special guest here today.
[inaudible] editor in chief
of the national, um, Mina,
you've been a political journalist
for a very, very, very long time.
How did it all begin and what was the
genesis of your career, if you will?
Right.
So first of all,
thank you so much for being here and thank
you Joyce for not only hosting me but
Google has been really kind to the
national since we relaunched last July.
So it's very nice to continue our
relationship. Um, you know, I'm,
I'm your rocky British and I think for
many people who are from countries,
um, the either suffer war
dictatorship or whatever,
it really dominates your
life in different ways. Um,
unfortunately I count myself as lucky
because we left when I was a child.
We left Iraq when I was a child,
but still politics kind of has
shaped who I am and where I came to.
And in a way, I think that's
what determined my getting
involved in journalism.
I want things to understand more, but
also cast a light on certain issues. Um,
so really I think it has to do with the
fact that I'm Iraq key and I also love
storytelling.
So combining the two together.
So political journalism,
I don't think there was ever a
time when it was easy or risky.
Would you say that being a political
journalist today comes with an even higher
set of risks and challenges then in the
past or was there never an easy time?
I don't think there's ever an easy time,
but again,
I think if we're talking about the Middle
East and North Africa at the moment,
unfortunately half the time that people
are thinking you're a journalist,
you have to be a war correspondent
and that's, that's really difficult.
I remember the first journalism story I
ever wrote in political Jerusalem was in
2002 and it was the 1 million person march
in London against the upcoming war in
Iraq.
And I remember at the time thinking,
I really should be going to Iraq to
cover this, but I'll be really frank.
My parents were like,
there is no way on earth you're
getting to Iraq and you know,
you're staying here and you're safer
here. And so forth. And to be fair,
I remember thinking,
I'm a less lesser journalist for not
being out there on the front line.
And I had a great mentor who's still a
friend and who actually now writes for
the, for the national, which I'm
really proud of, but he was, you know,
this big John List and I hadn't worked
with him. And he said to me, me now,
not every journalist has to be a war
correspondent and war correspondents do
incredible work and credible stories, but
you can still do, you know, the other, um,
types of stories. And I said, well,
what I really am interested in is the
policy side and the thematic side.
And sometimes,
fortunately,
especially with what we're seeing at
the moment with UN failures and, um,
other problems with the
international community,
you still want to write about those and
explain those and also have the contacts
and the sourcing and piecing together
a story. So that's the field I went to.
And you know,
I studied history at university partly
because I wanted to know how did we get
here in order to frame anything that
I'm going to bring writing about. Um,
and so, so that's the
difficulty of one. If you're,
if you're a war correspondent,
I think the dangers are so much
more today than they were 15, 20,
30 years ago. It's incredible. And I
think that journalism is poorer for it,
especially as we're trying to understand
what's happening in different conflict
zones around the world. And
that suddenly, you know,
having a flak jacket that says press,
you're almost a target.
Whereas before that would be your safety.
So I think that's one concern. Um,
but the local journalists of course
also carry different types of risks.
So you know,
where do you cross the line that can
get you the only in trouble who can get
your organization in trouble and so
forth. And of course now, you know,
it's funny because before sensors,
if you're working in a,
in a newspaper and it just have to skim
the newspaper and things could pass.
Whereas now,
you know,
with one keyword alert search can
unravel a whole host of things.
So it's changed for sure.
And do you feel that being a political
journalist in the Middle East and also
being a woman poses an
extra set of challenges?
I think every job has its own challenges.
And I think in journalism you
have different challenges,
especially as we see disruption that's
happening in the media industry and
trying to figure out how
do you get the right story,
the pressure now to get a story out even
if you haven't double sourced or triple
sourced for confirmation.
Being a woman, yes,
of course has its own sets of challenges.
And I also think,
especially in the Middle East,
um,
there's certain conceptions
about women in media.
And I remember when I first said
I wanted to go into journalism,
my mother was quite this approving, um,
and not because of me, but she said,
you know,
you'll find so many challenges and how
you'll be perceived as a woman and so
forth. Um, she quickly changed her mind,
which was good. And my father taught me,
they were really encouraging,
but they were concerned because they
felt that in our societies there's a
certain element of prejudice against
women and in the media sector,
I think that's changed.
I do think opening up of everything
from the variety of outlets we now have,
television has changed,
but it's a bit of that perception remains.
And do you feel there's
a good representation?
And we did journalism today of women.
I'm very proud of the national there is.
Um, but I think across the board, no,
and we still, we still
face, uh, challenges.
I think there are still issues
primarily to do with, um,
gender gaps in pay for sure. That, I think
that's one of the biggest challenges.
And,
um,
compensation is really important because
that's got to do with confidence,
has got to do with how you feel that
you're being valued as journalists
irregular, you know, regardless
of your gender or your sex.
So it's still a huge issue and across
the board, across the world. Okay.
So if we were to dig in a
bit more into your career,
what was the hardest interview
you've ever had to do and why?
So I was thinking about this,
cause you said to me,
you might ask about the hardest interview.
So I was really thinking about this
and there are so many different ones.
One that was really difficult for me,
but then I was really proud of was
interviewing the daughters of the lady who
was killed in the suit square,
that famous black water incident
in Baghdad when you had,
um,
suddenly these young girls were orphans.
Their father had died previously.
Their mother had worked as a driver to
try to get some sort of income to come in
and she was shot with several
other civilians by black water.
And so I went to interview them in Jordan.
It was really difficult because
there's three, it had to be told,
but they were so emotional.
And I was also getting emotional and I
was trying not to because I felt like,
but they also wanted to show
them empathy and I felt it.
It was really difficult to,
to interview them and took a long time.
And I went to visit them several times
before I could even write something or
have them open up.
And it's always difficult with these
human interest stories because you want to
tell their story, but you all, we also
don't want to pry. And there's a sense of,
you know what, right? Do I have a complete
stranger? They've just met to say,
how'd you feel about your mother? How do
you feel about what's happening in rock?
Where is your future going? So that, that,
for me it was emotionally
really difficult. And then
there are difficult people,
like the officials that you
end up having to intervene.
They're not really interested
in giving an interview.
So it's like you ask them a question,
they'll give you a one word answer and
you're like, why am I doing this? Um,
but they're, you know, they're part
of the job, but the one, the one that,
the ones that are difficult or
emotional ones actually for me.
And if you were to do
one more interview again,
was it that was a person you've
interviewed, who would it be
with somebody I've already interviewed,
flustered Nodi Maliki,
former prime minister of Iraq.
I answered him when he was prime minister
and I do quite tempted to interview
him again and see where we were. Um, I
think that would be quite interesting.
Great.
Okay.
Um,
so there are Gallup polls in the u s
that show a significant drop in trust in
mass media in America,
but um,
many, many would argue that this
does not apply in the Middle East.
And a lot of research shows that trust
in mass media is still very high.
What would you say about that?
What are your thoughts on it?
Is there a continuous trust in mass
media and are part of the world?
I think there is more trust because the
alternatives in especially the Arabic
language had been so weak
and are so untrustworthy.
So I think that's why actually more legacy
media, traditional media, mass media,
um, trust is there because
the alternatives and when
we've seen that mount of
really, um, shoddy fake news,
like it's so obvious that this is fake,
that people don't catch onto it in the
same way that you've had in other places
that more sophisticated.
I also think there's,
there's more trust because in some way
we almost know the biases of different or
editorial lines of
different organizations.
So people know that when
they're coming to it,
kind of what they're receiving and then
they make their judgment call. Whereas,
especially in the U S I find it
fascinating when I speak with American
journalists,
there's this thing of you know,
where objective and I
genuinely don't believe that.
I think everything is subjective.
The headline, we choose a subjective,
the photo we choose to be on the front
page or the top of your homepage is
subjective. Everything's subjective.
Whereas in the u s for the longest time,
it was always,
no,
everything is objective and it's a
level playing field and it's not,
and it doesn't necessarily have to mean
that you have a bias with ill intent,
but I think you do have biases
based on your knowledge,
on your personal experience,
on who's actually in the newsroom,
who's making the shot.
And so I think in the u s there's less
trust now because people bought into this
idea that everything's objective
and suddenly they're like, oh no,
it's actually not. And
it's hard to be. Um,
so I mean,
now you are British Iraqi,
you grew up in Sweden and you
lived in Australia and the UK.
What should we know about Mina that we
won't find an a quick search on Google?
Um, I think one of the things
that when, when I first speak,
people are always like, oh, where
did the accident come from? Um,
and I first learned to
speak English in Australia,
so I had a proper Aussie accent,
but I lost. But I was a child.
We lived in Australia and then I left
Australia and I lost my Aussie accent.
So I guess that's one thing
most people don't know about me.
Well you can always get it again after
living in the UAE with such a mixed
community you can,
well you know it's funny cause my,
this accent is from years of living in
Saudi Arabia and then they moved to the
UK when I was 15 and I never
picked up a British accent.
Whereas my sister who's older picked
up a British accent. I don't know,
maybe I watch too much Hollywood.
Um,
so you were appointed editor
in chief last year of four,
the national.
And one of the things you said where you
want to take a new and fresh approach
to news. What did you mean
by that? Well several things.
I think the most important part of any
news organization newsroom is the team
and how you're putting together different
teams and what capabilities and how
you're equipping them and think what's,
and this is a challenge and we still
haven't cracked at the national.
And the continued to work on it is
how we make sure that you give each
journalist the chance to, you
know, whether they're editing,
whether they're using multimedia with
they're writing chance to develop
different ideas because
you need expertise,
but you also need them to break
out of it. So for example, um,
we try to make sure that everybody has
the chance to write about either of their
favorite books or you know,
and they could be genuinely writing
usually or just a sub editor every day,
but then they have the chance to
write about sports or so forth.
So giving them a more rounded
approach to telling stories.
And that's what we hope to do with the
nationals. That's one element of it.
The second element also of it is
getting that balance between, yes,
we have to be up to date,
but we're never going to be a newswire.
So there's that and that's
for many newspapers. There's
that tension now, right?
Because you want to be the
first person to break something.
But that's not really our,
our raise on death death is to make sure
that we're giving you and analysis why
do you care about this?
Why is this story important?
And so getting that balance
right of also how, where,
and we have an integrated newsroom so
people are working towards our digital
outlets, but also the actual
physical print newspaper.
So taking that approach of one,
it's integrated and two,
how are we understanding reader behavior
and therefore making sure that our
stories are being updated and developed
in a way that suits the reader to come
back and have fresh stories but also not
getting into this rat race of we have
to update every two
minutes or five minutes.
And I must say,
I'm not being biased here,
but the national's website
is probably one of the,
one of the greatest new sites out
there today covering the region.
And if you haven't listened
to the nationals podcasts,
you should definitely
try it out. It's, it's,
it's really good and it's a
good chance to go deep and have,
have long form conversations. Um,
thank you for saying that. I mean,
the thing with the podcasts and
other things, you know,
we relaunched a July,
2017 and we had a very short
time to turn things around.
But one of the things is, for
example, on the podcasting,
there were people who never sat
behind the microphone before.
And so we really nervous about it and
we gave them basic training. I mean,
it wasn't something
long over months. We didn't have the time,
a few days of it, but giving them an,
equipping them with skills and
then seeing who wants to do it.
So rather than assigning people say
you have to do this, you have to,
that it was people coming forward and say,
actually, yes, I think I could do that.
And seeing that they have the skills.
So that's been actually one of the
things that I'm really proud of,
the national that we've tried new
things and people have been, you know,
great journalists want to tell
stories in different ways. Nicknames.
So news consumption is becoming
more fragmented and more,
um, you know, um, digital than
ever before. How does that,
how are you guys receiving this at the
national and what are you doing to,
you know, to change it and to
transform into digital? You know,
that's the big question I think for
all newspapers. And so part of it,
like I said, is understanding
what our readers actually want.
And you will know this,
um,
is your core loyal group of readers who
will always come to the national and you
know, they've downloaded our app
when they wake up in the morning,
they have to look at other,
or they go to the website and there at
the moment comprising about 50% of our
readership and a little over
50% are coming through search.
Um, and of course Google being
the primary resource for that,
but also coming through social
media and sharing. And so, you know,
you all know this, all these changes
happening to what makes you read a story.
Is it because someone you trust?
Again,
it goes back to I'll know if trust has
sent it to you and therefore you think
it's worth your time.
So we're trying to develop way that we
have our core readers and we grow our
base of the loyal readers
that will always come back.
And then also catering for those people
that are finding us because of a certain
topic we've written about
through search or social media.
So that's something that you never had
to worry about in newspaper before.
And um,
it just 15 years ago you would,
you would be,
what's the front page?
How are we making sure that we've got
a good spread of news over 40 pages?
And you're kind of,
that was it.
And now it's completely changed in terms
of prioritization and also you can't
control how you're going
have that experience with a
reader if they're coming to
you only through search or social,
but you want to keep them on the page
in order to stay engaged and actually
think, hey, yes,
the national has more to offer me then
this immediate story that I'm going to.
So that's really part of our every
day in terms of how were curating the
homepage on the website,
how we're creating a curating the APP,
what we're putting out through
our social media feeds.
And I always say we have five outlets
now at the national we have the paper,
which I'm very proud of,
but it's only in the UAE.
So I only see it if you're in the UAE,
you've got the website,
which again is the main
source of our readership.
Now you've got the APP
and we have the Ereader,
which is just the basic kind of readership
and that's what people a people go
for. But we have the more, you know,
sophisticated app that
actually is more curated.
And then we've got our social media feeds
and then we've got the fifth element,
which is our very specific products like
our newsletter that lands in your inbox
every morning and our podcasts and our
some at times we have videos that are
purely video.
There's no other story to go with it
cause we're also expanding our multimedia.
So though, so working across those
five everyday is very challenging.
It's not easy,
but it's also keeping that priority
of saying that's how we're reaching a
greater readership.
Now do you envision a day where you will
start distributing your print paper,
Africa quests that you know,
I don't want to,
I don't want to stop distributing print
paper but I have to envision it because
if that's where the market will go,
then you have to be prepared for.
I don't think that's going to
happen. Um, for various reasons. One,
I think there is still something to
be said about reading a newspaper.
Now whether my niece is three years
old and when I go visit my sister,
I always take the paper with me and I
put it in front of her so she can play
with it because I'm thinking if we can
get children to play with newspapers,
they're going to enjoy reading it.
Like we enjoy reading newspapers.
Now when I worry about is that most
toddlers and young children now are always
just holding a device so they won't
even know what to do with the paper.
So my niece and nephew
are being indoctrinate. My
nephew's a year and a half.
So he's still got a year or two to go,
but my niece is totally indoctrinated.
And so I think that experience, as long
as people find joy in and having that,
you know,
it's an experience having your coffee
and your morning paper and all of that.
So long as that exists,
then we'll stay.
We'll stay good because I think we're
competitive newspaper and people want to
read us. However, if with
time people's behavior,
it just no longer includes that little
ritual, then it's very hard to keep up.
It was, we have our very own
homage of, of, of newspapers
at our, at our reception.
You'll go in and you'll see lots of
print papers decorating our reception.
Um, so I'm going to, we can start to warm
up with the questions from the room. Uh,
I will ask my last question
here and at somewhat of a,
of an existential one with spread
of misinformation that, you know,
we're seeing around the world today.
What,
how do you see the future of journalism?
Uh,
I know you wrote a piece for the world
economic forums that the future is
credibility,
right?
But how do you see that rolling out the
future of journalism in an age where
there's more and more miserable
commission?
I think as awareness is raised about
this issue of this information,
I do think people are more aware today
than they were maybe two years ago. Right?
So I think as more and more
of that becomes a problem,
it actually works better for journalism
because you go back to the basics of
journalism, which is, you know, how did
we get the story? What's her source?
What's the credibility behind
it? Um, you know, can I,
can I tell all aspects of the story if
I've missed something about the aspect
story, am I making my reader aware and
so forth. So I think that stays true.
And if you get that right with time,
people will come back to it.
Now how you're competing with,
you know, I say as a newspaper,
we compete with everything from Twitter
to Google news to the economist,
which used to be,
no,
if you're a newspaper Nooyi who
cares what the economist is writing,
but now you know,
they're distributing here.
And we're also trying to reach an audience
that's sitting in the UK or the u s
so that,
um,
that change means that you have to be
strong in your journalism in order for
people to come to you rather than fake
news. That's just being shared around.
So I think there's more awareness and
I do think it's, it's a challenge now,
but with time,
people are beginning to know that if you
take a screen grab of a tweet and you
haven't sent me the actual team tweets,
it means the screen grab is something
that's photoshopped and fabricated.
We're still not there, but I think
more people are becoming aware of that.
So it's also part of our job as
journalists to raise awareness about that.
And I do think that
media literacy with time,
we'll actually be part of people's
education, like to be well rounded.
You're going to have to understand just
like we talk about financial literacy,
I think we need to talk about media
literacy and understanding information.
And if that really kicks in, which I
think it's beginning to in certain parts,
then it holds realism. Good stuff. Great.
That's a great final words.
Um, questions from Davao.
Thank you for joining
us today.
Wow.
Um,
okay.
I guess it depends where here is.
So I would probably first talk about your
rock because I'm a single issue voter.
If I was in the U S I'd say I'm a single
issue voter cause everything goes back
to Iraq, which was, you
know, rightly or wrongly. Um,
and I think with the rocket
was just failed leadership.
And I think unfortunately for rock I
can say that with absolute certainty,
knowing the ins and outs of it all.
But I think also when you, as you said,
you know, I studied history.
When you look at history,
the impact that leadership can have at
taking you on the right course of the
completely wrong course, especially
when many of our societies are top down.
So how the top goes
can really impact that.
I'd say that that's probably
my immediate answer.
My second answer of how did we
get here is also a lack of vision.
Not knowing where we want to be in
four years' time, five years' time,
20 years' time, rather everything
was so immediate and reactionary.
And I think that's been
one of our pitfalls.
But I hope that I can say to her
where we got to here as women, um,
as societies that there are
some progressive elements
that we don't necessarily
always see because me as a political
journalist always thinks of the current
affairs status,
which depresses mate.
But when you think about also society
and how we've been able to either build
bridges or push back against stereotypes,
then that's also showed the strength,
the strength of people. And I think, um,
we've been really lucky with immigration.
Um, unfortunately now we're
seeing a trend against,
but I think with immigration both
ways, um, people coming to the region,
leaving from the region, so forth,
we've seen some great dynamic,
I think, you know, leaps and society.
And so that I would say is also people
movements and people's mobility has been
a good thing when it's not forced,
of course,
international women's Day
with your audience. Nationals,
a SPEC file.
Sorry,
Eh, again, you know,
I think we talk about the Middle East
and it's so different from country to
country. And so it is kind of
incredible here. Cause I, you know,
this is the first I moved to
upper lobby on the 1st of March,
2017 is the first time I live
in the Arab world as an adult.
So I've been going back and forth. I've
actually never lived here as an adult.
And so I had friends, I had
colleagues contacting, you know,
are you going to struggle as
a woman? They said, actually,
it's been amazing because I'm actually
in a country where I feel comfortable as
a woman and I genuinely mean that this
is not because the camera's rolling,
I genuinely mean that.
And that's amazing.
And I'm not sure how many other places
that could say that about. Right. And I,
and I go into ruminate and I find that
most times people are gender blind,
which is really rare anywhere in the
world. Um, and you said that, you know,
we're talking about Middle Eastern women
and there is that stereotype of either,
you know,
it's like this curious,
mysterious veiled oriental woman
that still exists in today's world,
which was crazy or the opposite that,
you know, they're old trailblazers,
but then there are women that are being
left behind partly because of our wider
societal and political problems,
especially for example, um, you know,
they always talk about the
impact of war on society.
So in some ways it forces women to go
out and perhaps take jobs they wouldn't
have taken before.
You know,
we saw that of course with World War
II and the impact it had on Europe.
And part of that is happening,
but at the same time,
war is actually making women's rights
and certain parts of the Middle East
really regress. So they're often,
it's linked to, you know, fear,
intimidation. How can you
eliminate women? And you know, I'm,
my father's family's from
Muslim in Iraq and you know,
mostly it was subjected to horrific
reign of terror under dash.
And so the only difference between my
cousin's and my father left and their
father had been ends basically.
And so the way that it was actually
women and how they were forced to get
completely covered up in their identity,
stripped from them and they couldn't work
and they can do all these things that
that targeting of women as we're seeing
is actually making them regrets because
after a dash goes or you know,
different extremist elements go,
it's still really hard to break out of it.
So it's really a mixed bag.
But in terms of international
perceptions of Middle Eastern woman,
unfortunately it's still so
stereotypical and quite shallow.
Thank you very much. I have a
question around kind of being fidgety
and in order to get the attention in
order to capture the attention of the
audience,
what we're seeing now in my view is
images and stories that are really shocked
value.
And I'm not talking about fake news,
I'm talking about things that are
really happening. Shocking images.
What's your view of that?
Is this valid?
Yeah.
Um,
I think probably the serious story
is one that increasingly we're seeing
shocking images,
partly because of the brutality and
how horrific the situation is there.
But partly, and this term really
frustrates me as a journalist.
You get people saying,
we have reader fatigue,
so we need to shock people into
caring. And I say, first of all,
I'm sorry you're tired.
Did that people are dying and
their lives are being destroyed.
I find that really offensive
as a term. But anyway. Um,
and then the second thing of actually,
you know what those shocking images,
if you don't already care, I honestly
don't think that's gonna make you care.
It may make you stop and say,
okay, why do I, you know,
make you stop and I don't think it's
going to make you care or move you to act
because it's more brutal
or more shocking. Um, so,
so that's kind of the approach we've
taken up the national at the national,
we have really,
you know,
really strict guidelines in terms of what
we're actually publishing in terms of
photos, in terms of
headlines. Um, you know,
it's really difficult
because you see this image.
I think most of you will conjure up now,
you know,
the buddies of children wrapped in white
shrouds and it's been really hard for
us because people were
like, oh, well, you know,
it tells a story of course Palestine.
We had these images for decades,
we've seen them coming off Palestine
and it's always been a thing of, okay,
but when does the dignity of
that child and their family,
this isn't their choice to be published.
And also the shock element should be
about the fact that it's happening.
We can't be so graphic
that we desensitize.
It's difficult because now everybody
can be a publisher because if I don't
publish it, somebody else's going to put
it on, you know, whatever page it is,
whether it's a Facebook page or
their own website and so forth.
So then do you lose out the, the
attitude we take up nationals, fine,
we can lose out,
but I think we need to shake people from,
from complacency. And it can't be done
by abusing actually the victims. So,
but it's, it's constantly a conversation
that we have in our newsroom.
Sure.
Um,
so that's of course one topic
that comes up a lot. Um,
and I have to say every outlet that I've
either worked for or been a guest of a
panel of has its own guidelines and
own issues that come up and they're
different. You know, there are
different, whether it's commercial,
whether it's political, you know, we
go back to the point of, uh, Isis,
do you call them isis that I
should [inaudible] state. You know,
I used to go on the BBC many times to
discuss it and they'd be so angered
because they'd say Islamic state and like,
it's not the Islamic state.
And the anchor would
be looking at me like,
can you just like leave
that discussion until later?
Because we need to get to where we say
late. So, you know, there are those,
that's one thing. And then there is the
issue of freedom of expression as such.
And I think freedom of expression as a,
as a concept is,
is different in different societies.
And it's really interesting because
recently I was speaking to an American
official and the way she was speaking
about freedom of expression is completely
different from how,
for example in the UK they'd speak about
freedom of expression and the whole
first amendment and so forth.
And then in our region it's,
it's much more about looking at journalism
as being responsible journalism and
that has its pluses and its minuses.
Because again, going back to that point,
I do actually think that there are
certain constraints that we placed on
ourselves that we have to,
and then there are certain trip
tricky topics and that it would be,
I think wrong, a
disingenuous to say. Yeah,
it's absolutely the same whether
you're in the Arab world or abroad.
I think it's difference the, and
China's the front and Russia, um,
it's a constant juggle.
And one of the things that you
have to think about is one,
the safety of the people
who work for you too.
What is the longevity of your,
uh, establishment? So for example,
again,
you'll have certain entities that are
commercial entities that you want to stay
on the right side off one way or the
other to make sure that you can continue
and that's not the national
but for other enterprises.
And then there's the politics and I
think you have to be really careful about
what you do and how you write about.
But in all seriousness and honesty,
it's not a constraint for us because
actually there are clear editorial
guidelines that I adhere
to the I believe in.
And then the newsroom also adheres to,
um,
and is happy with it in
terms of the battle of ideas.
Where do we stand in the Middle East?
And especially in the Arab world,
the situation wherein the right
now in terms of, you know,
do we believe in enforcing
religion into politics?
Do we believe in the use of arms outside
of state rule and all of that stuff.
And so we have, again, clear lines on
that and that's where we stick to. Um,
so for us,
that's how we approach it.
I think for others it comes down
to what's politically acceptable,
what's politically unacceptable.
And there are very few, you know,
people always ask me what
are the red lines? I'm like,
honestly there are no red lines of such,
but there's an understanding
of our societies and where,
where we're publishing.
And this goes back to the digital
element because sometimes you're writing
something that will work for a reader
that's in your immediate vicinity.
They'll be completely different
if they're Australian. Um,
and so we think about who's our core
audience and horror core readers and we,
and we stick with that.
So large.
You choose to ask the questions.
I touched the party museum literacy,
looking at your general Arabic
speaking public in the Middle East,
obviously I have my own opinion about
the quality, the literacy we have.
I'm wondering what do you think about it?
Do you think there is high media
literacy in the Middle East?
Because we know that there's good quality,
so there are many air journalists
who are doing excellent work,
but there was also a lot of journalists
for doing horrible work. Yeah.
So what do you think about Arab media
literacy and if you can improve it or if
you all, do you think it's, if you think
it needs approvement, what would you do?
Yeah, so, so when I say
media literacy, I mean like,
so I'm just making sure we're, we're on
the same page. When I say media literacy,
it's basically all of us,
how we understand news and
how we're consuming it.
So it's for the reader or the consumer
or the viewer. Um, I don't, again,
I think it's varied
from country to country,
but they don't think there is a high
level of media literacy in the Arab world
or internationally. But if we're sticking
to just the Arab world, absolutely not.
There isn't enough understanding
or awareness. He, you
still get people saying,
I read it on the Internet.
Okay, congratulations.
Well and to that, um, and
so, so that's, you know,
that's partly because technological
change has happened so quickly,
but partly because it's not part
of our school ethos to like,
actually this is not something
that you teach in schools. Again,
if people have strong history
classes and they understand sourcing,
then it gets ingrained with that.
But most of it,
unfortunately in most of the Arab world
history curricula is not taught that way.
It's not taught for critical thinking or
questioning that this actually happened
the way I'm being told it's happening.
So it's completely different. Um,
so we don't have high media literacy.
What would they change about it?
I would honestly bring in
classes into schools. Um,
I would open up for more
journalists to go and speak.
When I was living in the UK,
I would often go to schools and you
can't actually in the u s I did this,
spoke at schools and so forth.
It's much more difficult here to actually
have the access to go and speak about
them.
So I would do a program where I would
have schools partner up with journalists
to go and speak about these. And again,
just simple things like sourcing.
How do you see if a photo is
photoshopped or otherwise?
Because I think that's a life
skill that's really important. Um,
so I would start quite young,
but then also older,
just simple things like you can't say,
I read that on the Internet.
What does that mean?
And sometimes people don't even realize,
but when you have that conversation
and be like, Oh yeah, I, you know,
I wrote an article for a shuttle
also at my former employer,
still people call them with them.
And I wrote an article that was really
popular a few weeks ago cause I said,
you the reader, have a responsibility
for what you're sharing. You know,
you get these, what's up
messages that says in Arabic
come out, we'll find a need.
Come on. What I'd done. And it
basically says as I received it,
as I go there and it's like what
you, and it's rubbish, right?
What they're sending it makes no sense.
And you're like,
how can you send this and then just write
back and say it's just what like, oh,
you know,
I held no responsibility because you
actually do all the resources that you're
sharing it. So then
you know, to get it to,
to tell people that they actually
have a responsibility as publishers.
But also distributors.
Wow.
Lots of questions.
Oh,
this was interesting.
Good.
Yeah. Oh my God. So many. Okay.
So here was this, uh, wow.
I should remember this. 2011, I
want to say, yeah. 2011. Okay.
So I,
um,
interviewed American officials during
the Bush administration times and the
Obama Times, the Bush
administration people were so
much more accessible. Right?
And they had, they had
no red lines. They would,
the only thing they would have as you
only have this site, this timeframe, um,
I interviewed Obama and Kerry and
they were so difficult because Obama,
they wouldn't even let me go see him.
So we did it actually by phone. Right?
So they wouldn't, and I said, I'll fly,
I'll come anytime they want. They said no.
And they wanted to control it completely.
And the same was true actually when I,
although Carrie was more fun
because he actually was like,
he was trying to be like, we've known
each other and I don't know him,
but where's,
or the wound that was really controlled.
It was absolutely controlled. The
questions were controlled. Um,
and it was really disappointing to be
honest. Um, with the Bush administration,
I did an interview, um, Bush or Cheney
by interviewed many others and honestly,
they would just,
the only constraint would be the time.
Like you have half an
hour do you want you want.
So they really control the message
and they believed, you know,
I worked in Washington
from the beginning 2009,
so end of 2011 they believed that all
we need to do is tweet something out or
send you an SMS of what saying we're going
to send you a speech that he's, he's,
he gave and that's it.
I had only one background briefing with
the White House the entire time I was
there. And then I had a couple of other
interviews like with Ben Rhodes and other
people,
but they really controlled the message
and I think it was to their detriment
internationally.
Wow.
Um, like I said, it's, it's the, um,
the only difference between me and my
cousins is that my cousins didn't leave
and I did.
Um,
but it's also incredible how resilient
they are and how much fun they are.
You know, I saw them recently, a few of
them for people from the Middle East.
Like we say, I have a cousin and there's
like 45 of them minimum, like genuine,
I think I have like 47
cousins. Um, and so,
so it's incredible how similar we are.
And I think, you know, again, that's,
you know, blood, it's incredible. You
know, some of my cousins I hadn't seen,
my family was an exile from 1990 to 2003
so I didn't seem family for that long
and we went back to Baghdad at the
end of 2003 and it was incredible.
Like I'd seen them just last weekend.
So that's amazing how like
through inheritance in
three or your, I don't know,
your parents' upbringing and so forth,
you're so similar,
but life would have been so much more,
so much more difficult.
I definitely wouldn't have had most of
the opportunities that I've had. Um,
but I would say in terms of confidence,
I see that in my cousin's in
terms of aspirations and so forth,
it kind of hasn't beat them
down. All that, the craziness
that's happened in Iraq,
you know,
if you are from my generation,
you were born at a time when there's
the Iran Iraq war, you finish that,
then you had the Kuwait invasion,
you finished that,
you had the years of sanctions,
you finished the years of sanctions,
you go into the 2003 more, you go into
sectarian strife, you go into isis.
And here we are today. So you know,
people who of that generation,
and especially actually for,
for many men who were slightly older
who actually had to be drafted into the
army,
it's heartbreaking because you know,
the years that they spent being
drafted into these senseless wars. Um,
so I think if I had stayed
in Iraq and if I was a man,
that would have been actually that
much worse. Um, but at the same time,
I think I would probably be very similar
in character because of what my parents
have instilled in me
question
that
on texting
would be,
journalists will actually push the button.
Yeah.
It costs them to being explosive.
Yeah. And we do on
certain things. So again,
it's a fine line and it's a negotiation.
It's a negotiation with yourself,
with your editor.
It's not an ego.
There's no external power that comes and
tells you do, do not. You know, we don't,
I mean, I definitely the Emirates,
we don't live in that landscape.
I think it's different depending on
the country, your rent. So there's no,
but it's one, it's an appreciation
and understanding, um,
of what would be acceptable,
what isn't acceptable. Um, but,
and I mean to political power is
the only two to audiences, so,
so it's your own understanding,
socio negotiation.
There are things that you choose and
you say, no, I'm going to push on this.
And we have had issues like that.
And to be frank, I mean touch with,
before I jinxed myself, um,
since July 1st until now,
there's not been one thing that you've
had somebody turn around and say, no,
you cannot write that.
Now.
Does that mean that we're careful
and therefore we haven't pushed?
I think we have pushed on certain issues.
I mean,
I don't know how frequently read national,
but we do try,
especially on issues that we think are
of public interest and, and that is,
it's kind of like our guiding force.
But again, I don't mean to belittle it,
but I just don't,
it really isn't that big a constraint
once you know what you want to be out
there saying I'm why you're
working in the Middle East.
I mean there is a joy to working
from here to be able to say there's a
publication coming out from the Arab
world that is able to tackle issues,
you know, social issues,
but also political issues,
question certain things. Again,
no easy,
we're not going to do it irresponsibly.
But there a joy in being able to do that.
Yeah.
Any more questions? Okay. I guess last
question. This is going to be a fun one.
Oh good, good, good note to end up.
Good positive note to end on.
So we're having,
you mentioned that media right now we
access videos where our phones before we
have to wait to wait by
the newspaper and all that.
So if you get to define one kind of like
logical advancements or like something
in the Internet of things
that would basically either
had people to reach out to
India or to read the media or to be more
informed and to get actual news instead
of fake news. Um, what would be like
your dream you device or you mentioned?
Okay. So, so I have to answer is
because my first answer is, did you,
did you guys ever see the
movie minority report? Right.
So that image of Tom Cruise, yeah, it was
Tom Cruise, Tom Cruise, who's in Emirates.
Um, some cruise holding the newspaper
that gets updated automatically,
which I guess is like
the modern day tablet,
but I wish it could be a
newspaper that gets updated.
So that's like kind of my crazy dream.
If I could have anything,
my newspaper would stay updating
while still being in newspaper. Um,
but if I can't have that,
my second thing is,
I guess is exactly the point
that you said about fake news.
So if there's a way that we can
distinguish trusted news sources and not
trusted, or even if they're trusted,
kind of like, who's the ownership?
Like let people know, what's the
ownership, where is that coming from?
What does that,
but there's a way that we can signal
that so people know what to take.
I want us to take that would be
the dream. Great. Um,
Amena on behalf of all Googlers,
I thank you very much for sharing such
candid thoughts and insights with us.
Um,
thank you again and please do stay
around and have some great food at all
healthy. We promise. And thank you again,
thanks to Songo Dina and Maria
[inaudible].