We're here today to talk to Angela
Duckworth who's book, uh, Grit,
the power, passion perseverance was today
is the official publication date. Right.
The official publication date.
Congrats. Congratulations. Yeah. Yeah.
Thank you.
Incredibly gracious of her to fit
time in at Google with a really,
really busy publicity tour, um, which, uh,
I was getting exhausted just hearing
about it a few minutes ago. So, um,
for those of you who aren't familiar
with Angela Duckworth's work,
let me read, try to briefly
read a biography. Um,
Angela Duckworth is a
professor of psychology at the
University of Pennsylvania
and the founder and scientific
director of the Character Lab,
a nonprofit whose mission is to advance
the science and practice of character
development.
In 2013,
Angelo was named in Macarthur Fellow
and recognition of her research on grit,
self control and other non Iq
competencies that predict success in life.
Uh, it's a very impressive resume.
Uh, prior to a career in research,
Angela founded the summer school for low
income children that was profiled as a
Harvard Kennedy School case study.
Um,
she's been in Mckinsey management
consultant, a math and science teacher.
In the public schools of New York City,
San Francisco and Philadelphia.
She has degrees from Harvard,
Oxford,
and the University of Pennsylvania in
neuroscience and in psychology. Um,
and did I mention she's a MacArthur
fellow, 2015 in MacArthur fellow. Um,
all right, I'll stop there. And Grit is
her first book. It says, so welcome again,
Angela.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you for having me.
Delighted.
So let's get right into it. If you're
not familiar with her work, the Ted talk,
the, uh, the, the book, um,
I guess, uh, is it maybe,
hopefully it's fair for me to summarize
the thesis as that the power as you put
it, the power of passion and perseverance
or at least a strong indicators and
contributors to success or achievement
as things like Iq and talent, which are,
I think what Societaly at least
we've traditionally focused on.
And that resonated enormously
for me because I think at
Google we spend a lot of
time thinking about, uh, uh, talent Iq,
raw talent. Uh, it's kind of baked into
this crazy hiring process that we have.
And, um, which brought me to the
first question I had for you,
which was do you think that, I mean,
from what you know about Google,
do you think that we are,
do you think that organizations in
general select for the wrong things in the
hiring process and would,
would we be better off what organizations
be better off if they looked for grip
plus bit as opposed to attempting
to measure innate talent?
You know, I think the interest
that we all have in talent,
right? And it's not just
Google, it's me to, you know, I,
I wish I were more talented
talents. Great. Um,
and if you could give me five
more Iq points, I'd take them.
It's not that I don't think it's wrong.
Think about talent.
I don't think it's wrong
to think about potential.
I do think it's useful to think about
what we really mean when we say the word
talent.
And if you force yourself to write down
on a piece of paper and a sentence that
ends with a period, talent is, it's
really hard to actually feel it.
Like what do I mean? I'd potential
and when we start to use metaphors,
here's my definition of talent
and I think it reveals that.
I do think it's important talent is the
rate at which you increase in your skill
with effort.
Some people are going to increase their
skills faster than others and I think
it's legitimate to say
those are the quick studies.
Those are the talented people.
I think it's legitimate for Google
to look for them, right? Why not?
Why not try to hire the more talented
people? But in my data I find two things.
One is that more talented individuals
don't always keep showing up, right?
Woody Allen famously once said,
80% of success in life is just showing up.
He was later asked by William Sapphire
of the New York Times how he got to the
number 80 and woody Allen who is not
exactly a scientist, said, well, you know,
I was going to say 70 but it had one
extra syllable. Nevertheless, you know,
70 86 to, you know, I think his point was,
is that his experience as a writer, which
was the context of the quote, you know,
there are many people who could write
a great book or who are talented in a
sense that when they write
they get better faster,
but they'd never finish what they begin.
And so what I find in my data is that
talent is no guarantee of actually showing
up and finishing the
things that you start.
And the second thing is characteristic
of high achievers. Really in any domain,
whether it's Google or outside,
Google is this kind of daily discipline
of trying to get better, right? You know,
just you know,
in sometimes you know,
microscopic infinitesimally trivial ways,
like all those little
details add up to excellence.
And it's not always the people who are
the quick studies were willing to put in
those hours and hours of behind
the scenes on glamorous work.
So sure Google should hire talented
people, but I, I do believe that you want,
people are going to stick with things
when they're hard and who are going to
daily submit themselves to the
Japanese principle of Kaizen,
continuous improvement.
So on that subject can
You talk in the book about practice
and the difference between,
I think he used the words
directed practice versus a
regular undirected practice
and it reminded me of, I think at
running there's a phrase junk miles,
which may be indicated.
I've never actually been a runner so
I can only hypothesize what, what,
what it means. But I guess
it means kind of a, you know,
running that doesn't really contribute
to your improve conditioning.
And w what is the difference between
director practice and on directed practice
in the spirit of Kaizen
and self improvement.
So let's take,
running is actually the perfect example.
So when I started to try to understand,
you know, the science of achievement,
right beyond bumper sticker
wisdom, you know, what,
what do we really know as a science
about experts and how they got that way?
I quickly found myself at the
doorstep of Anders Ericsson who is,
who's the world expert on world experts.
He studies what experts do that make them
different from the rest of us. Right?
It's a great job.
He goes to like the Sudoku Tournament
and he studies World Cup soccer players
and um, and, and he,
he refers to it actually as deliberate
practice and he would like to say that
deliberate practice is different from
anything else that we do in four important
ways. And I'm going to come
back to running as an example,
but the first thing when you're doing
truly deliberate practice is that it's
extremely intentional.
It's problem solving.
Something in particular like not like
I'm going to come in to Google and be a
better CEO w whatever it is.
I, it's, it's like, you know,
I'm going to say that the first 15 seconds
of my presentations are going to be a
little sharper. I mean it's extremely,
extremely precise. That's the first thing,
a very specific goal that you're
working on. And often it's a weakness,
not a strength.
Second is 100% focus.
Or as some coaches would say,
like Pete Carroll of the Seahawks
practicing with great effort, right?
A third is feedback,
ideally right away,
and ideally information rich and forth,
the kind of refinement that you reflect
on and you try the whole thing over
again. Right? In fact,
these four things are
incredibly straightforward
and you might wonder why only
worldclass experts do it.
But let's come back to running.
So when I heard about this research on
deliberate practice, I, I asked Anders,
you know,
why is it that I had gone running pretty
much every day for years and I'm not a
second faster than I ever was, right? This
isn't that evidence that you're wrong,
that it's not thousands and
thousands of hours of practice.
He started asking me questions like,
well, when you go out for a run, um,
do you have a goal like a certain time,
right? Or are you trying to run, you know,
hills and said, no, no, I'm taking
the same route, you know, every,
every time I go out around my neighborhood
and he said, okay, well that's great.
What do you do when you're, when
you're running? I was like, well,
I listened to NPR, um, and you know,
any other podcasts because I'm trying
to distract myself. And he said, well,
that's interesting because people who
are trying to improve their running or
actually concentrating on their running
and their strides and they're breathing
all right? And he said, so, um,
how are you getting feedback
on your writing? I mean,
are you keeping your times? Are you
measuring your heart rate? You know,
do you have a coach who's looking
at your form? No, no and no.
Right?
And then he said,
are you going back every time when
you run and thinking to yourself,
what can I refine here right
before this next repetition?
What is there that I can do
differently? No. And he said, well,
then I can tell you why you're not getting
any better at running. And that is,
those thousands of hours are not
thousands of hours of deliberate practice.
So I think this idea that, you know,
we should be getting better at things,
you know, we can unpack that a little.
It's not just going out and trying hard.
It's actually trying hard in
those four very specific ways.
So on the subject of deliberate
practice, uh, and coaching,
I thought it's an interesting
question. What, what, um, you know,
in the organization,
do you have theories about what roles
managers can play in helping people
develop in the same way?
Is,
is do you have opinions on
how professional development
works in organizations
versus how it should work?
You know,
one of the things that's really important
to know about human beings is that
it's not that we stopped
growing up when we're 18. Right?
And if you look at the
etymology of the word parent,
the word parent really means to bring
forth. So after we leave our own parents,
right, who have tried to bring
forth our about, you know, we,
we kind of like leap
into other situations,
which frankly are our parenting
situations. I mean, I had teachers,
I had professors, I still do, you know,
mentors who in a very authentic
way, our, our parenting me,
all right, now what does it really
mean? What does it look like?
I think that really, really great
leaders do a couple of things right.
One is they model the character that
they want other people to emulate.
And there are two schools
of thought about leadership.
Some people say the leader
doesn't really matter, you know,
swap out one put in the next one. Really
culture is going to happen without them.
I'm in the other school of thought.
I think that's absolutely wrong.
Everybody watches the leader,
the leader sets the pace
for the entire organization.
And when the leader is nice
to other people, you know,
when I go and visit famous
people like you and I, you know,
I watched them and I watch how they
talk to the people who aren't famous.
You know, I watched them like, you know,
when they order their food, you know,
do they look the person in the eye?
And all of those little things are being
watched by all the people who work for
you. No pressure. Um, and, and, and
they're emulating you. I mean, and,
and especially if they respect you.
And that brings me to the next
thing that leaders do. I mean,
our leader is respected when they
provide both the kind of demanding
challenging, it's not good enough,
it's still not good enough.
I need you to do this differently.
Bring it back to me again.
It's that in combination
with support and uh,
and it brings me all the way back to the
parenting metaphor because that's what
great parents do. They're demanding,
they're challenging, it's not good enough.
I'm occasionally disappointing you,
but at the same time
genuinely care about you.
I want you to be successful
and I respect you.
So on, on the subject of mentoring
and parenting, I thought it was, uh,
I don't know where I
read it, but that, uh,
you share your peer review of
what you submit papers is share,
you share the negative peer reviews
and grant proposal rejections with the
people in your lab and your students.
Is that right?
And it's all true. And here's the
thing about it, right? And when,
when you interview someone who is, you
know, whatever, they win an award, right?
So like it was more or,
or you just read now you read off
someone's resume and by the way,
you only usually read the good parts,
right?
Like how about the time that you
completely screwed up and made this wrong
decision? I didn't put that on my resume
so you couldn't read it. But you know, I,
I think a lot of my work is
about demystifying things
like excellence, right?
You know, people who succeed
fail all the time. In fact,
I think they feel more than anyone else.
Like that's what makes him so successful
because failure provides an opportunity
for information in academia.
When you submit an article,
even when you're very good,
odds are it's going to get rejected.
And in my world comes with a 13 page
single spaced review letter about exactly
how you suck, right? Like I can't believe
how badly written as like, oh my God,
does this person not know the Meta
analysis done in 2000 you know?
And I send those letters out as soon as
I get them to everybody who's working in
my lab so that they can see all the
imperfection that eventually will lead to
some kind of achievement. I want them
to know the truth as opposed to the,
you know,
Shiny,
polished myth that I think
is easy to fall into,
which feeds into the myth of talent,
right?
There's some people who were just so good,
they appear onstage one day never having
thought about what they might say and
you know, and perform King Lear flawlessly
or whatever the case may be, right?
Whereas in reality it was direct
and practice and failure. Right?
And again, that person may have
been so, so take, you know,
take your few favorite actor or actress,
you know, Duty Judi Dench. I mean,
take whoever you want to think of
as somebody who's like a paragon of,
of masterful performance,
right? It's not that, you know,
I'm saying that anybody
could have been that person.
I'm not saying that we all
could have been Einstein,
but even Einstein wasn't born
knowing anything about physics.
Even Judi Dench had to
learn how to be an actress.
I mean skills because we are human and
we are not horses or other lower order
animals who are born with a
lot of stuff hardwired, right?
Horses don't really have to learn
how to run hours after they're born.
They run right?
Human beings are born knowing nothing.
The only thing that we're
born knowing is how to learn.
And so skills are acquired
over a lifetime. Sure.
The talented progress faster if they
stay with things and if they continue to
work at it.
On the subject of learning,
um, I guess, do you think that,
I wonder,
is it,
do you think that the educational system
is set up to support and recognize
grit?
Perseverance.
It seems like the academic cycle is short
with immediate feedback and it's easy,
for example,
to move on from one subject to another
after three or six months of study if
things don't go well.
Uh, is, is, is academic,
are the standards we've
set for academic success,
hurting our ability to
develop grit in people.
Obviously all of them could benefit.
Well, if you think about
younger kids, right?
The kids are still in elementary school
or middle school and high school.
One way in which our system I think
doesn't do a great job of encouraging grit
is there's a kind of a narrowing of the
focus on what it means to be successful
to essentially mean what are your scores
on the annual standardized tests of
math and reading.
That's incredibly narrow.
It not only leaves out a lot
of things that I care about.
Grit for example for something that you
find meaningful and I haven't yet met
the 16 year old who finds their
standardized test scores, you know,
a meaningful life goal.
Right?
It also leaves out the kind
of interest where a lot of us,
it probably in this room would say that
that's what they really did care about.
Like, you know, there are a sports team,
you know, being on the baseball, you know,
writing for the school paper,
you know the things that kids do outside
of the classroom that are unmeasured,
that policy makers, not only are they
not measuring and caring about them,
these things are getting cut. You know,
from, from schools, uh, left and right.
Then we talk about university
education, right? Well, you know,
you do have to have a
major in most schools.
So that's gritty in the sense that
grip means doing something in depth as
opposed to being scattershot.
But I'll tell you a story.
I was once on a committee to decide
who was going to be elected to Phi Beta
kappa. And as you may recall, this is,
you know, the honor society that uh,
there are people like me, you
know, faculty who say, okay,
well this kid's really extraordinary
as a budding academic and this kid,
maybe not so. So, you know, the first kid
gets on Phi Beta Kappa and the second,
so I remember looking at this one kid's
record and it was very clear to me that
it was grit and the passion for
this kid was biochemistry. Right.
You could see in his transcript that
like all of his classes were taken in
biochem. You know, at the med school.
Every summer he was doing internships.
Even before he was going to graduate,
he was going to be a published author,
which is a very hard thing to do for
any kind of scientific publication.
Committee gets to discussion and
people are like, Oh, you know,
I don't really see much humanities
here. Like, oh you know,
this isn't a very good grade, and his
his writing class, I was like, look,
this kid's going to win the Nobel prize.
Okay,
I exaggerate but this kid has a passion,
let's reward that.
And I argued hard enough that
he did get Phi Beta Kappa,
but I think that there is this
kind of averaging, you know,
people don't care about the average
ability that you have across all thing.
Most of us in life are going to become,
if we're lucky,
good at something and it's that one
thing that actually matters and not the
other things that you didn't invest in.
Do you have a favorite grit story?
Someone who even,
I mean your book is full of great stories
of people who've demonstrated so many
facets of passion and perseverance and
interest and a commitment over time.
Is there a favorite one?
Is there a,
you know, it's a great job that I have,
you know, so like Anders Ericsson,
I kind of go around
studying experts and um, uh,
and you see it everywhere by the way.
It's not just that you have to go to
the Olympics or to a chess tournament.
You know, you go into a great restaurant,
and this is a very trivial example,
but I think it resonates for me.
You went to a restaurant and you ever
have like a great waiter or waitress.
I mean, they're just so considerate.
And they, and I was like, you know,
that is a pro.
That is somebody who loves what they do
and who seems to be trying to get better
at it. And, and, and that is grit
just as much as a famous story.
I do have a story that I've recently
been rereading and that is Julia child in
her autobiography.
Um,
and you may or may not know that Julia
Child took until her late thirties to
really figure out that she wanted to
do anything at all related to food.
She grew up in a wealthy family that
had a cook. She said she had an,
I quote zero interest in the kitchen
when she was a young woman going to
college. She thought she might
want to be a writer, a novelist.
Then World War II happened,
so she's sort of, you know,
went to work mean this is
not a story of Grit so far.
She marries Paul Child and for his job,
not for her as they go to France
and she has a really memorable meal.
It was soul Moniere in a little restaurant
outside of Paris and that was the
beginning of a journey,
right? Not by the way,
an epiphany that she knew that she was
going to revolutionize the way Americans
cook and introduce them to French cuisine.
But you know,
one step in a journey where,
you know,
in the next meal she noticed that was
also different than anything she'd ever
eaten.
Then there was a bee Stroh they went to,
she started wandering around Paris and
looking at this beautiful produce and
this bread that she had never tasted.
You know, she got more interested.
Somebody gave her a cookbook,
a her husband,
I think gave her her
second French cookbook.
She found out that there were classes
that she could walk to and learn French
cooking. What I want to say about
these stories of grit is that one that,
that is accessible.
When you actually dig down into the
details of how people became great,
suddenly it becomes something that,
you know, you might actually aspire to.
And it's never really a snapshot.
It's always a movie and it's a long movie
and you might not want to see all of
the scenes that, you know, could
be edited out to make more drama.
But in a very real sense, I think
excellence is a long story that has, um,
you know, parts that are not
suspenseful, that parts are mundane.
Yeah. There's like practice that happens
every day, right? You do it all the time,
it gets better. Um, just so, um,
I guess how measurable is Great.
I mean,
you actually did a bunch of pioneering
work to measure it in west point cadets,
right? But is, I mean, what do we
think about talent in Iq and so on?
There's a a rich, if somewhat
colored history in the
measurement of intelligence,
right? Is Grit equally measurable
and you're in your opinion or
I think scientists have a much better
grip on how to measure intelligence than
they do to kind of measure grit or so
many other things that you could say are
under this broad umbrella
called character. And you know,
we've had these Iq tests really for over
a century continually being refined.
And in 45 minutes I can give
you your Iq score. Well,
in two minutes I can give you
your grit scale score, right?
So what's the difference?
The difference is that my
questionnaire is completely fake.
Double my questionnaire.
I mean really like I am a hard worker.
It's not, you know, it's
not hard to, you know,
think about what the answer is to that.
If you want a higher score in an Iq test,
you can't really fake. I mean, you
can't say like, oh, I'm going to guess.
See Cause I know it's the right thing,
but I don't really know, but I'm fake.
You know, that doesn't work. Right? Second
thing is when you're taking an Iq test,
there's no subjectivity. There's no
judgment, right? You take the test,
you get a score with the grit scale.
If I gave it to you and you said
to yourself, am I a hard worker?
I can only imagine the people that you
would be comparing yourself to, right?
When I talk about finishing whatever,
I begin on the,
you're going to compare yourself to your
peers who are all probably extremely
gritty.
So in addition to faking,
there's what in sciences called
the frame of reference bias.
And that is your standard
of comparison can vary.
And here's one concrete example. In high
performing charter schools like Kipp,
right? Eh, these are schools that
are in New York, but you know,
all over the country, kids are, are like
in, in many other schools, you know,
brought to a very high
standard of excellence.
When kids rate themselves on
items like I just read you,
their mental frame is different from kids
who could be just down the block at a
different school that doesn't have
those standards. So that distorts the,
the scores to some extent. As a
researcher, I know about that.
I know how to adjust for that when
I run statistics and so forth.
I also know that there's,
there's error.
I know that there's the
possibility of faking.
What I worry about is employers
or schools or you know,
government agencies who make the mistake
of thinking that you can take, uh,
a grit scale score and make
those high stakes decisions.
That the grit scale was never designed
for, like don't hire with the grit scale.
We want that to be the headline.
Didn't think it was going to be,
but I do wonder, uh, I mean it, it, uh,
it seems to me like we've perfected a lot
of ways of measuring a bunch of talent.
Just want me to tell you my best
ideas haven't been tested yet. Okay.
So I've one idea that has been tested
when you look at the resumes of people who
want to be Googlers,
which I can also tell you,
I think that's interesting that
you use that term Googlers.
And I think I know why you do.
But that will be for another question.
I would love to know why. Why would
I tell you? I'm going to tell you.
I think it's actually like, yeah, I think
it's not trivial so I'll tell you, but,
but when you look at the resume is
somebody who wants to get in here.
What I would look for is evidence of Grit.
I'm not saying that it has
to be an exactly this domain
or even for the job with
that. Ideally, yes, but
sometimes it can be like, wow,
this kid was on the tennis team for three
or four years in college and went from
a to B in their accomplishments.
Like who this kid weren't. You know,
I'll tell you about my own husband.
Like this kid worked for
Domino's pizza as a delivered,
but like they got promoted,
right? Like they kept,
you know that there's progression and
there's continuity in a high grit resume.
Conversely,
don't hire the people who have these sort
of like Dilla taunt resumes of sort of
like, oh, a little bit here,
a little bit there. You know,
where is the evidence of passion and
perseverance applied to something before
they got to my, to my doorstep. So
I think you can look for the res,
the residue of grid as it
were like in people's resumes.
What I don't think you should do is use
the grit scale and also I don't think
you can rely on interviews.
I am of the opinion that you
can interview for charisma,
you can interview for social intelligence,
you can interview for confidence,
you can interview even for chemistry,
like am I going to like to sit next
to this person and work with them,
but how are you going to interview for
that quality of a person where the next
day they're going to get up and they're
going to be the first into the office or
the last,
you know,
you know when you give them the feedback
that says this isn't good enough,
is that person going to genuinely
reflect on that and try to improve?
That's really hard to get out of
any kind of short interaction.
And my best idea, which
hasn't been tested, right,
is if there is something that people are
going to have to do at Google and its
particular obvious to their job,
right.
That is really hard where you can set
up a kind of mini grid experiment right
where you're going to April. We are going
to let them perform right. And learn,
get feedback,
see whether they take that feedback,
see whether they come back for
a second, try, get more fat,
see whether they come back for a third
try. I think that would be fascinating.
Assessment as opposed to
InterMune. Exactly. But you know,
it's like you're piloting
the person, right. I mean,
giving them a chance to display their
grit as opposed to trying to guess at it.
Do you want me to tell you why I
think he used the word Google? Yeah.
I would love to know. Yeah. Um, so, so
my dad worked for dupont his whole life,
right? It was, um, you know, he
actually retired with a gold watch.
I thought that was just like a metaphor
or it's he got one and it said dupont
better things for better living on it.
Um,
spent his entire adult life there in
automotive refinishing products. Um,
which was his passion by the way. Um,
and you know, my dad did not talk about,
you know, working at dupont. He talked
about being a dupont or really? Yeah.
And um, you know, people who go to
west point graduate from West Point,
so they call themselves west
pointers, right? Kids who go to Kipp,
they're not students. They're our
kipsters. Uh, at the Seattle Seahawks.
You're not just a football player.
You're a Seahawk, right? These are nouns.
They're not adjectives.
And when people have a extremely
strong cultural identity,
they're usually able to express
that as a noun. You know,
I'm a Googler,
I'm not working for any other company
there a way that we do things here.
There is a language that we use here.
You probably don't use it where you
are because you're not a Googler.
So we also have an adjective googly,
oh, what does that mean? Just in the,
in the spirit of Google.
And the spending eight years
trying to figure out what it means.
But I think you should
stick with Googler googly.
Sounds like those little eyeballs that
on Brian on stage once made that comment.
The old googly. Yeah. I
don't think that's the,
I let the marketing department decide,
but I mean that's what you're going for.
Yeah. So yet, sadly Google,
he is pretty baked in already.
But I still don't feel that does happen
with culture too. Yeah. But it probably,
you know, but it really, these words that
you, I don't know how many vocabulary,
cause I'm not a Googler.
Right. So I wouldn't know.
But at west point they have
this entire glossary, right.
And there are all these words that you
wouldn't know unless you go to west point.
So a plebe, right. He was like, you know,
you know a plebe and a firstie and a year
later and it's like what are those and
Woo Yah.
So at west point they exclaim Buya,
which doesn't have an easy translation,
but like you say it,
when somebody does something really good,
it's like we are. And then you know,
the whole, the whole crowd of
cadets that you're in will erupt.
And these words that you've
never heard in the English. And,
and that's very important because that's
what it means to be a west pointer.
You know,
every company has a culture and
when that culture is really strong,
people identify with it in and now form,
they speak the language,
they often wear the colors,
they follow the rituals. It, you know,
it becomes part of your identity.
And when I heard about Googlers,
I thought immediately of all these other
very strong cultures that are very,
I'm not saying intentional and that like
one person's writing the handbook, um,
but it really is part of the,
you know,
it is part of what
makes the company great.
No.
Is there a,
is there a connection between that
kind of cultural identity and grit or,
and non ICU correlates with success?
I absolutely think so.
So you know,
you can identify with an organization
or a culture that itself is gritty.
I'll give you a national example.
Right?
Country of Finland has actually
fewer citizens then New York City has
inhabitants. It's small, it's a cold. Uh,
what is there to know about, uh,
Finland that could be of interest to us.
There's a word and finished
called [inaudible],
which very roughly translates to grit,
but quite literally translates
to your insights to your guts.
And if you're finished,
you have the identity of someone who
when things are really hard and you've
given all you can and you
still are falling short,
you reached down inside and you use
your see sue and you do it anyway.
Now it's anatomically impossible that the
fins are walking around with this like
extra battery pack in them.
And, and if they did have that,
why don't like the Swedes have that right?
Because it's like not that far and it's,
you know, Scandinavia and then ones,
I think they had those little
bit of rivalry there. Yeah.
Going back. But you know,
I think what's important to learn
there is that you have an identity as a
Finnish person. And Finnish
people do things that are hard.
And we have see sue and
we and we, uh, we prevail.
And I think that when you are part of
an organization like West Point or on a
team like the Seahawks or the Celtics,
there are another very gritty team with
another very gritty leader or you work
at a company like Google.
That identity is very much part of why
you often struggle through when in a
different context with a different
cultural identity. You might not,
no,
are the,
I mean expanding it to national identities
and national cultures is fascinating
in itself. Are there, you know,
are there particular cultures or immigrant
groups that are grittier than others
or
I'm sure there are. I'm
sure there are, right?
The lots of countries and cultures in the
world and then trying to race bait you,
by the way. No. Well, I haven't
looked at the question directly,
but let me tell you why. Right?
First, let me just acknowledge,
I mean anybody who wants to say that
like all cultures are the same. That's,
that's naive.
I don't have any impulse to say that,
but it's really hard to ask the question.
You are the Americans grittier than
the French and other French, you know,
less gritty than the Japanese.
You know? And here's why.
When I give my grit scale to you,
you're going to answer it as
would with your comparison group.
When I give it in Japan, they're going to
answer it with those cultural standard,
not only of their company and their
family and their neighborhood, but,
but the coal country.
I want to tell you about a study that
was done of over 60 countries where they
asked people to fill out
personality questionnaires.
They didn't give the grit scale, but
they gave a scale of conscientiousness,
right? Related, it's in the family,
right? Dependability, orderliness,
I'm punctual,
et Cetera.
So now you have data on dozens
of countries around the world,
and you can ask the question,
which countries are the most conscientious
and which ones are the least? Well,
I'll tell you what. The findings are the
three least gritty areas in the world.
War Japan. This conscientious
says by the data, right?
Japan, Korea, and China, really?
They're messy people. They're not
dependable. They don't work hard.
They're really,
yeah.
So the researchers in that study concluded
that perhaps these data were being
influenced by the very high standard
that exists in this country.
That's why it's so,
so hard to make these comparisons
because two things go into your score,
what you really are,
and then the frame of reference,
the standard to which
you're holding herself.
W we should probably try to open up
to questions in the room. And uh,
and on the Dory, I think it's given
time. We have about 15, 20 minutes left.
I'd love to that. Yeah. Uh,
we have lot of questions.
Can you use peer assessments,
especially cross cultural
or ethnic boundaries to then
get a more baseline grit
comparison?
Yeah.
So the problem with a peer assessments
when you're talking about the cross
cultural work in particular is
that, you know, who are your peers,
like other people who also
live in the same culture.
So I don't think peer ratings get you
out of that. But I do think that if you,
and you know, I know Google is always
trying to hire better, right? You know,
triangulation is a great strategy.
In psychology,
we call it the principle of aggregation.
Whenever you have imperfect data from one
source and imperfect data from another.
So like what you do is you put more
and more imperfect data together,
the error cancels out,
right?
Or the unsystematic variance the are
and you get a stronger signal. So yeah,
get a pure rating and a teacher rating
and a performance task and look at their
resumes. You could even
throw the grit scale, Lynn,
if you know it's only
one thing among many.
And when you get a consistent signal that
everybody thinks this person is gritty,
then you actually have a
good bet that they are.
Yeah. Thank you for coming. First of
all. Also, I saw you have an audio book,
so props to you and also guidance.
She read it herself, which I did,
which was really sweet. Yeah, it's fun.
I'm going to listen to it like sped up
anyway, but I really liked chip Monck.
Yeah, three, three times. Okay, good.
Yeah. Uh, no, but, um, so my question is,
you talk about, um, this example
of the biochem kid who is really,
really, really deep into biochem. I would
call him pointy, so to speak. Like he,
he dug into that thing really hard and
you're talking about how you can use grit.
The grit property gets you
to do that, right? It's the
people who who can do that.
So I had a question that's
maybe it's outside of the
scope of, of, of the grit. Um,
but my friends and I were
actually very gritty people. We,
we dig into things very,
very deeply. But recently,
particularly after graduating college,
we had trouble figuring out what
to actually be gritty, like into,
right. Yeah. Right. In
college it's very easy.
Or even in school because you know, it's
kind of, the metric is there, you know,
you get good grades, maybe you pick
a major, you do well in it, fine.
But then in the real world,
I find that my friends in particular,
they have trouble being gritty.
Not because they can't be gritty,
but because they want to be pointing you,
but they don't know what to pick.
And then you can be really pointing
and like Russian literature and then it
turns out you need to
make money or something.
Yeah,
I'm just
punch the Russian lit.
There are any,
yeah.
So how do you actually go about deciding
what to be pointy and especially when
the cost of picking
incorrectly is can be high?
You know,
I think that one of the things that makes
it so hard is that we know the cost is
high, right? It can, it can make
us freeze up a little bit. Right.
I was at Mckinsey and you know,
there are a lot of people
at Mckinsey who like me,
had basically spent their entire life
opening doors of opportunity, right?
If I do this internship, I can do
anything. And then if I go to Mckinsey,
anybody will hire me. Well, you know,
you get to a certain point in life where
you realize that that's not the game
anymore. It's not opening
doors of opportunity. It's
actually walking through.
Right. And it's walking through and
hearing the other doors slam shut.
Now that's even more paralyzing in terms
of the anxiety that would produce when
you don't have this really strong
inner compass. You're like, okay,
follow my passion. Where do
I get one? Right? And, um,
and here's my advice about that. You know,
I do think that really, really gritty,
passionate people have two
sources of motivation and this,
these are two questions to ask yourself
when you're going to ask yourself what
to do with the rest of your life. One is
what are my real interests, right? And,
and there's still emerging, you know, they
develop over years, but for many of you,
there were things that you were interested
in and things that you were less
interested in that we're kind of boring
for you around the time that you were
hitting adolescence.
So many gritty people will remember that
they started liking to do something.
You know, at 12 or 13, there are
exceptions like Julia Child, right?
But interestingly, her or interest at
that early adolescent stage was writing.
Maybe think about Hulu, Julia Child,
really key, you know, grew up to be,
it was not just a chef, but equally if
not more so a writer, right. Of Cookbooks.
So, so first to kind of like think back
down memory lane to when you were a young
teenager, what are the things
that you absolutely hated doing,
but what are the things that you kind
of started wanting to do spontaneously?
That's a clue, right? That's a thread.
The second major motivational drive of
passion is purpose. You know, importance.
It really is almost moral for something.
It's like what is the,
what is the greater mission
that my work serves?
And if you think about your
values, right? It can be, you know,
I really want to help people become
their best selves or you know,
I really care about the environment. I
mean, whatever it is that is for you,
a value that you think is deeply
meaningful and isn't going to change.
If you can follow that and figure
out where it overlaps with interests.
We finally mentioned not becoming
an impoverished, you know,
professional Russian literature
critic, right? You know,
I don't know how many
jobs there are like that.
You probably do need a third
circle, which is reality, right?
And trying to make a living, but at
least starting with the first two, right.
My interests and my purpose,
where my values, I think that's,
that's more helpful than just saying like,
oh,
we'll go follow your passion because most
of us don't know what that even means
until we actually find one.
Cool.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Uh, all right. Why don't we go?
Okay, great. I certainly enjoyed the
topic and the presentation. Clearly,
grit has a lot of value both
in professional life and
personal life. A different,
a podcast I'd been listening to recently.
Maybe you heard it,
one of your runs by the, uh,
freakonomics authors. Yeah.
About the power of quitting and failing
fast. We might say an engineer. Yeah,
I was on that podcast.
Oh, I can't remember.
I remember maybe I don't really listen
to them afterwards, but go on. Yeah, I,
and I love that podcast.
It's a great one. Yeah. Yeah.
So it was trying to figure out how to
like combine them because isn't a personal
life on the sort of taken off that last
question because we've tried a lot of
things until you find something
you choose as a passion,
do you have any advice from the
corporate world of how to combine,
choosing when to fail and when
to stick it? Stick to it? You
know, let me use the
metaphor of dating, right?
Because I am personally really happy
that I did not end up marrying my first
boyfriend. Um, and, and so I
quit on him. Right. I mean,
every time you break up with someone,
you're quitting and, and you know,
is that a good thing? Is it a bad thing?
You know, I think that for me anyway,
you know, I was dating to
find my life partner, right?
I guess people can date for other
reasons, but that was like, oh,
we're not going to get
married over. Um, and,
and it took a few dates and guys to
kind of find the guy that I'm with.
This is my husband.
Uh,
but I think it's actually exactly what
we do in our careers too. I mean, you,
you're exploring,
right?
But there are some people
who are exploring with
intention and I was dating to
get married, right? I mean,
I wasn't really ever intending
to like stay dating forever.
I think that makes all the
difference. So shore quit. But for me,
quitting the White House speech writing
Gig and Mckinsey and being a teacher,
it was, it was sort of a groping towards
something that I wanted to stick with.
You know,
I was only quitting those things so
that I could find something that I would
never want to quit. And when
I was 32, finally, after much,
you know, exploration, I figured that
out and it was to have the career I have,
but it's, it's not, uh,
you know, predictable,
efficient process. Uh, so quitting
in the service of not quitting is,
I guess my,
my answer.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Thanks Angela. So much for
coming. It's great. Um,
there's something about grit that seems
very intrinsic or natural, almost.
Unlearnable do you have
any recommendations for how
people can increase their
greediness?
So I want everybody in this room to watch
their own language in the next day or
so for the word just, you
know, um, whenever we say, Ooh,
they just have it. Oh, they just are,
you know, a natural or, you know,
he's just extroverted, you know, like
how does he do that? He's just, you know,
kind of a math guy.
You know,
we use that language I think when we
can't explain something, right? I mean,
that's when we use the word just actually
when Nancy Reagan said, you know,
just don't do it. Or you know,
when Nike says just do it,
I always find that like deeply unhelpful.
Like,
could you please tell me how or are you
just going to, you know, like, so, um, so,
so this,
this idea that when we see
someone do something fluently,
particularly when we can't do it, I
mean, somebody who dances really well,
we can't dance or plays
music, really willing it, we
start to use words like just,
and we say things like, there are
natural. And I was actually giving a talk,
what was the pre book tour, right?
Today's the first day of book tour.
But you know, I gave a talk and I give
talks all the time. Sure you do too.
And you know, you get
practice, you get feedback,
you make these little refinements,
tiny little ones.
Like oof that fourth slide I totally
had to change the background color.
I mean it's really that trivial.
I get off the stage and I'm talking to
the person who's handling it and she's
like,
you are just a natural.
And I thought about the irony that I
just wrote a book about, you know, uh,
I can say I recently wrote a
book instead of, I just wrote it,
I recently wrote a book about, about
the fact that that is a, is a, you know,
such an attractive myth
as like a seductive myth.
And I think the answer is this, you
know, we can say that people, you know,
Jerry Seinfeld would say that some
people are born to be comedians and some
people are not born.
I think there is a sense in which people
are born with different inclinations
thinks that they find fun to do
things that hold their interest.
But if you ask the question of how they
eventually became Jerry Seinfeld, right.
If they eventually wrote a book that's
halfway decent or they gave a talk that's
reasonably fluent,
it's not just anything except if you want
to say it is just hours and hours and
hours of iteration with feedback to get
better at something which may be I did
just like,
you know when I was a little kid.
Yeah.
My question is how do you, what
conditions do you, for a child,
not you were talking about kids do you
set in order to or no breed greediness.
So to give an example,
I don't have kids. Yeah.
Thinking about him though. Okay,
good. So I'm a, I recommend them.
I'm a Colombian immigrant
to the United States.
I came here when I was five years old,
eventually graduated west point low
income household in New York City,
four of us living in one bedroom,
mom, dad, sister, et cetera. So,
I dunno what can,
I still don't know what conditions were
set for me to persevere because I could
have been easily in that demographic
of Hispanics that ended up in jail or
whatever it is. Yeah. Especially
in the city. So what conditions,
what makes me different or people liking
me different than my peers that I went
to high school with that perhaps did not.
Do you have any hypotheses?
You have? Any guesses?
I mean,
I think parents,
parenting definitely had a lot to do
with it as an example of the hardworking
immigrant parents, et cetera. Um,
but then outside of that, you know,
in the classroom it
may have been teachers,
but at the end of the day I still have
to do the work and I just, I don't know.
And you probably see people who grew up
in maybe not identical but such similar
circumstances and they didn't end up
anywhere close to to where you are.
You know, that is itself, I think
you know, my life's work, right,
is to answer your question and, and I,
and I only have an incomplete answer,
but I will say this, first of all, you
did inherit Dna from your mom and dad.
And so when you see gritty little kids
who have gritty parents, you know,
you have to at least pause and
acknowledge the fact that you know,
half of their deans came from mom and
half came from dad. They got shuffled up.
And in part we are like our parents
because of our shared genetic heritage.
At the same time,
it's absolutely unequivocal that
parents model certain behaviors.
It's usually the case, not
always, there are exceptions,
but it's usually the case that kids are
modeling the work ethic and the passion
of their parents. Uh, if
it's not their parents,
often there was another strong role model,
like a particular teacher who had a
big effect or a coach and so forth.
So that's maybe part of the equation.
I also think that a lot of grit comes
down to kind of these virtuous cycles.
You know, you start to find that you
have, uh, a thing for a certain sport,
that that becomes a source
of pride and success.
People begin encouraging you.
It's an upward feedback
cycle of motivation,
effort and achievement.
And it feeds itself.
I think there are people who then are on
the opposite spiral, which is, you know,
they get a little down at the about
themselves. They stopped trying,
they proved themselves right because
things don't go well and they kind of
spiral on the opposite direction.
And Einstein is quoted and I
am not sure I can verify this,
but somebody at Google can as saying
that compound interest is what we all
really need to understand.
That is the mystery of the universe.
And I think this compounding of,
you know, a little bit of Grit,
a little bit of effort, you know, a
little bit of success, little more grit,
you know, a little more effort,
a little more six. Like,
if we could understand that compounding,
then maybe we could, why, you know,
kids like you ended up where you are.
But we could also maybe understand
why so many other do, you know, don't
Nice.
And I would like Google to help me figure
that out by the way. So it would be,
yeah. Volunteer. Great. Thank you.
I think we only have to want
right, if I'm, whereas in his,
his annual expected to sign books at the
end to know at the end. Okay. All right.
So we have five more minutes.
Should we do a question on the
dory? This is somewhat confrontational.
I don't mean to, oh, that's okay.
It's all good. Yeah, yeah. No,
it's good. Wait, I'll read it.
I'll read it to the hard one. Yeah. Yeah.
There was a study of 4,000 UK students
published back in February in the journal
of personality and social psychology
in which grit was not shown to be that
predictive of
academic success.
Instead, intelligence and
conscientiousness were key. Do you,
do you have any thoughts on that study?
Yes, I do have thoughts on that study. Um,
actually one of the coauthors of that
study sent me the report before it was
published and here's what I said to him.
So I'll tell you the full study.
So there are thousands of,
of British kids,
about 16 years old, I think, uh,
who were going through the British school
system and their grit scores on these
kids.
And they're also,
they're standardized math and
reading scores on the UK test. Right.
It's a something like that. And I guess,
right, yeah. Not British enough to know.
Right.
But it's a standardized achievement
test and we've all taken them so we know
what they are.
The finding is this grid does predict
their standardized test scores,
but not quite as well as a
measure of conscientiousness,
which we were already talking
about, you know, dependability,
being able to control your impulses,
that sort of thing. So yes,
it predicted but maybe
not quite as, uh, as much.
And also intelligence was a
better predictor in that study.
I don't find that all that
surprising. I also don't, I mean,
I don't question those findings
for one moment. I think there,
there are very real,
for me,
my complaint is that if you were going
to equate your standardized test scores
when you were 16 and things that
frankly most 16 year olds are not,
are not invested in, right. It's
not a meaningful personal goal.
If you're going to equate that
with success or even, you know,
with academic achievement
grades for example,
do not send all the same
signal as your test scores.
Grades are a better predictor
of college persistence.
Then your standardized test scores,
so not interchangeable.
There's information that's
carried by, you know, grades.
It's not carried by test scores.
There's information carried by your
extracurricular activities that's not
embedded in your test scores. My
complaint is not with the finding itself,
but the,
the idea that that is everything that
we would need to know about success for
those kids. So I guess that's the major
thing that I'll say about that study.
And I think that it's very important
to recognize the grid isn't the only
important thing in the world.
I studied high achievement
in challenging circumstances.
It's in those circumstances where
the goal also matters to you.
That I think re emerges as a,
you know,
the most reliable predictor and not
just a moderately predictive one.
Should we go back to, Oh yeah.
Question. Yeah, I got a live question.
But if you're applying your
amazing good to the wrong thing.
Let's say I wanted to be a film star
that I have no grasp of what the world
actually wants from a film star.
When should I just say I should probably
stop trying to do that and apply my
grit to something else. Right? It
might actually be more successful.
Yeah.
So for example,
what if you're trying to be a film star
and you're just disastrously untalented,
right? There's like nothing that you
could do that you would ever beat, right?
So that's one way that you could be wrong.
The other thing that you could be wrong
is that you're picking an industry that
is going to melt, like, you know,
like the polar ice caps, right?
Like the whole industry is
going to go away. And you know,
that happens these days, right? In,
in ways that are faster than before.
So there's lots of ways that grit
can get you into trouble, right?
I think the question is this, you
know, you got to take risks in life.
There's no getting away really for, even
if you do nothing, you're taking a risk.
What grit means is to put your left foot
in front of your right foot and then
your left foot again and keep
heading in a certain direction.
And you're absolutely right that you might
end up somewhere that you didn't want
to be,
but you can guarantee yourself that
you'll never get anywhere by switching
direction every few paces or not
walking forward at all. So yeah,
there's absolutely risk and
being a paragon of grit,
but I'd say there's a guarantee of
failure and not being passionate and
persevering.
So a related question to the one
he just asked is, is, is grit
in a continuum with obsession?
Is there a bright line between grit
and obsession or are they unrelated?
No, I think there is actually a strong
family resemblance between grit and
obsession. You know, one of the
individuals that I interviewed,
but I didn't put her into the book,
partly because I forgot to push record
when I was interviewing her was temple
Grandin and I don't know
if you know her work,
but she is Lino famously autistic and she,
she writes about her
autism and in her words,
a little bit of obsession gets a hell
of a lot of work done. Um, and you know,
this idea that you wake
up, I mean, I'm obsessive.
If you woke me up at three in the morning,
which sometimes just happens to me,
you know, like you wake up and you
have to go to the bathroom and yeah.
You know what I'm thinking about?
I'm thinking about grit.
I'm thinking about like, why did
that person do that? You know,
it's so interesting. Like where did they
get them? I think about it all the time.
I think about it in the shower.
I think about it in Yoga when I'm supposed
to not be thinking about anything,
but I'm thinking about grit,
right? Like Shavasana pose,
you're supposed to be doing nothing. And
I'm like, I wonder where that, you know,
is gonna you know, it's,
it is an obsession.
The difference maybe between the way most
people think about obsessions and the
way gritty people think about the
sessions is, you know, when they say,
I love what I do, they love
that. They love what they do.
There's no sense in which they would
trade that life for, for any other,
and that's how I feel about my own work.
No,
I think we have time for one more
question. Should we? Yup. Hi.
So a lot of your examples of people that
have shown great grid, like Julia Child,
she starts at 30 and then becomes
this great. They also need
to be underdogs that then succeed.
Do they have to be,
you know,
you don't have to be an underdog,
but I am fascinated by underdog
psychology because, and I'll, I'll,
I'll say these words to you and
I wonder if they'll resonate.
There is characteristic of many,
many grit paragons that I've studied
a sort of all show you rebel,
you know,
like you know why I don't think you
really cut out to be a programmer or you
know, just this like, you know, fear.
It's an aggression almost. Yeah.
And I felt that when I was,
you know,
failing my neuro biology class my
freshman year of college and my very well
meaning teaching assistant,
my ta said, you know,
you really should withdraw from this
course because you're going to get an f on
your transcript and you don't know this
yet because you're 18 that's not a good
thing to have. Right. And
I felt a kind of, you know,
like a hot anger.
I mean I marched out of that office to
the registrar's office and I not only
didn't drop the course,
I declared my major in
neurobiology that very day.
What the hell is that? You know, the,
I will show you response I think is
fascinating. I don't fully understand it,
but it's fascinating that,
you know,
the same exact experience can either
lead people to feel like I'm a loser.
I give up or the precisely
opposite psychological reaction,
and I think it's not need necessarily,
but it's very,
very common to paragons of grit.
Okay.
I think we're out of time. Hey, Angela,
thank you so much. That was good.
Fascinating.
Thank you.