Hey,
what's going on is bill burn?
It's the Monday morning
podcasts about the October six,
2014 hello?
It's me.
I haven't podcast for a long,
long time.
Actually it was last Monday
in the morning due to Ooh,
it's important too.
Hey,
what's going on? How are
Ya? Um, as you can tell,
I screamed and yelled all this fucking
weekend and that only means one thing. Oh,
Billy red face had a standup gig.
If you're new to my podcast,
well why is your voice gets raspy?
FTF His show because I don't
know how to write a joke.
So what I have to do is I have
to scream my ideas. I asked,
I have to use the f word right and
left and left and right. You know,
and then make silly faces.
I was actually up in San Francisco.
If you're going to San
Fran [inaudible] goal,
um, I'm going to put some
flowers in your hair. Yeah.
And some change in your pockets for the
fucking 9,000 homeless people that have
up there. Jesus Christ just inundated
with them. You know, it was great.
It was towards the end of the
month and two great things. Wait,
that doesn't make sense.
The beginning of the month was back when
you wouldn't see the homeless people in
San Francisco because they actually gave
them a stipend, which was a, you know,
a little bit of money so they could
get them off the fucking streets.
You know, like these fucking
people know how to handle money.
They knew how to handle money. They
wouldn't have been homeless. Hey,
this guy sucks at math. I know. Let's
give them an Algebra book. All right,
see a fella.
Good luck with that.
We're not going to teach you on any
level. That's not even true. That's,
that's even worse that, that, that
example doesn't even make sense.
That wasn't the correct example.
Because if somebody sucks with money
and you just give them money, you know,
so he sucks at math.
He give him an Algebra book.
They could actually learn about math.
How do you just give somebody some math,
give him a bag and numbers, whatever you
want. You know what I'm trying to say?
All right.
And even if you don't,
I don't know that you don't because
you can't call into to this show.
All right.
The phone lines,
the nonexistent phone
lines cannot light up. I'm
trying to write down in Alabama, so I
don't forget to talk about them this week.
Alabama,
the dream ended this weekend.
Um,
anyway,
so I was up there in San Francisco and I
was working Davies Symphony Hall and a,
I had a great time.
And you know,
my favorite part of the fucking weekend
was j law had Jason Lawhead Rosebowl
tailgate legend Jason Law head,
uh,
before he's gonna bring me out.
He's like,
okay.
what do you want to have fast?
She turned on the
fucking air conditioning.
Can he hear that stupid thing rattling?
I tried to tell her, you know,
you try to tell your wife
you don't want something.
And what did they fucking do it anyways?
Because they think that they know.
I know what's good for him. I
know it's good from, hang on,
I gotta shut this fucking thing off.
Yeah.
All right. I'm back. Unfucking
believable. I swear to God they they,
you know for all their bitch moaning
and complaining they do on all those,
those fucking Yap Yap and shows their,
you know,
I know I was what's better than
one woman running her? Yap.
Well let's get three others and have
them all sit around with their shoes,
you know. Yap, Yap, Yap.
And about all the fucking shit that's
going on are those shows by the way,
the view,
the talk and all those are those like
women's versions of like a guy watching
those stupid pregame NFL shows,
you know rather than four broads,
you get fucking four
meathead guys in their suits.
Okay.
You know it's,
it's a bit of bubble screen.
John Gruden says fucking bubble screen.
One more goddamn time this fucking week.
I got it. It's a bubble screen.
There's a screen and there's a
bubble and he's got an option and they're
going to fucking have the Lyman go
this way and see what their doors
you. I took her to abroad broad. Okay,
now you guys just saw option over here.
If he wants to,
we could throw it burger
Gertrude to keep a fork, a ball.
And you could try to run it with
your cues to Corny book. Her's door.
Understood were to make the decision to
Eagle with loose the pool or to hold on
to it. Oh, tell you work when you,
when you start to join no dirt, dirt.
When good things will be helping
it. The, this you don't put pool.
Um,
so just all of that dumb shit that I
just fucking said that I don't need to
know.
I don't need to know any of that.
I don't need to know what a fucking
bubble screen is to watch a God damn gay.
It's a hot read. It's a hot read or
you, yeah, it comes up in the line.
It's a fucking hot.
Is it a heart rate?
It's a hot read. I can't, it just be,
he goes up to the line and if he sees
something, yeah, let's fucking do it.
And if he doesn't,
let's just stick with the play.
It's a hot read on a bubble
screen in a cupboard to tango,
Sierra Alpha. Um, anyways,
so I'm up there in San
Fransisco and for once
every, I was up there
Friday, Saturday and Sunday,
and it was beautiful weather
every single day. 85 degrees,
80 degrees, global warming
at its finest. Right?
This is how miserable the fucking
weather is in San Francisco.
They,
most places don't have air conditioning
because they don't fucking need it.
They're in California and they
don't need air conditioning.
Okay.
All right.
Why don't you wrap your little fucking
podcasting listening brain around that?
Alright.
I'm not sure when you think about a
California goes pretty much almost the
entire coast
of the west coast of the continental
United States, the lower 48. Anyways,
so I guess at some point,
right?
You gotta be as far north is like Wyoming.
I know they get snow,
but I know people in Wyoming got
to have fucking air conditioning.
Yeah.
Does anybody in Wyoming listen to this?
You out there right now on a horse,
just sitting there staring a cattle,
trying to figure out what's out there
that keeps killing one or your cows every
fucking eight days.
Okay.
Sitting there arguing with your buddies.
Look at the [inaudible] Lou,
the bite marks there.
I ain't no fucking coyote.
Coyote can't kill fucking dumb bitch.
You know you get that from
you get that from your mother.
I knew she was fucking dumb the moment
I looked down at her boots. All right,
butter titch wire hanging out.
My favorite song was on the Jukebox,
so I said fuck it. I ain't got
nothing in the back of my truck.
I layered her down there, stick my
cores, lied on her forehead and I'll,
I'll tell you I'm a put a rod in there.
Well next thing you know,
she starts calling me up.
All my SAP come in,
they're good buddy.
My stomach's getting bigger and I ain't
been eating shit. I faked I'm pregnant.
And I'm like, why ain't this the
sum bitch? All right, let us,
Jesus is coming back again as a baby.
It must be mine.
Say you are here you are half a fucking
stupid telling me that a goddamn coyote
killed his fucking cow.
I will tell you one more time
then it was a pack of wolves.
And if you keep having that dumb look
on your face, I swear to fucking God,
I'm a shoot you on my own God
damn property. Is that understood?
Oh, quit your crying and
you're just like your mother.
If you're out there in Wyoming.
All right.
Yeah, I know you got air conditioning.
You might not have teeth,
but I know you have Eric and I'm sorry.
Why do I keep doing this?
You know what's funny about Wyoming?
Um,
a lot of it is fucking rich people
who've gone out there and bought property
like Ted fucking Turner,
like Ted Turner I think can ride his horse
from the border of the United States,
Mexico
and ride his fucking horse all
the way up to Canada. Please.
That's his goal without ever not
being on his own property. You know,
and like most driven men,
at any point does he even think about
the fucking horse that does not want to
walk Gallup or trot all the things
that horses do shit in public.
It doesn't want to do
it.
Doesn't want to do that.
Okay.
They never wanted you on
its back to begin with.
Why the fuck would it
want you on its back?
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. You're Ted Turner.
You can't afford a robot horse.
Hi with your jeopardy mustache.
Having said all that great investment,
I got to tell you that tech journey,
you know when it comes to money,
he understands it. You know,
it'd be great if Ted Turner just walked
up to a homeless guy and rather than
explain money to him,
just started yelling at him about money,
dressing them down.
You know,
like a head coach pissed
off at his fucking starting
quarterback who's making a
bunch of mistakes. Right. And his job
is like right on the bubble. You know,
if he just came walking
up to the homeless guy,
throws a fucking clipboard down at
his feet after he sees the guy by some
fucking heroin with a bunch of nickels.
Okay.
I don't fucking, I don't got an immediate
FGL again. All right. I'm sorry.
I just set up a total comedy scenario
and now I'm baling. All right.
I'm fucking rolling right out of it.
You know what? I can't do a Ted Turner.
I even know what he sounds like.
Okay.
I just, when I picture him,
I picture Norm Mcdonald.
When he used to imitate that guy used to
hold the pan and run for President Bob
Dole or the above though.
That's how I pictured Ted Turner.
Ted Turner talking a new talk show.
He's so fucking rich.
He doesn't have any guests.
Um, all right. So anyways,
I go up to som slams,
see school and the
weather's beautiful and um,
you know, I got some family and
friends up there. We fucking hang out.
What do we do? What did
we do Friday night? Oh,
went out to this unbelievable
Italian restaurant and uh,
I actually have been craving
a pork chop for a while,
for years. I actually am not gonna lie to
you. I got to, I got a great pork shop.
Why is that word sounds so annoying.
Pork Chop.
I'm at this restaurant out here in la
and it was so fucking unbelievably good.
All right,
so unbelievably fucking
that. I came back like 10 days later
going, I got to get this pork chop again.
Pork chops and applesauce g that swell,
right Brady bunch,
Brady bunch reference there wold
champion Apple, Shush, shush match. Well,
um, and I fucking, I went back
and they had taken it off the menu
and idea or just something else since
sucked. In fact, everything's sucked.
The offense shocked. The defense sacked.
We sucked. Um, the whole fucking,
the whole meal stunk.
So I went years just thinking
about this fucking pork shop,
waiting for the right fucking restaurant
with the right level of quality of food
that if it was on the God damn menu,
I was going to order it.
There's not a lot of plate.
Not a lot of Nice restaurants
will serve via fucking pork chop.
You know, your choices
are usually, you know,
stake some sort of chicken fish,
maybe lamp.
All right?
They might do a pull pork.
Uh,
they might do a piggy or fucking
sandwich, a brisket or whatever, but,
but to try to get somebody to get dim,
to make a fucking pork chop,
all right. The way that your mom
never did. Cause who's kidding who,
whose kid? No moms do not
know how to cook pork chops.
All right? They just date
as my dad would say, Christ,
you're cut the shit out of it.
Right?
They cook the shit out of it,
which is very easy to do with pork.
I don't know why,
but it's very easy for that thing to
taste like one of the fucking tiles that's
on the floor. Your
kitchen. Um, so anyways,
I went to this restaurant and this Italian
restaurant that had homemade fucking
pasta, one of my favorites, and
I saw that pork chop and I said,
fuck that pasta. All right there, Luigi,
you tell Clemenza and the kitchen.
I don't need his fucking
pasta. All right, I want,
I want to fucking porkchop. Solera
this portrait. I got a side of pasta.
The Pasta was fucking outstanding.
And I know like most times,
most shows like Anthony Bordain would
tell you what fucking restaurant he went
to. I don't do that. You know why?
Because I want to be able to go back
there without standing in any sort of a
fucking line.
So why don't you go to San Francisco
and figure it out for yourself?
That would be my cooking show.
Do you like how arrogant I am?
Anthony Bordain has this huge fucking
millions and millions of fans watching his
show. I just got, you know,
I got a couple thousand fans listen to
this fucking thing and I want to make
sure I cannot guys,
I can't say the names of
things on my podcast, the, the,
the,
the crush of people that will be showing
up to get a fucking porch up at God
damn.
Oh my God.
Are you kidding me? Oh my
God. Are you kidding me?
Oh my God. All right. I thought the,
I just thought this whole
fucking thing just shut off.
When I set it back down,
I'm doing this right as I woke up.
Okay.
The law many times that's happened to me.
Like I go to restart it and then I fucking
riff for 20 minutes and I look in the
fucking recorders off and I'm like, oh
my God. Just like I just said, oh my God,
are you fucking Katie?
I got to do it all over again.
I had a really funny character from
Wyoming. I'll never be recreated.
Um, all right, good. I just fucking
panicked. And you know what,
that brings me into a fucking unbelievable
story that I got to talk about later.
Let me finish with the pork chop,
then I'll do a little bit of advertising.
All right.
That's your second course.
They're right in the dessert will be
my little fucking story about panicking
that will not be enjoyable and listened
to it. Absolutely terrified me. Alright,
so I ordered this fucking pork chop.
Absolutely delicious.
Yeah,
absolutely. Fucking
delicious. You know, and um,
I was I talking about it yet and I'm
not going to tell you where I got it.
Not only what, I never tell you if I know
I can't even remember the name of it.
So now I'm fucked.
I don't know who gives a shit.
You heard me trying to remember the
name of the fucking x men as a Goddamn
zillion dollar movie. I'm going to
remember the name of a restaurant.
The fuck was it called? It was
a number in it. I remember that.
Okay,
that Jesus Christ,
this is when the cops would just
put away their little fucking,
you know that little pad that they write
on their part. We have an iPad now.
Can you describe what he looked like?
I Dunno. Why don't you go, fuck.
I look at the security footage.
We're in the middle of nowhere. Well,
fucking call up the drone company.
I'm sure they were watching something.
Fucking nerd Weirdos jerking
off to the top of my head.
All right, let's go. Let's do a little
bit of advertising here for this week,
everybody,
all right,
okay.
Oh No. What? What is going
on with this shit? Come on,
Bill for Christ. Fucking sakes.
All right. I swear to God.
Me Undies, right? Me
undies. I swear to God.
This is the name of a
company. Me undies, everybody.
It's unbelievable how putting on a great
pair of underwear changes your entire
outlook for the day.
That is not a joke.
You know that feeling of putting
on that ratty old saggy underwear.
I want you to know that feeling
of wearing great fitting,
great looking underwear
that's cupping you bull.
This is ridiculous.
You need to know about me.
undies.com me undies has the
most comfortable underwear
you have ever tried on.
They fit perfectly.
They don't ride up on you
and they literally pull
moisture away from your skin.
They pull moisture away from your skin
all day. So you're cool all day long.
But here's the thing, they also make
you look great. They give you a package,
a nice profile.
Go to me undies.com and check out the
pics of all the different styles of
underwear on. I know I'm going to do
that. I don't know about you guys.
And for the ladies,
checkout those hot looking boy shorts
men and went Nah. Yeah, nothing like
suggested you might have a Dick, uh,
men and women, high quality materials
for your high quality materials,
if you know what I mean.
The price.
Glad you didn't ask a a fraction of what
typical high end underwear designers
charge here.
I'll help you out.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr
and get 20% off your first order,
20% off your first order when you go to
[inaudible] dot slash bar and right now
you'll even get free shipping
and the U S and Canada. Well,
you know what I gotta go.
I got to see me undies.
M E U N D e s.com.
Let me check out me undies.
Me Undies,
me undies cup and my fucking bald.
Boop, boop, boop. Me, undies.
Me undies.
Does that chick ever Dick?
Okay.
All right.
Hang on me on these men.
Yup. Those are underwear.
A men's Pajama pants,
men's, French, Terry slim at sweatpants,
Unisex French Terry sweat shorts.
They got boxer briefs.
They got trunk and they
got the men's brief.
You know what I got to tell you,
those things look comfortable as hell.
I owe them an apology.
You guys got to go to me on
days beyond Ds. God copier,
mother fucking balls. Bateau
boop, boop me undies. Mandy's.
Hey does that chick of
a Dick. All right. Um,
dollar dollar shave club. Everyone,
guys, dollar shave club.com.
I've been talking to you
about them for years.
They deliver great raises
for a few bucks a month. Hey,
if you're not a member yet,
what's your old up think?
They'll hit you with a bunch of fees.
Dollar Shave club.com has no fees.
You just pay for the raises and they
ship them right to you and that's it.
Get there.
Four blade razor and for replacement
blades sent to your door each month for $6
including shipping. This is the
greatest thing ever and you know,
it's the greatest thing ever is because
some of the other big fucking razor
companies are trying to do with
these guys has been doing all right.
You got to stick with dollar shave club.
What would you rather see?
Led Zeppelin or the people imitate
and led Zepplin. All right?
You don't want to get locked
into a monthly commitment.
Dollar Shave club.com doesn't have any
contracts and if you decide you don't
want raises for a month or two, they won't
send you any and you don't pay a dime.
Okay?
Dillard, they're bending over
backwards for you. Hear people? Um,
don't know if you liked their products.
I already told you this stuff is amazing,
but if you don't agree,
dollars shaved up,
dollar shave club.com we'll refund
your money. No questions asked.
Stop with the excuses unless you some
idiot who likes wasting his money.
Go sign up@dollarshaveclub.com slash bar
right now I'm telling you what's great.
That's dollar shave, shave
club.com/burr. See right there.
That's how you run a company. That's how
you write. No contract, no fees. Hey,
you need some this month. You don't.
We got you. You don't want them.
We won't send them. You want to leave?
See you later. Thanks for stopping by.
That's the way you do it in a ramming
it down your throat like a fucking cell
phone company. All right, one
more. He voice.com everybody. Oh,
I love that. The flexibility that owning
your own business provides. Look at me.
I've created an empire with
this show. Have I? I Dunno,
that's what the copy says,
but when it comes to handling business
calls, you're stuck with a challenge.
Either hire a full time receptionist
or handle all of your calls yourself,
it's a lose lose. Uh,
that's why I love he voice.
They will set your business up
with a toll free number or a local,
a local number, toll free
number, or a local number.
That's what I was trying to say. Sorry
about that one. Customer's calls call.
They're greeted professionally by,
by a virtual receptionist that will
route your call to wherever you are.
That's,
there's even a dial by name directory.
You're going to sound like a fortune
500 company, and more importantly,
you'll never miss an important call again,
all for under 13 bucks a month. Okay,
look at this. She got yourself your
underwear, you got a free shave,
and now you're going to sound like
you've got a giant company. I mean,
look at this advertising.
It's just streamlined. Okay?
Right now for a limited time,
I listeners can try.
He voice.com could try he voice
for free for 60 days. Seriously,
my listeners get an extended 60 day
trial to test drive this amazing business
tool that is right. 60
days. For our listeners,
go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bill right now to sign up.
Set up your [inaudible] voice.
60 day extended free trial now at
[inaudible] dot com slash bill.
That's he voice dotcom.
Slash. Bill. All right,
let's get back to the full good podcast.
Um,
all right.
Why the hell are we
okay?
Oh yeah.
So I go up to San Fransisco and I
got this great pork chop and um,
okay.
Smoked a cigar at the top of one
of those God Damn Hills and uh,
called it a night.
Okay.
And Oh my God, I almost forgot
about the fucking steam room.
Okay.
I got to tell you about
the fucking steam room.
Okay.
I gotta make sure I remembered
to tell you that. All right,
so let's just get to the show.
So I go over to a Davies Symphony Hall,
beautiful venue. Bunch of people
showed up. And uh, so before I,
I go out on stage or whatever, before
we starting to show Jason Law had goes,
hey bill. He's like, what do
you want me to say about you?
And I was like, you know,
I'm going to see them on
Netflix, Letterman. And he goes,
you want me to hype the new
special? And I said, yeah,
if you don't mind doing that. He said,
absolutely. When does it come out?
What's it called?
They said,
it comes out December 5th
on Netflix and it's called,
I'm sorry you feel that way. And
he goes, okay, all right, cool.
And then five minutes later he goes,
Hey, what's your special called again?
I keep thinking, why do I do
this? What did I go? It's called,
I'm sorry you feel this way.
He goes, okay, I got it. I
got it. And I looked at him,
I go, Jay, he's like, what? I go, you're
going to fuck this up. And he goes, no,
I'm not. I'm a professional.
And he laughs and he leaves.
So he goes out and he does his thing.
He gets to his clothes and bit,
it crushes right. And uh, and I'm like,
okay, you know, I'm getting a bubble.
I'm getting ready to get brought out.
So I'm ready to get brought up and I'm
waiting for him know to do as little
fighting out of the red corner. He stands
at five foot 10. He can't get a Tan.
He's got freckles on
his ass though. Rating.
Right. Um, but he doesn't do that.
He just starts talking.
He finished his fucking act like he
always does. He kills like he always does.
And now we supposed to fucking bring
me up and instead of bringing me up,
he starts Yammer and all and on going,
you know,
it's been great out here to
be here in San Francisco,
a beautiful weather today.
You know,
me and bill were out there a sampling,
some of the local fare
Blahblahblahblahblah and he
just starts just not telling
jokes,
not really telling a story.
Just sort of vaguely describing the day.
Yeah.
It was about 82 degrees out there,
barometric pressure.
And I'm sitting there going,
what the fuck is this guy doing it?
And then he just goes, all right, you
guys ready for the man? He came to see,
you know, you know, he is, uh,
he's got a special coming out on Netflix
and then he just looks over at me and
he goes and he's like,
I can't remember what it's called.
And then I fuckin died laughing,
died laughing.
Cause then I realized what he was doing,
he wasn't even talking to the crowd,
he was just saying English words that
they'd understand is in his brain.
He was going,
what the fuck is it called?
So I went out there and for
five minutes just trashed him
for saying sampling some of the local fair
and looking back,
I should have trashed the crowd for
not immediately heckling him for saying
fucking sampling some of the local fare.
What the fuck does that mean? Do you
realize what a creepy,
creepy fucking expression that is?
Sampling the local fare.
Anybody who just blew into town could
be talking about anything from getting
something to eat,
to being a fucking serial rapist.
And that was sampling some
of the local fare. You know,
something like Hannibal Lecter would say
50 fucking took a bite out of your neck.
Um,
so anyways,
so I went out there and I tried a bunch
of new shit and it seemed to work and
then we did a
okay.
It was just, it was just a perfect show,
man. That first show was just awesome,
right? Not saying the second one wasn't,
but I had such a funny moment, uh,
during the show where I'm in the
middle of my act and the giants.
Okay.
You know, they were in the
playoffs, playoffs. And um,
I'm in the middle of one of my jokes and
I have no idea what's going on in the
game.
And all of a sudden this guy just yells
out in the upper deck. He just goes,
and the crowd just fucking
erupts into chairs.
So I immediately do the math. I might, San
Francisco giants. It's fucking October.
That's right. I've been watching some of
the minutes to playoffs and I was like,
all right. Yeah. I can't get mad at that.
I can't get mad at that. Your giants fans,
you want to be watching the games,
but you fucking bought tickets to my
show so you know you're going to do a
little multitask in there. So I said, all
right, two to one and I was like, what?
Editing is it?
And the crowd starts yelling,
you know when a bunch of people are
yelling and you standing up on stage,
it bounced.
The sound bounces off the wall behind
you and it can be very hard to understand
what people are saying. So I
was like, what? Anything is
it? And they're like, Yay.
I'm like, why? Why don't you
know, Yay Jay. And then I go,
I go, I can't hear you.
There you go. Hey Jay.
Okay.
Oh gone. 88 80 come on. What? What?
And just fucking hold up your fingers.
And they kept yelling out and it sounded
like they was saying eight. I go,
you know what? It sounds like
you're saying 18 what inning?
Just one person.
One person was holding up seven fingers.
So I was like the seventh and
they were like, hey, chain.
I sorta kept sounding
like I kept the goal.
He keeps sounding like you're
saying the 18th a minute,
90 excruciating seconds to this.
Yeah,
until I find out they
were actually saying 18.
It was the fucking eighth inning.
Okay.
The national score to run in like the
third fucking inning to go up one to
nothing.
Okay.
And then the giants scored one in the
top of the ninth to tie it up or the
bottom of the night. Oh No. Top of the
night. That's right. It was in Washington.
Yeah.
To tie it at one to one and then they
didn't score again until the fucking top
of the 18th and neither did the nationals.
The nationals went 15 fucking
innings without scoring a run.
The giants played a whole nother
baseball game before they scored another
fucking run. And uh, unfucking believable.
And you know what? It's odd enough
that happened in the middle of July.
You'd want to kill yourself, but if it
happens in October, it's unbelievable.
You know, for as much shit as
people give me as a hockey fan.
Why do you watch the regular season?
It doesn't even count.
Everybody makes it, but like four
fucking teams. It's like, yeah,
but there's exciting games.
They're allowed to fight. Okay.
There's great things that can happen.
You know,
baseball on the other fucking hand
other than the beginning in April where
you're excited because it's a new season.
Other than that, I mean it's just,
it's fucking brutal
until you get to October.
And I would put baseball
playoffs right up playoffs.
I put it up there with any other
fucking playoffs. Um, I actually,
I love October baseball. Um, it's,
this is the best time of fucking year.
October a playoff baseball,
national football league.
The national football league has been
going on long enough where he's starting
to know who's going to be
competitive and who isn't.
And then hockey's coming up and
then right after that basketball,
it's unfucking believable.
Unbelievable. My life is perfect.
Um,
and I actually watched that first.
Um, cod knows Dodgers game.
I didn't see game too.
I watched game one and I was,
I am 100% convinced that
Donnie baseball is cursed.
I mean, they had their race. What's
the guy? Kershaw, I don't even know.
I don't even watch baseball. I have
no fucking idea. And all I do is I,
I just keep hearing about this guy that
he's basically having like a seasoned
better than Pedro Martinez in like 1999.
I'm like,
I gotta Watch this guy. And, uh,
I start watching the game and I
know the Dodgers have this debt.
Unbelievable, right fielder. He's
like fucking Willie Mays on steroids.
Not Literally steroids, but you know,
people are just bigger now. And uh,
so he gets drilled in the fucking arm
when he's up there and I guess the
cardinals were doing that shit last year.
So all of a sudden the next guy
that comes up there, first base,
when he was like my height, he gets in
the face of fucking some guy named Benji.
I don't know anybody's name anymore. They
start fucking screaming at each other.
And uh, I was, I was totally
hooked. I was into it.
The fucking Dodgers were up six to two
going into the seventh or eighth
fucking ending. All right.
I think Clayton Kershaw is the name of
the pitcher. I have no fucking idea.
But now they all have beards
and all that crazy shit.
They all stole it from the Red Sox who
stole it from the homeless guys, right?
And uh, you know, they've
got their fucking ace
guys got no, was it six to one or
62? It's got a full run fucking lead.
The get Goddamn game is over.
All of a sudden he loads up the
basis is a single six to three.
There's another single six to four Donny
baseball comes walking out like, dude,
what the fuck are you doing in the
little bearded wonder goes, hey,
I may not be able to grow a man's beard,
but I know how to get out of
this fucking Annie. All right.
I'm only at a hundred pitches.
I won the Cy Young Award.
I won every fucking award you
can win as a goddamn picture.
I've got this Donnie and Donnie
baseball makes the right choice.
That's a fucking locally. This is the
move to make. We've got to win game one.
We got to do it on your arm,
right? Fucking comes up.
This other fucking dude who owns them.
This is the worst fucking sports coverage
ever. I don't know anybody's name.
He fucking,
it's a a God damn
double. That just clears
the basis. Three run score,
six to five, six to six.
Now it's six to seven.
They're down by a fucking run
and they've got a man on second.
Now Donnie baseball comes up,
poses fucking kid brings in this
fucking pull Luca, he comes in,
serves up a fucking meatball,
right? That's gotta be the
Saint Louis fucking announcer.
They score two more runs.
It is now nine to six.
They started the inning,
six to two,
up for fucking runs with the greatest
picture of the last 15 fucking years.
By the end of the inning, they are down
by three runs. How does that happen?
You know how bad I'm rooting
for the Dodgers to win.
There's so many teams that I love this
year. Kansas City, you got to love that.
They're back in at the Baltimore Orioles.
You gotta love that. They're back in it.
You know, don Mattingly, you got
to want that guy to win a fucking,
uh, you know, when a ring and then he
got the giants. I mean, I, you know,
they've just one, two, I mean,
I like seeing a fucking dynasty,
whatever the fuck they would
be called. It's great, right?
A lot of fucking teams to root
for. And then they'd sit, nick, uh,
suggested that maybe the cardinals is
steel and signs from second base and that
they have a reputation for doing that.
And once I found out that's not illegal,
it's like a fucking love these guys.
And even if it was illegal,
that's the kind of cheating that
you got to respect. You know,
if you can look over at your fucking
neighbors paper and they're smarter than
you are, you know, are
you're really cheating. Oh,
you just delegating
power. Um, anyways. Oh,
what the fuck I'm talking about?
So I watched that whole
game beside myself.
I just can't fucking believe it.
And the thing about don Mattingly's
such a class act and he just sits there
expressionless and you know,
it's just ripping his fucking hard out.
I want to see that guy get a ring.
So God damn bad if he doesn't,
I would love to see either
the royals or the Orioles.
Because when I first started
watching playoff baseball,
it was always the royals would always
win the west and they could not get past
the Yankees. Um, and then there was a,
when do they all they find got by him in
1980 and then lost to the Phillies with
Pete rose at first base dribbling the
ball up to the picture on the fucking
astro turf. And um, and the Orioles,
I, I have to see, I saw them when it in
83 and a, the first world series, well,
the Third World series that I watched,
1979, the orals versus the pirate.
So I was hoping the pirates are going
to win that one game playoff and maybe I
could have a rematch in 1979 and nine
different, they'd bring back. We Ah,
Woo Hoo. Who? Um, sorry. Um, anyways,
uh,
so I watch that shit so that I'm
rooting for a Donny baseball. So anyway,
so I'm watching that shit. Then I go
on and I go do my show, smoke a cigar.
And one of the greatest things
you can do after you smoke cigars,
besides take a fucking shower and
gargle with mouthwash for an hour,
you still gonna wake up with that
taste in the back of your throat.
So if you have access to a steam shower,
you go down and you'd take a state,
you take a steam and you're fucking
sweat out all the impurities and um,
okay.
And then you get, yeah,
you, you're good to go.
You go out and you're fucking
jump in a cold shower.
A lot of people don't know how to
take a fucking steam. You know,
they fucking go into this steam sweat,
they're fucking nuts off.
And then they walk out and they stand
there. Oh God, it's hot as shit.
And they just stand there and then they
fucking go back in and then they come
back out and then they go,
I got one more session and mean
they fucking go back in again.
Morons fucking morons.
All right,
this is how you take a steam. You just
stay in there for like 10 minutes.
That's all you need.
And as you're in there for 10 minutes,
be wiping the fucking sweat off of you.
Your body is,
is when he made you sweat. It's releasing
toxins. Your skin is like a sponge.
If you let it sit there on you,
okay,
you're gonna fucking reabsorb some of it.
As you're sitting there in the fucking
steam shower, these fucking guys do that.
Then you supposed to walk out of the
steam shower and immediately walk in and
take an ice cold shower immediately.
So your poor state closed and your wash
off as much of the fucking toxins that
you sweat it out as possible and you
will feel like a fucking million bucks.
All right? And all you need
to do is just be in the water,
the ice cold water for like, you
know, whatever. Five, six seconds,
okay,
oh long it takes you to fucking hoes off
your body and then he could turn it on
to an acceptable temperature
and then you're good to go.
And you always wear flops,
so you don't get fucking plantars warts
or athlete's foot or any other fucking
awful bacteria. That's, that's, it's
in the God damn thing there. Right.
So, um, anyways, the fucking, uh,
how's it going to say? So we
fucking go there and there's, I,
I walk in one with law head and I walk
in to see if there's anybody in the steam
shower and I walk and there's the, uh,
the sauna, which is just the dry heat.
And I look in there and there was this
Asian dude completely fucking naked.
Yeah.
Okay. He had the decency to put his
arm in front of his junk as I walk by,
kind of like Burt Reynolds when he
did the fucking, uh, the playgirl,
whatever the, the playgirls center
fold or whatever the fuck he did. Um,
I'm like, Oh God, a naked Asian and
Asian. We've got an Asian in their law it,
and he's like,
and then he's sitting there butt ass naked
on the fucking seat that someone else
has to sit on.
Okay.
Fucking unbelievable.
So meanwhile I had,
you know,
because I was walking in and make
sure that the steam was on. Uh,
so then we fucking come walking back in.
And as we walked back in the, the
naked Asian, the nation there is,
he had gone into the shower,
he knew to take the cold shower and he
just comes walking out completely fucking
naked. All right, so I'm laughing.
There's always the fucking naked guy.
All right. So then I, uh,
I opened the sauna and in, no, no, no,
no, no. If I fucked up as, as we go,
that's right. Then we went
back to the lockers. We change.
Now we're walking back in and we'll laugh.
And about the naked Asian dude.
And right as we go to turn the
fucking corner to go into the sauna,
like the fucking Truman show for people
walk in front of us and go right into
the sauna and there's this little fuck,
I mean,
the steam room is this little ass fucking
steam room and they all fucking go in
there and I'm thinking, Oh man, maybe
it's, maybe there'll be enough room.
And I opened the door and then
I'll just fucking sit in there.
It's just a nice guy, a
packed house, whatever.
These guys will just being
in here for 10 minutes.
So me and law had go back and we'd just
sitting there and we're laughing about
the naked Asian dude,
right? Um, long story short,
these fucking jerk offs
are in this Goddamn a steam
room and they're doing that
shit with a commonality.
So fucking hot and then drinking water,
letting it all reabsorb and they just
go on back in there in there for like a
fucking half hour. So finally me lie, how
to like, fuck, we got to go with like,
you know, we want to go watch the
football. What the fuck are we gonna do?
Okay?
You know what our options,
you got all fucking 20 sweaty ball guys
in there or we go in with the nation and
in, in the sauna. So we say, well,
the naked agent guy had left.
At least we thought he did.
So we go into the sauna and who comes
fucking walking back the naked Asian.
But now he's got a fucking towel
on. Now he sits down, me and Jay,
a fucking wearing towels.
Thank God. Generally speaking,
they come from a polite culture, so he
leaves his towel on. So I'm thinking,
all right, we're good here.
We're fucking good here.
And I'm sitting there and the sauna,
the sauna isn't hot enough so
the door hasn't clouded up.
So we're just sitting there,
we can see right out the door and
all of a sudden this other naked guy
completely fucking naked,
comes walking out of the
fucking is steam thing,
just butt ass naked and is standing
there like fucking will Ferrell and old
school at the water fountain, Bending
over, getting a goddamn drink.
And me and Jay are just
laughing our asses off,
staring down into the floor going,
what the fuck is going on?
And then the naked Asian guy crosses
his fucking legs and starts cracking his
toes in the ungodly.
Sa Silence in this fucking sauna is this
fucking will Pharrel asses in front of
us. We're just like, I can't
fucking believe it, right?
So then we're sitting there and
we got this deal. Like I said,
the window is in fogged up.
Then this fucking World War Two vet comes
walking by completely fucking naked.
You know the greatest generation,
they never put a towel on.
He comes fucking walking by all
man balls and Dick and everything.
And at this point, which is fucking
does not to duty, just start laughing.
And another guy comes walking in,
he has a robe on another tub of
shit and he goes into the song,
he goes into the steam. And
finally we were like, look,
if we just don't fucking walk in there,
whenever going to be able to take a steam.
And I fucking hate us on.
I don't like the dry heat.
I like the other thing.
So we finally come walking in
there. All right. And as I walk in,
I see a place where I can sit down.
This is all fogged up and I
see how the corner of my eye,
there's someone else sitting there,
no towel on Dick and balls hanging out.
So I go to shoot the guy at dirty look
and who is it? It's the naked Asian.
I thought he left. He did. And he left,
got in the shower and then fucking
went back in there. Fucking nightmare.
So then we're sitting in there,
all right,
the will feral naked dude too.
Fat fucks in the naked agent.
And then me and Jay law had
is sitting in there, right?
And the football guys now they're running
their yaps totally killing any sorta
relaxing, just sort of
chilling out. Anyways, royal
axes you can be with fucking,
you know, naked guys all around you.
And this sitting in the, you know,
former athletes talking about sports and
some sort of benefit that they would do
it. Aw Man. Arizona was unbelievable.
Is just hookers everywhere. People,
Drake and blah blah blah blah, blah.
The kids guys telling this story.
It was some sort of benefit for kids
and in the end he goes, you know,
but it's all about the kids.
It's all about the kids.
Fucking jerk off starts the
story talking about hookers. Um,
anyways,
long short,
it finally ends up just being the two of
us in there and we're just laughing our
covered balls off.
Okay.
I, I've never seen, I've
never seen it like that ever.
Look like if you go to any sort of
fucking gym, any sort of locker room,
this going to be the naked guy,
the guy just standing there. Right.
And for you ladies out there,
you'd probably think that, well,
it's gotta be the well endowed guy
showing off his fucking God damn mule,
right. It, it, it usually isn't. It's
usually just fucking some average guy,
regular old fucking user-friendly
Dick just standing there.
You know,
like the kind of package that they always
make when they're like sculptors make,
you know, they never make like
a fucking huge Dick Statue.
They don't, they just draw a regular
old Dick. That's what it usually is.
And there's usually one of them and he'd
just sit there. Got Out is always why?
Why the fuck does he fucking not notice?
He's the only fucking naked
dude in here of yourself.
Right.
But there's always that one guy,
unless you go to the YMC a then there's
usually about three because there's
older people there.
I never seen a fucking Dick and
ball display like this in my life.
Unfucking believable. We would joke and
we were waiting for what's his face,
uncle melty to come walk in.
Um, anyways, so that's
the Dick and balls story.
So plowing ahead here.
Oh, I actually said that.
I was going to tell you a fucking
goddamn creepy story here.
Um, and I gotta wrap this
podcast up because a, I get,
you know, we'll bill, he's got
a day job now. Tell you what,
I'll read the rest of the
advertising and then I'll, uh,
I'll tell you this fucking terrifying
story that I read while on a plane.
All right,
stamps.com everybody
computers are designed to make
running a business easier,
including your mailing and shipping.
Just use stamps.com to get 24
hour access to the post office,
right from your computer. No
waiting in line, no hassles, man.
stamps.com stamps.com makes
mailing and shipping easy.
Just use the computer and printer.
You already have to get official US
postage for any letter or any package.
Print the postage directly onto
envelopes, labels, and even paper,
even plain paper.
Then hand it to your mail carrier.
There's no guesswork.
stamps.com we'll send you a digital
scale that automatically calculates the
exact postage you need
for any class of male.
You'll never have to go
to the post office again.
I use stamps.com to send out all my
Billy red state tee shirts, my posters,
whatever I'm selling right now.
Here's my last name, burpee.
You are our for this special offer,
no risk trial plus $110 bonus offer that
includes a digital scale and up to $55
free postage. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top
of the homepage and type in you are,
are that stamps.com enter Berg?
Yeah.
All right. Hulu plus everyone. Uh,
you've probably tried
Hulu on your computer.
Hulu plus is so much more with Hulu plus
you can watch shows on your schedule.
Hulu plus has all of your
favorite shows like the cosmos,
a spacetime Odyssey,
Bob's Burgers or undateable
starring Kristalina and
watch every episode of shows
like South Park, the Cosby
show, our doctor who who
lupus works on your computers,
smart TV, Roku, apple TV, Xbox.
Pretty much any streaming
device you already own,
you should be blocking off a
day to just binge with Hulu.
Plus you're in total control to
stream with these and thousands more,
as much as you want,
whenever you want. Also,
get exclusive access to stream the
criterion, criterion, collection, movies,
and Hulu plus has all of them.
All movies and kid shows our ad
free to for only seven 99 a month.
Get your shows anytime,
anywhere,
but right now I'm offering my
listeners a two week free trial.
When you go to Hulu plus.com/bill that's
a whole extra week for absolutely free.
Please make sure you use
Hulu plus.com/bill so you
get an extended free trial
and so that they know that
we sent you all right.
It helps us to keep the lights on
and it gives you a better deal.
One more time for the extended
free trial. Hulu plus. Dot.
Comp slash bill.
All right,
so the terrifying story
than I have been teasing,
teasing you guys about over the
last couple of, uh, I don't know,
minutes here. Um, so anyways,
the shows went great in San
Francisco and San Francisco and um,
we're flying back and my wife bought, um,
vanity fair I think.
Okay.
I Dunno,
it's the magazine where Robert Downey Jr
is on the cover and he looks like he's
leaning out of the port hole of a ship
dressed in a Tuxedo. It makes you think,
are they, are they remaking the
titanic? It's one of those photos.
So she says, Hey, you are a,
you know, she knows I'm a fan,
obviously guys, unbelievable
fucking actor. And she goes, hey,
this is a great article.
You ought to read it.
So I'm looking in the table of contents.
You know, it's one of those magazines.
You've got to go buy 50 pages of
advertiser advertisements before.
Um,
okay.
You know, you get to the actual
story. And the table of contents.
So I found the table of contents and
there was a story about this flight.
Okay.
Um, that was flying from
Brazil to Paris, France.
Um,
and it was talking about technology and
how this thing just basically fell out
of the fucking sky because the
pilots was the perfect storm of not
communicating, getting
confused, a malfunction in the,
the, the, the system and um,
these guys being able to recover.
Yeah,
it was uneasy.
You know what the malfunction was
basically they were flying out and the,
uh, the captain, you'd only got an hour
of sleep and he wanted to go take a nap.
They had some thunder storms or whatever,
a line of storm clouds coming up there
flying at 36,000 feet and this guy wanted
to climb up to 38 which is basically
the ceiling that that plane could fly at
safely. Cause at that point the
air is going to be too thin.
I and I would assume that the engine
has to work too hard to suck in the air,
suck, squeeze, Bang, blow, whatever the
fuck they say. How a jet engine works. Um,
and they said that the guy sounded nervous
and it was this weird thing where the
guy had like
the,
the copilot had like over 2,500 hours,
which is a significant amount of time
flying a fucking this type of an airplane.
But most of it was just sitting
there while it was on autopilot.
And this was kind of the point of,
of the um,
okay.
The article where,
how just through the,
the whole timeline of aviation back in
the day you just had stick and rudder
guys and they just flew the fucking thing.
MMM.
And then gradually they worked on these
automated systems and the pilots were
arguing against them saying
there's nothing better than
a thinking human being.
And then these automated
systems got so good that the um,
yeah,
basically accidents and everything went
through the floor and it became way
safer to fly and the
automated systems took over.
But now they've gotten to the point where,
I don't know if they're saying that
they can actually be dangerous. So
basically what happened was
that the captain went to
go take a nap and then this
other guy goes and he sits down and there
was a miscommunication as to who the
pilot in command was or who
was in command or whatever.
And they don't even have
sticks anymore up there.
They have like a joystick that you
move and then the system interprets the
movement.
Yeah.
Like not instantly.
It has to have that split second where
it interprets it and then it, it,
it acts on whatever
movement you did and um,
the sticks camp,
the joysticks can't move at the same time.
Like say if both people in both,
mmm.
Both seats up there.
If one was to move the joystick to the
right and the other was to move it all
the way to the left,
what the computer would do would
split the difference on the movement.
And I dunno,
it just,
basically all that happened
was they went into this storm
and the air was cold enough with a water
droplet said formed into ice crystals
and it blocked there. Pito Tube. The Pito
Tube is, you know, is on all aircraft.
It's just a tube that points towards the
front of the aircraft. And as you fly, as
the air is coming in it,
that's how you figure out your airspeed.
So what happened was they flew through
this ice, ice went into the Pito Tube,
it froze it up so the air
couldn't go in anymore.
So they no longer could,
they lost their,
uh,
their air speed indicator.
So they immediately lost that.
All right.
And they had the lights on in the
cabinet there out over the ocean.
They must've been
then,
it must have not been any
moonlight or anything.
So basically they couldn't see a horizon.
All right.
But all they had to do was just look at
that little plane thing that just let
you know if your level and not,
and for some reason,
when they lost their airspeed indicator,
they then lost all faith in
the entire fucking system.
And the nervous Nelly
Guy who wanted to climb,
you know, above the storm play, he
wanted to fly at the absolute height.
He's immediate instinct
was he started pulling the,
or moving the joystick back.
And if you lose all faith
in your instruments and you,
and you don't have any horizon to look at,
you don't know where the fuck you're at.
And this dude was panicking so he pulled
the stick back too far and it got to
the point where they were going to stall.
Okay.
And I forget, it's such a long fucking
article and it's really involved. So he,
they start, the other guy
starts going, no, what are
you doing? What are you doing?
Do this,
do this.
And he starts moving his thing and then
that the computer is going dual input,
meaning that they're both
moving the fucking thing.
So they start going up and
down and they basically,
the fucking nervous Nelly,
he pulls it all the way back
and they start feeling the,
the airplane starts rocking and that's
that point where you're going to stall.
Okay.
Because at that point,
the air foil is so far back,
you're going to lose lift and it's,
the air is just tumbling over the tea.
It's like all of a sudden now you might
as well have a fucking two pieces of
plywood,
like flying into the fucking wind.
So they start losing altitude.
So they see that they're losing altitude,
they're basically starting to
fall out of the fucking sky.
Um, and what kills me is in part
of this, as they started to drop,
they started to basically fall out of
the fucking sky and not recognizing the
sound of, of, of basically as the,
is the air's rolling over the fucking
win over the wings there that they were
starting,
they were going to stall.
They were so in their head looking
at the fucking screens going,
what the fuck this, this thing's
going haywire. Where are we?
They panicked and this
fucking guy kept pulling back.
He pulled back the fucking joy so far.
They almost got to get
to a 46 degree angle.
They said it was so far back that the
computer didn't even recognize that as an
input that would be possible because
no one would do it. So it stops saying,
stall that thing that you know or
pull up, pull up. It's still not,
I wouldn't say pull up there. It stopped
warning that they were going to stop.
So then it got quiet and that literally
just falling out of the fucking sky.
They were falling it like,
like 10,000 feet per minute at one point.
Okay,
so do the fucking math.
They're like 36,000 feet up to falling
10th that you've got three minutes before
you're gonna hit the deck.
Right? So these fucking guys,
that one guy goes,
no level of the nose level to know.
So he goes to level it off from 46
degrees to start bringing it back down to
something that the computer
could actually understand.
And as he brings it down again, it
starts going stall, stall, stall.
So he pulled back again. So it would
stop saying that shit. And then they're,
they're calling the captain and the
captain finally goes up there and now he's
come in in the middle of this fucking
crisis. He doesn't know what's going on.
He had, they, he at no point was
informed that the pito tube was frozen.
And at this point they had lost so much
altitude that they were down into warmer
air in it and an unfroze and it was,
the airspeed indicator was
actually fucking working,
but they had no faith in it.
And these guys were basically
falling out of the fucking sky.
And this is the scariest thing
when they get to 12,000 feet.
That was the last moment that they had
where they could have just pushed the
joystick forward and started a dive and
that they will at the speed that they
were falling,
that they would have had enough time to
try to restart those engines and fucking
pull back up again, you
know, and basically buzz the
surface of the fucking water.
And, um, they kept falling.
They were fallen at one point 15,000 feet.
Okay.
Permitted. And uh, the whole thing,
they just basically pancaked into the
ocean in a perfectly good airplane because
they're pido tubes froze.
And because they panicked and because
I guess most of their hours is just
sitting there letting something
else fly the fucking plane.
I'd never heard of this story. Uh, I
believe it's in Vanity Fair. I can,
I can't believe I just said all this
shit and I can't even tell you. And I'm,
and of course I'm reading
this on a, uh, on a flight
and I remember at the end of my flight,
this baby's face looking dude gets out.
Um, baby face to me, I'm 46.
He looked like he wasn't even 30 and
he, oh, he's doing this simple flight,
San Francisco to La. Nice quick
flight. But whatever. Yeah,
we were flying commercial airline,
we were flying all the way up there
and uh, but it was during the day.
So that was one thing that was
actually keeping me calm. I'm like,
even if the pedal tubes where the frees
up the sky can still see the horizon. Um,
but anyways, man, it was
absolutely terrifying.
And they were writing the dialogue or
the shit that they were saying and every
input that they would like,
describe what the plane was doing,
what they should've done,
and then they would then they would write
out the dialogue of what they did and
what they said, and I'm telling you to
do. My fucking heart was in my throat. Um,
so for someone who flies all
the fucking time, you know,
that wasn't a very fun article
to be reading. Um, shit,
I got to end this fucking podcast.
I didn't even get into any of the
questions for this week. A really,
really quickly, the Patriots came
back against the Bengals and a,
I know a lot of people now we're going
to go all the way to the other side. Oh,
they're gonna win the Super Bowl.
Um,
I don't think the Patriots were the
team that lost to the chiefs and I don't
think they, they were
necessarily that team last night.
I think there's somewhere in the middle.
I'm hoping they're more towards
the team that beat the Bengals.
But I think we got a couple
more brutal losses in us. Um,
you saw what happened when Reavis
went down, and I hate to say it,
but he gets injured a lot. Um, the second
he got injured, these fucking scored him.
God Damn. Two, three plays. But you
know what's amazing about Darrelle?
Revis even the fact that
he's on our fucking team and
then I'm actually cheering
for that guy who I couldn't,
I always respected,
but I hate him because he was a jet.
He's only 29 years old.
I had no idea.
It seems like he's been in the league
forever and he also looks like he's like
37. Um, all right, let's, uh, let's
plow ahead and the jets. Jesus Christ.
Jts Jess just jets. They're
in a fucking bad way, man.
They are in a bad God damn
way. I didn't see that one. I,
I watched the cowboys Texans,
which was a great game,
won and I saw a little bit of
the bills game. Big Win for them.
How about the Cleveland browns
coming back? Um, and also the saints.
A lot of great games. It was one o'clock
games. We'll fucking insane this week.
But uh,
I got a plow ahead here.
Let me just read some of your questions
and then I'll get out of here.
I'm Aussie with an idea.
Bill,
how about you shooting your next special
in Australia? You draw huge crowds here.
And when was the last time someone
shot a special down here? Um,
you know what a I did
this last one down south.
I kind of like taping them a different
place. I don't know how to fuck.
What kind of cameras do
you guys have over there?
Do you guys make movies over there?
Do you wait for us to make them for you?
That would be my big question. Do you
have the latest in fucking the technology?
Cause then maybe you know, maybe
I would die. Wasn't hey bill,
why don't you get on a plane and fly 14
hours and have jet lag and then do your
fucking special?
I'm not going to do that.
I will definitely be torn your country
though. We're looking at January. Um,
all right car dear Billy oil rag.
I want to get an old
car and learn to fix it.
Every time I asked someone what
make and model year I should buy,
they give me horrible answers.
Can you please narrow it down to two or
three cars from the late sixties to the
early mid seventies?
That would be a great car to work on.
I know there are a ton of just
looking for a place to start.
I have a little experience with
parts and repair, but not a lot.
That's why I want to dive right in
and learn. Thanks. Uh, well look,
you want to call it you want to you will
you I would ask, uh, Christopher Titus,
he could give you that answer, but I would
tell you what I would do if I was you.
All right? What I would do is I
would buy an old fucking engine,
all right? That would buy, I buy
that fucking thing that you did.
Whatever that engine mount thing is
that you can have non engine mount that
thing where you can just have
it on a rotisserie. All right.
And I would take that entire fucking
thing apart and rebuild that engine.
All right.
I might even do that a couple of fucking
times just so I got it down so that
that's how I would learn.
Don't go out and go buy a whole new,
a whole fucking car.
Just go buy a fucking engine.
Okay.
Just take the, you know, what would
you do? You'd be remove the carburetor,
then you've got the intake manifold,
then you've got the valve
covers and you got the valves.
Take all of that shit off.
Okay.
Then you're down to your fucking
year, your Pistons. Right.
I'm not good with the
electrical or anything like
that, but you go all the way.
Do you know the cam shaft all the way
down to the crank shaft and if you just
start over,
even if you just put the thing back
to fucking gether with the old shit,
although probably they'll probably have
a problem trying to get some of the shit
off. You might break something,
but I would just do that.
Okay.
And I would buy,
if you could buy a four cylinder.
I look at it the same way I
learned how to tune drums.
You start with the smallest drum
that had the fewest amount of Lug.
So it was easier to tune because you
couldn't make that many mistakes.
So I would actually,
if I,
if you can't buy an old four
cylinder engine at a junkyard,
I would buy an old six cylinder.
Then you only get six cylinders
you've got to worry about,
or you could just buy the eight cylinder
and then you've got to do everything
eight fucking times and you're
going to be that much better at it.
And I think once you fucking tear down
an engine and then just build the thing
back up, even if he did it a
couple, two, three times. Um,
I mean I think that that's the way to
go two or three times just by an old
engine, by the whole fucking kit
on how to replace everything.
Go through the hell of fucking getting
it apart and shipping stuck and frozen
and all goop together.
Get that whole fucking thing torn
apart and then rebuild the thing,
make all your fucking mistakes.
And then do it again and then do it
again and then do it again and then do it
again and then go out and buy
the fucking car you want to buy.
Yeah.
You know, I mean, dude,
you can buy an old piece of shit fucking
engine for a couple of hundred bucks
and then go buy.
What did I forget how much I was going
to do this if I ever had fucking time on
my life? I think that that's
the way to go about doing it,
rather than buying a whole God damn car
that's going to have all kinds of other
fucking problems.
If you just learn how to do basically
the heart of the goddamn engine,
I really feel like all of a sudden
the rest of the car is not going
to be nearly as intimidating. Um,
maybe the transmission could
get a little la a little scary,
but that's another thing to go out. Buy
a fucking transmission, take it apart,
rebuild it, put it back together. Do
it again. Do it again. Do it again.
Okay.
Sorry.
The battery just crapped out on me there
and now I'm fucking late and I got to
get going here. So yeah,
that's what I would do if, uh,
if you want to learn how to,
you know, how to fix up a
car, I mean that's, that's,
that's basic. What I would
do maybe if, you know,
if people who are into cars
gearheads out there, if he,
if he know a better way to go about
it, um, which I'm sure you do. Um,
but that's basic what I would do and a,
but if you aren't going to buy a car, man,
okay.
I don't know.
I would,
I would maybe one of those cars that I
always had the slant six and everybody
says like, the greatest engine isn't
the easiest thing to work on. You know,
everything's like right in a row.
All the spark plugs,
all of that stuff is like right there.
Um,
I would work with dodge darts, I think
usually had those, the lower level models.
I don't know. I'm not, I don't
know, cars to that level, but, uh,
that is on a mom, you know, I would
like to do that at some point.
Just take apart a whole engine and then
rebuild it and put it back together.
Even if I didn't put it in something,
just sell it or something and
give it to somebody else. Um,
because I think that's cool as hell.
The Nora do something like that.
If I just had the fucking time in my life.
And speaking of time,
I don't have any time here, so I
got to a, I gotta jump off here.
Thanks to everybody listened to the
podcast and thanks to everybody in San
Francisco. That was ridiculous. The
amount of people that showed up. Um,
I had a great time and I appreciate you
guys listening to the new material is
I'm working it out as I have a new
special, as I mentioned before,
coming out on Netflix December 5th
called, I'm sorry you feel that way. And,
um, oh, by the way, my, uh, new, uh,
comedy album, vinyl, um,
live and Andrew's house is available
for purchase on my website and a,
for those of you would like to donate
to this podcast and easy way to do it is
if you're going to buy
something on Amazon, uh,
just swing by [inaudible] Dot com
first click on the podcast page,
click on the link and I'll, it's a bit of
a pain in the ass. Do it if you want to.
If you don't,
I get it and it takes you right to
Amazon and I'll get credit for the,
for driving traffic there.
It won't cost you any extra
money and whatever you buy,
they give me like a percentage of, uh,
whatever. That's basically how it works.
All right, that's it. Uh, that's
the podcast. Go fuck yourselves.
I will talk to you next week.