Hey, what's going on and spill burned his
time for the Monday morning podcast for
Monday, January 15th,
2018 what's going on?
How, why, how are you?
I'm in San Francisco would still Sunday.
Uh,
the second half has just begun.
The saints go marching in
verse the Minnesota Vikings.
This saints was my pick this weekend.
I loved drew Brees going into Minnesota
and fucking having everybody crying at
the fucking mall of America
by the end of the game.
And so far the vikings
are up 17 to nothing,
although I think they just
fucking went three and out. Oh,
case key to just got put
down on his fucking Keester.
MMM.
We'll see. We'll see. You
never know what's going to
happen, you know. I mean, look,
look at the fucking Jaguar's.
The Jaguar's when just came right out,
gave the Steelers the old
right there. Fred, all of a
sudden they're running back,
twist his ankle. Right. I don't
feel, I can't put any weight on it,
man.
Right.
Then all of a sudden the Steelers come
roaring fucking back and I'm saying
[inaudible] gone. This game's over the
Pittsburgh Steelers. It's in Pittsburgh.
This shit is over. No Way. Uh, uh,
what the fuck's his name? Bryce
Bortles. I kicked, by the way,
I can't keep up with these
fucking names from the 90s. Okay.
The cases, the Bryce, the boltons
the fuck. I don't know. You know,
a lot of comics have done bits about
it, but you know, back when it was like,
you know,
Bill,
Bob fucking Steve Joe Greatest quarterback
of all fucking time at one point was
named Joe. You know Joe
Nemeth, Joe Montana,
Joe size man Joe.
Okay.
Fucking Blake Bortles I, you know,
whatever. I'm just, I'm
an old crabby fucking man.
I guess the nineties, it was really
big to name your kid after a c name,
considering all the quarterbacks.
Right. Kurt Carson case.
It's like, did Roger Clemens
fuck all these women now?
But he did that. You had like
fucking nine kids and he get Cody,
Kyle Conti, Chris,
right. They're all case.
They are all case. Yeah. Why would
you have them have their own identity?
Let's fuck it. Have their name
be about your fucking career. Um,
what do you mean you want to be a
veterinarian? Get the fuck out there.
Pick up a baseball and throw some hay.
MMM,
sorry. That was my impression of what
it's like inside their households.
Like I have any idea.
All right.
Yeah.
I have nothing against the Clemens family.
I love Roger Clemens.
You know,
fuck it.
Did some great things with the red
sox before he went to Toronto. Well,
we let them go. Right then he fucking
jumped on that poor police horse.
Jesus Christ.
You know,
that horse was wishing it was a fucking
clydesdale when he got on his goddamn
back.
Um,
okay.
Uh, just in a bad mood because
I'm in San Francisco, right?
I fucking came here yesterday
and no guy has even looked at me.
No.
I came here yesterday and it was sunny
up one of the rare sunny beautiful days
and San Francisco when it is sunny out,
when the weather's nice
can fuck with any city.
I'll even say in North America, forget
about the continental United States,
including Alaska,
Hawaii,
and some of our tributaries
like fucking Puerto Rico there.
I say Fox with any city. Okay. However,
on the usual cloudy,
rainy day,
this place, there's, there's a misery
to this fucking place. This it's cold,
wet air blowing against you as you
walk up yet another fucking hill,
you know,
nothing is ever down a hill.
It's always up a hill around a corner
to an even steeper hill, you know,
when they still have all that
mamas and Papas, you know,
although leaves are brown Hippie
vibe going out here a little bit,
even all the evil people from
fucking a silicone valley,
which I still never know
quite where that is.
It's somewhere down near like San Jose.
I just don't know where it
begins and where it ends.
But silicone to me and
my level of intellect,
the amount of books
that I've read in life,
silicone to me is and will
always be what's in fake titties.
So, you know, I don't know what
they're doing. I actually flew up here,
okay.
Uh, rented a helicopter and flew
up here with a couple people,
had a great fucking time,
picked up a couple of hours and um,
we went by this giant building that
was this huge circle and I was like,
what the fuck is that?
That looks like, I dunno,
it looks like like the Pentagon.
If it was groovy man, right.
That's was like, what is that? And my
buddy guests, he goes, it's probably,
maybe it's apple. I never seen a building
like it. It was just a total circle.
Then in the middle there
was like all of this,
like it looked like a jungle
in the middle, you know?
And if you look down you could see
the employees screaming and waving.
Don't get me Outta here. He still
alive. Steve is still alive.
I think that's what it's set up.
But I was too busy focusing on not hitting
somebody else while I was up there.
It turns out it was the apple building.
Very impressive,
very in fucking impressive structure.
And then we went right by
Stanford and saw that stadium.
I buddy was hitting me with a
trivia before we got there. He goes,
I went to a game,
I went to a Superbowl,
he claimed it was the only super bowl
ever played at a college or something like
that. Which isn't true because they
played a bunch of the rose bowl,
most of the two lane maybe. He said the
last one played it a college stadium.
Was it that, I forget what it was. Don't
blame him. Blame me for not remembering.
And uh, I was able to get
sad. I said was the, uh,
40 niners dolphins at Stanford Stadium?
Only because I had recently read that
that's where they played that game.
And because I got that right, he then
had to be like, what was the score?
I was like, I dunno. But Fulton Walker
took a kickoff back for the first time.
Super Bowl history. It's like 35, 10.
So anyways,
we fucking land at San Francisco
International Airport, which it's so,
it's so much different.
You know, when you,
and when you actually
get to see how cool it,
fuck it looks when you sitting in
the back of the tube, you know,
and you're just looking out the
back, just praying, you know,
just please get this thing
on the fucking ground.
It's different when you come up there.
It's fucking amazing.
It's expensive as shit, but
it's amazing, right? So we land,
everything's going great.
And uh,
okay.
I ended up doing this thing with the,
what is it?
The San Francisco,
uh,
sketch fest and um,
I did this,
what was it? The, uh,
who's the guy from Cuba,
Castro,
the Castro theater with Kevin Pollak.
And we just went out and,
uh, sort of an interview,
just riff and fucking around that people
came up and ask questions afterwards.
I want to thank everybody who showed
up was like one in the afternoon.
All of these people showed up.
It was a great time and a campus,
just the greatest fucking dude ever.
And we actually,
I got to do a scene with them in a
movie coming up called a front runner.
It's coming up this year.
Um,
we had a great time doing that.
And uh, you know, San Francisco,
why in a bad mood belt? The south
sounds great. It's all great.
It's all fucking great. Then
I get to my hotel, of course,
I show up right in the lady
takes my driver's license.
I forgot to not just show it to her like
she took the driver's license, right?
So then she starts clicking on a keyboard
and say, Hey, can you do me favor keen,
teeny, not type any personal
information on a license.
And she got all this fucking
attitude. She goes, I am not,
I will tell you what I'm typing in and
bubble and his whole fucking, you know,
snap to the 12th to the sex,
whatever the fucking kids say,
I want to be like Lady Lady,
you're not going to tell
me what you're going to do.
I'm going to tell you what you're
not going to do, you fucking cunt.
But of course they can't say that,
you know, I can't say that too.
I don't know what the fuck
happened to customer service,
but her fucking attitude,
the way she talked to me,
it was like I told her
how to parent or kid.
So then she looks at me up.
Of course they don't fucking have me down
cause I probably miscommunicated when
I was going to come up here anyways. I
just didn't say a fucking word. Right.
And then she went out of
her way and actually got me,
you know she didn't get it. I mean out
of the way she fucking did her job.
Fuckers still fuck her sir.
I'm going to tell you one bit like what
enough. I felt like I was getting booked.
I just, I, I fucking, I don't understand
what has happened to customer service.
So then I was just like, all right,
all right, fucking whatever. All right.
And then this hotel turns out they don't
have the two things that I need in a
hotel.
The only two fucking things I need other
than a fucking door that doesn't open
up out into the parking lot. In other
words, I'm not staying in a motel. Okay.
And all I need is some sort of gym
and an ironing board. That's it.
This hotel has, neither has,
neither has little steam fucking machine.
I don't want to steam my fucking clothes.
I practice my drum shit,
but I'm on the road.
It bring a little practice pad.
And after all these years of trying to
find a fucking table that fits right.
The ironing board was there the whole
time. He just play standing up. Okay.
And you can adjust it down.
If it's not high enough,
he just put a couple of towels underneath
and then it's at the height you need
it to be.
They don't fucking happen.
MMM.
And then lastly, I went to go
get a burrito and I fucked up.
Like San Francisco makes
the best burritos. Right?
They got the best break perfected them.
I don't know where they came from.
I believe France invented the Burrito.
I'm not sure.
MMM.
So there's this fucking,
I'm not gonna name the Burrito place,
but evidently they got a great spot in
the mission and I'm all the way down near
the fucking touristy area where they
got like rides to Alcatraz. I'm like,
I'm not fucking going
all the way out there.
I want to watch both these fucking
football games. And the one behold,
I find that there is,
there's a guy that,
there's a one that's in on everybody's
top 10 list that makes a fucking Burrito
in the mission but also has another
location down near the fishermen place.
Right. The wharf down here.
So I'm like, all right,
well I know it's probably not going to
be as good as the original cause that's
the original oven and blah blah blah
blah blah. So I fucking go to the new,
obviously the second one that
they opened, I show up. Right.
And uh,
yeah,
dislike fucking,
I dunno,
a group of Ford Front me in a group of
two in front of me and you would have
thought the amount of time it took
them to order a fucking Burrito,
you would've thought that they
were trying to like, you know,
it was like war time and they were trying
to catch the last flight out before
the, you know, the impending
regime or whatever.
It's going to send them
to a fucking labor camp.
That's like how long they
were negotiating this.
And what kills me is these four people
that took for fucking ever then the two
people behind him who had enough
time to fucking go on Youtube,
find out what's in a Burrito,
go to a fucking supermarket,
buy the shit and cook one.
That's the amount of time they had it.
They step up to the register.
It's their moment of truth to order a
Burrito and they will start looking at the
menu. Uh, we're good.
Ugh.
Fucking ridiculous. Fucking ridiculous.
So I get up there. What do you want?
Give me an original burrito.
Chicken
chips and salsa in a water to go cash.
Thank you.
Step aside over,
how hard is that?
You know what it is is somewhere in the
last century it became illegal to punch
somebody in the back of the head when
they were taking too long and align.
And now everybody, they just, you know,
they just a little too comfortable.
They just a little too comfortable.
So I'm standing there and uh,
you know, now in behind the fucking couple
that you know, over at the salsa line,
Salsa line, salsa, salsa line and uh,
I'm behind them again and it's taking
them forever to get fucking salsa.
Fucking looking around and they're
looking at other people. It's like,
use your fucking braid. Mild, medium hot.
Okay.
The fuck
damn saints.
Or when the saints go
marching in but up up,
oh, oh, plenty of time left. No,
there isn't.
What am I talking about?
I thought that was fucking one
18 into the third quarter. Well,
I guess there's plenty of time left,
right?
This is the way the game is
played nowadays. It's like,
do they go for two here?
There's only a quarter in a minute.
13 left. Kick the fucking extra point.
Um,
yeah.
Jesus Christ. That guy just had a
soul patch on the back of his head.
Wow. You know, tough.
You have to be to have that because
if somebody just how hard it would be,
do not tell that guy how fucking
annoying that. It's like, dude,
I just want to fucking, can you
just grow it out? A shave it off.
MMM.
All right. Touchdown Saints
touched my prediction lives.
This is such a disturbing commercial
with this guy falls off the cruise ship.
This is one of my biggest fucking
fears in life. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Just being in the fucking ocean,
praying for hypothermia
to set it before summer,
something comes up to you and
just takes a bite out of you.
Can you imagine when you see that
fucking shark fin? Just break the water,
you know, and you know,
you smell the thing.
Fucking wild animals. You could smell
them from a mile away to the point.
I don't understand how
they're able to kill anybody.
You know?
You didn't.
You ever go to the fucking sue when
you just smell those God damn lions?
I guess every, everything
stinks out there, you know? Um,
yeah.
Anyways. Then they just leave.
The guy in the fucking ocean
fucking really bothers me. I this gotta
be somebody complaining about that,
you know,
once a year that seems to
happen or every couple of years,
like somebody goes on a honeymoon and
their spouse fucking falls overboard.
You know,
I gotta look that up. How many fucking
times? What do you, what are the odds?
Are the odds higher on a honeymoon
or FTE been married for awhile?
Like how many times somebody who's like
fucking thrown his spouse overboard,
you know, and if it's anywhere
near the number that I think it is,
I want to know why it
doesn't have its own Hashtag.
I think we need to start
a Hashtag on Twitter.
Let me just do fucking three seconds of a
research here.
Spouse,
how do you spell spouse?
I just spelt spas,
spouse, what would I look up? Your spouse,
dead
cruise ship.
Uh,
significant other question mark.
What a passionate your dyes
and see what you need to know.
Oh my God, what do they do? Do they
have a burial at sea? You know,
with the Carnival cruise line flag and
they try to make it look official is just
sitting there looking at
fucking Gilligan. And Gofer. Um,
so the guy's name go for the
guy became like a senator.
Husband pleads not guilty and wife's
cruise ship killing. Oh my God.
Geez. If they, if they figure out, ah,
can you imagine that?
Wow. That's, that's just
cruel and unusual punishment.
It bad enough you killed somebody.
The fact that you would send them
to that of a lonely, brutal death.
I Utah Man who allegedly brutally murdered
his wife last month while onboard and
Alaska. Oh, he just,
he killed her on, yeah.
Fourth.
All right,
well Jesus,
this and fucking serious music
dude who compose that, hey,
this guy killed his wife.
This guy killed his wife on a fucking
cruise ship and this Guy Jay, we need,
we need music for that. And
that guy, he'd just come,
I can't get back to the fade in that war.
That was what the Jimmy page
army a fucking guitars there.
Can you imagine that?
You wanted to write the next stairway
to heaven and now you just write in
fucking music, you know, that fits
people dying on a fucking cruise.
Okay. This dude is accused of first degree
murder in the death of his 39 year old
wife.
Uh,
she must've fucking choked her and
shuffleboard or something. I'm sorry.
A Kennis wife was found dead in
her cruise ship cabin on July 25th.
That's the couple had a domestic dispute.
Oh my God. D there's, you know, they
should throw this guy overboard.
Jesus Christ
said blood was spread throughout
the room on multiple surfaces.
Who's immediately detained by ship
security in a witness said that the,
the defendant allegedly told him
she would not stop laughing at me.
Jesus Christ
waterfall. She ridiculing him. You know,
it's funny if this was
the other way around,
I think the woman goes free if,
if she just said he was fat shaming her,
like she put on some baby weight
or something like that and he just,
he wouldn't stop laughing at me and
I just made me feel like I was small
each year over 4,000 men
laugh at their recently,
not pregnant wise,
causing them to feel bad
about themselves. Um, okay.
He had been acting terrible all night.
The source claim adding at some point
that evening. He, yeah, she wouldn't stay.
Somebody not stop laughing at you.
You go for a walk.
What if,
wow,
what was going that that guy is not
just a straight up fucking psycho,
you know
like what the fuck was going on?
How many movies could you
make out of that relationship?
Like if,
if that guy never did anything wrong
in his life and she was just so fucking
sadistic, sadistic and hits,
so gotten into his fucking head
that her just laughing at him, Pete,
that he fucking snap like that. You know,
I'm just playing the other side.
I'm just playing devil's advocate here.
Interception Sal.
Window saints.
Go marching in yet that
day. Dot. Bada boom.
How annoying am I? Do the fucking
person next to me. Cascade them.
Case, case and drew.
Those are the quarterbacks
used to be Joe Verse Phillip
Roger Verse Terry.
What was some of the great rivalry names?
Yeah,
Dan Verse Kenny.
Dan Fouts first, Kenny Anderson
and that fucking freezing bowl. Oh,
we definitely stepped out of bounds.
You can see right there. That's exactly
what happened there. You can't see any
grade between the white wide gay scheme.
Got out a giant IPAD.
It's going to play a little donkey
Kong put on a hat. There you go.
Hugs all around like the game
has been one on the safe side.
Is it made of the saints?
The uniforms look a little cheap.
I don't know what's going on.
[inaudible] they take some
stripe away in their shirt.
It looks like they should be playing on
half a field inside a hockey arena. Um,
I right drill braise.
He's got the ball.
Hey hands that off and that
guy immediately is tackled.
What a waste of a play.
One or two to go in the
fucking third quarter.
You want me to announce the rest
of the third quarter for you?
Some of you guys like when I do this shit.
All right.
Yeah.
Number 29 he's upset. What
is he upset about? I Dunno,
but a guy with fucking night vision
glasses is talking to them. Listen,
I just got from the gun range. I didn't
see what happened, but I believe in you.
Okay.
29. What the fuck is he doing out there?
That's a running back number, isn't it?
Yeah.
Maybe he's mad at,
maybe he's mad at case.
Okay,
get off my case.
Keenum sorry.
Jubilees drops back to pass
over the fucking middle.
When those sates get a fucking first down.
Woo.
Why don't I give a shit about this game?
It's literally just cause I told Paul
Versey that I thought the states are going
to win.
That I need this to happen to fill me
up in life because I'm a married guy and
you know, and the compliments, you know,
they're, they're on it. They're on a, Oh,
we're, we're on. I'm on
like a compliment ration.
I get one a season and
there's only one season in La.
I used to get four a year when I
lived in New York. Now I'm out in La.
I get about one. Um, how'd he
get that job as water, water guy?
Like how do you know who's
fucking thirsty? Nobody
ever points to their mouth.
You just kind of walk up. You
stick it, you know. All right.
I swear to God,
the Black Guy.
And this commercial looks like they stuck
his head on like an eight year old's
body.
Yeah.
Um,
although I do like this commercial
build, nobody gives a fuck. Most
people aren't even watching this now.
They don't even know what
you're talking about.
You're literally doing common commentary
for fucking Youtube video that doesn't
exist while they're listening
to your podcast. Get back
on the fucking game here.
Um, fucking Steelers. What are
the, what is what this steel is?
How many times are they going to look past
the opponent that week? That's, that's,
that's what they say it out there.
They're saying that they focus too much
on the New England patriots because you
know, who's kidding who they beat the
Patriots earlier this year, you know?
Yeah.
That was a touch. I don't know. You know
what I don't understand about, you know,
whether it's a catch or
whether it's not a catch,
is the fact that the ground can't
cause a fumble if you're running.
But if you're, it can, it can cause
an incomplete pass San how it works.
I Dunno,
I have no idea. But I liked that
commercial. I just saw that guy was like,
practice in speed skating,
like in his living room.
That'd be like the latest
thing people will get.
Rather than reading about nutrition,
they'll literally spend like
fucking 10 grand on that thing
and then they'll have some sort of app
where they can project it onto their TV,
where they can, you can be, you know,
in different speedskating
arenas around the fucking world.
I saw this picture today on the Internet.
It just fuck it.
And it made me feel so God damn
old. It was this woman, right?
Where's that place where people go
to vacation? Right? It's like the,
the ocean looks absolutely perfect.
And then Z, these grass, like the,
these huts and the hover out
over the water, you know,
one tsunami and everybody's dead. Right?
But it looks like absolute paradise.
Okay. And the picture of
this woman, she's in a thong,
right leaning on one leg.
So her butt cheeks sticking out and she's
looking at the huts and over her head,
she, she's making, you know, those,
that stupid thing where you
make the heart with your hands.
She's still with that. You know, and
that it made me feel so fucking old.
It's like what even happened to just go
into a fucking unbelievable place and
just geeking out and taken a picture of
yourself and you have that look on your
face like you can't believe you.
They're like,
she literally used that paradise
to enhance her whole fucking like,
okay,
I don't know what the word is.
Her Harness,
I dunno,
the Selfie just,
it just makes everybody act like a dude
who doesn't know how to behave when they
get their road show. In other words,
they behave like myself. What's going on?
I stepped out of bounds, eight
yards. He picked up eight yards. Oh,
I'll tell you right now.
You know what I tell you?
Who's going to make a big
a lot of fucking money?
Whoever owns the Kleenex
store in the mall of America,
it's my prediction that every one of
these Minnesota fans are going to fucking
at the end of this game,
or they're all going to go down to the
mall of America and they're going to go
into the Kleenex store. They gotta
get their own fucking, you know,
Kleenex with their own initial on it
because everybody's fucking special now.
And you could take a Selfie,
but how sad you are actually,
you know it would be amazing is if
the vikings go to the Superbowl, okay.
And they play a home game.
Ah,
ah.
Oh.
When no saints go marching in there
down to the fucking two yard line.
You guys like Pete Fountain, okay.
Huh? Put on the old gray bonnet.
I love Pete. Phone. Fucking
always had a killer drummer,
right?
Played the shit out of the clarinet.
Okay.
You know what I mean? And he's never
had any sexual harassment scandals.
Um, anyways, plowing ahead
here. Oh, Jesus Christ.
This fucking guy. There's a guy,
he's hurt. Now what happened?
What happened to the guy? Does he
got to go inside the tent? Well,
thank God there's an 80 year old bald
white guy to help him off the field.
The dude was so short,
he couldn't even lean on him.
He's probably going to
have a separated shoulder.
By the time he gets over to that
little fucking a little pop tent,
they put them in.
Okay.
Um,
hey,
I think I found the MP three player that
now that I'm seeing this poor bastard
with the umbilical cord hanging on,
I'm getting out of the apple world,
right as I said that, that Weirdo just
stared at me in the galaxy commercial.
Like he knew I was going to fucking do it.
Um,
I'm going to get a new, uh, NP, I'm
going to go with one of those. Sonys
yeah.
You know, and I want to tell you guys
the exact model so you can be like, dude,
oh my God. Really? You're going to buy?
Yeah, I am. I am. Because
I have a bunch of music,
but I didn't get on fucking a apple
and those round building costs.
Okay.
But the forest in the middle with a
reeducate their employees that want to ask
for more money or maybe pay the poor
bastards that put together their products
so they don't jump to
their fucking deaths. Uh,
how crazy it would be if they still
advertise on this podcast after that. Um,
yeah, I want to fucking get out of
that world. I want to, I'm like,
I still want to use this shit,
but I suppose I don't like how they
were all there. Like fucking a,
this is our shit over here. I should
only works with our, with our shit.
None of about shit works with other
people's Shit. Why don't you just shit,
you got to buy our other shit to use
our shit. Fuck people's other shit.
We're going to fucking own everything.
I don't say, wait, what is your problem?
How many billions of dollars to you?
I swear to God at that point. Um,
I know a promoted like that,
I know promoted like that he wants
to make all the money, you know,
it's not enough that he's
making the most money.
He wants to make all the money
and it actually gives them joy
when, when other people, uh, when
other people's, uh, you know,
other promoters in his town are
not doing well, he'll just say, oh,
did you hear about so and sold?
They bought I, I took a bath.
Okay.
And I'd be like, ah, I bet that makes
you happy. Oh, I fucking love it. Um,
anyways,
I guess I never gave you guys a Hashtag.
Yeah.
Uh, for the cruise ships. Why don't
you guys come up with one? Oh,
here comes the tent. The pop up tent.
Dick's sporting. Good. All right,
let's see a dick. What happened? Did he
hit your left ball? You're right, ball.
All right,
we're going to freeze it here.
We're going to do a little fucking put
a little desk, sit next on it. And a,
I think it'd be all right. All
right. Drew Brees hands the ball off.
A knee guy runs into everybody. Evidently
there was supposed to be a hole there.
You know,
when I was a kid,
I thought that running backs rather
than running around the outside,
the reason why they ran in the middle's
cause they thought they'd get famous for
trying to do something so impossible.
Um,
what do you guys thinks going to happen
here? Actually, you already know,
I say that they're going
to score on third goal,
right?
Unless they try and run
it three fucking times.
How about a little play action fake here?
Drove for the love of fucking Christ.
Oh, by the way, congratulations
to Liverpool, Liverpool.
Be fucking man city.
Cause you guys didn't realize I've been
paying attention a little bit to the
premier league.
That soccer for everybody here at north,
it's America. Drew Brees throws
a dam and then say it's go ma.
Hmm. It's fucking 17
too, mother fucking 13.
Oh right. Okay. Case Kate Cascade.
[inaudible] he's on the case. Kanombe
they must do a bunch of shit like that,
right? Anytime. Uh, you know,
they always have the punch, right?
You must do a bunch of those things.
Jesus Christ. This is, that's
becoming a tale of two halves.
It comes drew Brees.
He's going to break their hearts.
I'll tell you right now
then, there, right now,
the last ride on the rollercoaster
at the mall of America is happening.
There's an overall sadness that is
going to descend on that mall right now.
There's a bunch of people
that do not give a fuck. Okay?
Two white guys trying to do
a cool handshake. They, uh,
I don't know what they just did their,
some sort of jerk off fucking motion by
drew Brees. Has He gave the okay sign?
You know, these are the times. Is
it okay that I'm stroking your deck?
I think that that's what that meant.
I think that was very
progressive by drew Brees. Um,
all right.
If you could tell I'm doing this thing
early and I've yet to get any of the
advertising. I don't have any fucking,
uh, any of the questions or anything.
So at some point I'm going to have to
fucking hit pause or I could text my
fucking guy here to send me the
bullshit. Right. That could happen.
That could happen. Right.
Let me hit pause. You don't
listen this fucking crap. Oh,
do ya Johnny. Oh, do you?
The fuck is going on with the
Black Hawks this year. Let me,
let me, I got to hit pause and not put
you through the shit. All right, I'm back.
Oh,
you know what I,
I was gonna say is if Minnesota wins
this game and then goes to the Superbowl
and uh, I'm actually a vikings
fan from way back in the day,
to be honest with you. I don't know why
I'm, I'm just being a Douche, right? I,
like I said, I just predicted this upset.
I don't care if the vikings went, ah,
right up the middle for first dad,
they're teen oh two to go in the
game. He's not, and he's not in like,
they didn't just give up
14 points in a row. What a,
every fucking guy now acts like they
just reinvented football. Look at this.
All those people blocked for him.
And then when there was finally a fucking
guy who could tackle them, then he did.
And this guy gets up like he's, he'd
ever see Jim Brown get up fucking nod.
Oh, the old man, this is, this
is what you sound like it,
the closer you get to death, you know,
he's like, well, why isn't it went away?
It used to be case Keenan.
He is on a strict no passing diet right
now. They saw that last one. They like,
fuck this guy just handed off. Now why
aren't you nodded? Okay. You're not. No,
I don't know
if I've got stuff for it
that God damn line everybody.
Anybody makes a good play at that point.
At the name of the back of the Jersey.
Anytime they fucking don't make a play
that looking for a flag or they run off
the field. Anyways, if I can
get through this God damn point,
if Minnesota actually goes to the God
damn Superbowl, it's a fucking home game.
Okay.
All right.
Everything there is purple.
There's no way you got to have
like a prince themed halftime show.
Do you think he would have played it and
think he would have come to the woulda
had to have prince come back?
Look at that fucking throat case kingdom
shaken off the interception of the
saint. Say it's not a catch. They say
it's not a catch. Right. Says, oh my God,
I can't even deal how fucking great and
it's driving me crazy case keyed and
everybody stopped shouting, settle
down. This is a great fucking throat.
Oh, he just drops it right in there.
I Dunno. A little bit of wobbly there.
In the end, he caught it. But
did he catch it long enough?
Case Kingdom gets to the, they get
it or not in time. Not In time.
The challenge flag
this degenerate gambling.
Looking at head coach. It's fucking
wife probably cries herself to sleep.
That's such a terrible thing to say.
Why would I say that? All right.
He's on the ground. He has it. He has it.
He has it. He has it. He still has it.
If they call this not a fucking catch.
Look at a shit. All right. There you go.
That's a catch. He's got it. He's got it.
He's got it. He's got it. He's got it.
He's got it.
What are they going to look at?
Jesus fucking Christ.
How long do you have to have it?
Oh my God. Now I got to see this
replay. 58 fucking time that he,
as you see right there daily as
it against his naval and his, his,
his fucking happy trail.
Um,
it's got pleading his case.
Take back your Red Hanky.
Uh,
all right.
I know you guys do you guys,
I don't think you want
to fucking love this.
I've really limited my goddamn audience
here. Let's talk about fucking,
let's limit it even more and I'll talk
to my six British fans over there.
Um,
man city.
Oh fuck.
Oh Fuck
Jesus Christ. It was like a full fucking
bottle of water and it's heavy on too.
And I fucking hate that shit.
Evian.
There's minerals in it. Yeah, I can
taste it. It tastes fucking weird.
Okay.
The water rushed through a plastic rock.
Why does it taste so fucking awful? I,
I fucking hate every yard.
MMM.
Anyways, this was to be
like the best bottled water.
It tastes like shit. I done. How do
I know it's from the French Alps?
I answering anything. Poland
spring to Disani smartwater.
I'll drink that box water.
I don't give a shit even though it tastes
like you're drinking out of a shoe.
Oh, that fucking wet cardboard. I
know it's better for the environment,
but Jesus Christ,
ugh.
You know what's the worst was when you
were a little kid and you drank out of
the garden hose and you didn't
realize it was sitting in the sun.
You'd had that fucking hot
blast of Stale fucking water.
They'd probably been in there for a week.
Jesus Christ.
So you know, they've taken out your
fucking small intestine. Um, all right,
let's look up this man city shit.
All right, man. City Man City lost
four to three, to Liverpool. Now.
Now for those of you who live in
the United States, a Merker of Marg,
um,
man city evidently was fucking
undefeated the whole year.
I guess that's really difficult.
It's difficult to do on any sports,
but I wasn't sure with soccer just seems
like you score one goal and the game's
over. But I will tell you lately
they four to three, seven goals.
You've got to love that.
Got a fucking love that they lost the
Liverpool homer, the fucking Beatles.
That's all I know.
Yeah,
that's all I know about touch
shit. Oh, let's talk about,
let's talk about dot. Hey,
Dani fog case. Kate, I'm sacked.
Oh No. He got the ball up,
Donald fucking Trump. I
got to say something, man,
that was a low,
that is a low point in modern United
States history and that's fucking saying
something.
Okay.
You just can't, uh, you know,
you know, you just can't, you can't
feel it. It's a fairly linear,
not even apologize and say, you know, I
shouldn't have said it that way, but blah,
blah, blah. That was just a fucking like,
yeah.
I don't know why people
still sticking by the guy.
What ea she tell it is.
All right.
This is number two.
Guy Number four is going to hold the ball.
The little skinny guy, he kicks
the ball right down fucking metal.
It was one at one horn flash. What?
What is the Minnesota Vikings?
What is this saints
Guide bitching about now?
Right?
What is he complaining about?
I'll tell you right now, okay.
If a fuck that fucking apnea,
she would've said no catch. Yes.
You would've guessed you want.
If you just like my wife,
you just like my fucking wife.
Okay.
Do you know you're fat? When you can
see a Manta Sunday. The windbreaker. Oh,
he was saying the guy was down.
All right. Nobody cares. Bill.
This is one of the worst podcasts
I've ever done. I apologize. Okay.
And I'm sure you guys will
let me know. All right. Oh,
so the burrito ended up getting like that.
It just sucked.
Wasn't wrapped tight or I guess I'm
supposed to keep it in the foil.
I have no fucking idea. And then the
chicken was like overcooked. You don't,
this is what happens. This is what
happens when you go to a city and you go,
you know what?
These people are known for this.
And then you as a tourist
don't know where to go.
And you just go out and get one and then
you go back to your city with the, the,
the wrong information saying,
I went there, their burrito's
sucked. It didn't take,
I could make a better breeder than
that. You know, that's like, you know,
people go to Chicago, New York and they
say that their pizza sucks. It's like,
well, who did you hang out with?
Will you with people from the city?
Did they tell you where the fuck
to go? Um, Oh, you know what?
I want it to look up because people
are sitting there saying, oh,
they got it when peach fucking Donald
Trump. And it's just like, well,
they impeach Bill Clinton. He got
impeached. I was like, Holy Shit.
Okay.
Hey, he's going to have to leave.
And then he, he didn't, he just,
why didn't Bill Clinton leave?
And then I'll just write in
peach, right, that she gave me.
How you spell impeached.
There you go. Impeached.
If Bill Clinton, why did he finish
Cape Bill Clinton was impeached.
Why did he finish up? I don't understand
how he could have been impeached,
but he did not leave office.
All right.
Being impeached doesn't guarantee the
person in peach has to leave office.
Here's some historical examples.
Uh,
the problem with your question is he was
not impeached in a way to have to leave
office.
I see.
You really don't understand the difference
between impeachment and having to
leave office now. You didn't have
to be that fucking conti about it.
Not True. He wasn't peached for
a public official in peach. Well,
this is just people arguing.
Bill Clinton was acquitted.
The Senate did not reach the two thirds
majority needed to fully process is
impeachment.
To further break it down,
Clinton was impeached by the House on
two charges. The first being perjury,
the second being obstruction
of justice following this,
he was acquitted by the Senate.
Okay.
The impeachment process takes
place in two steps. First,
the president has to stick a cigar
in somebody pussy. No, that's right.
First the president, it has to be
impeached in the of Representatives.
That is the equivalent of an indictment.
Ah.
Then the president has tried in the Senate
with the chief justice of the United
States presiding, oh, this is
why all the lefties are saying,
we got to fucking kill these elections
in October so we can get Trump out.
I was going,
what the fuck are they talking about?
So then they could actually indict him
in the house and then impeach him in the
Senate.
Yeah.
It requires a two thirds vote of the
Senate to remove and impeachment.
You think if he got impeached,
right?
If it went to the Senate
and he got impeached,
like I actually think that he would
leave before they took the vote.
He would get on his own fucking plane and
he would just leave and he'd be on the
like just so his ego could
handle it. Like, you know,
you're not going to come walking in here
and have me pack up my shit and have me
escorted out like I just get fired at,
you know, some fucking corporation.
All right?
I haven't been,
I don't take the amount of time that I
take to comb my hair over the top of my
fucking head to be treated this
way. All right. Seven deadly.
They fucking didn't
think the guy was down.
Yeah.
I'm literally commentating a game that
you already know the results of that
you're not watching. This is the
stupidest fucking thing I've ever done.
All right? I'll be honest with you.
I'm just, I'm fucking lonely. Okay.
I just felt like talking to somebody can,
can you guys just be there for me?
All right. The fucking fucking guy
did his God damn job. He hit it twice.
Hey, how about a round of applause for
the person who's making the field goal
kickers, helmets. Now they finally,
you know, they gave him like two bars.
Okay.
You know I went back in the day,
they just had that like Fred Cox,
Joe size been all those guys just had
that one bar across the front of their
fucking,
I mean I dunno.
I Dunno how those people
survived. All right. You know it.
This is going to be a
mercy pause right here.
I'm going to just wait for the all the
information to come from my fucking
podcast so I can actually
do this. Okay. Yes.
We'll send over in five getting
advertising now. Alright.
I still got advertising.
Um, all right, I'll talk
to you two seconds here.
Okay.
All right. I'm back and I got all the
materials I need here. By the way,
all when does say it stayed fucking
scored again? They were up by one point.
That's where I am in the game.
They just,
Vikings just got a pass interference
call with number 19 or some shit on the
vikings who has the smallest shoulder
pads I've ever seen in my life.
Remember the eighties,
how big fucking shoulder pads were?
What do they make those things out of now?
I guess if everybody has small ones,
then it's a fucking, it's a
fair game. Oh, by the way.
So
basically what happened with Bill Clinton
was he got indicted in the House of
Representatives and then when
it went to the Senate, the,
I needed two thirds of the vote and none
of the Democrats voted to impeach him.
So that's how we got off the liberals
look the other way with the sexual
harassment.
And you know,
it's all just politics.
It's not like one side's better than
the other. If it was a Republican,
they would have voted the,
oh,
they all would have voted the
exact fucking opposite way,
except maybe one or two fucking
actually decent human beings. Um,
Eh, the result. But, so
Bill Clinton got acquitted,
but he did lose his license to
practice law because of that.
That fucking unbelievable
unfuckable would have. Oh, I,
one of the hardest things I think is
to become a lawyer. Just all like,
like trying to pass the
bar and all of that.
You go through all of that shit and
then what do you do? You stick a cigar.
It's some fucking woman's pussy. That is
it. Your wife and then you lie about it.
And then all that studying goes
right out the window. Jesus Christ.
I love cigars and I love women,
but I'm telling you if I learned anything,
you got to keep them separate.
All right?
Okay, let's do some advertising
here. Uh, three reads. All right,
honey.
That's the name of this new company.
There is an amazing free
browser extension called honey.
Honey,
could you that millions and millions
of people use every day to save money.
Honey is the word.
The world's most popular money saving
browser ed on it works on chrome,
Firefox, safari, all the major
browsers. And it's always free.
I have no idea what it is. Oh, it's
his money saving browser. Okay.
It only takes two clicks to add oh,
honey to your browser.
Uh,
when it starts working in the back,
it starts working in the
background right away.
When you shop honey scans and tests,
millions of coupon codes all over the
Internet to find you the biggest discount
on everything you buy online.
Well that's cool.
No more googling random coupon codes
that don't end up working. Yeah,
I was trying to buy it. Oh, they
fucking Minnesota hit a field goal
case Kane and let them write down
the goddamn feels a minute. 29 left.
And they got drew Brees though when
the states. Anyways, I was trying to,
the some fucking old lady
came get up for it. Um,
I tried to buy a Jersey for my nephew
and I filled out where I lived,
all my credit card information, all of
this shit. And then when I hit process,
they're like, Eh, it's not in stock.
And then they kept all my information,
the bricks. So, uh, why
don't you try out honey?
But here's the best part of it.
Whenever you're ready,
the checkout honey automatically
applies the best coupon to your cart.
There is no reason not to add
honey to your browser. It's free.
It will always save your
cash on everything you were
going to buy anyways. Yeah,
this a no brainer.
If you're not using honey when you shop,
you're missing out on free money,
salary free money.
You're throwing away money
is what you're doing. Okay,
and honey
to your browser for free.
Right now@atjoinhoney.com slash
bird that's joined honey.com/burr
the saints do not return minute 29 to go.
How the fuck did that kick off?
Take no time but guy caught it. That
must have been a split second, right?
Simply safe. Uh, eight bill,
stop using her pussy as a
human dog. Uh, simply safe.
Studies show that security
systems deter burglars.
It's a fact,
but there is still a burglary burglary
every eight seconds in America,
burglars don't give up. Just because
someone's house has a security system,
they find a house that isn't protected.
That's why securing your home with simply
faith is truly is truly a necessity.
Simply safe is ridiculously smart and
its senses and it's sensors will protect
every point of access to your home.
Plus,
if a burglar so much as tries to
break in an ear shattering siren,
we'll let them know that the place that
the police are already on their way.
Well, let's hope it's not your fucking
old neighbor checking in on you.
They might have a heart attack.
Okay,
drew Brees, drew Brees, and complete.
Okay.
Best of all simply saves 24 seven
monitoring is just 1499 a month to get ear
splitting security.
They'll never lock you in your long
term contract with simply safe.
You'll even get a 60 day
money back guarantee,
so there's no reason not to try it today.
Protect your home and family was simply
safe by going to simply safe bird.com
today. That's simply saved
bird.com to order today,
you're simply safe home security system.
Simply safe. [inaudible] dot com s.
I. M P L, I. That's how you spell simply,
simply safe burg.com why is
it always earsplitting? Why
can't they have it? Like,
just why don't they just have it sound
like somebody really tough, you know,
like something breaks and he just have
some guy, you know, really deep voice,
Bitch. Get my good right. That wasn't
a tough voice. You know what I mean?
Somebody just says some crazy shit.
Yeah,
I'm going to fucking murder you, right?
You said the creepiest voice ever.
You just whisper that. Have that. That's
your alarm. I'm going to murder you.
All right. Well maybe this is
what it, this baby. It fucking,
the alarm goes to your phone and then
you see the person breaking in and then
you start talking all this shit like
you're in there and you're crazy.
You'll be all brave
because you're not home.
Yeah,
I see you and your green shirt. You
motherfucker. I will like you on fire.
You know some crazy shit
instead of, yeah. All right.
stamps.com everybody here's
a new year's resolution.
You can actually keep a add stance,
stop,
add stance Dotcom to your business
and save a ton of time and money year.
Um, I use stamps.com any
nice fucking defensive play.
I use stamps.com anytime I'm sending
out my posters and I'm going to whore
myself out after shows and deal
with cougars groping me, uh,
which of course goes unchecked because
they're women and they're not held
accountable for their actions.
Plus stamps.com has postage discounts
you can't get at the post office.
Not to mention it's a fraction of the
cost of those super expensive postage
meters.
stamps.com send you a digital scale that
automatically calculates exact postage.
You will never overpay or underpay
for poaches postage. Again,
I use stamps.com be club because I already
told you why and I if I can figure it
out, you can figure out cause I'm a
moron and right now you too can enjoy the
stamps.com service with a special offer
that includes a four week trial plus
drew Brees throwing fuck
postage and a digital scale.
Ready for a happier new year.
Ready for happy new year.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburgerburthatstamps.com
enter
burr.
Alright, number three, Bobby a bear.
They brought it back from the fucking
retirement is loosening up is what he
needs to wear that number.
Okay.
He's fucking loosening up his leg here.
To kick a fucking field goal, which
would win it. Oh my God. Oh my God.
What's my prediction? True. Are these poor
viking fans going to get fucked again?
Are they going to be crying at
the mall of America? How much?
How many yards does he need?
They need like another 15 yards.
Oh.
Oh,
okay. Here we go. The
Vikings are one play away.
Yeah.
Unless this guy comes in and just
kits like a fucking 70 yarder. Oh,
you got to catch that.
You got to catch that.
Okay.
Hey, fuck you. I want to
throw it was right there.
Yeah,
drew Brees.
Okay.
Oh God. The coach has on his reading
glasses. He's already in the f off season.
It's going to read catcher
in the rye or some shit.
Okay.
Come on man. Come on Dro.
Why do I give a shit? I, I,
the vikings have had a drought.
The the states one in 2010
I just want to be right.
I said the states are going to win.
I apologize to everybody in Minneapolis,
Saint Paul Duluth.
Oh No.
First Down fucking fun.
The sates.
Oh my God,
I have to turn this up.
Okay.
Oh my God.
He's in the guys feel
goal rage. Oh No, no.
Yeah.
You know what's funny? I Love Minneapolis.
I don't want you people to be sad.
I was just joking around.
Oh,
case Kate and puts it head on and takes
it off. Puts it on, holds his head.
How am I ever going to talk to
my loved ones again? Holy Shit.
Ten nine eight Jesus Christ.
Route. What are we doing? I learned
from Tony Romo, Hasa play clock. You
fucking moron. Alright, 40 seconds to go.
I was like, Jesus, he's nonchalant. I
learned from Tony Romo. You want to,
you want to kick it
with four seconds left.
I think it's four seconds left cause then
you don't have to kick off like that's
how long it feel gold takes.
But with Tony Romo after it's done,
Bob Lynn it, it probably takes 11 seconds.
Oh, come on. He shits on Deion Sanders.
I can give him a little fucking rough
time. I love Tony Romo, by the way.
All right.
Practice. Tee you alright? He kicked
it. Okay. I put it into the net.
37 seconds to go. Oh my God. Is this
the mall of America?
God,
why didn't I invest in the clean
tech store at the mall of America?
One of the dumbest things I ever did.
Blitz and true
breeze. Fucking picked
it up. It's a catch. Oh,
I'm going to talk so much
shit. [inaudible] I'm
going to talk so much shit.
Diversey what did I say? I called it. Oh,
he's a ball was bobbling.
Now he got it. He got it.
Did he catch it enough times for it to be
a kid and all that. Dot. Nope. Nope. No.
That's not a catch.
The little tail was hanging down
in the bottom. See, now here go.
He goes all the fucking drama.
This is going to be 20 fucking
minutes of this shit. All right.
I'm not even looking at this goddamn
game at this point. That is not a catch.
The vikings come.
You gotta throw the challenge flag.
Did the vikings coach just
come from the gun range?
What with those God damn glasses.
Okay.
That I duh Duh Duh.
You can see the point of the ball
touches the ground or right there.
Yeah.
It's not a catch.
Everybody knows it's not a catch for
the fucking love of Christ. All right.
This is hilarious. The first letter that
I got this week, there's the water guy.
Now how did he know the guy wanted the
water down his back when that be annoying.
Top of fuck is the name of this one.
Dear Billy Booze Hound.
I had been a big fan of the podcast
and you stand up for several years now.
I am writing you to tell you that I
owe you a lot. Oh Jesus. Look at this.
It was about a year ago.
I heard you first say that every now and
then you would look into the mirror and
call yourself a tub of fuck.
I do.
I thought it was hilarious and it made me
realize I was at top of fuck as wealth.
Look at that.
We're bonding.
MMM.
Fucking sound. ICLOUD preferences. I don't
know. My password and you won't give me,
you won't give me a second chance, so
I don't want to update it. All right.
Since last February,
I have woken up every morning and
told myself that I am a tub of fuck.
I made my phone wallpaper,
a picture of me when I was at my heaviest
two 55 so whenever I unlock my phone
there was a reminder of the tub of
fuck I am and no longer want to beat.
That's great. I'm proud to announce
that I have lost 70 pounds in
11 months. Dude, that's
awesome. And honestly,
I owe you a big thanks for giving me
the motivation to do this because of you
and Joe Rogan, probably more Joe
Rogan. He's actually a shape.
I have done a lot of things in the
last year that have taken me out of my
comfort zone. You've been
a great inspiration in my
life in many different ways.
Hope you and the loving Neil and the baby
have a great 2018 from one tub of fuck
to another. Go Fuck Yourself.
Well that was just, you know,
for all you guys know that I wrote that
there was really no question there.
After further review,
did he say that was a catch?
What?
How the fuck was that a catch?
You saw that little cone of the ball
case kingdom cannot grow a
beard. God dammit. He's trying.
What the fuck?
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Everybody's got on their granny glasses.
All right, drew Brees. What's he gonna do?
He's gonna get a hands off the
fucking ball and nothing happens,
but he didn't fumble it. All right.
You guys want to listen to this shit?
Do you want to listen to the sound of
a bunch of 80,000 people have already
started crying to go to the mall of
America. If I ran the mall of America,
I would say free rollercoaster
rides for the entire month.
Well, maybe for the week. You know,
they've gotta make that money over there.
Can't imagine how much.
Okay.
Oh my God.
How does this always happen
to the fucking vikings?
It always happens to them when they're
at home. Everything with like 15 in one.
The dirty birds came in and it just,
okay.
Somehow came in and fucking beat him.
It's unreal.
Done.
Then they have a game against like the
fucking red skins or something like that
and 88
yeah.
Well they had the game won and
then it just fucking went away.
Uh,
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
All right, here we go. Bobby. A bears
fucking lining up for the kick.
The kick is up la and it's good.
Oh No.
Yes.
Oh,
when the saints go marching in?
Oh my God.
Okay.
The game is not over
cause they got case Keenum
perfect.
What the fuck?
I'm already typing in capital letters.
So Paul Versey. What the fuck
did I say? What did I say?
All right. Let me turn this down.
What did I do to the fucking thing?
Is there an exit button?
Exit.
Holy fucking shit.
I can't, I can't fucking believe
they came back and won this game.
I knew. I just say, you know, I
don't know shit about football.
I just had a feeling set of feelings.
I was like drew Brees.
He's like third all time passing. He never
gets the respect. He fucking deserves.
I think he's good.
I said it last week on the podcast.
Okay.
Uh, I'm texting Paul Versey
right fucking now Paul for Z.
Should I do, I should wait. Right? What
is this guy takes it back. All right.
25 seconds left case.
Keenum
it's going to present his case that he
is, he is the key. Numb to them. Winning.
Sorry. What the fuck? I mean,
they did a bunch for Aaron. Judge.
I can't have fun with case. Keenum steam.
That's what I'm going to do someday.
You know,
when I retire from being a comedian,
I'm going to ghost write
headlines for sports pages,
you know,
and I'll finally get to do all my pun
jokes that I'm not allowed to do in a
comedy.
You do a pun jokes in a comedy club,
you're going to get a grown and
people can you do enough of them?
People going to ask for their fucking
money back. All right. The Daily News,
the New York Post, all of these
guys, they live on it. Oh, I'll fall.
Start false start.
Okay.
Everybody's pointing at everybody else.
A little disco dancing on the Vikings.
Yeah.
Oh Jeez. Look at that guy. How much
is his breath stink? I fucking beard.
He's probably still get cereal
in there. Oh, that wasn't good.
That's not the way you want.
That's not the way you want to
start your two minute offense.
I like the Vikings when I was a kid
cause purple was my favorite color when I
was a little kid. I wanted to, I
wanted to be a painter now like of art.
I would just wanted to paint houses.
I thought it was going to,
that would be a cool
job. And uh, all right,
prevent defense there on the 38 yard line.
Don't take a dump penalty.
Okay.
Um,
I just,
I just wanted to paint houses and I was
going to paint everybody's house purple
whether they liked it or not,
cause that was my favorite color.
So right out of the gate,
you know, I was a con.
Um,
yeah.
Uh, Jesus, here we go.
Paul Versey. Here we go.
Okay.
I'm actually going to,
I'm going to text it right now
cause if I'm wrong you guys will,
I will put the sound on,
you'll get to listen to be deleted,
dude.
I fucking called it called.
It's why is it so much fun
being right about sports?
It's probably cause you know I'm
so wrong in the rest of my life.
Just feels good.
Every once in a while incomplete.
It only took fucking two seconds
off. All right. You know what?
This is going to be boring the amount
of time this is going to fucking me.
Read the next goddamn question. Is it
going to be another love letter? Oh,
bill tip on making oatmeal.
Okay.
I started eating steel cut
oats and uh, they, they,
they have this glee consistency. Unless
you just keep stirring the fucking thing.
He said,
get an instant instant pot and you could
make steel cut oats in like three to
four minutes.
They're like $90 on Amazon.
Okay.
I should use honey.
See if I can get it for 87.
If you go to your website
and click the link,
they'll even throw you a little
bit of cash. The chief, uh,
the fuck is an instapot.
Okay.
It's, do you mean like
a microwave? Insta Pot?
Let me see this. It's like a
vaporizer for oatmeal. Insta pot.
Okay.
I need to Google a fucking picture of that
Insta pot that looks like I've
complete piece of shit. Oh,
in pot.
What does that,
what you wrote my losing my mind.
Where is it now? You wrote
Insta Pot. It's instant.
Instant pot. Like I'll have this
breakfast made in an instant.
Okay.
Oh,
but then on Amazon it says in step pot,
maybe the instant pot is
fucking ripping them off.
Okay.
All right. What is it? It's ball
on young 39. What down is it?
Case Kane and back for fucking
pass throws the ball and complete.
Oh boy. Oh boy. Oh boy. Yeah.
That's what it is. Instapot is
120 bucks.
So I'm like,
this is just going to be something else
in my fucking cupboard because I can't
wait an extra 26 minutes.
So my oats, you're like, oh,
this person was just trying to help me
out and I'm still being a jerk about him.
I am into, uh, I didn't see that New
Matt Damon movie about downsizing,
but I am all about that shit.
I just fucking,
I had a lot of layoffs in my wardrobe.
I just sent everything. Fuck,
I'm gonna I'm going to be like,
I'm gonna have like three pairs of pants,
one black, one blue, and then just one
for every shit moment of my fucking day.
Uh,
oh.
Oh my God. No. Fuck it.
That could not have just happened.
Oh my God.
I feel I can't fucking police the greatest
podcast ever that could not have just
happened.
How do you let that happen?
Holy Shit. All right. Wait.
Okay.
Unfucking believable.
Oh, you know what? I didn't save
the thing when I've texted Diversey
I almost said, dude, I fucking call that.
How did that fucking just happen
on the last play of the game.
Okay.
And that he missed him and
knocked his own guy down.
Okay.
You have to be fucking kidding me.
I've literally seen it all.
Okay.
I cannot fucking believe
that just happened.
Okay.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Exactly. Case Keenum. Oh my God.
I just saw it when the guy
caught it. I was like, holy fuck.
Are they going to have
time to kick a field goal?
Okay.
Why won't anybody hug case Keenum
okay.
Look at the wide receiver.
Acted like he just did something to me.
He caught the ball,
but that saves completely fucked up.
He act like he faked
out that guy. He, wow.
Oh my God. I don't know what the name
of that St is, but I got to feel in,
everybody's going to know that
name by the night. Holy Shit.
Okay.
I cannot fucking believe
that just happened.
Okay.
There was another med when drew
Pearson caught that fucking ball.
The Vikings are finally on the
right side of one of these place.
Okay.
Holy Shit.
Oh my God. I cannot fucking believe. I
cannot fucking believe that just happened.
That was unbelievable.
Happy for Minnesota,
but Jesus Christ's sad for the saints.
What the fuck now?
How if you're that guy in the saints
that miss the guy completely didn't even
put your fucking arms out and
then took out another player.
How do you go into that locker room?
What do you say?
What the fuck do you say?
Okay.
Oh my God.
What were the fucking odds? I was going
to be watching this game the entire time.
Oh Jesus. Now the rest got to
look reviewing the score. It's a,
he didn't step out of bounds.
Don't take this away from football fence.
Don't take this away. What did
he do? He just put his head down.
That's like some pop Warner shit.
Oh my God.
Ruling a field has confirmed the
ref taken a lot of time here.
He never gets cheered.
Okay,
we must kick the field goal.
Okay.
I just shut it off. I cannot wait
a minute. I got to leave it on.
What if they fucking block it and
scored score. Fucking touchdown. Right.
I got to leave that on.
I can't,
I don't believe what I just saw.
I cannot fucking believe that.
How many times have I said that?
That was fucking unbelievable.
Okay.
How do I follow this up with questions?
I just did all of that.
Now my next question, do you
miss the Prius? I swear to
God. That's the question.
MMM.
Oh,
now they're going to clear the field.
We have to fucking kick the extra point.
The saints are gone.
Now they got to come
out of the locker room.
Can you imagine if the guy
just fucked that play a block,
this extra point and ran
it back for a touchdown?
That would be like watching
a tosh point. Oh. Like,
you know when he has the people be able
to do the redemptions without needing
tosh point. Oh, it'd be a
self contained episode. Um,
alright. Hang on a second. Let me
fucking get my password in here.
Let me read this Prius. Think
while we're waiting. Uh,
okay. Do you miss the
Prius? What up Billy Buick?
I actually love a Buick back in the
day. I love [inaudible]. You know when,
when a Cadillac was a Cadillac
and a Buick was like, you know,
you weren't quite a Cadillac guy.
I wonder if this would have put
them at least in field goal range,
the worst fucking attempt
ever at a fucking,
the fact that that guy is a safety.
Oh my God,
I don't fight.
I seen a lot of shit.
I have seen a lot of shit.
What the fuck anyways.
Do you
hmm.
I know you're thrifty for years
while driving your Prius Bill.
I was wondering if you still like driving
a nicer vehicle or regret spending the
money. I'm in the recovery
from buying new vehicles.
I wasted money for years on new cars and
never really got any satisfaction from
it. For the past three years I've been
driving a 2007 Honda accord. Awesome.
And surprisingly, I'm pretty happy with
it. Yeah, dude, once you get it paid off,
it's a shit. I still have to fight the
urge to buy a new ride often anyways,
happy new year from down in Alabama.
Um,
uh, no, cause I didn't buy a
nice car till I could afford one.
Uh, that's a mistake a lot
of people do. You know,
the trying to get some lady's attention
or whatever the fuck it is or they just
love cars so much. Like if
you're really, really a car guy,
I understand like along the way
you're going to have like nice cars,
but I was always about paying off my
house and getting the bankers off my back.
I was into that shit. This is what's
fucked up is the saints right now.
They have a chance,
a very small chance,
but they have a chance don't they
to block the extra point in return for a
touchdown. Can't that fucking happen? Um,
anyways, yeah, I was always,
I was always way into no debt or
working my way towards having no debt.
Like, um, I,
I just, I can't stress that
enough to young people,
but when you get like a credit card
and all that shit, it's just like be,
be really careful with those
things and you can't like,
um, oh, this is smart.
They're just going to go for a two point
of conversion and just down the ball so
that can't happen. There you
go. That's smart. My dumb ass.
That's why I don't coach
on any level. Um, anyways.
The um, yeah, I was,
I just was always into like,
just not being in debt,
you know,
it just absolutely paralyzes you and it
affects your ability to go after what
you want to go after.
I've told this story before,
like I kept a day job until I moved to
New York the first three and a half years.
I was a comedian probably the last year.
Well actually it's not true cause I was
still living at home with my parents.
I could have basically,
um,
you know, said, hey, hey, can you
help support me with my dream?
And I could have just been sitting around
the house, so just making comedy money.
But I continued to work and
before I moved down to New York,
I paid off everything.
MMM.
I paid off my student loans.
I paid off my car,
which died right before
I went to New York.
And I saved up a chunk of money and I
just moved down to New York. And, uh,
I was never a ramen noodle guy,
but I definitely ate a lot of fucking
Rigatoni and Spaghetti and shit.
MMM.
And I just did that. So, um,
okay.
When I finally got it,
when I finally bought myself a nice car,
I could afford it and felt
like I earned it. And um, yeah,
I loved it. But I also love the Prius. The
Prius is a fucking great car, you know,
cheap as shit to fucking own. It's never
a problem. You Park it wherever you want.
No one's trying to steal a fucking Prius.
You know, I always joked like you don't,
once mine was like
eight or nine years old,
I literally could leave that thing on
with the door open in the middle of a
fucking, you know, riot and no one
would take it. Like, you know, you know,
whenever they do the trap car, I try
to get people to steal that car. They,
they've never, I will be willing to bet
they never did that with a fucking Prius.
Now I want to know how many of those
Viking fan stuck around. You know,
some people left,
you know that they fucking left and as
they were winding down the fucking stairs,
they just heard every
going, oh my God, Oh my God.
And they had to fucking run
their fat asses back up there.
Congratulations to the vikings.
Holy Shit.
The Vikings did not win that game.
That was a the biggest
fuck up I have seen,
okay
in a long goddamn time.
Ah,
drew Brees and once again
drew Brees to silent assassin.
Nobody knows how good that guy is and
now he's not going to get to prove in the
NFC championship game. Potentially tried
to win a super bowl tragedy. All right.
Bulletproof glass bullshit. A
dear Billy dad bought, you know,
that hurts.
I was listening to your podcast a while
back where you read someone's email
concerning owning a store
with a bulletproof glass
where his grandfather was
almost killed and he was outraged at the
mandate and claimed the person pushing
the bill said,
bulletproof windows are racist.
I just wanted to point out that it was
bullshit. Most people in this country,
okay.
Who get outraged over things
are oftentimes just misinformed.
And because we live in a consumer culture
where the customer is always right. No,
they're not. That's old school.
The customer is not right.
The customer can go fuck themselves and
talk to a fucking robot on the phone.
If you're bleeding to death,
the press to the mindset has transitioned
to politicians saying the citizens are
hardworking, honest, honorable
Americans rather than saying the truth.
Most citizens are ignorant, entitled
tribal mouth, tribal mouth breathers.
Sir,
I don't know at what point in political
history politicians were saying that.
They never said that either.
So you're kind of speaking in hyperbole,
I believe is the expression. Uh, but
I understand what you're saying. Um,
you're trying to build up your point.
This is the bill that was proposed
regarding bulletproof windows. Um,
I have not fucking reading all of that.
Uh,
it's re regarding restaurants
and no other places of business.
So that person that wrote you in fear
of having his bulletproof glass band is
basically an outrage over nothing.
Okay.
Oh, in outrage and
outrage, you mean? No D it,
it doesn't even affect him or his
grandfather. Well, that's good.
It was never called racist.
We want to make sure that there
isn't this sort of indignity,
in my opinion,
to serving food through a Plexiglas
only in certain neighborhoods.
What?
That doesn't make sense.
Well, who are you to say it's
indignant? I, you know what, that's,
that's sneaky writing right there.
You're going to get offended for people.
I don't understand what's going on here.
I don't know. It was never called racist.
We want to make sure that there isn't
this sort of indignity, in my opinion,
to serving food through a Plexiglas
only in a certain neighborhoods. Well,
whenever I was doing gigs and bad
neighborhoods and they had that follicle
bulletproof glass, I always
looked at it. Okay, heads up.
Keep your head on a swivel.
I appreciated it being there.
I didn't feel like fucking,
I dunno what you tried to do here,
but I am in favor of hurting
some people's feelings.
If it keeps people who want to just
have the honest job of working at a
restaurant alive, um, I
would be in favor of it.
I don't think it's plexiglass is,
is it? Plexiglass stops a bullet.
I don't fuck it though.
Um,
that's from Philadelphia.
Council woman. Cindy Bass.
All right, let's look up Cindy.
Cindy can be your friend.
Three 10.
She's your fucking council man.
Why does it always take me
to fucking Wikipedia now?
Oh, what the fuck? Where
are we Cindy bass images.
Cindy Bass appears to be African American.
All right,
so this person was saying that
she was being racist. Now,
according to some people, it's
impossible for a black person to be ray.
I don't even know what the fuck is
going on right now. I don't know.
All I know is if I worked in Oh God damn
restaurant and somebody nearby had shot
someone in a restaurant to the point
that somebody felt that they needed to be
some fucking glass up
there, uh, I would want it.
But who the fuck am I to say what
people need in their neighborhood?
Ah, well how the fuck did I get
signed out of that thing? Hey,
when it's signed you out as it
goes, you want to make a report? No,
I don't have time for that shit like
Kuwait where it's time to do that. Um,
I was trying to do a podcast and you know
who it was, so nobody's showing dope.
Um,
it was never called Kate.
While I still don't agree that any type
of business should be mandated to remove
a type of security for whatever it was.
Websites like steadfast and loyal.com
that wrote bulletproof glass is now racist
in their title. However, you know what,
I actually understand
what you're saying here.
Cause that type of shit happens to
comedians all the time where they just,
you know, if they float something
out there, Huffington Post,
and then they try to get you in trouble
or make it more sensationalized so they
can get views. Uh, however,
in the body of the article,
they admitted that the council woman
never used those words. But of course,
most people don't read beyond
this article. Yeah, see, I mean,
that's the Internet. There's really
no, uh, there's no libel. There's no,
there's none. I cannot fucking,
I got to hit with this guy said,
uh,
God cared.
God cared that this Guy Yeps God care
and the other guy had too much devil in
him, Debbie other that the safety on
the saints. He prayed to the devil.
That's what happened in the devil.
Misled to tackle air,
to tackle his own fucking teammate.
Uh,
I know you're a comedian and not
some fucking political spot it,
so it's not like I'm trying to hold
you up to some Barbara Walters type of
standard,
but I know some people in your audience
forget that and believe everything they
read and everything they hear that
feeds into what they already believe.
Like you said, I am
bright.com. Yeah, well dude,
nobody's coming to this fucking
website to become informed. Okay. Um,
don't put that on me. Okay.
I did not pursue that,
which is why I became a comedian.
All right.
I tried to Siri, the serious world.
It didn't fucking work out for me.
I failed miserably. Okay. Failed my wife.
All right,
dear Billy buddy guy.
My wife and I had been
married for a year and a half.
We both have a child from prior
relationships and a seventh month old Jada
together. She's an angel by
the way. Of course she is.
She is Latina and I only bring that
up because she fits all the fiery
stereotypes. Both good and bad.
She completes my life with this.
Although arguments can get very difficult.
Dude, I thought you were talking
about your seven month old.
That's fucking hilarious. She went
right into that. I thought you're good.
You already have an arguments with
a seven month old and she's fiery,
blah blah blah.
Fucking talking. Jibberish
okay. Your wife. Okay.
She's Latina and I only bring that up
because she fits all these stereotypes.
She completes my life.
I Blah Blah Blah.
I have some of the same temper issues
that you use to describe yourself and your
bit about kneeling on the ball when
I'm right has paid off huge. Uh,
so thank you for that.
Yeah.
I wish I should probably rewatch that
bit cause I have not been doing that
lately. I've been airing it
out. Anyway to cut to the chase,
we decided together to fight
for primary custody of my son.
The case is very complicated,
but for the sake of everyone listening,
I'll summarize it with his
few details as possible.
In family court before
appearing in front of a judge,
there is a conference where a meteor
mediator tries everything they can to make
sure you can come to an agreement
and avoid a judge. Deciding,
my wife and I had a plan going in to not
cut a deal with my ex at the conference
and hold out for a judge to
rule on custody. However,
I had no idea the level of pressure that
they'd be able to put me and I buckled
under it and made a
deal for the next year.
Then I had to go home and explain to
my wife that I had failed our plan.
I don't know if you've ever
completely disappointed your woman,
but this is the worst feeling in
the world. Well, wait a minute.
She's going to judge you because they
probably used your love of your own kid
right against you.
Anyways,
and as you can imagine over the past
day or so, she's cutting me into me.
It just about every opportunity for all
the little failures and I can see it
right in and arise that are man had a
moment of weakness and didn't come through
in the clutch.
Worse is that she absolutely hates my ex
and feels like I let her get the better
of me. US. Yeah. You know,
I kinda had a feeling. Yeah.
Okay. All right. Oh Geez.
You're in the middle of that.
You're in the middle of the two ladies.
You have ever disappointed you're
a woman with a grand fuck up. Yeah.
About every three days.
I guess a good boxing analogy is that
my hands are down and I don't know how
long to let her continue jabbing at
me until I put them back up. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Uh, I wouldn't
take another ounce of shit from her.
I, you, you just sit down and talk
to her and be like, wait a minute.
I'm trying to get my kid back. I'm going
back with all of this emotion. Wait,
let me make sure this is
okay.
You decided together to get
primary custody of your son.
Now who's idea was that?
Was that totally yours or was the hatred
your wife has of your ex wife played
into the thing?
Um,
I don't know, Dude. I
don't know what's going on,
but it sounds when it went into my head.
Okay,
now no notice.
No that everything that you say is now
perverted cause it went into my brain.
As I say, once you say something,
it's not what you said anymore.
It's cut with the other
person's experiences.
It's like drugs that have been stepped on.
What you said was pure cocaine.
Now it's in my head and there's all
this x selects, fucking laxatives,
getting fucking put it. Um, all
I hear is that your wife, uh,
your current wife presents your
previous fucking wife and uh,
she's doing that woman thing where they
don't solve things with their fists.
They tried to fucking make,
they just
okay.
Do that thing where they tried to make
the other woman as miserable as they
possibly can and she knows
probably how much it would break.
Okay.
Your ex, why it's hard to lose
a primary custody of your son.
And she really wanted to do that to her
because that would make her feel better
and more secure in your relationship. I
don't fucking know. I have no idea too.
There's too many fucking variables here.
But um,
I wouldn't take an ounce of shit if I had
a son from a previous marriage and you
know,
I was trying to do what you were doing
and then I caved under that pressure.
My wife won't understand it and if she
ever gave me shit, I would be stunned.
And then I would fucking read her the
riot act and I would go out to a bar and
have a couple of cold ones there.
That's what I would do. Okay.
Now I get into a lot of
arguments in my relationships.
We probably don't want to listen to me.
I have no professional background. Okay?
I'm the type of man that once
that already types out, dude,
I called it with 25 seconds left
in fucking jinx is the saints.
Maybe it was my fault. Um, all right.
I don't know what the fuck that was,
but he can't say it wasn't compelling.
If you're a football fan,
everybody else, I apologize to, uh,
go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on, yeah, on a Thursday.