Okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
February 6th, eighth, and
I'm back in the USA baby.
Finally I should say I'm back home,
back home.
And home is where the hardest. Don't you
think? I actually, I have a new recorder.
I don't know if the levels are too
high here. I have no fucking idea.
I can't really hear myself. Um, the old
girl finally died. I mentioned last week,
the Olympus Ellis 10 is what I had.
And uh,
they're all the way up to the
14th. And I got the 14, which I'm,
I seem to be enjoying so far,
although I can't stand
the fucking lady voice.
Every button that you hit,
it goes like recording
back to main menu and it's this
fucking English lady. It's like,
what the fuck are you doing? Why, why?
When the fuck did an American accent
just become like, you can't have that.
You can't have it on like you're,
uh, like all these fucking,
one of those things that I advertise on,
on this podcast.
It's like they try to give you like a,
for your voicemail,
you have some sort of international,
just not from America voice and all of a
sudden it makes it sound like you. Okay.
Wow. I like this company. They must
be fucking people over globally,
all over the world. They fucking
did you. Did you hear this?
Okay?
Did you hear the outgoing message?
Oh, hello. Welcome to pink Barry.
All of a sudden I think I'm getting
a higher class fucking yogurt
because what?
Because it's got an English accent.
What the fuck is it with the goddamn
English that everybody thinks it's so
fucking,
you know what it is?
It has to do with the fact that we're
over here on our own God damn island.
All right. And if it actually
had some sort of French accent,
all it does is remind you that you can't
fucking speak the language, but what?
Like English, all of a sudden it
starts to sound a little hoity. Toity.
You know who I blame for all of this?
I blame Madonna.
All right,
let me tell you something
about that fucking lady there.
All right.
She's from fucking Detroit.
She grew up side outside
of that fucking hell hole.
Okay.
A, by the way, you know something? Oh,
let's complete the thought bill for
the love of God. See it through. Okay.
She grew up outside of
their fucking hell house.
She does a couple of fucking woopty dudes
around the world singing her dumb ass
song in our mustard colored pumps and
all of a sudden she's got a fucking
English accent.
It's annoying.
All right.
I've lived out here for fucking
coming up on eight. All right.
I still like, I still sound
like a go down the tarp pike.
You know I was just over
in Asia that it come back.
Sounded like I was from fucking India.
Yeah,
know.
I mean Madonna,
how much he is searching.
Okay.
How bad was your fucking childhood?
How bad was this country that
you felt you had that you had it,
you move to another one and then
you took on their goddamn accent.
Like they wouldn't notice.
Yeah.
Why am I jumping all over her?
All right. Favorite Madonna Song?
What would you like?
Would you like the guilty pleasure or
would you like the one that I actually
liked the musicianship.
What's the guilty pleasure one? Oh
God. It was one of earlier ones,
you know,
before she got into all of that.
I don't know what the fuck she was doing,
you know, before the sex book, you
know? Or it's just like, you know,
I'll fuck anything her those
years. It's like we get it,
we get it. All right. Yeah.
Like you like Dick, you like women
too. You like Dick and women.
You know you liked that
fucking fat guy in a,
in the Monty python,
get a better get it buck.
I'm going to sell APP except
it's with Dicks. You know?
It's like this new thing I've
noticed with comedy with women,
like that's like this fucking,
it's considered edgy.
If they talk about the clamps and it's
just like, you know, with all due respect,
you just sort of a bar hack at that point,
aren't you?
Aren't you just doing Dick Jokes? Because
it's a vagina. All of a sudden, you know,
they're taking good shoulder,
their bodies. It's like,
I don't give a fuck what you doing?
You're doing a dick joke.
My acidic with the pussy.
It's the same fucking shits like Sam
Smith with the Tom Petty Song. Right?
It's the same fucking thing.
Okay.
No, ah, stay with me. Um,
it's just a fucking Dick joke.
We could,
everybody stopped losing their fucking
minds over a dick joke because now it's a
pussy joke.
It's the same fucking joke.
Blah, blah, blah, blah. So
let me get this straight.
If you're shooting a loaded somebodies
face, you're just a fucking, you know,
a blue comic.
But if you're taking the load to the face,
you're groundbreaking. Is that how it work
with you? God Damn kids today. Well, Hey,
more power to you.
And by the way,
I'm just fucking with Sam Smith because
that song doesn't sound anything like
the other song. I guess when you speed up
and slow down the other then yeah. Yeah.
Then I guess it is the same
sound is the same song.
But like at no point that I ever listened
to it and think of that Tom Petty Song
and not to mention Sam Smith
Song was way fucking better.
And you know, there's people
out there that actually say, um,
what kind of going like,
what the fuck? When uh,
when he said he had never heard that Tom
petty song and like everybody was like
flipping out mostly older people don't.
What do you mean you didn't hear that?
That big hit? That was a hit when I was
a kid. This is the thing that you got to,
you got to know about, about
these to the kids. Dot. Right.
They don't even know who
the fuck Paul Mccartney was.
Paul Mccartney came out and sang with
Kanye west and like kids in their twenties
they don't know who Paul Mccartney is.
Some of them don't even know
who the fucking Beatles are.
And then those kids who
know who the Beatles are,
they listened to the Beatles and they go,
what's the big deal?
These guys are overrated because
they're fucking songs are 50 years old.
At least the early ones.
She loves you. Okay. Okay.
Yeah,
all that Shit,
all that shit in right then their,
their, uh, their end shit there and shit,
the shit that they did right before
they broke up is as old as me. 46, 44,
45, 46 years old. They don't
know where the fuck they are.
So if you don't know the god damn
beetles are, if they come out, you know,
with Kanye West.
Okay.
And he sings a fucking song with them,
they're not going to know who the fuck he.
Yes. He, she looks like a, he looks
like he should be like a civil war.
Reenactor now he's actually
more revolutionary war.
When I think of a Sir Paul Mccartney,
I fucking hate that shit.
I hate how over in England they
date night people dumb it set.
Then what do you have a
little fucking pretense?
Sword fight really is Paul Mccartney
of fucking, he's knighted now.
What's he gonna do?
Go storm a castle in a far away land or
is he just going to put on a big silly
necklace and get down on one fucking DEA?
How the whole fucking stupid.
Um, but anyways, yeah,
I, for the life of me,
I didn't notice it.
That was the same song and I don't
get how that guy gets sued, but lady,
a lady Gaga, it doesn't.
With that Madonna Song,
which was the exact same fucking temple
and I guess the same chord progression
and all of that shit where I would go in
into like clubs or whatever and just
regular people with singing the Madonna
Song along to the Lady Gaga Song.
I didn't fucking ever think of the Tom
Petty Song with the Sam Smith Song and
what I love is the second the
lawsuit comes around, then everybody,
all of a sudden everybody's Phil Spector.
Now everybody fucking heard it, right?
Everybody's got a gun in some fucking
horse mouth going admitted, admitted.
It's a Tom Petty Song, right?
Isn't that what he did?
Can you imagine being in a studio with
that fucking weasel who's walking around
with a goddamn gun coke dial
up or whatever the hell he is?
I just don't understand how people
get into a situation like that. Like,
how bad do you want to make
it that you stay in a studio?
The first time that guy waves the
gun around, it's like, Hey Phil,
I'm going to burger king.
Do you want anything? Yeah,
you pull an amps absentee father.
Thank he just abandoned the whole thing.
What's he going to do, do you
think? A guy that fucking crazy,
he still drives,
probably has some old fucking Limo,
you know, really high roof so
he can hold his fucking wig.
Um, anyway, she'll listen it
to the Monday morning podcast.
I hope this thing is recording.
I really hope it is because I
can't hear myself right now.
I have a bit of a cold.
All right.
I just flew around the world
and the last fucking thing,
I still can't believe I just
did that Shit, man. Um, hey.
You know what seems like a really hacky
fucking city to go to is a Dubai and
that's just from landing there and
then seeing all their advertising,
you know?
Do you remember that?
What was that fucking commercial they
had where they fed those dumb whores?
Uh, oh, you know what,
I'm trying to get better
with the add here.
Borderline is my guilty Madonna pleasure.
And then my favorite,
uh,
fucking actual song is bad girl cause of
all Mar Omar Hakim is that he said his
fucking drumming on, that's the shit. Uh,
and actually when they played it live,
live on Saturday night live a
long time ago. I remember, uh,
just watching him playing the drums on
that and thought he was fucking awesome.
Um, but it's a classic
radio hit. You know,
you listen to it three times in a
row and you're like, you know what?
I don't think I have,
want to hear that song again.
And then you've got to wait like three,
four years and then you listen to it
again. Like oh yeah, oh yeah. Oh yeah,
shut it off, shut it off. And that's
what, you know, you have a head.
Um,
so Sam Smith gets fucking sued.
What about that new song that
Bruno Mars is singing on?
Cause that dam funk gonna give it to you.
I mean,
how many fucking times it's that
Song Ben Written. Don't believe me.
Just watch how many times is
that line been written? Doh,
Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh to this.
Here's that same song that save
song comes out of his summer.
Oh Jesus. Hey. Don't
believe me. Just watch.
Um, but whatever the fuck
you saying, I have no idea.
Uh, what was I talking
about now? I just all Dubai,
that lecture seems like a,
if Jersey shore was given out just to
open fucking checkbook to make a Goddamn
city,
that just,
that's what it seems like that with the
little bit of a fucking car Dashi and
Calabasas vibe to it. Like it
seems like when people go to Dubai,
they come back and I imagined
they would say shit like,
like Dude Day had a Lamborghini store
next to a Ferrari store next to a water
slide where you slitted of champagne,
you know,
all this fucking horse shit.
And then outside the city they got like
a fucking tent city of all these fucking
basically modern day slaves that had to
build the whole fucking thing just
by sitting on the airplane because we
connected and do by. Um, after we
left Mumbai, that used to be Bombay.
Bombay is now suing Mumbai,
just like Tom Petty suits.
Sam Smith to same fucking city.
There's too many of the same letters
in Mumbai that was in Bombay. Right?
Would that be just the A,
there's no fucking way I'm trying to do
this in my head anyway. Spec to Dubai.
So we,
we connected in Dubai by the way,
to then depart flyover.
I ran and then over Russian,
I'm fucking as an American,
I am nervous flying over Iran.
But then when I looked at the stewardesses
and they kind of had those little
fancy little head dress things
on, I'm like, oh, okay, wait,
I think we're all right.
I think I'm on the right team here.
I think I should be all right. So,
but they had all these advertisings
advertising's advertisements for Dubai for
all this stupid hotels over
there. And that's, it just,
it reminded me of that commercial a long
time ago where they had like, uh, uh,
do you remember was just
some shitty restaurants
like olive garden or it was
like a Domino's, you know,
dominoes is fucking hilarious too with
their whole ad campaign where they just
admit that their product sucks, you know?
Well, you know what, you guys, you know,
you're right. I mean, we
ate it tastes like shit.
Okay.
We couldn't believe how bad it was
either. We agree. We're joining it.
We're joining it like, like during
civil rights. She can't stop it. See,
you join it and then
you take control of it.
I had some of that page site and Ah,
I thought it tastes like shit.
Ask not what your paycheck
Joe for. Yep. Yep. Nope.
Right.
They just joined the fucking thing.
They come to our side of the fence.
We're yelling at Deb gold.
Your pizza sucks. And then they just join
our cry. Yeah. Yeah. It fucking sucks.
And then we'll yelling at,
nobody in the whole thing goes away and
then they come back with their fucking
pizza. It's the exact same God damn
price. The lovely Nia said it the best.
She goes, why don't you charge more
than five 99 for a fucking large?
Maybe you could put a
little more into the product
and when you really think about it,
that's should have been the
ally when people said that
pizza sucks, but okay. Hey,
it's five 99 for a large. All
right, you broke son of a bitch.
I'm just trying to fill that hole
in your belly. Okay? Yes. Sucks.
But I have a couple of beers and starts
to taste better, doesn't it? All right.
Then who else is going to bring in this
much fucking food for that little of a
price at two o'clock in the
fucking morning, Huh? Nobody.
Nobody. We all know what
you do. This is what you do,
you or okay, you put in an order, right?
For one large pizza. Okay. Providing,
and then you pick another address out of
the fucking phone book and your order.
Fucking three of them,
but it's close enough to the other house
so they know that you're coming to your
house first.
You would have four largest
for that fucking place and
then you have one of your
friends hide in the fucking bushes across
the street. That Domino's guy pulls up.
All right? He jumps out of the car
and he's going to leave it unlocked.
He brings your pizza up to the car while
you're paying for that PC of friends go
and they steal the other fucking pies.
Then you run around the fucking house
and he got four pies for five 99 okay.
That's how it was done
anyways,
we should just go out and just grab them
and then just eat whatever the other
people fucking ordered and then you know,
a lot of times it was something he
didn't want like a vegetable pizza,
which is so fucking stupid. It's like you,
they have vegetables. Eat something bad.
Okay. Stop with the yard and you already
have the guilt is you're eating this
all right,
it's cheese topping or Salami, Salami,
Pepperoni, mushroom, something like that.
Okay enough with the fucking
peppers and all of that shit.
You know how much heartburn
and you're trying to get here.
So then what we would do is we then
eventually we'd start to order pizzas.
You know,
that we want it a little further down
the street knowing that that come to our
place first.
Occasionally it didn't work out and then
they just went to somebody's fucking
house and they were like, we didn't order
that shit. Oh, are you serious? Yeah,
I'm serious. And then they come to our
house and then we'd still steal it.
And that's how you did it.
That was how it was done. Um,
but it wasn't Domino's. What, what was
that? I'm trying to talk about Dubai here.
That fucking commercial,
I think it was all of garden
where they had these people sit down and
they had cloth Napkins and they had all
this fucking pomp and circumstance.
Right. If that's how you say, um,
just pump and circumstantial evidence.
Right.
And then they're eating this
pasta and they go, oh my
God, it's so decadent. Right.
You know what I loved was they had
a bunch of animals eating the shit.
So of course they think it's great.
The second you throw a cloth Napkin.
Okay.
It's somebody that goes to a tanning bed.
I mean they automatically think that
they're eating a five star fucking meal.
You've already,
you've already mind fucked him.
It's like those psychological tests where
they give them a pill that doesn't do
anything,
but you tell him it's going to make
him feel better and then they convinced
themselves that they feel better.
Right.
To me is like what Dubai
is. Dubai is like, you know,
if you took olive garden's Pasta,
however they're trying to make it steady,
you know all the bread you want.
Like that's, that's Dubai. That's what
it seems like to me. Having said that,
I'll still fucking go there
if I get a Gig, you know,
so I'm just trying to sell the shit that
I would say if it was more of a free
fucking area, cause God knows how
go there, you know Jesus Christ.
I'm going to go over there just to
see what I have to wrap Nia in. Oh,
oh, I'm going to have a good
time at one of those countries.
I'm going to talk all kinds of shit.
I'm going to make me a walk
like five feet behind me.
Okay.
Nia looked down at the floor
when you walk behind me.
Oh, that's great. They got it down over
there. Huh? You just wrap them all up?
Yeah. That's, you know what
they are actually doing?
They're actually admitting how
much smarter women are that men,
the fact that they have to have them
on that level of control. You know,
what were they doing before then?
They must have just been running shit
and they're just like, we can't fuck it.
You know? Why don't you
put your foot down? Okay,
fucker. Right. We'll wrap them up.
We can't see what they look like then
they can't use their but Japanese to, to,
to mess with my,
our minds.
I just don't understand
why you would do that.
Yeah.
She's gotta be crazy.
Like when you're fucking,
I guess you're definitely gonna marry
somebody that you love because you can't
see what they look like. You know?
Because guys will put up with a lot,
okay.
If the woman is beautiful the same
way I'll, I'll lady, we'll put up,
if you've got money and you're
making money and you can provide,
they're going to put up with way
more shit than they should. You know?
And it's true.
As much as nobody wants to admit it,
we all want to sit there and act like
where that fucking Badass that has a line
in the sand that you won't cross.
But give me a fucking break.
If she's a 10 that there's no line.
Sure you got it down there and
she's stepping over oil all over it.
And what are you going to do? You're
going to walk. You want to walk.
You know you should walk when you get
in your car and you drive away fucking
bitch.
You know what? You treat me like, dude,
you fucker.
All right, I'll let shit you say
in your car. And then what happens?
That fear voice in the back of your head.
What if this is the best fucking person
I'm ever with it and I never find
anybody else. I grow it. Dick, you're
feeling you're flipping back and forth,
but you're not going to do it, right.
The same thing with the broads.
They do the same thing. Okay? You walk
around, you got yourself an ATM card,
you buy them a couple of trinkets down
on a mall and all of a sudden they start
feeling comfortable,
right? Next thing you know,
you take a little bit of
your frozen yogurt and you
flip it right in their face.
And what do they do? You know, do they
leave yet? No. Do they pouch share?
They do. You know, but
they're not going anywhere.
You just bought him a couple of fucking
tee shirts over at the hot topic. Oh,
what the fuck are they going? Huh? Sorry.
That was really negative.
All right, let's uh,
pursue a little bit of advertising here.
Um,
all the shady shade people.
All right, here we go.
Everybody dollar shave club doe.
Can someone tell me when
racers got so damn expensive,
could someone tell me when
they're going to change the copy?
Okay.
Especially cause they're trying to
rate fund is the same jokes every week.
Have I been asleep for 20 years.
I was in the store the other day and
one pack of razors just now. 20 bucks,
one pack. That's crazy.
Exclamation point, but hey,
hey. Sometimes they give you a free
gift when you buy, they're overpriced.
Rage at raises, which is actually a punch
in the Dick. That's such a great joke.
Once A, don't get beat up by
ridiculous razor prices. Look, dude,
I don't need to read all of this.
You know what the deal is?
You go to a fucking cvs, they're going
to charge you out the ass for this stuff,
all right? It never should have been that
high and it's been that high forever,
but for whatever reason they've been
able to get away with it. For finally,
the geniuses at dollar shave club, they
filled the goddamn void, all right?
Just a few bucks.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers amazing
razors and other great grooming supplies
right to your doorstep. That plan
starts at just three bucks, all right?
You can get half a pizza Domino's for
that. Here's how it works. They said,
send your handle for free, and every
month you get replacement blades.
It's one less thing to worry about.
You can get deliveries every month,
every other month, however the
hell you want to do it. All right?
They got other stuff too. Like one
wipe Charlies, which is for your ass.
Why
pay $20 for a razor when you get a
fantastic shape from dollar shave club.com
for a fraction of the price.
All right, stop getting screwed.
Get out of this,
this abusive relationship with Duane Reed.
Wherever the hell you go,
go to dollar shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/burn
for some fucking reason.
I've got to say it three times
dollar shave club.com/bar all right,
here we go. Me, me, me,
me, me, me, you, me,
undies beyond bees. No more
sweaty balls. Boop, boop,
boop me on days beyond these,
you can wear him down at the
mall and talk to that horror.
As you're walking right up, you can feel
good cause your balls are up to snuff.
You can't get oh the AH, the Andes.
You want an old fucking underwear?
Oh yeah.
No more sweaty balls.
Butoh feel how dry my taint is.
Uh,
sorry. Uh, you know that feeling
of putting on saggy old underwear.
I gotta be honest with you.
I don't,
and it makes me feel like it makes me
think about old people wearing underwear,
which is really gross. You need another
feeling of great fitting young underwear,
nice and tight under your chin.
You changed your ball bag there.
That is two times softer than cotton.
You need to know about me on
Ds Biondi Uber Duber do Boop,
boop me undies is the most company.
Am I going to get sued for a
Alice's restaurant for doing this?
I guess I'm not making any money.
Right?
Me undies is the most
comfortable underwear you will
ever wear and it's insane
how good they make you feel
easy, dude. My Dick standing up.
I'm not even thinking, man. I'm
not even thinking about a broad.
They fit perfectly.
They don't ride up on you
and they literally pull
moisture rows away from your
skin. See a steak stay cool. I
have mine on right now. I think.
I actually do right now. I
have to check. Yes, I do.
I had to check because that's
how comfortable they feel.
They have cool styles for both men and
women and all. They all look great.
Check out the photos for yourself.
Yeah,
go look at a bunch of people in underwear.
Your Weirdo at me,
undies.com this quality would typically
retail for two times to me. Undies.
Price. No retail middlemen
means more savings to you. Here.
I will make it easy.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burn and
get 20% off your first order and free
shipping. Save more. When
you buy a pack of them,
they guarantee you're going to be happy
with them or your first pair is free.
There you go. Well, how many
more do I got to read here? Yeah.
All right, let's, I get five total,
so why don't we get three? Well,
let's get over the hump here. I shall. We.
National Association of Sports Medicine.
Life is too short to be worse at work.
Boring in a lifeless job.
The National Academy of Sports Medicine
is looking for people who want exciting
careers.
In the fitness industry.
Make good money doing something
you love and help people reach,
reach their health and fitness goals.
And a s m is the way.
Being a personal trainer is awesome.
Yeah, it is awesome. You
get to work out for free.
You get to get to be in a slave
master relationship with the gym.
You set your own hours,
work in a health club,
sports clinics and corporate wellness.
Imagine waking up every
day smelling rubber mats,
excited to get to work, not to
a job, but a rewarding career.
You can get fatties and turn
their lives around, right?
How many times you've seen an absolutely
beautiful woman who needs to lose a
little bit away,
right?
You could sit there and you can help her
big find that beautiful woman inside of
it,
right?
And then you're right there and you
know the weight in your head when you're
going to ask her out. Right? Cause
she just a piece of meat to you. Uh,
the National Academy of Sports Medicine
even offers specialization courses like
MMA conditioning. Oh, that's the shit.
You know what's so funny about that?
How many that's going to be like
the new fed, the MMA workout,
and everyone's gonna have a sledge
hammer and tipping over tires,
doing the rope thing. You're
fighting anybody. Yeah,
go do some Chin ups.
Said I'm get a headstart on two 2015
and begin your certification with the
National Academy of Sports Medicine.
Now n a s m guarantees you'll
land a job within 60 days.
Averting your CPT certification
certification or your money back.
Call to action.
Go to us.
Go to my us trader.com for a free 14 trial
of their fast and fun online program.
That's my us trainer.com by USA
trader.com. Restrictions apply.
Visit my USA trainer.com for details.
So many one of those ad companies figured
out that if you say it three times,
they're going to remember
it. You know? Wait,
what should I say here?
What should I say three times?
That'll make you fucking do it.
Uh,
okay.
I don't know what I'm thinking.
I feel like you've got a hyper
Joe to Rosa date here for best.
It's taking a bunch of heat
out there and let's see,
it was Joe to Rosa going to be yet
Joe to Rosa de Rosa due to do to,
to, to, to, where is he?
Where is he? Where is he?
Ah, Christ. He'll come
up here in a second.
My fucking computer and
just love on your computers.
Just the shit for like three
weeks after you buy it. Yeah.
It's the fastest thing out there
and then it just sucks after that.
Such a fucking rip off. Anyways, what
did I want to talk about this week?
Um, American sports.
Let's talk about that.
I have no fucking idea who's doing what.
I know the Bruins were playing really
well right up to the all star break and
then we, uh, I don't know if we can have
an a it bit having a rough one, you know?
Um, I think we lost a van. It's
the beginning of a big west coast,
a trip here.
And I got,
I got to get back into a
watching that type of stuff. Um,
I do have to tell you, I fucking,
sports are awesome over here. You know,
we have at least three really
exciting sports, football,
hockey, basketball or fucking
exciting goddamn sports. All right.
They have basketball over in Australia
but it's called Netball and women play it
in. There's no back board. I can watch
that little bit, but the rules are,
I can't remember if they
can't dribble or some shit.
Like they get it then they just have to
stop and I'll see any dunking or any of
that type of stuff.
But um,
I'm looking forward to
getting back into it. But um,
I have no idea what's going on.
One of my buddies up in Canada to gave
me shit cause I guess we got swept by the
Canadians, um, for this season.
It's so sad to listen to the Canadian
fence gloat about that seasoned sweep is
complete, you know? Yeah.
There's just Stanley Cup.
What do you guys done in the
last 20 years? Lose the expos
you think? I give up. Fuck
that. We lost a Montreal again.
We just won another championship. We won
a super bowl. All right. In a real league.
Montreal's not that poor shit
CFL thing. Yeah, I've up there.
All right.
We're bubby Barista can go up there
and it's fucking throw for 500 yards or
meters, whatever the fuck you call
them up there. Every God damn game
me a fucking break.
Did I already did I already
break new city's balls.
Do you realize that the fucking city
of Boston with four teams has one,
one more championship then the,
then the fucking city of New
York has professional teams.
We would have enough rigs to give each
fucking sad ass New York fucking team of
fucking ring and still have one leftover
for ourselves with just four tapes.
That's why I don't respect New
York sports in their championships.
It's like you doubled down in every
fucking sport. Gee, did you win one?
How many at bats do you need to baseball
to football to basketball and if you
include the island is they got to fucking
hockey. It's fucking pathetic. Oh,
I love Robin and into those constant,
you'd probably go on like bill,
why are you rubbing it in on the ads?
Because they've been dicks to me
my entire fucking sports life.
Cause we now we never won anything and
they and all of them fucking just run and
hide. Anytime Boston wins
something or they tried to, no, no,
I'm happy for you guys. You
have, I'm really happy for
you guys. Go Fuck Yourself.
Go Fuck Yourself. All
right. I swear to God,
it's what that city is,
is it's the Yankees,
the Yankees prop that entire
fucking city up. If, if the, if,
if it wasn't for the fucking Yankees,
New York City would be exposed as being
basically one of the saddest places to,
to ever be as a sports fan.
You know,
wait, but the giants are good. What
am I talking about? The giant ticket,
but rather than that, all right. The
jets. Horrific. 1969 the next, you know,
you have to get, it's
1973 the rangers have one,
one cup and like fucking
90 years. 80 years, right?
Well, yes. Nets have never
won anything. The island is,
they had their run,
but at that point it's like 30 fucking
years a Gulf that plant better though.
Right? I don't know. Just a sad,
sad fuck you got the Yankees.
Thank God for the fucking
Yankees have won like 99%.
I guess he probably wouldn't
99% for everybody, but I dunno,
I dunno. I'm quoting here a little bit.
It's been a hell of a fucking decade,
everybody. And if you think, I think that
this is going to last. I know it isn't.
I know that right now I am at the tail
end of the greatest run Boston sports is
going to have in my lifetime. I know.
I don't know when it's going to Ed,
but, uh, I'll take it.
If it just becomes like,
you know,
like the Bruins don't seem
like they have it this year.
It seems like they're going to have
to fucking shake it up. A Celtics.
It goes without saying, um, the red
sox, you never know what today's game,
we kind of seem like we, uh,
when it, then we shit the bed,
then we win it. So we'll see
what happens. Maybe we'll, uh,
we'll come back around and try to stay.
Uh,
we'll try to keep up with the giants.
We've won three,
they've won three in this century.
Oh, we will be like one ahead. If
we end up winning it this year,
who the who the fuck knows
and the Patriots, I don't
know what happens with them,
but at some point Bella checks going to
have to retire and Brady's going to have
to retire and then we're going to go back
to be in the team that I watched when
I was growing up.
And uh,
yeah,
you watch how that stadium empties out,
it's going to go right.
But you know,
it'd be funny as if you
actually had a camera, right?
Like doing like this still photography
and you had people who were there,
um,
basically before Bob Craft and he got
them in this seats and then you just sort
of fast forward through all the years.
Robert Kraft, Bill Parcells, Pete Carroll,
Bill Belicheck, he just see the stadium,
fill it up, filling up, filling up,
and then they gradually retire and then
all the seats around start getting empty
again.
And then you just see that same person
you saw before Robert Kraft bought the
team and he's just fucking much older
at, fuck, am I going to sneeze here?
God dammit. I hope I didn't
catch a fucking cold. Um,
so anyways,
um,
somebody was telling me that they read
a story that Pete Carroll said that,
I don't know if it was like
three nights in a row, whatever,
but he was laying in bed crying
that he lost the super bowl.
And that's why I love Pete Carroll.
I can't,
I mean I hate that Wu
and I hate the dockers,
but that fucking guy is so fucking driven.
He wants to win it.
Do you realize like the pain that guy,
that guy was going to do something that,
I'm trying to think how many people did
it. If he went back to back Superbowls,
that guy joins fence,
Lombardi Don Shula,
Chuck Noll,
uh,
Jim at Johnson
and bill Bellacheck.
That's it,
right?
It would become one of six people
to ever do it. Any be in the same,
the same fucking categories.
Lombardi, Shula, chuck Noll,
Jimmy Johnson and bill Bellacheck.
Bill Bell check. By the way,
I would actually say it's the greatest
coach of all fucking time of all fucking
time.
How long he's one.
Yeah.
Doing it now on the salary cap era,
the amount of fucking players
switching and switching out,
even when he doesn't win it, we still
win like 12, 13 fucking games a year. Um,
I think he's,
I think he's the greatest of all time
and I really hope that we keep pushing to
get the fucking cult to make some sort
of public apology for their absolute
fucking, there's such fucking
babies, man. I love Andrew Luck.
This is nothing against the colts. The
team. It's their fucking owner, man.
That guy,
such a goddamn baby.
The amount of times that they've lost
and then of course they can't just lose.
It has to be like a fucking rule change.
He's got to send a video to the,
to the League office.
It's like, dude, you lost
Aaron.
It go fuck yourself.
What a fucking baby man.
Anyways,
so,
but you know, they throw it out there.
It was great. They throw it out there.
So forever. Bill Bellacheck, you know,
by all the fucking people out
there who just hate the guy,
are forever going to quit. I
love our Jerry Rice to Sarah
and goes, yeah, you know,
they should have an
asterisk next to their, uh,
their championship and then
admits to using stick them.
Okay.
Give me a fucking break. So now what
Jerry? Now you're not, he's now,
you're no longer the greatest receiver
of all. Tag me a fucking break.
You still are.
Grow Up. Um, so anyways,
that was on the, uh,
I was on the plane coming
back from a Dubai and um,
I blew,
I blew basically all any,
any gig money that I
made going through Asia.
I blew on plane tickets because I'm too
fucking old to fly in the back of the
plane. I just can't do it. Okay.
I can't, I'm too fucking old.
So I actually lost money.
You went to Asia and probably lost a good
month of my life breathing in some of
that air over there.
Uh,
but I'm still going back cause I
absolutely loved it and I fucking love the
people over there.
So a nia was giving me shit because
she saw the money that I spent.
She saw what I was going to gross and
then what I spent on plane tickets.
She's like, what the fuck are you
doing? And I was just like, listen,
I know you can't put a price on it.
Okay, this is like a fucking vacation.
Just look at it that way.
And we're actually going to maybe make
a little money on this thing. All right.
But I am not going to fucking
fly to Australia with my
fucking pasty knees up to
my chest. I'm not doing it. All right?
So enjoy it. So like the entire time
we were, we just flew business class.
All right.
And uh,
every time we'd go on and get a nice seat
and I always just kept looking over it
and he had just go and you can't put a
price on it, you know, you can't put,
just kept saying that and she just kept
shaking her head and you get off the
plane and then they give you a little
pass. So when you went through customs,
just letting you guys know this.
So if you want to use your fucking miles,
I'm telling you, look, if you're flying
within the United States, I mean,
you don't need to do that, I guess
do you have to la as a motherfucker,
but you can handle that. But when
you start talking about a 14, 10,
14 hour fucking flight, take out your
miles, take out your credit card.
Just I'm telling you,
I'm telling you you won't regret it.
So we'll fly it back air Emirates.
And it was one of those double decker
planes and we were upstairs in the
business class. So like
fucking ridiculously excited,
totally exposing ourselves.
Um, and so I got, went up
to get to the, you know,
we sit down and uh,
you know,
nice big ass fucking chairs and I look
and I look over it and Nia and she laughs
and goes, you can't put a price on
it. I'm like, that's right. So, uh,
I get up like about an hour into the
flight and I go in the bath to go to the
bathroom.
When I go in the back and they have a,
they have a bar in the back of the plane,
like not giant bar but
just like a little fucking,
but a bartender sitting there with a
bunch of fucking booze behind, you know,
bottles and all that shit.
And then on either side of the plane,
like the get these s shaped benches with
like four seats with four seat belts
and you can just sit down and put
on a seatbelt. I can have a bar.
So I like my fucking heart.
I can't believe I didn't faint.
My heart rate went through the fucking
ceiling. So I go back and I go,
Nia did come on the back of the
plane. She's like, Wah, Wah. You know,
she's watching some fucking TV
thing. And I go like, come on,
I want to get you a drink. She goes,
what do you mean get me a drink?
She thinks I'm just
going to go back there.
It's gonna be like three stewardesses,
like huddled in the back.
We go in the back and she saw it. She
just starts laughing. We sat down,
put seatbelts on an order,
the fucking drinks,
they're like olives and shit
back there was ridiculous.
And they looked at it and she
finally sent us. She goes,
you can't put a price on it.
There's all of the great fucker moments.
And I sat with her drinking a
goddamn drink flying over Iraq going,
if I'm going to get hit by a fucking RPG,
I'm going to be doing it like this.
This is the way to do it. Right? So, uh,
that is the one thing that I've learned
to all of my fucking travel is that, uh,
you have to have a line.
And once you go and beyond,
I mean, granted, I haven't gotten the
bill yet. When I get that bill, oh, Jesus.
When I get that bill, um,
and I don't give a fuck,
fuck that. I don't give a shit. All
right. I need you to be comfortable.
If I'm going into a goddamn country where
I could get caned are hung, you know,
you want to ride there in a
comfy chair. So, um, all right,
well I'm already 40 minutes in here. I
gotta a fucking move along here, but um,
I can't even remember what I talked
about last week as far as India. Um,
I can't help.
It was such a good time.
Maybe I'll tell the story again if
I've already told it. But after,
after the Gig in India,
um,
I hung out with a bunch of comics all
went out and got dinner and just sat down
and talk comedy for uh,
for like a good hour.
And it was probably one of the highlights
of my career just as far as just one
of the coolest things ever.
You are on the other side of the globe
hanging out and you met people that do
what you do then have the
same passion and love for.
And what was killing me was the questions
with the exact same questions that I
would hear from American
comics are comics.
I meant in the UK or Ireland or
Scandinavia. It's just, it's,
it's the same art form. And, um,
my favorite thing was in the end when it
started getting petty where they would
go in like, all right, Bill,
who's a comic that you
think just fucking stinks,
but for some unexplained reason
is selling a bunch of tickets.
I just started laughing. I was just like,
Jesus, even over here it's like that,
you know. But, uh, I don't know if that's
one of the really cool things about,
uh, about traveling or whatever. So, um,
I'm definitely going to go
back, definitely going to go
back. And what's funny is,
um,
Jerry Seinfeld actually has,
is doing four shows over there.
MMM.
And,
uh,
I was just back in New York next month
he's going to be over there and I was
just in New York was doing the
Patrice O'Neal benefit and uh,
I just happened to run into Seinfeld.
He comes down the cellar, you know,
which is always fucking
unreal when he shows up.
And I mentioned to him that he was,
you know, him going over there.
So it was just kind of comparing
trading notes with them or whatever.
So I can't wait to hear how those
shows go cause he was, you know,
he's asking all the questions like, you
know, can they understand like, yes,
I was like, dude, they get
everything. They get everything,
all the slang and all that
shit. But uh, anyways, I that,
I don't know, I wish I could actually go
to those shows. That'd be pretty cool.
Honestly, and Seinfeld
and fucking Mumbai. Um,
anyways, uh, sell the Patrice O'neal
Benefit Ladies and gentlemen, uh,
thank you to everybody
that came out to the, uh,
to the benefit this year I actually
think was one of the best shows because,
um, we only had eight comics this
year in the past. The thing is,
is so many people love Patrice and so
when people want to be a part of it that
we've been having like 12 to 13 comics
and it really gets like jammed up towards
the end and it's a union house. And if we
go over like, you know, unions, they've,
they're fine sit through the roof and
we're defeating the purpose of why we're
doing this thing. So it becomes
really stressful. This year,
there was only eight moved
along quick. And um, you know,
everybody crushed it. And, uh,
this year was great because I felt like
by having Hannibal Burress and Michael
Che on it, we actually had guys that were
influenced by Patrice has comedy. Um,
this is the first time we
didn't just have like his peers,
the guys who came up with that
started the same time he did,
or maybe a little bit before this is
when we actually had the generation of
comic set as they were
deciding to become comedians,
could actually have watched Patrice on
TV and been influenced by him. And, uh,
those two guys killed it. Uh,
Jim Florentine, Ben Bailey,
David Tell Jim Norton, Collin Quinn, uh,
rich foss hosting it as always.
MMM.
It was just an awesome,
awesome time.
I know I always forget somebody and
they're going to get pissed at me, but um,
yeah,
I dunno. Thanks again to everybody
who, who, uh, came out to that thing.
We're going to of course
do it again next year.
Thank you to the opium Chimi
show for helped me promote
it, but blah, blah, blah,
blah, Blah and all that type
of stuff. And um, I dunno.
It's definitely a, it's, I
don't know. It's been, it's fun.
It's my favorite thing to
do of the year because, uh,
it is such a great cause we obviously
love Patrice and getting to see his mom,
his stepdaughter and his,
uh, his girlfriend and uh,
becomes like, uh, like the standup,
like high school reunion and it's really
fucking cool. So, all right, here we go.
I got to wrap this up because guess what
I'm doing the second this podcast is
over, other than uploading it
is a, I get to go see my dog.
I'm see my dog and like three weeks and
I know what you're thinking. Like bill,
wait, wait. Did you put your
dog? Where did your board
your dog? And it's like, no,
I just kept her in the garage, you
know, Shit and piss all over the place.
But I had plenty of food for and
uh, you know, I had a tie. Paul.
Um,
we actually bought at our,
our veterinarian and my dog is one of the
few dogs that absolutely loves the vet
because she, you know, she's a pit bull.
She's got herself heard a couple of
times cause she's a maniac and um,
you know, my dog's got this
thing that he looks at you,
she looks at you sideways.
Like who the fuck are you?
The second you take care of
her, that's it. You, you're,
you're, you're a made man.
So they took care of her a
couple of times. You know,
she broke one of her teeth one time
and a couple other things she's done to
herself, Bang yourself
up. And um, you know,
they took care of her down there and when
she sees that someone's going to take
care of, she's like, she's
like a little fucking
goddamn baby when she's down there.
So whenever I take her to the vet,
all these other dogs are like wine and
going in there and I'm like water skiing
behind my dog.
She's like dragging me in there.
And what kills me was whenever
I drop her off to border,
she's so excited to be there. She
doesn't even turn around and look at me.
She tails wagging and she just
fucking runs away with somebody else.
Kind of hurts my feelings a little bit.
But um, anyways, let's get to the, uh,
let's get to the, uh,
the, the, the fucking, um,
what am I saying here though? The
letters for this week. All right.
Sam Smith and Tom Petty. I actually
kind of already answered this one. Uh,
when is this one? All right. I've been
a big fan of the podcast for years.
I've got to say hello and correct.
Congrats to you and lovely Nia when
you played Dublin Ireland a while back.
Oh, I got to say congrats to you.
Okay. This is a trivial point,
but I'd like to throw in my 2
cents on Tom Petty Suing Sam Smith.
Tom Petty is almost famous for looking
the other way when people happen to sound
like him.
He's been quoted as laughing it off when
last night by the strokes appeared to
rip off American girl saying
his early stuff.
And then he just said that his early
stuff sat and like Chuck Berry even gave
the strokes credit for owning up to it.
There's a similar story about
the red hot chili peppers,
Danny California sounding like
last dance with Mary Jane. However,
in this case with Sam Smith,
Smith's response to the story
was that he never heard,
I won't back down if we believe that.
Are we supposed to believe
that every musician, producer,
and other asshole heard that
song before it was released,
had never heard Tom Petty's.
I won't back down. Uh,
maybe.
So for what?
My dumb ass opinion's worth petty either
sued because he didn't believe that
denial or who was offended because Sam
Smith didn't know him and not because the
songs sounded alike, but what the hell
do I know? That's actually interesting.
Go back to Ireland sometime soon.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
That's a really interesting take.
I never even thought about that.
If he just owned up to it,
like you have to get pulled over
by a cop and you just, you know,
you know why I pulled you over.
Yup. Yup. I made that illegal.
Uturn why'd you make it?
Because I was impatient and I
didn't want to do it the right way.
Do you know I could give you
a ticket? Yeah, yeah, I do,
but I'm not going to lie to you. That's
an actual conversation I had with a cop.
Okay.
And he goes, all right, I'm going to
let you go. And then I laughed and said,
you're awesome.
And then he laughed like,
yeah.
Not laughing like, yeah, this is
great. He was laughing just like,
it was just a weird conversation for him,
I think.
Okay.
I always tell the truth whenever they pull
you over, you know, I pulled you over.
Yeah, absolutely. Stealing,
doing like fucking, you know,
fast. You're going, yeah,
like 85 soap and I wasn't
going to run into you.
Most of the Times.
They still give you the ticket,
but sometimes if you just fucking honest,
Ya know,
it's towards the end of their shift
electorally. Fucking let you go.
Um, yeah, of course.
Being old fucking freckled faced howdy
duty looking white guy probably doesn't
hurt me either.
I'm already hearing envy.
Anybody not white listening
to this going? Oh yeah, yeah.
Now if I go take the shit out of it, I
know. I know. What do you want me to do?
You know, one of my, I mean,
I, I don't make the rules.
I'm happy it works out that way for me.
Um, I'm sorry it doesn't for you, uh,
moving across the country. Uh, dear bill,
birth bill, I'd think you podcast.
Thank you. Okay. Okay. I just, I,
I just turned 23 years old a few months
ago and I realized I have lived in the,
in the West Michigan town. I've officially
lived in the western Michigan town.
I live in for more than half my life.
Can you guys please?
Yeah,
please try to proof read your
shit. This is a sentence. Okay.
So I turned 23 a few months ago and I
realize I have lived in the West Michigan
town. I've officially lived
in the western Michigan town.
I live in for more than half of my life.
All right.
So it was definitely editing as he wrote
this and just kind of fucked that up.
This crushed me.
Okay.
Why cause you're living in western
Michigan. I like it out there.
Well, you got to move to the
big city. Uh, this crushed me.
So I began saving up as I wanted to
live in Portland, Oregon. Good choice.
I've always been musical and I
want to go do the band thing,
but I've never, but I have an
associate's of science degree,
so if that doesn't work out,
I can go back to school.
But in Portland after
establishing reds, but I'll, I'll,
I'll go back to school in Portland
after establishing residency. All right,
so you've got a plan here.
My question to you is this,
how much do you think I should save up
with the plan to live minimally and just
work a job slash play music?
I've never felt I could express myself
here as I am isolated and since the town
is small, high school follows
you everywhere in which I
was a total weirdo. Slash.
Loser. Uh, thanks and go. Love Yourself.
Um, all right. I totally
relate. I totally relate. Like,
you know,
I was a loser too in high school.
So there was an element of like going
to Boston to try stand up comedy.
And I remember whenever I would get
a gig anywhere near where I was from,
that'd be so nervous that my entire
high school class would show up and they
wouldn't laugh and be like,
dude, you're that jackass.
And went to school with who are you to
think that you could make this dream come
true? Go Fuck Yourself. Right. So
I totally understand all of that.
And I also worked a day job and I saved
up money before I moved to New York.
I paid off all of my debts.
I just paid it down.
I paid down everything and I saved up.
I saved up some money and then
I moved to New York. And uh,
I went there thinking I
got to get a day job and a,
but I had enough money where that wasn't,
you know,
wasn't dire. Like I gotta get a job right
now. I could actually go a few months.
So I started getting some standup gigs.
So,
even though it was negative cash flow,
it wasn't 100% negative. Like say my
nut, I think my rent, I swear to God,
I had to walk two bedroom.
My rent was uh,
it was for 25 a month.
This is 20 years ago.
And, um, but I mean I had no spots.
I had no gigs.
So I think I did a couple of road
gigs when probably back to Boston,
maybe did addict already gig or something.
And I probably made Jesus,
I don't even know. I probably made like
300 bucks, three 75 for the weekend.
But I also had to travel up there
and I took the bus and I had to eat.
So it was probably in pay taxes
on it eventually. So I mean,
I was probably walking away with 125
bucks. So I probably had, you know,
and plus all the other eating, living,
every time you walked outside in New York,
it's like you blew 20 bucks. So, um,
I watched my nest egg start to dwindle,
but after a couple months I
stopped thinking about a day job.
I just started thinking,
um,
I got to get more gigs and
I got to get more gigs.
And then what happened was I was able
to kind of slowly stopped the nosedive,
a cash to level it off a little bit.
And um,
then I booked some acting gig or something
way I was able to make enough money
and I just stashed it.
And at that point then I got to college
age and it just all starts to happen.
You know what? I'm a guy
brought up on this, um,
podcasts before Mike Johnston,
Mike lessons.com.
I'll try to find the video for you,
but he's got this great video
that he does where he talks about,
you know, or maybe I was, when
I went and I saw him live,
I think it was when I saw him live.
So I'll paraphrase what he said,
but when he wanted to
make money as a musician,
you know,
he just,
he just totally like his day, even his day
job, he just stayed in the music arena.
I'm really going to butcher this story,
but he started giving drum lessons.
All right. So that was money
he was earning as a drummer.
He started working at a
music studio, tuning up the
drums and that type of thing.
So that was two way. And then
then he got into, you know,
a couple of bands and he had a couple of
gigs on the weekends. So that was three,
four different ways that he
was making money as a drummer.
And he just keep doing that. So when
you're out there, I would just make,
make it all about music.
You know,
if you get a job at fucking guitar
center or something like that,
you can get a discount on some of your,
your equipment and then you can also get
to know guys and you can start talking
to people. Like I want to get into a
band, join a couple of fucking bands.
I mean that's,
I would do all of that shit.
And then also you can get a discount on
all the recording stuff that you need.
If you're going to start writing songs.
I would just keep getting jobs in the
music industry because it seems to me like
that's what you want to do.
And then your backup is to do this
associates of the sciences degree.
Like that's your backup plan. Um,
just by reading your, your letter,
it seems like,
you know,
you want to be in the music business
that's going to make you happy.
So that's what I would do.
And uh,
he just kind of have to try to shake
off that whole idea that, you know,
you have to fall back on this college
degree and this whole idea that you can't
have a fun job.
You could totally have a fun job and it's
going to be a job and it's going to be
working all that shit, but you
could totally have a fun job. Um,
you just keep applying for jobs that
have fun and you will have a fun job and
just stay there and then
that's it. And then, you know,
you know how to do it though.
Do you eat your ramen noodles?
If you wake up in the morning,
you just have a fucking apple that'll
fill you up and you'll be in great shape.
You just pound some waters.
Um,
you know, you know the deal.
Everybody fucking does this shit.
I use each spaghetti. That
was my thing. Spaghetti and,
and a couple pieces of bread. And that
was my dinner that would fill me up.
And uh, I remember I didn't
have any of, have a table.
I had a fucking chair that I turn around
and I use that as the table and I just
would fucking get the prego and I'd
throw fucking spaghetti in there.
I could make the fucking meal in my sleep.
And you have to measure
the water or anything.
I just knew where to pour it in the pot.
I've just had it every fucking night
and I was so fucking sick of it.
I remember like every once in a
while I would either take a taxi cab.
I just be so tired after
doing gigs and just fucking,
every once in a while I treat myself
to a cab ride. All right. Treat myself.
I'd actually order out.
And when I say order Ron,
I'm talking like ordering
Chinese food. Um, cause you know,
when you first moved to a city,
you know, I'm from a small,
tiny moved to a big city,
you're on your own and it's really on you.
Uh, you're terrified to spend money.
This is creeping thing, you know,
you got to get your footing once,
you know, you've survived for seven,
eight months. One day it just kinda hits
you like, Hey, I'm on my own here and I'm,
I'm making it. It's a
great failing, you know,
even though you've got fucking spaghetti
coming out of your goddamn ears. Um,
so good luck to you, sir.
All right, so a workout,
a William B, do you still work
out? If yes, what is your routine?
Do you do any running or biking?
Love the podcast man. Uh,
I actually did quite a bit of working
out when I was on the road because I was,
you know, eating airplane food, airport
food and that type of stuff and Gig food.
Uh, and I only think I put on like
five pounds, which is pretty good,
you know,
for the amount of time that was away for
three weeks to only put on five pounds.
And really what fucked me over
was when I went to New York.
I was there for a few days and uh,
oh, the booze was flowing anyways.
Um,
do I do any running nine oh two running,
running kills my fuck. You know, you
can't do that to myself at my age.
You can't keep running like that. It
fucking, you need your feet, your knees,
your hips, you need all of that
shit for the rest of your life.
What you really have to do at my age
is actually finally sit down and learn
about nutrition. So you're not
eating your way into the gym.
You're actually eating your way out
of it so you don't have to do as much.
I do a lot. Like I take my dog. Um,
there's a lot of hiking trails out here
in la, the fucking greatest city ever.
I love it, man. I'd have to be
in a freeze and fucking New York.
I love New York and that
shit. But, uh, Jesus Christ,
when it's that fucking cold and
there's no Christmas lights out,
it's pretty goddamn bleak.
Um, but anyways, yeah,
I kind of do that. And then I'm
into, uh, your own body weight.
I have a climbing rope, I
got a peg board, I got a,
I got one of those pull up dip stations.
I'm into that type of stuff cause I
feel like it's a much better strength.
Yeah.
Being able to move your own body and
it's much more practical when you're in
situations to be able to move your body,
um,
climb up on to something,
lower yourself down onto something.
Just getting it up and out of bed is
easier if you're used to being able to
handle your own body weight as opposed
to that weird shit with like bench
pressing,
which is you're pushing all this weight
up off of you while adding this mop
muscle weight to yourself,
which is, I dunno,
it just seems more of a complete
workout when you move in your own body.
So I'm into that stuff. And, uh,
I'll skip rope I guess every once in a
while, but I make sure that I do, like,
I don't jump up too high.
So it's more like I'm kind of not
even like running in place so much,
just sort of lifting a foot up
and setting it back down. Uh,
once you get the muscle memory down,
you can really minimally
be slamming your joints.
Is she coming back down?
Uh,
it's sorta like lightly running in place
as you do it. And I'll just do like two,
three rounds. I, you know,
it's funny, as I brought it,
I brought a jump rope on the
trip and I never used it once.
I just never fucking used it. But I did
do like a lot of that elliptical shit.
And,
um,
I dunno.
So what I, what's my routine?
All right. So my routine, I do
a set of pull ups and I do it to
exhaustion as many as I can do.
And even after I can't put my head
over the Chin a get my chin over the,
over the bar, I still am doing Reps. Uh,
even if you only go halfway up a third
of the way up an eighth of the way up and
just to exhaustion, that's
the first set I do. Then,
uh, I climb up the rope, go back down,
and then I go over to the peg board.
And it's weird because my garage
ceiling isn't high enough.
I had to buy the skinniest ones and to
have them go horizontal. So I'm actually,
I only do the peg board but I go to the
side and at this point I'm only at the
point where,
you know,
I can take the pegs out like
two or three times total.
MMM.
You know, and actually make it
happen. If you do get a peg board,
you want to aim a little bit
higher than the whole because your,
your body is going to be going down.
So you actually stick it in there.
And then the next time I go through is
I do a set of pull ups where I do the
negatives.
Will you pull yourself up over the bar
and then you lower yourself super slow
and that actually helps you
reps over time. And then
the next, and then I do the,
I got this tree that I jump up and I,
there's a branch that goes
way out where I kind of do a,
how the fuck do you describe it? Right
hand over, left hand, right hand over,
left hand,
walking out towards the end of the branch.
And then I come all the way back again.
Um,
and I tried to keep my arms
at like a 90 degree angle,
not just hanging straight down like that.
Um,
okay.
And then the third set I do is a wide
grip and then it's the same again.
And I go back up the rope instead of
the tree that time, something like that.
And then I'm always switching it up.
Um,
sometimes I just do three straight things,
a regular pull ups or whatever.
This sounds boring as shit, so I'm gonna
move on. But that's basically what I do.
And then I take my dog for a fucking hike.
That's it.
And then I try not to eat like a fucking
animal. They go and that is my workout.
Let me actually do the last bit
of advertising here. Fucking that.
Richard Simmons,
the hell am I doing here?
I'm sitting in candy striped shorts
right now. People doing this podcast.
All right,
stamps.com everybody get your
mailing and shipping done.
Getting your mailing and shipping
done can seem like a no win situation.
Nobody wants to go to the post office.
It takes up valuable time.
You don't want to lease a postage meter.
It's expensive with the multiyear
commitments and hidden fees.
Who the hell wants to deal with that?
Do you want to deal with that? No.
Well luckily I know a better
way. What is it, Bill?
It's stamps.com stamps.com you can buy
and print official US postage for any
letter or package right from your desk
using your own computer or printer.
Even get the special postage discount.
She can't find it.
The post office plus
stamps dot coms is a more,
is more powerful than a postage
meter at a fraction of the cost.
You could save up to 80% compared to a
postage meter and you can avoid all those
time consuming trips.
To The post office.
I use stamps.com to send out all the
bullshit that I said left or my shows.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now use my last
name bur bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a hen $110 bonus offer
that includes a digital scale and up
to $55 freeze posters. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
enter
bar. And lastly, but certainly
not leastly legal zoom.
I'm going to use this shit this month
cause I gotta I have to get a wealth.
I finally,
I got to get a will together.
The best time to start getting
your life organized is right now.
And the easiest place to do it is legal
zoom.com. Getting your life organized,
uh, with protecting your family.
And a great way to control you,
uh, take control of your family's future
is making a will or a living trust.
You really got to,
you got to do this people.
MMM.
Then again, you know, you look at
the Robin Williams family there,
they're challenging the wealth.
You want to do this basically so the
state doesn't have it and the only people
that are arguing over the will or people
that you want to get stuff anyways,
I guess that's why you do it.
I don't know. But anyways,
that's where legal zoom can help you.
There's no easier way to make sure your
family is legally taken care of getting
your life organize also means taking
control of your financial affairs.
So if you're thinking of starting
a business or you have one already,
legal zoom can help you form your business
and provide the support you need to
run a successfully for more than 10 years.
Legal Zoom has helped millions of people
get the personalized attention they
need and if you need
legal advice or guidance,
they can connect you with an independent
attorney in both since they are not a
law firm. A don't wait any
longer to organize your life.
This is literally talking to me right now
and save even more by entering bird in
the referral box.
That's discount code,
burr discount code bar for legal or
help you can count on for your family a
small business. Go to legalzoom.com today,
legal zoom.com discount code burpee.
You are are all right.
Mercifully the ads are done for this week.
Um,
let me close this here.
All right. Out of the closet.
Here we go. Dear bill,
I'm a 17 year old high school student
who recently came out of the closet.
Congratulations. That's it.
Very courageous thing. It's 17.
Um,
I have always been fairly timid and
don't have a very aggressive character.
Once again,
even more courageous.
Three years ago I found your comedy
and I was inspired by your race,
your religion of logic and passion.
Listening to your comedy and hour on
the podcast gave me exposure to a strong
personality that I could relate to
internally and be inspired by outwardly.
If this is going to be all compliments,
I can't read these. All right,
some point you got to shit on me.
Uh,
without exaggeration,
exaggeration and moved my type table
up at least a year for forever.
I plan on waiting til I was 18. Thank
you for the inspiration. Good, sir. Uh,
this is where you call yourself an
idiot and downplay the situation. Ah,
your son of a bitch.
You with two sentences short.
I lifted that moved from you two.
When my aunt said I was very brave.
I just brushed it off like you will
with this email. Go Fuck Yourself.
Jesus Christ. He's fucking
guy's killing it here. Uh,
should I be worried? Oh, it's totally
different. This is a different thing.
I actually just assumed that this was
a guy too. It could have been a lady.
All right. Should I be worried?
Well, congratulations sir. Or ma'am.
Um, where am I? Uh, should
I be worried? Hey Bill.
Burrington the first,
please read this on the video.
So I'm an English guy studying psychology
in France and I've been dating an
Italian girl for the last five months.
Do what? Do you fucking James Bond.
Yeah,
I'm insanely in love. It's
international cunt. What is the problem?
Should I be worried?
You should be worried.
You're an English guy living in France,
studying psychology date
and some Italian woman.
That's fucking awesome. I
want you to life. Uh, he goes,
I'm insanely in love with her
and I think she may be the one,
or at least the mother of my
hypothetical children. Hilarious.
We both have a long
history of relationship.
I've been with a lot of girls and
she's been with a lot of guys. Nice.
You both experienced when he came
out of it unscathed? No STDs. That's,
that's great for both of you.
You know what that's like when you've
bagged a lot of women and she's banged a
lot of guys and you get there unscathed.
You know what that's like?
That's like one of those great
fucking Superbowl matchups you know,
that's a pickup. It's like
the cowboys steel is 79. Uh,
I'm insanely in love with Tara Bubba
Bubba way. Okay. The other day I bought,
I brought up an ex and this
obviously pissed her off. Yeah.
What the fuck you don't do that?
Because she then said she was speaking
with an x on Facebook and he said he
wanted to marry her. I know she's
still friends with some of her exes,
those so am I. But I still, you
guys both need to fucking grow up.
All right. Either get out of this
relationship, friends with your exes.
But I still think her getting messages
from these guys who clearly still want to
fuck her is messed up obviously. And why
you still talking to your ladies? Uh,
you're keeping them in your little
fucking Dick Orbit, aren't ya? Uh,
we're moving in together at the end of
the year and usually you would say dump
the bitch. No, I'm not. I'm
saying you both need to grow up,
but she says she loves me and I can't
lose this one. She's fucking beautiful,
smart,
funny and sweet.
So should I be worried about these fuckers
and therefore bring it up or should I
just shrug it off? Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Well,
I think you need to do what you
need to commit to this woman.
You have to tell us. Say, listen,
I'm not talking to any of my,
any more of my exes and it, and I would
appreciate it if you would do the same.
I think we got a great
thing going here and um,
you know,
I don't,
I don't feel it's right then I'm still
in contact with women that I used to be
intimate with. It doesn't feel right
to me anymore the way I feel about you.
And I'm hoping that you feel the same way
about you keeping in contact with your
excess.
I'm not trying to have a fight here.
I just want to have a
rational conversation.
Just start that way and then you know
what? You commit to her dude. It's over.
Okay. All those other fucking guys
at Bangor and all that type of stuff.
Did they give her a ring? No. You know,
so you sound like you're an
older guy as far as like,
you've been down the fucking,
you know.
Okay.
You know, you've been hacking your
way through the jungle for a while.
Who the fuck's kitten home? All
right, what are you going to do here?
You know you're going to lose this one.
I don't think you're Gunna so commit to
her and then just show you come in by.
But you know, once you lead by example,
maybe that'll work. I don't fucking know.
But uh, that whole bullshit
where you both stay in, uh,
well you're both fucking um,
okay.
You know, staying in contact
with the x's is bullshit. Uh,
come on. Who's getting home? And you know,
if you're a little drunk and then
he'd get on the fucking Facebook,
their shit is said Bob bub knowledge.
So you know what you need to do. You're
both too. All right, good luck to you.
All right,
that's the podcast for this week.
You'll fuck yourselves if you'd
like to donate to this podcast.
Anytime you go on to Amazon, you're going
to go buy yourself a little hairnet.
You know, maybe an apron a, if
you go to, uh, my wet website,
[inaudible] dot com and you go into
the podcast page as an Amazon link.
If you click that,
it'll take you right to Amazon,
then buy whatever the fuck you want and
it doesn't cost you any extra money.
And then they get me,
they give me a little doe
ray me for driving traffic
to their website. That's it.
Simple as that. If you don't want
to do it, I totally understand. Oh,
there's Joe to Rosa.
Joe To Rosa will be at the punchline
in San Francisco this weekend.
Oh, twinkle toes himself. So if you're
in the San Francisco area, it goes,
see fucking Joe to Rosa.
All right, there you go.
That's my 2 cents for the fucking week.
Uh,
I'm going to get caught up on some
Bruins games. I'm psyched to be back.
And once again, thank you.
Thank you to everybody.
Australia, New Zealand, Zealand,
Singapore, Hong Kong in Mumbai. Uh,
thanks for coming out to the shows.
Thanks to all the comics that I got to
hang out with and shoot the shit with. Uh,
there's no fucking way. I'm not going
to come back and do it again. Uh,
I just got to write some more
bullshit. Um, I had a great time.
So that is it.
I'll talk to you fuckers next week.