Hey, what's going on? It's Phil Burn.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, October 26,
2015 what's going on?
How is everything good with you?
Did she have a good weekend?
Oh God bless you God. Play everything.
Go with the family. All got pleasure.
Um,
I am in beautiful downtown Detroit,
Michigan.
Um,
I know some of you probably laughed cause
you fear all that fucking shit about
Detroit. All Times fucking
cities. Awesome. Um, can be scary.
I'm not going to lie to you,
but every time I come here it
gets a little bit better. And um,
you know, it's kind of a fucking
exciting thing. You know,
it's one of our great cities here,
sits there right by the lake, right?
Lake Erie,
you know,
beautiful Goddamn city.
You know,
I like when you go through Detroit is
you always see a bunch of Cadillacs,
Buicks. Even though those
fucking cops left this place.
I swear to God, man, you know, I don't
know who's at fault for that shit.
If it really is just a corporate greed
or if the unions became just such
constant was it was cheaper.
I always go with the corporate guys
being assholes because you know,
basically if you didn't have the unions,
we'd have sweatshop labor in this
country. Right? So then they just went on,
but then the unions became,
oh my God,
the unions have horrible reputation,
which is well earned, isn't it?
Oh, it always starts out with a good
idea, does it, you know, some theaters,
I go to a union,
some art,
and sometimes the unions are cool
and sometimes they're not. You know,
fucking guy's just sitting there on
a chair, you know? It's like, dude,
why would you do that?
Just go on the back and play cards.
I'm sitting there looking,
knowing that I'm fucking paying you.
You're not doing anything.
I Dunno. Look at me.
I'm all over the map right now.
Anyways,
that's one of the worst fucking
things we ever did was a,
I dunno, we allowed all of that
fucking industry to lead this country.
So fucking stupid. We should still
be here making those cars right.
And you can feel good about it.
You know what I saw more goddamn Buick
Regal [inaudible] he brought that car
back, you know, and it
looks fucking cool, right?
Bewkes always had cool front
grills, but you, yeah. You know,
just grossly under powered.
That'd be a great car to fucking to Redo.
Just pull the whole fucking drive,
train out and put a new
suspension and it just, you know,
have you self a fucking sweat.
Right.
Keep those granny looking
fucking tires and rims. Um,
just like that.
What's that movie?
What's that movie Ryan Gosling was in
and he would pause 30 seconds to deliver
his line. He had that, that Mona Lisa
smile he always has. It was at Mona Lisa.
It's much soda regard. Right?
I always started ricotta cheese.
I guess we got,
I'm learning all this shift from fucking
Versie and Joe Barnick that to half
Italian set or on the fucking
bus listening to Italians
talking about food is
the one of the funniest
fucking things ever.
But then after about like 15 minutes,
they, it's as annoying is, listen to this.
Somebody who's talking about their
kid that you don't give a fuck about.
You know what I mean? Like, oh, you
can't believe so then little joke,
he came in raw 80 Edital slippers on.
He was so cute. And I said,
Joey t know what time it is?
A said it was 14 o'clock.
Hey, isn't that funny?
That doesn't exist.
You just got to sit there and be like,
I don't give a shit about that
little snot nose kid. Right.
Then you get fucking Barnick and Barney.
Conversely,
when we were in Pittsburgh
and we played Heinz Hall, um,
they went to some fucking Italian Deli
in the morning and came back with all
these cheeses and uh, they
came back with this, uh,
was a Kappa Cold Capicola Aka Gaba,
Google,
which was fucking unreal. I guess it
comes from the, the neck of the pig.
You would think that would be any good.
They came back with spicy gobble,
Google the,
and um,
it was finished. It was fucking
amazing. But they wouldn't shut up.
I guess it comes from the shoulder
and the neck, I should say.
They wouldn't shut up about it.
They're going to bill.
And then the core Dan Oho section,
it was just cheeses.
They pull whole load,
Mozzarella,
a Vogel fucking go and on and on at k
and then we're standing in and then Joe,
I pull out this piece of bread bill and
I handed to Joe and he squeezes it and
it, he nodded at me, dude. It
was like a mafia hit man. Talent.
Somebody was going to get whacked. All
right, and then you think it's over.
And then we go over the US and
they had all these all in day,
it's spicy olives they had
all is with garlic in it.
And I was like, I'm getting the
spicy one and a Joe's like, oh,
I'm getting the fucking garlic
and then and all these, why'd you like,
all right, I get it. Jesus Christ.
Fucking get it. I see it.
It's right here. Try that.
Try it to try it. Sharp
provolone. Go ahead and take
a piece of that and I'm not,
I'll put it on a bread, put it on the
bread, pull little Gabo go one day
I'm fucking around it.
It's actually hilarious.
But they just wouldn't
shut up about the place.
And the food was unbelievably
delicious. That fucking great. Okay.
But you can understand, I'm German, Irish.
All right. We just put shit in a pot.
You boil it and then you
think about either or, uh,
eliminating a race of people.
That's, that's, that's the family
tree that I come from. Right?
There's nothing about food.
MMM.
It's probably just all jealousy, man.
The fucking food was unreal. You know,
it was funny.
Versing made me a plate or on the bus
ride and he makes me a plate and I can
tell he's got his back to me and I can
tell just the way he's laying it out.
He's so fucking excited. He wants me
to love it as much as he loves it.
Right? So I fucking,
uh, I, he gives to me,
I started eating and
it's fucking delicious.
And I didn't realize he's waiting for me
to say it's delicious cause I'm so busy
eating because it's delicious.
And then he just sort of like,
just was looking at me. He goes,
how is it to cook? And I just,
I spit, take bursted out,
fucking laughing. It's like,
yeah, dude, it's delicious.
He was like, I could good.
Like he was almost like,
I don't know
why do it? Why don't we Italians give
a fuck that much about food and every,
everybody else doesn't.
They pretend to nobody gives a fuck.
Okay.
That's why they, food is so fucking, I
believe it's the best food on the planet,
you know? Fucking it. Yeah. I,
you start to make a meal and it's an
Italian person in the fucking room.
If you start fucking it up,
they'll get emotional. Like, oh no,
what do what you did? No, no.
You want to put the fucking here,
but go was your job to do a uni? He
just like, don't just, you just do it.
You just get over here.
You know what I mean?
It'd be like if I started playing
drums in a black guy, walked in a big,
all right, do it hit here's a
statute. You just do it. You just,
I don't know why you're just better.
So anyways, I never heard a
capicola before. You know,
I heard a cabbage,
you know,
bratwursts and sausages and all of that
fucking shit. You know, it's funny.
As much as I love Italian food,
I would love to,
I'd love some fucking some
German food right now.
So krauts fucking giant God beer Stein
dress like I'm going to walk out of a
cuckoo clock. You know what I mean?
You would think about Germany is,
is we're never going to shake
off that world war two shit.
We're just never going to do it. You know
what I mean? We went too hard. You know,
it's over how you, there's no way.
There's certain things that you do.
There's no comeback from, I don't
give a fuck how good a car you make.
You know what I mean?
I don't give a shit how good your beer is.
I don't give a fuck how good the
watches you make. You know what I mean?
Okay.
You pick one wrong guy
and he ruins it then just fucking real.
How fucking long, you know what I mean?
What about Attila the Hun? Where
was he from? That's what happened.
He was from some fucking, I dunno.
Empire, right? Who was that guy from?
Was He from Jersey? Let me look at this
guy. Who was the guy that the fucking guy,
the impaler. Vlad Vladimir. The impaler.
What the fuck was that maniac from?
You don't know.
Or wherever the fuck he's from doesn't
exist anymore so people can move on flat
and mayor, the impaler saw that
the who they based like Dracula od.
Where is the battle? Vladimir.
The impaler. Here we go.
Okay.
Oh Jesus Christ. I gotta
tell you something right now.
This fucker Detroit. Why?
But believe something to be desired.
You know what is exciting about fucking?
Yeah. It's not going to come up. Let's do
one. That stupid pinwheel speeding. We,
Tony Brown
given me no internet.
You fucking try to read about the dude.
She was stuck. Would [inaudible]
got no. All right. Vladimir,
the impaler was a member
of the House of Dracula,
lest some shit. Yeah, this is all. Do
they base track it? Where was he from?
Okay.
What street?
What country was this guy from?
Transylvanian noble woman.
That was his wife
House. House of Jackie. The father.
I don't give a shit about his dad.
Where they from?
Yeah.
Bluster. Vladimir. They have
a fucking bus to this guy.
Okay.
You know what I mean? You go to Germany,
they don't have a bus to Hitler. Do they
buy all damage down out.
Don't bust a move.
Right.
Fucking have a little hologram.
A fucking Caitlin doing the running man.
You know the thing about it is,
is every other cunt, you know,
wherever the fuck they are from,
it doesn't exist anymore.
Okay.
Book imprisonment and hungry.
All right, so there's a country.
Okay.
They put that guy in jail.
They didn't fucking impale him.
Did you ever hear about like
in PA I didn't pay it. I'm
not going to go through.
I'll go through a really quickly.
They basically split you up your backside.
Alright.
Grease up a fucking stake.
Yeah.
And basically use your body weight
to have it go in through the outdoor.
Sometimes it pay,
eventually your body weight,
their pairs that shoot through your gut.
Sometimes it would come all the way
up to the person's fucking mouth.
Take like fucking, I dunno, 12
hours to days to die that way.
And he used to do it all fucking time.
He had like a whole fucking field of
people there and he'd be sitting there
eating some Gaba. Google with
the vogue in gs and Musu rep. Um,
no one knows where he is. Where's
he from? Romania. You know,
they were able to shake it off.
Can you say, Hey, oh, I'm Romanian.
What did they think?
They think you're a gypsy stealing a
fucking wallet in fucking Rome. That's,
that's all they think. You know
what I mean? You say you're German.
Do they think about the bear?
They think about the cars? No.
So he's like, what do you a Nazi?
Uh, no I'm not. I'm not, I'm a drunk.
I don't know how to make a car
anyways.
I don't know what I'm talking about
here. Um, let's get back to Detroit.
So I guess the owner of
the Cavaliers Isam, shit,
I probably should have got the guy's
fucking name he bought like fucking, like,
since like 70 buildings out here and
he's giving major companies breaks,
um, to come in here. I guess
Google has some offices,
Twitter or something like that and it's
starting to build back up again now
whether he did it for
financial reasons or one,
it's the most patriotic thing that's been
going on here in a long fucking time.
And um, and other cool things. When
I went to Cleveland, Cleveland,
like every time I go there,
every two years it looks,
it's making a major comeback.
I was joking when I was on stage,
they had like flowers going right down
the center of the road and one of the
roads that was unheard of 10 fucking
years ago when I was out there,
I told you I used to get an escort
from the fuck and I don't meet a hula.
I had like a cop have to walk me over at
the end of the night from the club over
to the hotel to make sure I wouldn't
get jumped. And hilarity was the only a,
I was the only,
you know,
only show in town right there and
now that whole fucking street,
it looks like the Vegas Strip.
And I'm telling you,
everybody out there,
if you make it some money,
don't sleep on the so called rust belt.
It's coming back.
You could make you fortune there.
MMM.
It'd be cool if there was a way to
fucking do it and not displace the people
that already lived there.
You know,
if he could somehow by a fucking building,
fixed the fucking thing up and then
help out the people that were in it.
But it never works out that way. It does
it, it's gotta be a way to do it. Right.
If you're dead it yet, it
ended up on Oprah. Right.
And she'd say your name.
Uh,
I don't even want, I'm talking about here.
So we've been rolling through here. Um,
I am on a fucking bender. Alright.
I every fucking show I go,
I'm not drinking afterwards.
And um,
and then it just happened to me. I'm
just, I have to break this fucking habit.
It's heavy.
You know what I got into on this trip,
I got into light beer from mill.
I was never a Miller lite guy.
It fucking hated it.
But they brought back the old school
bottles that they used to have those short
squat ones. And when I was coming
back from the Notre Dame game,
we had them in this fucking ice
chest and they was so god damn cold,
so fucking delicious. It just turned
something on. Now I'm like craving it.
Last night I was just like,
all right guys,
I just want to go home and I'm fucking
right outside the Fox theater by the way,
which is one of the top three theaters
I think I've ever played in my life.
Um,
I probably say Carnegie Hall,
Chicago Theater,
and the Fox Theater in Detroit. Uh,
but the tabernacle and Atlanta is cool.
There's so many cool ones. But
this one was, um, you know,
we got to the show a little bit late,
so I didn't have time to go out and like
look at it before the crowd came in.
But when I came walking out with the
lights down was reminded me of like Royal
Albert halls, like fucking gigantic. It's
one of the biggest places I ever played.
And, uh, the crowd was amazing
and afterwards we embark nick,
we're hanging out in the lobby part in
excel and a CD and I was taking some
pictures and shit talking to
the people down there. And um,
so, you know, we were all talking
about how we're going to be good boys.
We're not going to go out and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Then, you know,
I get very easy, low key starts fucking
laughing and next thing you know,
you know bad around the place.
They had a place to get tacos and they
had another place to get fucking, uh,
drinks and shit. But I was like, no,
no, no man, let's get in the car.
Let's just go back to the fucking hotel.
All right. They a little hotel bar.
They ever get one quick one,
we'll watch the end of the panthers
fucking eagles game. We'll go to bed,
we'll call it a night. He said, then
we show up, we sit down at the bar,
there's some guys sitting there and it
looks like he just sat down in a four top,
just left at the bar. Um, and I found
out all of the drinks was hit were his,
and he was a chef and he was trying every
drink that this place had was sampling
them or something. This guy
Manny. So next thing you know,
we start doing what he's doing
and uh, Eh, it was stupid.
I just remember verse, he would, you
know, you don't mix liquor, right?
And we're doing it just because we'll
laugh and cause we know it's stupid.
And I remember we'd drag this fucking,
it's coffee flavored Tequila and as
versus bringing it up to his lips,
he goes off, I'm definitely puke it
tonight. And then he just throws it down.
So the weird thing was I was so many
different kinds of liquors in me head,
a Moscow mule.
I had some patrol,
I had some like this fucking that coffee
flavor patroned I had one light beer
from Miller then add this other shit that
had like an orange in it with bourbon
in it.
And the funny thing was is I didn't even
feel drunk and I'm going to VRC like,
I think this shit's water down.
He goes, yeah, it's a good point.
I don't really feel drunk either.
And then I went upstairs
and got on facetime and I
got into a big fight with my
wife and I woke up this morning and I
was like, yeah, I guess that was drunk.
I was just being mean for no reason. And
I'm not a mean drunk, I'm a happy drunk.
But when you fucking, you know, cross
pollinate and all of those things, I was,
I was, I wasn't mean. I was, I was surly.
She was like, you, you went drinking.
I was like, no, it's painted
asshole. You know, it's funny,
she's such a sweetheart.
She hung up on me and she apologized
to me so I got to wait til she wakes up
cause I'm still on east coast
time and I'm going to fuck,
I'm going to apologize to her.
I'm sorry honey. I'm sorry.
So sorry that I drank 50 different kinds
of booze and then I called you and I
was a red cunt.
Can you ever forgive me lady?
Um,
hey, just laid it all you guys know. Uh,
I have still have some leftover posters
from that tour that I did up the
northwest, the tour where I got the
inner tube standing in the dry river bed.
That one. Um, they will go on sale
tomorrow morning. That's Tuesday morning,
October 27th,
2015 cause God knows you
might be listening to this
five years into the future.
How's California doing?
Person in 2020 is it still exist?
All right. Very limited
northwest posters less than 50.
Also there will be 75 Bible
belt posters available.
They're all autographed and um,
you can get them a off of the merge page
on [inaudible] dot com. All right. Now
what did I want to do here?
There was something I was going for.
Well that's right. I got to read a little
bit of advertising here. Yeah. All right.
Oh, okay. Here we go. We're
starting right out of the gate.
Oh.
Bodo boat boat me ids beyond
these GI got switched up there.
They're fucking soft as felts. Boo
Doo doot, doot me undies, v and D,
put them on with a belt and walk around
like you're superhero and get fucking
arrested for taking out your deck.
But your boss will feel nice and good
when you sitting in that holding cell next
to a rapist. Get yourself some
soft underwears me undies.
We all know how sexy confidence can be.
I don't know what it is.
And that confidence comes
from being comfortable.
You can't be comfortable when your balls
are for rubbing up against some sand
paper there.
But how great can you feel if your own
words wrinkling and riding up me undies
gets it.
And that's why they've created the
world's most comfortable underwear for a
daily dose of confidence.
A dose of confidence stowed.
It's up against your balls all day.
That's a heaping helping of confidence.
You can be walking around like that guy.
Remember that guy that you know they
were singing the whistle and song, right?
Dad, Dad, dad at at, at, at
data. Boom, boom, boom, boom.
I remember the Guy Cause
he's Dick finally worked.
And then you know what's funny?
I ended up seeing the guy who made
that product on American greed.
It never worked,
but me undies works and so does the copy,
so I'm going to keep reading it.
You wear underwear every day.
You need to be extraordinary without
an insane price tag beyond these
understands this and that's why they've
created the world's most comfortable
underwear. Luxury at half the
retail price you find anywhere else.
When you look good, you feel great. It's
a cliche because it's true. God dammit we,
Andy's understands this and that's why
they designed underwear that makes you
look and feel fantastic.
All right?
Yeah.
Beyond these is made from modal bowed
out a fabric for the life of me.
I don't know why you go. It's pronounced
and you're right. It all in lowercase
either the front or the second
first syllabo. Second syllable is,
is accented.
Can you help me out here model?
All right.
Mandy just made from model or medallion
promote Al got to go to booze.
A fabric that's twice as soft,
softest cotton.
That's twice as soft as whatever
underwear you're wearing right now.
Unless she got on a pier me undies
there be and he says tons of colors and
styles and they even have a,
and the only place to get matching pairs
for men and women even release a new
design every month. Um, I wear
whatever free period they give me.
My balls have never complained.
My balls never shut the fuck up before
I got this underwear. Now they're happy,
his health, you know, it's
like shutting up. You'll lady.
Plus we all know that paying for
shipping sucks. So me, and he says,
removed that from the equation.
All orders in the U S and Canada
shipped for free me. And he says,
even more has a money back guarantee.
If you don't love your first pair,
you get to keep it for free. You
literally have nothing to lose. Uh,
to sweeten the deal,
me undies is offering 20% off your
first order and me undies.com/burr.
That's a special offer just for my
listeners and wherever else they gave this
copy to make sure you go to [inaudible]
dot com slash bird and get 20% off your
first order. So they know that we
sent you all right. Trunk Club,
Trunk Club Shock.
It's too many hard consonants here.
Trunk Club shopping is awful.
Who has the patience for crowded stores
or the time to try on 10 pairs of pants
that don't even fit? Well, you know,
standing behind some do with that really
wide pants and are unbelievably flat
ass. You know what I mean? You can
literally put a billboard on its, see,
can't walk around them.
By the time he get fucking,
you get around the
circumference of the person,
he's already walking in the doorway,
then you're behind him again.
Then you exhale really loudly
and he turns his head right.
You see that neck fat, the Gaba, uh,
shopping is awful.
Whereas the patients for crowded stores
and the time to try on 10 pairs of pants
that don't even fit well. Well, if you
knew you, I hear, we hate that line.
If you knew your fucking size,
you wouldn't have to.
And if even remotely knew what color
pair Pa and I tried on 10 pairs,
we know the mall sucks. All
right, but here's the problem.
You still want to look great.
And with Trunk Club you never get to set
foot and you never have to sit and set
foot in the mall again.
Trunk Club takes the hassle man out of
shopping by shipping you a trunk full of
clothes that fit perfectly and unless
you lied about your sizes and make you
look like 1 million bucks with all the
new fall styles@trunkclub.com slash Burr
you answer simple
questions about your style,
preferences and sizes in our
signed in expert stylists.
Now people don't lie about your sizes
and then blame trunk club. All right,
go get yourself measured down to some
habit dash store so you know what the f
you can know what the damages,
uh,
they cure rate close from the best premium
brands you approve of what you like.
And just like that a trunk
arrives on your doorstep filled,
filled with handpicked clothes that
are perfect for you. Try them on,
keep what you like and easily return what
you don't like in their prepaid trunk.
This is not a subscription service.
You only pay for the clothes you keep
from your trunk. No hidden charges,
just great closes, closes,
just great clothes.
Get started today and Trunk Club.
All this is all in capital letters.
Get started today.
And Trunk Club will style your clothes
for free plus free shipping both ways.
Why do they want me to yell here?
You only paid for closure.
Keep to take advantage.
Go to trunk club.com/burr one last time.
It's trunk club.com/burr for a trunk
filled with clothes you'll love wearing.
Um, all right. How many minutes into this?
24 minutes. It's 9:54 AM all
right, this is gonna work out good.
I've gotta be on the bus it fucking
11:00 AM. And then tonight we're,
we're a in grand rapids, Michigan.
And I got some relatives coming
out to that. As I mentioned, I got,
I got relatives in
Indiana, Ohio, Michigan.
I'm from out these here parts.
And uh, oh. So I got my,
I got speaking to underwears.
Yeah, Trunk Club and me undies.
I actually did my laundry or had
somebody do it for me, you know.
Uh, I walked like a mile and a half
through downtown Detroit yesterday.
Uh,
which is a scary thing for anybody to do.
Forget about when you look like
a sickly Ron Howard. And um,
I went down and, uh, founded laundry mat.
This is like the greatest fucking feeling
when you're on tour is when you get
your laundry done. You know what I mean?
Is it starting to pile up in your bag?
You know, you got it all fucking twisted
up and you, you fucking grocery bag,
you know, and all of a sudden
you look in any and you,
your suitcases getting all empty looking
cause everything's fucking dirty.
I mean, I went over there and gave him
every fucking thing that was dirty and uh,
a laid it down. So that's going to
get me through the rest of the tour.
But when I get to Chicago,
I'm going to get my, uh,
my laundry done again is I hate having
a dirty laundry in my fucking luggage.
It's just fucking gross, you know, and
you just pay somebody else to do it.
Don't be a cheap content. All right.
I went down there, it was minute,
it was a dollar 50 a pound minimum
10 pound thing, and I went down.
They would just my fucking me undies,
me undies and Mike,
one of the fucking socks. Right?
That's all I brought down there, right?
Because they're going to dry
everything on high, you know,
they get dry.
Everything on high c can't give him
anything that's going to fucking shrink.
So you don't give a fuck
about you underway. Sucks.
So I'm just bringing that shit down there.
I mean,
it probably weighed two pounds and they
still charged me $12 and 50 cents to do
it. And you know what? I don't
give a fuck. I would have
given him 20 bucks to do,
to pay another person to do your
laundry. I mean, Jesus, Craig,
you're living like a king. They
got it all folded, you know,
washed my compression socks.
I wear compression socks now.
It's really helping us.
I'm getting this fucking varicose
vein treated in my left leg.
It's really helping it out. The Guy
told me to get them. It's like, dude,
I'm not wearing those fucking socks.
I might as well get soc
guard is at that point.
It's basically like the Allen Iverson
sleeve that he wore for the last three
quarters of his career,
except it's on your legs. Um,
and it feels weird at first,
but I got to admit on a cold day,
it's kind of Nice to have socks
that go up to your kneecaps,
but when you put them on and you're
standing in your underwear and you've got
them on, like last night I had the
old man once, like I went to a,
I bought some from Nike that
were actually that kind of Nice,
but I bought the old man
of ones from the fucking,
like the rite aid of the fucking cvs and
they'd just jet black and they went up
to my knees and I was standing there and
my fucking underwear and I just burst
out laughing.
I look like dead fucking 50 year old
married white guide that gets busted,
you know, get an thinks he's getting
no hooker and it's some undercover cop.
And then I just start crying.
Well, I thought it was always
just trying to talk to her poop,
right. Being that guy. Um, by the way,
I apologize for putting
that image in your head,
but it was just too fucking
funny not to share it with you.
MMM.
So anyway, so I went on a
nice walk this morning. Uh,
it was a nice mile and a
half walk there and back.
And then I did it again this morning.
And, um, you know, it's cool.
It's cool to be in downtown Detroit and
as people come in and work down here,
excuse me, hiccups here, uh,
people coming down to work. Uh,
it's great to see Cleveland comment
back and all this. I swear to God, man,
I've got to buy something out here. I
think it's a smart move and it's really a,
I think it's a patriotic thing to do,
to invest in a fucking city.
That was the shit and it should be the
shit to try. It should be the shit.
It really should. Cleveland should be the
shit, all of these fucking places. So, uh,
he can bama be the like, don't wanna beat
the real estate agent for these fees.
Fucking cities and a, and I won't take
a commission. How about that? Yeah,
you can buy something for nothing,
you know,
and he can help his fucking place come
back. I mean, I don't know. You figure,
you know, you start buying up buildings
and then they legalize weed, right?
And then somebody buys the old Packard
fucking factory and he just start making
weed in there. There you
go. That's the fucking move.
You come back to Detroit and all those,
you know,
grandsons and granddaughters of the great
auto workers in this country, right?
They go back to work in the same factory,
except you're growing weed.
Come on, man. That's like that Michael
Keaton movie from way back in the day,
except you got weed in
it, right? I Dunno. There,
these are just ideas. I'm just
throwing it out there. All right,
let's talk some sports here.
Let's stock some sports and we'll start
with the greatest fucking sport that's
ever been created.
Nhl Hockey,
God damn motherfucking cock
sucking Frenchie sons of bitches.
The fucking,
I can't even shit on him at this point.
The God Canadians are nine
and eight. Oh nine, eight. Oh
have won 18 out of a possible 18 points.
And for the longest time nobody in the
east look like they could fuck with
anybody in the west. And uh, I dunno,
it's looked at me. Well, the
best record out in, uh, out
in the West, who do we got?
Los Angeles is,
is five and three after a slow stat,
the turn it it on Nashville.
Six and one Dallas thousands looking good.
Huh?
Six and two when a pig, you
know what it is. So they have,
don't have a tough guy.
I don't know if that's because we
got rid of Lou Cheech or whatever.
From what I heard, I was talking to
a Canadiens fan last night. Actually,
Ted took a picture with them too, you
know, she's like, and I actually made his,
his girlfriend or wife standing
between us because it's too,
I can't put my arm around you
with that fucking shirt on. Um,
but he was saying that,
uh, they, they don't have,
they don't have a tough guy
anymore. And, um, so I dunno,
I think that might come
back to haunt you if he,
if he ended up playing whoever the fuck
makes it to the finals out there. Right.
Kings a tough Winnipeg's tough Chicago.
You never fuck with the Blackhawks,
right? I Dunno who the
fuck knows. But anyways,
congratulations to those cons.
I mean,
you gotta you gotta you gotta give
respect to that night and it was fucking
insane. But the Bruins playing in
on, right? They're doing all right.
Three one and one that's a winning
record. I think the, uh, the tie there,
we fucking blew it
against the filthy flyers.
And then we came back and we beat
the islanders. You know, Craig,
he's having a fucking career year
that he's leading the Leed points.
I don't know. I'm psych and um, you
always can be great. When I get back,
even at the games that we lose,
I don't give a shit.
And we have all these games on my DVR.
I'm going to sit down and watch all of
them. I get to watch a game at night,
you know,
sometimes two games at the Bruins,
half a game and I'm gonna get
all fucking caught up. Um,
and the NFL yesterday to
Patriots beat the jets. Um,
I got to tell you man, jets were
getting 11 points. I loved that fucking,
I love that fucking bet.
The jets getting 11. Um,
I was actually thinking that we could
possibly lose to them just because we add,
we have no fucking offensive line and
they got a great defense, you know,
Reavis is going to shut down his
whole fucking part of the fields.
And um,
what did we ended up winning by?
We ended up winning by seven points,
but uh, Edelman dropped that pass.
Then he always go for the new drug to
appear as, and we build a blue. Yeah.
But if he caught it, maybe they would've
done something different. You never know.
So, uh, you know, we beat the green cons.
They're not the green cards anymore
cause rex Ryan isn't there. But uh,
I got to admit, it's um, kind
of, uh, this is the German in me.
Was it going to shine? Freud?
Is that what they call it?
Taking pleasure out of somebody else's
suffering. Seeing the bills struggling.
Not because I don't like the bills just
because rex Ryan talks all these shit
about what he's going
to do to the Patriots.
It's kind of fun to see the jets be
equality squad with the class act for a
coach,
you know?
And to watch him fucking lose into
Jacksonville all the way over there in
England. Fucking great. But the
sunbelt rex, I still love the guy.
I'm feeling bad for me. It looks
like he's putting on weight again.
I think he's stressing, you
know, talked to all that shit.
There's always people talking shit.
There was somebody on the jets talk shit.
But what? They were going to come up
and due to the Patriots and saying,
why would you do that?
Why would you give them extra motivation
to help people continue to fucking talk
shit. You know what I mean? We
know you think you're going to,
when we know you're going up there
to win and we know you're not scared,
you just don't say it. You're
dope. We go up to, we go,
we'll go blue blue. We go there.
Yeah, it's how you're going.
You're gonna go up there and play
football. How about the dolphins?
Jesus Christ.
Talk about making your former coach look
like a fucking jerk off they came in
there and absolutely raped
the fucking Texas. You know,
where they went like fucking 97 to two.
Where is it is you can tell I was on a
bus. They barely saw anything. I watched,
I watched the Dallas game and I, uh, and
I watched the Patriots. That's all I saw.
And I also saw the end of the panthers.
It's pissing me off that I keep missing,
uh, the panthers play because
I feel like I'm missing a,
the emergence of the next great
quarterback in the league.
And for the life of me,
I can't remember his name,
but he has those Michael Jordan
years where they're really tiny,
but they looked like the top just
staple to the side of his head.
And he's also one of those guys
that he yells a lot, you know,
he walks up to the camera
and for some reason
it goes,
ah,
which is really gonna.
It's gonna be difficult for me to enjoy.
What should I just, that's the
generation gap. I for the life of me,
I don't fucking understand that Johnny
Unitas through for 41,000 yards in the
fifties and sixties. Keep he beat out the
next guy, but like 15,000 fucking yards.
I don't think there's any footage of him
throwing a touchdown pass and walking
up to a camera with this flat top.
Ah,
that's
back when you could fucking hit the
quarterback until the end of the play.
You can keep hitting the guy
maybe. And if he ever did that,
it was because he was screaming in pain.
I was kidding who?
I'm an old fucking white guy.
What do you want from me?
And I want the game to
be the way it used to be.
We established the running game
and then you throw the ball. Um,
but anyways, um, the fuck did I want
to talk about there was something,
I'm all over the map because I'm stressing
because I got to finish this fucking
thing and hopefully this internet won't
suck and I can try and upload it here.
Um,
so I figured the next thing of course
people were going to play in our division
will be the dolphins and I imagine one
of them is going to talk shit about how,
um, you know, they don't think the
Patriots are as good as it used to be.
The fucking sick of is too sick
of that. Did that, did that. Uh,
all I know is a patriots on a collision
course with the New York football giants
to be undefeated.
And I said Diversey last night
and my drunken stupor, I go,
can you do me a favor?
Can you just have the giants
beat us during the regular
season this year and not
in a,
not in fucking the,
not the Superbowl.
I Dunno.
I'm really praying for the packages should
to knock off the fucking giants cause
I do not want to see them
again. Uh, I don't, I'm good.
I'm fine with just losing to them
twice. I'm, I'm good with that.
Rather than rolling the dice and
risking losing a third time. Um,
even though it'd be great to
come and beat him, you know,
and this is why I don't play professional
football because even as a fan,
I'm a little fucking girl. I don't want
to see them again. They always win.
Um, but what was I gonna say? The, uh,
you know, Odell Beckham that they got
and then they got the fucking guy,
just a salsa dance. He's coming back.
That guy's coming back. Then again,
it's going to be a fucking
nightmare. Fucking nightmare. Um,
hopefully we get healthy or
offensive line gets healthy, but uh,
who knows who the fuck knows what's
going to happen. But, uh, anyways,
let me get to some of the reeds
here for this week. Um, all right.
Who versus home? People always try to
explain this to me and I'll never get you.
I'll never get it. All right, Bill,
I have the solution to your who versus
whom dilemma that will solve the issue
for the rest of your life. Okay, IOP.
Now one of those snake oil salesman.
I feel like I'm in your tent right now.
You're starting to religion.
You know when you're fucking
putting your hand on my forehead.
Exercise and the demons. Um, if
the statement could be answer,
if the statement could answer,
answer the question with him or her,
then use whom?
Whom did you say that too?
I sent it to him. I said
it to her. Not he or she.
So it's home example to who told you that?
He told me that. She told me that no
fucking way. It's sad that studies.
He who told you that?
She did.
Whom did you say to a certain,
wait a minute. So now using it as
wait. So if I, to whom do
I owe this pleasure too?
Yo tell him children's home.
Who fucking did it? He
did it. Jesus Christ.
It was that easy. What the fuck were
you 40 years ago when I needed you?
Maybe I could have passed the class.
Got To Notre Dame become a lawyer.
I hope that made sense. It totally makes
sense. I just hope I can remember it.
You know what? I'm actually going to
take a picture of that in my phone.
Speaking of which the
phone starts ringing.
Hang on.
Oh Shit. Hold on. Hold on. Huh? Hello?
I thought it said 11.
Okay.
It's, it's, it's, it's Paul
and Joe down there already.
No.
All right, well I'm finishing up
my podcast. I'll be down there 11.
Sorry about that.
Okay.
All right buddy.
See you a fucked up.
I thought I said 11 o'clock.
That was the bus driver going,
just checking.
We did say it's fucking hilarious. 10,
10 because we've always been on time,
so he knew. Um, so anyways,
um,
yeah,
Goddamn it, you fixed it. You fuck,
I got to take a picture of that.
Whom did you say that to?
Who told you that?
That's all I have to remember.
Yeah.
I wish it was more fucking
sentences and then, you know,
you gave me 10 of them and then I had
to try to guess. All right, good fellas.
Dean explained. Oh my
God, I feel fucking smart.
You know what to think about whom is
you can't use it without looking like a
Douche. The only time you can use
whom as if you write something.
The funny thing is if you, if you
use whom, you know what I mean?
You sound like those, uh, you
know when he stepped on the bull,
those guys from fucking trading
places. Um, but if you're,
if you're writing a, you know,
an email or sorry, even tweets,
something people would call you out on
it because if you don't use it then,
then you look like a Douche.
So I think that's the other rule,
you know what I mean? Like,
Hey, who would you say that too?
You can't be in a bar and be like,
hey, whom did you say that too?
I said to him, you fucking dose. Right?
You can't do that, but you're right,
it down everybody, you know,
everybody sees it. You know,
they just break your balls. So
there's another roof. All right.
A good fellas seen explained that. Okay.
Last week I thought that the reason why,
um,
Joe pashing the end
Scorsese just brings back
a Tommy's character and he
just pointed the gun at the
camera and start shooting was because
that was Tommy from beyond the grave
shooting fucking,
uh,
Henry because he was a rat
and ratted everybody out. Um,
so somebody said, Goodfellows x, that was
my theory. Good fellas seen, explained,
hey bill,
you mentioned in your recent Thursday
morning podcast your theory on why we see
Joe [inaudible], Joe [inaudible],
Joe [inaudible] fire a pistol.
Fucking brain is three fucking words
ahead of my mouth at the screen at the end
of Goodfellas,
it's actually an old modge or a
homage if you're in a bar, uh,
to the 1906 black and white film as
opposed to the color films back there.
The great train robbery.
It was the first film with a narrative
storyline and at the end there is a shot
of a cowboy looking at the camera
who fires his pistol at the screen,
just like in Goodfellas. I
actually watched the clip.
It's pretty fucking cool.
It was very jarring to the film audiences
who had never seen anything like that.
And in many cases,
movie goers would duck or a shout
thinking they were actually being shot at.
It's not fucking hilarious because
everybody had a sad iron back then.
Um, just a little film history
from a film nerd to you,
the funniest read to you,
the funniest redhead and the plan and keep
up the good work and go fuck yourself.
Here's the movie. All right.
I will definitely post that.
Uh, that, uh, that clip.
All right, election bill.
You've been pretty quiet about
the election. Seems like,
uh, they got their start early this year
and people are going to be tired out by
February.
If you had to vote today,
do you know who you'd vote for a also,
is there anyone less stable
looking than Hillary Clinton?
She can't be getting any good sleep.
Love you and your wife. Thanks for,
for the weekly laughs. Uh, I thought
Hillary crushed it on that stupid inquiry.
You know, I didn't understand
what the fucking problem was.
She admitted that had happened on her
watch and she took full responsibility for
it.
So like what was the fucking problem?
Okay.
You know, that seemed like a, you know,
deflate gate type shit.
I mean, honestly, what,
what are you supposed to do to
stop a terrorist attack? I have,
they've said that forever. Like even
the secret service says, you know,
if somebody doesn't
give a shit about dying,
the only thing that they can
share is instantaneous death.
After you do whatever the fuck
you're going to attempt to do.
You know what I mean?
Once you take out the fucking,
I don't give a shit whether
I live that this, you know,
it's over.
So I mean, what are we going to
do? You know, was an away game.
It's fucking horrific that it
happened, but I'm out. You know,
she should have done this. She should
have done that. The same people say,
and that Saint George Bush kept us safe
after nine 11 but they don't bring up
the fact that nine 11 happened. What?
He was fucking president. Right?
The same people breaking fucking
Hillary's ovaries are fucking rub.
And George Bush has balls and
then vice versa, the same people,
Finger Bang and Hillary of fucking
twisted up. What's his face? His nuts.
Rather than giving them
a pair of me undies,
what he's supposed to do when
somebody doesn't give a fuck,
you know,
what are you going to call you up and
tell you what they're going to do?
Yeah.
You know, I don't know.
By the way, we met a,
a professional pilot commercial
pilot, by the way. Um,
and uh, he knew some of the
people on those flights, you know,
some of the pilots and that type of shit.
So all these fucking people that are
trying to say that it didn't happen,
that they were actually fucking these
missiles or something like that that was
shot in there. I mean, um, I
dunno. And that's coming from me.
He was a fucking conspiracy theory. Sorry.
GAVISCON everybody. Hey there. Bilderberg
just checking in on you from
fucking Southie kid. Uh,
I listened to your podcast almost every
day in the sea of cubicles. I work in a,
you are the fucking mouth.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
I also saw your comics come home,
but Boba last year and there were a
bunch of constant front of me who are
getting offended at the things you were
saying and it made it funnier for me and
my girlfriend anyways.
Oh, I remember that.
That one was a little bit of a
rough one, you know. Anyways,
I just came across Dan Carlin's hardcore
history podcast and the first one that
is free on iTunes is the wrath of Khan
series on Gangas con and the Mongol
Empire during the Middle Ages.
This dude was one of the greatest men
and conquerors who ever lived and his
story is incredible.
The fear and loyalty this man instilled
in people of his day is unparalleled.
Although he's responsible
for 20 to 80 million deaths.
He completely changed the world and built
the largest empire the world had ever
seen.
And I thought you might be interested
in it because you've talked about other
great men who have lived in the past.
Arnold Schwartzenegger thanks for a
great show and go fuck yourself. Yeah,
see there's another one. You don't even
know what it is. There's no footage
on like Vladi the fucking impaler
and fucking, uh, the g man,
they're fucking gang his card.
So you know,
nobody got where you are
fucking, you know, get that.
What do you and not seek think,
you know, I gotta check that out.
I gotta I gotta listen to that.
I gotta be in the mood to
listen to a fucking podcast.
Like I love being on podcasts,
I love doing them, but, um,
I just, uh, my brain is, I can't
handle just sitting still. That lock,
I guess I could have it on
in the background is I was
doing something else maybe
cleaning up or freshening
up before a show. Um,
all right. My roommate is a
pervert. Okay, here we go.
Uh,
but let's go back to yet,
do you realize the work it is
to kill 20 to 80 million people?
I mean, you could do it today with
just a push of a button, but back then,
I mean you've,
that's like before they had like the
fucking lawnmowers with the engines in.
I mean, you had to push the fucking
thing. You Self, do you know what?
I'm so old that we actually had
one of those when I was a kid.
Okay.
Was the fucking worst. And if it
was to gift of grass was too long,
he just,
I just didn't have the strength to do it.
So you'd push it forward and then had
to go back and you had to get like a
running start,
you know?
Okay.
Oh it was a mess of so hard
to keep it fucking straight.
That's basically like if you had
to look up a push mower that,
that didn't have an edge in,
in it,
I would think that you'd have
to like be cutting it every day.
Like George Michael did with his beard
and then it'd be like nice and easy.
Right. But she went on
like a bender, you know?
Oh you went away to some place that they
used to vacation back in the day like
Sarasota,
Florida or myrtle beach or some of the
classic ones that they used to go to way
back in the day.
Reno,
you know those old school places,
Palm Springs,
you know when you came back you fucking
lawn was through the God damn. Well,
I guess you do it the wintertime,
right?
All I'm saying is that you
were out there all the time.
That's probably why a lot of
people weren't as fucking fat.
Although you know what the
big thing was back in the day,
everybody was scared about was just having
a heart attack because they couldn't
do any of those fucking,
I'm gonna send rhinoplasty,
which of course is your nose
gets getting a nose job.
Do you know there's
something called rhinorrhea.
I learned that by ringing about
heroin junkies and shit like that.
That uh, oh, of raw ryo Rhea.
See if I can look it up.
I know you guys think I'm full of Shit.
It's like diarrhea of the nose.
It's just fucking when you,
uh,
one of the symptoms when
you're quitting cold Turkey,
Rhino,
see I spelled diary Da da Da.
A r. R. H. E a, something like that. Oh,
there it is.
Brian or Maria rhinorrhea.
Rhinorrhea is a condition where the
nasal cavity is filled with a significant
amount of mucus, mucus, fluid.
That condition commonly known as a
runny nose occurs relatively frequently.
Rhinorrhea is a common symptoms of
allergies or certain diseases such as the
common cold or Hay fever. Oh, I thought
that test when you were a, I thought you,
I thought you said you were all
right. Spider. Um, I thought,
I can't even say it because
I've done it so many times.
I always started imitating fucking spider.
I thought that rhinorrhea was an next
level runny nose that you got when you
were kicking heroin. Um, I've kind
of got interested in all that,
like the whole heroin epidemic that's
going on here in this country. Oh,
by the way, I keep forgetting to bring
up to how great the Indianapolis Gig was.
First of all, I got to come
back and play this theater. Um,
do you remember that story I told you
guys and I put the video up where, uh,
I was playing a theater upstairs and
downstairs. Was that totally Elmo show?
Whatever the fuck it was, keeping up
with the muppets, whatever the fuck,
I don't want to come. You
know? Um, and when I walked
the door of to the backstage of
their theater was open and like all,
like the count was sitting there and
Bert was there an Oscar the grouch,
like these actors in these suits and
they were just chilling out, you know,
and they look tired from doing a
bunch of shows. So it was hilarious.
So I filmed them and all of a sudden
Bert got up and came walking over and was
waving his hands. I thought he
was saying, what's up my God,
look at birthdays coming up here.
And he fucking reached out and slammed
the door. And I was just like, wait,
wow.
He really is a content.
We're real used to happy go lucky one,
I was choking in Indianapolis that, um,
that Ernie, Ernie parents six like
it or accepting of his homosexuality,
right. We're Burt's weren't like
they kicked him out of the family.
So it caused him to be like sad and
bitter. You know what I mean? Um,
but thank God he had earning his
life. Right. Cheer him up. Um,
anyways,
and then I posted the video
and then sesame street told
me I had to take it down.
The children's television workshop was
like, you got to take it down. That's,
that's not legal footage, which
I think it was. I mean, what,
I don't understand.
What exactly were they going to do to
me if I didn't take it down? I Dunno.
So I took it down and I was like, all
right, whatever, you know, it was,
was they were going through that shit
with the Elmo guy. They said, you know,
fucking it was grab ass. And with some
kid, I have no fucking clue. But anyways,
so this time around, I got
to played downstairs where
the Elmo theater was and I,
it's one of the great theories I've ever
played in my life is far as the crowd
was just on top of you. They had
like those, those little balconies,
things they had like four
of them on each side.
It was like an old hockey arena.
It was just fucking awesome. Uh,
just been an incredible,
incredible fucking, um,
yeah,
credible fucking a tour here.
And we went to one of the sickest
fucking cigar bars I've ever been to.
What's your course? Because I was
fucking idiot. I just walked into it.
I got to look it up right now.
Indianapolis cigar bars.
All right, let's see.
Let's see.
Blend.
This fucking place might've been the
greatest cigar bar I've ever been to.
It's fucking incredible.
You have to go to it.
And they're opening one in
Nashville and Dallas. All right.
Six selection of fucking cigars there.
The Davidoff Davidoff a Nicaraguan,
um,
all these other just amazing cigars.
That's the one that I smoked.
And then they had like all these whiskies,
limited edition list whiskeys and
bourbons sent. Um, that I thought,
I mean, did you know they had
dead Jack Daniels Sinatra?
I'd never even heard of that. We had
partnered with like what the fuck is that?
Like that was his drink and I'm like he
just saying Sinatra cause that was his
drink to like, no,
that's a limited edition.
MMM.
I'm looking it up right now.
Jack Daniels Sinatra.
Where is it here? Yeah, I know. I
never fucking heard of that shit.
And of course they was sold out of it.
Let me do the old Wiki here.
Wikipedia, Jack Daniels, Sinatra Wiki.
I hate. What did you mean that of course
I met that. You know what I meant?
That got damaged.
It always do.
Showing us slot Sinatra's select
as what it was called anyway,
so it was fucking just an
amazing, amazing place. And uh,
don't you ain't these fucking websites
when you go there and you got to fucking
put in your birthday. All right,
I'll give you my birthday.
We'll say a November 11th.
Okay.
1890 to enter.
Please enter a valid year. They
don't think it. Let's see what,
see what year they'll actually
the 1893 they won't let,
let's see when they believe in.
Okay.
1890 how about 1899 do they?
They don't believe anybody's alive.
How about 1900 see that's what it is.
Anything with an 18 go fuck yourself.
Enter
Sinatra's selects bottle of 90 proof
and made with unique Sinatra barrels.
And it sounds like fucking bullshit to me.
Jack Daniels Sinatra.
So what does that Sinatra barrel to
get a fucking to pay on it? Sorry.
Select pays a tribute
to Jack's biggest fan.
Mr. Frank Sinatra.
The Sinatra barrels have deep grooves
on the inside of their staves,
which exposes the whiskey to extra
layers of boke a god damn it.
Now I got to get a bottle,
but she can't just get a bottle.
They got a video here of
Frank Sinatra porn it.
I wonder if his fucking
next akin gets any money.
Do they got a picture here sitting at
the bar of Sinatra laughing while Jackie
Gleason's laughing with Frank Sinatra
and Jackie Gleason. We're close friends.
In fact, it was Jack Jackie
Gleason himself who introduced
frank to Jack Daniels.
And as the story is told,
it was sometime in the 1940s Jackie and
frank was sitting together at a bar in
New York City. Frank was for
loan over a woman, probably.
What a great song about it and was
sharing his troubles with Gleason Franken
formed as good friend that he was in
need of some of the serious drink turning
to Sinatra Gleason responded Jack Daniels.
That's a good place to start.
And then the rest as they
say it was history. Oh,
frank said he needed a drink
now. There you go. All right.
What the fuck am I talking
about at this point? All right,
let's get back to the podcast.
Um,
so definitely check out blending if
you live in. Um, if you live in uh,
Nashville or Dallas, they're on
their way over there. All right,
let's read a couple of fucking advertising
then I'll get the last fucking thing
in there and I'm out, right? All right.
Dollar Shave Club. Everybody, uh,
stop shaving with old
razors. It's gross, man.
Why are you torturing yourself with
gross old blade week after week?
Probably cause you don't want to
shell out $20 for a pack of new ones.
Dollar Shave club.com has revolutionized
the way men shave with dollar shave
club.
You could shave with a fresh blade as
often as she won't because they deliver a
whole sleeve of amazing reasons
for just a few bucks a month.
Their razors are so good.
Millions of guys have joined,
even the billion dollar raise or
corporations are freaking out,
but instead of lowering
their bloated prices,
they're trying to fool you into milking
the same blade for an entire month and
that's gross.
They'd price gouged us for long enough.
Never got back to squeezing weeks and
weeks of shaves out of a discussing rusty
bleed, joined dollar shave club, and
he was a fresh blade whenever you want.
It feels amazing and it's a third of
the price during the millions of others
who've figured out a smarter way to Shave
Joint Dallas Sheep club now by going
to dollar shave club.com/burr that's
dollar shave club.com/bro Hey,
dollar shave club.com/barb all
right, legal zoom, everybody.
He shouldn't have to choose a random
lawyer who charges expensive hourly rates
when you need legal help,
but the legal system is so complicated
whether the choice do you have when you
need help with your business
or want to protect your family.
While you can start with legal zoom,
they make it easy for more than a decade.
They've provided a way for regular
people like you and me to confidently
navigate the legal system.
Legal Zooms, not a law firm,
and that's how they
provide such a great value.
They don't rely on charging you by the
hour. Instead, you'll get a trance.
You get transparent pricing and customer
reviews so you know exactly what you're
getting upfront. If you need
help with your incorporation,
[inaudible] trademarks,
last wills, living trusts, and
more legal zooms. The smart choice.
They've got the right people on hand to
answer your questions and if you need
legal advice to network of independent
attorneys can provide the straight
forward guidance you need. Most states
don't let legal hurdles become an excuse.
Go to legalzoom.com today to start
building your own future the right way to
save even more. Enter burr in
the referral box at checkout.
That's legalzoom.com Promo Code Burr.
Fuck,
I got another one.
stamps.com have he won.
Most of ours are trying to hide,
trying to find more time every day to
get things done so you can't let trips to
the post office slow you down. Well
you know what? Now you don't have to.
Thanks to stamps.com stamps.com you can
buy and print official US postage right
from your own computer and printer
stamps.com we'll send you a digital scale
automatically.
That out automatically calculates the
exact posts that you need for any letter,
any package,
a class of male,
you'll never waste valuable time
going to the post office. Again,
do the right thing from your desk.
Do everything from your desk with
stamps.com print the postage you need,
put it on your letter or package and
then hand it to your mail carrier. Um,
and you're done. That's it. I use stamps.
Com. Just send out all my posters.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name, birth for this special offer,
four week trial.
Plus they give you a $110 bonus plus
$110 bonus offer that includes a post
including postage and a digital
scale. Jesus, Bill, don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeofbarthatstamps.com
enter
bar
are right. Lastly, but
certainly not leastly. Um,
all right. My roommate, my
roommate is a perv, so sir,
billion of Boston. I'm a longtime
listener. Love Your Shit. Anyway,
my roommate just started dating a girl,
a lady,
and they're getting a really,
Copley,
they even talk about having sex
with each other in front of people,
including myself.
I have a girlfriend,
but I try not to be overly [inaudible]
or discuss our sex life in public.
Uh,
the worst part is that they have taken
to having sex throughout our shared
house, including our living
room couch in our kitchen.
I think that their behavior is annoying
at best and disgusting it worse,
but I'm certain,
but I'm uncertain as how I should proceed.
Do you have any thoughts? Also go
fuck you. Go Fuck Yourself. Yeah,
I have some thoughts. Why don't
you sit them down and say, Hey,
can you guys do me a favor and
not fuck on the sofa? All right.
This isn't your house. This is our
house. I don't need your bodily fluids.
All crust it up.
You know on the couch?
Yeah,
I would just do. I would just, you know,
they like openly talking about sex.
Just say, listen, you
have sex in your bedroom.
Don't have sex on the couch
where we all sit. It's gross.
I would say that and I would just, I would
just stare at them until they talked.
Okay.
I just don't,
I go agitated.
Is there a reason why you guys feel it's
okay to have sex all around the house?
I live here too.
Yeah.
You know I make a sandwich on that kitchen
counter. I don't need to know that.
Her ass dripping pussy with fucking
laying on there. You fucking pig.
You guys are both animals. I have no
respect for either one of you. All right.
Go ahead and advocate. It'll be a fucking
who now you don't get to be that mean.
Just be like, listen, I'm
not trying to be a jerk.
I think it's great that you found
somebody that you can connect it with,
but could you not have sex on the kitchen,
counter of pleas or in the kitchen?
I eaten there. It's gross. You
see that's so far over there.
I sit there and I watch TV. All right.
I don't need that. See that table?
I eat there. All right. If you
want to fuck all over an apartment,
you're going to need to get your
own apartment, but until you do,
this is our apartment and don't.
Yeah,
fuck anywhere
where it's,
you know where it's hours.
I feel like I could use who or whom here.
Maybe you should out a home. See if
I can do it here. All right. Whom?
Whom did I say that too?
I sent it to him.
Yeah, that's what you say. You come out
of the gate using home to freak them out.
Yeah,
call, call the guy and be
like, can I cheat? Can I ask
you a question? Be like, sure.
Whom did you fuck on that counter?
He's gotta be a car.
Okay.
Or my girlfriend.
What if he says my girlfriend?
You got to say that. I would just be
like, whom did you fuck on the counter?
Whom did you fuck on the table?
And whom did you fuck on the couch?
That almost sounds like bill Cosby.
And why would a children die?
You can't bring up bill Cosby,
especially when you're talking
about a woman, right? It
was consensual. Everybody.
All right, that's the podcast for this
week. I'll check in on you on Thursday.
And once again, thanks to everybody that
came out in Indianapolis, Cleveland,
Detroit, and Pittsburgh, um,
just for fucking great cities, math for
great cities, and it's great to see,
uh,
all of them are having a resurgence.
Every time I've gone back,
they always get a little bit better.
And I think it's great because like I
said, I love this part of the country.
I'm not going to lie to you. I like
all the parts of country, you know,
I'm a patriotic come
when it comes down to it.
So I'd always made me sad to come to
Cleveland and Detroit and Indianapolis and
Cincinnati and that shit at five o'clock
where everybody just screws it goes out
to the suburbs and the fucking place
looks like a Zombie movie at night. Uh,
it's nice to see some nightlife in that
type of shit. Cause of beautiful cities.
All right. There you go. Legalize
weed. Open the plants again.
Let's grow some weed.
Let's get the world high right then maybe
they'll give us the oil for the price
we want. We don't have to blow people
up. You know what I mean? Alright,
go fuck yourself.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.