Hey,
what's going on is bill burr and it's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday.
UH, June 1st, 2015.
How's it going everybody? How, why? Yeah,
how are things that is good.
Um,
I apologize for a last
Thursday's podcasts.
I guess I recorded it in Mono,
which was just on I guess
not stereo is what I learned.
I don't know if I'm doing it again because
I don't know how to use my recorder
and I am currently not in the United
States, so I don't know any nerds.
I'm where I'm at.
Where am I at right now?
You asked [inaudible] I am in Paris,
France.
Oh,
fancy freckles over here to
get a couple of Maca runes
stake in pumps.
Free Bull [inaudible] Helge ohm frame.
All may know. Um, yeah, I'm over here. Uh,
I dunno. What the fuck, what else am I
going to do? I tell shit jokes in a mall.
Government takes all my fucking money.
I might as well blow a little on myself.
I'm over here with the lovely Nia and uh,
we actually just got here and uh,
we're going to be here for whatever,
seven, 10 days. You know what's cool
man? I'm actually going to go to the, uh,
the Roland Garros the fucking
French Open on the clay,
going to go to the, uh, going
to go to a game at some point.
Going to go over their scalp some
tickets. That's going to be fun, right?
Talking to some fucking French scalper
this goddamn Bahrain is stripe shirt.
It really wished they'd look like
that, but they don't. So, uh,
we just got here to the city.
I'm about maybe 40 minutes ago,
had a decent flight coming over here.
It was a little delayed, but uh,
this guy in front of us. Oh my
God, you guys think I'm an asshole.
I know you do. I know you do. I know
you think I give ne a ton of Shit.
This fucking guy was just one of the most
horrible human beings who still weird.
His thing, like he was walking
around like talking to everybody.
Just one of those older guys that
just talks all the time. First of all,
when he sat down, he's
got one of those, uh,
I lived the good life guts or
one of those bodies, you know,
will your legs and arms are the
exact same size, like super skinny.
And then he's just got
this belly. Um, and he,
and one of those people that starts
to sit down and then the weight of the
decisions that they've put down,
their mouth just takes over
and then they just give up.
They don't use any leg muscles.
They just collapse into the seat.
And that's what he would
do every time he would,
he'd go down about a third of the way and
then just free fall into his chair and
then at the top of his lungs
would go, ah, what he sat down,
which to me was funny. That was just like,
this is an old guy, doesn't give a fuck.
He's probably going to have a
couple of something, you know,
a couple sasper gorillas on the flight.
But dude,
he was so fucking rude
in Maine to his wife.
He was nasty.
Yeah.
He kept telling her to shut up. Like I
tell me to shut up, but I'm joking around.
This guy was serious and one
point he goes, he goes, he goes,
he goes, where my books? And I heard her
mumble something. I guess she said what?
And he just goes, my God, like yelled
at her and then everybody else,
he'd walk up to the guy I used to work
for this place. We had a great time there.
Jay. You're cute. As a button.
Fucking weird as shit. So, um,
okay.
So we're sitting there and
we're reading right from Osh,
whatever the fuck they given us.
Uh, I love her. That's it. That,
that's their idea of a dessert cheese.
The fuck is wrong with you.
Put It on a burger,
take this back and go put
it on a birth. Right. Um,
and then they have like a date and
that's supposed to be like your sugar.
God knows, you know, that's probably
the right way to eat. Who knows?
They're all fucking skinny over here,
but they smoked like a goddamn chimney.
So me, I always think that that's why
they're so skinny. So anyways, um,
I'm trying to watch a couple of movies,
both my movie thing.
Every time I go to watch it,
I'll get a half hour and then the dialogue
gets like the audio gets like five
minutes behind the movie,
which I guess I deserve.
That was my punishment for doing my
last fucking podcast and Manav right.
Let me make sure this thing is
even recording here. Okay. So, um,
I started watching a cupola with the
late Great Phillip Seymour Hoffman.
That guy was fucking unbelievable.
I was enjoying the hell out of the movie,
first of all because I saw in cold blood
a long time ago with Robert Blake and
somebody else, one of the most
amazingly shot movies. Um,
well I guess trauma could probably wrote
the book. God knows I don't read. So, um,
but I knew a little bit of the backstory
and I was really into it and all of a
sudden the audio was like
five minutes behind. Um,
so then I put on Americans
and um,
that was really a joy in that
Bradley Cooper was great.
He was picking everybody off.
I liked how they had the, uh,
soldiers seemed to be talking the way
they would talk, they way they would talk,
you know, it's a bunch of
savages over here and animals,
just the way you dehumanize the
enemy and all that type of shit.
I was enjoying the hell out of it, you
know? And I also, I really respect,
I was almost gonna say archery. What
do you call it? No, that's good.
The bow and Arrow. What's, when you're
good with the pistol and a rifle,
what do you want to sharp shooter?
I just really respect,
I really respect anybody that
is a master of anything and a,
and weaponry. I think he's just a
really cool thing, you know what I mean?
Being a fucking snipers bad ass,
just fucking nice throat shot.
She's taking people out, controlling
your breathing and all of that.
I was really getting into it. I'm really
enjoying it. And then all of a sudden,
like the,
you know,
they're going after this butcher guy and
when it was getting really fucking good,
the audio kicked out again. And uh, so I
was like, all right, fuck this. Whatever.
I'm going to go to sleep,
so I start,
I'm in the middle of sleeping and I hear
this glass hit the floor or something
and the guy,
it's spilled his water,
the nasty guy up front in the row
in front of us or he had spilled a,
his wife had spilled the water and he was,
he just started screaming at
the top of his fucking lungs.
It wasn't like every word. You would just
like, you know, like the way it went,
my box, he would go like that.
He would just be like, oh,
now it's all what you just yet,
I wanted to fucking kill this guy.
He's just,
he was,
he was yelling like he was walking around
in his underwear in his own fucking
house and nobody would say
anything to the guy, including me.
I wanted to stand up and be like,
do we stop fucking yelling at your wife,
your old content. There's other
people on the plane. You Nasty God.
He was fucking nasty, mean son of a
pitch. Then he goes to get off the plane.
He's walking way out in front of
his wife and that type of shit,
just like just a fucking asshole,
complete asshole.
Other than that, other
than that, it was a, uh,
a nice flight over here. So, you know,
Nia picked out this little apartment.
Little is the key fucking word.
Jesus Christ. He's fucking thing.
Napoleon Bang somebody in the
say I'm telling you it's small.
You know what I mean? Now seriously,
it's fucking old as hell. And uh,
so everything in here is like, I
guess whoever owns this, you know,
they rent them out. So everything is
antique. He goes, he's a real antique.
So he's like, these are very
Betty, uh, dedicate. So you,
you sit down like easy, easy,
easy, uh, the table, you,
you set the bull down easy.
Everything is like, it's like, dude,
what the fuck how the fuck apartment
is? I can't sit down. He said,
you know what's funny too?
Cause there's English, you know,
he said the last person who stayed
here was very strong and they kind of
weakened the chair and I wanted
to be like, you mean fat?
But he was a cool guy, man who explained
and everything is that you use the uh,
uh, they stole that is the day the
fatality and it would go dah, Dah, Dah,
that say Yada, Yada, Yada. He had Dah,
Dah, Dah, you liberals, the auto spa.
And so anyways, so we're fucking
over here and I'm sites, um,
my whole thing is my wife's
birthday in a couple of days.
So that's why I brought her
over here. And, uh, you know,
when you're as big an asshole as me,
you need to do shit like that, that,
that'll status.
That shuts him up for a good
two to three days. You know,
when you get back, you got a good two to
three days where they're like, you know,
he took me to Paris, I'm
going to, I'll, I'll back off,
you know, trying to change him
a bitching about shit and um,
you know,
and then it's,
then it's all back to normal and it
doesn't mean shit to other than the,
unless you bring it up, which you
have to do, you gotta be like,
I just took you to Paris really three
days later you still bitching about it,
you know, you got, I'm telling you,
they give us like a boxing
match with as a bigger guy,
he just sticks his myth right and right.
And the other dude's face.
That's what you gotta do. You just got
to keep that mic right in their face,
you know? So anyway,
so why would I do that?
It's such a nice city and I got
to take it to that fucking level.
I'm really laying in this fucking bed,
this ikea bed next to something that, uh,
Louis the 14th probably fucking, I
dunno, bank some whore on and uh,
they got a, I'm looking
out here, the rooftops,
we've got a five floor walk up each floor,
the fucking stairs,
getting more like angled,
like you'd have to have like 20 beers in
you for these stairs to look straight.
Like, like a lot of these buildings over
here. Super, super, super fucking old.
And they don't do anything to update
and they keep 'em all original. So, uh,
they've settled for like three century,
so it's really weird.
But I'm up here on the fifth floor and
I'm looking out the window here and all I
see is like TV and tennis.
It's Miami,
that Flintstone episode when him and
Barney were gonna get in trouble and they
were driving down the street
and he was last someone,
although the wooden TV
antennas by the way, um,
off of the rooftops. So
anyways, whatever, um, um, um,
Pavlin here this week I'm on vacation and,
um,
I had an unbelievable,
a unbelievable month.
I'm still riding high on the whole,
uh, all those shows. I didn't Boston,
so, so here's the deal, you know,
and we spend like 10 days here
in France and then writing,
I'm going to be home for like three,
four days.
And then I started another tour of the
west coast and that ends up in Vegas.
And then Tucson.
So I'm like,
well there goes my entire June.
So I've been doing the helicopter
lessons and I was done.
I basically been done with ground school,
um,
since like February,
but I worked a lot in March and April and
I was studying for the written part of
it. So when I did the southern
tour, I really, you know,
that whole month I was studying for
the multiple choice part, I should say,
test that you had to fucking
take. And, uh, as I told you guys,
I passed that and then I had, you
know, I was looking at my schedule,
I had that run in Boston and then, oh
my June was fucked. And uh, you know,
flying a helicopter is like anything else.
It's like going to the gym.
You don't go for fucking two months,
you're going to come back sucking wind.
So it's like, dude, I got to
fucking put this thing to bed.
So it was just talking to my
instructor. I was like, dude,
I got to take the fucking check ride this
month. I got to do it. And he was like,
I like it. I like it. I like
having a plan, let's do it.
So just studied my fucking balls off
this whole month while doing shows.
I would literally be in the green room
like reading on fucking airspace and w
when correction angles and all of
that shit. So long story short,
um,
yeah,
my check ride was on Saturday.
And your check ride is where you sit
down with the FAA guy for like an hour,
an hour and a half. And depending on
how you're answering the questions,
depends on how long it is. If you
fucking crushing it, it's uh, you know,
it can be short as a half hour if it's
a little bit longer, you know, if you,
if you're not quite getting them and
they'll, they'll talk to you more.
And then if you pass that,
then you go out and fly and it's
all these different maneuvers.
And um,
and then if you,
there's this weird thing when you,
you were either a fail or you pass a
bunch of things and you just failed.
Like one thing,
like if you failed your steep approach or
your hover rado or something like that,
you could pass everything else.
And then when you retook it,
you just have to do that one maneuver
and show that you could do it. So,
um,
we're coming right up on it.
And they ended up looking at my log book
and they realized that I was short on
my solo time and I was
short on my, uh, uh,
my fucking, um, night flying.
So I had to go down there Friday, I was
taking a Saturday morning at 9:00 AM,
so Friday night I go down there all right
around four and I just flew around the
traffic pattern. I needed
a, a one point, uh,
I needed a 1.4 and I was flying around,
flying around.
I'll tell him one time I
scared the shit on myself.
I was gripping the throttle too much
and I started my descent and the low rpm
horn came on and basically if that drops
below 80%, you just fall out of the sky.
So when that fucking thing comes on,
like you just slammed the collective
down and I couldn't figure out why it was
doing that. Uh, for like this split
second, I realized I had a death grip,
not really death up. I just had a
two fucking tiny just let go on.
The RPMS came back up.
But you know,
I could have just rolled the rpms on
and couldn't put it down. But you know,
the first, the first time I've been
alone in the helicopter and the law,
our pm horn came on and uh,
you know,
kind of like,
I brought it in for a landing and just
kind of sat there on the pad for a second,
go and like, all right, fuck it,
don't grab my, is unbelievable.
It's an unbelievable experience.
I can't explain it.
When something like that happens,
it's like the adrenaline rush and you're
slightly nauseous and then you plow
through it and you feel fucking
awesome about yourself. Um, so anyways,
okay.
So I did all of that and then we did a,
I got my points,
I needed 0.7,
so I had a total of 10 hours.
I had my 10 hours of a solo
time and then I forget what it,
how many hours I needed a night flight,
but I was like 0.7 short,
which is a,
yeah,
I dunno, what does that seven
times take? About 40 minutes. Um,
it means basically an hour,
I believe on the Hobbs meter.
Every one is six minutes. There's 10, 10
times six is 60 minutes. I think that's,
I believe that's how it
goes. So anyways, I'm a
flying around with my instructor and
he's taken me through the paces and he's
really, really a stickler, um,
and just gets on you about everything.
And I'm old enough to,
to not be frustrated
by it because I'm like,
I know this guy is being as hard as the
f probably being harder than the FAA
guys going to be on me, which is
going to help, um, come game time.
And um, so anyways, we did like, you know,
auto rotations at night,
you know,
which is fucked because you can't see
where you're going to land until you get
down there.
And the auto rotation is basically,
if you had a drive system or of engine
failure, you use the weight of this ship,
um,
to basically and the glide Jesus
Christ can't even explain it here.
You want to basically establish the 65
not a attitude and the way to the ship,
the air rather than being pulled down
into the main rotor is now rushing up
through it. And that's what's turning
it. And you just keep it, you know,
you want to keep it in the green.
Um,
and you can just,
you can just bring the thing down and
just like set it down on a fucking picnic
table. When you get good at
this shit. I can't do that yet.
So we're doing it at night. I'm fucking
him up and everything. I'm going, fuck,
I'm going to flunk this thing
and I instructors going,
don't psych yourself up,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. So anyways,
I know him take drunk, dragging this out.
So anyways, long story
short, Saturday morning,
I'm going to take it. I wake up at
like fucking three 30 in the morning.
I went back asleep, woke up at
five, and then I just, you know,
I went over everything one more time
and then I went in there and uh,
I sat down with the guy and I was
like, Oh fuck, here we go. Here we go.
I don't want to flunk this fucking thing
and then go to Paris and ruin the first
fucking day of the vacation. Moping
around, ruined it for my wife, you know.
So I sat down and, uh, I had a really,
really cool FAA dude and,
uh,
you know, we went through
the whole thing and you know,
I was getting a lot of questions, but I,
I got, I felt like I got a lot wrong too,
but I got a lot right. And,
um, and then he finally,
and I saw he was getting towards the
end of it and I was just go, I just,
I was gone, but God, he's going to tell
me, I gotta fucking take this over and a,
which is embarrassing because your
instructors or did there at the school,
you're going to come walking
out. Like I failed. And, um,
we finished and he goes, all right, he
goes, that was adequate. Let's go fly.
And I was thinking, I thought that was
horrific. Alright. So we'd go out there,
I'm thinking like, all right, now,
two thirds of the fucking way there,
it's an hour walking out there.
We're doing the preflight. And, um,
I was just thinking of
something my instructor said,
well, it's just like, just,
you know,
slow controlled movements.
And I just made that like my,
my mission statement that I was going
to fly controlled smoothly as much as I
can just to demonstrate that I had
control of the aircraft. Then, uh,
so we go up, right.
And uh, we started him,
of course it's fucking easy is shit.
It's the most hazy Goddamn
fucking day I've ever flown in.
I mean, I couldn't believe it was
still like visual flight rules.
Like that's how fucking hazy it was.
So the first thing we're doing is we're
flying up to this place Rose Hills to do
these pinnacle landings, which
is, uh, basically if you're,
it's like you remember in Mash when they
were flying around the Hollywood hills
and they'd find a patch of dirt to
land on. That's what you gotta do.
So you go to your high reconnaissance
first and you've gotta be talking out loud
going,
all right,
it looks like it's hard packed dirt
sloping down like four degrees.
I got trees on this side.
The wind's coming from here.
Son is not going to be a factor.
You gotta be saying all of that shit
while you're maintaining your fucking
altitude, which is, you know, not going up
and down and that type of shit, which is,
you know,
it's not easy when you start out.
So we started heading up there and I
lucked out. It was so fucking hazy.
We ended up, you know, he goes,
turn around and take me to Compton
content has an uncontrolled airport.
So I turned back around,
I'm making my calls and uh,
on the radio and I think I'm doing
all right. And I'm thinking like,
I've never gone to Compton this way.
And I know basically where it is.
I fly out of Long Beach, said, I know
how to get it where I fly, you know,
westward load departure and you follow
this road and you get to these oil tanks
and you bang a right,
except when north of that shit.
So all I'm doing is I'm looking
for the fucking courthouse.
So I'm trying to stay cool and I'm like,
if I can't find this thing,
I'm going to flunk this fucking thing
and we'll come through the haze.
And all of a sudden I just see it
sitting right over there. And um,
we did a couple of maneuvers.
They're one point.
I was so nervous I forgot to do a clearing
turn and he was all right with that.
Um, I did a running landing. Um,
that one went great. Running landing
was basically if you will, coming in,
if you were at high density altitude,
which means the air's really thin,
you wouldn't be able to,
you wouldn't be able to hold the harbor.
So if you actually came in, how,
you know, your normal approach,
if you went to to try to hold a harbor,
you just basically you'd crash. Um,
so what you do as a running landing,
which is you basically come
in like an airplane does.
It's actually one of my
favorite things to do maneuvers.
And he put it down on the skids and you
fucking slide and your brand gradually
bringing the collective down,
which is the thing that looks like the
emergency brake. That's your power.
You know,
he just brat gradually bringing it down,
creating more and more friction as you
stop and then you're steering the nose
with your feet.
And a I did well on that and um,
I thought I did anyways. He's not
saying shit. So he told me, he goes,
if I'm not saying anything, you know,
that doesn't mean you're not doing well.
You know that you're doing fine.
If you see me writing down that doesn't,
you know, I can be taken a lunch order.
He was real cool, really put me at ease.
So then I did a,
a normal approach and then
I did a steep approach.
Then we did the landing off airport shit.
And then we did a hover auto in
the harbor. Rado is basically,
if you were in a hover like
eight feet off the ground or so,
and I'm all of a sudden your engineering,
your drive train system quit.
Um,
he engine quicks it's going to kick it up.
The nose is going to kick to the
left and then you go right pedal.
It's pedal settle. Kush is what you're
supposed to think. Right. And He,
we'd just done the, the the, which is
basically you go right pedal to get,
you know, straight and then
you settle, you're dropping.
And right before he hit the ground,
you pull the,
the collective up in that
cushions your landing.
So fucking he does it and I'm
thinking pedal settle cushion in it.
And he does it in the low rpm horn comes
on and I'm trained like a lab rat to
slam the, collected them. So
I put the collective down.
Then I was like, no, no, no.
Up, up, up. And we landed hard. And then
he just goes, now why would you do that?
Why would you do? I was like,
sorry man, I got, I go, I was
nervous, man. Let me just,
you can ask him, like, let
me, let me try that again. It
goes, all right, do it again.
And then I nailed it the second time,
but then I was thinking like,
I just fucking flunked it. I just
flunked it. And I, I, the way he said,
now why would you do that? I felt like
I was gonna pass you and now I can't.
So, um, so then we got to do the
last thing, the auto rotation.
So we fly around, we come in and he
could come sit down three, two, one,
we do it.
And uh,
for a lot of the time the fucking
low rpm horn was on, but I kept it,
but I wasn't losing it. It was just
underneath 97% or whatever, once percent.
And then I'd get it back up in and then
it come back down or whatever. And I, I,
but I guess it was good enough or
whatever. So he goes, all right, let's,
I w I didn't know. So he goes, all
right, let's go back to long beach.
So I'm thinking like, ah, fuck,
I just flunked it. Is it over?
I don't know what's going on.
So a flying back and I'm talking to the
guy and he's like a test pilot for these
things and he's telling me all
these cool stories and shit. And uh,
at that point we flew over to Torrance.
We'd already in Torrance where I
did the other half of that shit.
So I was just thinking of myself on the
way over there. I was like, you know what,
even if I flunk this fucking thing,
how cool is it that I, I'm, I'm,
I'm doing a check ride in a
fucking helicopter right now.
If you told me this a year and a half
ago, I wouldn't believe it. Right?
So fuck it. Just keep yourself
in that mindset. So we ended up,
we go back to the,
uh,
to long beach land over at air
plex, set it down. Fuck it.
Set it down real nice.
And he's not saying anything and I'm like,
I'm not going to ask him. And
then I'm thinking, well, ask him.
It's not going to change either
way. Blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then I'm taking everything out.
And they left the key in the ignition and
I was like, oh fuck. Cause he pointed,
he goes, you left a key there. I was
like, Oh God, is that the tipping point?
What's going on? So, you
know, put the wheels on it,
wheel the thing back and then rose, we
start walking back in. He said, all right,
you passed. And I couldn't fucking
believe it. I couldn't believe it.
Um, so there you go. That was my,
that was my Saturday morning.
Uh,
all freckles is officially
a licensed pilot and I am a,
I am licensed to fly
helicopters up to a 12,000,
500 times
I'll fucking call.
Is that? Huh? So anyways, um,
today I know what you think it's, we
do bill, you're going to go fly around.
It's like, no, I'm not.
I'm going to go take the advanced
auto rotation class because um,
I don't think my reaction time,
I didn't like it with the low rpm horn.
I didn't think it was quick enough and
I want to get like he'd take that one,
like the low rpm that I have
to do now to pass my test.
I just had to take it down to the
flare, which is basically, you know,
40 feet off the ground,
gentle aft cyclic and you basically
killing your airspeed and your descent and
you basically stop in the air and then
that's when we roll back on the throttle.
We fly away, the advanced, you've got
to take it all the way to the ground.
So then you actually come in
lower and then as you drop down,
then you just like the hover auto.
He pulled the fucking
collective to cushion it.
And I've watched these guys do it. They're
fucking amazing at it. And it's like,
I want to be able to do that. I if
I can, if I can fucking do that,
then I'll start flying
around the La Basin. So, um,
for those of you thinking like,
Bill, you're already fucking mine.
I'm taking it really seriously.
And uh,
so I'm going to pass that class and get
200 hours under my belt before I ever
take anybody up by now. But, um,
I still can't fucking believe it.
I can't fucking bleed them.
And the great thing now is that fucking
God damn weight is off of my chest.
I passed it. I mean,
instructor told me goes,
this is the biggest hill to climb as
far as like just getting your license,
getting through,
just starting from fucking zero and
getting all the way up there. But, uh,
I don't know.
Getting instrument rated sounds like
it's a motherfucker too and it's like 40
fucking hours of that shit. I don't
know about that one. So anyways,
I hope I didn't bore you
with that. Um, let me, uh,
I got to read some of the
uh, the advertising here. Um,
I'll do it.
I am so fucking relieved that I passed.
Thank fucking God.
Thank God.
If I didn't pass that thing then I'd
have all of June to be sitting there
thinking about it. Trying to cram in
lessons. Thank God. All right, here we go.
Dollar Shave club everybody.
All right people I'm fed up who still
hasn't joined dollar shave club.
I'm supposed to do this.
More Emotional Ra people.
Yours truly is fed up who still
hasn't joined dollar shave club.
They're awesome. No, I'm serious.
Their raises are amazing and it's more
convenient and it costs a fraction of the
price. So what's the issue? Still don't
get it. Here's how the club works.
Go to dollar shave club.com and pick
one of their three great razors.
The two blade humble twin.
Personally,
I think that two blades was the best one.
Blade sucks too,
is perfect. Once they did three or more,
it was too much. You know what I mean?
Who's like Britney Spears
back in the day when she, she,
she just accessorize too much. It's like
Brittany takes some of that off. Right?
Wow. All right. Um,
they got the four blade x and the six
blade executive we ashamed in a fucking
gorilla six fucking blade. They, when
you get to three blades there, uh,
that's what I use. Is that what I use?
Is that what I use? I use the two blade.
Oh, I guess I'm supposed to pick the
one. The two blade humble twin. Uh,
you get your first box in about a week.
It includes a free handle in
a sleeve of blade cartridges.
It's high quality stuff. Everybody,
uh, it's got that weight to it.
Like the expensive ones I've used before.
My exec has six days.
I don't use this fucking thing.
Listen, the exact has six stainless steel
blades. This is for like somebody like,
I dunno what, Eastern
European or some shit. Uh,
my exec has six stainless steel blades
and 90 degree pivot angle and an an aloe
strip. You're never going to get
a shave like that. After that,
they mail you for replacement blades every
month or every other depending on how
you want to do what. He never have
to worry about it again. That's it.
If you haven't joined yet,
you missing out. Simple as
that. Try Dollar Shave Club,
duck.
Go to dollar shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/burr father's
day is around the corner and dollar
shave club makes a great gift.
All right here. Oh, here it is.
Here it is everybody. Me, undies, me
undies. No more sweaty balls, booboo.
Boo Boo me undies.
Biondi get him in the fuck.
I'm running out.
There's nothing fucking
left. What else? Greives with
no more sweaty balls and let me
try some different me undies.
Mondays. No more sweaty tape. Blue Dude,
do me undies. Me undies other.
Are those your balls? No,
they ain't there. Tucked,
nicest, snug up to my scrotum.
I think your balls. I use chrome. Who
gives a fuck? I'm riffing with Tate.
I like to see you do better. Oh yeah,
they're really good for the clam.
They keep it dry. We
really mean it. Sorry.
You know that feeling of
putting on old saggy underwear.
You need another feeling
of great fitting underwear.
There's two times softer than cotton.
You need to know about me undies.
Startcom the undies has the
most comfortable underwear
you will ever try on and
it's insane how good they make you feel.
They fit perfectly.
They don't ride up on you
and they literally pull
moisture rouse away from your
skin so your stake stay cool.
Do you ever see those astronauts when
they're in that zero gravity thing?
They do the somersaults.
That's what your balls feel like
there in me undies right here.
Sandra Bullock right next to him.
Uh,
but they also make you look great.
Go to me undies.com and check out
the photography and for the girls.
Checkout those smoking hot boy shorts.
But you have to try them on for yourself.
It's fucking hilarious.
Checkout those smoking hot boy short
there. Aren't you talking to the guys?
The guys should be checking them out.
You know I had a fucking, anyway.
It's the quality.
Yeah,
I mean it's women really.
Look,
we'll look at those smoking
hot boy shorts on that check.
I guess if you're lesbian,
you do that. I don't know.
That sentence is confusing to me.
There's quality would typically retail
for two times the me Andy Price.
No retail middlemen means more savings
for you here. We'll make it easy.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash and get
20% off your first order and low flat
rate. International shipping save even
more. When you buy a pack of them,
they guarantee you're going to be happy
with them when your first pair is free.
Once you feel me undies on your body,
you're never going back and he
undies isn't just for you guys.
They just launched their all on me.
Why not take all of me
women's Co collection?
Can't you see?
I want my clam dry.
I shaved my twat and I want
some comfortable underwears uh,
sorry of four piece line of
undies designed specifically
for the female body in
all of its complex,
gorgeous as hell. Glory.
But to get that 20% off, you have
to go to me undies. Me undies,
dotcom. Slash. Birth. That's
[inaudible] dot com slash [inaudible]
all right. How many more of
these fucking things are there?
Is Tomorrow we'll do two and two. How
about that? All right. So anyways,
I was reading another fucking
thing. You know, I talked to her,
the baby seals of Washington up on the,
uh,
the shores of the west coast because of
oceans are fished out now on the east
coast of the United States.
You got fucking a bunch of turtles by
just dying off because there's something
like this too much because
the temperature went up.
There's too much algae in the water,
which creates something and which just
gets into the fucking turtle shells.
It gets infected and it actually paralyzes
them and they just drown and they
fucking die. And I,
I'm telling you, I, I,
I think I finally figured out why they
never addressed the population problem.
And it's basically because the upper
1% does not view it as a problem.
They view it as an opportunity
to make more money.
You know what I mean?
To hoard water and do all of that shit.
I was watching this thing on the plane
about cities of the future that they're
making. I mean it's apt. Like the whole
fucking thing is total big brother.
They are saying everybody is going to
start migrating towards the cities and you
have like fucking eight zillion people
living in the city who's going to live
out in the country.
You know those fat cat rich people and
you know what eventually is going to come.
It's going to happen that it's going
to be illegal for a regular person to
fucking go up to the country.
You're going to be shot on sight.
Um,
it's insane what they,
if they really wanted to be responsible,
what they would be doing and being
encouraging people to have less children.
Let's level off it's 7 billion
people and let's try to dial it back.
You know,
dial it down.
Everybody has one fucking kid and then
the people don't have kids or people who
die or people who can't have
kids or gay people. Right.
You know,
it'll actually cut off more than a half.
The way I look at it, right. With one jet,
a generation could cut itself in half
and then the next generation cuts itself
and half, and the next one cuts itself
in half. Right. And then after, you know,
the older generations that had
three or four, they all die off.
If you have like a string of four
generations that all had one kid,
you can go from 7 billion all the
way down to three and a half million.
I think my math is correct on that.
I don't fucking know.
But they don't bring it up.
They don't.
They just fucking figuring out new ways
to corral people and we're going to beat
powdered food. It's
fucking, it's terrible.
Then I, I, I don't really, I don't have
anything fucking funny to say about it.
Let's, let's get scored as something
funny. Let's talk about soccer.
Speaking of billions of God damn people.
All right.
Everybody in America doesn't give
a fuck about soccer. You know,
it's funny cause that Pfeiffer, FIFA,
whatever the fuck they're called,
the f I f a the, the, the,
the ruling governing body of world soccer,
World Cup soccer.
I don't even know what they are. I'm
American. I don't give a shit. Right?
I really don't. I've finally given
up on that sport. I sat down,
I tried to fucking watch it.
It's so fucking boring.
And the crying and laying. I know I've
said this a zillion times. I can't,
like if I'm in England
or something like that,
there's a premier league
game and I go there,
I go to the game and I'm
sucking down some beers. I then,
then I could get into it, this singing
songs and shit and I just, I dunno,
whatever. It's like you were
in a pub with no seats, right?
That's basically what's happening. Well,
they are, but you never sit down it.
So anyways, um, Darin, they're in trouble.
Uh, first of all, this is how big
soccer is, by the way. Football,
let me have some respect here. Call it
by. It's real name football. All right.
For all the, all the fellow
Americans set, listen to this shit.
This is how big a world cup soccer is.
They had some big championship match
recently that wasn't the World Cup.
Or maybe it was the World Cup.
Let's just say it was the World Cup.
The worldwide viewing
viewership was 3.5 billion.
It was like half the planet.
They got a 50 share on the planet.
All right? And they, that was
listed to the end. Something
like NPR I'd like to do,
to put that into perspective,
the Superbowl had 150 million viewers.
Okay.
So if you're looking at it like a TV show,
the Superbowl would get cancelled
to be an absolute fucking flop.
So that's how big,
yeah,
this sport is. And that's how big
that fucking league is. So surprise,
surprise.
Okay.
There's a lot of people jockeying to get
the championship game in their country.
There's a lot of people jockeying
to get the fucking TV rights.
So there's a lot of payola. There's
a lot of, kickbacks is a lot of coke.
There's a lot of horse surprise,
surprise.
So here's the funniest fucking thing is
they're being prosecuted as some of them.
I like nine of them got busted in one,
one network executive is taken off
the fall for an entire fucking, uh,
attire. Fucking, uh, a network.
Just hilarious to me.
I'd love to see what his payoff is
after he goes to that fucking, you know,
white collar jail. It's probably the same
place where they play Wimbledon, right.
And,
uh,
the United States Department of
Justice as the one pressing charges.
And I'm thinking like, what the fuck?
How are we involved in this shit?
We don't even like the game.
This is just gonna be another reason
for people to fucking hate us.
But I guess they did all this
shit with American banks,
so it fell under our jurisdiction.
So not only do we not give a fuck about
the game when I'm going to sit there and
break their fucking balls.
Yeah.
About corruption. You know what I mean?
Because we don't tolerate corruption.
Here are the United States. Ah,
everything's above board over here.
Hang on. I gotta blow
my nose. I apologize.
Yeah. The stupidest shit ever like this.
There's a fucking
zillion dollars at stake.
Yeah.
Obviously there's going to be horse,
there's going to be drugs,
there's going to be a lot of underhanded
shit going on, but nobody got killed.
Right. The only thing that they're
really, I thought was fucked up was they,
they've been accused of
fixing a couple of games.
I thought that that was
fucked up. Although if it's
done on a worldwide level,
you know you do it in some
shit bump country, you know,
and I know you're not
supposed to say that,
but the fact that I haven't named
the ship bump country, can't,
we all agree that there are shipped
bump countries, you know what I mean?
Because for all you know, I'm not
talking about Yeoc did this. Just this.
Just like, you know what I mean?
There's this nice cars in this car,
so it's just like, this really
isn't a car. This is a shitbox.
This was not done correctly.
You know what I mean?
The physics of it, it's
still fucking work. And look,
I'm not saying the trees aren't beautiful.
I'm not saying that
people aren't beautiful,
I'm just saying the way the
whole fucking thing set up,
or if it's being crushed
by a more powerful nations,
I'll, you know, I'll give you a
pass. Shit, I fucked up a hover auto.
That guy gave me a pass.
I can't give you a country.
You know what the Fuck I'm saying?
There's two shitty ass fucking
teams playing each other.
Okay.
You know what I mean? To make an interest.
Interesting. Let's, let's fix the game.
I don't fucking know.
I'm just embarrassed that we're involved
in it and I also think it's fucking
Hilarious, Huh? The rest of the world,
you bunch of scumbags can't even run a
fucking legitimate league like we do here
in the United States. The
national football league, there's,
there's an upstanding that's an
upstanding leak. It's all fucking corrupt.
It's all corrupt.
We take money from fucking cancer to
buy yachts and I collect per fucking
helping out people who were sick.
You know those fucking console over while
we're here in France. What do they do?
Right. The whole fucking
bike thing is, is, is,
is a filthy from top to bottom.
Lance Armstrong figures and out goes,
all right,
that's how the game's played.
I'm going to play it better than
anybody else. It was fucking assholes.
They couldn't catch him.
They had a wait to 10 years later where
they froze his fucking year in Assam
shipped or they finally had a test
advanced enough to catch the guy.
I actually feel like the statute of
limitations to run out on that. Um,
I don't mind corruption and sports
unless you, you're like fixing the game.
You know what I mean? If you're
actually fixing the outcome of the game,
then that bugs me.
But as far as like performance
enhancing drugs and like cycling,
I don't give a shit.
All right.
These people riding a bicycle 60 miles
an hour up and down a fucking mountain,
they're obviously on something and
everybody's on something. All right?
They're all on something.
At that point it becomes fair,
I think. And I say, let them do
the drugs, let them do the drugs.
Let's see the side effects, let's adjust
them. And then once it's all safe,
give it to me. Give it
to a guy like me. Right?
I'm turning 47 and a few weeks.
I love to get the spring in my step back,
you know,
which was a steroids for your hair.
Would that be amazing if he had like,
like fucking mark McGwire like his
forearms. You had that level hair.
Every once in a see a guy like that.
Like my age with hair like that.
It's just like,
dude,
you got no fucking idea how fucking lucky
you white motherfucker. Um, all right.
Let me read some, uh, some of the
questions here for this week. Um,
we have two 41 minutes here.
All right. Sinatra comparison,
a Billy big leagues. Uh, this week
I'm Billy check ride or Billy big day.
Uh,
I recall a few months back you mentioned
Frank Sinatra at the end of his career.
Well,
driving down highway 80,
I saw a billboard for the silver
legacy casino in Reno. Uh,
with you and Frank Sinatra Jr sharing
the same weekend as well as the same
billboard. Oh Man, I'd
love to meet the guy.
Maybe this will drive you
further to become that slum
Lord you've always dreamed
about being after you retired from
co after you retired from comedy.
I'll try to take a picture of
it. Uh, the next time I pass it.
Can't wait to see in Sacramento. Thanks.
And Go. Fuck. Yeah, just soft veil.
It's hilarious. Um, yeah, I told
you guys that story like, uh,
the way Sinatra retired the
right way the first time. Okay.
Yeah. Whatever that line he had that ended
that song who stand in the spotlight.
It was something like,
excuse me while I something step aside
or something and he just steps out of the
light and that was it.
And he was gone and it's like,
that's the way you fucking do it. But he
kept coming back and it's just, you know,
and that was Sinatra.
Sinatra had to make a comeback.
So I understand how this fucking,
okay,
this business works,
like how quickly they forget about
you and all that type of shit. So, uh,
having said all that,
I would love to meet Frank Sinatra Jr
what if I can do that when I'm out there?
Well I have to,
you know what actually in Reno has my,
one of my favorite stores
in a, in a, in the country,
it's bizarre guitar and gunshop I
told you about this same guy owns it.
It's a strip mall,
two stores.
One side is this sick ass
place with all these guns.
Every gun you've seen from every
fucking Stallone movie back in the day.
Awesome guns.
And then the other one is his guitars
and you walk in the guitar place,
it looks like a normal place,
but downstairs is where he has his real
collection of this giant fucking safe.
He has like the third
fender guitar ever made.
Just like there was like,
I don't even,
it was like millions and
millions of dollars worth of
vintage guitars downstairs.
So, um, I'm a big fan of Reno.
I am a big fan of Merino.
I actually like it better than Vegas.
Uh,
I don't know why I'm just one of those
struck in people. I like the, uh,
like those kinds of cities better.
You know,
the ones that are still trying instead
of the ones like, yeah, we're the shit.
Everything's a fuck over. Go Fuck
Yourself. You know what I mean? Uh,
it's hilarious to see. I like those kinds
of things as I'm sitting here in Paris.
All right, periscope.
Hey dear Billy Gates. Um,
I'm sure it's fucking annoying having
people stick their phone in your face for
the watching on periscope.
That being said,
I think you would kill it on
there just once or twice a week.
You should go on and rev your truck
engine while hollering and your southern
accent or Pester the shit out of me.
It's Nia with an n
people and the lovely Nia
n like axl rose, Shannon,
ana knees, knees. Um,
uh, pester the shit out of Nia while
she's trying to read a book. Uh,
I love the podcast now I periscope,
this is why I don't like periscope.
Periscope is like, so like people just
walk in, like comics are doing that now.
They just walk in with it on Luke.
Hey,
walking backstage at the
comedy store, it's like, dude,
shut that fucking thing off.
It's like,
if you want to turn your life into a
TV show, you know, more power to you.
But like, you know what, everybody's
chilling out here. It's like,
and when I do this podcast,
I decide what the fuck I'm going to
tell you about and what I'm not going to
tell you about and uh, what I'm going to
leave and we're going to take out. Okay.
She didn't understand what
I just said previously.
I literally just said the same
thing two times in a row, whatever.
I don't have my headphones on my
headphones. I like my fucking light saber.
It's my security blanket. I don't
have him on, I'm feeling naked. Okay.
I'm feeling very fragile,
um,
for someone else to just come walking
in and it's fucking annoying as shit.
And um, I advocate the, uh,
we got to come up with something
for people who don't like periscope,
I don't know what to call it, but is
a working title, the periscopes slap,
which is basically somebody comes in and
with their phone and they're holding it
up to their face. You just fucking
slap it right down to the floor. Right.
And then you do Bruce Lee's finishing
move when he kills him, which is a stomp.
And then a twist and
you're going to do the, Oh,
when you do it be perfect.
And then somebody else films that right
now don't film it because then they'll
have evidence. Uh, he should do,
I was just, you know what I mean?
Or you walk around with a water bottle
and you don't like to do it for like a
fucking cat that won't get off the
couch when somebody comes in just doing
periscope without asking you,
you just fucking, you spray.
You just spray the water and ruined their
phone. Something like that. I advocate,
I mean last week I
advocated killing your boss.
I actually felt bad about that
cause I just thought of, I like,
what if somebody actually went out
and did it? The world is so fucked up,
I could actually get sued.
And the like, you know,
it was irresponsible, but blah,
blah blah. It's like say, yeah,
you don't think that that person's a
maniac listens to a podcast. Like, Hey,
go commit a murder. And then they
go, okay, okay, you told me to do it.
You owe me money. Um,
yeah, don't kill your boss.
But a I advocate slap, slap on the
fucking phone out of somebodies hand,
slap it right down to the ground, stomp
on it, twisted, knowing full well the,
you don't have to pay for it, but you
just, you preserving your privacy.
It's gotta be a politically correct
way to say it. You're a, uh,
you're a privacy warrior.
Sorry. Oh fuck you.
You come up with a Goddamn
name for it. Um, all right.
You know, it's funny.
It's my wife's birthday.
Tomorrow is her birthday
and she's a fucking smarty
pants and she always figures
out what the fuck I get her and this,
this year I totally threw her off.
Totally fucking threw her off.
She's got no fucking clue where I'm going
to take her one I'm going to do while
she knows that somewhere in Paris,
but she has no idea.
And right now this might be a lie,
this might be a lie,
just in case when he decides to Tweet,
Oh,
Bill's going to do something fucking
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Do it.
You already know what the fuck I'm doing.
All right. Now, I can tell you right now,
I only have 50% of an idea of what
the fuck I'm going to do. All right,
so don't even try and figure it out.
All right. It's fucking useless.
It's a waste of your time.
Uh,
favorite music video downtown Billy Brown.
Nice fucking reference.
I absolutely fucking love downtown.
Judy Brown at the biggest fucking crush
on her. When I first moved to New York,
um,
and like 95,
96 I went to some benefit thing is hoity
toity thing where my manager at the
time knew a bigger manager
who was managing a big comic
and we got to tag along
and I went there and she was standing
just hanging out at the thing.
She was fucking gorgeous.
Fucking gorgeous. All right.
Too early to get into comedy.
No such thing, sir. Dear bill,
I'm 17 and just did my first
open mic at a coffee shop.
I've got a few laughs and a few
awkward silences silences, but overall,
uh,
I enjoy it.
I really want to go to a comedy club
soon so I don't have to be so selective
about my words.
And advice to someone this young
looking to get into this. Ps.
I know bombing is part of the process.
Problem is I have paper,
thin skin. Does your hide thicken
up after a while of bombing?
All right, two things. Any
advice on somebody, uh,
looking to get into this?
Dude, you're already into it.
It's like you just shot heroin and now
you're asking me about heroin. Dick,
you're already did it.
Now you're hooked and you already
want to go down to a comedy club. Uh,
you started at 17. That's not
too early. That's fucking great.
And don't listen to the fucking older
people who are jealous and be like, dude,
you 17 years, you've got nothing to talk
about. You got nothing to talk about.
And then watch them go on stage and see
what the fuck they're talking about. Ah,
dude, shit jokes. Wait,
am I talking about myself?
Don't listen to them. All
right? This is the deal.
You're young and there's going to be
a lot of people fucking jealous. Okay?
And then there's,
if you're a guy and he's going to be a
couple of old fucking lady comics that
are going to try bang, you stay
away from them if you're a female.
Okay.
MMM. You know, just stay away from,
and anybody who tells jokes cause
they're all gonna try to bang you.
I'm so fucking, it's a job. Go
down there and get better at it.
Surround yourself with positive,
motivated people that you feel are going
to make it and then not doing this just
fucking around and you guys will
all feed off of each other's drive.
That's what happened to me
in Boston when I started.
I started with Dane and Patrice O'Neal,
rest his soul and we were
down at Nick's comedy,
Stop Donald Warrants and street in Boston.
We were down there every fucking
night unless we had a gig elsewhere.
And even then, a lot of times
we would drive back in there.
We were there every fucking night.
And um,
okay.
I remember when one of the
great compliments I got
when I first started out,
this guy came walking in and I was
like, and I was already there, you know,
write down my jokes. And he looked at
me, he said, dude, you are everywhere.
And it's just like, yeah, yeah, I am.
So that's what you gotta be, Dude.
And you can't just do
like club comedy clubs.
You've got to do stand up any way
you can. And as far as bombing, yes,
it is part of the PRA process. Every,
you know, I had a paper, thin skin,
I was shy, I was introverted,
I had all of that.
And it just fucking hot. When
you bomb it, it was just, ah,
just sucks.
It just sucks in the beginning.
But I'm the same way.
You learn how to kill,
you're going to learn how to bomb
and you can learn how to, how to, um,
like have hold your,
uh,
hold your ground and you'll have,
you'll have poise while ground, uh,
bombing. And then when you get to a
really high level of bombing is you'll,
you'll VA began to understand if you're
bombing, because if it's your fault,
if it's the crowds fault, if it's
just a set up, if it's half the crowd,
half you, if it's 60%, you are
the, that to me is the best thing.
When if you figure it out, it's you, then
you just start making fun of yourself.
If you figure it out,
it's them.
You start giving him shit and
they loosen up a little bit. Um,
if it's a little bit in the middle,
you sort of make fun of yourself
while you're ripping them,
you'll figure out the whole recipe
to the thing. But, um, you know, uh,
I think it's great. You Start and it takes
a lot of balls. 17 to start off. So, uh,
my, my fucking, my hat
is off to you. All right.
Helicopter loser. Hi Bill.
And then quotes it said,
oh my God, I'm gonna lose her. I'll
never own a helicopter. I'm a disgrace.
And they said, that's from Bill
Burr, emotionally unavailable.
That's quoting one of my jokes.
So do you remember saying this
during the MTV cribs bit? Uh,
feel like you made it now. Shot
helicopter guy. Go Fuck Yourself.
But seriously, well done on the helicopter
driving. Thank you. Um, oh yeah,
I remember that bit. I didn't know that
I've said helicopter, but I remember uh,
talking about how MTV cribs,
how you would watch that show and you'd
just end up feeling like a fucking loser
because it was all like these,
you know,
am I really going to say Brittany Spears
twice in this fucking podcast? Yes,
it is. 2015. Um, I'll,
I'll all those fucking people's
houses back then. Cisco's house,
the one hit wonders to,
they all had pet and all of this shit
and they made you feel like a loser.
He is a fucking inside joke.
A inside story on, on that.
All right.
When I did that pit,
um,
one night I did it at the comedy
cellar in the late great. Greg Geraldo,
rest his soul. He came up to me
after I did the bit. He goes, dude,
he goes,
just to let you know,
I have a bit on MTV cribs and
it's almost word for word,
the exact same bit,
it's exact same angle.
And both of us would just send a part
of our career where we were writing our
hours and we, I didn't have anything
else. I was just like, ah man.
He's as like, neither one of us wanted to
dry. You have to have the conversation.
Usually someone's like, I'll drop it
now. You do it. Nah, Nah. You know,
and I've usually been the one that I,
that I was always like, I'll drop it,
I'll drop it cause I didn't
want any of my shit. You know,
somebody else seen somebody else
doing it and thinking I'm stealing.
So we both just sat there going like
stare at the floor and then we both just
started laughing, going like, all right,
we'll only do that, choke on the road.
So me and Geraldo had this, this, uh,
gentleman's agreement that even though
we didn't steal from each other,
but we basically had the exact same bit,
um,
that we would only do it on the road.
So that's what happened.
And we never really talked about it again
and we both just kind of forgot that
we kind of had the same joke.
And then like the same season,
we both got a half hour on comedy central
and Lee and we both did the bit.
And I remember my special came out
first and I remember getting an email in
somebody's gone, hey bro,
just to let you know,
Greg Geraldo still jury is still your
MTV cribs that, and I've gotten like,
oh fuck, that's right. He's got the
same thing. So I emailed the kid back,
told them the story,
and then I called Geraldo and we both
just started laughing and we were trying
to guess which one of us was going to
be, you know, called the joke thief more.
Wow. That was, wow. That
was way back. Way, way back.
It was like 2002,
um,
oh my God, I'm a loser. I'll never own a
helicopter over just Christ Jesus Christ.
That's fucked. I don't remember
saying that. Here I am.
Years later, years later, years later. Um,
all right, let me read a couple
more of these, uh, these,
these advertising things here.
Then I can wrap this podcast up and
hopefully I'll be able to upload this with
the Euro fucking Internet here.
Okay.
Please tell me that's not wind chimes.
Is that a fucking telephone?
Okay,
I'm going to answer in that shit.
Yeah.
Hello. This is Louis, uh, legal zoom.
Everybody.
Okay.
Are you, uh, are you the next
world famous entrepreneur? No.
Or maybe you don't care about fame? Nope.
Wrong again, all for, to their legal zoom.
You just want to help people.
Oh, for fucking three.
But maybe one of those three
or all three pertains to you.
Whatever your motivation. If
you're an innovator, it's an easy,
it's easy to launch your dream
this month with legal zoom to, uh,
incorporate or form an LLC to
start Your Business Register.
He had trademark to protect
your products and services.
Apply for a patent to secure your
invention. Over the past decade,
legal zoom has helped more
than a million people,
just like you turn their
ideas into reality.
So what's special about this month?
For a limited time,
you can get special savings
on any trademark copyright
or a provisional patent
application. It's one of those random
pickups here. It makes you voice quiver.
Go to legalzoom.com today to get started.
They can even help you
if you have a great idea,
but you're not sure where to begin
since they're not a law firm,
you can't get advice from legalzoom's
network or independent attorneys. Wait,
since they're not a law firm,
you can get advice from legalzoom's
network of independent attorneys in most
states.
That means you can get the guidance
you need to get your great idea off the
ground.
Don't forget to enter burpee.
You are in the referral box at checkout
this month for your special discount,
legalzoom.com Promo Code Burpee,
you orr legal help is here.
And lastly,
but not leastly are old friends
here. Stamps dot Cobb. Uh,
all right.
Okay.
Sorry if I just sniffled
into the microphone.
How great would it be if
the post office was open?
24 seven no more limited hours.
No more grumpy people behind the counter.
You could get your mailing and
shipping done on your schedule.
Now you can when you use stamps.com print
postage whenever you need it. Right?
Finger desk staff starcomm will
save you the time and hassle,
man of going to the post office.
No more rushing there
during your busy day.
Just use your computer and printer to
get official US postage for any letter or
package.
Then the mailman picks it up.
You'll save money with stamps.com
to get the exact postage the inches.
Do you need it? No more overpaying
even get special postage discounts.
She can't get it.
The post office.
I use stand stop center on all those
great posters that I sell after my shows
right now. Use My last name
bur bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a hundred $110 bonus
offer that includes a digital scale that
up to $55 free postage. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top of
the homepage and type in [inaudible] B u.
R. R. All right, there we go.
So before I check out here and uh,
begin my fucking vacation here,
what are you going to do, Bill?
You know what I'm going to do?
I'm not doing shit.
I'm going to sit in the cafes and uh,
I don't know.
Eat some fucking as some of their food.
I forget what that beer was that I
liked the last time I was over here.
I'm looking forward to doing that,
but uh, to be honest with you,
I just want to chill out,
not be an asshole.
It makes sure my wife has a
good time to be honest with you.
That's going to be my attempt because
I know I don't want to end up like that
guy. That guy was so I was fucking
depressing. I felt bad like it.
His wife was just sitting there taking it,
one of those old school fucking women,
just someone needed to
take her aside and be like,
d can't take this from this guy in a
fucking slap them around or something.
I don't know what. So anyways,
let's talk about the NHL Finals,
which I'm gonna fucking miss over here.
Unless they can find an NHL bar. Um,
I know,
I know.
You can watch it online with the password
and I'll probably fuck it up. Uh,
but anyways, uh, black hawks
versus the Tampa Bay lightning.
Um, I'm going to say something
right now. Jonathan tapes,
Dat guy. He is in the process of, uh,
being one of those guys who they're going
to be selling his Jersey like 20 years
from now and little kids in 20 years.
They're going to know who
he is that fucking gay.
Like he's just a man that
cage just fucking steps up,
dad, game seven against the ducks and
congratulations to the ducks to where,
what is, what it, what it sees. And
they had just a great fucking team.
Um, and, uh,
just game seven,
they're on the road in Anaheim and
just write in the first two minutes,
just shuts the crowd
the fuck up with a goal
and then scores another one. And the
first period it's two to nothing and teed,
scored both fucking goals. It's just
the gay is, he's just, he's the shit.
So I dunno. Uh, um,
who isn't a fan of greatness sold?
There's usually I like the underdog and I,
I like Tampa Bay and I really like,
you know,
Steve [inaudible] and everything
that he's done with that thing.
So it Tampa Bay wins. I'll be, I'll
also be happy, but like, uh, I,
I obviously just having a player
like teams get a third is,
uh, it's great for the game and it's also
for Chicago. Cause then now, you know,
when they do their, their whole,
like the great people of, uh,
who are the greats of Chicago
Sports, right? Bobby Hall,
Michael Jordan, I'm sorry,
Walter Payton, Michael Jordan.
And then tapes is going to be right in
there. Right. He gets his third. Um,
wait, we've got to have they
to have a great Ernie banks.
Okay.
Who is it? Who's a great
white sock? I don't know.
Let shoeless Joe Jackson
from the fucking black socks.
I hate that they call him the black socks.
It's like no,
they were the fucking white socks or they
think fixed the world series now that
my friends,
that was cheating
fucking air pressure. I'll never get
over it. I'll never get over it anyways.
Um, so obviously I think the Black Hawks
are going to win just because they're so
deep in the, uh, the uh,
experience they have.
But I'm really bummed out that I'm
not going to fucking see it. Um,
I'll figure it out a fucking way to do it.
And then what's the other one we got here?
Oh,
let me sit in this fucking antique
chair. I hope it doesn't break it. Um,
who else is it? Oh, Lebron first.
What's his face? Steph curry.
I don't know shit about basketball.
All I know is curries,
one of the most amazing basketball
players I've ever seen in my life.
But I gotta be honest with you.
I am so sick of a closeup on his face
while he's chewing his mouthpiece.
It's fucking gross.
Okay.
Okay. Just keeping your fucking mind. That
shit. Do you know what it's going to do?
Cause he's so good.
It's going to inspire an entire generation
of young kids to walk around with
their children on their fucking mouth
piece after every fucking play cause they
want to be like him. You know?
Then when you want to be like Mike,
you just stuck your tongue out and tried
to dunk as you floated in sideways.
Then you just tripped and fell.
Uh,
now they're going to have the fucking
that thing hanging out of their mouth.
But um,
I don't know who the real fruit for there.
I love the whole thing that's Lebron came
back in one, one for fucking Cleveland,
but they could finally put their fucking
wine and all the time about how awful
the sports situation is.
But then on the other side,
I like golden state man, golden state
to me like a, that team is like a,
what was that will Ferrell movie semi-pro.
Like to me,
golden state is like,
they got the sickest floor in the NBA,
but before they had a man, like where
they play is just old school sports.
It's not a lot of venues
like that anymore.
I went to a game there a long time
ago when they played the Spurs. Uh,
David Robinson was still on the team.
He was in street clothes. Uh, and uh,
what's his face was really young, uh,
captain, the big fundamental there,
whatever the fuck his
name is. Uh, but anyways,
they are the sickest live
band there. So you know what?
This is tough. I think I got to go if
I might got to go for the warriors.
You know why?
Because Al Madrigal is a fan and he's
the fucking driving force behind the all
things comedy network. They go that
tipped it in favor. I know you like,
what about Jason Law head? What about
Jason Law had, well, you know what?
The buckeyes wanted it this year,
so he's already got a championship.
So I'm rooting for the warriors.
They go,
I'm rooting for the warriors and
I'm rooting for the Black Hawks.
The greatness of a Jonathan tastes.
I want to see a,
I want to see him get his third
one and a plus original six.
And I obviously got to be honest with you,
the fucking Black Hawks that,
that home jersey,
which used to be the way that red one,
that's one of the best jerseys and
all the fucking sports. All right,
that's the deal.
Everybody.
A thank you to everybody that's listening
and I'm going a generous move here.
I'm still gonna tell you to
go fuck yourselves. But, uh,
I'm just so fucking psyched.
I finally got the helicopter thing
done and then I can now go on to a,
actually really learn how
to fly the fucking thing,
which is really what your
pilot's licenses. It's a
licensed to learn, they say.
So I got to get on that shit.
So that is it.
I'm going to do another goddamn
comedy jam coming up this month. Uh,
so I got to get my drum
and chops back together,
but nothing but helicopters
this month. So, uh,
brought my little fucking pad over here.
You don't get a pair of digital my
fucking way back into drumming shape,
but when I come back, I
forget what date that is. Uh,
but they'll have it up on their website.
As always,
please visit the all things comedy
network and, uh, that's sick.
Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.