Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the Monday
morning podcast for Monday, June 11th
yeah,
2012 2012 which I am
actually recording on Sunday,
June 10th which is my birthday.
My birthday.
It's your birthday.
You fucking cunt.
Another year's gone by.
Your still sitting there
in that fucking place.
You don't want,
I'll be so eat some cake.
Blow out the candles,
but not in that order or else
you will burn your fucking mouth.
Mouth.
Mouf
f mouth.
Hey, did, did Manny Pacquiao lose
last night? Is that what I heard?
Somebody left me a message that he
fuck he lost. That's unbelievable.
I can't believe that little
roided up guy couldn't
do it. I think everything is
fucking fixed. Don't listen to me.
I don't think it's possible for a guy
comes in and 109 pounds to put on 40
pounds of muscle,
not lose any speed or any power.
Get actually get faster and stronger.
Okay.
I've seen that show.
It's called the fucking bionic man.
That's the only thing that was missing.
That's what they should have shown
in the beginning of all packy.
I'll fights was him crashing some
experimental aircraft like John Denver,
except he doesn't die.
Okay.
You know, and John Denver
would died, wouldn't have died.
He would have lived if he wasn't
wearing those stupid glasses.
That's what did him in
those little granny glasses,
like he sat around making cookies and a
tree, you know, like those Keebler Elf.
That's what killed them.
A lot of people don't know that.
They thought it was
massive head trauma and a,
and a carnage to his rib cage area with
the, with the vitals there behind it.
You know,
the floating rib that they gave over
to that fucking contract couldn't stop
eating the apples. Right. Wasn't
that, it wasn't massive head trauma.
It was very minimal,
very specific.
He slammed his head off the
experimental dashboard and, um,
his mainstream glasses then shot it
through his eyes into his brainstem,
rocky mountain hack, Colorado. And
then he died. And that's what happened.
Everybody blamed the aircraft,
you know,
but everybody who actually goes
out and gets a pilot's license,
I believe on the first day they
tell him not to wear those glasses.
When was the last time you got on a plane
and you saw your pilot wearing those
John Denver glasses.
All right.
There's a reason for
that. Think about it. Um,
what am I talking about here?
Can they show that fucking John Malcovich
talking to his phone and just having
the time of his life commercial
one more fucking time.
What's more annoying that one or
where that weird family does the, uh,
the acapella version of Ozzy Osborne's
crazy trade with that random black kid in
the back. Like where did they
get that kid? Like, you know,
it was he an exchange student and he just
seems like he's over all of it and not
enjoying hanging out with the other white
people as he fucking shakes the ice in
his, in his great drink, you know,
and then they gotta end that great song
with the parents singing like they're on
Broadway.
Right.
Go.
You know
anybody else with me on that? John fucking
Malcovich sitting there all, you know,
if that, if that commercial was 30
seconds longer, he'd have the phone. Like,
like blowing him.
Yeah.
Tell me a joke.
Do I have anything coming up tonight now?
Oh,
okay.
Lobster souffle or whatever.
Pretentious fucking foodie orders.
Was it pretentious,
Bill,
or are you just not cultured and in his
order made you feel dumb. All right,
you got me on that one.
You got me on that one. Um,
I'm the only one who was creeped out
that there's a fucking robot in my phone.
Well, whatever it is, it's
that they try to make it human.
Why did they do that?
Just make it sound like a robot.
Okay.
How can I help you?
Massage Parlor.
Gary's Mhi rack. My brains
just do it like that. So I,
it's still keeps that like
we keep that distance.
I don't need intimacy with this
thing that isn't fucking alive.
I don't need that 2001
space odyssey experience.
That's all I'm trying to say here. People,
oh, he's bill burr. He's mad at phones.
Get out of his way. Everybody.
This guy's got something to say.
What's the deal with y'all?
MMM.
You have a wonder if you're going to
stand the test of time, your decisions.
You know what I mean?
I had a fucking panic attack last night,
you know, turning 44 years old. I just
woke up mill and night like Jesus Christ,
I'm sliding into 50,
you know,
and I don't give a fuck how well you
take care of yourself when you're 50.
You fucking look 50 unless you had some
fat for your ass blasted India face and
then you just look shiny.
But everybody knows you're 50.
You're not fooling anybody with your
real housewife for forehead, Aria,
for forehead. Eight head. Huh?
Is that show still on?
You know,
how long are they going to keep doing
that to the clams are hanging out in their
bikinis.
It's not how it
is that,
how am I going to do that one for?
Let's try to beat beat
out the drew Carey show.
How many fucking episodes that mummy
years of that fucking show did they do
while people still didn't give a fuck?
Um,
the
second they rolled in that fat lady
with the makeup, I mean, right there,
it's just like, we're really not going
to develop anything on this show. Are We?
If we're just going to try to keep
it, uh, just kinda keep it wacky. Um,
ah, Jeez. There goes the
phone. Hang on a second.
Hang on a fucking second. Christ's sake.
Why don't I shut the damn phone off?
Who's this? Who's this dopey?
My mom. It's my dad. Oh.
I just chose the podcast over
my own father, who I owe.
I owe a huge apology to.
I owe a huge apology to my dad.
All right.
Last night I was sitting on a couch
Bududa Lou do it mine and my own fucking
business. Lou Lou Lou. Dude.
I was watching metal mania on VH one.
Metal Mania.
Cleo.
Okay.
I think my dog is sleeping
with, with his eyes open. Oh No.
She just moved her eyebrows. Dude.
Where the fuck did you just go?
Uh Huh.
Cleo. Whatever you're thinking
about, it's going to be okay.
All right.
Anyways, you know, it's weird when my
dog sees a squirrel through a window, it,
it cries
like it's a long lost buddy.
But if my dog is outside and
there's a squirrel, you know,
if there's no window between
my dog and the squirrel it,
we'll try and rip his
fucking head off so I don't,
does anybody know anything
about dogs? What is it crying
about? Is it crying? Like,
Ooh, I want to rip it set off.
Oh, I wish I could just end.
That thing's fucking life.
You don't make any sense to me anyway.
So I'm watching fucking
metal mania alliteration.
This has gotta be a hit show, right?
So I'm watching this shit and uh,
okay.
At the risk of pissing
off a lot of listeners,
I think most metal slash hair metal,
it arguably is the worst
fucking music ever made.
Worst the disco, I don't know why disco
gets such a bad rap. Like disco was the,
is that the default example of bad music?
The Way Hitler is,
the default example of,
of evil duties.
The next Tatler it's always the next
fucking Hitler never pull pot yet. No,
never a fucking, I dunno. Pick a
noun. I don't even know another one.
Okay.
You know, Ivan, the terrible,
was that a wrestler?
Was that a comic strip? I know. Horrible.
Haggar I don't fucking know. Right. See,
I don't even, I don't even have any
other examples. Whose fault is that?
Bill is a library right down the street.
I'll go fuck yourself.
You know what I'm saying?
Um,
everybody always talks about disco and
how bad disco was and it just needs to be
a change man.
Right?
And like then they'll talk about like the,
and all this new wave shit and the
punk scene and all that, but what they,
they completely fucking ignore
is that right after disco,
uh,
just immediately the mainstream then went
over to like this fucking heavy metal
music,
like that was better than disco.
I think it's fucking worse.
And I think all these times where they
keep saying that everybody there was a
big change and that this quality music
came out. I don't know if that happens.
I think it just, you know, you know,
nirvana comes around and they're, what,
four years later,
everybody's listening to fucking
old town or the main stream is,
it's just this long,
tragic,
just flat line of shit music.
I was watching the shit last night,
shit that I used to like, and my jaw was
on the ground. How fucking bad it was.
It was horrible. I, I
actually, I was so bad.
I was like texting paragraphs to the
sensation Joe to Rosa capitol records.
The guy who built capital records.
Joe Rosa, I'll actually, you go, wow.
I'll get a little intimate here with you.
I'll,
I'll read you the text message
I fucking wrote Joe. Uh,
Joe, where the hell out
here? Where the hell are we?
Okay.
Joe Hair slash heavy metal
is the worst music ever made.
Disco gets a bad rap watching
metal mania on VH one.
Guns and roses. Queens,
Reich, wasp, quiet riot.
David Lee Roth Solo Shit.
It's fucking God awful. Yeah.
I saw David Lee Roth on, on his, uh,
eat them and smile tour
and I saw that video last night.
Go wing crazy
from day he,
that sounds like a song Wahlberg's
character would have written with John C.
Reilly and Boogie nights.
I remember that
he will rock you
and he will low you like it was,
it was that bad
teenage Frankenstein.
I'm a teenage package died.
You're telling me that that song
is better than more than a woman?
You know, I think arguably it's, I dunno,
I can't believe the shit that I used to
watch and like I used to listen to this
shit around checks,
you know,
just hopelessly thinking
that this would get me laid.
Like they would think that I
was some Badass, like Loner Bang
your,
I mean,
the whole fucking, the fact that
I never got laid in high school,
it just fuck it went away. Right
in that moment. It was like,
this is what I was going to do.
I wasn't going to try to make them laugh.
I wasn't going to hit on him.
I wasn't going to try it.
I was just going to play this music
around them and this was going to bring me
to the fucking promise land looking
like a fucking teenage Ron Howard.
That was my game plan.
Is it any wonder I failed Jesus Christ?
And I remember I would be
watching it on a big square TV.
Um, just watch it. Lay it down.
Lay Your Dad is fucking
horrific fucking music.
And my dad would come in and just have
his face would just be all twisted up,
gone. Jesus Christ. What the fuck?
You listen to it. You like to shift.
And I thought I was a rebel. I mean
he doesn't know. Understand man.
You know what? He totally
understood. He totally understood.
My Dad called it back in [inaudible]
83 called it jungle music,
says a bunch of shit.
He told me straight up
gay man, he was like, son,
this music you're listening
to is fucking horrible.
And there was all these
shout at the devil.
Is anybody really going to sit there
and defend that fucking song? Doodoo
delay
Doodoo Doh,
Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh,
Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh.
You couldn't find that you do.
You could fucking,
a five year old could write down
on a xylophone shout at the devil.
Never knew why we were shouting,
you know,
blacking lawless, blackie
lawless, that was his show name.
And he took a radial arm saw and cut
the blade in half and put one hat,
one blade, one of his forearms at
one or the other on these leather.
Uh, I'm going to do a bunch of
dishes in an evil way. Gloves
and we all thought it was crazy.
Can you imagine if we
gave you a forearm shiver?
It was just Eddie used to throw
fucking raw meat to the crowd.
A couple of them did.
That's why that lady Gaga covering
or clam and that fucking Pastrami,
it's just been done. You know, comes
out in a fucking egg from Mork.
I Dunno,
I've seen the nasally horror
act my whole fucking life.
You know those fucking checks with
the big noses. They can, you know,
that's like white people's answer to the
big black girl who can sing at church.
We, we what, what the, what the
check we bring to that fight is the,
the white chick with the big nose
white chicks with big noses can sing.
I don't know what it is.
Barbara Streisand,
right. I Dunno. It's like their nose is,
it's like that dome at the top of
all those con con uh, concert halls.
There you go, Bill. Try to spit
it out. You dumb fuck. But um,
I, some emails people, I
want people try to tell me
how a rowdy crowd love book,
by the way. Good. Damn. It'd be,
tell me the musical validity
that that has over like disco,
that all those people probably
had Comiskey plaque when
they blew up those disco
records like fucking five, six years
later. That's what they were listening to.
Okay.
Nope,
that was a hit.
It was a hit in the 80s.
Okay.
Wow.
Do I owe my dad an apology?
I just, I was sitting there just one
video after the queen's Reich. I mean,
all this stuff that I thought was just
fucking unbelievable. You know what?
I'm going to get emails this week.
It's like,
I don't know what it's going to be.
It's going to be like,
people either going to be like, yes,
absolutely. This is going to be,
there's going to be no middle ground.
If he was going to 100%
agree with me or a,
I'm going to get punched
in the face by Eddie trunk.
Okay.
I just, I was taken aback. I mean,
I haven't seen those videos and fucking
forever Kasian I'll go back and I'll
look at some old videos,
but I mean a lot of it was like ACDC,
like shit they can like, you know,
I mean back in black is timeless.
There's some timely shit in there.
You know?
I even watched that guns and roses,
sweet child of mine and I thought,
I thought it was horrible.
Wow.
Please.
And that little fucking Shim Sham
dance he was doing, it's just was
okay.
Oh, and then the emotion he
tried to have in the end.
Wow.
All right. And they kind of
closed his eyes like, ah,
I really went somewhere when I've, I
was just fucking horrible. You know,
I was right down. I helped
hold it up. Oh, def Leppard,
pour some sugar, rob me. I hated
that when I fucking came out
and all the ladies liked it and he
came out in his acid washed jeans.
I actually saw him on
that tour, didn't I? Yeah.
Reynolds' Coliseum and
Tesla opened up Tessa,
which I didn't think they were that bed.
They weren't that bad.
I Dunno. I thought you're supposed to go
back and listen to the fucking music of,
uh, of your youth being like, wow, that
stuff was wow. That was awesome man.
I remember that. And then, you know, that
was the first time I tried blow, you know,
reminiscent
actually first time I ever saw cocaine,
uh,
sought and saw it being done was a,
at the providence civic center.
I saw ACDC on the who made
who tour with loudness,
the Japanese heavy metal band that
couldn't speak any English yet.
Sang in English.
Um,
I just can't imagine
the disconnect as yours.
I can't imagine like memorizing a bunch
of Japanese and going and over there and
just singing it and then not knowing,
uh,
what the fuck I was saying going out there
and everybody just be like,
I have no idea what I just said.
Tee Shirts at 20 bucks.
Did I just say that or did I say, are you
ready to rock? I have no fucking idea.
Um, anyways, so I saw them,
they opened up and uh,
anyways,
we're out in the parking lot
and we're drinking beers.
They can work crazy driving of course,
cause it's the 80s.
This was right around before,
right before mad kicked in and they
used to bring like wreckage from a fatal
drunk driving accident.
Anybody else's high school do that?
They actually brought a car
from a fatal drunk driving, uh,
accident. They dragged in
onto the lawn of our campus.
You want to call it a campus?
A little island with the tree.
They just left it there and we all just
stared at it trying to figure out how
many people were in the car, how many
people died. And then we just walked away.
Like, you know, when you're
young, you don't give a fuck.
10 minutes later you're talking about,
dude, I can't fucking rap tonight. Rat.
That was the word. Get wrapped. Getting
steroid handed, right? So anyways,
we're driving down their beer between
your legs. As you do see eighties,
you know,
you fucking lifted weights all that week.
Never all of it above the waist.
Curls,
fucking bench shoulders.
Nobody did squats in the 80s.
Nobody did.
Right?
So you got your fucking tight five oh
one blues on with the Little Pencil
fucking legs.
Then you overdeveloped upper body,
you stupid gold chain and a,
he had a beer between your legs.
That's how he did it.
So we're fucking going down.
There were probably on eight
a piece fucking hammered. Uh,
I was driving this piece of shit.
83 Ford Ranger.
I got like five fucking
drunk friends in the back,
which was still not even
grounds for getting pulled over.
You could just have people in the back,
like you bring in fucking turkeys off
to slaughter. Nobody gave a shit. Right?
So we pull in and right as I pulled
up and it got a parking spot,
there was this kid,
he had his door open and he kinda had
like a Sammy Hagar meets John Fogarty
haircut blonde hair.
And I remember he fucking did
align right as I was pulling up.
And I had fortunately had my
window up and he saw me and he saw,
we all had ACDC tee shirts on or whatever,
and he just got to, the cow is just,
it's like a haunted house right
up to the fucking window.
And I was just trying to take
it all in like, okay, he just,
how am I supposed to behave around
somebody with, with WHO's on coke?
Does this guy have like, you
know, Hulk Strength Right now?
Is he going to tip over the truck?
Um, anyway, so that was the,
Fred was the first time I saw blow.
I don't even know what the point of
all that was. I was just shocked. Look,
I know it wasn't all bad like
the street early Metallica,
you know, right through and justice for
all. I know that that stuff was great,
but uh, I'll tell you it
is slim. Fucking pickings,
my friends slim pickings.
Um,
okay.
Ah, I don't even, I didn't
know what to tell you.
Yeah,
I mean, I even go back sometimes I try
to listen to appetite for destruction.
I know that's this,
this watershed fucking moment and that
music with some of those fucking songs,
they're out to get me.
So you can stop me.
Take that one to heart, kill yourself. Um,
all right then I'd get me
a lot of fucking criticism.
Okay.
Ah, really. Okay, well let's,
you don't want, I think it's
time for some advertising.
You're listening to the Monday morning
podcast, by the way. And this is my, uh,
my trip down memory lane.
The 1980 [inaudible] they'll fuck and 80.
Did I nail it though, by the way?
Everyone had the five one blues.
Remember that button fly dude,
I washed him three times and you're nuts.
Couldn't breathe.
You know,
and you wonder why you've got all these
fucking crazy kids that need to be on
drugs now. There you go. Hey everybody,
father's day is next weekend.
God knows I'm going to get my dad a man.
Great Guy.
Tried to help me out 30 fricking years
ago telling me that the music I was
lifting, the two sucked and I
didn't even listen to him. Um,
you got to act quickly on this one.
Seriously. Uh, it's Monday. All right.
Is there anything worse than when either
mother's Day or father's day comes
around and you ran out of time
and you didn't get him a card?
You didn't get them flowers. You didn't
get them. You didn't get them a damn man.
Great. Why don't you just take care of
it today? All right. Just go on there.
Slap it on your cad and
he's going to be psyched.
He's going to be psyched.
Father's days, next weekend.
You got to act quickly and get
the perfect father's day gift.
It's the man get man. Great Grill
enhancement system. So heavy duty grill.
It's 100% made in America with cast iron.
Really grates to upgrade any
grill out there on the market, um,
making you and your family. Very
happy. Jesus. They got it. Got Better.
Copy on that one.
Making everybody happy instead of sad act.
Now we get the $20 Monday morning
podcast special by clicking on the man.
Great banner on billboard.com
I do is go to the podcast page.
You Click on the man great thing and die.
Every bill burr order comes with a
heavy duty man, Greg grilling brush.
Um, so for father's Day, go to
[inaudible] dot com the podcast page.
Hit the button and take advantage
of our special $20 offer.
These things are great.
Instead of having like those little Wussy,
you know like when you buy your grills
you have like, you know, little skinny,
you have all the way from
the little Hibachi ones that
they're the size, the uh,
the grill marks,
basically the size of pretzel rods.
And then if you get a halfway decent
one, you know, they move up to the,
the thick pretzel rods.
When, when you were a kid,
you pretended like you smoked a cigar.
Wouldn't it be great if you could just
switch it out and just have the same size
ones you do when you go to
your favorite steak houses?
That's what these guys are
doing with demand. Great.
It's actually a genius system.
Um,
and it kind of annoys me that I didn't
think of doing that. It's the same way.
It's like building a hot Rod,
right?
You're switching out the crap you got
at the factory to put it on some high
performance stuff. Help Your Dad's
supercharged his grill this Friday.
Maybe we'll make you a burger,
you know,
and you guys can share an awkward hug
the man. Great. Everybody $20 off.
There we go. There we go. That
was, that was, that was easy.
That was easy advertising.
Oh, and by the way,
I finally sent off a check to the,
uh,
the wounded warriors project so
I can stop feeling like a fraud.
I know I told you I finally
got to check in two weeks ago,
but I've been so damn busy that I
couldn't take two seconds to click on the
Internet to find where to send the
check. And uh, we gave him a nice check.
I rounded it up to the next hundred
cause I'm a good shit. And, uh,
I felt like it did my good deed.
And if you're new to my
podcast and you wondering, oh,
how can I donate to this podcast and
the wounded warriors project all at the
same time,
just go to [inaudible] dot com
click on the podcast page and uh,
and you'll see a banner for Amazon.
All right?
And if you're going to buy anything on
amazon.com instead of just going directly
there, just go to the podcast page on
my website, click on the banner and a,
whatever you buy on there,
they kicked me a percentage
and then I take 10% of that.
Give it to the wounded warriors project.
And now you can feel good about yourself
knowing that you helped a group
of people that truly needed it.
And one jackass who, uh, probably doesn't.
All right. All right, let's start it
off. Good. It started off as a good read.
You know, it's a good read or that
three o'clock. Hi. Um, all right,
let's get back to the, uh,
the podcast. Um, all right.
What do we got here? She would,
you know what? I think it's time.
I think it's time for a, uh, for uh, for,
for one of a pyramid scheme. Let's read
this one. Hello Mr. Byrd. I liked that.
Very formal. A lot of respect. We did
it out of respect. We were wise guys.
We did what we wanted.
Um,
I am writing to you today because
I need some help about something.
Uh, recently my girlfriend's father,
mother, father separated. Thank God,
uh,
started reeling,
really annoying everyone with calls,
emails and meeting requests for
some Mlm Multilevel Marketing,
Aka pyramid schemes. I was pyramid
schemes. Retarded little brother.
All right. Your girlfriend's
father started really
annoying. Everyone. Okay, I'm,
I'm back on Pacey, right. At first it was,
please look at a DVD about a poor guy
becoming a rich guy by spending his time
building a water aqueduct
instead of wasting his time,
like the second guy doing the hard work
and carrying the water on his back to
the village plan for the future, they
said, or some other bullshit of that sort.
Uh,
there's been a few other great and amazing
business opportunities that I could
just delete from my inbox. But this
time it's just gone too far. Okay,
so first they gave you the DVD,
then he's sending you some emails and it
was sort of, yeah, whatever, you know,
use the DVD as a doorstop or maybe to
break up your weed and then you just
delete the emails. So, so
far he's not being annoying.
Let's move onto the second.
That's the first 10 pages of
this screen play. All right,
let's move on to the action here.
Now he requires all of us to drop all
our phone internet providers to go with
his offer.
What do you mean he requires you?
He actually can't get anyone
to go along with that crap.
But as in every fable,
he's got many pseudo facts about
a big thing that will come, oh,
big thing that will make this company
rich and that for the small fee of $500,
we can start selling those great
deals to how is this shit legal?
Um, by now he's contacting me
everyday, text message to Mimi, emails,
Facebook comments, all of
that. At first he was nice.
Now we starting to use his
skills on me saying things like,
he's doing this for me and
for his daughter's future.
I couldn't believe he argued back when I
told him I believed it was not worth my
time and effort for the little
monetary reward. Good for you.
He said I was wrong not to want to do it.
I mean,
my opinion is wrong. Lol. Uh, in any case,
if it was anybody else, I
would take pleasure. Why can't
I read this week? I mean,
I know I can't read every week,
but this week I'm just really just,
was it cause I just had bacon is the
grease fucking up my clogging up my
synopsis here. All right, let's try this
build. It's dragging a little momentum.
In any case,
it was anybody else.
I would take pleasure out of telling
him to go fuck himself with his residual
income and that I am perfectly happy
to be a fucking loser with the linear
income. Uh, he taught me
those terms. Yuck. Uh,
I want to tell him that I would like to
work by the hour better than having to
beg or suck a dick in the back
of a gas station to sell a phone,
Internet package that will be worth a few
points. I already have a great day job.
I work on my photography.
I played PC games.
I jerk off a lot too. I have no time
for this. Not that I would even not,
I would even if I had the time,
I'm thinking of a good old fading
technique I learned in the past.
Love relationships,
but we'll always be there at Christmas
parties and such pitching his bullshit.
Please help me before I strangle
him. Thank you. Uh, all right.
What do you do here?
Well,
you've already done what I said what I
was going to fix it say was basically say
I'm not interested.
Um,
why don't you make your own
DVD and what'd he hands you?
A DVD of what you should be
investing in investing in you.
Just hand him a DVD of you going,
thank you for your interest
in making me a millionaire.
Unfortunately at this time
I am not interested. Uh,
please don't try again later
just to see how annoying he is.
Why don't you start spamming him?
Nah, that's gay. Don't do that.
Sorry. I'm fucking throwing shit
against the wall here. What can you do?
Why don't you just, anytime he starts
bringing it up, just anything. Oh,
Jj is just fucking yell something.
Why don't you just go all my God really
loud and walk out of the room every time
he does.
How about you get an Air Horn and
anytime he brings it up just right in his
face. Something. I don't know
what I mean I don't, I don't know.
You already told the guy
you're not interested. I can
tell you what you don't do.
Don't bitch about him to your girlfriend.
All right.
He's his own separate annoying entity.
And uh,
always keep it a joke between
you and your girl. You know,
that's the only way you could do it.
If you really care about this girl and
you want to and you want to stay with her,
if you don't, this is a great reason
to fucking dumper. But I mean,
I don't know what to tell you.
Uh, this is your girlfriend's dad.
And, uh, to be honest with you,
if he wasn't doing this shit,
he probably do something else
that would annoy you. You know,
maybe this is his passive aggressive way
of trying to just ruin a part of your
life because he knows at the end
of the day, you're fucking his kid.
You ever think about that?
Why don't you stop being so selfish?
Put yourself in his position
for as an annoying as his,
his,
you know,
pyramid scheme is the end of the
day when you need your Dick Suck.
You're going to this guy's
daughter. So you know, if, if you,
if you look at it that way, I think that
you're winning. All right? All right.
Bill fathers is another topic. Uh,
what's with fathers having this,
the standard ringtones,
standard father's shoes and not giving
a shit what they were for a hat.
Oh, I can answer that. Despite
the fact that I'm not a father,
I know what that is.
It's what I've been fighting my entire
adult life is having the woman in your
life just wear you down. It's
not that. And then just the
laws in society,
it's
what happens when you get
married is a guy, is the,
uh,
the pilot light goes out
for a lot of things. You just don't
give a fuck anymore, you know?
I know you have kids, so you put them
first and all of that type of shit,
but this, it, as much as
it's, from what I've heard,
having a kid is the greatest fucking thing
ever, and I'm not making fun of that.
But there is a part of you that dies,
you know that howling at the
moon that fuck it. You know,
don't want to, I just
living this, just something,
this is a part of life that just
dies and you just don't give a shit.
You're a beaten man. All
right? You gave him the love.
You're married.
There's no way out without just fucking
having your wallet ripped out through
your balls and then back
into your chest cavity,
through your heart and through
your spinal cord. You're fucked.
You're looking at a beaten man.
He doesn't give a fuck.
All I need is the phone to make
a noise, you know, and I can,
I know it's ringing and I'll answer it.
I just need these shoes to cover
my feet so it doesn't hurt.
If I step on a nail and I don't get wet
when it rains and I don't give a fuck,
I just don't want to get a
sunburn on top of my head.
I'll fucking wear whatever hat
you give me. I don't give a shit.
You just don't give a shit after awhile.
I guess what it is.
It's really sad actually when that
part of you dies. You know what I mean?
Like I hate all that.
That midlife crisis shit that people talk
about that if you're in your mid life,
you can't go out and have a good
time if you go out and get hammered.
If you buy a cool car,
you know if you haven't played guitar
forever and then you want to start playing
guitar again, it's like you
trying to recapture your youth.
Now I'm trying to fucking live. I'm trying
to, to have something that excites me.
You can't be excited beyond
a certain fucking age. When
are you going to grow up?
I think it's time to grow up and if
anybody says that, even if it's a woman,
you slap him right in the fucking
face and say, how dare you.
That's how you get away with it.
Because the second the bouncer
sees you slap a woman, the face,
he's coming over there to choke you out.
But if he hears the magic phrase,
how dare you,
he stops in his tracks cause he's
immediately knows that the woman was
completely out of line, that that
works. Try it out this weekend.
Slap a woman in the face and then scream.
How dare you.
I guarantee you that the physical way
that you're removed from that bar will be
less than if you just
hauled off and slapped.
A woman is haul off and slap a woman.
You're an animal. Okay? If you,
if you say, how dare you right
afterwards, you're sort of the victim.
That theory has never been tested.
Um, if you're a faithful listener,
I'd like you to try it out.
Not just randomly.
You know, you got to find a woman
that deserves it. In other words,
stand in a bar for about eight minutes.
This is bad.
Don't do it. I do not Cook
Doug. Uh, the slapping of women.
That was actually to get me out of any
legal trouble and I said it in a funny
voice, so then I'll get in trouble. We're
weren't you mocking or it wasn't that,
it wasn't even the warning part
of the comedy. Mr [inaudible]. Oh,
go fuck yourself, counselor. Huh?
What are you supposed to win
when those Matlock suits? Um,
all right. Do Roses. Bio
To hell is this bill?
I was reading Joe to Rose's IMD
be bio and it said something like,
he did all these things despite the
fact that he was born without shoulders.
Is this a fact? Um, no,
that's actually
people who say Joe,
like that whole urban myth that Joe Rosa
doesn't have shoulders is like the same
thing like that Mama Cass from the Mamas
and Papas died by choking on a chicken
bone.
You know,
people just assume that that's why
she died because she was a fat chick.
But that isn't how she, she died
of a, of a, of cardiac arrest.
But the rumor started that she died
choking on a chicken bone and a,
and it stuck
like that Gerbil up Richard Gere's ass.
That's just some urban
myths that just never died,
that just have no facts behind them.
Um,
Dan Richard Gere,
he ain't get a durable up his ass
and it got stuck or some shit.
I don't ran the wrong way. Fucking
fell asleep in a rest area up his ass.
I don't know what the fuck happened,
but um,
you know that like, it's the stupidest
thing I've ever heard of my life.
And that was just clearly started by
somebody whose girlfriend thought Richard
Gere was dreamy and he just walked
into a bar and just, just set it.
I mean, I don't know how these fucking
things start. Jode Rosa has shoulders.
If Joe de Rosa did not have shoulders,
it would be impossible for him to then,
you know,
he'd be missing his shoulder joint.
He couldn't hold that microphone in the,
the um,
and drudging this way that he does
the reality is what Joe is missing is
he's missing the meat between his neck and
his shoulders. That's what he's
missing. Like it's a birth defect.
Joe was actually born without collarbones
if you are in, which gives the, the
fact that he doesn't have collarbones,
it gives the illusion that he doesn't
have any shoulders. And the reality is,
is because his shoulders are aware that,
I don't know what you call it,
the shoulder taint, it's that meet
between your neck and your shoulders.
Joe was not born with that,
unfortunately. And, and even sadder,
there is no cure at this time,
but that doesn't mean we're not going to
stop fighting and we're going to have a
benefit, which is trying to get, you
know, it's hard to get all these guys,
you know, get everybody's schedules lined
up, but we're definitely going to have,
um,
you know,
some sort of benefit to try and get
Joe some sort of prosthesis for a,
you know, plastic collar bones. So,
all right. I hope that clears it up,
but,
um,
I'm not trying to take away the fact that
he has accomplished amazing things for
a guy who has a defective torso.
You know,
you ever think about that?
Me collarbones are a bone that you
really do take for granted. You know,
he really is an inspiration
that just why is this sensation?
You'd have to be a sensation to achieve
what he's done with that awful body,
that awful hand that God
dealt him. Um, all right.
Okay.
All right. So Bill, you've been,
you've been doing a lot of activities,
you know, when they say what do you, what
do you buy the man who has everything,
you know, what you do,
you get them activities.
My girl gets annoyed at me cause she goes,
I don't know what to get you.
You buy anything that you
want. You know, I fucking a,
and I do and I don't apologize for it.
If I want to play hockey, you know,
I'll go buy some skates. God dammit.
I got to sit around and wait for you.
Wait for a fucking birthday and a Goddamn
desert with flames coming out of it
before I get what the fuck I want.
All right.
And the words of Bobbi Brown, I made this
money. You didn't, I'm fucking buying it.
I want to buy a guitar. I'm going
to fucking buy it. So she's,
I don't know what to catch you.
Should I get you a shirt?
You know what? I'd rather you
slapped me in the fucking face.
Don't ever get anybody a shirt for
a gut for birthday or Christmas.
Said that's the go fuck yourself
gift. Here you go. Here's something.
Here's something that I could
put paper around and you could,
you don't buy anybody close.
How dare you?
So the lovely Nia has, has been
getting me a, you know, just,
she got me tickets to the John Bonham
birthday bash, which was the shit.
Um, oh, that was one,
a heavy metal video that I fucking
loved. And really, it actually,
uh, stood the test of
time was the second album.
Um,
I liked the second skid row.
Sebastian Sebastian Bach, Sebastian
Sebastian Bach bill or Sebastian back.
Sebastian Bach.
MMM.
They had a couple songs on there
that I liked. It wasn't all bad,
but I mean come on. I was,
it was shockingly bad.
You went from that awful quiet
right video to teenage Frankenstein.
Like I just was, I couldn't, I couldn't
fucking believe it. It was unbelievable.
So anyways, so the lovely
Nia, yesterday she took me uh,
uh, horseback riding over
in Griffith Park and uh,
oh I shouldn't have said that. Why
did I say where we went? Ah, Jesus.
Cause now I'm going to shit on
it. Um, so we went over there.
I've only written a horse once in my life.
And the hard fucking thing about riding
a horse when you've never written one or
taken any lessons is when they start
trodding is to stop your balls from
slamming off the fucking saddle. There's
a way you supposed to ride with them,
which of course they don't explain.
So I was kind of, you know,
that was like my goal to learn how to
ride a horse while it trots without having
my nuts slammed, you know, backup into
my body. Like I'm freezing to death.
You guys are aware of that, right?
Your balls pull up into you.
If it gets cold enough
in a desperate attempt to preserve heat
down there, they pull up into you. That's,
that's, that's where that term freezing
your balls off, you know, came,
you know, if you stomp somebody long
enough, like they will shit themselves,
which is the, the genesis of
a, I beat the shit out of him.
Beat the piss out of him. You know,
that's the thing about getting, you know,
if you got the shit beat out of you,
you already got the Piss beat
out of you because the, the, the,
the piss gets beaten out of you before
this shit gets beat out of you unless
you're dehydrated. All
right, those, those are the,
those are the different levels
of, of an ass kicking. So anyways,
we go over to this, this, um,
this place to go to go horseback riding
and we go over there and there's these
horses and the, the, you know,
if you don't ride horses,
the first thing whenever you see him
aside from the fact that they're beautiful
you like that is a big fucking animal
and that thing is a 100% muscle.
And if that thing kicks me in my temple,
I am going to be drooling until
the fucking till Jesus comes,
I'm going to be done. And uh, so
anyway, so we're feeding these things,
you know, with their English man teeth,
you know, really straight and yellow,
you know,
home you hand out like it's a plate in
the sitting there with the soft little
muzzle eating a carrot and uh,
that was all the good types. And
then, then we go to, uh, you know,
there's all these good looking horses now.
Then we go to like go to the horses that
were going to ride and they're all back
in this pen and is like
fucking 12 of them.
They all have saddles on them and
they just got this look on their face.
You know what I mean?
Like you remember in platoon when fucking
Charlie Sheen's character just fucking
lands in the nom, remember
that? And it's, he's walking in,
he's seen all those fucking troops home
and he just sees that fucking look and
if that's what those horses look like.
And I felt like Charlie Sheen,
I was waiting for one of the horses out.
We got ourselves a crusade to here.
MMM,
I did. I felt like the uh, you know,
the little bitchy guy going into prison,
I felt all these things is,
I looked at those fucking,
they just had this one
vibe and uh,
so they pulled two horses out,
one bigger than the other.
And the bitch in me is like,
I want the smaller horse
cause I'm telling you the
second you get on a horse,
all you think is Christopher Reeve
fucking lawn dart right in the ground.
And then I wheeled myself out at some
fucking benefit and act like I'm still
enjoying life. Fuck that. Right.
I drive myself right off the end of
the stage, I'd go right along with it.
Get myself a Tuxedo. Oh
yeah. Everything's all good.
Just fucking Florida with my tongue.
And I zoomed myself right off.
Hopefully hitting a TV executive,
taking them out with me. Um,
that's how I would handle that
challenge in life because I'm a coward.
So anyways,
I fucking,
you know, then I'm like, come on man,
you gotta let your girl
had the smaller horse.
So now they go drag the bigger horse
out and this thing is just fucking like,
it's not rearing back,
but it's making it really difficult.
The thing is clearly communicating.
I don't want to go
and uh,
so I get on this fucking thing.
Okay.
And the guy, hey, you
know, you could go right,
your pull right to go left you
Paul left and now you want to stop.
You just pull it back.
All right?
So we start riding these
things and they know the trail.
They're just completely ignoring
me. And Nia, you want to go left?
They fucking Yank they head back. Like,
go fuck yourself. We're going this way.
I know,
I know the trail.
Okay.
All right. There. Fucking a, what's a,
what's a word they use
for some novice cowboy.
Okay.
Ah, what does that word all right there.
Huckleberry. Some of those western words.
Hey,
what is worst hair metal or some of that
fucking patriotic country music post
nine 11. What is worse to you?
What is more cringe worthy?
You know,
um,
shout at the devil or that,
that Toby Keith,
Uncle Sam's going to pull
the boot in your ass.
Ugh. Um, oh my God.
Every dime that guy made in that song
should've been thrown in his face and then
give it to the troops or something else
or just, and then the, and then the,
then a partial of it would be to
incinerate any record that, that,
that track was ever recorded.
The most pandering horse shit
you could ever come out with.
A horrific, sorry, sorry.
Plowing ahead here. So anyways, like
the horses were just in bad moods.
They'll bite and in each
other and they just like,
at one point I tried to make the thing
go left and went back and I tried to bite
my foot and I said the knee, I go,
Jesus, I go, this fucking thing hates me.
And then I just thought, I was like,
you know what? I'd hate me. Okay.
If I climbed on my back and I had a walk
me up this Goddamn Hill, I'd hate me.
There's somebody said that, you know,
they don't even feed a well over there.
I shouldn't say that shit cause
I named the place, I don't know,
tried to claim it.
They're over there.
They feed them like fucking shredded
wheat instead of the real stuff.
I have no idea.
But um,
okay.
It started off as this really
peaceful thing to be riding the horse,
which was awesome.
And then immediately I just was just like,
I couldn't get back soon enough
because I wanted to get off.
This thing's fucking back because I
knew that that's what the horse wanted.
You know, it's awful.
Just fucking, it just,
I think if I ever, if I have a fucking
had a ton of money, I've said this before,
I've ever got a horse I would get,
I would buy a horse just so I would never
ride it. So going to have, you know,
maybe once a week just to show him who's
boss, right? You plant those carrots,
they're fucking Seabiscuit.
Anyways,
I thought that was gonna be a funny
story and I've just been a sad story.
Kind of like the Boston Celtics losing
games seven. Oh, that's, that kills me.
That kills me that those guys, they're
going to break up that team, man.
I got to tell you, I've been, you know,
I wa I was lucky Celtic fan when I grew
up, I started watching and you know,
in sixth grade when a Larry Bird
came through and all that Shit,
the battles with the 70 sixers the fuck
in a Lakers and all that type of stuff.
And um,
I gotta tell you,
I am hard pressed to think of another
Celtic team that had more heart than the
Celtics. This, this version of the
Celtics, you know, they just never quit,
never say die.
It was brutal.
I'm watching doc rivers getting
all emotional when he hugged Kevin,
Garnett was uh,
it was fucking fucking brutal.
Brutal.
But you know by him, he, he did that
thing and you, I, I'm loving that Lebron,
you know, Lebron's one of those
guys that like, uh, I was like yeah,
what a Douche bag when he said I'm going
to bring my talents to south beach and
all that.
But I got over it after a while and then
just people just kept hating the guy
and it's to the point now I
almost want to see him win.
If I didn't like George didn't so much
like either way I'm going to be really
happy. Um, because uh,
I would love to see Lebron get one just
to make all everybody who hates him,
unless you're from Cleveland, if you
still hate Lebron, you're a Douche bag.
You know, you really just hate some aspect
of your life. But people in Cleveland,
they should hate that guy
and New York and Chicago,
they should be annoyed with that guy.
Cause he got you.
You guys get you all
excited. Like, you know,
Chicago six fucking rings.
They have the greatest player of all time.
Michael Jordan.
Okay.
They roll out the red carpet for you
and all you can come up with was, yeah,
I found their, their offer
intriguing, intriguing,
like he was rubbing his little,
uh, you know, I read books, beard,
that he's grown,
you know,
I'm into alternative medicine.
Uh, half a goatee. You know,
if you grow a fucking
beard like Brian has,
you better be like inventing
shit somewhere, wearing
some sort of a lab coat.
All right.
And stop putting on your fake black
rimmed glasses with the clear windshield.
Um,
you gotta hand it to black people.
They are the only ones who could make
somebody within a fucking erector set look
cool. They can somehow make
that look appealing, I guess.
But I got to tell you that NBA montage
where they showed like 12 of them in a
row all wearing those glasses was
fucking ridiculous. But anyways,
Chris Bosch killed us and
all that type of shit. Uh,
so I don't know. I have
no idea. But, um, I dunno,
I thought that they hate fucking aren't
it? They came out in the second half.
They fucking,
and they just never let up and we
couldn't get back in it. And uh,
I dunno. I don't know why the fuck we
were trying to guard Lebron that far out.
I mean, even van Gundy,
the whole game was like,
just make the guy take a jump shot.
You fucking press up on the guy.
He's too quick.
He's gonna run by you.
Once he gets to fucking a step and
a half that freight trains common,
you know, did, first of all,
there's no way to get in front of
them quick enough to get a charge.
You're going to get hurt.
All he could do is just try to hack at
the guy and he's going to get fouled and
it's either going to be two shots
or an an one. So why not hang back?
I don't know. Look at me watching
fucking the NBA for a couple of weeks.
All of a sudden I think I can
coach better than doc rivers. Um,
but anyways,
I'm going to game six tomorrow night
because the fucking kings have lost two in
a row. Flows. You don't watch
hockey man. They were a four game,
three games to none. Going to close
out the fourth game. I went downtown,
got absolutely fucking hammered.
MMM.
I planned on getting drunk.
I did take this subway
and uh,
what I also planned on eating something
went down there on an empty stomach and
we found this fucking bar that no one
was at that had this giant screen.
And we was sitting there laughing
lives two minutes before the game,
there was nobody in there felt
like we were on MTV cribs.
We didn't have to pay for the house.
And I don't know, we had two drinks.
We turned around and the place was jam
packed and then I went to order food and
the guy's like,
I'm sorry I'm not serving food now because
the stupid manager didn't take into
account that the kings could have won
their first Stanley Cup ever and that this
sports bar was going to be packed.
So he just had one guy working in the bar.
So while he was doing was making a
make drinks and uh, you know, me,
I'm trying to watch my girlish
figure here. So I fucking,
after a couple beers I
switched over to crowns at, uh,
I don't know what happened.
I vaguely remember at the end of the game
going out and getting a cheeseburger.
And uh, the dude behind
the counter, you know,
was a standup fan.
So he knew me and my buddy and he gave
us a drink and then he actually brought
over some sort of like, and I never
drink shit like this. He goes,
you should try these out. They're really
good. And it tasted like a milkshake,
but it had, it was like a shot
of it, but it had booze in it.
I just don't do well with that Shit,
you know,
I don't like that cross pollinating,
a let's have a dessert and get fucking
hammered. I don't do that. You know,
let's go to a titty bar and
get a cheeseburger. I don't
do that either. You know,
all the strip clubs that
serve fucking food, you know,
it's like do one or the other get,
get one of these things to focus,
need to be streamlined.
All right.
Okay.
So I'm trying to be the best
buy a titties. Right. Um,
just got absolutely fucking a knee.
Variated went down on the
subway and the subway,
it's almost like the red line in Boston.
Well one goes out to Braintree,
the other one goes to Matt a pan.
I was trying to go to Braintree and I
got on the mat of Pan one by accident.
I was like fuck.
So I had to get off hammered,
took it back the other way and I
go, yeah, I want the brain tree one.
Oh go downstairs.
So I go downstairs and they still
have two trains running on that track.
So I fucking got on the
mat of pan one again.
It was actually the Wilshire one and uh,
Oh God,
I was fucking livid when I
realized they made a mistake,
looked over at other passengers.
I was like,
it's just fucking thing
going down Wilshire.
And somebody looked at his buddy's like,
is he with you?
And everyone laughed at me. I
was like, Oh God, I'm that guy.
Then I got off the platform on the
platform and just had Tourette's fucking
Goddamn fucking stupid ass fucking city.
No fucking subway in the whole fucking
countries are just absolute f bomb.
And then some really nice girl
actually talk to me like ignored my
cursing and my angry anger and spitting on
the tracks. Just like, oh,
did you get on the wrong way to like,
yeah,
it's fucking fucking fucking fucking.
And then she's just like, yeah,
it is kinda confused. She didn't,
she didn't give it to him.
She was a saint. Everybody, that's
what I'm trying to say. All right,
last little round here of a,
of a,
what do we got here of advertising? I got
the last one here. Uh, gamefly everybody,
my listeners get a 15 day free trial
with two games mailed out in the trial.
New offer. What did you just give
me bullet points at this point?
Do you think I have the copy memorized?
See what all I remember. Remember, Hey,
you guys like playing video games,
don't you?
Wouldn't it be great if you had
8,000 video at your fingertips?
What does they can be delivered
right to your doorstep or your PC?
What if he got 15 day free
trial? Free trial? Come on,
you just broke up with your girlfriend,
right?
How many times are you going to lay there
staring at the ceiling wondering what
the hell you just did before you got to
play a video game and take your mind off
of it?
Well,
here's 8,008 you get a break up with with
like a thousand checks and never think
of any of them with 8,000 games at
your fingertips for 15 day free trial.
You can't beat it. Gamefly fly.com/burr
go in there. Click on the microphone.
Do what you gotta do.
Get all those video games.
All right,
Cleo,
we just stop licking your privates.
Hey,
we just go off in the corner.
Okay?
What are you doing?
Okay,
fucking weird.
You do it like every fucking 20 minutes.
Yeah.
Do you know?
Do you need to go to the doctor?
You if you could see the way
this dog is just staring at me,
like she actually understands what I'm
saying. What's up buddy? You know what?
You know what's a great place to
scratch your dog is underneath the call.
Every once in a while they
wear the collar forever.
I take my dog's collar off
like every night, you know,
not because I'm a good dog owner.
It's because she wakes up before I do
and she shakes like a madman like this,
like that. And it's basically
my alarm clock in the morning.
So I take this fucking thing off and then
I give her a nice scratch on the back
of the neck and she gets,
you know that look,
dogs get on their face
where they kind of like,
it's this weird thing where they
don't move their body forward.
They just move their face forward. Like,
Ah God, that's what it's doing right now.
And you liked it, don't ya? Huh?
That's what you can't get to.
Alright,
next scratch.
That's it right there. That's what
she does with her fucking years.
And I know it did sound that loud, but
at fucking six in the morning. I'm sorry,
seven o'clock in the morning.
It's real loud. All Right, Bill,
we've had enough of your personal life.
Hey Bill,
is there any way you could bring the post
office into my apartment? Absolutely.
I could. Um, stamps.com everybody,
there's no reason to go to
the post office anymore. Okay,
so over like bell bottoms,
it's done. All right,
this is just yet another
thing with today's technology.
You can just actually handle while you're
walking around eating a bowl of fruit
loops. If you could do that with
one hand and type on a keyboard,
you go to stamps.com everybody,
um,
is a great thing about stamps.com.
Not only will it save you time,
you can buy and print official US postage
from your own computer or printer.
Okay. Slap it on an envelope.
They give you a little stick,
give you a little scale.
You can weigh whatever the
hell you're trying to ship out.
It'll give you the
postage right on the Meta.
You slap that on there and you stick it
out in your mailbox. It's done. It's,
it's a, it's a complete circle. All right.
stamps.com also will you money.
It's a fraction of the cost of a,
of a postage meter. Plus you get
discounts. You can't even find it.
The post office. What more do these
people need to do a, right now,
if you use my last name bur
bur for the special offer,
you get a no risk trial plus a $110 bonus
that includes a digital scale and up
to $55 in free postage or right?
Don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before you do
anything else, click on the radio
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburpeeyouarearethatstamps.com
enter B,
u r r. Do that. You know, unless
you enjoy going to the post office,
maybe you're one of those people,
maybe you like going down there trying
to find a place to park and all the other
things that go along with that.
The homeless guy holding the door for you.
Thank you. God bless. Thank
you. God bless. I could
done that myself. Thank you.
Thank you. Now you're the martyr. I know.
Now I got to give you money on the
way out. I get it. I get it. Um,
or you could just be, you know,
sitting there and your jocks.
Anyone else's dad used to call?
You're underway. Get jocks. Uh,
all right. This podcast is getting
too long. All right, let's,
let's wrap it up here. Why did we
go here? Where did we go here? Uh
Oh,
what is this? Oh, there's
somebody reacting to last
week's that epic story, uh,
that,
that bisexual kid whose mom parents were
really religious and how they find out
he was gay was he was
hooking up with, uh, is,
is some dude in the house and she
started whacking them with the male,
uh, and it was just guy says
Cybele I heard the bisexual,
a gay dude story you told in your podcast
most recently about the guy who moved
from the Carolinas to Arizona for college
and it got caught doing the deed by
his mom. I am not gay. I do not have any
gay tendencies or anything like that,
but I've seen a similar circumstance
happen with a close friend.
I know that the dude's mom and the whole
family feels awkward about him being
gay,
but the more indifferent they act,
the more likely the 19
year old guy from Carolina,
we'll end up doing something he will
probably regret. Absolutely. Anyway,
my advice is this,
show your mom the movie prayers for
Bobby and she will turn right around.
I guarantee it. Hope things work out. All
right. I don't know what that movie is,
but if the person who wrote in last
week, uh, go ahead and read that,
go watch that movie will show it to your
mom and hopefully she'll come around.
Um, dilemma number one, Bill,
would you rather have been born with this
sporting talent to be an NHL all star
or the musical talent to drum
for ACDC after Phil Rudd?
Ah, that's a good, that
is a fucking dilemma.
MMM.
God dammit. That's a coin flip
right there. All, all right,
well here's the deal.
If I could play in the NHL,
I play in the eighties despite the hair
metal music that would probably be being
played while I did the skate
around at the beginning.
That's a shoot around whenever
the fuck you call it. Um,
wait. Do I have my body? I
mean, I want to be a tough guy.
If I'm going to play in the
NHL, I'm be, I have a a a eight.
The very best a goal scorer,
his body.
And even then I'm too small.
I'm barely five foot 10 guys could
do that back then. Could I be,
if I could be chippy every once
in a while, Nevin mark what style?
I don't know. Oh, the musical talent
to drum for ACDC after Phil Rudd Wolf.
I drummed for ACDC after Phil Rudd,
I'd be Simon Wright from 83 to 90.
Then I would leave to Joan [inaudible]
and have to play last in line.
Okay.
Or I could have been considering balding.
Maybe I'd be Chris Slade
who drums from 90 to 96 and all of a
sudden gets kicked out just because they
want to bring Phil Rudd back. I
don't like those endings. Those are,
those are like running back careers
was a real short, I know what,
I'll take the Nhl all star,
a fucking all star and I get to worry
that that Campbell's or whales jersey. Oh,
I take that have a fucking red mullet.
I'm a Harris to gets
curly when it grows long.
I'd looked like Bernie from run to 22
I take the NHL. That was a good one.
That was the old coin flip.
All right, now, but to dilemma,
imagine you're walking in a built up
area and come across a glittery box.
What does a built up area,
curiosity compels you to look
inside it and upon doing so,
find it stacked full of child pornography,
your prints and DNA or on the box.
She can't walk away from it.
If you set it on fire,
what happens if the cops stop?
If a cop stops you or a residence and
they notice a half charred picture of an
eight year, ah, he's burning evidence.
If you handed it into the complete the
police, you'd still be implicated. No,
I wouldn't. If I find a fucking
dead body on the side of the road,
I don't get charged with murder.
Quick light it on fire.
Okay.
This is hilarious. Anyway, let
me just keep reading this. Um,
I'd be implicated as a suspect because
I found a tin of child pornography and I
brought it in. They probably give me
shift for contaminating the evidence.
That would look weird though if I walked
in. Hey, I found this on the side.
I kind of see where you go with this.
Yeah.
Ah, you just would, uh, oh,
he's just saying no matter what,
you just would get implicated.
And I think you could do without
headlines like comedian hands,
child porn into police claims
found it and he's misunderstood.
Like Michael Jackson, if you decide
to take it home to destroy it.
What if you stopped by a gang of use
on the way and it's knocked out of your
hand and the entire Detroit depraved
mass spills across the floor.
Uh, if you don't get at home and turn
it into a paper machete and the sink,
what
if you do get it home and it turns
into paper machine, the sink.
What if it blocks it? Or Nia
asks what? You're up to. Nothing.
They are just destroying images of naked.
Preteens.
So how would you deal with this
terrible situation? A simple,
yeah.
Curiosity compels me to
look at the glittery box.
I would open it and upon
seeing the content within,
I would jump back like Morgan Freeman's
character in [inaudible] seven,
when he sees Gwyneth Paltrow's
severed head in the box.
All right.
Then I would just start
running in circles yelling.
He has the upper hand until I'm
arrested and put in an insane asylum.
I just, if I've found, I would
just, I would report it immediately.
I would report it immediately,
you know,
that's it.
I saw it, I opened it, it was in
there and that's it. Go ahead.
Parade a bunch of half naked kids in
front of me and watch me not get aroused.
There you go. There's my fucking
defense. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'm trying to help you guys out.
Why don't you dust it and find the other
set of friends and go start with that
Douche. All right, now me and my pussy
looking dog or getting Outta here.
Go Fuck Yourself. Hi,
I'm all right. Lights,
camera dumped bill.
I'm a 29 year old guy in recently broke
up with a funny attractive and all
around Greg girl. Oh Gee.
Why Sir would you do that?
You ask.
All right.
MMM.
Two things.
Her Dad was born without teeth and you're
worried your baby will if you braid
with her or
is she has got something
going on in the vaginal area,
some sort of odor, stinky pussy. I
don't know. Well, here we go. Well,
let me tell you,
this girl and I had been dating for about
three months and we had a great thing
going. She's half Afro Cuban,
half Puerto Rican and really sexy.
She had a rough upbringing,
but I didn't care because she's honest,
easy going and not bitchy. Like so many
girls I've dated. She was a bit needy,
but I didn't mind.
Um,
we were out at a bar one night having a
few drinks and I was feeling pretty good.
I was looking at a couple of floozies
at the end of the bar and asked her if
she's ever been with another woman.
She coyly looked at me and said, yes,
good stuff. I thought, yeah, dude,
this is a fucking fantasy right here.
If I get a red shoe diaries.
Um, then I proceeded with,
have you ever been in a threesome
with two girls and a guy again?
She answered yes.
Okay.
Okay. Kind of slutty, but I'm no
saint. While he couldn't stop,
they are God, you're going to
go for the rotisserie question.
What's in the box? Ah, here we go.
Here we go. Strap yourselves in for
this one. Well, I couldn't stop there.
So I asked, have you ever had
a threesome with two guys?
She looked down at the ground
and she looked up a bit ashamed,
Lee and said yes. Wow. Skank alert.
I thought I then asked
her one more question.
I knew this one could back for
where the fuck do you go from here?
Like throwing the high heat to Albert
Albert pool hosts. I finally asked,
wait,
have you ever been in a porn?
She then blushed and look me
in the eye and said, yeah.
I looked at her calmly and was
like, oh, but inside I was like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Yes. Well, you should,
you know those first couple.
I mean,
you can look at let, let's,
let's break this down here.
All right. She's been with,
uh,
she's had a threesome with another
girl and a guy who get that.
That's who gives a fuck right there.
All right.
You're already knew she banged
another guy. All right. But, uh,
the fact that she also did it with another
girl, that takes a little fucking, uh,
that tones down his dick in her pussy.
Right? This is how guys think. Women,
I'm sorry. All right. That's something
that, that's something in the, uh,
the credits that the
credit a bit. Why, why,
why do you try to talk with counting
shit yet to dump. All right,
that one's all right.
The two guys thing.
Now you can look the other way on that.
Maybe if it, if it was in another state,
but it can't be in the same state because
if you run into one of the two guys
that fucking, you know, we're high fiving
as they fucking banged her that, I mean,
I dunno about that one. But then the third
one she did a porno. I mean, yeah, no,
that's a,
yeah.
You got to walk away from that
or,
or you have to go to NASA to get
tested for the latest fucking STDs,
I would think. And then also
God knows what's going on, uh,
mentally that you would do that.
What I just liked sex,
not on health is some going on. Who
doesn't like sex? I Dunno. Anyways,
plowing ahead. See, she's so, she egos.
So basically she had moved down
to Los Angeles when she was 20.
She's now 25 and after a
short stint in the military,
somehow she got into the porn industry
for eight months. She did everything.
Ooh.
Fox sucked the whole Shebang.
I asked her if I could see her video but
she wouldn't tell me her performer name
and said Vietnam, the that it would be
impossible to find her body of work.
I asked her why she got
into porn and she replies,
yeah
cause I wanted some feeling in my life.
And then he writes Dao Ji Ji is,
yeah dude. Oh this poor girl.
Something happened to her.
The thing was she was clean,
had a good job and I really liked her
and the sex was great. Yeah. Obviously,
you know it's funny,
there was something you wrote in the
beginning where I just thought she was
going to be good. 29 year old guy.
Attractive all around. Great girl.
Oh, the fact that you said she had a rough
upbringing but she was easy going and
honest and not bitchy right there.
I was like, that girl's good in bed.
Okay.
That just seemed like a kind
of free open person. I Dunno.
Okay.
I didn't know she was going to be
that open. Oh Geez. Um, anyways,
okay.
The thing was she was clean and
I have a blah. The sex is great,
but I couldn't stop picturing her in some
sleazy porno that was probably filmed
in some junk yard on labrea.
So I went to ask for a friend's advice.
Most of my guys were telling me to dumper
my gay friends told me it was fabulous
and that I should overlook it.
I didn't even bother asking my girlfriends
because they would automatically
reject her and assume I had aids.
There you go. Keep your options open.
So regretfully I dumped her.
Okay.
I felt terrible and obviously didn't tell
her it was because she was a porn star
because she would have been
ashamed for the rest of her life.
And I was happy that she was honest with
me. I've done my fair share of sleeves,
but this was too much. My question
bill was, Bill, my question bill,
was it wrong for me to dump him for
some decisions she made years ago?
Should I have stayed with her?
What would have you done? Um,
well, you don't want to know what I
would've done. I'm a fucking degenerate.
So lets you, you seem
like a good person. Um,
okay,
dude.
When you're trying to find the person
you're going to spend the rest of your
life with you, you have to have
a list of criteria. All right?
You sound like you still young, so there's
no reason to compromise. All right?
I mean,
when you get with somebody like that and
you're going to live with them and you
would, you get with anybody, you're
taking on all of their fucking baggage.
All right?
You're only three months in.
Okay.
And you know, people who go into
the porn industry that, you know,
it's like people will come. Comedians
were not healthy individuals. Okay.
And that is like a
specific area that I just,
this is just my own personal nonmedical
feeling that you're just not a healthy
person. Something awful happen. And that
line, I just wanted to feel something.
I mean, something bad happened to
her, caused her to a wall or self off.
I don't even want to try to guess what,
but you know,
there's nothing wrong with that. She
did purse, you know, technically,
and she was honest with it.
It all comes down to whether or not
you want to deal with it. All right?
And if you feel that you know,
you want to deal with it and that there
was this sort of connection that you
just had,
this girl had to be in your life,
then you're going to have to learn
to live with it and get past it.
Okay.
MMM.
But I would be definitely,
I would definitely be concerned
with a certain mental issues,
um,
now like she's insane.
And then I would also be concerned with,
uh,
sexual boundaries,
you know,
like,
would she have any,
and could she remain faithful after a
while and when you settle into the seven
year itch or whatever,
and you really start needing to work at
the relationship and it's feeling boring
and she needs to feel something again,
is she going to go back to that
leather couch from that show,
Martin? My end, you know,
down on fog in the valley and get
bagged again. I mean, I don't know.
I Dunno. That is a, uh,
that is, you know what,
that is beyond my skills.
I don't know how to tame that horse.
I can tell you that right fucking now.
I have no fucking clue. That's a a,
you know what?
That's a doctor drew question.
That is a classic doctor drew question.
And that guy within two seconds
we'll get right to the core of it.
I would call out, call in love line
man, if you're out here, call him up.
Cause that's a, that's a great one. Um,
yeah,
I guess you'd have to figure out is,
is has she worked through whatever the
fuck she was working through and now
she's ready to.
Okay.
I mean, I dunno. Hey those are some good
looking girls down there and she's like,
yeah they are or whatever. Like, I mean
if you kept steering it in that direction,
you'd probably get you fucking
threesome right there. Um,
okay.
So there's that,
there's that option.
The option that you have is if
you're with her, like I think that's,
that's a selfish fucking and I,
and a shallow reason to stay
with somebody long term,
uh,
that Jesus, I don't know.
Great fucking emails by the
way. Everybody open and Piss.
You guys off too much by fucking trash
and all that metal shit. You know,
I have half those t shirts
and I went to go see that.
I was just embarrassed by some of that
shit that I used to listen to. Um,
okay.
Oh Jesus. Right up until I was like
2021 fucking brutal. What, what, what,
what redeemable thing that I have.
I did listen to the Beatles,
the doors to stones, all that
white boy shit. Stevie Ray Vaughan.
I did listen to Hendrix.
I listened to all the big band swing.
My Dad shift from the fifties.
Uh,
I had such a weird musical
upbringing anyways,
which was actually good because
it was kind of all over the map.
MMM.
I started hanging out with
Patrice back in the day.
Patrice was the one rest
his soul got me the, uh,
I still remember when he got in that same
piece of shit truck that I went to the
ACDC concert and seven fucking years
later, I'm still driving it. Right.
Making the sacrifices.
Remember that I told you,
you don't get some fucking job and
go out and buy a fucking new car.
You just change yourself to your cubicle.
I was kept Mike,
I put a new engine in the fucking truck,
had somebody slap that
in there for 1200 bucks,
pay that down rather than 12 grand for
a new car like it was back then. Um,
so when he was,
I still remember
mmm.
Swinging by picking Patrice up and going
into next and he had the cassette tape
of re, uh, ready to die.
And him putting that in.
MMM.
Telling me that this guy was
going to be the next guy.
And then through all of that,
like he cured me of all the rap that a
white kid liked who lived in a cul de
sac.
MMM.
And he showed me all the, all of that
shit. So I had that whole background,
all that stuff fucking held up.
But the fucking metals that I listened to,
I even watched like Lawrence
Welk when I was a kid,
when the creepiest shows ever even
that was fucking thrown in there.
Okay.
It's funny,
like fucking almost 40 years later I'll
be walking down the street and all of a
sudden Winchester cathedral,
we'll be going through my head when
Chester could thedro Bozzuto de to yell
Brang and made down.
Am I really gonna sing this?
You could have done something.
All right, let's wrap this
up. Um, upcoming shows.
Uh,
I want to be at the Improv in San Jose.
June 14th and 15th. This
weekend, Sacramento zone.
Chelsea Peretti is not going to be
there unfortunately. So I replaced her.
Okay.
Like that chick on that fucking
show with the Sandy Duncan.
Um, Kevin shake, Kevin Shay is going
to be there. Was fucking hilarious.
Really original. So it's
going to be an awesome show.
San Jose. June 14th and 15th,
at the Improv Theater in
downtown San Jose. Uh,
on June 17th,
I'll be at the Chicago theater part of
the Vince Vaughn Wild West comedy show,
uh,
with Steve Byrne.
Vince Vaughn and a bunch of other
guys is going to be an amazing show.
I that might already be sold out
a mets June 17th. So if it isn't,
it's going to be go to [inaudible] dot
com and you click on all these ticket
links real quick. Uh, the
Ontario Improv, June 9th,
30th and July 1st the inland empire.
And then I'll be going out
in the Boston area, dote,
Hampton Beach Ballroom Casino,
Hampton Beach, fucking New Hampshire.
July 14th and after that I'm going down
to Rhode Island kid going down to the
Newport yacht and center July 15th,
I'll be in a tent out in the parking lot.
Come on down. There'll be a good time.
And that's it. That's it. That's
the podcast for this week.
Thank you for listening. Um,
I'm going to miss those Celtics.
God dammit. I'm going to miss him.
Hell of a run. And it still kills me.
That fourth quarter of the 2009 finals,
I really wished the refs had gotten out
of the way and if the Celtics were going
to lose, I could have watched the
Lakers. You know when that, you know,
not taking 24 unguarded
shots that just fucking kid.
And it's not the Lakers fault. I
just, the fucking reps, they just,
they have too much goddamn power.
Too much fucking power, man.
Puts you a fucking whistle
away. All right. That's it.
Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next week.