Hey,
what's going on is Bill Byrd is time for
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
February 15th, 2016 hello. How are you?
How was your world going on this Monday?
How was your Valentine's Day? Huh?
Did she get her something special?
Um, if you're a smart son of a bitch, um,
you're either not in a relationship or
you're not taking her out until tonight
or tomorrow, whatever. Whenever the
prices go back down again, you know,
and by the way,
if enough people start doing this in the
old fucking restaurants get wise to it
and they start making their prices higher,
Valentine's Day prices a few days before,
a few days after,
then fucking wait a week, wait
a month, do it a month earlier.
Um,
it's the biggest fucking rip
off probably of the year,
other than probably what's
going on to Bernie Sanders,
but I don't really understand.
I guess she has some Super Dell delegates,
you know,
oh fuck.
And Hillary Clinton's got the super
and she already has to super delegate.
She already has a hundred. She, he
needs 120, whatever the fuck that is.
Jesus Christ. It's like,
it's like playing bridge,
trying to keep up what's going on.
I have no idea.
All I know is I liked that Bernie looks
like an old dog trying to eat a meal
when he's talking. Harvard recovered. I
don't know what the fucking jowls going.
And the weird thing said his fingers do.
I like it.
I could look at that for four
years. Um, and it got to admit,
and as much as I don't like all
the racist shit Trump is doing,
I do love some fucking jerk off
yelling at other politicians.
So that part has been enjoyable.
You're a liar.
There are there,
there weren't any mass weapons of mass
destruction and they know it maybe sounds
like he's quoting some podcasts.
Um, I have no idea. At some point
I'm going to start paying attention.
There's gotta be some even
keeled so-and-so out there.
I have no fucking clue.
I have no clue.
And last week I said that I hated when
people are in the public eye. Talk about,
uh, politics. You know, that's not true.
I hate when they fucking tell me why
I should vote for somebody. Oh Shit.
Well you were you the guy from a
interview with the vampire. Oh yeah.
Who should I elect for a
leader of the free world?
It was like with Tom Cruise was talking
about psychology. It's like, Oh yeah,
you pretended to be a shogun
warrior in a NASCAR champion.
Let me a while. But by all means, let me
listen to you talk about modern medicine.
Um, as long as you preface it
with like, I'm a fucking moron,
I don't know what I'm talking about.
But uh, here you go. You know,
but when you really start believing it,
that's when you get in trouble. It may be,
I believe it, and maybe this is the way
I'm just sort of soft pedaling it, Tia,
I'm playing the more on is
I'm fucking feeding your,
my putting the little a ringworm and
you're fucking ear whatever people say
there with the fucking ear worm,
right?
Some song you can't stand gets
in your fucking head. You know,
it's kind of a weird ones.
What a song you like gets in your
head and then you don't mind.
And then you drive everybody
nuts around you. Like, uh, um,
Steve Gorman from Steve Gorman sports
sent me this, this link to this, uh,
this country star that's been, um,
that's been struggling for a long,
long time.
And he finally got a big break.
I believe he's a distant cousin
of worry. Clark, I'm not sure,
but his name is Wheeler Walker Jr and uh,
he sent me a clip that
I'll send you guys a,
it's a great fucking song for Valentine's
Day if you are not in a relationship
for a man or a woman.
And a,
the hook is just been stuck in my head
and I really want to sing it to you,
but it's going to ruin it for you.
So go look up a wheeler Walker Jr.
Uh, well I guess the song kind of
ruins it. It's called fuck you bitch.
And it's really catchy and it's a,
I dunno, it's fits rich, kind of
poetic. I really think the, uh,
the chorus really sums up what you
feel when somebody breaks your heart.
So, um, you know, country music,
those country music stars,
they can do that to you
every once in a while.
And it's nice to see someone
go to the left, you know,
those fucking country singer. So those
poor bastards for all these fucking years,
you know,
they've been abusing drugs and you know,
going to clan meetings and beating
the shit out of their women,
but when they get on TV, they got to
do that family values thing, you know?
Yeah. Gosh, well thank Jesus. I'm just,
I just feel blessed at Y'all taking
me into your heart. TNL Hey yell,
he wants you on some potato salad.
That's stupid,
phony fucking southern thing where if
you're from up north the first time you
see it,
you know your heart and melts.
When you hear that Twang and
you just think that the egg,
the nicest fucking person, nobody can
stick the fucking knife in your back
like a fucking southerner. What that
fucking, hey y'all, how'd you hit our,
you spoke and they downplay it.
They play dumb,
but Blahblahblahblahblah
and next thing you know,
you're laying in a fucking pig trough
about ready to get fucking eaten alive.
That's how it goes down.
All right.
And that guy from fucking 50
snatches and 40 smoking barrels,
that's where he got it from.
Okay. Not from that content,
you know, I dunno what the fuck
I'm talking about. Anyways,
I watched a brand new TV
show last night and uh,
I was really fucking disappointed,
you know, I fucking turned it on.
I needed a new show and I thought it
was going to be the one, you know,
I was like, this is going to be it.
It's Valentine's Day night. Okay.
Me and the lovely Nia,
we're not going out.
I had a fucking one of those Tomahawk
steaks frozen in the freezer.
The fucking
right defroster dead bitch all day.
I watch like 30 youtube
videos has had dude sat.
Do you know if you're going to do to them?
Look to it to do one
more towards don't soon.
I watch like 50 those fucking things.
And I just sort of like,
I took a survey with temperature and
time flippage in all of that stuff,
and I went down the middle and,
uh,
I got a little impatient
with the big green egg.
My temperature's a little
higher than I want it.
So came out of the medium
rather than a medium rare,
but it was still fucking delish. And
now there was a new series that, that,
um,
that I tried to get into last
night and I put it on and, uh,
it looked good. The acting was great,
but the dialogue just wasn't there.
And I tried to fucking fight it out for
the first 20 minutes and then I was just
looked over at Nia. Nia
did one of those. Yeah.
You know, big inhale and the fucking
eyes like, yeah, this is a, yeah.
And then I was just like, well, let's
shut it off. She's like, no, you know,
we gotta at least watch the pilot episode,
you know,
which is how she ended up marrying me
because I believe 20 minutes into our
relationship, she was like, yeah,
but she fucking stuck it through night.
She kept panning for gold and she found
a little nugget and she stuck with me.
I didn't, I was just like,
fuck this. I'm out. And uh,
by 40 minutes into it, I was
imitating people in it and, uh,
the whole thing just went down
the shitter. So once again,
but you know what it, you
know, I'm finally going to do,
I think I'm finally going to start
watching game of Thrones now that they're
fucking five, 10, 15 fucking
seasons into it. I've,
I've been trying to watch
it for the longest time,
but a nia has just not into it.
You know,
she has want to see a bunch of white
people running around chasing dragons.
It's just not what she's into. And,
uh, I'm not really into dragons either,
but like, if you're going to cut somebody
fucking head off, like, um, you know,
you got to do a lot to lose me
after that point, you know, I dunno.
Maybe. I Dunno who the
fuck knows. Maybe I,
I remember watching the first one and
there was some sort of spooky thing going
on and there was some little kid that
was supposed to watch a beheading and he
looked away and then it is,
I figured out what his dad did,
put them on the rack or
something. I don't remember. Um,
but then I don't, I don't know
what happened and that just kept,
it kept going and you know,
it was like a train that was coming right.
And you coulda ran and caught
it, but I, but you don't,
you just stand there and
you watch it disappear.
And in that moment when that train
disappears and you realize you're late for
work in that fucking moment,
you question everything that
you're doing in your life.
Why didn't I run for that train?
Because I have this job that I don't like.
What am I doing in this relationship?
What happened to me?
What happened the last six
years in my fucking life? Right?
It's a critical moment there where you
have to beat all those thoughts down,
bury them, and go back to be
in the Zombie that you are.
Which brings me to the walking
dead. No, I'm kidding. Um,
anyways,
I want to thank everyone
who came out in Cheyenne,
Wyoming.
I kept doing a southern accent the
entire time I was out there and I was
addressing it, but, uh, I don't know what
Wyoming people sound like. I'm Cheyenne,
Wyoming and Denver,
Colorado.
I went out with a deed del Rey and uh,
we had the great fucking time played this,
um,
the Cheyenne civic center.
How cool does that sound?
Had all this amazing woodwork inside of
it that really looked like one of those
log cabins that either an oil man or a
fucking Hollywood starlet goes and buys.
You know,
like when people like it,
a huge amount of success
pretending to be other people.
At some point they have to get out of La.
And then they always end up
in like Wyoming or Montana.
It's fucking hilarious.
And they buy what looks like a log cabin,
sort of.
It looks like a log cabin and like a
fucking resort all at the same time,
you know? And then they go out there
and they buy, they're a designer.
I'm a fucking cattle rancher wardrobe.
And then they do the fucking interview,
right.
With their big stupid
cowboy hat on and older,
wiser is so and so steps back to uh,
evaluate the last six years of a
whirlwind, whatever the fuck it is. Right.
You know what I mean?
And then they pretend that they can
live this little fucking life out there
before they go nuts after three days and
they call up and chief five to pick him
up and take them right back, you know,
and they end up back down to the chateau,
the Chateau Mall, um,
doing blow in a bungalow.
That's what you do. You find it
a little bit of balance. Um, Oh,
speaking of fucking,
before I go back on that shit.
Speaking of fucking sick ass houses,
I was,
I went on this Paul Newman kick, you
know, he's my favorite of all time.
You know, a lot of people go Steve
McQueen. I like Steve Mcqueen,
but Paul Newman's my guy. He's
my fella. I just, I dunno,
once I look into those blue eyes, I just,
I melt to Thalia. Anything. I believe it.
Are you a pool shark? Are you
a lawyer? Do you play hockey?
Um, I watched, uh,
well I guess the first thing I watched, I
watched, uh, the man with the golden arm,
which d, which Delray was
telling me to watch, which was a,
a movie about a Frank Sinatra
playing a heroin addict who,
uh,
you know,
comes out of jail when it gets cleaned
and he plays the drums and he wants to
get a gig playing drums. And uh,
I watched a great fucking movie.
There's some brutal,
brutal overacting. Um,
you gotta I dunno, I would definitely
recommend seeing that. So I finished that.
You know,
it's like the next thing that was coming
up was somebody up there likes me,
which I'd always heard
of when I was growing up.
And then once I saw it was Paul
Newman, I was like, all right,
I'm going to watch it.
And it was him playing now rocky
Graziano the rocky Graziano story.
And um, and I literally forget what
I was talking. Oh, that's right.
That's right. So then it just got me
on this, this, this Paul Newman thing.
And you know what's funny is, uh, this,
this thing actually Steve McQueen is in
that movie for fucking two seconds and
it's right as Graziani was getting
out of some fucking, uh, you know,
juvenile detention home
that he fucking escapes.
So He's going around the
neighborhood, tapping all
these guys, all this tough guy,
friends on the shoulders to be like,
Hey, I'm back in the neighborhood.
And all of them turn around like,
who the fuck is this guy? Right?
Cause cause it Tufts street
kids, so fucking, uh,
fucking Steve McQueen is shooting pool.
They rocky taps him on the shoulder and
he fucking turns around with a knife out,
just two seconds. And then he
realizes it's reads like it's rocky.
He's like gay,
rocky.
And he does this stupid fucking thing
with his head that I don't know who
fucking,
there's certain things in movies that
the first guy who plays that guy does.
And then it's this weird fucking thing
where every other actor after it starts
fucking doing it. And you
know, nobody ever did it.
Who's actually the guy
that they're playing.
But then it's done enough and fucking
movies that the people who were actually a
guy, then they start fucking doing it.
And that's when it becomes a circle.
And you don't know who the fuck it is.
It's this fucking thing like a,
it's almost like, say you were
getting a manicure, right?
And you want it to dry off your nails
and you do just exactly a rocky and he's
doing this stupid fucking
thing with his hand. Um,
I dunno,
I'm going a really long way here to
tell you what I really want to tell you.
But like one of my favorite things is
to watch actors during that era playing
Tufts street kids. Um, like it's just,
it's fucking cringeworthy dead
fucking movie that Marlon Brando did.
He's on the motorcycle.
What the fuck was that one called?
It's not the wild bunch. That was a
cowboy movie. Rebel without a cart now.
And it's James Dean. I can't
remember, but just the,
the have to sit there and watch that shit.
Um,
how fucking brutal it is.
That west side story,
which I don't think I've ever seen.
I'm just going to throw that in
that cause I need three of them. Um,
I dunno. Whatever. So I
started watching that.
So then I finished that one and
then the next one that came on,
I can't even remember the name
of it. Fuck, hang on a second.
I got to IMD be fucking Paul Newman.
Um,
he just has the bluest eyes,
Paul Newman.
I am fucking be filmography.
So anyways, um, I think
it was called not Hudson.
The long story was this
next movie comes on, right?
And in the beginning he's driving in
this car and he's clearly in Los Angeles,
which was one of my favorite fucking
things ever to just see old footage,
black and white or color of La.
And he just get to see like you can
usually tell by the Hollywood hills and
sometimes the highways and shit
kind of where they are. And um,
you'll see like train tracks and shit
that they ripped up those fucking cunts or
you'll see, um, you know, you just see how
less populated is all right. Here it is.
Harper Harper is the movie the
very beginning of the movie.
He goes into a house and uh,
Lauren because in there Lauren Bacall
who married a Humphrey Bogart Bogie and
Bacall, one of the great couples
in Hollywood history and uh,
you know,
Humphrey Bogart,
somebody that Frank Sinatra's
stole a lot of his swagger from.
They were also the first rat pack
Humphrey Bogart and all his fucking crew.
And uh,
not only did a Sinatra steel,
a lot of Humphrey Bogart swagger,
he actually ended up fucking Lauren Bacall
later on after Humphrey Bogart died,
which is really fucked up. But
anyways, I digress. So at Harper,
he pulls into this fucking house
that I could not believe and uh,
I actually looked it up and it's
still exists. Look it up right now.
If you're at work, pretend that you're
doing, uh, that you're doing some sort of,
I'm busy work.
It's,
it's on one zero one
one north Beverly drive,
10 11 Beverly drive.
And uh,
this fucking house, I think it's
just called the Beverly House,
it's in Beverly Hills,
probably has one of the sickest fucking
pools I've ever seen in my life.
It's like a three tiered thing.
The first two tiers I believe
are just considered a waterfall.
And first of all, it has like a half mile
driveway that he DKI comes up around.
And what's Hilarious,
which will,
it looks like the first year they had
the Porsche, which at this point by 1965,
when they shot,
it was just considered a piece of shit.
Who would know that years later,
some baby boomer would play
like fucking 900 grand for it.
So he's driving up one of, you know, it's
one of the fenders is like that fucking,
you know, what's that dead paint
that they primered and all that shit.
So he pulls up in this fucking house.
You got to see the backyard if it,
so actually I look the fucking thing up.
I found out where it was and the
next time I fly a helicopter,
I'm gonna fucking fly over the house
and check it out. Um, it's actually, uh,
just a little bit north of
the Beverly Hills Hotel,
but you got to check this
fucking thing out. Um,
one of the great things about living in
Los Angeles, a lot of people, you know,
always shit on living in la,
but one of the main,
I think la arguably has some
of the most amazing homes,
um, in the country, just for the
simple fact that for whatever reason,
I don't know if it's the weather out here
or what, they haven't been torn down.
Um, so many of them, um, you know,
other places that I've been to,
but they have like craftsman houses out
here and then they have all the Spanish,
the Mediterranean style
ones. They have a, they got,
it's just incredible houses.
So you've got to check this one out.
This house is actually kind of
ugly, you know, when you pull up,
they shot the godfather, part
two there, but I part one there.
This is actually the house
where, uh, the horses head scene,
um,
spoiler alert if he,
if you're one of the two people
I've never seen that fucking movie.
They shot that scene in there and JFK and
his wife Jackie had their honeymoon in
this fucking house and I just saw it
recently. The last time it's sold.
It's sold for $135 million.
And all I'm doing looking at it after
by in my old ass house that was made in
1923,
all I see is fucking 50,000 square foot
of galvanized pipe and cloth wiring that
they're going to have to somehow
fucking redo where we'll sections of it.
You know,
there's a little bit of copper pipe here,
a little bit of wiring that
was done correctly. Um,
but anyways,
that's another cool thing about these
fucking houses out there is that they've
been around so long and if they're
in a desirable area in Hollywood,
like the stories of like the people
that live there, like how cool. I mean,
that's $135 million house,
obviously be a fucking amazing house.
But how fucking amazing it would
be to have that house and be like,
you didn't see a movie and you watch him,
Paul Newman walking across your fucking
terrorists that you now want to.
I don't know. I think that Shit's
cool as hell. But um, you know,
while you're at it,
you can check out a lot of those.
And also just look up
famous Hollywood homes. Um,
I told you there's a house about,
not even like,
I dunno,
maybe a 15 minute drive away
from me in, in, in Los Angeles.
15 minutes is a big fucking
deal. Sometimes just, you know,
15 blocks,
it can go one way or another.
It can literally go like to,
I'm going to get stabbed to,
how to fuck can you
ever afford to live in?
How many people did you steal
from to get this fucking,
this guy's got a moat around his
house. Lets, lets the way La is,
it's like really like patchwork.
So like a 15 minute drive
away from where I live. Um,
my neighbor told me there's a
house that went up for sale.
I think I told this story before and um,
it's an old ass house. It's pre
prohibition and basically, uh,
when prohibition came around this,
this house had a pool and then it had a,
a Cabana and in the Cabana at this guy,
he built a bar during prohibition and he
had illegal booze or I don't know if he
was making beer in the bathtub, whatever
the fuck he was doing. But he used to,
he used to have all these famous people
come over there and they would just
booze it up. And um, he,
anybody who came over there
and drank that was famous,
he would have them carve their
names into the bar. And, uh,
evidently according to my neighbor
who went and looked at the house,
even though we couldn't afford it,
he just wanted to see the bar.
He went and looked at it. And it's one
of those things, if you buy the house,
it's that bars obviously protected
by the historical society,
some shit.
But you go in there and everyone from
like Louis Armstrong to like fucking
Humphrey Bogart have to have carved their
names into that fucking bar. So, um,
whatever, that's some sort of nerdy
Los Angeles. How shit. But um,
yeah, definitely. Uh,
rather than work today,
just go on Google earth and just look
at some of those fucking houses. Um,
or just Google, like famous Hollywood
homes through this homes where like,
you know, when I was watching that, you
know, somebody up there likes me, uh,
or I should really know the
name of the fucking actress,
the one who plays Paul
Newman's love interest,
obviously is an absolute,
uh,
fucking knockout.
And I had never heard of her.
So the fact that I never heard
of her, I'm like, ah, fuck, I,
I've looked up enough of those,
those old movies,
like I got this creepy thing that I always
look people up. Like an older person.
Like, all right, that person is definitely
dead. Let's see how long they lived for.
Right.
Or you try to find a cast
where like everybody's dead,
you know, which is a very
difficult thing to, to, so anyways,
so I started looking up, you know, the
people that were, you know, this woman,
I hope I say her name right, it's
p, I. E. R is it Pierre? Pete Pier,
I dunno. And Jelly. I have no idea.
I looked her up and I was
immediately going like,
she probably died a pills
cause back then like, I dunno,
like getting given people pills.
Like it seems back then every guy either
died of a heart attack in his fifties
and sixties or he died of cancer
and like 90% of the women died of an
accidental, like barbiturate overdose.
Because back then, like, you know,
if a woman came in and she had
some emotional issues, you know,
the doctors are like,
for God's sakes,
get all the ESL and they would just
give her some pills to relax her.
It was like in that movie airplane where
they will just slap on you and giving
you a backhand and shit. So, um,
she was as gorgeous, amazing actress.
And then of course I looked it up and um,
you know, she died accidentally.
Um, some people say suicide,
some people say accidentally
at 39 years of age.
And then I look it up and sure enough,
the place where she fucking
overdosed is still there.
That's another one of those things.
It's a really fucking, you know,
and see the cool
or creepy, all these fucking
houses that people died in.
There's another actor in there.
This guy's Sal Mineo or whatever.
Um, I swear to God, who's a
dead ringer for Ralph Machio.
He's in it. And uh, he ended up,
he got fucking stabbed to death in like
the mid Seventies. It's fucking unreal,
man. Like a lot of people, a lot of stars
back in the day they dated and make it,
they didn't fucking write it out.
It seemed like just crazy
shit app and tool and die.
Guess what I'm saying is that a lot of
these houses still exist and if you're
sort of, um, I guess I'm becoming
morbid in my older age is I realize,
you know, you know what I
mean? Your, your mortality,
you start looking how long this parts to
live, how do they live? How did they die?
Fuck. Is that going to happen to me?
Get all that type of ship. I Dunno.
All right, let's, let's read it.
Let's read a little fucking
advertising here for the week. Oh, Jj,
what'd you look at?
Their MVMT watches movement
watches this company,
Ladies and gentlemen, was started
by two college dropouts, uh,
with the idea to make quality watches
that don't break the god Damn Bank.
They started just 95 bucks.
There's sold online.
So they cut out all the
bullshit retail markup, um,
movement watches sent some over
here. And I gotta tell you, man,
you throw it on your wrist.
Nobody has any idea that it's not a
really expensive watch unless they sell
watches or they come over and they touch
it and they realize it's a lot lighter.
Um, quality materials and sleek designs
to perfect every day. Watch it's easy.
Order online today for free shipping,
free returns and a 24 month warranty.
Um,
join the movement and say no to big
brand retail markups and say yes to great
styles.
Checkout MVMT,
watches.com/ [inaudible] and you'll
get 50% off your entire purchase.
That's MVMT watches.com/burr.
Um,
all right, the next one, dollar
shave club. Everybody, you know,
lots of players will be sporting playoff
beard. Now that the post seasons here,
they got update this, um, we
vet to the pros kickoff the uh,
your year, right kickoff your year the
right way. Sorry with the fresh shit,
a blade shave.
That's why me and millions of others
have joined the dollar Shave Club have
joined dollar shave club.com. You don't
realize about me reading out loud.
My fucking mouth is like I've sentence
and a half with my fucking eyes are slow
it down.
Bill Dollar Shave Club knows the key
to getting an amazing shave is simple.
One,
use a fresh dollar shave called blade
to use their Dr Covey's easy shea
bye.
That's it.
Dot.
Dollar Shave Club delivers amazing razors
right to my door for a third of the
price of those greedy
mega razor corporations.
That means listeners who switched now
can afford the luxury of shaving with a
fresh blade anytime and save hundreds
this year and when you combine the fresh
blade with their doctor cabbies,
easy shave butter.
It just glides.
It's unimaginably smooth and telling you.
If you're not, it's not your average
shave foam. It won't dry out your skin.
The all natural ingredients.
Leave your skin feeling soft,
smooth and moisturized after
every shaved shapes. Sorry,
take it from me. I'll take it
from somebody else or whatever.
Don't take it.
Do whatever the fuck you want to do.
Use a fresh dollar shave club blade
with donkey caddies. Easy shape bladder.
If you wanted the most gentle
shave imaginable, dollar
shave club.com/bird today,
that's dollar shave club.com/burr.
Um,
oh by the way, I'm doing my first
solo flight through a bravo airspace.
So if you're still on the map,
if you're still on the Google Earth math,
I love looking at this shit,
right? And you go onto a,
you go on to, um, what do you do when
you click it on the fucking globe?
They're all right.
Now go over to the ocean.
Okay, follow Santa Monica
Boulevard over to the ocean.
All right,
right where it says the 10.
Now go down a little bit and you'll see
something that kind of looks like a tree,
but it's made out of water.
That's Marina del Rey. All right?
Now if you're flying south,
that's where Bravo airspace begins.
Along the coastline.
And when you're there,
you have to be at a 150 feet or
below at or below one 50 and then you
transitioned the bravo airspace.
If you go a little bit further south,
you'll see lax.
All right?
And that's to the south of it is two,
five,
right into five left and to the
north there's two five, right?
Two five left, those two runways. And
those were the big boys are taken off.
So you fly underneath those guys
or ladies and you stay at or below,
um, 150 feet until you get to,
and then you got to zoom in,
uh, the Manhattan Beach Pier and, uh,
which is almost a beam as they say,
the a comedy and magic club
down on her most of beach.
Um, so you want to be, you
want to be right down there,
150 fucking God damn feet.
Um, oh wait a minute.
Wouldn't that be Hermosa?
Yeah. And I'm sorry,
Hermosa Beach Pier is where the comedy
clubs that, but the Manhattan Beach Pier,
that's where you want to be. You guys
from, from there to Marina del Ray,
you got to be at or below 150 feet.
So if you come out here and
you're on the beach as a tourist,
you see these helicopters
flying by really low. Uh,
they're not buzzing the beach looking
at your or whatever they are. Uh,
they are transitioning the bravo airspace.
So I'm going to be doing that.
Um,
I don't know on what day,
but that's my big goal this week with the
helicopter thing there. Um, but anyways,
let's get back to the, uh, skip
back to the podcast here. Um,
where is it? What else did I want to talk
about? Oh, how about those Boston Bruins.
And I know we lost, I know
we lost to a, the Redwings.
I didn't get to see the, uh, the game
yet. I have a taped, I'm a game behind.
I watched, um, I'm actually
gaming two thirds behind.
I watched the first quarter of a,
of us beating the wild and Brad Marshawn
scored again his 12th goal and 12
games.
And I actually looked up the ticker and
I saw that he scored his 13th fucking
goal. And, uh, in 13 games,
the guy's on fire. And, uh,
I saw his goal in the, um,
the Minnesota wild game.
Um, a shorthanded goal, just
a beautiful pass. And, uh,
I don't know. It's fucking awesome.
And he's going to have like guys,
he's on his way. He's gonna have
like 40 goals is fucking year. Um,
and I gotta say just the Bruins and
the Celtics this year. Both of them.
I was just going to be like, this is,
you know, after all the moves they made,
you know,
I just kind of felt that neither one was
going to be that competitive and it was
going to be tough to watch
him this year. And uh, I am,
I think they're both over achieve
and it's been fun to watch him,
although for some reason my fucking
recorder stopped taping the Celtics Games.
I was really getting into it
watching Isaiah Thomas and, um,
Crowder,
a Jae Crowder and uh,
it was the jam band guy and I
finally learned his fucking name.
They're a Kelly Olynyk.
Right.
I was enjoying watching it and our young
coach there who I still don't know his
fucking name cause I always take the
games and they talked to them and I just
fast forward through all of that shit.
And then they just show him,
I think his name's Stan. Steven.
Something with an s Sean. I Dunno.
It looks like a baby man.
The guy's like fucking 15 years younger
than me and he's coaching the Celtics.
He's doing a great job. And evidently we
got a couple of number one draft picks.
We're in a great fucking position.
Um,
I missed the all star weekend stuff.
I saw some of the dunking
stuff and Kevin Hart,
did anybody see Kevin Hardy? I, he
went up against some other NBA guy.
I can tell,
I know watched fucking NBA.
He went up against a
professional basketball player
and a three point contest.
Um, should I give you a spoiler
alert or should I do that?
The clickbait and the results will
surprise you and it gives a fuck.
He actually beat the guy.
And what I loved about it,
besides being a big fan of his stuff
and everything was when he went to start
shooting is three pointers.
They were playing disrespectful music
underneath them. They were playing this,
I'm always in this like,
oh, it's adorable. Or is it,
it's silly that this little man is going
to come out here and try and beat one
of our professional athletes and uh,
okay.
They were right through the first two
racks and then he fucking close strong.
And I think he might have beat them
on the last ball. You got to see it.
I mean it's, uh, it's pretty fucking
impressive. If I remember correctly,
in long time ago, he was telling me that
before he was a comedian, he went to a,
uh,
you know,
he went to a basketball camp that had
our young unknown Colby Bryant and that
type of shit. So, um,
but still math, you know,
it was a long fucking time ago.
Since then,
he's gone all the way to selling out the
eagles football stadium doing standup
comedy. You'd think that his basketball
game would drop off a little bit,
that maybe he'd be a
little rusty at the y.
Forget about being able to beat a fucking
NBA player and a three point contest.
It was pretty, uh, pretty
God. Damn impressive. Um,
so anyways, let me get back.
Jesus Christ.
Why Omi?
Cheyenne Wyoming. So I go there and, um,
okay,
you know, this was the last of
the, the 50 that I had to do.
So of course I'm reading all up on
Wyoming and all that type of stuff.
And I see that Yellowstone
park is right in the north
northwest corner of it.
And I'm like, Oh fuck,
I got to go up there and go do a gig
in the middle of nowhere at some point.
And uh, maybe I'll do a nice run through
Montana, Idaho and all that shit.
The DAKOTAS, um, you know,
I get into all that fucking nerdy
shit, right? So we do the Gig,
we have a great time. It take some
pictures with some people afterwards.
And when I was on stage I was saying,
hey,
where should we go tonight if I want
to go out and have a pot? Right.
Okay.
So of course everybody's yelling out
everything at the same time and I can't
hear anything. So I'm like
one at a time, one at a time.
And then just in the back,
this guy yells out the gray door,
said to go to the green door. And then
the whole crowd just goes, ah, like,
you know, don't go there.
And I was like, I was like,
I don't even need you guys to say that.
The green door just sounds like some
creepy serial killer place. So I go,
I'm not fucking going there.
So then somebody said by,
forget the fuck it was called
the Cadillac lounge or something.
I took a picture of it. So, um,
I,
uh,
I decide, you know, all right,
that's where the fuck we'll go.
We'll go over to this thing. I'm actually
looking at the picture right now on my,
uh,
on my phone here.
Okay,
come on. Come on. Where is
it? Where is it? There it is.
The Cadillac Cadillac ranch. Sorry.
So we go in there, you know, there's a
big American flag lit up on the side.
I'm like, all right, here we go.
Let's fucking go in there and
see what this place is about.
And we went in there and I gotta tell you,
man,
it was the most diverse group of
people I've ever seen in my life.
And I think for the simple fact,
there was no other place to go.
So there was like a group of bikers,
there was,
there was soldiers,
um,
there was like ranchers,
there was a group of lesbians,
and then there was just filler people
that you couldn't really tell what the
fuck they were. They was older, younger,
the whole fucking thing. So we're in,
they're like, wow man, this is fucking,
this is nuts. And then it had a real,
like cowboy can of feel to it.
Yet there was like a fucking Dj play
in like modern music. It was this,
it was fucked.
So we're in there and dean for whatever
fucking reason is just pointing at Shit.
And people go and look at that fucking
guy, look at this shit, look at it.
It's fucking bar. And I'm sitting there
going, Dean, stop pointing. It's shit.
Stop Pointing Shit. You know, Dean's
been sober for like 20 fucking years,
so he's got no excuse. He just
kept but pointed shit. Um,
and then finally, you
know, I had a, you know,
I was talking to a couple of the people
in there talking to this guy that was in
the middle of taking a
two year welding class,
which of course was really interesting
to me. I was talking to about that shit.
I was talking to some other people in,
uh, then at one point somebody said, hey,
you want to a whiskey? So
like, um, my thing now when
I go on the road and I drink,
I have a beer and uh,
in a whiskey or a scotch
and then that's it.
I call it a fucking night and it's
been working out great for me,
you know what I mean?
So I have a nice little taste,
but then I don't get hammered and then
I'm fine the next morning and I can work
out and shit. Right. So, uh,
this guy offers, you know,
it comes over, hey, you know,
I got to buy a drink. I said, well, I'm
just getting a beer. And I said, well,
all right, well, you know, I was
going to get a whiskey too. He goes,
what do you want? He goes, we've
got a local fucking Wyoming whiskey.
I was like, all right, when is
shy? Let's fucking do it. Right?
So he gets me this fucking shot and
he brings it over and it looked,
it was almost like seethrough.
Now I don't know if if they
did whiskey and water or what,
but I fucking took a sip of it
and it had no bite or anything.
I was just looking, I'm like, dude, what
the fuck is this? He goes, he goes, well,
it hasn't been aged at all.
I've got to tell you, dude,
it was the worst whiskey I've ever had
in my apology to the person who bought me
the shot. I couldn't finish
it. I looked, I said, Dina,
go look at this fucking thing.
And he was just like, yeah, dude,
that looks like piss. So, um,
and then at that point I wasn't looking,
but dean was saying that the biker
people were mean mugging everybody and he
goes to, let's get the fuck out of here.
So we get out of there and, uh, oh,
as we were driving over there,
I noticed that there was a drive,
there was a liquor store with a
drive through. So I was like, Oh God,
I gotta get a picture of that. So I
get pulled over, I get a picture of it.
And then I'm just like,
dude, I got to do it.
I got to go to a drive through liquor
store. So I fucking pull up. We actually,
I posted video of this and I just wanted
to get one beer and the guy goes, well,
I can give you like the 24 ounce.
So I got like a Budweiser, um,
I'll repost the video, the, uh,
the, the Monday morning podcast,
Twitter page. So I went up,
I ordered a fucking beer.
And what was really cool is that had the
old fucking remember the old air hoses
when you would pull up at
the, the, uh, the gas station
and it would ring the bell,
like, Dang, Dang, as your, as your car
pulled in. It was so fucking cool. And,
um,
we was sitting there and then this dude
just sort of walked into the place or
whatever. And as we drive out,
there's an Arby's across the street,
which I never fucking eat, you
know, fucking fast food roasts,
roast beef. I mean, I like to
think I'm a courageous person,
but that's just a little, that's, that
gets a little too shady for me. Right.
I'd rather eat the pink
slime. Um, so anyways, uh,
del Ray's going like came in and it
goes, let's hit the Arby's. I'm hungry.
So I go, all right, so we
go into the Arby's, right?
He owed us some shit and then I
ordered like some chicken sliders,
which I shouldn't have fucking got.
They were fucking disgusting.
It was like eating the, he'll have some
chicks fucking boot boot, you know,
just the way they were shaped like
clogs, they would just fucking gross. So,
um, we go around to the drive through
and this is right across from the drive
through liquor store.
And I look across the street and I
read the sign and what does it say?
It says the green door.
So the drive through liquor store is part
of this shady fucking teddy bar called
the green door.
That urban legend said that there was a
one legged stripper and now the younger
me would have been like,
I got to go in and go see that shit.
The older me goes like, oh my
God, that's somebody's daughter.
So I'm so technically I kind of
did go to the green door. I didn't,
I didn't go in there. I just fucking
pulled up or whatever. So I'll, I'll,
I'll post some pictures of that shit. Um,
let me see if I actually took them. So,
and then the next day we got up right.
And we want it to go to some
local place to get a, uh,
to get breakfast.
And we went to this local place and I
don't know if the regular chef was out of
town,
but I ordered eggs over easy
and I cut into them. Dude,
they were so under cooked.
Like it came out clear,
like the white part of the egg
was still clear. Like, you know,
when those people drink like egg
whites, it was like that. And so deans,
eggs were the same way. And a,
I just never sent food back.
So I just started them in
with the fucking Hash. I mean,
they should have just served the eggs
and a glass like fucking rocky Balboa and
I just suck it down.
And I noticed a woman diagonally from me,
she sent her eggs back to, and
then in the end when I went to, uh,
I went to pay, she was just like, how was
it? And then when I said it was great,
I kind of stumbled on when it was
great. It was great. And then she goes,
and then she immediately looked
up, she goes, is everything okay?
Is Everything okay?
So I've just guessing that the,
the normal chef was out of town, so I'm
not going to out this place is being a,
uh, as being something bad. But, uh,
it was pretty rough. It was one of the
worst breakfast as I've ever had. But, uh,
when we, when we came back
down, we'd drive down to Denver.
I lived for like a little kid right now.
Like,
I'm just telling you every moment
of this fucking, this tour,
but a dean's a big motorcycle guy.
It's been Ryan for 30 years.
So they had this huge fucking Harley
Davidson dealership right on the 25 as we
would come down.
So we stopped in and I didn't know,
but Harley has a new bike that's
just right out of my childhood.
It's called the 72.
And it's got the big spoked front wheel.
It's got the handle bars, it's like
fucking Arthur Fonzie rallies bike,
which obviously was fucking, uh, from
the, the, you know, the 50s or whatever.
But um, I haven't written in
like a year and a half and,
uh, I dunno man. I think
I got to ride that bike.
I think I'm going to rent it just one day.
There's a park up around where I'm at.
I've co Brent it on like a Sunday and
just go up there in the morning time and
just fucking ride around
and bring it back on.
Too much of a pussy to ride all
the time because uh, you know,
I got too much to fucking lose and um,
oh my God,
they had one in,
in this black and gold
metal flake was fucking,
it's just perfect man.
As much as I love the road king,
like every one to be motorcycle rider
who watched a couple episodes of, uh,
whatever that fucking show was,
what was that fucking show there that
everybody watched about? About the bikes?
Um,
you know,
like every fucking want to be bad ass
who doesn't have a tattoo and it's not a
motorcycle guy.
Like Delray took a picture of me on
the fucking 70 to 72 and I just started
laughing. I was like, how much, how
much am I not a motorcycle guy? Like,
do you realize if what a fucking nerd
you have to look like to sit on a Harley
and still look like a fucking still
look like somebody you could pulley?
I look like every fucking just
white dude having a midlife crisis.
They're like, you know who watched
it? What is that fucking show?
What is the fucking show that was all
about the motorcycles that everybody
watched. I never got
into it. Um, goddammit,
it's the perfect reference for
this shit. But um, anyways,
I might have to rent one coming up, uh,
my go ride a dirt bike and get my fucking,
my skills back up to the ridiculously
low level that they were.
I just go to a local park out here and
I just drive this loop around and around
and around.
It's actually good because a,
there's a lot of downshift and
then that shit a lot of turns.
You got to look your way through all
this shit that I learned in the safety
course and everything.
But like I told you guys,
so one time when I rode a motorcycle
down sunset all the way out to the beach,
just like, I want it to just thinking
this is going to feel, you know,
freedom man America. Right. And I
was going to see all this shit, dude,
I didn't see shit.
I was fucking terrified.
There was just too many fucking
people. And um, you know,
we went later than I wanted to go. I
rode with Dean and dean. Yeah. You know,
I had done spots so he
didn't get up til like 10,
so we didn't get on the road till like 11.
And I want it to go at like seven in the
fucking morning when there was nobody
on the road and really just be able to
relax a little bit and not have somebody
right behind me.
Uh,
and I just remember getting off the bike
and I was like shaking and I was just
like, I had to have that fucking get
out of your ego moment and just be like,
Bill, this isn't you. You
don't have this in your blood.
You're not a motorcycle fucking guy.
He just not, so don't be that shithead.
And, uh, I immediately sold the bike
or get rid of it, whatever the fuck.
I don't even remember. But, um, I dunno.
I think every once in a while, if,
you know,
I smoke a couple cigars a month,
I got that under control for every once
in a while I run a motorcycle and I know
everybody's going to fucking
be like, Oh, who jokes reward,
you're a Jewish cause you're going
to be focusing rusty. I right.
Taking all the fun out of
everything. Um, all right.
Oh also, uh, this week, uh,
I got back into like drinking juices and
shit and there was this fucking algae
shit,
which was disgusting when I drank it.
But I felt amazing afterwards
and I'm trying to, uh,
you know, like Dean said, you know,
it's a good addiction to have.
Like you get addicted to shit.
I realized that.
And if you're addicted to
like working out good stuff,
that's obviously a much
better thing for you.
So I might try to get back into
that type of stuff. But anyways, um,
this, uh, this past weekend, on
Saturday night when I got back,
I went to a,
uh,
this music music cares event. And, um,
every year they honor somebody and whoever
they're honoring, everybody comes out.
And I'm just does this person's
music. So say they wandering, ACDC,
a bunch of famous fucking musicians that
are into ACDC would come out and do all
their songs and switch them up
and do different versions of them.
So it was Lionel Richie,
right? Oh, word. A feeling,
right.
So I go to this fucking thing and uh,
it was unreal.
It was like Lenny Kravis usher,
who I couldn't believe how small
he was. He fucking crushed it. Um,
John Legend, Stevie wonder. All right,
all these monsters.
And then Stevie wonder,
and I knew Dave Grohl was
going to go on and I'm like,
kind of fuck is Dave Grohl gonna follow
it? Is he going to play drums and saying,
is he going to do the,
come out with his blue guitar and sing?
And he just went up and just sang a song.
That was it.
He told his fucking story about,
you know,
when he broke his leg or very fell
off the stage where he broke his leg.
He was talking about all the
outpouring from the fans and all that.
And then one day he just got this
giant fucking basket of muffins,
the biggest basket, I guess
ever. This fucking giant thing.
And there was no note or anything on,
and he's,
he's telling this story that the
band sorta just playing, you know,
some music underneath it and he's telling
this story. He's got people laughing,
but they're listening and all that shit.
And then like two days later,
I guess he got a, he got a, a,
a call from his manager
who said, yeah, uh,
Lionel Richie,
Lionel Richie just called up to see
if you got the fucking giant basket of
muffins. And then he just
goes, uh, so I just, you know,
I forget how we fucking ended the story.
I'm butchering it now,
right as the ends the store and you
realize that it was Lionel Richie,
they kick into that his song.
You are Dave Grohl just crushed it in the,
let's argue are there's
something in you are the rain.
And he just was up there singing it.
Fucking crushed.
It went on after Stevie
wonder and crushed it.
Um, so I, I got to, I got to do that.
You know, it was funny. It was, uh,
I, I went down there and, um,
you know, I'm not a suit guy,
but you had to wear like a shirt and tie
dude. And I swear to God, like, I dunno,
just like me when I was on the motorcycle
when I had on that suit and tie, dude,
I don't know what it was. Sometimes
I look all right, but, uh,
the thing about suits is if you,
if you, you got to buy them,
like they go on a style really quick, and
this one was like three, four years old.
I just gotten a dry clean to some
show the last time I wore it.
And I put this fucking thing on. And,
uh, I was talking to Neil, I was like,
and I just kept going. I look
like an asshole right there.
And like, she's like, no,
you look fine again. Yeah, I don't
think so. I looked like an asshole.
So the whole fucking night, um, you know,
anytime I would walk into the bathroom,
you know, it was a long fucking night,
was like a four hour fucking
thing, you know? And, uh,
anytime I would go in there and I would
wash my hands and I would just sit there
and I would look at myself in the mirror.
I just kept laughing.
What a fucking jerk off I look like a,
I know it wasn't a good scene, you know,
I don't like hate myself.
It's not good place for me to be
like say I think it's time
to retire that suit. Um,
all right, let's get into some of the, uh,
some of the fucking questions
here for the week. Um, uh,
here we go.
A judge Scalia,
bill listener from Virginia here,
the death of Judge Scalia brought out
some jokes on social media and a lot of
people took the angle that they
were happy that he died. Now I'm a,
I'm assuming this is somebody
on the supreme court because
I don't pay attention
to shit,
but I did see some stuff about this is
the first time the supreme court won't be
conservative.
He goes,
what's your position on making
jokes about being happy people died.
Thanks for, for, for that.
Laughs and give me thank you.
Thanks for the laughs. Um,
my position on making joke about,
well yeah,
I think he got a be,
uh,
I think you gotta be like a dictator
for people to do shit like that. Yeah.
I mean, I wouldn't say don't do
it because there's always a joke.
I mean, someday when I die, there's
going to be a joke. I mean, I know,
and if I'm hovering around is a ghost,
I'm going to laugh about it.
What the fuck do I care? I'm a ghost at
that point, right. I didn't go to hell.
All right. I'm floating around. I
could deal with this. Uh, but yeah,
I don't do that. Um, well look,
if you just make a joke joke,
that's fine,
but if you're doing it because you didn't
share like their political views, uh,
yeah,
I'm not into
doing that type of shit. Like,
you know, some, some Shithead,
I'm going to start doing this.
Like the shit had tweeted the week.
Somebody sent me a text today telling me
that I needed to distance myself. Bill,
just to let you know, you need to
distance yourself from so and so.
Um,
and then sent me a link and this is
somebody that had been friends with for 20
fucking years.
And then I see this link and it has to
do with being a vegetarian or eating meat
and the name of the video is
so and so is an ignorant moron,
which right there I love,
like that's your angle,
like to get someone to listen
to your opinion right there.
I just look at it like this is just,
this is just somebody trying
to make a name for themselves,
trashing somebody that, that has
made a name for themselves, you know,
with some over the top title.
First of all,
I love is an ignorant moron.
Like that's like redundant,
you know, he's a stupid, not smart person.
I'm like,
I need to distance myself from some,
from someone who's been a great friend
for 20 years because of their dietary
decisions,
you know,
because they talk about food and nutrition
in a way that's a truth that they
believe in all of us, you know,
like, and then, and, and what,
you're a fucking genius, you know,
and it's just, you know, I dunno.
I Dunno why people do shit like that.
So that kind of ties into you and
I would never, obviously, you know,
that's, I don't know, I would
never tweet it. Somebody like that.
You need to distance yourself from this
person because I don't agree with their
workout regimen. And the same
thing with like, that, like,
I wouldn't be happy that somebody died
because I didn't like their political
views. You know what I mean?
I always have that in my head.
They add somebody's dad, somebody's
husband or some shit, you know, whatever.
He was a gay judge. That's somebody's
boyfriend right out of fucking know.
I, yeah. I don't do shit like that,
but if somebody does, you know,
I'm not the comedy fucking police.
Um, all right. Summer home bill.
My wife wants to own a home by a lake in
New Hampshire. That's fucking awesome.
I'm trying to convince her that it's
cheaper to just rent a sick house every
summer for a couple of weeks.
Instead of paying 15 grand a year
in taxes on top of the mortgage,
help me sort out business. Please go fuck
yourself. Well, what I would say is a,
you know, you can rent out your
house, your summerhouse, you know,
this is what I would do. Okay. I would,
I would buy that house on the lake and
then I would just rent the whole fucking,
yeah.
And then whenever I wanted to go,
I would rent some other place.
You know what I mean?
And this is how I'm weird
because I wouldn't want to
go into a place that I own
no one that everybody fucked in my bed.
I would rather go to a place knowing
that a bunch of people fucked it,
somebody else's bed.
It makes no sense. What you should do
is buy it and then rent it out. I mean,
buying property is always great. However,
if you're having a rough time, like I,
I'm a big believer in no
paying down your first house,
mmm.
You should really pay that thing down and
get it under control before you go and
get a summer house.
And I do know that in relationships,
when it comes to money,
there's usually one person understands
it and the other person doesn't
understand it and they want everything
yesterday and you might be a little more
conservative, which is what
you sound like. So, um,
okay.
I, you know, I would just sit down
and just say, look, first of all,
you're in a great position because it
doesn't sound like she can just go out and
pull the trigger itself. So I just say,
listen, I definitely want to do that,
but we need to, we need to pay down
this house a little bit or, you know,
if we can't afford it,
let's buy it and then we'll rent the
thing out all the weekends that we're not
going to be there. Um, I
think that's definitely,
it's definitely a smart way to do
it. But, uh, I would just sit down,
okay.
And write out all the points that you
want to make and then draw a smiley face.
This is what I do when I'm being a smart
person because I know how short a fuse
I have. And, uh, I
write all this shit out,
everything that I want to
say and all that stuff.
And then I draw a smiley face
reminding me to not lose my temper,
reminding me that other
people are entitled to have
different opinions and uh,
you know,
and not to be a cunt.
I didn't do that a couple of days ago
and ended up having a big stupid fight
over the, the bathroom sink. You
know, I'd gone on the road in a ditch,
start,
started to clog up and I didn't
have time to fucking fix it,
but you know, we had drain
up. So I figured, you know,
my wife would fucking handle it and I
come home to brush my teeth and I turn it
on and within fucking two seconds,
it's already filling up as a puddle.
It's completely backed up
and you know,
it's usual shit, usual shit in a
relationship. You say to somebody,
did you know her? No, I didn't
notice. And in your head you like,
how the fuck did you not notice the shit?
But what I learned in that argument is
I have to understand that this shit that
she's looking at me yet
looking at me at about like,
how the fuck do you not notice it?
And it's just cause I'm just not wired
like that. And that's why you get married.
Hopefully you're a yin and a Yang.
I finally set him right.
I didn't say ying and Yang. I said, yen,
Y I n I think that's the first time
publicly I've ever said it right. Um,
yeah, they're going to be good at this
shit that you're not good at. And um,
actually had a great
day with Nia yesterday.
Like I didn't do shit for once
and we just hung out all day.
And um, you know, we watched
some movies and shit.
You made a little bit of food.
And I always forget that,
that every once in a while you guys,
you got to hang out with each other
rather than just being roommates to remind
yourself like, oh yeah, that's right.
We actually really love each other.
I forgot about that shit and I don't
know the amount of times I've had to
fucking learn that, you
know, she getting married,
you really start doing the math like dude,
fuck too shit. I don't need anything.
I will literally give her everything.
I will fucking just give you fucking
everything and I will walk out with the
shirt on my fucking back and
I will start all over again.
Like I think that that's the way to
fucking do it and just walked down the
street after it like
Johnny fucking Appleseed.
Um,
cause I really think you just get
into having all of this fucking stuff,
but if you just let go of all of it,
then you don't have it.
I think getting divorced could
be a really light feeling.
This is how far I went over an argument
over a clogged up sink before it came to
my senses.
I was walking down the street with the,
with the stick with the Bandana and a
peanut butter and jelly sandwich in it.
And I was just fine.
What am I doing? You know,
stop being a fucking idiot.
All right, let's get to some advertising
here. All right, me undies, everybody.
Oh Gee, I got to sing this quietly because
we have company over here right now.
Poop. Poop. Poop me and eat me undies.
No more sweaty nuts. Boo.
Doo Doo, Doo me undies.
BMDS keep it dry with your butts.
Wasn't that doesn't make sense.
And they said not sounds thinking bus
would rhyme. I, you know what I, I've,
I've got to retire this fucking
song and he's a new fucking,
I need some new bits on this goddamn
thing. All right, me undies. All right.
This year don't be predictable and show
up at your Valentine's Day dinner with
some last minute box of chocolate or
bouquet of roses. Bouquet bouquet.
I don't want to say it are going to die
in a week anyways. Uh, give the gift.
Everyone's talking about me.
Yon Ds me on days taking
care of your taint.
Bhutto dude do me, me, Andy's your balls.
We'll say you're a saint.
Uh, show your special day.
That fucking guy up here either fall.
Can you shake ski?
What is dry over here?
Show you a special someone.
Just how much you care with the present.
You're both love a gift that
looks great and feels great.
Something that says you deserve the
best. I have to tell you right now, you,
if you give somebody underwear for a gift,
you better be fucking them.
Are they better be your kid? Cause
other than that, it's fucking weird. Uh,
you know, give you kid under where
you know you're, there you go.
Jesus Christ straighten up and fly,
right?
No,
I have a little respect for yourself.
You know, and then if you, you know,
you're with the person intimately,
you can give it to them, you know,
there's no fucking way actually as a joke,
you can do that,
you know?
Do you know what was actually thinking
the other day when I went to buy my wife
a Valentine's Day card?
You know,
I was looking for the blank ones cause I
hate the fucking Valentine's Day cards.
You know,
they're either over the top gross or
they're just fucking like too distant,
you know,
it's very hard to find that one.
That's the nice balance of I
love you but let's not be gross.
So I was looking for the blank ones and
I came to the sympathy cards and uh,
I just was thinking like,
you know what,
I really want to stand up with Joe de
Rosa again and then sent him a sympathy
card afterwards,
you know,
telling him I hope he feels better and
everything and just basically, right. Joe,
I saw your set last night.
I know you're going through a rough time.
Um, I dunno, it was funny to me. Anyways,
let's get back to me and he's saying
treat yourself and your boo two a matching
pair of me. Meundies, the world's
most comfortable underwear. Um,
this company,
I'm this underwear is comfrey is,
it gets me undies are made of micro modal,
modal fabric,
meaning they're twice as soft as
cotton and they don't just feel great.
They look great to me.
Undies comes and tons of cool prints and
styles and new designs come out every
month.
You won't want to miss.
Miss February is limited edition
designs from the legendary Keith Herring
herring.
This retro design is inspired
by love making it the
perfect Valentine's Day gift.
Well, it's over. Uh,
grab yourself a pair and celebrate the
holiday sporting matching underwear with
your sweetheart.
How do you do it?
You go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr
now to get 20% off your first order.
Um, that's 20% off at [inaudible]
dot com slash burr. All right,
stamps.com sometimes it feels
like there aren't enough.
Sometimes it feels like there's not
enough hours in the day. You know what?
You're just flustered even when
you're working past the nine to five.
So if you're still making time
consuming trips to the post office,
she need a better way.
You stamps.com with stamps.com you can
get the postage you need the instance you
need it.
Buy and print official US postage for
any letter or package right from your
computer. When printer, you'll
save money with stamps.com too.
It's just a fraction of the cost of
one of those expensive postage meters.
Plus you'll get super
special postage discounts.
She can't even get at the post office.
I use stamps.com to send out all my
posters. I'm a if I can figure out
how to do it.
So can you right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name [inaudible] for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes a occludes postage and a
digital scale. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburgerburthatstamps.com
and
to burn as always, if you want to
contribute to this podcast. Um,
next time you're going to buy something
on amazon.com just go to my, uh,
my website,
[inaudible] dot com click on the podcast
page and there's a link to Amazon.
All it does is take you to Amazon.
It doesn't cost you any more money.
I just get credit for driving traffic
to the site. All right, trash man.
Everybody a Billy bubbles.
Billy bubbles in the rain.
Um, I went to high school with
the guy who picks up my trash.
I get along with them and I always
wave and sometimes if he's not rushing,
I'll have a short conversation with them.
Last week I saw my neighbor yell at him.
He wasn't a,
he wasn't a jerk back,
but he wasn't a dick either.
What? He wasn't a jerk back, but he
wasn't a dick either. Later on that day,
my neighbor came over and asked me if
I'd make a statement about the issue that
he harassed her. I saw the whole
thing go down. He didn't harass her.
She yelled at him for coming a day late
during a week when a holiday pushed
everything back a day in terms of
sanitation, pickup a what? A cunt.
She said that even without my statement,
she's going to press charges
and file a complaint.
I'm going to call the town or police
and let them know what's going on.
I'm so livid that she would ruin
this guy's life. He's a great dude.
Thoughts on how we should handle this?
Should I report her for lying apps?
A fuckin lutely and I would take time
off from work to testify that she's Elian
whore apps.
A fuckin lutely.
Who the fuck yells in a trash man?
The service that they're providing.
Fuck her. Fuck her. Do you know something?
I would 100% do it and I would,
I would even fucking tell her that
you're going to do it at some point.
Not Not in the beginning because
you don't want to weaken his case.
But I would do it without a doubt. And
when the whole fucking thing goes away,
I would let her know that you did that
and I would let her know what a small
person you think she is and that she's
disgusting and to stay away from you and
anybody else that you love
because she subhuman there.
I was at the limit dilemma. Dear Bill. Oh,
what a fucking whore.
He came in day late and then you
harassed me to, you know what?
You know what she I, you know
what? I bet she does for a living.
She sounds like a blogger.
Always playing the fucking victim and
always going down and just trying to get
somebody in trouble and try and fuck
over there. Their ability, you know,
to earn a living. What a
fucking Twat. All right. Derek,
would you rather have to live
in an air balloon for a month?
Never you having set down or would you
rather live in a submarine? Never
breathing the surface for a whole month.
Both scare the shit out
of me for a whole month,
but I think I choose the submarine
seems more natural. Yeah.
And there's also a bathroom.
I wouldn't want to have to
shit on people and p why,
but obviously wait till I
was over a a rural area.
Yeah. Plus you'd be inside,
you'd have a bed. If you,
when you were in the submarine,
you have a blanket, you know,
you get to be down there
with all the fellows. Hey.
Um, no man. I mean,
I think it would be cool to fucking look
out the window and see all the fucking,
uh,
the sea life and all that shit.
I would go fucking nuts down
there. But, um, I don't know.
Fucking up there in an air
balloon gets cold or hot.
You're really dealing with the fucking
elements when you're up there and starts
fucking raining.
Uh,
yeah, I dunno. I W I would be a, I
would get over that really quickly,
but I think being in a sub,
you know, you're down there,
you get flake cards so you could fucking
break each other's balls or whatever.
I don't know. Yeah, I definitely would
take, I would much rather do with sub. Um,
and if I had to die either way,
I'd rather die in a sub.
I'd rather have it just fucking, you
know, if you're going to die in the cell,
it's going to be quick. You
know, it's just, it's just over,
right. I don't know. Yeah. I don't know.
Sometimes maybe it might not be
quick. They close that door. Yeah.
Those are two terrifying. Thanks. I got to
go with you. Got To go with you on that.
Um,
okay.
Alright. Dilemma Billy boy. Uh,
if you had to choose which holiday to
get canceled and never celebrate again,
would you choose Valentine's
Day or President's Day?
Who deserves more recognition,
your girl for doing what you
do all year without a holiday.
That's hilarious. Yeah. We don't get a
holiday. Um, no. Maybe I read that wrong.
Or presidents who may or may not be
horrible people who hurt the country.
I canceled president's Day because
I'd rather keep the one that involved
chocolate being around. Oh,
that's a good reason for it. Um,
if I had to get rid of one,
I don't think anybody really
celebrates president's Day.
I don't really consider it a day off.
It's kind of like flag day,
you know what I mean?
Or a buttermilk pancakes day.
Isn't there one of those
fucking days to, um, cheeses?
Do you want me to cancel a holiday?
Uh, I would cancel Valentine's Day
just because women like it so much.
Believe it or not, I am a concert,
but I'm not that fucking bad.
So I'd keep that one. Yeah. You
know what? Fuck Presidents' Day.
All those guys are
bought and sold any ways.
You've seen it with Hillary
Clinton and Bernie Sanders.
You've seen how the Democrats had just
going to pick her because going to play
ball,
they're all tied into the fucking,
the fucking,
I don't know what you want to call it.
Did she?
She that Bernie Sanders
is too fucking radical.
He's going to switch shit up too much
and then they're not going to work with
them. Even if Bernie Sanders
gets fucking elected,
they're not going to work with them.
They're gonna show their fucking true
colors. There are a bunch of that.
Just a bunch of, they're all bought
and paid for it. They don't. Well,
how the fuck do the Clinton's got $3
million to throw their kid a wedding?
You know what I mean? We have
fucking break. Cause you went out,
you gave speeches to all
the people that fucking
financed your campaign and then you hook
them up and look the other fucking way.
I swear to God,
I swear to God.
Do you want to have the
fucking pharmaceutical
companies and the people who
fucked up the food supplier
able to do it and there's not,
there's nothing behind it is cause
they fucking paid everybody off.
I swear to God. All right, I'm
on my stomach on my eye is,
this is why I always vote for that
third party guy. And everybody goes, Oh,
you throwing away your fucking vote.
How is thrown away my fucking vote?
Vote for somebody as a decent fucking
human being. I swear to God, people, they,
they, they don't want to try to do
what's right. They just want to win.
They want to be like, go buy one again.
See that every time I sit there and I
trashed people for fucking given the
public opinion, then look, I meet
the gumby. I do the exact same thing.
I am what's known as a hypocrite.
The HIPAA can't. Alright,
that's the a, the podcast
for this week. Um,
I want to thank everybody that
came out, Cheyenne, Wyoming, a,
I know it was last second, but uh, I had
a great time. At a great time in your, uh,
your, your state capital.
Uh, Joe was just a really,
really cool fucking town and I had a
great time in the Cadillac ranch there.
That sounds, I swear to God,
like the fucking bunny ranch.
It sounds like a fucking whore
house, but it wasn't, um,
it was cool talking to the people
there and thank you to everybody.
You know the bought me a beer and a shot
and all that shit. Thank you everybody.
Denver by the way,
which was just a fucking insane show.
Um,
that was another thing,
special one.
Just cause I'd done so many fucking gigs
in Colorado in the middle of nowhere.
I always bring up Arapahoe community
college. I'll never forget that.
Nooner where they had me standing in
an area where three hallways met right
before class ended.
That was a fucking nightmare.
Next to a popcorn machine and five
people scattered out about 40 chairs,
empty chairs.
Anyways,
that's a podcast for this week.
Uh,
I'm going to try to watch some Celtics
and get caught up on the Bruins games, um,
and keep drinking my juice.
All right. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll talk to you later on this week.