Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
March 31st,
2014 and a I know you're a bitch and
you're saying this is late. You're right.
It is late.
I'll give it to you this week.
It is late but that's only because I'm
doing a very special episode of on the
Monday morning podcast.
Uh,
I alluded in past episodes that uh,
about this tour that was coming together
with the guys that I go out on the road
with, Paul Versey, Jason
Lawhead and Joe Barton,
nick that possibly the three of them
were going to come together like one of
those superhero movies and
do their own fucking tour.
And they are they all in tour and it
starts tonight and I'm at Lago in a seven
30 tonight and a right now a Joe
Barden. Nick isn't here yet, but uh,
Paul Dude,
I called it Versie is here and uh,
Jason Law had a bullet here so I want to
welcome both of you to the podcast. Oh,
thanks man. Thanks for having us here
at your lovely studio. No, thank you.
This is all things comics studios.
It's late today. What is the podcast?
I noticed though, you take
a wow, what of what it was.
It was a matter of being
knighted. I sounded weird
there for a second. I saw it,
but they can't hear.
Okay.
You take a lot of flack for that shit
for like if you're like an a couple hours
late,
I noticed like you'll post your day.
We'll, we'll, we'll go Billy
red fucking Dick. Yeah, so I,
I can't believe I'm going
to have the afternoon. It's Chang
guys internet. It's what people do.
Everybody's in the bushes so they
could say whatever the fuck they want.
Every just, I don't read
Twitter. That's hilarious.
I don't think they're really genuinely
mad. I think they just want to like,
you know, they want to get their
little, like I said this today,
are they not doing that?
They like that
general then not big on heckling
during the show, but afterwards,
if you're standing out there, whoring
yourself out, that's when they,
they'll come by and the
be like, oh, you're not as tall as I
thought you were going to be like that.
And I always, I always, yeah,
just give him, should I go? You know,
you had 90 minutes to say that
when I'm [inaudible] pussy,
it's always good when there's a woman
standing there too and then they go home.
They probably take it out on
her hate fucker or something.
I like to feel that I had,
I had something to do with that,
but that's not why we're here today.
We're here to promote, uh, your
guys, your guys tour and uh, do,
do you have any of the dates here that
I could actually start reading? Okay.
This is what we got tonight.
Tonight. It's already sold out. Um,
we're going to go ahead and answer it.
We'll still waiting for Bart. Nick.
Pardon Nixon. Answer it. Um, all right.
By the way, if you hear weird noises out
of Jason Law head, he fucked his back.
Yeah. There you go. All
right, so here we go.
The all things comedy tours starring
Paul Versey. Jason Law hadn't Joe Barton.
Nick is, uh, tonight. It's
at the Largo in Los Angeles,
which is already sold and Tuesday,
April 1st tomorrow night if you
down in comedy starved San Diego,
a lot of comics never go down there.
They're going to be at the Mad
House Comedy Club tomorrow, Tuesday,
April 1st Sunday, April six. They're
going to be a parlor live in Bellevue,
Washington.
Monday,
April 7th there at helium comedy
club in Portland, Oregon. Tuesday,
April 8th San Francisco. They're going
to be at the punchline. Wednesday,
April 9th, they're going to be
at the punchline. And Thursday,
April 10th the punchline. So eighth,
ninth and 10th. 10th is in Sacramento.
Sacramento, sorry, eighth and ninth in
San Francisco and a 10th and Sacramento.
You go, there you go. And I'm excited
because I've never been to Sacramento.
I've never been anywhere.
Oh Jesus.
What are we doing here?
I've never been anywhere in California
other than Long Beach in La.
So I'm looking forward
to San Diego tomorrow.
See this is one for me because you're,
you're in California.
I've been out to see you in New York
at least a handful of times since we've
been friends. But you've never been
to California, you know in all verse.
He does his shit on California
as he got hammered when we were in this
cigar bar in Calgary and I was shitting
on the Yankees are shitting on golf.
I think he was shitting on golf,
golf. And then I, cause I was
saying about playing it or the,
or follow me like where I keep, where
I put it as far as sports competition.
Gotcha. And I put it in with
bowling pool shuffleboard where,
where it's one of those things.
So he gets mad at me and he starts going,
he starts going like, you know what
bill? He goes, I wish. He goes, he goes,
Brito suck. Comes me with
the cuisine. He goes,
all it is is beans and rice. And
I go, Yeah Paul, it's all it is.
No one ever thought to put anything
else in there. I got by. But you know,
you even said I got drunk. He said
it hit me like a, like a smoke bomb.
Like I that time you've started slumping,
but at the time he got hammered and
you were just like, you were a mess.
Like let me get my calendar. But can you
take, do you think that's bad though?
I saw you shaking your head that
that's where I put I put golf. I'm not,
not anywhere near bowling or
shuffleboard. The no, no, no.
I'm not saying that because there's all
different degrees of, of, of difficulty.
But I'm just saying as far
as you're playing a sport
where it's all between your
ears, between your ears. There's
nobody physically trying to stop you.
In other nations it's fall times.
I'll give me five.
I'm just saying when Wa, I mean
there's a lot of forest, well no,
I think
places and shucking,
but playing against of
what leaves us in the way.
I'm not saying that it's still wouldn't
hold that. Oh, a guy hits a home run.
Like know what I know. But when face ball
players talk about how difficult it is,
they talk about trying to hit a curve
ball. They don't talk about the wind.
I'll forget my hitting the golf ball
is in your, I forget mother nature.
There may in cancer they no walking.
No, but there's more than that.
It's not even that.
It's how about the fact that you actually
do have to have a proper swing posture,
your hips,
your legs, you're not listen to me
in tech to your body. Listen to me.
I'm not saying it's not difficult.
You Golfing zombies.
What I'm saying is, is it's not
fucking playing football, basketball,
hockey with is somebody
trying to stop you.
There's not a pitcher throwing the fucking
golf ball a hundred miles an hour at
your chin to Bacchae off the,
uh,
the t and then you've got to come up
there and settle back into your fucking
swing. Okay? That's all I'm saying.
I know it's mentally difficult,
but it's in the same family is
pool, bowling, shuffleboard,
horseshoes, all the way down to
some of the most simplistic sports.
There are tiddly winks.
Nobody's stopping you na,
I mean already stopping in Jacks.
You don't need to be in
shape to do shuffleboard.
You don't need to be in shape to bowl.
That's a such a terrible point to bring
up with. Cause I'll, I'll tell him,
I'll fucking show you Duke. First Time
I watched the masters, Kenny Perry,
he looked like somebody's grandfather
fucking came out. He blew it. He blew it.
And then some other fat Argentina
guy won it. They'll go fat.
Oh Cabrera fat guys still,
Ugh. I give up. Give up,
can see the fat guys can play golf. I
get to the sweat bill. Nicholas's man,
tits is so unacceptable.
He should always have. Why?
They should have married her own bag.
Yeah, but they're not piles of shit.
Kenny Perry is not a pile of shit.
Dude. What is he? Donna's? What?
Is he close to? Death
playoff. He is. No, no,
no. But what is he closer to? Is he
closer to an a donnas or a tub of shit?
Oh No. Yeah, he's, he's
definitely closer to a Tbi Shit.
Then another tub of Shit beat him
to fucking dude. Even that cow.
But the general Lee car,
he doesn't look like he did a
fucking pull up in his life.
He had those seventh grade
straight arms where you don't have,
you just have basically the humorous
bone with a little bit of meat hanging on
and you can still pick up a pencil
or a phone. Gene iron the the guy,
the guy who hit that amazing
shot and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, chef on the one.
Right, right. I love that. We're
cores light drinking. Come on.
He's like the guy that's,
he's a Digi jetskis.
He's totally the Kenny powers of May,
but I'm not disrespecting the sport.
I'm not disrespecting the sport,
but I'm just saying the reason why I
find the sport boring as hell to play is
the fact that there's nobody
guarding me and I just get,
I get bored shitless by three,
four fucking holes. I don't care.
The whole thing is silly.
I'm trying to put this little ball
in a hole and the hole is on garden.
There's nobody trying to swat
it away as it goaltending.
It's this fucking hole in the ground that
you should have a good way to look at
it. He designed differently. It's
just a different game. Listen,
there's a reason why it should have been
a Getty shack too. There's a business,
there's a reason why a bunch of fucking
old people when they start putting on
weight, you know, and
they need to get active.
They always pick up that
sport and I'm telling you,
those fat fucks who if
you throw a baseball,
the the odds of them chipping that tooth
can somehow still get on a golf course.
And I'm not saying crush it like a pro,
but they can hit the fucking
thing straight enough.
They're, they're all right.
They're okay. They're okay.
They're good fun to play with.
They can shoot a one oh five I love our
colon millionaire golfers tubs. Yeah,
they're not fun. Not Daily. Used
to be fucking pounding beers.
John Daly was an animal.
I heard his book like he was an animal.
I used to fit. We used to go
to the a Firestone every year.
Some buddies of mine down at the
NAC and Akron and we used to follow,
this is back in their like late nineties
mid to late nineties when daily was on
top of the world. He was in every
tournament because he was, you know,
he was still exempt from all of his wins.
I love that guy too. He was the best.
We would follow him around and he
bombed the ball past everybody.
This is before tiger made a name for
himself on the tour and he was a smoking
Cha Cha Jim Jane Smoke.
You know they don't show it on TV,
but a lot of these guys chain smoke,
it's like they hit the driver,
they liked the cigarette and he literally
changed when the camera goes away from
him and the camera goes away from him. He
there, they don't put the camera on him.
And then a lot of times when you do,
they'll go back and be like,
we'll go to daily at 16 he's got a
cigarette burning in the fairway.
You just don't see it. He takes his hit
and they say, and then they show the ball.
You know, he saw it hit the green and
they show him like give his cloak.
And then once they show like
the trees and the leaderboard,
he's back smoking again. He carries
a, he actually smoked so much.
He's got an old coffee can with a
hook on the side of his bag when his,
when his as an extra.
Yeah.
So cause they don't want them litter and
up those nice courses, that's not cool.
So he is like,
you literally you would follow him and
his caddy had put the bag down and he'd
be waiting to hit is approaching and he'd
be smoking cigarettes as long as they
go and he throws it in the coffee can
or if he still had a cigarette when it's
time to hit, he throw it on the grass and
just let it burn. Wait till pick it up.
It's hilarious.
Well listen,
I know it's difficult because I've
actually talked to a professional athlete
hall of Famer who said those guys
mentally, the strongest athletes,
cause you've got all that time to stand
with a ball. Think and I understand that.
But there's just something about the fact
that there's nobody trying to stop you
but me. It's just the, the activity of it.
I feel like I might as well just sit in
a restaurant with a chopstick trying to
catch a fly. It's just like, why
am I doing this? This is dumb.
I'm not working up a sweat.
Like I just,
I would rather play fucking horse shoes
and they just walked back over to the
grill and just grab a sandwich.
Like I decided to stay on what I'm doing.
Part of it might be because
I'm so pasty and I'm out there.
Do you know how bad I want to go out on
the course that you guys get you smoking
cigars and drinking? Like I'll meet
you at the fucking at the club? Yeah.
The drinking and the smoking on the
course is so fun. Oh, there's no,
I know, but this is the
thing. Maybe that's time.
That's how you have to sell the
sport because it's not like, yeah,
you want to go play hockey and it just
be like, Hey, you smoking stogies ah,
maybe I'll come down and have a,
and it's fun.
We should have an annual,
like we'll call it the cube it open.
We'll just get like a gag for eight guys,
get a couple of forums.
We meet at a golf course every
year and we just absolutely,
we just play like two rounds of golf
over two days and just smoke Cubans
and drink scotch. I got to
tell you this, if, if I,
if I ever became a center and going again,
if I ever, if I ever became president,
one of the first things I would do was,
and I would risk my own assassination
by doing this because I would go against
all the corporate cons
and I would basically,
I would break bread with Castro and
those guys and I would just be like,
all right,
listen,
we will wrong to try and turn your island
into a bunch of Starbucks and casinos
and the end of the day it is your
property. Do what with it what you want.
We'll bring you some cars down here.
Just start sending us to cigars exam
and would just leave it at that.
But that's not what they're
actually waiting for him to die.
And then they're going to
turn that place into a,
it's going to look like Orange County.
It's going to be fucking brutal.
It's terrible. He, you know, I'm not
saying the guy's the greatest leader.
I'm not saying I'm going to be underneath
the guy, but in principle they will.
Right. It was their country.
They had the right to do. Okay,
we're going to take college here.
All of a sudden come see him like a
fucking place getting back to the cigar.
I'm so fucking sick of
having to try and find,
it's kind of the excitement of smoking
a Cuban is trying to find one. Yeah.
You know, and uh, now you know what
everyone was saying, you know? No,
you've said up on the fake.
Yeah. Where you go. They are,
they're already on Twitter
doing it properly. They,
they do that shit. But, um,
what even know, like, you
know, if you order them and
they send them in, you know,
they get a little bit,
a little hard. What was,
I'm just getting tired of people talking
about like how it could get you sick
and how it could give you,
you know, get, you know,
give you a throat cancer and shit.
It's like, listen man, you know,
I'm not smoking these like cigarettes,
like a package.
If I'm going to smoke one or two
cigars a week, that's it. That's it.
I seen you smoke four and two nights
and I don't even live in New
York. I mean, it just happened.
I just happened to be there.
Yeah,
yeah. Well, you know. No, I was like,
fuck. It was, it was, it was a, yeah,
it was of Thursday. It was, wasn't
that was her back pedal at night.
There was a couple of days I went
a little bit does break down to 14
anyway, dude, I love it.
I fucking love them.
So do what now I gotta ask you guys
now when you go to go out on this tour,
being the Scotch drinking cigar smokers
that you are, uh, what, what is the,
what is the over under, on weight
gained on, uh, on this, the all the, uh,
the Olin tour here? Well, my, well, my
plan coming in and I told, I told my wife,
does my plan coming in was to, to
not try to hang with Bart. Nick
like, no, no, no. I'm not
even kidding. Like Bart,
nick is not like we're the bargaining to
be a day behind the tour when we're in
Portland. He's going to be the, in
Seattle when we're in Sacramento,
he's going to have to be in San Francis.
Never seen, I'm not even kidding.
I'm not even joking around.
I'm not just saying this,
you know,
I've never seen a grown man in door
what he can do and still be able to hold
this role back to throw it, like to
hold it together. I mean that dude,
like he was going back to the
bar. He's going, yeah, man.
How about another heater and member. I
had to tell him, I go, hey dude, listen,
I'm not hiding. I was at my wedding,
right? Yeah. At Bill's wedding he goes,
hey dude,
you guys would be a lot at versus you
want another heater and I literally,
you did it. Yeah, I got, I go
guys, I'm not going to lie to,
I can't do it like I need. I need a break
here. The bartenders at the wedding,
we're pulling, we're pulling bartenders
over from other bars to watch.
They were like, watch, watch,
watch, watch what he does.
The Guy Walking up now watch what he
does and like think about your wedding,
which was awesome. Was
there, it was never like,
it was never hard to get
either a be a hard liquor.
It was just always right there and the
guy knew what you wanted so Barney could
go, yeah, you guys want more heaters.
Another round of hears and he would
just start giving them Barton.
It's just drinking his crown and I just
patted him on the back and I was like,
you are at, and he just had that shitty
and green, but he was talking straight on,
but all the way into the bar, he said
for people who don't know him, he's a,
he's a mountain of a man. Like he could
give, he's like Cam Neely size man.
He said, well he's a, yeah, we're all
like, what? Like five, 10 or whatever.
Trying to keep up with a dude
who's like six, four. Yeah,
I mean me and you by the end of the
night we were shot and he was just like,
hey guys, you want one of these for the
road? He was like helping us. He was like,
Jason, when it comes back against, uh,
you know, a fast Eddie in the fuck,
you know what?
I used to sit in there and putting
the carnation back in his jacket.
Let's play some cool pop in.
Yeah. Well, that's how they,
that's funny is because like I think
over those heaters that all that drinking
as well,
how we came kind of came up with this
idea for the door that that was at bill's
wedding in October. We'll see.
We just started joking about it.
Bill's not going to beat a
voice of reason on this one.
He's kind of letting us go. Bill's not
going to be around. Hey guys, let's,
that's a good sign. You're in trouble
when I'm the voice of reason. No,
but you would at times. How much do
you have to talk me into something now?
That's the thing. No, you know what
bill does? This is what he does.
He acts like he's the guy who like to
like to keep it cool. He'd be like, yeah,
really? I should go. Well,
this was so funny. We were in
Canada. He goes, listen man,
I'm not, I'm not trying to get tonight.
I'm not tryna get tonight. I swear to God.
I'm backstage and he's on stage.
He's onstage and I'm thinking,
I'm going back to the old ties
again. No, not tonight. Not Tonight.
He's onstage asking the
crap. You guys know where we
could, let's just say we did.
Let's just say we were to go out and
then after after I get, you know,
take close out the show, he'll be like,
yeah, we'll get one, we'll get one.
So like he acts like he's not going to,
but see Barton has just like,
I mean every tweet,
crowns,
crown like Barton examine like
what he saw when he's all in. Dude,
that was hilarious.
We were in buffalo one time.
He pulled the same thing in buffalo.
It was after a Bruins
playoff when we were in,
but we were in buffalo doing
buffalo wild in June. Right.
And then we were like talking to
the whole time, the place like
I couldn't really drink
tonight. [inaudible] we get
back to the hotel. He's like,
you didn't have Bruins game still on it.
Let's just go down to that little like
bar like yeah, we watch it Bruins William,
we celebrate e right there to the part
that we have one, we'll have one beer,
right. Wait one very of it ruins way and
we're going to celebrate the book part.
Then as the bill goes, hey,
if we weren't going to go out
next door,
next thing you know we're next door
getting hammered talking to these locals
eaten Bacon. Remember that Bacon, they
put bacon out as a bar snack. Remoteness.
That's right. So we had the
west man, I know it's buffalo,
but you're already north of Pittsburgh.
And then there's like peanuts,
peanuts and pretzels.
They can,
she bring hot bacon out in baskets for the
bars neck. And I'm like, look. And I go,
Bacon's not cheap man. I, I know, like I
asked the part, I'm like, wait a minute,
this is crazy. She's like, Hey, it's
Friday and Saturday nights only,
but it gets people drink, they, they
make the bake and I asked the guy,
he came out,
they make the Bacon,
they let it cool for like 25 minutes
so you don't burn yourself on it.
So it's warm but not hot and it
just comes in. He just, he was like,
I'm not gonna eat this.
And then it's like literally like crack.
You have a couple of handfuls
and then you get all that.
It's all salty and then you
want to start pounding. Yeah,
they was setting this up.
I gotta I gotta do some ads here.
Hang on one second. All right.
All right. Here we go. Um,
let's see if I can read these
without messing them up. All right.
Dollar Shave club,
everybody.
Nothing feels better than that first
shave with that with a fresh blade, right?
It's smooth. It's close in.
The blade is sharp and it's,
it's as shoppers it's ever going to be.
It feels fantastic,
but thanks to the big shave companies,
ridiculous prices.
You can't afford to use
a fresh blade every week.
Can you see a drag that Dulles blade
across your face for two, three weeks,
10 weeks?
Why do you do it to yourself?
Maybe because the only thing more
painful than shaving with an old blade is
shelling out 30 bucks for
a pack of new ones. Well,
if you want to enjoy the fresh bro,
if you want to enjoy a
fresh blade every week,
but you don't want to go out and take
out another mortgage on your house,
you got to join dollar shave club.com
for just a couple of bucks a month.
Dollar Shave club.com ships the
highest quality blades you can get.
Um, ms, that stuff where I'm supposed
to act like I'm a four blade guy.
I like the three blade guy.
I'm seriously only six bucks for
the best quality blades you can get.
So every week you can pop in a fresh
blade and treat yourself to an amazing
shape. It's incredible. Um,
join dollar shave club.com.
Get amazing quality blades in the mail
for a couple of bucks bucks and treat
yourself to a brand new blade every single
week. Hundreds of thousands of guys.
Um, Jesus, I suck this week.
Hundreds of thousands of guys
with their up with have upgraded.
See, this isn't me, this is the copy.
Hundreds of thousands of guys
have upgraded their shaving
with dollar shave club.
I'm one of them and I'm loving
it. Now. What's your terms?
Shave time, shave money,
dollar shave club.com/bird. That's
dollar shave club.com/bar. All right,
one more here. stamps.com everybody.
The classic. Uh, I know it's a tough,
I know it's tough deciding where to focus
your resources to grow your business
while isn't it? Uh, but
one thing I can tell you,
you don't need to waste valuable time
going to the post office for mailing and
shipping anymore. Why you
ask? Well, I'll tell you why.
Just use stamps.com to ask access all the
services of the post office right from
your desk 24 seven with stamps.com buy
and print official us postage using your
own computer and printer.
Get Post Office,
get postage for any letter or package,
any class of mail,
all for just a fraction of the cost
of an expense of a postage meter with
stamps.com you'll never have to go to
the post office again so you can spend
your time where it matters most focused
on your business or other areas of your
body. I use stamps.com right now.
Use Your last name, Bill Birth.
What? Right now use my last name.
Birth for this special offer.
No risk trial plus $110 bonus offer
includes a digital scale and up to $55
postage. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburrthatstamps.com
enter
burr. Try. That was a rough one. You know
panty parried that one.
Dot. I was terrible. No,
but then you guys were moving in the
background and then when you guys started
talking about built how we finished,
that's what happened. That's
also basketball. That's
every other fucking sport.
If you're trying to take a foul shot.
No.
What it was was I started thinking like
this is how uninterested people are at
home.
Listening to this shit be effected.
I love,
my favorite part is like when I watch,
I've been watching every dribble of
March madness is I've been having his bad
back. Like, I literally have seen like
more traveling calls in a reps have.
But the thing is,
I've been sitting there whole time and
I love like Vern Lundquist is the best,
cause you know we talked about like
dial and stuff in like, yeah, that guy,
like when he's doing the, Oh yeah, he's
been broadcasting for a hundred years,
but he has to do those live spots for
like 60 minutes, you know? He's like,
well, 1218 to go and conduct
these right? Fag in it.
Now this one coming up 60 minutes.
Don't forget to catch the pink panthers.
Do we get the jewel? Thieves are,
don't wait tonight and 60 minutes
and you are like a horny aids.
Then he just totally
reading ads on a podcast that's
called. That's how tough. Right?
There you go. There's your
point made. All right,
well let's get into how I
actually met you, how I met you,
assholes out on the road.
The fact that I would loan the Monday
morning podcast presents the all things
comedy tour for some reason,
you can't be late to this thing
because you downloaded it.
But if you know you're playing this in,
your wife is walking around in the
background or husband? Uh, once again,
the all things, comedy tours coming
to San Diego Tuesday, April 1st, uh,
it's going to be in Bellevue, Washington
Sunday, April six at parlor live,
a helium comedy club, Portland, Oregon
and then two nights at Saint and uh,
at the punchline in San Francisco,
the eighth and ninth in
Sacramento on the 10th. Um, yeah.
Then we're going to swing it over to
the east coast and a couple months more
dates to follow.
I think they're working on that,
but I'm looking forward to doing that.
Those dates are coming.
[inaudible] Boston bought,
we're [inaudible] all these guys,
all these guys opened for me.
If you've come out and seen any of
my shows basically in the last shit,
I don't know, five, six years. It's
been one of these guys open it for me.
So I'm excited for you guys. I was
actually trying to think who I met first.
I think I met you. Law Ahead. We've
known each other for a long time.
It's coming up on 10 years.
No
over 10 years. You know what's
funny is I didn't want to get,
I didn't want to get like sentimental
about it because my first whiskey,
but no, like we did that show. We
did that show on New Year's Eve.
We did that show on new years eve at the
Wiltern and that was literally 10 years
to the day we met. We like hung out on
New Year's Day, New Year's Day tenure,
like New Year's Eve.
You did Cleveland and then hung out.
We got and then that's when we,
that's when we became friends.
It's like you just came and hung out
with me on New Year's Day because you had
nothing to do.
We were dark,
but you had to stay in Cleveland
for like two more nights.
This was a deal like New Year's eve
was a was like, like a Thursday. Yeah,
there was a Wednesday or Thursday.
So then there was new year's day
and nobody's coming out that day,
but then there was,
you still had the weekend,
so I had this weird weekend there
where I was working new years.
I was doing a run the whole week doing
new years and I had a day off so I had a
day off and nick, the club owner
of the greatest guy ever at, uh,
hilarity is out there in
Cleveland. He goes, hey, you know,
just just watch out for the guy, you
know, keep them company, Blah Blah.
Do we fucking drank all day?
They actually lost me at one point.
We somehow ended up in this brutal titty.
Yeah.
Rudel Silverhorse silver horse and a,
yeah,
that's a boring Cleveland as you need.
Like the comic needs to be
assigned somebody to just
invest. That's how it was.
I was like that guy. I was like,
Hey Jason, what are you doing now?
Well entertain this guy please.
Cleveland is way better than even,
it was like 10 years. What's wrong?
Like an attitude. I wish she had money
back then cause I was like, I'm, I'm like,
I'm going to buy a frigging building.
Cause you could see it in common.
It's common back around,
unlike Detroit,
which keeps starting
and stopping Cleveland.
You could buy a hospital for like 80
grand and Cleveland they showed me,
they showed how, I swear I'm
there, I'm closing on a hospital.
You could get like a four bedroom house
there for like $36,000. It's insane.
But I gotta tell you though, but like
when, when I first played hilarity,
he's in Cleveland. That was the
only game in town on that street.
You walk like you walked up that street
like a cotton and I crossed the street
out of my hotel.
It's the cop met you at the corner and
walked you up the street and now it's
like closed off to traffic.
They got the house of blues across the
street and they got all this stuff going
on,
restaurants and stuff.
I remember seeing this giant apartment
building like right across the way.
I think Mike was living there at the
time around the corner and I was thinking
like,
like I was literally thinking that I bet
you could buy that thing for 75 grand
and in 20 years it's going to be worth
like millions of dollars as this whole
thing eventually hopefully comes back,
you know, you know they've got the casino,
they just build another casino. Like
not downtown but somewhere else. But um
oh that's not a good idea
that I don't like that idea.
I just don't like the casino at the,
I think that we could have built that,
that there is no reason that that city
can't be built on its waterfront and its
character and its positioned
geographically in the
country through casinos.
Then casino nightlife for like toddlers.
The nice thing about the [inaudible],
we're close to DC,
we're close to New York.
There's no reason we can't be successful.
But you know, it's funny though,
the Nice thing was I said to, well you
know ball the color I love, but I said,
I said, he loves you pay, he loves
your parents. And I said to Bob, I go,
how come to, you know, where's the home?
Cause homeless is big out there. Big, big,
like they come after you and I go,
how come there is it just light
on the homeless? And he goes,
they're all at the casino. That's just
like all, yeah. Oh, is that right?
Yeah. They just all hanging out at the
workplace. A nickel slots all day long.
That was like the lottery for that one.
That was the lottery.
Then you're bringing in the trenches,
started stretching when that clicks again.
Wow.
Why would homeless people go to a casino?
They don't have any fucking money.
What are they doing that they,
whatever they make those,
some of those people make decent money.
It's amazing. I love that theory.
And it's all those guys. Yeah, they make
like a hundred grand. So of them do. Now,
I don't know about a hundred grand a year,
but some of them make their own
urine in that fucking cardboard box.
And we talk about committed to the free
scam. It's freezing fucking Ohio. Whether
it was fucking, uh, what's that shit?
When you feed a frostbite black toes,
making a hundred grand a year, you know,
you gotta make sacrifices.
Nfl guys smash their brains around
the homeless. They lose their toe,
do that scam and south beach to
call my own gift. Black Long.
You get a blood flow to it. I got to tell
you, when I was in San Francisco, uh,
I was just up there trying
to find someplace where I
could shoot my special and,
and I have never seen so many
people laying around not doing shit.
Then that city, I don't
know what, everywhere. Well,
they used to have a stipend.
They used to fucking give them
money. It was, this was hilarious.
Like gave the homeless, we would
give him enough money to get there,
tried to get him off the street.
That was one of those things where it
made sense if you were giving it to people
who thought sensibly, but they did and
they gave it to the fucking homeless.
So they would give you enough money so
you could afford rent in some flop house
for a month.
So what would happen is the first four
days of the month you wouldn't see any
homeless people.
They were all inside drinking,
you're shooting and drugs and
all that shit with the money.
They didn't have enough money for four
days and then by the fifth day they'd
start coming out like zombies and
then you had the problem again.
So they get with basically we're
buying themselves like a four,
five day reprieve. Now of course,
as always with all my stories,
that's just something that like four,
four or five people did tell
me that story in San Francisco.
I don't know if it's true, but I was
there and they had, um, they all have the,
all these beautiful parks and dude,
these people are snoozing to a level.
You actually start thinking like, what
am I working for it? Look at that too.
And I saw this guy like,
he was like face down in the sun,
like some old hound dog. And I was, you're
just thinking like this fucking guy.
Like I know he's living outside,
but he's eating. Yeah. You know,
he doesn't have any conference calls.
There's no debt. Doesn't wake him up.
This guy, dude, and it was
such a beautiful sunny day.
It was one of those days
where you actually would
entertain the thought that I
could like I maybe I could just
fucking live. I'll dad. Beautiful Dude.
I took a picture of the guy and I just,
I tweeted it and what was funny is I
didn't even realize that there was another
guy in the background.
It's like you can't just get one.
This is so many of them
when you get to the parks,
just fucking lying all over the place.
Um,
I saw what I was just there and do a is
a couple of weeks ago and I saw a guy
laying on a park bench sleeping covered
up champagne bottle ed is at his feet,
right?
Cop Strolling. I was sitting in another
part, but it's just people watching.
This guy's hilarious. He just bundled
up. Not only am I watching this guy,
he's got the champagne bottle,
have his feet,
two cops comes strolling up towards
him. They're like, Hey god, Hey,
let's go pick it up.
Let's go.
And one guy picks up and he like wakes
up out of a panic and he sees the one cop
holding is half empty bottle and he's
getting ready to go pour it out and he's
like panicking like it's not my wine and
I wanted a guy doesn't care. He knows.
He's like, yeah, I'm sure it's not.
He's like pouring it out. Right.
The funniest thing is is this guy,
when he got up and he rattled off and I
noticed it after he woke up and he put
it up there,
he had American Airlines I the
patches to cover your eyes.
You can sort of the sleep mask
on an American Airlines logo,
flimsy little woman.
They probably give you on the flight and
they were so then they were up on his
forehead as he was like begging
for mercy when the cop was,
I'm looking at them going, wait a minute,
what are you worried about anyway?
Did I'm putting you under a route, like
a roof? What are you worried about?
Yeah, but dude, I would
rather sleep outside,
worry about getting hit over the head
with a log. Fucking take. One of my acid,
you know, hey, you know,
I heard I just like a bed.
They actually, uh, they actually, uh,
one of those cities when
they had like the stipend,
other cities were flying their fucking
homeless people in there to just get rid
of them because they were having,
and then they started sending them back.
I forget what the fuck happened.
Maybe that's where that guy got the mask.
I can't remember.
I can't remember what,
it would be hilarious if that's
where he got the legs still had it.
That's what I'm guessing.
The other night in New York
I saw a lot of the homeless,
they sleep on the top step of the church,
but the church never lets him in.
So like they're just laying
there like what? No, I know.
But after a while they got to be
like, listen, they're not listening.
They're not opening up. Let's go
somewhere else. You know what I mean?
Like they're just laying on the thing and
it's almost like sad cause it's almost
like they have the belief and the
faith and they're being shut out. Well,
I think that the church church,
and I'm going to Starbucks,
I'm going to somewhere else because it's
no one, someone's not listening to him.
I'm showing my faith. No, but it's good
business for them to let them stay there.
Like they give a fuck, but they're
not going to let them in. Um,
but I don't know.
That seems like a safe place.
You want a safe place
to sleep if you're home.
I want if any homeless
people in the church floor,
cause I don't want it in there to say
this part about how this conversation got
steered into is we were
talking about Cleveland.
It's the saddest part of it all.
Oh we,
we've just gone to the dregs of humor
comics, dark Cleveland. But anyway,
no,
but I find that interesting when I kept
seeing you don't want a bunch of smelly
homeless people sticking up the church
for the decent people who've come in on
Sundays. And that might sound like
Fox News. But at the end of the day,
if you smell like urine, you smell like
urine. You gotta go outside with the dogs.
What if to do doesn't smell and
he's just freezing, you know, put a,
put them in one of the
pews and let them get home.
Fucking let him sleep in your base,
but smell only thousand. I said, look,
I understand. Going to let him see my
butt. You smells good though, Paul.
You got it. You've just got
some Irish spring. Me, just
stranger. There's a church.
He's going to go in there and steal all
the chalices that they stole from the
other fucking people.
I just feel like if he's saying
that he's got faith in that church,
they should do something. And that's
all. That's what churches should be.
That's what it's about. Should be
homeless after cost. Money, baby.
Put a little in the back. Exactly.
But that's my point. That's my point.
What is your point, Paul? My point is that
like, they kind of get faith on us here.
No, no, no. I'm just saying like,
uh, you know, uh, I know, you know
what I'm saying is I,
I,
I see them laying on the front step of
the churches and it's kind of a sad thing
to see because they're wrapped up in
their blankets and they have so much faith
in that belief. Yet the doors are
never opening and it was just a,
an observation that I've found fucked up.
Why do you think that the fact that
they're sleeping on the stairs means they
believe in Jesus Christ? I'm not saying
that. I'm just saying that it's just,
I, I think the people that show thing
is unraveling. No, I think that,
I think the fact that these
people choose to be on the,
on the top step at the door of a church,
it tells me that they have some sort
of faith because I think I put it down.
What if it rains? You want to be
underneath the arch. There's a million.
You could go under, you know, awnings are
places or you could go on dirt, you know,
buildings. They have a little
one. The church stairs. Yeah.
It doesn't mean you believe in
Burger King, but you know what?
The church that I saw this guy on, there
was no roof. He was just sleeping there,
man. So I just put, I just pushed off.
I don't think he believes in it. Okay.
I don't think he does. Cause you know,
no, but you don't know him either. No,
I don't.
But I think it's he could or he might not.
It's that just because
you're sleeping on church,
there's doesn't mean you fucking
believe in anything. Well,
what did you think it's a good guest to
think that he's got some sort of faith.
If that's his choice of,
I would think it would be safer to sleep
there then outside of white castle.
This is the first dude you've
called it on a homeless.
What a fuck is Bart? Nick
say he ain't making it. Yeah,
that's Barton nigger.
He ain't gonna make it cause it's
gonna make it. This is, this is this.
So this education,
this is the dedication we're going
to have with this fucking tour.
Is that what we're saying here? Um, no,
but going back to drinking on, let's,
let's start some more arguments here.
Hey, so you're a Cleveland Indians Fan,
a red sox fan. He's a Yankees
fan or all American league east.
They're all American league east night.
Um,
w how do you feel about both of our teams
and the way we spend money each year?
I think it's disgusting.
Now.
I will say that Boston last year wanted
in a way where they didn't go out and
over, like they didn't spend any more
than they kind of had been spending. Uh,
I love the fact that most of the,
most of the trend is all these deans
that are spending money aren't really the
teams that are being successful.
At the end of the day,
the doctors were $135 million.
Any outspend the Yankees
and the number one to you.
I loved it. That sits, you can
finally say that. See, I loved it. No,
not because of that. I just love the
fact that like the Dodgers are trying to,
you know, the Dodgers are
going all in. Well they hell,
they have to all link towards what's he
know because they've been, they've been,
they've been 25 years
without a championship. Um,
they've corrected their financial
situation after the guy and magic new,
you know what,
I forget the guy's name at random.
Under the ground spending $230 million
is the waiting, well, you know,
they didn't set the trend.
I I to believe that if they believe
that they're going to do something, uh,
that the Yankees or Boston have done,
which they haven't done yet in this,
in this economics of baseball. Yeah, you
got to do it. I mean, the last time they,
they, one was in 88 when the economics,
we're shifting a little, but it wasn't,
it wasn't a five mega market league.
Being able to spend that kind of,
there,
there's only five teams
I can spend that kind of,
there's only five teams that can spend
that kind of money. So why wouldn't they,
if they're one of the five teams that
can spend it anywhere, should question,
why do you think that
baseball allowed it to,
to go the direction?
What was the,
what was the thinking that it was good
to let fucking the Yankees do what they
did, which caused the red sox to have
to react to it and then we became them.
What, I mean, we're not right now I
don't think, but, but we in oh seven.
I mean there's no fucking,
there's no,
there's nobody on the
planet that can't tell me,
oh seven we didn't buy a fucking title.
Well, I think it all stems back.
A lot of it stems back from,
obviously you can't change what happens
moneywise but I think a lot of it sends
back to when the um,
owners were, you know, uh,
found out about the collusion in,
in the late eighties and they
had to pay once they paid the,
once they played the players union,
I think $350 million settlement
for collusion and the players,
union owners getting together going down.
They said don't pay Jack
Morris is what it was.
Jack Morris was on the free agent market,
I think in [inaudible] 86 or 87.
And The tigers owner told all
the other owners, don't pay him.
Keep him at the market value that we
have in Italy in the long run. Yeah,
we get to keep Jack Morris,
but in the long run all you guys will get
be able to keep your Kirby buckets and
your Roger Clemens is at a
price that won't gorgeous.
That was vida blah blah blah.
The end of the day is it strength in
the player's Union to a point where the
salaries have gotten to the point that
the player's union really runs the market
and they run the market.
So now the big market teams that
have the money they've opened,
the player's union is have made,
has made it able to be able to speak for
those teams to spend that money and the
rich teams can, well that's, that's
the bottom line. The bottom line,
as long as there's no cap in baseball,
80% of the teams will
never win a world series.
No, it says as long as there's
no cap, the Kansas city royals,
I'm never going to one off.
It's that high.
But I mean it's good to at least 60 close
to one thing is is what baseball has
tried to do is obviously with the
wildcard and now the extra wild card,
if you tried to make it
somewhat competable where as
a team like Cleveland or if
by the all star break,
if we look like we're playing really
well with the guys we've groomed in,
we can go out and you know,
get a,
if the Philadelphia Phillies
are fallen flat on her face,
we can go out and get a
Jimmy Rollins if he doesn't,
if he wants to waive his
trade clause and be like,
you know what I want to go play
for these guys are pretty good.
I'm at a certain point in my career, I'd
go hit, you know, when a title, whatever.
That's the only thing baseball's
done. The kind of recoup that. But
why they just don't look at the NFL and
be like, okay, the way they're doing it.
Greenbay can compete with New York City.
Can you walkie compete with Boston? No.
Like brewers compete with the red sox.
They can't. So what the F why don't we do,
why should I assume you're so strong?
Because they can get big players.
You need to get the guys pay.
I think there's another walkout coming.
We'll talk and lock out here on the
podcast. Uh, I like talking and stuff.
I don't,
I don't see it looming anytime soon.
I think baseball's in probably
a pretty pretty good labor,
a labor situation because now the bay,
the players haven't had to kind of weigh,
crawl with their tails between their
legs a little bit in the last few years
with the,
with the PE deals and everything else.
So they've kind of had to kind of
come off their high horse a bit.
So now there's a little bit of love.
There's a little bit of balance between
players and owners because the players
ever kind of had to go, hey,
yeah, we were doing all of this.
That's so fucked up that those guys
actually went in front of the Senate or
whatever the fuck was going on.
I don't understand.
I just don't get why
politics had to get involved.
Why am I watching curt Schilling?
Yeah.
Talking to some representative
from Minnesota. Yeah,
because it's just fucking all stupid and
you should be talking to is accountable
shit. Hey, speaking of
a lot, this sexual time,
this ties in with a question here that
uh, somebody said, I said Bill, what team,
dear Billy batts if you could coach
one team in history without knowing the
outcome of the season, which team
would you pick? Keep in mind,
stack teams don't always
win championships in,
there were other teams that you that
could have one perhaps with some better
coaching. What the fuck? That
was like a brain twister.
Like a train's going this way.
If I could coach one team in history
without knowing the outcome of the season,
which would I pick? Keep in
mind, stack teams don't always
win championships. Yeah,
but the teams won the championship.
I know if I coached the
cowboys in 78 they won.
They beat the Broncos.
I don't get your question.
All right,
drop that part of it.
But what team would you coach
because that is an interest in quit.
Like if you could coach one team.
No, I think the question
is saying now, like,
I think the question is
basically like what you see now.
If you could coach one of these
teams that's out there now,
don't go out and try to win a championship
to stack. Don't look who stack,
but just say, well, who would you want it?
Debbie says one team in history. Ah, okay.
All right.
Then look at this guy is either really
smart and we're dumb or this is a fucking
confusion question. Uh, I don't
fucking know if I could coach one team.
How about, can I play on the team
and said, look, I'd like to cook. Go.
I'll go every error in hockey. If I can
play on any team, I would play for the,
the, the eighties Edmonton
Oilers. Um, if I could play,
if I could, I guess, coach, Dude,
you're the, you're a coach's son.
Who would you coach? If I could
coach one team one time, uh,
I would probably,
I would probably coach Larry Bird's
79 Indiana state team against magic.
I'd like to, I'd like to coach that
game. I like to see if we could,
if I could help,
I'd like to see if I can beat magic.
Maybe there's this question.
You know what I'd like to do?
I'd like to coach the fucking,
uh,
79 Dallas cowboys and the 76 Dallas
cowboys to against the Steelers in both.
And I, and I would win the fucking
game. Yeah. That's how confident I am.
Because they had their number in the first
half. Uh, this is what we need Barton,
dude, if you, I want somebody,
somebody put up the 70 Superbowl 10,
they put that up on,
on the Internet to the cowboys
called a reverse on the first play,
reverse to Hollywood Henderson.
He ran down the field that they're kicker
tackled and we took a need of the ribs,
fucked up three of his field goals and
they will play in loose and all that.
And they were up and then they played
Marty ball in the second half and they got
all fucking tight and they just stay,
basically conserved the game away.
Um, as far as the, uh, the 79, oh,
I guess I would know this.
I wouldn't throw it to fucking Jackie
Slater or whatever the hell his name was.
Jess Smith, bless his heart. He's a
sec. As man in America, I would coach.
Did you see they outlawed the dunk.
You know they made that a penalty.
Now the dunk of over the goalpost and
you were saying Hollywood Henderson,
Hollywood Henderson invented
the dunk of the goalposts.
They would just had a base mesh
first one or did they set up,
they had a big thing on ESPN. Yeah, it was
a, the owner's meeting over the winter.
It's a 15 yard penalty now if you dunked
the ball cause Joey Graham and all
these guys. Oh it's a, you
know, they dated it back to
history. They like the WHO,
the first man and it was Hollywood
Henderson after a reverse.
Landry used to call it reverse all the
time to Hollywood Hendrickson and it was
a, in 75 they called a reverse
the Hollywood Henderson
and a regular season game
and he busted one loose for a touchdown
and he was the first guy and they show
it. He's the first guy that glove and
dunk it over the goalposts and outlawed
because these tear there, they're
tearing down low. They're tearing down.
Some goalposts guys have gotten to
heard, I guess. I don't know. Wow Mill.
One Time Joey Graham from the saints was
so strongly pulled one down where they
had to come out and re level the
goalpost cause it wasn't, you know,
so he pulled it and then the next guy
to kicks in and is kicking in and out.
A lot of white guys upset about that rule.
Wes Welker now the West woken
up bitching about that at all.
As long as it needs to. It needs to
be on Joey, Jimmy Graham shoulders.
Why this is the deal. I would,
I would, I would actually,
if I could coach any team in history,
what I would probably do is I
would maybe the 86 red sox. Yeah.
But no, but then I put Dave
Stapleton in at first. Yeah. But,
but that's only because I know what was
going to happen. So like I could know.
So like, uh, I would, I would
try to pick a team that,
that hasn't won a championship,
but I live in Boston and they
won't run the table. So I know,
I don't know what to tell for me.
It's a no brainer.
I would 100% coach to nicks and I would,
I would make them run, listen to that.
I would make that run.
I would make them run until they puked.
I would I,
if they didn't play defense,
they're out there find I would fucking
goes up fast with this team. Quit on
his second. You'd be a second nick
coach in history to get choked. I would,
I would fucking, I'd lay into those
lazy cock suckers like I like,
I swear to God, Dude. I
want to be fun. Actually.
I would like to just take a
horrible team and just terrible.
Yeah, you show me. You don't
get back. Just get all my shit.
I would do with Gene Hackman.
Didn't Hoosiers minimum of three passes.
Minimum of three passes. Okay. You fuckers
are going to run all day. We're not,
we're practicing the first month without
a ball. Who are running up and down.
Carmelo Anthony's.
If you didn't go,
you can do this with rows
or they're all Carmello.
Anthony's lazy we'd face would
fuck it. Get everything shut. No,
you want to wear that headband? Go
take it off the top of the back. Yeah,
I would fucking turn into,
oh, that's what I would do.
[inaudible]
Nick Joey to do my puck off podcast and
I thought I said I couldn't be heard and
until to hey between you guys like
you would need another 10 mikes.
I don't think anyone's
missing my, my uh, hey.
Well we're currently answering a
question right now. If you, if you,
this would be perfect for you.
Worked in coach, any team in history,
not knowing the outcome.
If you could just be the head coach who,
who would you want to be? Head coach
of? Oh, the Steelers 78 Steelers 78. Oh,
I want to do the 78 cowboys or 76 cowboys.
76 roll the market.
The whole ready for that shit.
You would've thought you'd
text Bart. Nick, the question
three sixers.
I was thinking to them too.
I said six or I said, did they played
four on five these play diver voting,
I mean they played four on five. They'd
be that. It'd be genuine anyway. Yeah,
I put them up against, I'd put
them up against the 96 bolts. Yeah,
we talked about that on mine. I never, he
goes, who's gonna Stop Jordan? I'm like,
why? I think doctor Janka kind of
offset a lot of the shit he was doing.
And then I got Moses against the
fucking Luke long week. Yeah.
I don't think anybody's
been in the 96 bulls.
That's because you're a child
of the nineties dude, that team,
they said they 79 Indiana state
defensively as they were all,
oh, that's a good one.
But I'm telling you.
But Luc Longley would have four files by,
by the end of the first quarter trying to
stop Moses Malone. And in all fairness,
I didn't see enough of that 76 15
but how good was Pippin on Dif?
I mean the defense xe offensively,
they were phenomenal.
There's a reason I picked the
96 bolts. Great. Well, Andrew,
Tony had bad feet or Andrew. Tony would
be in the hall of fame. Yeah, absolutely.
Tony could, they didn't have six
quarters back to your career.
Broke him,
strangling stroke them that they,
that that was the ultimate two man
game.
If you had to double team m and M,
most of them bouts of nearby.
He went from,
from high school to
dominating the dominate Aba.
Aba Aba was like a
fucking prison rec league.
It was that mean the bet he was. Dot.
People were afraid of Moses Malone.
He like,
he was 17 he was a beast.
He was remember the mere expression
of a man child and it was like him,
Daryl Dawkins. He never
lived up to those guys. Joe,
was he the first guy to come out?
Yeah, early. Yeah. Bose as well.
Darryl Dawkins a second.
Yeah.
You know the funny thing is is Moses
Malone and Lebron James are the only two
guys in the history of the NBA to win
consecutive MVP awards with different
teams and they're the, and the, and
they both never played college ball.
It's pretty freaking impressive. Wow.
I mean if you take out the big three,
you know the, the, the, the,
the, the, the mount, right.
You know, we'll Kareem and uh,
Bill Russell the next,
I mean this was in below weight
and Moses, Moses, just like six,
six, 10 truck. Yeah.
Yeah. That's 17 who just,
he's just crazy. He just didn't
miss, what did they lose that year?
They lost one playoff high school kid.
That's a baby coming into that.
Firstly they lost one playoff game.
They actually, I asked Moses to predict.
That's his famous thing. He goes,
what do you think about the playoffs?
He just goes, fold, fold, fold. Just
me and we're going to sweep everybody.
And they basically would, they'd lost
one to the Lakers, three pho, pho, pho.
Because back then it was the first round
game was a five but three. Oh was okay.
But the funny thing was is
that was a huge six or fan.
He seems to fit back in
because I was a huge Dr Fan.
Huge six or fan and when he
got traded cause you could,
they could never win because Coldwell
Jones and Dawkins and Steve Mix whatever
agglomeration,
the shit that they put together to stop
either like parish or Jabar would never
work. So we, they get him and
he was heading to cover rock.
He was like sitting on the steps like
rocky. It was like you knew it was over.
There was never a lock in the history
of sports like Moses go into the sixers
like was over. It was, it was,
how come they only won one though?
Cause doctor Jay was old. Moses
wasn't, no, I mean he will,
he wasn't old but he was,
he was dude Moses,
bad play back in the day where that do
play 46 minutes and Knight Dragon gives
up without it as I say like,
because because of black Monday is why
they definitely one one black Monday he
trade hit black eye.
The eye.
The only time I ever cried in sports
other than like Lemieux getting cancer,
they were crying sports black Monday
dude, they traded bread dough. They,
they try to,
they try to hit those below and the
rights to bread Doherty for Roy Henson and
Ruland dude,
they trade.
They are or are you still a NASCAR shit
would do but they traded like they,
the front line would have been a
Barkley bread bread Doherty in Bozeman.
Moses said I will never lose to the 76
there's again the bullets when
like eight games that year,
like five of them were against the six
[inaudible] five he was like 30 and 25 it
give Brad Doroty has probably the
the most epic fucking hairline.
It almost touches his eyebrows. I mean
the fucking guy when he gets a shape up,
I mean they gotta like put a separate
it like at the grocery store between his
eyebrows and his, it's just something sad
about seeing Brad already talk NASCAR,
you know, he's just sitting there
talking. NASA was even sadder.
We see this in the bench at all star
Games. It was going to say this,
this and this check I drafted.
It was like,
well they're good for Nascar is
probably like fuck this. It's like,
well Brad already cause they'll
make plans for all star weekend.
How did he get
you fucking go from, he's like, he's
like one of the announcers for Nascar,
Black Mountain North Carolina and he
grew up in that shit and he loves it.
He's always loved that.
Oh, that's all right.
Then he ended up doing
something like that. Guys,
I've got to read a cut by the last
fucking my last three brutal reads of this
week. This, this is, this is
not a Vern one. I'm not, not
on my game here this week.
I'm going to try to focus the right.
This is just like golfing. All right.
He voice everybody.
Um, what your business,
what your business want your business.
Dude, I fucked up the first word.
He voice. Everybody want your business
to make more money. He voice can help.
Here's how when your customers call,
you'll have your own toll free number,
professional greeting,
dial by name directory and more.
You'll sound like a fortune 500
company and really stand out from your
competitors. He voice lets you give
one number that rings wherever you are.
You could be at your kid's soccer game.
You'll never miss a chance
to grow your business.
He voice takes all your voicemail calls,
transcribes them,
and sends them to you instantly
as a text or an email, a email,
so you can check your voicemails before
the meeting ends and not look rude. Rude,
evil voice is only 13 bucks a month.
And right now my listeners get to try.
He voice free for 60 days. That's right.
A 60 day free trial. Don't put this off.
Turn down the radio,
get a computer and set up your ear voice
60 day free trial now so you can see
what I mean.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com Promo Code Bill.
That's [inaudible] dot com Promo Code
Bill. All right, the next one, legal zoom,
everybody. If the excitement
of starting your business,
getting your first customer
and finally quitting your job,
has it moved you to action yet? Here's
another great reason to get started.
It's net started,
its national starch,
your business month@legalzoom.com and
they want to help you start your own
business or corporation
or LLC C or file a DBA.
So you can get up and
running quickly and easily.
Find out why more than 1
million entrepreneurs use
legal zoom to start down the
path of successful business
ownership this month.
Only take advantage of their national
start your business month special and get
a free three month trial
of all new quickbooks,
making it so much easier to
run your new business. Uh,
that's $119 value for absolutely free
when you enter Burr in the referral box.
Checkout.
That's legalzoom.com promo
called [inaudible] legal
zoom.com Promo code birth.
All right, there we go. I'll save the
other one until the end. Um, so anyways,
Joe Barden, nick, you excited for
the all things a comedy, a tour here.
All in tour is going to be epic. It's
going to be APP. It's going to be epic.
Look at his game plan is he's going to
try to avoid you as far as like his drink
and he's going to try to like, he's
going to try to drink it either. No,
they I'm drinking. Drinking. No,
we were talking about we were
drinking and drinking.
Nice.
[inaudible] afford to buy a drink too.
Exactly.
Pointed at you like he was an NFL coach
and you were a defensive player who
missed an assignment?
I I'm drinking but he said like,
we were talking about smoking
cigars and drinking and bill said,
what's your game plan to not, you know,
to not gain so much weight and go nuts.
And I go listen,
I go,
I got to really just watch Barton
it cause Barnick is you know you,
you got that thing dude, you're
unstoppable. You're fucking unstoppable.
The thing is like an idiot
every year at the rose bowl.
I tried to go blow for blow your shot.
I don't know why I was telling him,
I was telling him that though
at the wedding you were like,
you guys want another heater. And like
after the fifth time I was like Joe Man,
you know we just met. I was
looking at, I love, I need,
I can't right now I need a break. And the
end of the night you had those crowns,
the shots and you're smoking a
cigar and you're just intact.
You are just fucking intact.
It's the way we grow them in Pittsburgh.
I was back home with this weekend.
I told people, I said, I
know people in Hollywood,
like I think I got to go to Rehab. I'm
like, first of all, you drink wine. Yeah.
I said, check the boat. My aunt's
drink more than you before dinner.
I mean, people pay it's drink. I
mean cope. I mean, but no, there's a,
there's never peer pressure because
there's more boost for me. No,
don't get me [inaudible]
somebody me stop early,
so we got to keep that in mind.
No, no, I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna definitely to have
some guys have a writer.
What is the writer on this tour? I
don't know. I haven't even seen it.
I didn't even have a rod track for openers
is going to be an amazing tour.
If you guys,
these guys are like that guy's
guys to fucking hilarious.
They know smarts and you know, it's
not going to be a, trust me. You did.
It's definitely worth the money.
As I mentioned earlier,
we're going to have all the dates up here.
Uh, they play in San Diego, a Bellevue,
Washington, Portland, Oregon, San
Francisco twice in Sacramento so far,
and then they got an east coast thing
line up. I'm really psyched for you.
You guys got some Midwest shows like a
people in that and did I want to thank
everyone that came to the shows this week
in Pittsburgh. They were awesome. We're,
we're, we're, we're coming
back as the tour. Nice. Nice.
They're stoked for us in the DV
guys are stoked for us to comment.
No, that's good. I just
meant that you got,
I told him, I told him all
about you. They're going to,
yeah, they're going to make fun of me.
Is that they're going to do, no, we do.
We feel your pain. We feel
your feet. What do you feel?
You don't feel super bowl championship
to Cleveland. Pittsburgh rivalry.
There is no, there is no robberies. No
rivalry though. There is no rivalry.
We don't even where we can't. You
can't be, no, there isn't. Right.
There's not a rivalry.
It's your,
your browns rivalry is now the ravens
that we don't even have a rivalry with you
because we haven't put up a fight and
15 years I made it. It's not as true.
It doesn't exist.
You think that there's people that I'm
the outside looking in that remember that
old brown Steelers that doesn't exist.
You go to Cleveland for Brown
Steelers games. It's a sea of black.
There's no browns fans there. They
sell their tickets of Pittsburgh fans.
There is no rivalry.
You can't be rival.
I wouldn't see the saddest moment and
one of the saddest moments in La heads,
adult life. We're watching the Steeler
game in a bar in San Francisco.
He was up there hanging out. We're
done doing shows. You did some sets
walking walk in the booth.
We look over to the booth next to us.
Guy Grew up right next door to him,
like four houses, four houses down.
They haven't seen it is cheering for the
Steelers and he goes like, he's like,
what are you doing? Is I just gave
up. I wanted to back a winner.
We see this kid in a booth next to me.
I think he grew up four houses down from
me. I'm like, Holy Christ, he's wearing a,
he's on,
it's a Sunday football that different
people are in there watching different
teams.
Right.
And he's like La head and I know he's
wearing like a Cordell stewardship.
I got really, and he just said,
he goes, hey, you know what?
I just gave up a long time ago.
I said, are you awareness steel?
Are you rooting for this dealer
that this the thing I understand,
just saying fuck it,
I am not watching it anymore.
And then go to go to a
different conferences.
I wouldn't even root for anybody in
the AFC. Exactly. I would, I would,
I mean if I could,
if I would root for any I've,
I've contemplated it and my thoughts on
my, my contemplations are, I would go,
and I know you hate him,
but they're central to me.
And I liked the new young quarterback.
If I had to quit, which I've thought of,
I'm thinking of quitting and
going to Indy. I don't mind
Nandy right. Well, I mean,
am I an idiot? I liked Gluck. They're
close by. They're a small little town.
They've done everything
right. I, I'm thinking what?
Whatever I've talked about.
That's a plus, right?
Exactly.
I'm saying their owner does drugs,
sits on the rules committee changes,
rules of passing the hell.
That's like a Knicks fan.
Becoming a fucking Brooklyn
Nets fan is despicable, man.
It can't. It can't do it. I'm just
saying, if I thought about it,
if I agree with bill, this guy watching
him, just stop watching it and give up,
but you can't just automatically take
your journey, puts it, go buy it.
Go to the store by how the fucking Jersey.
Then what happens when your team
actually fucking wins it? Yeah.
Then you're an idiot.
Then you deserve it.
You deserve your team to win
it a couple of years ago,
that's not going to actually happen. No.
It has to happen. Eventually. Say, Hey,
listen, we're going to, we're
going, do I have your guarantee?
We went up this year. It
opens on to Delta. Got April.
That's a guy that rats out.
It's a movie called draft day.
It opens.
I'm sure it's something good's going
to come out of it. That's a got it.
Ratchet as friends, if you
do that, if you do that,
if you switch uniforms because
they're not winning, you're a rat.
You'll read sturdily. It's a
carrier. Your waffle walls,
you'll rate your friends
out or you can't trust deck.
Are you going to trust that guy?
No, you can't trust that. Exactly.
That's been going to what's going with
stadium with his mother and father as a
kid and then he just fucking throws in
the towel and throws on the enemy shirt.
That cable sell you down a fucking shirt.
Is that,
that's a character that is a character.
That's a character flaw.
Something's wrong. No, you're right and
I think he and that person specifically,
I'm not going to name names, you know?
Yeah. I need to join a puck off today.
I need you a pug of, there's a lot, a lot
of Bruin stuff going on. My man crush.
What was just what he did.
Did he do dude hitting the guy in the
and the balls from behind with a stick.
I didn't see it yesterday. No. Can
they have all the Canadian gay dude?
I was so jet lagged and not so wiped off
my toy. I actually forgot Monday nights,
usually dark. Not only did they have
a game, they played the Canadians.
I missed every second of that.
I saw the capitals game.
I saw the flyers game this weekend.
Uh, who else did they play?
I think they each do what? Looch he
speared him from the back under his butt.
Like hit him in the taint. The guy went
down like a house of cards. It was,
it was not,
it was not something that does Lou
chicken to put that on the highlight reel.
I got to see that. What a thing.
I got to see that. Yeah, he,
he's stick them underneath like
it was real. I'm like, Luke,
what are you doing?
Huh?
Well, just so that people know we're
not going to just talk sports on the,
on the tour. No, I was, no,
I didn't even all my sports jokes or I
cut them out and I say the nice thing
taggers and I'm fucking around. I'm
just, the great thing about this tour,
it's like we're all alike,
but ours comedies different,
which is great. I'm clean,
Huh?
All right.
Well we're gonna have,
we're gonna have to wrap
this thing up here soon.
I want to talk a little little hockey
though. Anybody's not as sports fans.
Give me like, what the fuck
would this podcast, I don't care.
Let me just read the last people
to see your podcasts, Huh? Yeah.
But people still fucking bitch.
Monae is always bitch.
You know what it really is is just six
people bitch and then I think it's like 6
million. So I mean I only have for
that is the map on the Internet, right?
A producer of a show one time.
He's like, well, like six people.
That's really the Internet term. That's
like 4,000 yeah. It's like really was,
what does that base don, he was a moron.
I it work with you. But based on how many,
if then people are listening to six
people, which is now 4,000 that, you know,
I'm not good at math.
There's something in the Internet though.
It was like one person. He goes, okay,
let me read this last one, the butcher,
this last one, and we'll, we'll wrap this
thing up here. Ah, Hulu plus everybody.
You've probably tried hulu.com Hulu plus
is so much more that with Hulu plus you
can watch your favorite shows anytime,
anywhere.
Hulu plus let you watch thousands of hit
TV shows and movies in the living room
or on go with your smartphone
or tablet with Hulu. Plus you can
watch your favorite TV shows like SNL,
Jimmy Kimmel live a shark tank
and scandal. Watch every, uh,
episode of shows like
lost law and order Svu,
doctor who and community. How old am
I? I don't even know. Half those shows.
You can also check out exclusive
content including Hulu originals,
like the wrong mans and behind the mask,
who's new docu-series that takes you
inside the world of sports of mascots
behind the mask. I'm
going to watch that. Uh,
you also get access to a collection of
ad free movies and kids content for only
seven 99 a month.
Catch up on current shows,
binge on old favorites or
catch great movies, a stream,
as many TV shows and movies as you want.
Revenue One, I don't know what Apps,
whatever else I've got to tell you here.
This stuff is great.
Make sure you use Hulu plus.com/bill so
you get the extended free trial and that
they know we sent you once again,
it's Hulu plus.com/bill right now
for your extended to free week trial.
All right, there we go. Um, anyways, uh,
that's been the podcast for this week.
I know it's difficult when we have three,
four guys in here and all
that. So I hope we, uh,
we didn't step on each other too
much for people listening out here,
but I'm really psyched for you guys.
Thanks. Thank you. Everyone's
just like amazed. Not Amazed,
but I mean it's really a nice thing
that you did. Hey, I appreciate it.
To give us the,
you guys didn't read the fine
print of the, uh, the tour.
I'm going to own the rights to
all your acts and your podcast.
You could have it
tried to sell my ass
tonight.
Tonight we're going to be down in Largo,
we're going to give a great show.
And then afterwards I go,
I brought some Cubans back from Canada,
so over my,
over my house. You know, we'll get,
we'll get along at a Shirley temple and
the rest of us can drink a little. I mean
Johnny like,
you know,
you'd thought you'd hang around with
some adults once in a while and like,
you know, it's funny, as soon
as he said that we just get,
it already looks 90 days.
That's a hard time. Right?
But 89 89 days might loosen your backup
a little bit. No, I don't know, man.
I heard it's good for it.
May of backstreet best thing if you're
not going to have like the real real
drugs.
Best thing is like three regular
aspirin and a couple couple big pops.
Yeah. On. Is that right? Yeah. Best
thing for my, I tell you what they were,
the day I went in for it, I was so
jacked up. They shot me with morphine.
They put needles in my back and I'm
going to tell you something. I was like,
well listen, he's, you know [inaudible]
I can't take it. And he was like, yeah,
it'll be a while to fill the
prescriptions. He's like,
how do you feel about needles?
I'm like, I don't like them,
but I even had a drink and like 80
days so stick me wherever. He's like,
it's morphine. I'm like, please, if
you ever had morphine shot India,
that's the greatest party.
Greatest party I've ever had.
Instant like oh I had the morphine
drip and only when you have surgery,
just a button and you get it and
it's just, it goes away like it's
mine. No you did. That's
the truth. You rang,
you rang it on jeopardy with that thing.
Drove partner.
I need more morphine. I do jam
the fucking machine. I did. I did.
I hit it so many times. That's the
Lariat. It only lets you like, cause it's,
you're only supposed to do every
12 if got like 12 minutes here.
It could kill you. Lighters
out of fluid. Like he just,
he couldn't get a flame that went away
with that stuff. Do you get hired?
He just getting know you get a hi, hi. Hi.
Not numb.
That can be Jesus high
where you're just like, ah,
yeah, you're too, it's, it's it. I'd
never had had it before. All my life.
40 years of living plus and I've never
had morphine and that was awesome. I mean,
I was like three hours just like,
ah,
man that was in the car.
West is a three of a month ago.
So my doctor was worried about me going
to New York and walked around and so he
shot me up and I was in the hospital
with like four guys were all lined up.
These old guys like war veterans were
like, came back to cry and I'm like, good.
Or their families are making fun of them.
I went in there,
my back's been so jacked up, it's
so much shit done to me. He's like,
you don't feel that, you don't
feel that. I'm like, Nah, Nah, Nah.
I don't feel well. That's amazing.
I came back and they were like,
you didn't feel nothing.
Like no cause like that's
amazing to have a machine.
Yeah. Don't destructible you are Joe.
You are, you are, you're one of a kind.
Well the uh, the show is tonight at
eight 30. Um, I think they're actually,
we've got about 10 tickets left that we're
probably going to release around four
o'clock if nobody else hits
us up a ticket. So, uh,
maybe you can grab some last second ones,
but I'm psyched to be working.
I don't think I've ever worked
with all you guys at the same time.
I know new years we came close.
Yeah. Barnick Lawhead and feminists
and us three. It was never
all of us. Here we go.
So that's nice.
The four horsemen,
you can't make it tonight if you're
listening in San Diego, San Diego,
you guys got to give me a website where
I can send these people as far as that
house comedy club.com is for
San Diego. I know that. Just um,
parlor live.com is,
there's helium PD x,
I think.com for a port.
And then a punchline,
sf.com and then plus punchline
as ac for sacramento.com.
Okay. And that's all for the
first, uh, the first, uh,
the west coast leg of this
tour. All right, guys,
thanks for coming down on the podcast.
Thank you, man. It's on the studio.
You guys a little studio and all
things comedy is comedy. All right,
that's the podcast. Go fuck yourselves
and I'll talk to you next week.