Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
a, this isn't the Monday morning podcast.
This is the special,
the epilogue from last week's Monday
morning podcast where yours truly the
wonderful host of this show
that even say truly yours,
truly promise that.
Um,
I was going to have Nia
answer the question,
the provocative question. Um,
the fuck list. So first of all,
let's welcome the lovely Nia
to the epilogue. How are you?
I'm great. Thanks for having me. Well, I
thank you Nia. That was very professional.
What was that all about? Why was
that so professional at? No, I do.
Why you did something when you were away.
That was very guilty of, hello bill.
How are you person? I am something
when I was away, when I was old snack.
Okay. Get your promo out. When I was in
London shooting the pilot that I wrote,
produced and directed for a
possible travel show, I didn't,
I didn't ran it and I didn't direct it,
but I did produce in house debt.
I'll take a compliment.
Yeah, it's a travel.
I travel show pilot. Okay.
Then I did with two friends.
It was amazing all about the,
uh,
what the black experience in different
parts of Europe are like racist,
starting with London.
What if I went over?
But if I went to Europe and did the
white experience, why don't you,
I'll start in Germany. What's stopping
you? Yeah. Um, political incorrectness.
See vites experience.
You don't need your papers.
He was so lights.
You need no papers. Um,
all right, the fuck list.
Here's the question. Bill. Uh, I
wake up at my girlfriend's house.
She leaves for work. I love this guy. He
gets right into it. I can't find my socks.
They bagged. Um, she
says I have, I have some.
Just use mine in leaves. All
right. Now, first of all,
why is this feet the same size of hers?
Who wants success? Stretchy.
Look at your socks.
Strike where little colorful ankle socks,
like girlies socks that most girls
do. Most girls do. But I mean,
maybe she has for those, those bitches
we saw last night in the crossfit thing.
Why are they bitches? Just because
I've got to get you going here. Oh,
we watched that on ESP or awesome.
These girls were ripped cry.
These girls rate crime cornerbacks with
titties. That's what they look like.
That girl that won that, that one
round we saw it didn't look like that.
She looked really sexy
show. No, no up top. Up Top.
She looked like a roid it up. Who said
that girl you watch on a, Oh my God,
I ate too much. Helped me.
The biggest loser. Oh my God.
I got to find it in my brain.
Jillian, she looked like,
but then she had regular girly legs and
she had a nice little button and she
know she had a great figure
and she looks amazing.
She was doing those muscle
ups that's going to make your,
your shoulders and shit really bag.
But she didn't look right about. Yeah,
he's just looking muscular number one.
Dennis Rodman wore the wedding dress.
That's what she would look like. Um,
no, I'm kidding. She was uh, I dunno.
Oddly sexy yet frightened. That's only
cause you know, she could kick here.
Oh absolutely.
Anybody could kick my ass.
I have the worst hand dyed coordination
ever drunk people. That's what I have.
I have heart. Yeah, I have that
classic cut. I ain't going down.
Hit me over the head with a hubcap will
keep coming at you. But I swear to God,
I took some martial arts classes.
I literally,
they were saying what punch was coming
and I would still get hit by it.
I just can't, I just can't. I
know you took martial arts class.
I took martial arts class the
way somebody comes up and look,
I did stand up a couple of times and then
considers himself a comedian. I'm, no,
I went down, it's a karate for a month
and I don't remember anything. No.
I went to a Jujitsu class and it was like
literally like literally fighting and
it was pilot season and I'm sitting there
going like, what am I doing down here?
All right, I'm fucking, I was
already in my mid thirties.
I don't give a shit how old you are by
the time you're in your mid thirties,
somebody can come in with,
with a fucking the mailbox and just
smash it over your head. You'd done,
I just did that for all the psycho
competitive guys out there. Um,
all right, the fuck list. Uh,
why didn't you just fucking sign me out
for no goddamn reason. Fucking thing.
You believe the timing of that, right. As
I go back to it. So where were we though?
Oh, he was, he was a barber.
He put under or fucking
sometimes I we get,
we would get our socks. Smith
step, the like gym socks.
So it is possible. No, no, no.
But the second I want to put them
on and went halfway up my foot,
I think these are yours with this guy.
It's a viable option for him to walk
around all day with his fucking lady.
All right. Um, I wake up later and I
looked, I looked for the sock drawer.
Top drawer, right. Dropped
or right is what he's saying.
And I find this list with
about 20 to 30 names on it. Oh.
And this guy brought this up and he
goes in, my name is near the bottom.
I missed that the first time
I read it. So thank you. Good.
A good looking out there on Twitter.
Um, some of check marks on them.
It's Cetera.
That's okay.
I asked her about it a while and while
she was initially up, it's upset.
It turns out to be her fuck list.
She made it after we got together
with some friends drunk one night.
She then admitted to being somewhat of a
whore. Her words, not mine before we met,
but assures me that she
hasn't done anything since
she met me with anyone else.
I do believe her but I totally blew up
on her and we haven't been talking for a
few days. I also look a bit creepy as
to why I went through her drawer. Uh,
it Wa it wasn't an envelope.
I need help.
I need help on this one
was snooping around.
No,
but this is the thing.
You are a creep from snooping until you
find something cause then you have the
APP. Well we'll maybe see, I knew I
should have looked. I just felt something.
You could just be a total straight up
creep looking just cause you're a creep.
But if you find something you can
get out of it. So when he goes,
I need help on this one. Do
I apologize? She already has.
Do I just say fuck it and forget about it?
What's knee his take on this?
Now this is something I want to add in
here that I missed the first time he said
his name was near the bottom.
It doesn't mean that this list
is in chronological order.
I know, I'm just saying,
but it also could be.
It could be or it could not be.
Sometimes it's just like in the
order in which you just remember.
Well then shouldn't she say
his name first? If she even
remotely gave a fuck. Oh,
is she was drunk with her friend.
It's not like she's,
she's going for accuracy here.
What are you fucking Matlock?
You have like every defense fence for
this person. All right, cool. Let's,
let's say you are take, I'm going to shut
the fuck up. Isn't that why I'm here?
Yeah. Thank you very much. But
I'm here to always be an asshole.
But um,
there's something slightly creepy and
mildly psychotic about making fuck list.
However, a lot of girls have done
them. I've certainly done them.
It's just a thing that you do because
you've got this voice in the back of your
head saying you made them leave with,
who was it?
You know? It's just, I've never even
done that. I just go on my head.
I go a fucking cam. Cathy, Susie,
fucking that chick with a Jello
shot. Well, girls let to make lists.
We like, we like writing things down like
to journal and why is that what it is?
So it's not really in like
a a fucking horror thing.
It's just like you're going to the
Navajo as she, and she means she was,
had went through a slutty
face on a Horay flays phase.
She should get the terminology right
unless she was in fact of what's the
difference between a slutty phase in a
hoary face is someone who just likes to
sleep around and sleep with a lot of
different people and have a good time.
A whore is someone who is fucking
people to get something out of it.
That's a horse. That's the
difference. Wow. That's what
I think. Yeah. I actually,
I don't think I can argue
with that assumption of who
worry about being a slut.
There's something funny
about being a whore.
Okay.
All right. I just got lost in
that one. Yeah, it got deep.
Uh, but you know what I think, I
think you should let it go. I mean,
it wasn't an envelope.
Come on, leave it alone.
But he saw it and he's,
he's right to feel he's right to feel a
certain kind of way about it because if
I found, wait a mail list or
notebook or whatever it is,
you have all of your cock
in an envelope to me,
seems like it's a work in progress.
If she scribbled it down on a cocktail
Napkin and then threw it away,
or even it was crumpled up in her genes,
as they say in my,
that's Spanish for genes. Genes.
That's the way they say it.
And I was fucking saying it back to
it going geed and they kept saying,
I was saying genes wrong and you're
a Rosetta stone. He's the guy.
That would be the funniest thing that
you've done the cm. You know what?
When I'm bilingual, you wake me, I'm
going to bilingual, I'm gonna give,
I'm gonna become filthy bilingual and
you wait till the shit that I'm saying
that you don't even fucking
understand when we're in the wreck.
I look nothing to it. Of course should
do with your fuck list. All right.
Wait a minute. The fact that the
fact that it's in an envelope, right?
It's in a fucking envelope.
It's just keeping it private and keep out.
Yeah, because it was so,
this is what I'm really,
you're going to call that a document.
Your Dick w nine form the fuck outta here.
To me,
this girl is, she's not done
fucking yet. Okay. This,
this is and what's the deal with
some of them have checkmarked.
Some of them don't. That's either a
performance thing. Yes. Look at that face.
You can't see the face you just made.
That's either a performance thing.
That could be a lot of things.
That could be,
these are the ones that really
put it on me up the ass.
These will be the ones that I really
liked. These are really the ones,
the ones I like blue, whatever.
Who knows? Did she not have a, um,
a guide at the bottom? Did he check
for that while he was snooping around?
They look for the fucking,
you know,
bibliography to go back to cross reference
with those check marks mean stay out
of the drawer and the private notes.
Creepo wait a minute.
No, he went on the drawer to get socks. I
get it. Can I just say something though?
What? Uh, I don't know that if a woman,
it really has the right to tell
a guy not to snoop. Why is that?
Because of your guys' history. But
then again, wait a minute. Wait,
am I three of what? I'm just snooping you
guys all do it. All right. But then, but,
but that kills my argument
because that would be like a,
then I should have no right to give you
shit for fucking around because guys do
it too. So that, that, that argument's
stuck. All right. So I think so what,
so what do you think is, what should
this guy do? Should he apologize?
Should what is, should he
apologize and let it go? Move on.
How exactly she apologized.
Said, listen, I'm sorry.
I went to get a pair of your Chris Everett
shock and I found your fuck list and
then I got upset about
it. Yeah, I'm sorry.
And like blew up at you about
it cause she up. By the way,
why isn't my name is that
guy brilliantly mentioned.
Why isn't my name at the bottom
of the or the top of the list?
It's not chronologically. You're
just throwing down names. Maybe.
Maybe she started off being like,
okay, who was the first guy?
And then she went down the list and
then she got things got thrown in there.
It doesn't matter. It doesn't
matter. She's with him now.
So stop focusing on the you.
Can I ask you a question?
Isn't it weird that she just has this
like a fucking serial killer as like this
trophy?
That's why.
That's why I said it's weird and mildly
psychotic that she has a fucking list.
We, but a lot of girls do it. I have done
it. It's one of those things that you do.
So you're sharing,
you're weird and mildly psychotic.
You speaking out of both sides of
your mouth here. I'm not, I'm not.
You don't think it's weird and mildly
psychotic to do that? Yes. I admit,
but then you're saying put up a lot
of women do it with a lot of people do
something. It doesn't, it doesn't it
become mainstream and not be be psychotic?
I guess so. I mean maybe it's more
normal than you think, but it's,
it's a little weird to,
I mean,
unless you're trying to trace back like
an STD or something like that then,
but people do it all the time.
That's another reason for possibly the
check thing. I wasn't itching with him.
No. He should just be like, listen, I'm
sorry I freaked out. Let's just move on.
You know what I mean? Like if there's
a bigger issue, what should she said?
She's already apologized to him. He
said, what would you, what do you think?
I'm sorry. I think she said fuck list.
Yeah, I was drunk with my girlfriend.
We made a little list and
I'm, I'm, I'm sorry. I,
she admitted that would make somebody
feel uncomfortable if she found it.
She would feel fucked up about it.
I would feel fucked up,
but I wouldn't want my girl being
out there with all her friends.
Man, I fucked this guy. I sucked his dick.
So guys and girls they sleep
with and then I come walking.
Yeah, but it's different.
Why? Why? I'll tell you why.
Why didn't you just say it like
that? Why? I'll tell you why.
First of all, physically we're
doing the fucking, Oh God,
this fucking argument.
Yeah. Yeah. And secondly,
a guy has a right to brag about getting
laid because for us it's a fucking skill.
You can go out any night of the week
and walk into a bar and be like, hey,
who fucking wants it? Yes. That's exactly
what we can do. You could get a fucking,
you could get a three on one on a God
damn fucking pool table if you want it to
a guy.
I don't give a fuck what he looks like
unless he's a fucking movie star and
they're just throwing themselves at him
and then even then they're going to try
to get fucking knocked up.
Take the old Turkey based or to
the use condom and then fucking,
you know that move the NBA move. Huh? I
don't know that. You don't know that move.
You don't have that on
your fucking lawyer.
I know. The reason, the
reason why a woman is a whore,
it's this.
I still a bit about it.
It's like a fat guy eating an ice cream
in public where he's like, oh cool,
I'll go to, if you do it, nobody cares
when I do so Google wouldn't fit. Fuck,
because it's gluttonous.
It's gluttonous.
Your guys' pursuit of sex takes
absolutely no skill whatsoever other than
other than four,
and I'll say it again.
The only thing you have to worry about
is which one's the rapist. Once you,
once you get, once you get
past that, it's just a field,
the dicks.
Maybe that's why you have guys make lists.
Whoa, whoa. Dang.
You're an idiot. Idiot. That
was, listen, a lot of my show,
very ignorant.
A lot of my shit is deliberately ignorant,
but there's a nice point in
there somewhere, which is what?
Like a little little rose booboo.
Um,
we know where my point is.
My point is the reason why we don't
fucking respect the fact that you guys go
out and do it is because
it takes no skill.
Because guys will fuck anything
that moves basically. Okay.
You want even, but even the fact
that we will fuck everything.
Anything that moves, we still got to
fucking do a little tap dance before.
Yeah,
look at you.
[inaudible] I'm old enough to realize
when you get that look on your face,
even if I'm making a great point,
you don't want to fucking hear you
already have your mind made up.
You know what it is.
You don't have a comeback to this other
than to sit there with your stupid
eyebrows doing whatever
they're doing right now. It
is true. You know, you don't,
you remember that time when I
was trying to explain to you,
this is a great story.
I'm going to tell them and tell the
podcast people this because I'm so sick of
looking at your funny story.
One time were in a bar, right?
And we were talking about whatever,
what it was like to be
a guy and all that shit.
And I was sitting there telling
her, you know, to, to get laid,
you know you got to have fucking, oh
you said, you know guys. Oh my God.
They used to just say the dumbest
things to me. That's what you said.
I said rarely. I go,
let's flip the tables.
Let's pretend I'm in control
and you were over there. Oh boy.
Come make them to hit on me and
you want to talk about bombing.
So she sitting there just with her
fucking nonexistent game. Like, Hey,
I theory gencon had drinking your glass
there and I love games and I was being a
total fucking jerk to you. And
at one point you go, you just be,
you just making this difficult on
purpose. And what did I say? I said,
welcome to my world.
I say,
and the whole bar ware Uno,
uno,
you start high fiving the birds.
That's what should have happened.
If I was miked up that what happened?
Oh Shit.
Z now you're doing is mopping the great
point that I made because you know your
rock dog, you fucking plot throw
it. It's difficult, isn't it?
When I was being a fucking jerk,
thinking, isn't that the craziest feeling?
Like what the fuck do I say?
How do I get into this?
That's what guys have to learn how to do.
You guys don't have to do that.
All you have to do is come there
to know how to flirt. I get what?
Come there with half your titties,
hanging out and sit there like the hats
is fucking slowly putting a straw in
your mouth. No suggest things. A whole
like seductive technique. You know?
It's like being charming
and funny and sexy.
Putting your hand on his forearm for
just a second and then taking it away.
And this isn't some like fucking cosmo
list of how to get a guy interested in
you. I'm just saying that wasn't
a cosmo loose. That was, that was,
that is something that I learned. That's
something, that's something I learned.
What putting your this girl one time
when we finally fucking hooked up,
you know, I as always, I was stunned
that it happened and then she was like,
fucking a, what did she say? How
did you not know? I liked, you know,
it's like we can have a fucking say. Then
she goes, I put my hand on, she goes,
I put my hand on your arm. And like
that to her was a sign of, yeah,
I want to have sex with you.
Well know that that's true,
but she liked me that she
was interested in. Okay.
Like the physical contact thing.
Okay.
I guess so you seem pretty confident
when you were hitting on me.
US because I had been bombing for years.
Okay.
No, I got, yeah, you get to, you get
to the point. We don't give a shit.
If I had to do it now, ah, forget it.
It'd be like taking five
years or six years off of
fucking standup. Yeah. I mean,
I feel like my flirtation dimension,
I'm old and balding like that.
That doesn't help either,
but I am making some money.
I am making some money so that
that trumps a lot of shit.
That's like me wearing a little hoary
dress. If you come fucking walking in with
money, what do you mean at, first
of all, I'm making money now.
It's not like you're walking around
dripping in diamonds and Rolex watches and
stuff and driving. You know a
Porsche where you read, I have money.
You're walking in there and I go out
of 50 Boston's sports related. CSUS,
I you have.
Okay.
When your socks pulled up
and your old man shorty like,
like you look like the
fucking little league.
Okay. You're not exactly the
screaming sexy money guy. Okay,
so this whole idea, oh, I make
money now. So now the pitches,
the bitches be loving name. No
one knows you having money. Okay,
seriously.
Well maybe that's my little whore
repelling. There you go. Dress
little league coach.
If you have money and you want to keep it,
that's what you do.
And then every once in a
while you go out and I,
I wouldn't even know what to wear.
I would watch an old r Kelly video.
Am I supposed to have like not have it,
have a tie on,
but have some sort of chain with my face
on it? Is that what it's supposed to do?
I don't know. One of these
days, needy. I'm going to,
I'm going to go down to fucking
Hollywood boulevard or sunset.
We're all those whores or walking around
wrestling. You keep threatening.
You're going to go down.
You're going to go down to the w hotel.
That's what it is.
You're going to go down Martha,
the Debbie
and have it all these young girls
asked me where the bathroom is.
Right.
I don't work here. I'm actually here
to intermingle with the opposite sex.
No, listen to. I act my fucking
age. All right. I'm not,
even if you were to fucking dumped me,
there's no,
I wouldn't go down to the fucking w.
What would you do?
I'd go none of the wine bar where all
that dusty divorce pussies. I just,
except my lot in life.
Oh, can we talk about how there's
no woman a cougar? And I said it's,
they're not cougars if they're
the same age as you. Oh
No, she, she wasn't hitting on me.
What do you mean who was she was a nun
when she hitting on somebody young.
Who are we talking about?
You said to me,
Oh,
we were out the other night and the is
the cougars came up and talked to us and
I said, oh, girls and all they were up.
I said, they're not cougars. If they say,
do you realize a female
cougars are your age?
The ones they call cougars are your,
I don't judge them by their rate.
So for you to say Cougar is Mason,
no science. Those are your peers.
I don't judge them by their age.
So then why'd you call him cougars?
Cougars allowed age. The
lack of elasticity. Fucking
they're dead.
Titties were like when
they pull their pants up,
like the titties were behind their belt.
Okay. They will fall. They were a mess.
You, you know, I'm like, one of
them was actually cool and the uh,
she was cool.
She was actually like hot for her
age and still fucking working out.
But she was like beyond the expiration
dates, you've actually said, hey,
you look good. She goes, thank you.
Thank you for noticing the
fucking attitude you would
like him to have 25 years
earlier. Right. So she was
cool. The other one was a mess.
I told you she kicked me in the fucking
leg. No. Yeah, like three times.
Right in the Shin.
Cause I made fun of her because
she was just an obnoxious that Kay,
we're thing over here.
I was hanging down.
I'm not gonna mention the person's name,
but I've ran into a comedian and we were
sitting down and they came walking by
man. So comedians, you know, we fucking
made fun of. Next thing you know,
they're sitting down and it was, it
was horrific. The second they sat down.
So the one was cool, the other one
was an asshole. What did I say to her?
I didn't comment on our age that did
something. And she had these big,
those big stupid fucking platform horse
shoes on that they're all wearing now.
Right.
And she fucking kicked me with his like
hit him with a block of wood and for
some reason it didn't hurt.
She hit me like three fucking times and
I just kept laughing at her and then
security came over. The whole thing
took like 90 seconds. She had that,
that's not a cigarette and
ges for fucking India. It is,
it is what it is. Come on. She came up,
she was in that window. Nini, she came up,
it was just herpes.
That's when she came up.
I think if she, if she had like a
CB that would be her handle. Um, oh,
one of the last thing I want to, I want
to ask you just to get you going again.
Yesterday we went to, we
got some barbecue. Yes. Um,
and we would drive it back and there was
the name of this store called peekaboo.
Peekaboo. I want to do with
that store is, and I go,
it's probably kids clothes and then
you're like, yeah it is kid clothes.
And then I said,
what if it was closed for those people
who are full grown adults but want to act
like babies before you go off on them?
There's this group of people,
Opie and Anthony exposed me to this.
Uh,
they would show him that
where they fucking a, it's,
they were adults and they don't want to
grow up and their mothers like 60 or 70
and they're like 35 in a
playpen wearing a diaper guy.
I go, I can't, oh my
God, stop. Stop. I can't,
I can't deal with that.
What's wrong with that?
I refused to ever be okay
with that lifestyle and I'm
a very tolerant person if
it was your son, but I no, no, no,
no. It's not going to be my son.
What if I find that whole thing?
So repellent,
pretend I'm your and you're wearing a
diaper and you want me to breastfeed you
and rocky back and forth and
have you put or whatever. Mark,
breastfeed and all that shit. No, get
up. Get a fucking job. You'll Weirdo.
So grows and no,
I refuse.
I refuse to be okay with the adult
baby. Trend, but if he had a job,
he had a job, but he, that's when,
that's just how he rolled
when he was in the house,
like he chilled and he just wanted to
come out of the couch and lay in your lap
and have you like tickle his tummy? No,
I mean, as he played with the mobile,
fine,
people can do whatever they want in their
free time and if they're not imposing
it on other people, I guess that's their
right. I mean, I know what to do that.
How many guys when you accept somebody,
but I don't accept it. I don't, I mean,
I have to say though,
people should do whatever they want to do,
but I just find it's so creepy and just
wrong to be crawling around and cab.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. What
would you do? Fucking weird.
What would you do? Your son, he,
you know, he, he took shop class,
he thought was going to be a carpenter,
but the only reason why I did it was so
he could build himself a giant crick and
then he was in there one day,
came home.
It's like Eddie standing there standing
up in the crib wearing a diaper and a
shirt that doesn't quite meet his diaper.
Oh,
with his hands on either
side of the rails going
no. Am Abby had, oh, I wouldn't be
okay with that. Be like with a beard,
right. Is there, there's,
there is a problem and we need
to get you help because why?
Why is this your escape like by
acting like a baby? I don't know.
Nope. Nope. Nope, nope. Nope.
Not into it. Don't like it.
Don't want to see it.
What if,
what if he went to,
I got help and everything was totally
fine but the only side effect was he still
wore,
he wore an adult feety
pajamas onesy and it was baby
blue. I can live with that. I suppose
what I just, you know the sound that a,
once he makes on hardwood floors,
adults acting like babies is weird to me.
It's just like,
I don't like girls who like to be like
these little girl princess is all the
time where they're like obsessed with a
hello kitty and they want to like be a
princess and like ponies and cupcakes
and this like that, that you know,
making yourself a child like a,
yeah, most of them are according
to the doctor drew show,
they got molested and then you
just sort of stopped there.
Like whatever age they're acting like
they're at something chromatic happened to
them. Oh, well I know the age old.
Don't know about that. I just mean like,
no, that was actually what was
actually when I did his show up.
Girls would call and be like, Lna
Raping Jackie, Jackie, me. Like,
like what happened to me yesterday?
Okay, we're almost up to a half hour.
This was only supposed to
be like 10 minutes. Okay,
well really quickly doing an entirely
different pocket, but really quickly,
remember I said yesterday
I went into that store and,
and that you don't shut up the,
I saw that little white fluffy dog,
one of those little tiny white
curly fluffy dogs running
around. I was like, oh,
how cute. And the girl in the shop goes,
that's waffles. And I went, oh, waffles.
Okay cute.
And she call icon that cause he looks
like a waffle and I she stress out waffle
like that.
Yeah.
While Paul and I looked at the dog
and I looked at her and I said,
is that what a waffle looks like to you?
And she goes, well now I just be like,
he reminds me of a waffle.
Like he really more looks
like a sheep or a lamb,
but I call them muffles and I just walked
away because I can't deal with that
because I just feel like you're trying
to be like this cute little nonsensical
girl.
And it's like,
why do you feel the need to like
dumb yourself down like that?
It's like girls need to be held to a
higher standard than that and not try to
like cute their way into things or change
their voice when they're asking for
tea. Yeah. Ernie, sorry, can I make
it, I'm so sorry. Can I like it?
Like an ice tea thing
is like don't do that.
Don't feel like you have to be
a baby to get what you want,
or that's what I say. Put Your
titties away. Not Standing yet.
It's just being a fully formed
adults being an adult. Okay.
We're going to end right now. Can you just
please do, do her saying waffles again?
Wow. Fucking horrific.
All right. There you go.
There's the answer to your question
and thanks for the guy on our Twitter.
Let me know that the major thing that I
missed at that dude wasn't even at the
bottom of the list. All right?
Not necessarily calm, logical.
We got it fucking Matlock
the whole fucking way.
I knew you were going to defend fender,
her, whatever. All right.