Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcasts for Monday,
February 17th, 2014. How's it going?
How are you?
Are you enjoying this podcast so far?
I'll tell you if you're
listening to it on Monday,
Monday the 17th, I am
actually a man the fuck. And
that's why the podcast is out.
Um,
as you guys like to think
early or on time, I should say,
it's early in my world.
All right. It's early.
Um, yeah, I'm on my way back to, uh,
back to the east coast to do a wonderful
run of shows starting Tuesday night
with the second annual Patrice.
So comedy benefit,
all money after the expenses.
Of course,
we do have to rent the place out after
we paid back for renting out the fucking
bar. Yeah. All monies goes to
basically all the people that, uh,
were in Patricia's life that
he was supporting, you know,
his mom, his wife, and on,
you know, stepdaughter and all that
stuff. So it's a wonderful thing. Um,
if you didn't get tickets, uh, we're
going to do it again next year.
We're going to do it every year. And
I know a lot of people like, well,
why does she have a fucking
donation button online?
Because I'm learning about
this shit. I'm learning. Okay.
Eventually every year it'll get bigger.
Maybe we can do two shows one year.
I don't know. Okay. I'm
new to the benefit thing.
I hope I don't have to do.
And another benefit for anybody
else that I know in love. All right,
so there you go. That's
the, those are your,
those are the answers to your questions.
And I know that a bunch of people are
gonna try to be helpful and it show me how
to set something up through a,
you know,
I'm trying to raise money for my buddies,
loved ones.com or whatever.
I'm not going to be able to figure it out.
All right.
I am.
I am anti technology unless it is trying
to save people's lives or the lives of
animals, nature. I don't mind that stuff.
But as far as all these fucking apps,
you can stick them on a ball,
turned them up sideways and shove
straight up Y'all candy. And no, sorry.
Had a rush of wrestling.
Fucking flashback. Dude.
I just was trying to check in for
my flight. That's all I was doing.
Just an old freckled fuck on the computer.
All I want to do is check in.
All I want to do is Roma Zoom.
Zoom.
I didn't want to do is find
what airline I'm flying.
It's all, when does it leave?
Oh yes. That when it leaves.
While I'll be sure to be there before it
takes off. All right, so what do I get?
I get some fucking email from these
goddamn cunts and I can't access by
itinerary unless I sign up for their APP.
Tripcase,
these mother fuckers just emailed me back.
Okay.
You're almost there. Verify your
email with TripCase. Go Fuck Yourself.
Yeah,
dude,
so I can basically,
I can't view when my plane takes off or
lance because now I have to download of
fucking app to say,
you know,
Eastern Airlines leaves your flight
leaves at fucking 11 in the morning and
arrives at 7:00 PM why do I
need an application for that?
Can somebody from this new world of fat
children where you don't go outside and
you play your video games and you sext
one another in the fucking six grade.
Can one of you now not, not at all.
Let's get out of that fucking world.
Could somebody of age
fucking tell me why in God's
name I would need this app.
I don't like the fucking word APP.
Download our APP.
Do you have our APP? I
literally, I have to just,
just to find out when my
fucking plane takes off.
I had to fucking download this thing.
They wanted my,
they wanted me to sign in
with my email and my password.
So now the console over there have
the fucking password to my email.
Like I, I'm, I don't, I don't understand
that. What do I need a password?
How do I know everybody at TripCase
is, is, is on the fucking level.
You don't,
if you're not trying to figure out how
to grow a kidney and a dish like a k and
you're not out there trying to fucking
prolong the life of a Walrus, you know,
I guess I'm guilty of it too.
What do I do?
What do I do to hurt the environment?
What just what do I do?
I take 40,000 flights a year.
I'm back to using Pam instead
of putting in the skillets,
you know, goes my wife wore me down.
Does Day why you just don't use Pam?
Okay,
fuck that bitch. You fucking
up the ozone layer. You know,
I try to be like that. That does it.
That doesn't work. That doesn't work.
When you live with somebody, you know,
at some point you just gotta be like,
alright,
you know,
I'm sure there'll be plenty of ozone
left for my life as we sit here in the
middle of this heat wave.
Um,
anyways.
Okay.
So I had to just bug somebody who's in
the middle of our weekend to tell her,
can you just copy and
paste what airline I'm on,
where I'm going and when can you do that
so and I don't have to go to TripCase
and download their fucking app?
Yeah.
Jesus [inaudible] is it really the
fault of the people at TripCase? Hey,
God bless him.
You know what?
They could've gone and fucking
work for somebody else, but no,
they all sat together and they sold
their skateboards and they and they,
and they made this company. God dammit,
they're trying to make their money.
What else are they supposed to do? We
don't make anything else in this country.
All right? We basically, we plant
and grow weed and we create apps.
That's what we do in this country and in
the middle of it we eat a lot of bugles.
Okay. This is from what? The people
outside of America. All right.
If you haven't been here.
And other than that,
we make great music and great movies
that you guys all then go and rip off you
bunch of fucking hacks.
Jesus Christ.
Has there been any fucking
original programming that
didn't come out of America?
I mean, it's absolutely
ridiculous. I mean,
the failed attempt of Ricky Gervais' and
those guys who did the original office,
like they did know that we had
the followup in development.
Come on England,
you're better than that.
You fucking better than that.
You went from an empire to that ripping
off our shows that we haven't put out
yet. But you know we're putting them
out. Fuck you with your cup of tea.
Who's this? Oh, he hit that
new stupid fucking ring.
Right? Like I'm on an
island, but I'm not. Oh,
shut up.
How do you get it to stop?
I had to download the new fucking
whatever cause my phone stopped working.
The latest. Well, it's like the fucking
iPhone. We're fine. It's unbelievable.
I stand on a fucking mountain.
I can talk to somebody that
hadn't froze to death yet.
Why do I need it to be better?
Why does it have to be made?
I don't want to, I don't want to
update anything else anymore. Okay.
I'm done updating. I'm done with apps.
I'm done with all of this fucking shit.
Like I said,
unless it literally is affecting my
ability to live a healthy fucking life.
I don't give a fuck about your APP.
You brushed your teeth.
Have you downloaded our APP?
It'll really show you how to get
in between your teeth. Really,
the fucking dentist can't tell me that.
You know what,
what, what, what are you supposed to do?
All the factories left back in the day.
You'd be in some auto auto worker place,
making a fucking fan.
Jesus. Boop, boop, boop, boop,
boop. Oh, hello, Mr [inaudible],
welcome to your cell phone. All
right, let's just shut this off.
You know what I like about it?
And it's actually weirdly upbeat,
which I think goes along with my fucking,
you know,
balances out my country behavior.
Um,
speaking of the dentist,
I went to the dentist this week Boto
Dodo do it and I sat in the chair,
but the blue boop, boop,
boop mother fucker. Gabe.
Um, I laid down in the chair, whatever,
shut the fuck a chair and I got
what's known as a deep cleaning,
you know, like six months ago or
whenever July was. What's that?
Eight come on egg heads.
How do you look at the calendar?
I'm sure it's in some beautiful
mind way. [inaudible] 72 days. Like,
um, actually it wouldn't be, that's
over a year. Three or 64 days in a year.
Really. All right. Anyways. Um,
okay.
Yeah. So I was supposed to get this,
I don't know. I got my teeth cleaned,
I don't know about a year ago this time.
And then I went back to the
dentist over the fucking
don't, when are you putting
your fucking boat in the water?
Come over there with a pack
of fucking cause light toad.
Scrape it off the fucking bod I coast.
Um,
and I guess I'm on my last
trip to fucking the dentist.
Okay.
To fucking the dentist.
Um,
I agreed to get this deep cleaning,
deep cleaning,
Ron Jeremy Stars in deep clean it. I, um,
I agreed to have this fucking
thing done and uh, you know,
I don't listen to people.
All right. I don't, I look,
I'm sort of looking at you and I'm
nodding. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sounds good.
Sounds good. Just stop talking.
Leave me. I want to get out of here.
So I come back in July and rather
than the lady who cleans my teeth,
there's some dude sitting there with
this smock on and he goes, all right,
do you want us to numb you up a,
we've got a numb you up is what he said.
And I went, Whoa, whoa. What
are we? I thought it was just,
he had to get a cleaning.
We get pulling teeth out. He goes, no.
You said last time that you wanted
to come in for a deep cleaning.
Right. And I was just like, all right,
well look, how long is this going to take?
You said like 90 minutes. I'm like,
I don't have time for that shit.
I thought this was going to be like 45.
I said, I didn't say shit, but I said,
listen, I, you know, I
have other stuff to do.
I have drums to play.
I might go play hockey,
I might go fly a kite because
I am a 45 year old child.
I have things that I have to
get to. So they go out, right.
Whoa, cool man. We know we're
not trying to hassle you man.
Just reschedule. And I said,
you got it, you got it,
doctor smoky smoke and I'll see you later.
That tootsie lady and I walked out and
I've been trying to get back to do it and
I just, you know, I traveled all
over the place. I got married.
All this fucking shit happens.
So now,
now I finally go in for the thing.
I go when I say, all right,
let's do this. So I go, okay,
so you've got to know me up. And
he said, well, it's option. I go,
what do you mean it's optional? Well,
some people know they get numbed up,
other people don't.
I'm taking basically a drill he thing and
I'm going in between your teeth and it
can kind of irritate your gums and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. And I said, well,
do I need to get numbed up? And he said,
well, personally I don't do it. So I say,
I will fuck it. Let's, let's see how it
feels. Let's see how it feels. Right.
So I gotta tell you this,
unless you have like, you know,
your teeth are sensitive to cold.
Do you have like a little bit
of a nerve involvement? Um,
I'll give you a pass on that, but people
get numbed up for that. You know what?
I'm going to try and to talk shit here,
but cheer a bunch of pussies.
Was it irritating?
Yes.
Was it something I would
like to be feeling every day,
every moment of the waking day now,
but was a screaming bloody murder and
not at all. It was fine, you know,
it was great when I walked out.
I didn't, my face wasn't Numb,
you know?
I like that bill Cosby bit. I would
cry. Ain't getting habit. Can Be, Hey,
I saw bill Cosby this week. I saw him,
he was walking right down the street.
Now I saw him a out in that,
the Pasadena Civic Center play House,
whatever they called it.
And uh, it was unbelievable.
The lovely Nia took me there for
Valentine's Day. Took me out. Um,
first of all,
that's the first time I've been out on
Valentine's Day in years because knee is
cool as shit. And I just
said, listen to stupid.
It's just stupid to go out on this night.
You guys know the steel.
Maybe there's somebody knew
somebody from OCI. Uh, not, oh,
she come thinking about who scored
all the goals there. What the fuck?
Ah,
Christ they can't Sochi
somebody in Sochi. Right? Hey,
how about a fucking round of
applause for Bob Costas? You know,
toughen it out.
Jesus Christ,
putting the glasses on every day that,
that, that infection got worse in his eye.
Then it jumped to his other ride.
They just kept pulling the camera back,
started up with a, they had like a fucking
three quarter shot by the end of it.
He was like on the other side of the
studio, they will pull back so far.
And finally just said, I was
literally by the last night I saw him,
I was just like, dude, he should just go
home. Just fucking get it. Say Fuck it.
You know, I've, I what, you're not
going to call me for the next Olympics.
Matt Lauer is going to come in here and
kill it so hard that you're not going to
hire Bob fucking costus.
I've been around since the Aba.
Go Fuck Yourself. I'll see you guys in
two years. And then he finally left.
I think he left good for him, good
for him, but he toughed it out, man.
He toughed it out. So anyways, um,
so I'm on my way to a over to Pasadena,
which is where a doctor Cosby show.
My respect to you was
performing and a dude,
I got a suit and tie on everything.
It's,
it's obvious because it's Valentine's
Day, three reasons, Valentine's Day,
I'm seeing, you know, out of respect
for Nia. And then also, you know,
I'm seeing Cosby. And then lastly, I buy
these fucking suits and I never wear,
I wear them once, put a gun to my head
and I do five minutes on a talk show.
Hope I don't fall off the stage,
you know,
which is the only way anybody's going to
see you're set on a fucking talk show.
Now if you do stand up,
if you kill nobody sees it.
If you fall off the stage,
you get dick falls out of your pants,
it's going to get 100 million
hits. So anyways, I have all these,
these suits from my
numerous TV appearances. Um,
and uh, I'm like, I got to
wear these motherfuckers.
So I was driving over there and uh,
I could not believe the
traffic and I can't believe,
oh, I don't believe, I don't believe the
couples put themselves through that shit.
Why would you do that? Don't
do that to yourselves. Okay.
There's a couple of fire and I know
you got what you guys are saying.
You only bill, you fucking say
this every week, but fuck you.
I saw the traffic out there.
Obviously nobody's listening to me.
What you guys can,
I'll tell it this way because you
guys already know this shit can,
can you tell other people?
Okay,
I would, you know if I can
accomplish anything in my life.
If I could just sabotage
that fucking holiday,
this guy to be like,
I was just going to say the anti holidays,
Valentine's Day, then that becomes
a fucking crowded mess. Okay.
There's a number of gatherings that you
do not have to participate in and you
can immediately without making a dollar
more an hour increase the quality of
your life. All right? You don't
need to go to super bowl parties.
I already told you how to get
through that. Now Valentine's Day,
you don't have to fucking go out
already told you how to do that.
Saint Patrick's Day.
Stupid fucking stupid.
Go out on the 16th going out on
the 16th I know you think of,
what about the 18th well,
everybody's yakked in the bar and no
matter how much chlorhexidine the use,
you still smelling that stomach acid.
Okay,
sorry ladies who are listening to this.
You go out on the 16th all right.
Unless the 16th is a Friday
night cause then they,
everybody's going to be
drinking all weekend. Whatever
you do. If that's the case,
go out on the Wednesday. As
you know, I was fucking dumb.
They don't even have Saint
Patrick's day in Ireland.
They don't even know who the guy is.
They don't even wear green in Ireland.
You think everybody's over
there with an Irish sweater on,
cutting into some soap after they jumped
off a horse to let you know how to wash
your fucking taint.
They're not.
They're going to work over there dressed
like coach on cheers and they're going
into their fucking cubicles.
All right.
And they put in their hands and their
keyboards and between their knees they got
themselves a flask. All right. And that's
how you celebrate Saint Patrick's Day.
Um, anyway, so I'm on my fucking soapbox
this week. Let me, uh, let me, uh,
I'll read a little bit of
advertising media and uh,
and then, then I'll, and I'll keep,
I'll tell you the bill Cosby story. Oh,
by the way,
no more a nature's box on this podcast.
Evidently there are a bunch of babies.
They took the little snacks and
they were of course, their babies.
They give out snacks.
So I will not be saying the name of
their company anymore from here on out.
They will just be known by their new
nickname, the tree twats. Alright.
Literation has nature.
All right.
I'm suggesting some sort of
female element. I like it. Um,
all right. Dollar Shave club dough
for a couple of bucks a month.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers
amazing quality raises.
Right.
[inaudible] not only does it save
you personally a ton of cash,
it saves you from trudge into the
drug store for a pack of blades.
I always get stuck behind that person
who just realized they shit their pants
and they don't have the decency to
walk out of the store. You know,
it's like they don't understand
the toilet exists. Sorry people,
I'm out of examples.
Uh,
but now with dollar shave club for
just a couple of bucks a month.
Amazing quality razor blades and delivered
right to your door. That's right.
In case you said, is that
correct? I just said that's right.
Like I'm in your room with you.
No more wasting time and no more
getting hit up for 20 bucks.
Every time you buy razors, like
they're not a piece of crap. All right,
everybody here meaning me is getting that
dollar shave club blades and you know
what? You should too if you want
to. And here's a great idea.
Try replacing your old shaving cream
with doctor cavities. Easy shame.
Wow.
From Dollar Shave club.com trust me,
your face will thank you later.
If it could speak,
don't waste time at the drug store
behind the lady paying and Penny's.
Got To dollar shave club.com forward
slash bar or go to [inaudible] dot com and
click on the dollar shave club banner.
Keep your stress level low and your
bank account Balance High Shave time,
shave money, go to dollar shave
club.com forward slash burr and we go,
no, please personalize
areas highlighted in yellow.
I did with the shit and the pants story.
It's about as personal as it gets.
All right, stamps.com oh my God.
stamps.com like the Willie Stargell
of this lineup in its 20th season.
stamps.com everybody you've probably
heard the cost of a stamp just went up to
49 cents.
I'm sure you were in a bar in the middle
of hanging out with your friends and
all of a sudden somebody had to have said,
hey,
did you hear stamps went up to 49 cents?
Um, anyways, if you haven't,
who cares to stamps.com with stamps.com
you'll pay less for postage? Uh,
you play less than you would pay at
the post office for first class mail.
Priority Priority Express
mail packages and Moa.
stamps.com is easy to use and convenient.
You can buy and print discounted stamps,
shipping labels,
and more using your own
computer and printer.
Not only will it save
you money was was stamps.
Not only will you save money with
stamps.com by not paying full price for
postage,
you'll save valuable time too,
because you don't have to go to
the post office anymore. Okay?
If you can't figure it out,
you can do it right at home,
standing in your underwears stamps.
Dotcoms always stamps.com always
keeps the rates up to date,
so you get the exact postage you
need every time right from your desk.
Never go to the post office again.
I absolutely love this product.
I use stamps.com anytime I
send out my DVDs, my posters,
whatever I'm selling after my shows,
I'm a moron. If I can figure it out,
you can't too.
However,
right now use my last name bur
bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a $110 bonus offer
that includes a digital scale and up to
$55 free postage.
Don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else. Okay.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburbburrthatstamps.com
enter
[inaudible] B u double r.
All right,
well let's talk about the cause.
All right.
First thing I get into a, I pull up to
the [inaudible], right? And uh, you know,
it's Valentine's Day. There's a bunch of
fucking animals out there. And I'm like,
I don't want to try to find the parking
garage. I don't know where it is.
And then they, I see valet and I
like, oh, valet, fuck it. Fuck it.
I'm going to valet a Prius isn't,
you know,
a 2008 Prius with a bird shit stain,
the likes of which I haven't seen since
owning the car, right on the windshield.
I'm pulling up and I'm valet in it. And
right as I pulled up, I started thinking,
well, this is like a 3000 seater.
What if half the crowd does this?
How long am I going to be waiting? And I
was just like, oh fuck it. My feet hurt.
I'm valet. So I valet, I
walk into the theater and uh,
you know, tickets work. I asked for
an no duels, they don't have any,
so I get a fucking water and I
get some wine for my wife, right?
So we go into the theater,
beautiful theatre,
lovely theater made in the 1930s.
Right?
And we go in there and uh,
first thing I do is look at the stage
and it's the coolest thing ever.
It's like there's this little
apartment up there, full bill Cosby.
He has like a little four by four rug.
Oriental rug.
All right. No offense
to the Orient. And uh,
he has a chair and then next duty has a
little like nightstand little table with
this little,
I don't know what little cooler
that has all his drinks in it.
And then he has his little headset thing.
It's the coolest thing ever. And I'm,
so we're sitting there,
it's supposed to start at eight
o'clock and right at eight on the nose,
no opening act, no intro.
He just walks out on stage.
I was actually looking down,
I don't know what the hell I was doing
and the only reason I knew he was had
walked out on stage is because
the crowd started cheering.
And of course everybody stood
up and all that type of stuff.
And he went over and he put on his little,
uh,
his little headset thing that's like
seethrough like John Bonham's vista light
kit. And a, so you don't even notice it.
He puts that thing on and then it's like
he's sitting right next to you and the
guy and literally is,
sits down and kills for
two and a half hours,
two and a half hour. He's
76 years old, 77 this year.
Two and a half hours,
absolutely destroys his first like bit,
took a half hour
just talking about Valentine's Day and
how you got all the pressure to get,
you know, uh, you know, the, the,
the woman's something and all you get
is a card starts with that premise and
then just goes,
I don't know where he went.
30 minutes later he
brings it back to that,
to a thunderous applause break.
And I looked over at my wife and I
go, that's his first joke, half hour.
So he did two and a half hours. So I
guess that's like what he did. Five jokes.
Okay.
It was, uh, it was amazing.
And, uh, what I, I don't know,
I never seen him live like, just do a
full set and get to sit in the crowd.
And it was um,
an unbelievable honor.
It was the best Valentine's gift
day gift I've ever gotten and she's,
she always gives me something nice
and, but that was the best. And um,
it's definitely a bucket list thing.
And just to be able to sit there in the
crowd and watch and do his thing is I've
tried to do what he's done for 22
years to have that perspective,
to have the perspective as a, as
a, as a fan and an audience member.
Like it was working on like five different
levels. It was, it was awesome. And uh,
then I walked out and I ran
into like three other comics.
They know that I knew and were all
geeking out. He's two and a half hours.
Can you fucking believe that I've done,
I've done two and a half hours
my life guys, 76. It was awesome.
And then I walked out there and there
must have been 900 people waiting for
their valid cars.
So I just stood there by the
theater with a couple other comics
and we just around just giving each
other shit and talking about the business
and all that. And then just kept going
back to how amazing bill Cosby was.
So if you get a chance, it's
really cool. He's also, you know,
he just put out that special, so he's,
he's working on some new material.
So I got to see that. I got to see bill
Cosby workshopping material and you know,
you know,
and you see which ones that are already
monster bits and then you see the other
ones that are on their way. It was, I
got the hiccups now. It was, it was,
it was amazing. So, um, you know,
definitely if there's very few masters
out there that you can go watch them live,
creating live, I highly
recommend going out and, and uh,
and seeing a bill Cosby manor was awesome.
It was awesome.
And I got to wear a suit, you
know, so it was a fucking two for,
um, all right. Oh, this is something
I have to mention. Hey everybody,
do you like buying shit off my website?
Well, I got some new stuff. Um,
I did a uh,
a tour at the end of last year
right before my European tour. Um,
oh I did that. Run a dates where I
played the beacon in New York City.
I played constitution hall in DC and
then I played tower theater three
absolutely legendary venues. I still
can't believe I got to perform there.
So as always thank you to
everybody who came out. Um,
I have a limited amount of posters
leftover from that tour and they will be
going on sale I believe. Like on Wednesday
of this week, there's like 300 left.
Um,
it's first come first serve.
The posters are 20 inches
tall and 16 inches wide.
They will arrive in a shipping tube and
reading on this stuff and you know what
I am and,
and in the effort to get these things
out of my house and to give you guys more
incentive,
I autographed each one of them.
I sat at my kitchen table
and painstakingly autographed
300 posters.
It must've taken me at least 17 minutes.
My wrist is still sore. I live a very
difficult life as an artist, whatever.
I have posters, autographed posters. If
you want them, they make a great gift,
that 20 bucks plus shipping, it's
going to be autographed. You know?
And if you go to give it to
somebody and they don't like it,
you got the empty tube to smash
over their head when you're done.
And then you pick up the poster
and you get it framed yourself,
not because you like me,
just because it will always remind you
of hitting that person over the head.
You know you, you know
what's great about the, the,
the poster tube is you get the release,
like you fucking smashed
a bat over somebody's head
without having to get rid of
a body afterwards cause it's
just cardboard. You know,
if I ran a prison, I would allow
everybody to have a poster tube.
It'd be like enough with the
shanks people. All right.
Just hit each other with cardboard.
If you break it, don't worry.
We'll make some more down the office.
All everybody relax.
We'll get you some pot cookies,
you know, get you some porno.
Everybody can rub one out
at the beginning of the day.
That way nobody gets raped in
the showers. Okay. This, this is,
this is a new kind of prison.
All right?
She's everybody just fucking
relax. All right. Lucky you might,
you're not getting out.
So I don't know why you want to sit here
fighting with each other and we all get
together and we will write some
songs now. Eh, well, you know, it's,
it's, it's, it's a it up. It's what we'll
work on it. Enjoy your, enjoy your tubes.
They took it too far with the Sif. I did.
Um, anyways. All right, let's, let's get,
let's get on with the, uh, the podcast
here. So, um, I've been watching,
I've been missing all the Olympic hockey
because it's coming on at four 30 in
the morning and because
I haven't been drinking,
I've been falling asleep like
the middle aged man that I have.
Like I'm falling asleep every
night, like nine 30, 10 o'clock.
And I wake up at like six in the morning
where I could at least watch the third
period I guess,
or the end of the third period.
But it never dawns on me cause
they just woke up, you know,
this is what I have to do
before I get out of bed. Um,
and if you feed a fucked up, um,
you know, I fucked up my foot too.
I got that planner, Fisher writers
and my bass drum for trying to get,
trying to play good times,
bad times. My technique.
I had poor technique
and I don't know how to,
does anybody know how to Rehab that?
Cause every time I run or do anything
that exerts pushing off with that foot,
it comes right back. But I'm
able to kind of, you know,
roll a tennis ball letter
and my foot and I'm fine.
But like when I get up in the morning,
if I don't want to have problems,
this is what I do. All right. I wake up,
I look at the ceiling. All right. I
look over my wife and I'm like, good.
She didn't leave me. All right, the
dog hears me stirring in immediately.
I hear her, I hear her stretching
because she makes, she makes this noise.
She goes, then she stretches
again. And then I hear her,
her dog licenses shaking as she fucking
shakes her head for whatever God damn
reason.
Um,
and all of that happens is I'm looking
at the ceiling and before I take step
number one,
if you have a fucked up your,
your whatever that is there
underneath your foot, that tendon,
if you ever fucked it up,
what really fucks you over?
It's that first step in the morning.
All right.
I learned this from another
comedian who was a world champion.
And this is basically what you
do before you get out of it.
This is what I have to do.
And I've never played organized
sports and this is just, and I,
and I stretch and I still, you get
to a certain fucking age. Like I,
I literally throw out my back sleeping.
I wake up like what did I do?
Was a lifting shit. What sleepwalking? Um,
I basically,
I point my toes at my knees.
He tried to do that paint
point toes towards your knees.
I'm doing it right now and you'll
hold it there for a good 10 22nd cow,
right? One Mississippi, two Mississippi,
but you say it in your head so you
don't wake up your significant other.
Then you point your toes down at the
the end of the bed for another 10 20
seconds. He'd do that right
now. You stretched the bottom,
you fought and you stretch.
It tends on the top of your foot and
then clockwise or counterclockwise.
I know a lot of young people like
Jesus Christ. What the fuck? Well,
I got news for you. This day is
coming in your life. All right?
It's called your late thirties
early forties all right.
Then what you do is then you have your
bring your feet to normal position,
standard side by side,
like those fucking jerk offs at guard.
That thing over there in London,
and then you either go clockwise or
counterclockwise. You just make big,
slow circles and then you go
the other way a couple of times.
Then I get out of bed and I gingerly walk,
no pun intended.
I know I'm a red head and I eye twinkle
toe my way over to the bathroom and I
just make noise on that.
Jesus Christ.
I curse and stuff as I'm
walking over there. Okay.
Yeah, and then that's it. Then that's
it and then I have to go through the,
the beginning I got a stretch.
This is just so I can walk my dog down
the fucking street and not be in traction.
I'll just pathetic.
It really makes me sad
that I used to wake up.
I remember as a little
kid you just woke up,
you woke up and one of the
other siblings or was like, Hey,
you want to go outside and
fucking believe it. Yeah,
you just jumped out of bed
and just ran down the stairs.
Waffles. That fucking scenario. You
just shoved the shit you need to.
You just ran out the fucking door.
You never stretched ever.
You never throw out your back. You're
jumping over shit, fucking play,
fight and get in a real fight.
You are fine.
You are brand new right
off the assembly line.
Brand fucking new. Then after
a while, I don't give a shit.
No matter how much
fucking juices you drink,
I don't know what happens to the
attendance. They just fucking,
they shrink up after awhile. Um, all
right. I don't mean to depress you guys.
Um, you know, my latest obsession
is when it comes to cars,
like learning, learning about
cars and that type of shit is a,
I am absolutely fascinated
with differentials.
I didn't know there was oil in there
all these years. The owner cars.
I didn't know that the oil was in
there and they each got to change it.
When should you change it?
Every 30 to 50,000 miles.
I'm dying to fucking change it.
I'm dying to take that
fucking thing off the back.
I've watched enough youtube
videos to know how to do it.
I'm changing the oil.
It's easy. You just gotta.
You just gotta get one of those Torque
wrenches and know what you're supposed to
fucking put the screws back. Two pounds
per square, whatever the fuck it is.
Or is that air? I Dunno. Fuck
you. I can figure it out.
But you know what sucks on my truck,
the 68 f 100,
um,
that backing plate that usually
faces the back of the car on mine.
It's on, it faces the engine.
It's on the other side.
So the drive shaft is there.
What? That other fucking
thing. And then there's that.
So I would have to take off
all of that and drain it out.
And I know what you guys would think
and bill for the love of fucking God.
Don't do that to yourself as much as
you probably get a funny bit out of it.
Please do not do, I didn't know the
other people who just love people,
the fried and shorts or have you the
fuck you say it. They'll be like, yeah,
we'll give that a whirl.
See how that happens?
That's a fucking scary thing
to do because that's not,
that's not a an injury you can walk
away from. In other words you don't,
it's weird at that point is if is if I
did all that and I couldn't get that shit
back together,
I could still start my truck up and I
could go through all the gears and all of
that shit. Well, grant,
I've against the transmission
fluid would be Lincoln leaking out.
If I took off to fucking, what if I
took off the, uh, what's that called?
The drive shaft. If I took that
fucking thing, I'm going to do it.
Fuck you up. Tried it. I just,
I'm just fascinated with the fact that
I don't think it's ever been changed in
that there's air in there from,
it was put together in March according to
the, the, uh, the number inside the door.
It was put together in Ontario.
Believe it or not,
Ford had an Ontario plant or
something like that. And uh,
in March of 1968 and somebody close that
fucker up and that air has been trapped
in there.
And I think it's high time I released it.
I guess it's an ungodly fucking smell.
But I posted this video before,
um,
for people like me who don't know shit
about cars and are just starting to learn,
um,
it's a very intimidating part of the car
and to actually see the genius of how
it fucking works,
I'm going to post that video again
because I absolutely love it and I'll
actually show this guy from a
bleeping jeep, um, youtube, uh,
or is it bleeping
jeep.com he gets in there,
he changes the oil and he does some
other shit in there. And then, then,
then on youtube there'll be a bunch
of other fucking youtube videos.
We can actually look at all the fucking
gears in there despite it gives the
pinion gears all that shit.
You know,
I watched this guy take an
axle off and all that type of,
with the little fucking c clamp,
whatever the fuck it is. I,
it was fascinating shit.
The balls to go in that deep.
That's what I, I just have to
respect it. And speaking of respect,
even though I missed all the Games, I
watched the highlights. I just saw the,
the third period in the shootout
of the, uh, USA Russia game.
How about that fucking Tj. Oh, oh,
she, she, Tj,
TJ. Oh, she
was just basically that
are fucking shootout guy.
We just kept sending him and he
delivered every time. Jonathan quick. I,
you know what I loved about him
scoring that over is how it went.
The second he scored the,
uh,
the shootout goal that
had us beat the Russians,
he immediately turned around and he
pointed at Johnathan quick, you know,
something somebody else could have done
when they tip the pass to a linebacker
about a month ago. You know, you
can do that every once in a while.
It's nice to see somebody do
that. Um, and Phil Kessel fill,
Castle's been crushing it, the former
Brooklyn and now Toronto Maple Leaf,
who I will be seeing.
I will be going to a maple leaf
game and I also be going to a,
a Canadians Bruins game
when I'm up there and I can,
I can't fucking believe it.
I'm going to see two original six home
games and one against another original
six and the best fucking rivalry as
far as I'm concerned, over the years,
you've got to say that,
you know,
not discounting any of the year
great Detroit rivalries and so on,
that shit out west.
Um,
or even the islanders and
rangers or flyers and penguins.
He's just a fucking great
leak. Um, anyways, so that,
that tour is coming up quick.
I have a week's worth of dates back
here for like four days and then I'm in
Canada,
man and I have not drank for 20 days.
By the time you hear this,
21 days and I got to tell you something.
I am fucking miserable. I'm not
miserable. But I, I miss him,
man. I really fucking miss it. I'm
not gonna lie. I don't need it.
I don't need it. I mean, what,
what do you really need? You know,
did I need to, to buy another pair of
socks? I have other socks, you know,
I miss,
I should've never broken up with it.
I'll live with this regret for the
rest of my life. No, I'm basically,
me and Versie are not drinking
until we get to Canada.
Once we get to Canada. It's hilarious
right now. I was talking to him, I said,
listen, Paul, all right,
both haven't drank in awhile.
I've been going easy on the stoves and um,
you know,
it would be a shame if in those 20 days
we gave back everything that we gained.
And he's like, Oh yeah, dude. Yeah, yeah,
no, I, and I, and I say, yes. Listen,
I'm not saying I'm not going to drink.
I'm not saying I'm not going to smoke
a couple of Cubans, but let's just,
you know, let's try to, to
manage, you know, let's try it.
Maybe the first two days we don't drink
and then we go to the fucking maple
leaf's game. We'll have a couple of
beers and, and Paulson, the IAA. Yeah.
And then we just start laughing
because we know what's going to happen.
We know what is going to happen.
All right.
It's going to be a fucking shit show.
So all I'm trying to do is drop as much
fucking weight as I possibly can and get
into such great shape because I know
what the fuck I'm going to do itself.
It's fucking over. I'm going to do
what every one of you guys would do.
So I'll fucking judge me.
I can't wait. I can't wait.
I wake up every day, you know, I dunno.
Yeah. I feel good, but I
don't, I, I don't know.
What am I supposed to do? I have
a porch. How am I not spell?
How do you not drink when you have a
porch? It's just a, I got a rocking chair,
you know, it was easy to not
drink when I didn't have a pool.
I don't know what it
is about the portrait.
Just get out there and all of a sudden
I wa I want to fucking, I want a drink.
Um, all right. Let me do a little
more advertising. When I come back,
I'm going to talk about my add and I
want to thank everybody who's been trying
to help me with it. Now that I've finally
agreed with my wife that I have it.
All right.
Legal zoom.com everybody.
Some things like starting a business
or protecting your family with a will
aren't like your other new
year's resolutions. You can't
afford to blow them off.
Instead of less snacking
and more exercise,
put this stuff at the top of your list.
Legal Zone helps you incorporate or form
an LLC with their simple questionnaire
starting at just $99 over 1 million
entrepreneurs have done it and 90% of
customers recommend legal
zoom to friends and family.
You can also create a will at just 69
bucks or even a living trust quickly and
easily and get peace of mind and
protection. No surprise fees, no hassles,
man and no headaches.
Legal Zoom step by step process was
created by a team of experts in law and
technology.
Legal Zoom is not not a law firm,
but can connect you with the third party
attorney and provide you with self help
services from wells to
business formations,
uh, trademarks, powers
of attorney and more.
Go to legal zoom.com for even
more savings. Type in Burra, B U,
double r into the
referral box at checkout.
Don't put things off today that
you need to do for tomorrow.
Go to legal zoom.com now and use the
discount code bur bur that's legalzoom.com
discount code. Burb B. U. R. R. All
right, you got to do that. By the way,
by the way, I'm actually in the process
of doing it right now, making out a will.
You got to, you got to do
it. Cause if you don't,
you know who's going to get you
smoking jacket. The government, um,
he voice the voice.
If you're a business owner,
um, wait, you're a business owner,
but automated phone systems
and secretaries are not
in your budget just yet.
And Juggling incoming calls makes you,
it makes it hard to look
like a professional.
Here's something that will
dramatically help you more, uh,
and make you wait a minute.
Here's something that will
dramatically help you make more money.
In 2014 he voice whether you're a business
of one or 100 he voice will help you
manage all of your incoming calls
with a toll free number, dial by name,
directory and call routing tools. Your
business will sound like 1 million bucks.
Can't take a call, no problem. He voice.
We'll transcribe the voicemail
and email it right to you.
Never be caught off guard again and with
he voice you can try it before you buy
it right now.
Just for my listeners,
you get a 60 day trial to iie
voice for absolutely free.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter the
Promo Code Bill B I l l at checkout.
Take charge of your business and make
more money in 2014 go to [inaudible] dot
com and enter bill at checkout for
your 60 day free trial free trial.
That's [inaudible] dot com
Promo Code Bill. You know
it's funny with those reads,
I was actually thinking through
the first couple. I was like,
I'm doing a great job. And then all
of a sudden that voice in my head,
whenever you're doing fuck it up, and of
course you start fucking it up, TJ. Oh,
she doesn't think that shit.
Phil Kessel doesn't think that shit.
That's why he puts the biscuit
and a basket. All right.
So I mentioned I'm add last week that
I've finally given him that I fucking have
it brutally. And um, so people sent me
all these links and as far as I can tell,
other than trying harder to focus,
you got to take some drugs, man.
Um, and I looked at the list of
drugs, none of which I would ever,
ever in a million years entertain
putting myself on, you know,
destroy your brain, beat up your
liver, but oh well you focus,
be sitting there totally listening to
every word is like a drool coming out of
my mouth.
I'm one of the things,
Ritalin was one of the things
that they suggest to take.
Like who's still suggest Ritalin?
Okay.
I've seen, I've even, I
have seen the stories okay.
With all the sports and bullshit
that I watch. Uh Oh. Speaking of aid,
DD and speaking of shows that I love,
is anybody watching? True detective,
please tell me you're watching.
True detective and if you've
seen all four episodes,
I'm not going to spoil
anything for anybody. Okay.
I just have to wait for that person.
Take that their,
their hands away from the ears.
I'm not going to ruin anything
that's dangerous to drive like that.
Stop staring with your knees.
Um,
I've seen all four episodes and uh,
this past week's episode,
certain people were,
were going on and on about the way it was
shot and I think that they actually in,
which was amazing,
but that gem of a conversation
in the bar this week,
I absolutely fucking loved it.
I thought I'm,
it's very rare that I see a scene with
both characters are arguing and I feel
like they're both 100% right.
They're both 100% right in that seat.
And uh, it's just, Oh my God,
fucking Matthew Mcconaughey,
Jesus Christ crushing it.
Everybody is Reggie. And even
that get that prisoner guy,
Reggie, Reggie to do. Did this shit.
Mother fuckers do. I fucking love
that guy. That's my new show.
Everybody considering gas monkey,
they're there.
I know they were between seasons.
Do you know how depressed I am when I
get through all of the fast and loud?
I watch all of them like three times and
then I just have like my favorite ones
where they just have certain cars.
Um, what are some of my favorite ones?
I'll tell you I liked the uh,
so my favorite cars did
they done was when they um,
yeah,
which one was the,
I would say the 55 for that
they made for a mark Cuban
that that morning I just absolutely
fine what they did to that car.
Paint it all white. I absolutely
in the, in the interior,
that fucking car and the way it sounds.
Then they did another one.
They did this 1950 rocket 88 where
they do this thing where you know,
it start no Ross,
but it's not like debilitating Russ
and they just put a clear coat over it.
So you've got this bad ass mean looking
car that you can lean up against an
underneath it.
Everything's fucking brand new and it
sounds like a fucking based as they go
down the road and they
got the white wall tires.
That was another one that I loved.
Um,
okay,
what else? I even liked that
crazy station wagon with the,
that opened like a clam shell.
Yeah.
There's just been so many. I don't know
my face. And then I'll of course though,
I've already talked about this,
the wine one,
Richard tried to sell the car back to the
people for 30 grand and they knew what
the fuck he's brother comes in.
His brother wanted 30 grand and he
busted him down to 18 grand and then his
other brother comes back and goes,
he shouldn't have sold the car.
What do you want for it? And Richard was
like, yeah, I was thinking like 30 grand.
And the other guy's like, hey fuck
head. I know what you paid for us.
And then Richard just laughed and
then they settled for like 20 grand.
He still made like 1500 bucks.
I fucking love that show. I wish
they'd do more motorcycles. Um,
anyways,
plowing ahead.
So my new show now that
breaking bad's over, um,
is that show true detective?
Uh,
get in early so you don't feel
overwhelmed like I am with house of cards.
I know I have to start watching that.
Just so many great shows. Shameless.
I haven't watched one episode of that.
I got a bunch of Shit I have to get
caught up on. But um, true detective,
I dunno if it can get better than that
right now man. It's fucking awesome seat.
But add helps me look at this.
It helps me on the podcast because I just
think of something I just go off like
basically what I just did there,
I was going to start talking about my
add and all of a sudden I'm talking about
a 55 Ford, right? And then I
bring it back around. It just,
it helps on this thing.
Have an add is great when you have a
podcast because you never run out of shit
to say because everything just
fucking reminds you of something else.
You just keep going. But it my day
to day trying to get shit done.
MMM.
And also trying to
listen to somebody else.
Like everything that they say reminds me,
I just reminds me of shit other stuff
and I just start thinking of that and I
dunno,
I even have add,
I'm just unbelievably self absorbed.
It's probably a little of both that go
fuck yourselves. What do you want from me?
Um,
okay.
So anyways, yeah. Oh, don't
forget to get your posters.
I did mention that I'm
scrolling down here and uh,
also amazon.com is a great way to donate
to this podcast. You just go to the,
go to my website, [inaudible] dot
com you click on the podcast page,
you click on the Amazon App and
it just takes you to Amazon.
I get credit for sending you there. It
doesn't cost you any, any, any money.
And they kicked me a little fucking money
for a send you to there so you can go
there and buy a whisk. All right.
Uh, dude, you called it, here we go.
The the, the reeds for
this week, man. The Dude,
you called it bill,
you called it last June on your
parents on Conan O'brien. You told,
you told Conan that Paula Dean would be
back on television because she's $100
million whale.
I read today she received a $75 million
investment from a guy who won't sky
mall. She's already in talks with
a mate with major television,
neck television networks for a new
show. Greg, Call Bill Love U podcast.
Keep being you. Yeah, Dude. I mean
that wasn't, I mean that was obvious.
I just predicted that everything that has
happened before we continue happening,
uh, she's back. She's back.
I actually don't have a
problem with Paula Dean.
I think it's refreshing that she actually
said, yeah, I've used the n word.
You know what I mean?
She was honest.
Yeah.
That's really what she was guilty
up. She, she really could have just,
you know what?
I should really shut the fuck up because
I can't even remember what she did.
Okay.
Did it start with she had a slave
themed wedding. Oh, that's right.
It's just what the fuck you don't.
She's like,
is anybody watching
the haunted house show?
American horror story me
is watching that this year.
And the theme was slavery and I fucking,
I,
I can't sit there and watch that with
Nia because I'm afraid she's going to cut
me by the end of the God damn show.
And you know, was I'm like going,
I wasn't alive then.
MMM.
That's what she's like. The uh, Paula
Deen is like, uh, what's her face?
The woman from misery.
She's like the real life version
of that in that she's not like, uh,
some dead living thing. She's actually
alive and she can make cookies.
But other than that, I think her
politics are the same. Um, all right.
Female athlete of the year is a horse.
What?
Hey Bill,
hearing the story last week about the
Seattle newspaper snubbing the women's
championship reminds me of this
story from a few years back.
The Daily Telegraph naming the Australian
sportswoman of the year and it was a
horse. He's got the link right
here. I'll put this up for you guys.
2012 the year of the London Olympics
were plenty of our female athletes,
one gold and gave great
performances by our athletes.
He means the Australian ones,
they completely blew it off and they
gave it to a horse here. Here's the link.
Also ever thought of adding Tasmania to
your itinerary when touring Australia.
It's the small island state below
the mainland. If you don't know.
Got that welcoming.
We don't get much down here,
so let's make it a good one. Kind of
feel. Uh, last time you were in US steel,
you mentioned how it's sucked driving
so far to get to different places.
None of that here can cross the state
and about five hours and take in whatever
you want in between.
Yeah, if you fly, right.
Uh Oh, that's me. Oh, in
Tasmania. I got it. Okay.
Got Some Nice old theaters and
the best beers in the country.
Not only will you have a blast,
I'll save $600 flying over to see you.
A win and a win through.
Fuck that. I'll go there.
They got some old ass theater,
Jesus Christ telling
me that's not haunted.
How many indigenous people is
that fucking built on top of?
Is it made out of Didgeridoo is um,
sorry,
sorry for the Hacky
fucking Australian humor.
I haven't been there enough to give you
anything original. I'll be there. Um,
although I was upset that, that, that uh,
Bruce Springsteen played Perth and his
band played highway to hell as a tribute
to bond Scott because that's where
bond was from and he's buried there.
And as cool as that was, as much as I
loved it as an ACDC fan, I was like, fuck,
I thought I was going to be the,
the American that goes over there and
let you know that I realized that Bond
Scott is from there.
I thought I'd get a little star on my
forehead and Bruce Springsteen went over
there and took it fright from me.
All right.
I'm done with my temper tantrum.
Dethroning the bankers, dear bill,
um,
I know how much you hate,
but the banker cunts and was wondering
if you ever considered getting into
bitcoin.
The decentralized nature of the currency
creates no need for central banks
controlling everything.
I'd suggest creating a bitcoin wallet.
And playing around with the small amount
of Bitcoin to learn how the system
works. It's the most exciting
thing in technology and finance.
Since the invention of the Internet.
Love the podcast.
Thanks and go fuck yourself.
Uh,
and he's nice enough to
take to leave the Wikipedia
definition either that are Andrew
feminists. Let me know what this is.
Bitcoin is a peer to peer payment
system and digital currency
introduced as open source software in
2009 by pseudo Nima develop pseudonymous
developer Satoshi Nakamoto.
Okay.
Nakamoto.
Do Japanese people got the best
fucking names that Toshi Naca Balta.
It's a fucking killer name. Bill
burr that Toshi Naca. Malta,
a motel knock on multiple,
said Doshi Nakamoto.
What would you say that if he
scored a goal, I can't do it.
All right. Let me just continue
here. Add. It's a wonderful thing.
It's crypto currency,
so called because it uses
crypto crypto cryptography,
no Jesus, to control the
creation and transfer of
money. Conventionally, Bitcoin,
capitalize a refers to the
technology and network,
whereas lowercase bitcoins
refers to the currency itself.
MMM.
Yeah. Well, the,
the big problem with this is
it's created by human beings.
I don't think that bankers
a necessarily evil.
I just think that they have or
more evil than I am. They just,
they're in a position to absolutely
devastate everyone walking the planet.
International bankers have that ability.
But I, I really think that the more,
MMM,
I dunno, the more I read up on it and
stuff, it's just a bunch of greedy counts.
And like somebody saying right now,
the big conspiracy is that they're going
to try to bankrupt all currencies to
eliminate all wealth on the planet and
then come back with the new currency and
well, I know that they're not going
to eliminate their own wealth,
so they're going to make everybody on
the planet broke except for them and
they're going to survive. Now.
Maybe they can do it, but I don't,
how do you pull that off?
That seems like that would
have a very finite, um,
life before people were just like,
all right,
I don't know about you guys,
but there's like nine people left in
the world that can afford a three piece
suit. And it's not any one of
us 7 billion. What do you say?
We go over there and beat them with
their pocket watches. You know,
it's eventually when that happened,
I dunno.
Um,
yeah, I, I would just like to go back to
just open bartering, just trading shit.
Hey, I'll give you this shirt
for that sandwich. I got
plenty of shirts. Fuck you.
Don't want hungry again, but look at my
waistline. I look awesome. All right. Um,
I'll read up on it, sir. I'll look
up on it. Uh, I look up on it. Oh,
I'll read up on it and I'll look it up.
How about that?
I'll do both of those things. I'll
look it up and then I'll read up on it.
A lot of up going on there. All
right. Donation, currency. Hey bill,
longtime listener loved the show,
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Let's get right to the point.
Um, the person wrote Blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Before you think I'm being arrogant,
let's get right to the point you should
think about adding an another way of
donating on your website,
bitcoins. Why is that?
You have fans in places so fucking strange
that you don't even know where it is
on the goddamn glove.
Go Fuck Yourself.
I know where most places are in the
globe and I know their capitals,
at least I used to. It's in my head
somewhere. They use different currency,
which might be a problem.
Bitcoin is providing an easy way to
dismiss a commercial and easy way to
transfer wealth. Use it and welcome
to the 21st century. By the way,
I'm from Poland. It's really cold in here.
It's a second language. All right? Um,
I, I would think that if
whoever starts bitcoin,
if they don't get murdered
in the next calendar year,
then it's just started by the bankers.
Um, or they're just going to buy it up.
They'll sell out. Right? I don't know.
I'm not going to fucking start
using a new currency. All right?
I saw what happened with the euro.
I'm going to go with bitcoin.
That started by some fucking
hippie Japanese guy, or even worse,
a businessman,
Japanese guy that Jesus Christ.
You can't tell me. They're
not still upset by the, uh,
the two piece we gave them back in
the forties. Um, adopt or birth.
Dear Billy,
read Billy red white beard bur
thanks for the laughs and look forward
to seeing you soon in Calgary, Calgary,
KL,
Gorag whole category.
I'll gladly take you out with,
with a couple of buddies for some ice
hockey and a couple of nonalcoholic Bros
unless you're back on the
wagon. Yeah, let's get shit
faced and play hockey. Dude.
I'll bring in my skates.
You provide a right handed
stick and his ski Parka.
I'll play some pond PandaDoc.
Um,
in which case we'll enjoy
some Granville island.
Oh, is that some Bruce? I know. What the
fuck. Yeah, I guess I'm off off the wagon.
Granville island. See,
see what I'm saying?
You see how much weight I'm
going to gain up there? No,
but then if I played pond hockey, he'll
skate it off. Ah, genius. Anyways,
my wife and I are toying with the idea
of either adopting a kid are doing it the
old fashioned way and making a
baby ourselves. She's only 27,
so it's not like she's
incapable of making babies.
But she preferred to adopt
a Korean kid because a,
those orphan kids need home be,
she'd like to skip the crying baby phase
and see that Korean kid will make me
filthy rich one day. Jesus
Christ doing what? Um,
personally I think all
what if it's a female,
get it into golf projected they're
destroying female golf right now ladies,
they hitting off the lady teas there.
Personally,
I think all her reasons are legit,
but I'm seriously freaked that if
we give birth to a second baby,
a love that second baby more than my
Korean kid that happened to a friend of
mine who adopted and then had another
kid and was ashamed of himself that he
honestly felt more love for the second
one even though he still loved the
adopted kid. What would you do
here if you were me? Adopter,
make one yourself a two and
I can't make that decision.
And I think it's natural that you feel
more of a connection to your own kid. But,
um, I don't think that would affect the
decisions you'd make unless she had some
Sophie's choice that you had to make.
I think have your buddies
just being really honest. Um,
I dunno.
I don't think it's a good reason to adopt
a kid gives you think it's gonna make
you money. Most orphan kids do
need homes. I agree with a B.
She'd like to skip the crying baby phase.
You know what?
Both of you guys are a couple of psychos.
You're trying to make money.
She does it.
I don't think you want a kid
skip this crying baby phase.
That doesn't sound like a mom.
What about when it can talk
and that's the whiny phase.
Like,
I don't know why
vegetables.
Well fuck
yeah, you're not mine anyways. You
want to go back to the orphanage? Yeah,
possibly to fix your baby teeth.
Right? That's what she's going to do.
I think both of you guys
should have a kid when you,
you want to have a kid
for the right reason.
Maybe you just trying to be funny. I don't
know what, I don't know. Jesus Christ.
All right.
A D d a d d coming to a theater near you.
Hey Bill, you're a
funny guy. You amuse me,
but before you go all Peshy,
I thought I'd run something past you.
Um,
does that mean Joe Peshy or you does
that Italian for fish on the north?
That is your recent self diagnosis of add.
It wasn't self-diagnosis.
It was from my,
my wife I think could be PTSD.
He said not showing me any sort of
credentials. I'm not an expert. Okay,
so now I can't sue them,
but I have a self diagnosis
of myself with this condition.
Isn't the internet wonderful?
I had an injury to the left side
of the brain when I was young,
which led to the right brain compensating
and in turn this led to above average
creative skills.
Hopefully you're just a naturally funny
fucker by suggest reading about this
condition if you've been looking into that
stuff. Well, I got run over by a jeep.
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Hey
wait. You had an injury to the left side
of your brain. That's where I got hit.
I was riding on my bicycle.
I was trying to beat my brother home.
I cross the street without
looking and I got hit by a jeep.
I was upside down and I got
hit right on the temple.
So I told you guys about this before,
when you,
when you bite down on
your Moelis by putting,
put your hand right in the side of your,
of your temple as if you're pointing like,
ah,
that's a smart suggestion there
Brian. Yeah, that part of your scope.
Put it right there and then
bite down on your molars.
You feel that thing that goes in and out.
That's right where I got hit.
And it happened on a Wednesday.
I remember that because the doctor said
I didn't have to go to school for the
rest of the week and I got a
four day weekend, Thursday,
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
And My fucking jaw hurts them.
It hurts to open the hurt to chew.
So eight with a little spoon. And I had
raisin bran. I remember all of that.
Um, I dunno if that's why
I'm, I became what I became.
I wonder if that's true. I have no idea.
I made people laugh before that. I was,
I was fucking killing it in
kindergarten. Um, that's interesting.
I will look that up, sir. PTSD. All right.
You know what debt is the
podcast for this week, everybody.
That's the podcast for each of you.
Now go back to work.
Look at your spreadsheets,
not at your boss and act
like you're fulfilled,
but secretly take another step
towards your fucking dream Booboo,
Uber,
obey dupe before you walk
in and shoot up the office.
All right, everybody, thank
you for listening to the
podcast. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next week.
Thank you to everybody who's coming
out to the Patrice O'Neal benefit.
It means the fucking world to me and
everybody else on the show that a bunch of
knuckleheads like us,
we actually stepped up and created the
opportunity for you guys to do what we
knew what you would do and thank
you to the opie and Anthony Show.
God knows they move most of those tickets
and all the fans of that show. It's,
it's really, um, it's the highlight of
my year, man. It's, it's just awesome.
It really is awesome. All right,
there you go. Go Fuck Yourself.
So talk to you next week.