Hey,
what's going on is bill burr and it's
time for the Monday morning podcast from
Monday, November 16 2015
what's going on? How are Ya?
Oh were you blah, blah, Blah
and all of that shit. I'm,
I am back out here in Los Angeles.
And guess what all Fraco sits on vacation.
That's right.
I did my last Gig of the year,
my last road gig. I should say,
let me drinking tea on this one.
Cause my fucking voice is shot as you
can hear after, uh, my past weekend,
but I'm, I don't have any more fucking
road gig. Say Oh damn all shit to do.
I think I do have to go back to New York
to promote emphasis for family by the
way,
which is coming out on Netflix December
18th the same day that they're released
in fucking, oh my God. Yo,
I want to go see, it's a prequel. You
can look at a little cute. You're Parker.
See Him when he was only fucking a puppy,
right?
So what do, do whatever. So we're
competing against star wars or whatever.
So I need you guys to police. I, I
tweeted out the, uh, the trailer for it.
I need you guys to,
a few ever going to be there for me,
which I like to think you want all
the time. I like to think you care.
Oh.
Um, if you guys could
retweet the, to the trailers,
show it to as many people as you possible.
All Ages, all races, all
sexes, transgenders, anybody.
Just get people to watch
this fucking show. Uh,
cause I think it's really funny and
I think you guys are a, you know,
if you liked this shit, you're gonna
like that Shit, you know, whatever. So a,
that comes out December 18th. That's
a big thing. Uh, I got coming up so,
but other than that, I don't know. I don't
got shit to do. I don't got shit to do.
I just got back from the airport,
lax.
I immediately came in here to do the
podcast. And uh, the second this is over,
I'm going downstairs,
I'm taking a shower and I put not
pajamas and I'm not taking them off until
fucking thanksgiving.
I think that's the next time I'm actually,
you have to be required to
wear fucking clothes, you know,
some sort of respectable clothes.
You know, you can't have you fucking,
uh,
just my,
my dad used to walk around in his
underwear all the fucking time.
It was just totally acceptable,
tidy. Why? He's in a tee shirt.
You have a dead like that,
who you had no chill out clothes.
My Dad was a suit and
he would just come home,
just take his suit off and then we'd be
walking around with his dark dress socks
on and is tidy. What? He
always just walked around.
My whole fucking chill was just completely
fucking normal. In fact, I mean,
the only time you ever put on pajamas
was when he was sick and it look weird.
Um, but anyways, so would say it.
The second this is over, that's it.
I'm jumping in the shower and I'm putting
all my fucking PJ's and I'm going to
watch a bunch of Bruins
games that I taped.
I'm so fucking happy right now.
Um,
with the whole way this
weekend went Madison Square
Garden from the bottom of my
heart. If you were one of the many
people that came out that night,
that was the single greatest
moment of my standup career.
I can't even put it into words.
I can't believe that it happened.
Um, I just, from the second I got
on stage to the second, it ended,
I did like 90 minutes. I went on stage,
right? And before I went on stage,
I was like, what time do I have
to be off? And they were like,
you can't go past 10 30,
cause then the union kicks in and then
I don't make any fucking money. Right.
So I, you know, I went on stage a little
before nine and I got off at like 10,
28.
I just,
I think I said at one point to the crowd
that I didn't want to get off. And, uh,
they, uh, fortunately applauded and
then I just kept going. And, um,
I did every joke that I could think of and
it was fucking amazing. My apology.
So I do have to apologize to, uh,
the people that were up to my right.
I thought they were drunk yelling at me.
What they were yelling was
that they couldn't hear.
It was evidently a couple of
pockets during VRC de Rosa. Um,
I felt bad for Versie cause he thought
they were half one them and stuff and it
kind of messed up is set a little
bit, but he's still killed. But, um,
I thought they were just
drunk. I was like, oh,
it's just a bunch of Yahoos who got a
box and now they're going to be screaming
it's setups. But they were actually
yelling that they couldn't hear.
So from what I heard, 10 minutes
into my act, they fixed it. And uh,
so you heard the last hour and 20? So my
apology or I feel real bad about that.
Um, I don't know why that happened. Um,
but anyways,
okay.
Uh, I'll take you through the whole
day. I want to take it to, you know,
I checked in, I checked
in on Thursday, Friday,
the day before Madison
Square Garden. All right. Um,
I went down to the stand to go do a spot
and I went up there and I fucked around
and trying out this new material
shit that I didn't do it.
Madison Square Garden and you know,
went well and everything.
And one of the owners over there
was, was telling me to fucking, um,
make sure I enjoy Madison Square
Garden and Blah, blah, blah,
Blah and all this type of shit.
And the whole fucking time I was
downplaying Madison Square Garden.
Um,
and the reality was because I had to,
cause it's fucking Madison Square Garden.
If I actually thought
about the magnitude of it,
I don't know what would have happened.
So I just kept downplaying
it and everything. And um,
so I did a spot there and then later
on after I did the spot at standup New
York, sorry, the stand
showing my age there,
I walked over to the Grammercy where
they had the goddamn comedy jam.
Um, some drinking my
fucking tee here. And uh,
I went over there and it was the best
comedy jam show that I've seen to date.
Um, Josh and all the guys had
been on the road doing the show.
So the band was, sounded the
best I ever heard him sound. Um,
I got to do a sound check there during
the day and you just feel some telling
you some venues, just have the magic
and you walked in, you're like,
this is going to be a six show.
And Josh and all the guys were excited
going to do this, going to be no chairs.
Everyone's going to be standing up.
There's going to be 600 people
in the fucking packed. So, um,
so anyway, so we would close out
the show doing paradise city,
um, because they got such great
fucking anthem to end the show with.
And also what's his face Josh was going
through and that's your funniest fucking
costume. Like that blonde
wig looks fucking ridiculous.
So I'm like, all right,
cool. We'll do that. So, um,
everybody went on and killed Matteo Lane,
crushed it,
singing that a Whitney Houston song,
I will always love you.
Right. Crushed it than Eliza Schlesinger
went up there. She fucking killed it.
Um,
then I saw a big Jay Oakerson
who's one of my favorite comics,
absolutely loved the guy. He sang that
song, is it Weezer say it ain't so,
and he was so fucking relaxed and so
comfortable in big Jake can actually sing.
He was crushing it and the whole fucking
room was singing along with them.
And I'm going to look at it, get why, how,
how's he that fucking comfortable
doing that shit? Each is killing it.
And uh, I was thinking maybe, cause you
know, he opened up for all these bands,
like he opened up for corn,
insane clown posse.
So those could be really hostile crowds.
He knew how to handle them.
So I'm thinking, well, maybe
he's just like, this is a layup.
These people actually want me to hear it.
So he was walking around like it
was no big deal. But it was funny.
The second he got offstage, he turned
into a little kid. He was just like, dude,
that's like the coolest thing I ever did.
He crushed it.
An animal birds came in and Sang
Bennie and the jets. And by the way,
everybody does stand up beforehand.
You gotta check this show up, you know,
does all their best shit
talks about going to shows.
So makes the crowd laugh, they get
great stand up and then you get to make,
watch them, uh, you know, act like an
idiot in front of a band. And then, um,
I went on in the end and did a,
um,
paradise city and it was
just a, yeah, it's just some,
it was just fucking sick.
It was just such a great environment
there and everyone was standing up.
And, uh, and then it's also always
fucking hilarious to walk out, you know,
dressed up as,
you know,
have a fucking wig on and shit and
then just go into my act, you know,
talking about people that I think are
fucked up as I'm standing there wearing
this stupid wig in a leather vest.
So we ended up having a great time.
The drums are tuned up.
Fucking just sounded amazing. So, um,
then ended up hanging out with Barton.
It can. We ended up in this Irish pub,
just me and him and uh,
and the bartender and we ordered like
one beer and in the course of doing,
you know,
sipping on the beer,
we all did like three shots
and then another shot with
the bartender and we just
had the best fucking time,
just sent New York Shit.
All of a sudden it's three in the morning,
you go into a Deli, you get a bacon,
egg and cheese, all this shit
you shouldn't be fucking eating.
And went back to my apartment
and just sat there, uh, you know,
talking about how we were going to be
at the garden the next day. So, um,
anyway,
so the next day comes and now here it is
and I'm still downplaying it going like
I'm not even fucking excited for this.
Maybe I over downplayed
this fucking thing. So,
as I mentioned during the day,
I was going to have them a,
I rented a drum kit
and I loaded it into a,
they had them loaded into fucking Madison
Square Garden and the Goddamn comedy
jam guys came over and we played for
an hour and a half and an empty Madison
Square Garden. It was like my manager,
my agent, my father in law was there,
my publicist, couple
other people. That was it.
And uh,
and Ben Bailey,
who I knew played guitar and
had a studio and everything,
I actually texted him a few
days early. I said, Hey Ben,
I'm in New York and we've been trying
to get together and jam for fucking like
five years. And I said,
hey man, do you want to la?
Can you play on Saturday? And
he goes, yeah man. He goes,
I just finished my studio at my house.
You got to come by. And I just wrote back,
now I've got a better place. He
writes back like, what the Fuck Kevin?
He see my place. How do you know it's
better? So I said, you want to fucking,
you know, go to Madison Square
Garden. He fucking freaked out.
So we got a setlist
together and all that shit.
Obviously all the shit that I
did with the combi jam guys,
we had that down and Ben Bailey is
like a fucking black Sabbath's freak.
So we learned war pigs and we
supposed to learn one other.
I don't know we ever got got to it,
but um,
so we ended up going in there,
right?
And there's all these guys setting up
chairs and shit for the show that night.
And I was like, Oh man, I don't want to
sit up here and making all this noise,
you know, fucking ruin in
this did thereafter. And I go,
when are they gonna be done setting
up the chair so we don't bug them.
They got out and now
that they're used to it,
they used to go ahead and get
up there and play. And um,
we started playing.
It was fucking unbelievable.
And the people working
there actually got into it.
They thought it was cool that we were
doing it because they know we were just
geeking out and they started, they'd
started turning on the lights, you know,
doing like a light show as we were
playing in an empty fucking Madison Square
Garden. And by the end of it they, uh,
they had the video guy comes
down and he starts filming us.
So I guess on the last song
we were up on the Jumbo Tron,
I think we closed the paradise city again,
but we did like custard pie.
We did war pigs.
Welcome to the jungle doctor feelgood.
Uh, my publicist also played
drums. He went up there.
They did wanted dead or alive. It
just, all this arena rock shit.
My agent went up there, had to drag
him up there. He went up and he played.
Um, I'll, and I'm going to pose, see
some of these pictures to that, that, uh,
that we had a photographer was
going to be there for that night.
He posted them and we had
the best fucking time.
And I really think that it helped me.
So my show that night,
cause I kind of went in there
and got a feel for the room,
got my stink in there a
little bit, you know, and um,
okay.
Just got on the train,
went back to my apartment in neo was
getting ready and I was just sitting there
as I was waiting for her to get ready
and I was uh, I was drinking a Budweiser.
Right.
And I never drink before shows ever.
I don't give a fuck how far ahead
it is. Right. So she just goes,
you having a beer? And I was like, yeah.
She goes, he never drank before shows.
I was like, no, no. I just felt like
having one. She goes, are you nervous?
I was like, nope. And I don't know why.
I don't know why I wasn't nervous.
I should have been, but I wasn't.
And I went down to the arena
and everybody was there,
had a bunch of people in the
dressing room hanging out,
talking almost right up to we went on.
Usually I'm like,
get the fuck Outta here
for the last 10 minutes.
Let me be alone with my thoughts.
I just, he knew what it was.
I did those two weeks on tour through
the Midwest and then I did that run
through Pennsylvania and down in Florida.
So I was just,
I was on my game and,
um,
I just felt like it was
going to be a good time. So,
so the moment of truth comes right
versus he shows up of course, you know,
wearing a sweater and it's fucking
Jordans or whatever the fuck he had.
I forget what he had air max to Rose's
showed up with wearing this fucking
hipster old lady sweater, which I
actually made fun of when I got on stage.
So Joe Barton,
it goes out and he does the voice of God.
You know, I got the video for that.
I'm going to post that too. Um,
it was fucking hilarious watching him.
He got people so fucking amped up, right.
So verse, he goes up, he does his thing
to Rosa does his thing and then they, uh,
and then we showed the trailer for the
first time ever we showed theF is for
family trailer,
uh,
which I literally had to walk into the
tunnel and block my ears because I didn't
want to handle if they weren't liking it.
So after it was done a hurricane,
a nice round of applause and the Netflix
people, everybody was excited that a,
that had done well. I hope I'm
not boring you guys with the ship.
I feel like I'm babbling here.
Um,
and then it was the moment of truth
going on stage to do stand up comedy at
Madison Square Garden is
sold out fucking show and uh,
Versie introed me
and I dunno,
I just walked out there
and I forget what I said,
but it just was one of those things.
It's like you hit your first
shot and you're like, I,
it's going to be a good game.
And
for the next 90 minutes, I don't
think I've ever bought more present.
I just totally fucking enjoyed
every last second of it.
I did every joke that I wanted to do. I
was improvising. I was fucking around.
I think I trash babe Ruth at one point,
cause me and Yannis Pappas had
this big debate about it. Um,
and I ended up telling this story about
me and versus smoking a cigar in his
garage. That's how I ended. And, uh,
and it was over, and I, and I
outro, uh, the outro music, oh,
I went on stage to the song remains the
same because the name of the show was,
does anybody remember laughter?
It was just like a fucking park.
It was a perfect night.
And then the outro music was Frank
Sinatra Sing in New York, New York,
which I thought was perfect.
It was a nod to, you know,
they played at Yankee Stadium
and everything and Madison
Square Gardens in such
a legendary venue. Uh, and I got
off dude, and it was just, it was,
it was unbelieving.
Everybody that I care about was backstage
was flipping out saying what a great
show it was.
And uh,
yeah. And I was worried. I was worried.
The only thing I was worried about was
that the next day I was going to have a
letdown. Like I was going
to have that hole. Now what?
And do you know all the big extent,
no psych after you open all the
gifts on Christmas, you know,
that feeling of melancholy,
I thought it was going to feel that I did.
The next day I woke up, I just
felt great. I felt satisfied.
I felt at peace. I was just like,
if I never get to do that again,
I couldn't have done it any better. And
I enjoy every last fucking second of it.
It was the night of my life and of course
I recorded it and I will be putting
that one out on vinyl. My Act is not
ready to be a special yet, but uh,
that will definitely be an, I'm putting
out every fucking second of that.
So it might be a double album.
Um,
I'll put that out hopefully
after my next special. Um,
but it was,
it was incredible.
The only part of the night
that wasn't fun was, uh,
when we went to the after party. Um,
one of the people that I work with,
um, no, it was a, it goes actually dates.
Uh, I don't want it to
say that. Business states,
this guy who was a big
fucking fan of the UFC,
so somehow he had the UFC feed on,
uh,
on his computer and neo was screaming,
going, Bill, get over here, get over here.
Rhonda is having a tough time, blah, blah.
And I was just talking to some people
and I didn't want to be rude. Um,
and then I just saw near
God, Oh my God. Oh my God.
But I hand over mouth and uh,
I went over there and I saw the replay
or Brian to get knocked out and I get it.
I haven't had a feeling like that
since I watched Tyson get knocked down.
It's just something like,
you know, you just, I dunno,
I love greatness and I didn't, I
didn't want to see the, you know,
I didn't want to see that.
Congratulations to Holly Holm.
I hope I'm saying her name right.
So she doesn't kick me in the fucking
John Neck. But that was fucking brutal.
Brutal to watch.
And it's one of the reasons why I have
such respect for fighters is they know
that say keep fighting eventually,
you know, on any given night,
even somebody is not as good as you,
you can just get caught.
And I hate when there's something like
that happens and then people say, yeah,
you know, you know what's up
now bitch and blah, blah, blah.
Like you ever had the balls
to fucking go in there. Um,
I obviously think Ryan is going to be
back. I mean, she's only 28 years old,
you know,
whatever she got caught,
I actually think now should probably
become a better fighter because a,
that whole fucking pressure of, of, um,
being undefeated is gone and she can
just focus on what she needs to do. But,
uh, that was fucking brutal,
man. That was really brilliant.
It actually reminded me,
I had this flashback aside from the fact
when I watched Tyson get knocked out by
buster Douglas, I watched that, uh,
over my buddies house up in his
bedroom. Right. We were like,
I think we were underage. Yeah, we were
underage. No, we weren't. No, we weren't.
Why are we, I can't even remember
how long ago I just went,
we were drinking beers in his bedroom,
right.
And he had this fucking TV in his bedroom,
which was fucking
ridiculous back in the day,
if you had a fucking TV in
your bedroom was insane.
Most houses had one TV and
maybe a little kitchen TV.
And we were watching it on
this fucking thing. And, um,
I, I just, I just remember,
I just remember sitting there
and just handled with my mouth.
I couldn't fucking believe it. You just
never thought Tyson was going to lose.
And I felt the same way about Rhonda and,
um,
but that's happened two times on big
gigs for me that there's been a big fight
with something unbelievable happen.
Sorry,
drinking the tea here.
I'm the first one was a,
okay.
Who was the first time I
ever did comics come home,
which I believe was the
second one afterwards.
The after party was in this bar and
they had the Tyson Holyfield fight,
the one where Tyson was biking,
holy fields, fucking ears. And,
uh, you know, the bar was loud so
he couldn't hear the announcers.
So he had no idea what was going on.
And the second time when like Holyfield
was like grabbing beautiful bodies,
like gloves up,
like trying to grab his ear and he
was dead fucking temper Tantrum,
almost like a little kid jumping up and
down when I got the fuck's going on with
them mad, he's looks like he's
like on fire or something.
And then so many fine just
goes, dude, did he like Joe Day?
Fucking buy is right. And then all of
a sudden it just became that. And then,
you know,
when he went to the,
it was kind of cool to actually see what
the sound down and then they focus in
on his ear,
the blood and that,
that little bit taken out of his ear and
everybody in the crowd just going like,
dude, what the fuck? Um, and
that was beyond a surreal night.
It was the first big Gig.
Let's first time ever met Denis leary
and it was all these famous guys on the
show. And Larry knew all these hockey
guys. Cam Neely was there, fucking, uh,
uh, Chris Nyland was there, Rick
Middleton, I couldn't fucking believe it.
And then I'm watching this fight and
I'm watching them reacting like regular
fight fans like I'll do, did he fucking
bite him in the air? Like, well, you know,
just acting regular. So, um,
I got to admit that was
really fucking tough to see.
Okay.
That was tough to see that
fucking picture. We're just
sort of taking that shot,
man. I ain't seen that happens to just
about every other than rocky Marciano that
happens to every Greg
fighter. Um, so anyways,
so that was that night. All right, so
here we go. My Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
So Friday I get to fucking do the goddamn
comedy jam in front of 600 standing
room only people at the Gramercy theater.
Saturday I jammed during the day in an
empty Madison Square Garden and have the
set of my fucking life
did this most famous
arena and all that shit.
The Mecca and all that crap that I
always hate that they say it, you know,
as a Celtic Fan, but Boston,
God doesn't exist anymore. Um,
and then Sunday, how do you top it?
Audio topic. Where did he get go?
I went to the giants patriots scape.
Hilarious. Mean a buddy of mine.
We ubered over there. Right. And
uh, and we knew like another,
like two or three other groups
of two that we're going to there.
And we were all looking for a tailgate.
We were trying to meet up with each other.
We just showed up.
Like the guy just pulls up to
like the exit off of the highway.
We just get out there,
you know,
stumbling up the fucking hill with a 12
pack in our hand and they let us into
this gated area where they had tailgates.
I felt like it was in like a tent city
and we just wandering around like a two
man without a country.
And we finally just ended up sitting
on like this Jersey barrier. Oh,
I remember what happened. Um,
a couple more of my friends
showed up and they will,
they like, did you find a tailgate?
I was like, no, I tweeted it out,
but nobody got back to me about,
uh, letting us crash the tailgates.
And my buddy was like,
well, when we walked in,
these people asked us if we had any beers.
So we walked back over and we literally
traded beers for food and joined their
tailgate. It was like a, we were like
fur trappers instead of having pelts,
we had like fucking bud light and shit
and I'm cooked us up some burgers.
They were all giant fans and uh,
you know,
breaking my balls about losing the
super bowl. But, you know, we were cool.
We were like, yeah, dude,
you guys fucking owners.
We haven't been since the end of 2007.
There's nothing we can say.
I fucking love Eli. You know,
he's a big, he's of fucking Gamer,
but I hate them because it
always breaks our heart.
So we fucking go in and
we watched the game.
I can't even intelligently
talk what was going on.
I was still flying so fucking high
from MSG and I was drinking of course.
And um,
it was this little kept giving a shit,
tearing up stuff and throwing it at
us and we weren't being assholes.
We laughed at it at first that she just
kept giving a shit. She was like seven,
you know, at some point you're looking
at the parents like, can, can you,
can you not have a her
app behave in this way?
What are you trying to do?
She was like going to be one
of the worst sports fans ever.
She's going to get one of her boyfriends
knocked the fuck out when she gets
older because she's going to behave this
way, but the person did nothing. So, um,
we watched the game and I thought
once again, you know, once,
when we scored that touchdown, they called
that bullshit holding call. I was like,
ah, here we go. Here we
go. What's going to happen?
But finally Tom Brady
had some Eli football.
God luck.
He threw up fucking picture and
the game and they dropped it.
Um, so there you go. I
said he lay was dealt.
I said the man was fucking do to have a
game where the football doesn't bounces
way or whatever, but uh, it's not
like he screwed up or anything.
He didn't throw a fucking picky.
He actually threw a touchdown,
great play by Malcolm Butler.
Um,
I didn't get to really see the
replay a son on the jump on Trump,
but I'm sure if I was watching it at
home, I probably say, well, you know,
back in the day that would have
been considered a touchdown. Um,
but who knows what these toll new
fucking football move rules or whatever.
But, um, it was great too. It was
great to see them fucking win the game.
And it was great to see,
you know,
to be able to say that I saw Brady and
he live play against each other live.
I saw Brady and Pete Manning
play each other live.
We back in all foreign manning was still
on the colts that hadn't won a super
bowl yet. Um, so that
was a great one to see.
But in all paled in comparison
to doing Madison Square Garden.
So Diego, there's a 24 minutes story
on my fucking last three days. Um,
I got to read some of the
advertising here, but once again,
I can't thank the people
that showed up enough, um,
that, that, that was, it was
unfucking believable. You know,
it's funny when I left too far as he was,
was Leno all amped up and shit.
Now, you know, I was flying high,
it was just sick and we walked
over to the after party,
write down like the streets in New York.
And first he was flipping out going,
dude, you realize what? You just did an
that he realized how hard you realize.
I was just like, yeah, yeah, it's
the best they could fucking do.
And then we went in and when I
went to the after party, we drank,
we smoked cigars. It was fucking second.
Then ended the night with a bacon,
egg and cheese. It has fucking was the
shit, the shit. And now I'm on vacation.
I remember somebody said
to me, Oh, now what?
Now I'm trying to put that in my head now
what? It's like, what do you mean now?
What? Now what? Now I enjoy my
evening. No, no. What's next?
I don't give a fuck.
Like you're not supposed to be able to
top something that what you supposed to
go in there is enjoy every fucking second
of it and do the best you can possibly
do, which is what I did. So I am told
there's diverse know what's next.
Okay.
I, you know, I think I probably, when
the person asked me that, it's just like,
do you want me to stand how much
I love doing what you stand up?
I do it right now and for a six people
and if I got a new bit out of it,
I'd still be excited.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we've got gotta be some kind of
fucking ruin it. Oh, it's my dog back.
Hey Buddy. Look who's hopefully
I'll get down to Jesus Christ.
Hey, what's going on?
Alright. Right. Alright,
get down all cleo. Hang on a second.
I haven't seen her in two weeks.
I've got to give her a proper, hello?
What do you say that? Why you come here?
What's that one?
You got a bath? Look at you. Yeah.
Okay. All right. I'm doing the podcast.
I'm doing applied yet.
Oh, sorry. Sorry, I'm back. I'm back.
Look at you. Wow. The old blue bear.
Your blueberries back in the building.
I haven't seen my dog in two weeks.
You and I, lady, Cleo, you and I are
going to go on some fucking hikes,
my friend. I'm in town for the rest of
the year. What do you think about that?
You know,
I put on some pounds and I'm going to
get back and pit bull shape and I'm not
talking about the wrap
up. Um, all right buddy.
Can you get over there and lay down?
Cleo, can you go lie down please? Go on.
Go lay down. Go lay down. No,
I'll play with you in a minute.
Hey, get your nose out of
there. Go lay down. Down. Sorry.
Is this even a podcast anymore? Clear
up. Get up. Get over there. Go on.
Walk over there. Lay down. You can't
keep jumping up here. Um, all right,
let's do some reads for this week,
a dollar shave club.
Everybody stopped shaving
with an old razor. It's gross.
Why are you torturing yourself with
the gross old blade week after week?
Why would you do that to yourself?
Why don't you love yourself? Uh,
it's probably because
you don't want to say,
actually the real reason is probably
because you want to shell out 20 bucks for
a pack of new ones,
right?
Dollar Shave club.com has revolutionized
the way that people shave men in
particularly with dollar Shave Club,
you shave with a fresh blade as often
as you want because they deliver a whole
sleeve of amazing raises.
But just a few bucks a month.
The razors are so good.
Hey, I keep it down.
I'm doing the podcast.
Hmm.
Um, I said, can you keep
it down? I'm trying to do,
the podcast should like louder than me.
I'm fucking with you,
Jesus. Sometimes the jokes
work, sometimes they don't. Um,
even the billion dollar razor companies,
uh, corporations are freaking out,
but instead of lowering their bloated
prices, what are these pigs do?
They trying to fool you into milking
the same blade for an extra month.
And you know what, that's gross.
It's not good for your face either.
They've price gouged to us
for long enough. Attica,
never go back to squeezing weeks and
weeks of shaves out of a disgusting rusty
blade. All you gotta to do is just join
dollar shave club and use a fresh blade,
uh, whenever you want. It feels
amazing and it's a third of the price.
Join the millions and millions of
fans, uh, millions of others who, uh,
figured out the smarter way to shave.
Uh,
join dollar shave club now by going
to dollar shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar hey
dollar shave club.com/burb all right,
here's a new one. MVMT watches. Oh,
movement watches,
sorry.
Thanks to movement watches for
their sponsorship of this podcast.
They sent over some watches and I
haven't received them yet. You know what?
I've been on the road, but whatever. I'm
sure they're great. Sure. They tell time,
you know,
check them up.
It was this little crowdfunded brand that
is revolutionizing the watch game and
they started to get a lot
of press from a GQ playboy.
Hypebeast askmen said they are the
hottest watch company on the market.
Is that right? Well, anything that's
fucking over the Iwatch is great for me.
I think that's hilarious.
Cleo, have you seen anybody,
any of your friends have
the, uh, the Iwatch?
Quality crafted watches start at just $95.
If you tried to get a watch
like this at a department store,
you'd be spending at least four or 500
bucks. They're style is minimalist.
It's clean and sleek.
Um,
you could wear this thing at the
office during the day or night at bars.
It's new, it's sharp, and it's an all day.
Where please spell MVMT.
When you say the URL,
I know it. I know what to do.
I'm going to help you style.
Get on point to checkout. MVMT
Michael Victor, Michael Thompson,
uh, watches. MVMT watches.com/burr.
We're hooking you up with
50% off your entire purchase.
That's MVMT watches.com/bar.
All right. And lastly,
but certainly not leastly
are old friends here.
stamps.com with the holidays almost here,
you don't have time to go to the post
office traffic parking old ladies lines.
It's going to be packed and
it's Kinda sucked, sucked.
It's going to suck with everyone.
Mailing holiday gifts and packages. Well,
why would you want to do with that?
You know, well, what do I do, Bill?
How do I get out of it?
Just use stamps.com instead with
stamps.com you can avoid all the hassles,
man. I'll go into the post office
during the busy holiday season.
Everything you would do with the post
office, you can do right from your desk.
Buy and print official US postage
using your own computer and printer,
print postage for any letter or
package the instinct you need it.
Then the mailman picks it up.
It's so easy and convenient.
I use stamps.com to send out all my
march, all my uh, posters and whatnot.
You should too. Right now, sign up
for stamps.com and use my last name,
birth for this special offer.
Four trial plus $110 bonus offer that
includes postage and a digital scale.
Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the
top of the homepage. Type Barb B,
You r R that stamps.com and to
bro. You know what, Cleo, you too.
God Damn Cute. Why don't you come up here
for the rest of the podcasts. All right.
Lay down. Lay down. Lay down. Lay
down. Thank you. Oh, you smell so good.
Yes you do. Okay. Okay.
All right. I know I missed you too.
Okay. I get done. All right, let's
read some questions for this week.
Um,
she'll calm down on that.
A military response,
a bill.
I'm not affiliated with any
political party. Read extremists.
Whenever anybody says I'm not
a Democrat or Republican, um,
hold on. You're just going to make all
kinds of fucking noise up here on shit.
All right.
I hate groups just as much as you do.
I'm not looking forward to hearing people
argue about proper responses to recent
attacks in Paris because everyone talks
like they have military background.
That being said,
what is the solution?
It seems like it's always a damned if
you do and damned if you don't situation
with the military action.
In one sense.
I find that comforting knowing
that it's fucked up either way,
it means we're just human beings
getting yeah. By thoughts. Um,
all right. What do I
think? Well, obviously,
you know what happened in Paris is
fucking brutal and I don't see how that,
you know, even if I agreed
with the political agenda
of wherever the hell did it,
like that's not the way to get people to,
uh,
pay attention to your plate
to do stuff like that.
Okay.
Having said that,
I live in a superpower and I know that
our bombs don't always land on the right
people. So I understand why countries
don't get along with each other.
Um,
and I've been to Paris twice in,
it's my favorite city in the world.
And I think the people are great and it's,
it's just brute an eagles
of death metal or on stage.
Thank God they were all right,
but just, I can't imagine why.
I mean,
nobody was in that building is going
to be the same. I mean, it's just like,
I can't even imagine. It's
just, I didn't actually,
I didn't even want to talk about this
stuff is so fucking brutal. But um,
unfortunately I think that human beings
are a hairless apes that can speak and,
um,
okay.
And we're doomed to destroy one another.
So try to enjoy every fucking
day before, uh, we deal. I mean,
that's the only thing. I mean, there's no,
okay,
there's no stopping 'em all this shit
that's going on the fucking world.
We're never going to get along.
We're just not going to, you know,
there's no solution in the Middle East,
whatever side you're on,
those people hate each other for fucking
ever. I'm the only way, you know,
the only way you could fucking do it
is you'd have to eliminate everybody.
But like babies and you'd have
to start over again. So all this,
nobody told them the fucking stories
about why you should hate these people.
Right? But even if you left
the fucking babies alone,
cause there's this big fucking
thing where they go, you know,
a baby comes into the world and a baby
isn't racist and a baby isn't this and a
baby isn't that. Uh, but you know what
a baby is. It's a fucking human being.
All right.
And so one of those babies,
eventually it's going to be a sociopath.
One of them's going to be, uh,
an egomaniac he's going to give into,
to jealousy and envy.
And it would just start all over again
in different parts of the world for
different fucking reasons. And, uh,
people would not like people
because of how they looked.
And it's just how we're wired.
I think everything has a beginning,
a middle and the end. We're closer
to the fucking end, unfortunately.
And um,
you know,
that's why I don't watch the fucking
news anymore. That's why I, I,
I, I don't, I don't understand
why it is the way it is.
And there is no fucking solution.
I know that's depressing and uh,
enjoy your holidays, everybody. I just,
what are you going to do?
What are you going to do to stop these
people do my dog just keeps wagging her
tail is right just sitting on a couch
with your fucking dark man, right?
That's it. Playing music with some
friends of yours, doing a comedy show,
going after a dream is going after
what the fuck you want in life.
That's all you can do.
You can do that and you can recycle
and you can try to use less materials.
But other than that, what do you,
what do you do you really think,
and all the years of watching the fucking,
the debates between Democrats
and republics do Republicans.
You think they're ever
going to fucking agree.
You think they're ever going to be
like, no. I see your point. You know,
if you get the people at top more
money, they're going to create jobs. Oh,
I get what you're doing. Or The people
on Republicans are going to be like, Oh,
you know what?
Maybe we are taking too much.
Maybe we should fucking do this
and do there. There's, there's no,
there's no fucking solution. It says
like when I was in New York, you know,
they were talking about, you know,
all the homeless people, you know,
and people with mental problems and
shit that, that's just on the street.
The police chief goes,
the solution was stop giving them
money and it's just like, all right.
And then what? They just go, okay,
well I guess the city isn't giving
money and they're going to do like what?
Walk to Philadelphia with no money and
no food. They're going to get desperate.
Um,
you know,
and then if you give them food and
money and then what does that mean?
Then they get their life back together.
I have no fucking idea. I just, I dunno.
I don't think there's any solution.
MMM.
And that's depressing
and it's not even funny.
That's why I don't talk
about that type of shit.
So moving along to the
next happy fucking topic.
Alright, boyfriend won't shut up and
let me listen to the game now. Right?
Bill, I'd been in a relationship.
What do you have fucking,
did you marry a hipster? So you want
to put on the Scifi channel a bell?
I've been in a relationship with
my wonderful boyfriend for a year.
I'm 29 and he is 33. Yeah, that's
a good age split right there. Uh,
he's a wonderful man. Treats me
very well and we are very in love,
but he has no respect.
When I tried to listen to the game,
I'm a diehard Denver Bronco
Fan and we live in Chicago.
It is Sunday and the game is not being
aired locally because there's showing
your laneless patriots instead.
Lame ass.
Patrius um, yeah, I get it.
We're undefeated and you're not. So
that annoys you. I get it. So your tech,
my team, my team of Patriots.
How can I like the Patriots?
That means you don't support the troops.
Uh,
so my only option is to listen to the
game on Denver Broncos radio network.
You Go,
you can also get the NFL package.
You could not go out and drink in one
weekend. You could use that money,
could watch him every
week. Anyway, she goes,
but my boyfriend makes it
impossible for me to listen to it.
He keeps playing a stupid videos
during the game talks, uh,
talks a lot like the game isn't even
on and even broke out into a song and
started vacuuming.
This is not a one time occurrence.
Last week it was on any kept switching
over to other Games is sports or hockey
and baseball and I never once interfered
with his ability to watch the black
hawks and the cubs. Yeah.
He makes it impossible for
me to listen to the Broncos,
the only sports team I really care about
Jesus Christ. This guy's an asshole.
He doesn't seem to have any respect
for my team and sports fandom.
It's surprising because he's
so respectful. Otherwise,
how do I handle this going forward? Should
I just always leave and go to the bar?
Because I know he makes it impossible
for you to watch the game or listen and
listen and watch the game. That's
one of them. That's one solution.
Why don't you just write down on a piece
of paper? If you don't shut the fuck up,
I will never blow you again.
And then flip it over and say
I'm serious after he goes,
are you serious right
now? I am serious. Um,
I dunno if you have you sat down and uh,
talk to them about it, you know, I dunno.
See then, let's see. Look at this right
here. This is a little tension here.
Hatfields and McCoys. What do you
do? And if he doesn't listen to you,
then you're going to get resentful.
That's it.
I would just politely ask them
not to do and he does it again.
The next time one of his games are on,
I would vacuum.
I just keep turning the vacuum
on, on and off, on and off.
And if you do that to him for like
five minutes, he's going to get it.
I think you got to go child to share.
If you haven't talked to him yet,
I think you got to go childish.
You know,
there's always room to act
like an absolute fucking baby.
Don't ever forget that and
it's fun. Um, all right,
thanksgiving dilemma. Uh,
hey Billy. So I will get,
I will get right to the details. My
family is hosting Thanksgiving this year.
Oh geesh. We have five people in our
family, mom, dad, and three brothers.
I am the middle child.
We have grandparents for both my mom
and dad's side coming along with my
grandparents. We have cousins coming.
All right, now, here is my dilemma.
Here's my dilemma.
Comes into play.
My cousin got married a while back and
his wife has asked if her mom could come
to our Thanksgiving
dinner. Uh, Jesus Christ,
Jesus Christ. You know, there's,
there's something to be said when you've
lived that long and you don't have a
Thanksgiving party to go to. The probably
means you're a fucking asshole. Um,
my mom had to go.
My mom had gotten into a little dispute
with her like a few months ago and my
mom fucking hates her. Uh, Jesus
Christ, you can't do that. People,
he can't get into a fight with
you fucking in. You can't do it.
You can't get in a fight with your, uh,
I don't even know what you call them.
If your brother or sister gets married,
you can't get into what they're
fucking analyze. You just can't do it.
You get to bite your
tongue and just be like,
I'm going to sit here and my sweater.
I'm going to smile and wave and this is
going to be over and then I'm going to
go back to the life that I'm,
that I'm leading,
that I built and I'll deal with this
person once a fucking year. Right.
Why is there always a
current male of female?
There's always that one fucking
person just doesn't know how to hang,
doesn't know how to be a good
person. You know what I mean? Like,
like if you are knowing people on
Thanksgiving, which is his coops, Kevin,
who that's just the greatest day.
You hanging with the people you love,
you're eating way too much food.
It's all delicious.
Everybody from all different families
and shed is breaking out their secret
recipes.
There's football on his video games.
You got the fire going.
There is no fucking reason
to even remotely be a cancer on
that day off for the whole weekend.
It's just a, it's just a Pfister,
the greatest fucking weekend.
College kids come back Wednesday night.
Everybody fucking hangs out.
He get to tired of fucking hookup with
people that you liked back in the day
when you were in high
school. Right? By the way,
you got to do that Wednesday night hookup,
man.
You got to do that until you're like
fucking 30 and everybody starts disappear
and then you've got to realize
you're too fucking old.
And then maybe I should go
out and fucking, uh, you know,
maybe I should go out and get
married myself or whatever. But uh,
read through your 20s. You're going to
hit that every fucking time. In fact,
you know, we did a great rant about
that. The one man thrill ride,
the one men throw rights. Got a great
one. I'll try to find that video. Um,
he's got a great video about
that. But anyways, yeah,
there's no reason to be a cunt.
I just don't fucking get it.
And there's nothing to like,
your mom needs to set aside her shit.
You had one fucking argument.
All right. Let me go back and read
every, forget now. This is this
your mom's sons mother-in-law.
You have to get along with her.
My cousin got me all your cousin.
Uh, it's a little distant.
Just just be fucking civil.
You know what's funny is when men don't
like each other, it's way more civil.
It's a family event like that because
we solve shit with via violence.
Do you know what I mean?
No one wants to get involved in that,
but women are more mature I guess.
So they don't solve shit with violence.
So it all it is is dirty looks
and fucking, you know, Sasha,
your sides or whatever the fuck you
call him, side glances and shit.
They just all day long.
They don't give a fuck.
They just be just openly being
rude to one another. Oh my God.
You know what you should do? You
should. You should have like a fucking,
I should just have an area to
put people like that. All right,
you two douche bags don't get along
so you can, you guys can both eat.
You can eat Thanksgiving dinner,
standing up outside in the backyard.
That's where you should stick them.
Right the fuck out of here. All right.
My mom had got into a little of the street
with them a few months ago and my mom
fucking hates her. She's the type
of lady that just sits on her ass.
It doesn't help making food,
doing the dishes, cleaning
up or anything. Yeah, yeah,
exactly. There's always one
of those. We know that. Yeah.
And then fucking goes to the, your bar and
did, takes out the most expensive shit.
Doesn't finish it. You know what I
mean? Dumps it down the fucking sink. A,
we know this from the shoot times.
We hung out with her at family gathering
spiked cousin's wife's mom has no other
place to go for Thanksgiving yet.
Cheat. Why do you think that is?
Cause she doesn't help making the food.
She doesn't do the dishes and clean up
or anything. She's a Douche. Oh my God,
I fucking hate this
person. Um, but honestly,
none of us really know her or nor do
we want her to come and make our day
awkward.
I guess I just need to ask advice and
how we respond to my cousin and tell him
that that bitch isn't invited.
We don't know how to do it without hurting
feelings or making it weird the next
time we see them.
Um,
you can bring Nia in on this one if she
knows how to set this bitch down easy.
You know what? I'm going to go get her.
Hang on one second. Hang on one second.
Hey Nia, I need you to help
on this one. All right.
Even though you still mad at me for
my, my rude comment earlier. Can you,
can you come over? This is, this is, this
is recording live. You couldn't clean up.
Get down. Get Down Buddy. I'm sorry.
Get over there laid out going. Yeah,
I hear you. All right, come
over here. So long story short,
this guy has got a dilemma he's having,
he's having Thanksgiving at his house.
Okay.
So here's this dilemma.
His cousin got married a while back and
his cousin's wife's asked if her mom can
come along. Okay. All right.
And evidently she's a Douche.
She doesn't help with the cooking.
She doesn't help with the cleaning.
She just sits around. She's
a jerk. Okay. And guess what?
She has no place to go for thanksgiving.
Can you believe it? Can you believe this?
Jerk him over here near the microphone.
I know, I know. Just really quickly.
Oh my God, you so mad at me right now.
So was the question. So how can he,
how can he just in a nice way,
let this woman down easy.
Like how can you just say,
listen,
we'd love to have your mother over here
if she wasn't such a jerk and she wasn't
going to ruin thanksgiving. So
we, so the cousin is coming,
the cousin was invited. Yup.
And he's bringing his wife.
They're both invited. Yeah.
They just don't want them to
bring his cousin's wife's mom.
Yeah. That's an impossible
situation. I feel you though,
because you want to be like,
well it's my house.
I can have how whoever I want over and
if I don't want this person over as you
know.
But the thing is what the holidays and
family and this is the cousin's wife's
mom, that's one. You're not
going to be able to win.
So I feel like you can't
turn them down and say, no,
they can't come because that will
create a bigger problem than it's worth.
And so what?
What does she do?
She just doesn't like my mom got into a
little dispute with her a few months ago
and my mom fucking hates or oh yeah.
Oh, it was brutal. Okay, well I know,
I love that you have to be like the
bigger person and just allow this fucking
stick in the mud to come over and
ruin this person's thanksgiving.
I really feel for this person,
right.
Blows. I think. I think
what you can do is,
especially since the mom
doesn't get along with her,
I think it may be one of those
things like, you know what,
we're really only prepared
for like this many people and
but they had the fight and the falling
out. They're going to know what's up.
They got to know why she's not. Show me
says, can, can you, can I bring my mom?
You have to say yes.
You can know your mom could stay at home.
That's the thing about it.
And the thing is I would,
I think maybe this is more
advice for the next time,
next time you can invite your cousin over.
That's what it is.
This year's Thanksgiving
is going to stink,
but the neuros of them won't because
your cousin can't come the next day.
Yeah. Just, I mean, just
ignore that woman for now.
Even if she doesn't help or
whatever, it's, you know what,
I've got to have fun with it. Yeah. And
you can also say, Oh hey, I'm, you know,
whatever her name is. Susan,
do you mind, you know,
gathering a couple of those plays
for us and you know, just kinda like,
just throw that in there.
But if she's continuing to be that way,
I'm sorry about your cousins can't come
to your thanksgiving anymore because
she's to be a part of the package.
And if they bring it up, just say,
you know what,
to be honest,
our mom does really get along with her
and we feel like it gets uncomfortable
and you know,
maybe they can come by for pie at the end
of the night or something and they can
just bring it out to the car and
just hand it to you as they're,
as they're driving by as a driving mode
just to stick your hand out the window
and I'll just have it on the,
I'll have it on a plate.
You know, we used to do it when there
was somebody like that around. We would,
they will be some sort of inside joke
that whenever the person was behaving the
way that we hated it was the
inside joke with the other people.
You would just like sing a song,
you don't make a deal with,
clean up the dishes and she doesn't do
it and then you just walk away and you
just sing like Jess was gay.
We tried and it just becomes,
and it actually makes it fun,
but I really think you should just do
the thing where you ask her to help out,
Hey, do you mind grabbing the
plates and sending them out?
It was so good at that too. I do do that
really well. I'm really good at like, Oh,
do you mind just grabbing
this for me really quickly?
It's all laced with do you might not
be in such a selfish Douche. Exactly.
Like it's, you know, it's,
it's customary when you're invited
to somebody's place over to dinner,
anything, can I help you with
the dishes? Do you need anything?
Like that's a custom, even if
the person is like, no, no,
no, no. I got it. I got it.
I got it. It's, it's customary.
It's an etiquette thing to at least ask
if you can help out or bring wine or
something like that.
Yeah. And here's a,
here's a major red flag.
If you're that fucking old and you
have nowhere to go for thanksgiving,
and it wasn't some boating accident,
but all your family was on,
like how do you not have anywhere to go?
Nobody wants to spend Thanksgiving
with you. Pick up up dirty plate,
you selfish whore.
Well,
the thing is like the cousin and the
wave and the cousin's mother in law,
and they can do their own
thing separately. I mean,
maybe not. Maybe it's a war.
It's all about the big family gathering,
but I think that's what I think.
You just got to grin and bear it.
I think you should definitely
gently suggest to her, hey,
do you mind grabbing this?
And just little stuff.
Not Crazy because then she'll be on to
you and I'll be like a real big blowout
and you don't want that,
but just subtly Turkey Douche Kimani
but next year, yeah, he's
just Canavan. You know what?
We're actually going to do a really
small things giving this year.
It's just gonna be me and the wife
and my mom like we're no assholes.
We're just doing a small this year.
You have to be very gentle about it,
but that's how you get around it.
Cause that you just don't
invite the people that are
attached to the people that
you don't like, which sucks.
But that's how it goes.
Here's the other thing
to watch, watch, watch,
watch your alcohol intake because you're,
the truth might be coming out later on.
You might say something and the alcohol
will start going like, I'll say it.
Say Fuck it. She wants the day. It's
your Thanksgiving too. All right,
I will do that. Okay. Who
do I make this sound too?
Uh, can we shout out Justin? Absolutely.
Shout out to Justin Long and
his brother Christian Long. Um,
they listen to the podcasts
and they're awesome. Justin,
you know what I found out the
next day after we met each other.
You and I have the exact same birthday,
the exact same birthday day,
year.
How crazy is that? It why was just in
there? He was there because he does it.
[inaudible] her family coming to
Netflix on December 18th. Yeah,
they go and he's been so great,
man. He tweeted out, uh, you know,
he was tweeting the hell out of the,
uh, the teaser and all that. And uh, he,
he does the voice of Kevin and he is
fucking hilarious and it's was one of my
favorite characters to write for once I
saw what Justin was going to do with it.
So, uh, we had a lot of fun hanging
with them. One Nia, thank you so much.
The lovely me. Everybody. Yeah.
Coming on the podcast supports to
support you at the Madison Square Garden.
You were incredible. You are
amazing. You are in the zone.
I was very proud of you. Thank you. Thank
you. I know, but I'm telling you, I'm you,
I'm uploading this and I'm taking a
shower and then I'll put on my pajamas.
So that's it. That's it. It's all
all right. One more question here.
One more question. I've got
to get through here all yet.
Get cleo some food. All
right. Gay Rumors Day,
Billy twinkle toes.
Uh,
my friends and I are freshmen
in college at different schools.
Recently he hooked up with this girl,
with this lady.
It was after the party had died
and everyone, uh, was cleared out.
She crawled into his bed,
Jesus Christ and started jacking him off.
And that's how it happened.
So what happened?
He had a hand,
baby
kind of open ended.
I was visiting that weekend and
I watched her walk into his room.
The rest I heard second hand from him,
no pun intended.
The next day she started talking
like they were in a relationship. Um,
he explained that he wasn't into being
in a relationship aside from the fact
that she's a slob. He wasn't into
the idea anyways with any girl.
Um,
she responded by telling a group of
people that he asked her to be his
girlfriend to cover that he was
gay and that he needed to meet,
needed her to meet his parents. Can
you blow? She just made that up.
Can you believe this chick? That's
sociopathic behavior. It's slander.
My question obviously is what should
he do? He's not a feeble soul.
He's actually really quick witted and
if he really wanted to, he could air,
he could clear the air publicly.
It's one of those situations where if
he lets it all fade away, it could,
it could end clean on the other hand,
fuck that.
She shouldn't get off that easily.
Uh,
she could do it again and the next guy
could respond with violence is suicide
Assam Shit.
What's the move here?
You know what the move here is to
fucking watch that crazy train.
Just go down the street and
disappear over the hell. Fuck her.
That's fucking hilarious. It's hilarious
that she said that. That she's, you know,
she's a maniac.
Why would you do that?
You know what I mean?
It gives a shit. How easy to
play are you gay? Well, I mean,
I am a sharp dresser. You can, you
got to give me that. Who knows?
Maybe I am. Maybe I'm not. I don't know.
Okay.
Hey ladies,
you want to see if he can ungay me like
they do with the fucking weird churches
where they try to cure your being gay.
I would just have fun with it.
Who gives a fuck?
Okay.
Honestly, who gives a shit some
swabs? Is that you're gay? All right.
Well,
I'm not,
and I can prove it.
Show me a text ladies.
Oh, look at all Frederick
standing up at attention.
Yeah. This is, this is like
childish. Who gives a shit?
Who gives a shit what people think.
MMM.
Yeah. I mean, that's, so
that's why it's a joke.
She's going to do it to
somebody else. Yeah. Okay.
And then why did she keeps going
around? Oh, that guy doesn't like me.
He doesn't like because he's gay.
MMM.
I Dunno.
Maybe she's a,
yeah,
maybe she that much of an ego maniac
that she's thinks the only way that you
could not 100% be endure
is because that you,
you liked men because evidently she's
just the most amazing fucking woman of all
time. Uh, yeah. When people
walk around and they say shit
like that to you, I mean,
if you have like a business and somebody
is trying to say like, yeah, Hey,
I got food poisoning there. I mean, you
got to put a stop to that. But you know,
Hell hath no fury like a woman scorned.
Like you,
you haven't hooked up with
a woman dated a woman,
you know,
unless you've had a woman go around and
just make up shit about you and say a
bunch of fucking yeah, stuff to try
and hurt you. That's what they do.
She wants to beat the shit out of him,
but she can't.
So she's doing what women do is they,
you know,
okay.
They just go around saying
shit about each other.
That's what they do at know this
woman is acting completely normally.
This is what completely
normally completely normal.
This is normal chick psycho
fucking behavior. Um,
I think it's fucking
hilarious and uh, oh yeah,
we'll just let it go. Yeah. Don't, don't
even, we can't let her get away with this.
You can't go vengeance, vengeance
never. That never ends. Well,
it never ends well because then
they're going to come back and get that
vengeance on your vengeance and then
eventually the only way to end it is
somebody's got to kill somebody.
Right. That's basically what happens.
Is it,
I don't know if it is.
All I know is it's the end of the
podcast and I am on fucking vacation and,
um,
I want to thank everybody over all the
years is coming out to my standup shows.
Anybody ever heckled me?
Anybody over lapped,
anybody would just fucking showed
up, got a free fucking ticket. Um,
because all of those shows led to
the one that I had Saturday night.
What a fucking way to end.
I got one more gig that I am do.
I am doing a New Year's eve
out here in, um, in, uh,
in La, but it's not a road
gig. It's going to be great.
It's gonna be the night
before the Rose Bowl.
It's going to be the four
horsemen coming together again.
I'm just going to be fucking
awesome. But, um, I dunno.
I hope I was able to convey it.
I can't even tell you what, uh,
I'll just fucking thrilled I was,
I still can't believe that it happened,
but I know it happened because I was
totally present and I enjoyed the whole
thing and the, you know, it was
great. The light was so in my eyes,
I couldn't see how big it was.
I couldn't see everybody,
but I could look up and see the
lights up at the top. And, uh,
one of the coolest things ever.
My comedy career,
at one point I was doing this Illuminati
act out like they were all sitting at a
table talking about the
population problem. And I
actually sat down on the stool
okay.
And I was doing this creepy
fucking thing about them,
thinking about how they
could get rid of people.
And I was able to bring the
whole fucking room down.
Like I was in a fucking comedy club.
And as I was doing it,
I was actually thinking like,
how fucking sick is this right now?
It's like 12,000 people listening to me.
I'm sitting down on a stool imitating
some lunatic in the Illuminati.
How fucking fun is that? It
was, it's was indescribable.
And anyways, please tell everybody,
you know, a lot F is for family.
Um, I would really appreciate it.
Um, although after Saturday night,
nobody owes me anything. But if you'd
like to, I would appreciate it because a,
I think it's going to be a great show.
Um,
a great TV series for many years to come
with any luck. All right. That's it.
So I'm thankful early this year,
man.
I'm thankful for all you guys listening
to this podcast and all that stuff. Um,
that's it. So go fuck yourselves. As
always. I'll check in on you on Thursday.
Check at our, yeah, I'm
going to go take a shower,
put on my pj's and play with my fucking
dog. Alright, that's it. I'll see you.