Okay. Hey, what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's time for the
Thursday afternoon. Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Dan Checking
in on Ya. How are Ya?
What's going on? Oh Shit.
It's the day before the
fucking space movie comes out,
but about
35 so fucking religion out there,
right?
Keep in mind dad,
Obi wan Kenobi has died for
us and he's using the force.
You
he had that dirty robe.
Maybe that's why he got sliced in half.
Um,
all right,
so I have,
I have a little cartoon coming out
called emphasis for family tomorrow.
I know it's not the big space
movie that everybody wants to see,
you know with r two d two and c three
Po and that fucking green thing that got
shot in the bar way back in the day.
Bob Power bar.
But was I was the evil one
goal as the evil song go
fucking same goddamn movie.
Why are you guys going to see that when
you don't know what's going to happen
and after it's for family, you know
what's going to happen in Star Wars?
Good is going to try him over evil,
doesn't it always except for that one.
You know where they ran around on
those mechanical fucking lamas,
whatever the hell the word,
the ad ads.
I know all this shit
cause one of my brothers,
he had all the fucking action figures,
you know,
I remember that Shit. You
know, I just, you know,
I talked about uncommon and I just missed
out. I didn't see it at the right age.
And then when I saw it I was like,
you know,
the hype was just so fucking big
and I was just like, this was what,
this was the big deal.
This is the big that I thought the first
one was boring and then the next one I
loved. I liked the one that fucking
dude cut to go it go with the blackout.
Darth Vader. Darth. Yeah, they Veda Joe.
Okay. Yeah. About Daniel fucking
guy moved into the neighborhood.
Fucking Darth Vader. Dude.
It's fucking ride is kid.
Um,
yeah,
he cut off Luke Skywalker's hand in that
air conditioning shaft, whatever it was.
None of it's explained by the way.
It's just all spacey looking shit.
You know what I mean? A
bill. You're a grumpy con.
Why can't you let people enjoy it?
You know they like it. You know what?
You're right. You're right. I wish I
cared. I wish I was in. I like Scifi.
Hey, I like Scifi. Why can't I come along?
Um, that'd be a great youtube video.
Just have people driving by just
heckling people in the lines.
Don't do that. Please don't do
that. Those people in that line,
they've been through enough.
You know what I mean?
I think the people who are into star wars,
but they've been through enough,
maybe not the younger ones.
Maybe then we can give shit to because
they haven't been bullied cause it's been
like outlawed right now.
Bullying.
How the fuck is this generation going
to produce another generation of great
comedians if nobody got their heads
stuffed into a toilet? I mean, it's just,
it's a fucking shame, you know, for
as much as people shit on bullies,
they're really the reason for
some of the great musicians,
comedians and all that.
They channel all that pain and
humiliation to the tone in their guitar,
right when they get through it. But
the silliness, you know what I mean?
Learning how to fucking who new toilet
water would make your cowlick finally
laid down. Who knew that, you
know, get jokes out of it. Nothing.
He's Auntie Star Wars. He's pro bullying.
This isn't what I signed up for.
Um, Sony was, so I'm done.
I'm done with my press. Uh,
I had a great time on
found that I did Conan.
I did like a fucking thousand goddamn
radio things and print things and all of
that. And uh, the cartoon finally
comes out tomorrow to go see star wars.
I'm just fucking with you guys,
man.
It's just fun to shit on
something that everybody's into.
They have so fucking good movies. What?
They're there for the kids, right.
You know what I mean? If the kids,
please tell me that for the kids,
please tell me you're not sitting there
with nobody in your life with a bunch of
stuffed animals.
He walks on some manmade shelf.
I guess they're all manmade but homemade,
you know,
a little fucking two by
six right above your head
with your action figures still in the box.
So they're worth more money.
But you know,
you're never going to sell them,
but you can't get yourself to open
them up. Why don't you take it out,
you know, do your little Chewbacca
impression. Oh, it was it Yoda.
Huh?
That fucking weird way. I knew my boy. He
talks, you know at the desk you must sit.
What are the fucking dies?
Oh my God.
What an annoying little green
can't. Yeah, you can't hate Yoda.
You know what you could,
if your drove cross country,
he'd have to do some gen I shit like every
half a state before he just like toad.
You either need to do some magic
stuff where you have to stop talking.
Okay. Because, uh, my fucking brain,
you're hurting or whatever the
fuck you say to him. Oh, you know,
you'd be annoying. Just start
imitating them. Roof really get Douche.
Um, no, what's wrong with me? You
know what's wrong with me is, uh, I,
I need to just fucking
chill out and I can't,
I got two shows tonight cause I gotta
get ready for my new year's show here in
la at the Orpheum.
Who's going to be on the show?
Got Damn at the four horsemen
are coming into town.
Well I guess I'm already
here. So three of them. Uh,
well I had lived out here to
open up Bart next out here.
One of them is coming to town. Sorry,
I just totally blew that out there.
One of them is coming to town. I'm
usually good about pulling the microwave.
One of them's is to town and the other
three are already here. All right. God,
God, go that. That's the
magnificent seven bill.
You need three more writers. Uh,
it's going to be me lot head Barnett.
Can Paul Versey at the Orpheum,
the legendary Orpheum downtown
downtown la first shows at seven 15.
For whatever fucking reason. I don't
know why it's not seven or seven 30.
It's seven 15. Everybody just to
make sure you're paying attention.
And then the, uh, the other one
is at 10 o'clock. All right.
Two fabulous shows. So last night we
had the premiere for F is for family.
And uh,
I told the lovely Nia that I was going to,
you know,
go up there with the Great Mike Price
from the Simpsons co creator of the show.
We were going to thank
everybody for coming out.
And the second I thanked everybody,
I was immediately going to walk right
out the movie theater because I did not
want to sit there. You know, watching
people watch it because that's just,
I can't describe that feeling after
years of being a comedian where you can
adjust, you know, if it's going bad,
you can speed up, you can slow down,
you can do this, you can do
that. The fucking, you know,
TV show is locked. It's
done, it starts bombing.
All you can do is just sit there
and I also want to have it.
So that was my game plan.
I thanked everybody and then I started
to walk out the theater and I just felt
everyone was looking at me and I'm like,
that's not good.
Everyone's going to think he
doesn't like his own show.
So I just walked in and I just sat
down in the nearest empty seat,
which was it next to my wife.
I just sat there and within three
seconds of watching it, I was like,
why the fuck did I do this?
And they played three episodes.
Fortunately people were
laughing, but um, yeah,
I sat there squirming for a, a good
fucking or whatever, however long it took,
90 minutes to watch.
But fortunately everybody loved it.
Everybody can relate all different
ages and that type of shit.
So I'm hoping you're going to like it
there. I'm done. I've done promoting it.
Um, why do you feel guilty
promoting your own projects?
You know,
you deserve it and it's your podcast.
You should have the right to
talk about whatever you want. Um,
is that what Yoda would say?
But in that douchey voice,
but why do I attack star was what,
every time it comes out,
I just can't handle the fact.
Okay.
I do the same thing. You know, there's a,
there's a lot of shit that
everybody likes it. I don't like it.
And maybe I should just be like,
you know what bill, maybe, uh,
maybe have to lighten up it a little bit,
you know?
Okay.
No, you know what I mean? You bought,
why don't you just let people like what
the fuck they like. I like Scifi that,
that fucking Sam Rockwell movie moon.
Did you guys see that? I liked that one.
I like Stanley Kubrick space. 1990 now.
The fuck was it called last
computer on ours. I'm sorry Brian.
I can't do or whether the fuck he
used to say 2001, a space odyssey.
I liked that movie Mo.
Uh,
so say Moonraker that was struck in James
Bond when he was in the space shuttle.
That wasn't it. Blade
runner. I liked that one.
I like those ones set in the future where
everybody lost their rights and we're
out of fucking natural resources.
Those are the ones I like, you know,
and then they got to fight back against,
oh fuck. Am I explaining it? I
think I'm describing star wars,
I guess it says self help.
I don't know what it is.
All right. You know what I'll say.
You know what? It's too nice there.
That's what it is. It's just too
fucking nice. You know what I mean?
Like they got a couple of malls out
here in la. They both called the grove.
You then you go down there,
right?
And it's all brand new and they got this
stupid fucking trolley going down the
center, right. Making it look like
it's this old style town. And you know,
it only runs like a hundred yards
and then it just turns around again.
But when you're in the middle of
this mall, you know, and that plane,
Sinatra and Tony Bennett,
if I ruled the world every day would be
the first day of spring and you fuck,
you're walking around,
there's a trolley, you fail,
you get a little spring in your step
and then it hits you. Like, dude,
I'm going into the gap.
Okay.
Uh, buying a bunch of Shit I
don't need, what am I doing here?
They create this whole fucking
atmosphere that's so fucking nice.
It uh, oh, it drives me up the wall.
I got to come with something positive.
You know what the most positive thing I
saw this this past week was I saw, um,
I saw these kids playing two on two
football in a basketball court at a,
when I was in New York that time when I
had the fight with the person at the gym.
So I went to that outdoor place.
You could do pull ups and uh,
I dunno, he just never see
that. You never see it anymore.
Which kids did that more, you
know, I wish kids weren't so fat.
I wish they'd go outside the house,
you know,
but you can't let them out
of the house now. Right.
Everybody is a fucking pervert
by having every fucking tree.
You know, they should give kids guts.
Yeah, just hear me. I said give,
if you give kids guns,
just somebody goes to snatch your beak.
It just fucking pull his gun out,
blow the guy's braids out.
And then if they shot each other, as
sad as that would be, it would probably,
it would definitely obviously help the
population problem. You know what I mean?
Cause one of them would be dead and
the other one would be going to jail.
That will be FBI would just
sticky when this place, you know,
you like leaning it stabbed.
That's weird, right?
It's desperate times.
You know,
someone's trying to tell me to watch
something that was trying to say that
fucking Miami is going to be
like finished in 10 years. Miami,
New Orleans, all of these fucking places.
And I was just like, dude, I don't,
I don't want to hear that. You know,
I'm, I'm going to be one of those guys.
They're going to figure something out.
I think everybody's saying that
all the way up to the top. Um,
so anyways, hey, I'll put my bro, it's,
they've been winning lately
and I had been so busy,
I haven't watched last
night I watched the uh,
the second period and uh,
just long enough to watch McQuade
take a puck to the fucking mouth.
I don't remember if you've never played
hockey. I took one time, but just once.
Okay. I'm played a lot of hockey
in my life. Just one fucking time.
One fucking time.
I took a risk off my big fucking toe.
All right. Just some fucking
novice guy. We were in Canada,
so it's probably a better wrist shot
than I would have run into down here.
I took it right off the firewall,
you know,
I wasn't doing anything in the game so
I wanted to do something productive for
my team.
I was like a minus 53 minutes into
play and pick up hockey and a I.
For some reason I decided
to block a shot in a,
in a pickup game when I had
a standup gigs at night.
It hit right off the inside of my, the
arch in my foot, in my fucking toe.
I felt like I got shot in the foot
and it didn't even hit me that hard.
This guy took a professional fucking
thank God it wasn't a slap shot. It was,
I think it was a wrist or took,
he wa he fucking turned
around to see what was up,
like where were the puck was
and it was like right there.
It's like when Tom Brady throws to
pass, you know, before you even turn,
the ball's already come and you're like,
oh shit. Right. If you've got like me,
you break your finger cause you didn't,
you didn't open them wide enough,
quick enough. Right. Um, took
it right in the fucking mouth.
That's it. And he's rolling around on
the ice and he announced, he's just like,
well fortunately you don't need
teeth to play hockey. Now was it,
could you imagine if a soccer player
took a fucking puck to the mouth,
he'd still be lying there.
He will be riding in the stands.
They had tear gas and all that
type of shit. Um, but anyways,
I am completely out of the loop with
that is one of my random picks for this
week. All right. If you're a gambling
man, if you're going on that draft king,
so that whatever,
if you go in old school and
you're actually betting a
team rather than players,
you know, um, I like the giants this
weekend. How do you know how many,
I don't even know how many fucking
points to get. I don't even,
I don't even know how many.
Let me see how many fucking points again,
they're playing the fucking panthers.
So I think everybody's going to be like,
all right, the panthers are
going to fucking kill him.
They're going to give the giants all
these fucking points cause everybody's
gonna bet the panthers.
You're going to get all these
extra points and I'm telling you,
fucking Odell Beckham and
Eli are going to be enough,
even though the giants have no defense.
Let me see. Right? That giants,
panthers bedding lie. Oh,
spread when I used to that.
That's easier. Huh? Though?
What's the fucking spread?
I launched last week too,
but lifetime. Lifetime.
I'm up like 660 bucks on the book, right?
Isn't that what all your friends say?
Nobody's ever, he admits. Nobody
knows what the fuck they figure is.
The second you gambled for more
than three weeks, you have no idea.
Okay,
dude, lifetime. Maybe
I'm the giants. Panthers,
odds to giants have a chance
against unbeaten. Carolina. Uh,
let's see here.
Just give me the fucking line.
I hate this new era.
I really do.
Draftkings they have all kinds of fucking
shit wasn't eighth I was going to bet
on, you know, Odell Beckham,
just him odds point spread week 15.
All right. The weekly odds,
where is it? Where is it?
Line Carolina minus four. That's it. Yeah.
Okay.
What the fuck is that game
under rovers 49. All right. You know what?
Fuck that I wanted eight gimme a
fucking points. I'd Bet Carolina.
What's the Games in New
York? You know, Bill,
he kind of helps you fucking looked
it up before you got involved in this,
wouldn't it? What have
helped. I don't give a shit.
All right. Anyways, let's,
let's plow ahead here. So I
gotta get my shit together,
man. I have, I have not
been working out and uh,
but I've been kind of maintaining and
I also haven't been doing that much
standup cause I've been promoting this
show and I got to get my fucking ass
ready for this, uh, for this
New Year's Eve shelf. Um,
and that starts tonight.
If you're in La,
I'll be done the laugh factory and
I'll be uh, at the comedy store,
although by the time they post this to
chose a, probably already have happened.
So that didn't make any sense. Did it? All
right. I don't know where this is going.
Hang on a second. Let me, let me look
up some shit, man. Give me something.
Give me something to talk
about here. Right. You don't,
what if you noticed lately I've had to
hit the pause button a lot. I think.
I think I'm coming to the end of
this podcast or at the very least,
at some point I'm going to have
to have a fucking guest. Right,
okay.
I mean, after a while
you just see, I mean,
when it gets to the point
you're making pie crust videos,
I'm pretty much at the
end of my rope here.
People telling me told you should
make some more fucking videos.
It's like there's nothing else that I
kind of know how to make that interesting,
I don't think.
Right.
I Dunno.
I have no idea.
We're finally getting the fucking my
house fixed up on the outside. You know,
the gates and everything
were falling down. It's never
ending. It's never ending.
I think when I get that fixed,
then I got to move on to the garage,
that hunk of Shit,
I'm never going to get my money back.
And I'm just doing this stubborn German
Irish shtick that I don't give a fuck
and I'm doing everything first
class. I don't give a fuck. Well,
we could use this PC shit.
Uh,
we could use this one that's
decent or we could use the tub
top of the line.
I'm like fucking John Bender. You know
when, when the press and breakfast club,
when he's going, I got you to Saturday.
She wanted another one. He's like, yes,
that's Drake.
Good
as with the construction people are
doing. Yeah. You know, uh, we, we,
we found another fucking problem.
It's going to cost another three grand.
Okay.
You want another, I'll keep digging.
I'll keep looking in your fucking walls.
The is really no sympathy here,
man.
This is my own God damn fault for buying
a 90 something year old to a hundred.
Yeah. 92 year old house. It's
my own fucking fault. Um,
and I have to be honest with you, I think
I'm over old shit. I think I'm over it.
Like the next house I buy is going
to be totally fucking modern.
Brand new,
you know,
just conk fucking two,
three concrete slabs.
Looked like a parking garage.
Now just build some walls around it.
Everything's going to be brand
fucking new and up to code. I've uh,
I, I've just, I've had it,
I've had it every motherfucking thing
cause you know what it is about this house
is it's settled to over the
last 90 something years, right?
So everything's fucking cockeyed and
twist it and all that type of shit.
So when they go to fix something,
they always go, well, you know,
this isn't really square and it's going
to look dumb. So I got a square it up.
So I go, hey, square it up. You know,
go ahead and square it up enough.
I just come walking out, you know,
at this point, anytime anyone he
could structure and talks to me,
I immediately decided my
eyes are squinting. I got
my fucking eyebrow furrowed.
Like, just, you know, I'm doing
that. Come on, come on, come on.
Just tell me how much it's going to be.
Wait, where do I sign? Yeah, go ahead.
Don't give a fuck. I'll be on the road
forever. Don't mind me. Don't mind me.
I'm just a guy just to
guide, pay in for it. Um,
but seriously, eventually
I have to do, uh, you know,
I got to Redo my fucking piece of shit.
Fucking do it yourself.
Tree fort of a garage and um,
I got a slip that one by the wife,
you know,
they're all about the shit that's in
their world, you know what I mean?
But the garage, which is funny,
which is where most, you know,
most guys who live with women,
you end up in the garage.
So when you say you want to do something
to the garage, like your wife is just,
I don't understand what
he's talking about.
His stick around and faces the garage.
Anyway, I just, I just feel like,
I feel like that's the place
where we just drop shit off.
You know?
I would eventually like to do a,
put a little bit of a gym in there.
That's what I should,
if I just had some fucking
here, but I heard this fucking,
those, those treadmills,
it's like running like 15
refrigerators at the same time.
So when I'm thinking of doing here me out,
this is my plan,
redoing the garage and on top of you
make it solar powered so it's just
completely off the fucking grid.
Right.
And then I can maybe guilt free,
have some sort of fucking elliptical
assumption that would tell you the time
when I was living with Bobby Kelly,
Robert Kelly from uh,
um Oh sex and drugs and
rock and roll a right.
He plays the drummer. We used to live
together and he was such a pack rat.
He used to just bring shit
in off of the fucking street.
And I remember one time I was kind of
living back and forth between La and New
York and I came back from La,
it's like the late nineties and he had
taken from off the street the most boot
leg fucking stairmaster
I'd ever seen in my life.
I swear to God it was made out of like,
I don't even know what I mean.
It was whatever the material was,
it just qualified to be metal.
I remember it was white with these red
stripes and you got on the fucking thing
and it had this little digital
clock and you'd start going on it.
And as you held the handles,
like any sort of body weight with
like sort of the whole thing,
fucking moved like the
frame that it was on.
And I remember he got it and he stuffed
it over in the corner and I just went
like, I was like, Bobby, what the
fuck is that? He was like, dude, wait,
talking about dude, you're fucking to
stem as to, I got it off the sidewalk.
I got it for free. Do you want
to use it? It's like, no, dude,
I'll go to the gym. Fucking Jim's like
15 bucks a month. It gives a shit.
So, uh, I remember watching him using it
one time and I was laughing my balls off
because he weighed like, and um, he
wasn't, you know, the size he is now.
I'm not trying to make fun of him here.
He just was,
he was 10 times the size of the thing.
It looked like it was built for an eight
year old and he was over in the corner
and it's a little ass
fucking liver numbers.
I'm trying to watch this little kitchen
TV that we had that was sitting on this
TV VCR. Oh my God. TV,
VCR Stan that I made in wood class,
like my junior or senior year in high
school that I gave to my dad and he was
supposed to put the TV on top of it and
then underneath it was the VCR and then
it had to drug doors that opened on the
bottom like cabinets and in there you
put all your VHS tapes. My Dad
took the fucking, I gave it to him.
He took the back off the thing
and he stuck the TV underneath it.
It was so stupid. Yet a lay on the
Florida fucking watch it. Who's classic?
My Dad like he's just, I guess I'm
like Kim, like I just see shit.
I don't see it for what it is. And
then people look at me like, dude,
the fuck is run. That same way that when
I stand in front of a stage, a stage,
a stove, and it says turn on
the front burner. To me it's,
it's what everybody else
considers the backburner.
Because the way I look at the stove is
it's like I'm standing behind a car.
I don't know why.
Okay.
Did I just look at it like, I don't
know. Maybe it's my low self esteem.
Like I'm standing in the back of the line.
So the front of the lines guy,
I have no fucking idea.
So he took the back off it and
shoved the TV under there and a,
I remember all my friends who also took
shop class when they would come over my
house like years later drink and they'd
be like, to, what the fuck is a TV?
And I was like, dude, don't even, I don't
even want to tell you I met with my dad,
took the back off,
he ripped the shelf out.
He just stuck the TV down
there and they were laughing.
They thought it was the funniest fucking
thing. Ever Day one, here you go, dad,
you know, merry Christmas or
whatever. And Yeah, just fucking,
he modified it. So anyway, so I, yeah,
when I moved out I got it back minus
the back or the shelf and I finally,
I remember it was a proud moment that I
put this little piece of shit TV on top
of it,
so that things sitting on top,
we got a VCR underneath it and then a
bunch of fucking tapes and shit like water
boy and all that stuff that was fucking
was coming out in the late nineties. And,
uh, we had all these Adam Sandler movies
and all this shit that was in there.
So I'm sitting down, oh my
God, it's spring break. We,
I had a fucking couch and uh,
and uh, like a lazy boy that,
but it didn't recline that
okay.
Was From my dad's dental office
from the early seventies.
So it had this horrific floral pattern
and it was made out of this wood that
weighed like 9 million.
It took like 10 guys to pick up the
fucking sofa and of course it was busted.
Um,
okay.
So I'm sitting there, right. And I'm,
I'm in the fucking lazy
boy that doesn't recline.
And Bobby's over in the corner on this
fucking hunk of shit. Stair master.
I'm trying to watch TV and he's over in
the corner. Go ahead. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fucking sweating and shit.
And I'm laughing at my
balls off. He's to fuck you.
Stop making me laugh. Did Right. He's,
he's trying to go on this thing and uh,
okay.
Oh, is this the day? I may
be. I may be combining days.
I just remember going into the bathroom
and as I was in the bathroom, you
walked out like the giant, Ooh,
this big living room. You, he
was a railroad apartment, right?
So you walked to the right,
he's in the back left of the room.
I walked to the right and then immediately
make a right into the bathroom.
So it's like a fucking hairpin turn.
So I go in and take a piss
and as I come walking out,
Bobby get picked up a racket ball
and threw it as hard as he could.
Okay.
To hit the wall. It Rekesh. It
was a perfect shot. Records,
she couldn't even see me
ricocheted off the wall,
came right in and hit me right in the
mouth and like split my lip a little bit,
my lip.
And I remember I had an audition to do
Conan O'Brien that night at the fucking,
uh,
at the comic strip
and I was so fucking mad at
him and he was dying laughing.
Cause see what it was like
a one in a million shot.
It was literally like Larry Bird,
you know,
off the fucking camper off the house,
Blah Blah, blah. Nothing but net.
Like he couldn't even see me.
He was on this fucking piece of shit.
Stair mastery farm from an off to Simon
and he fucking just fire this thing hit
me right in the God damn mouth. So I
just sit there and put pressure on it.
And he kept saying he was sorry,
but I knew he wasn't. And uh,
then I had to get them back and that's
what it was like living with him.
Ah Fuck Man. I don't know how it came
up with that. And that was a long, long,
long ass time where I moved into the end
of that place in 1995 and I moved out,
I want to say in 2000,
um,
this fucking railroad apartment.
And I had a walkthrough bedroom and
this little single mattress bed mattress
fucking thing, just sitting on a
frame. And I remember my roommate,
this Nigerian dude who was into the
Rangers, played hockey and all that shit.
He, uh, he had to walk through our,
like my bedroom to get either to
okay,
his bedroom or to go into the basic
railroad apartment means it's just side by
side.
So when his bedroom and then my little
half a bedroom and then the living room,
then there was a little hallway with
the bathroom and then the kitchen and it
was all just lined right up, like, uh,
people standing in line for
some coffee or some shit.
So he had to walk through my
bedroom. So obviously, um,
there was a tremendous lack of fucking
privacy and I remember living there.
And then when I,
I started living in La,
I like sublet it out to Bobby.
And then the roommate was cool to let
me come back when I was in New York to
crash. They for like a week or so, we were
all young guys. We didn't give a fuck,
right. So it was fine. And
um, I remember after a while,
a couple of years of being
there, I remember Bobby
telling me going like, dude,
we'll be talking about getting
them an apartment. Like,
do we should just get an apartment.
I can't fucking do this anymore.
I can't live like this anymore. We living
like, fuck, we will live in like animals.
And uh,
okay.
I remember Bobby just go,
dude, I just want a door.
I just want a door to a room
that's mine that I can close.
And uh, and I remember just sitting
like, oh my God, that'd be unbelievable.
Like that was the big,
that was the big fantasy back then
to just have a fucking door
that you could close. MMM.
Jesus Christ. Was that 20 fucking years
ago? I guess it was. I'm an old man.
All right. It's time for some
fucking advertising here.
Uh, for the holiday season.
You guys enjoy star wars? I just, I just,
it's just such an easy target
to make fun of a, okay,
here we go. Here we go. All right.
The advertising. Oh my. What am I,
one of my new favorites.
Everybody. Kalib. Debbie club.
Dubby club. Debbie, my dad
knows how to ride a horse.
A don't you hate when
wine looks like a 10, but,
but winds up look tasting like a six or
even worse when you walk into the store
to pick out your wine,
you could easily be fooled into
a situation just like this.
Well now there's this new wine
club called club Debbie clubbed.
Gabby had care. Uh,
they've changed everything.
No more being fooled by winds that
pretends to be hotter or tastier than they
actually are.
It's easy.
You just go to club debbie.com
and answer simple questions.
Their algorithm creates a
palate profile just for you.
Then they send you wine
directly to your door,
perfectly customized to match
your taste at glub. Debbie, hey,
can't America safe is leading the
grape to glass wine revolution.
They worked directly with the vineyards,
the vineyards to cut out the middle man,
which saves you money. This
is great, man. Pick, you know,
you gotta be totally into wind to
know what fucking wine is. Good man.
You gotta be one of those people. So
why not have these people do it for you,
right? Have, who do
for you, who do it for.
You can even talk club Debbie Club,
Debbie Donald Rosales,
a friend of mine,
you get premium wine customized.
Your tasted a third of
what you paid his store.
They even have a no risk hundred percent
guarantee that you're gonna love.
You're gonna love what the Sandy and
Ride Nad Club dubby and for Daddy's.
Got a ranch is offering my
listeners 50% off your first order.
Then go to club Debbie at.com/burr stop
wasting time and money messing around at
retail stores and start drinking wine.
Uh, you know you're going to love.
Just go to club Debbie [inaudible] dot
com slash burner to get 50% off your
first order. That's clubbed.
Debbie had dotcom slash burr food.
We want, she not going to fool me again.
Um, and he was, let's end on this.
Uh, I've been watching, um,
was it Fargo the entire
fucking, uh, season?
I watched such great TV, man,
I'm telling you, bloodline,
peaky blinders and I'm watching
the second season of Fargo and a,
there's an actor on there, Jesse
Plemons, who I actually, I did. Uh,
I never really had a scene with them,
but I worked the same day on breaking
bad with them when we did the a train
robbery thing. And uh,
I got tell you man is
his fucking act. He's an astoundingly
talented guy, man. That guy is,
he's like that guy has an Oscar
in m and a and also Chris,
is it Kirsten? Kirsten Dunst. Like
the two of them, man, I fuck every,
everybody on the show is
obviously amazing, but the
two of them have been, uh,
have been me and my wife's favorite
man. Um, so check that out.
If you guys know anything. I'm kind
of in between shows right now. Um,
and I got time to binge watch shows.
So if you guys,
and you can watch my show F is for family
and about two and a half, three hours.
Um, but if you guys know of anything
else good that you're watching,
please let me know cause uh, I'm on a
nice roll here. All right, well listen,
that's the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
We're going to close out here with a
little bit of music picked by Andrew,
Sam Willis, and then we're
going to have some, uh,
some throwback greatest hits
stuff from podcasts gone by.
Um, if I don't talk to you, have a
merry Christmas, I'm fucking with you.
How many days away is that?
I was not,
I will do another couple of podcasts
before that. Oh, it's next Friday.
Isn't that something? Um, all right.
And happy Hanukkah to everybody.
I didn't say that. Mandy, did you
enjoy the nine? Is it nine days?
How did Adam Sandler song
got me days or in Hanukkah?
I should know that on the
first day of Hanukkah,
my true love gave to me
shopped in fucking nice
fucking soup for you.
How many days I should know
this. It's a Menorah, right?
How many days in Hanukkah?
How many days does eight days?
Eight days. Get the fuck out
either. Why is it nine candles?
Yeah.
Hanukkah period last for eight days. And
then they get, they get nine candles.
I don't understand it.
Is that like Michael Jackson and the
Jacksons and they stopped being in the
Jackson five? Um, not
whenever. Okay. That's it.
I'm done. Uh, you gotta you can't,
you have a great weekend and I'll talk to
you on Monday. Bye. Right glitch. Go Pam.
[inaudible]
those guys always get on Monday.
Cross country, fucking flight. So anyways,
there was this adorable
woman next to me and uh,
she was from Australia,
had the little fucking accent
and all that type of shit.
So what have long story short,
we've taken off from JFK and
one of the runways shut down.
So it's taken for fucking ever write
a couple of people on the plane or in
wheelchairs. So that takes more time. You
know, you prefer bial fat fucks, you know,
the whole deal. So, uh,
we take off like an hour and a half late.
Is it just the whole fucking thing.
The bedtime, we land, we
land, there's no gate.
And then we got to sit there and wait
to get towed into the whole thing is
taking forever and sheets does this
shit was, she just goes, she says,
she goes as is everything in America slow,
you know,
so I let it slide and then the plane
lands and we're all trying to see who won
the Celtics and the Lakers cause
we all miss the fucking game.
Thank God ESPN showed the replay.
I caught the second half and it goes
around the plane, like wildfire fire,
you know the Celtics won,
Celtics won and this girl Maya,
we're always joking about
how much people gives a shit.
And then this girl makes comics something
that, you know, Americans fucking Blah,
blah blah blah. And it's
just like, you know what,
I let it slide with the first fucking war,
but it's just really like,
they always talk about
the ignorant American.
What kind of a fucking asshole comes here
from another country and shits on the
country to somebody who's from this
country. When I was over in England,
I didn't walk around saying the English
people how fucking awful their torsos
where I didn't do that. They
said I enjoyed England. I'm
like, it's fucking great.
I can't believe I'm over here.
Royal Albert Hall. It's beautiful.
I can't wait to come over here again.
Phenomenal fucking city.
I didn't say your food sucks. You
guys all have will. Pharrel mushy.
Torsos I didn't say any of that shit.
I didn't talk about your
teeth being fucked up.
I didn't talk about the weird inbred
look because you've all been fucking each
other and the same God damn strip of
land for fucking thousands of years.
I didn't do that shit.
I was on my best behavior and here I am
sitting next to this fucking clam who's
everything in America
slow as opposed to what?
That beacon of speed
that fucking Australia is
fucking people. You know,
I went to Australia, I was
there for like three days.
I had a good time down there, but you
know, I could've picked that place apart.
All the unemployed people
just sitting in bars drinking.
Okay.
I fucking hate, you know, same
fucking cunts. Same Goddamn just cuts.
That's all it is.
Everybody taking pot shots in America now.
That's what it is because we've been on
top and we'd been exploiting their labor
and I guess maybe that's maybe we
deserve a little bit of that shit,
but you know what to look in the
fucking mirror Australia or a woman from
Australia.
Yeah,
the fuck I went there. I wasn't so like,
wow, like I was going into the future.
Can I have a ham and then the fucking
sandwiches right in my hand before I even
finish it. I didn't find them to
be overly fast over there either.
You wait, you fucking wait. You
think it's not coming your way?
Our corporations are just ahead of the
curve of where where your corporations
are.
Are corporations have basically every
last legal way that they can make more
fucking money over here,
so now they're just stealing.
They're just stealing and they're
cut and fucking staff members.
I actually had to wait like a half hour,
40 minutes to get my bag last night.
I think it was that Sunday thing.
Once again, it's Sunday, it's Sunday.
So we just have like a skeleton crew.
I Dunno all I'm saying, you know,
it's just bugging me.
It's like,
do you think I know that that shit
isn't a little fucked up over here?
Do I need you to come over here?
I would never be in Australia and go like,
yeah, Australians to another
fucking Australian. You know,
that's the type of shit I should felt
like fucking stuffing her in a god damned
boogie board bag. Boogie board
bag. What did I pick that?
Because I saw that documentary of that
stupid fuck from Australia who put 200
pounds of fucking weed
into a boogie board bag.
Right alliteration for you
and then goes to like Bali,
you know with even have cold medication,
they hang you by your balls in the public
square and she gets life in prison.
Well that's what you get. You
dumped. Fuck. That's what you get.
That's one of my theknot fuck
Australia. That's how it works. You see?
And that's how it works right there.
There's a lot of people in Australia
right now, maybe listen to the shit gone.
You know, I would never say that. I
would never do that if I went. Yeah,
well one he did.
So there you go.
Do you think Germany likes to be
judged by Hitler alone? They don't.
I bet there's a lot of
sweethearts over in Germany.
Look at all those fucking fat jolly
people during October fest running around,
dressed like they're in Hansel and
Gretel, you know, shitting on each other.
Whatever weird fetishes
they're into over there.
[inaudible]
I've started their season at zero and zero
with the holy as amped up the kick the
shit out of them as people were amped up
to beat the fucking patriots
it by mid November. All right,
and I'm telling you right now, they are
going to have a mediocre fucking season.
I think it's going to start
off with the loss tonight.
I'm not saying that they're not going
to go nine and seven, but these guys,
I don't know what their fucking problem
is and not to mention that now they have
a nice little scandal cover the daily
news. They says cool. Your jets,
TV reporter flags team for Lewd behavior.
Um,
Ean is saints reporter for as a TV.
Where the fuck is that broadcast?
It's is at the center of a jet Brouhaha.
Basically, if you see this girl,
she's fucking hottie right?
She's got her little pass here and uh,
you know,
she's got some Cleveland show.
Oh my God. Are you serious?
They got a picture of
her at a jets practice.
She's got on the tightest fucking jeans
I've ever seen in my life with the most
perfect round ass you've ever seen.
And she's in high heels.
Okay.
And she's walking around a bunch of
football players who got that testosterone
going with a fat shit talk and coach,
let me guess.
Somebody said something out of
line. Oh, this is just, this is,
you know what I mean?
This right here,
and this is one of these
things where you can't say,
well look how you're dressed. Cause
they go, you're blaming the victim.
She should have a right to have three
quarters of her tits outside of her shirt
with a thong going up
her fucking ass crack.
And she should be allowed to walk into
a locker room with a bunch of football
players and not have one out of fucking
whatever the fuck you're going to say.
Well, one fucking rude
comic. Gimme a break.
Nfl boss Roger Goodell was
demanding answers last night
from jets players. Well,
why don't you look at
the pictures, Roger. Huh?
What are you a fucking unique? You don't
understand what the problem was. Uh,
for players,
coaches accused of subjecting a female
sports reporter to sexist locker room
conduct, they should've just said for
subjecting her to locker room conduct.
This is basically what happened.
She went into a locker room and was
subjected to lock a rump conduct.
Can you believe it?
I remember last night when I went out
to a bar and I was subjected to bar rum
conduct. I couldn't
believe it. I was like,
what am I in a bar or something as they
prepare for their season opener tonight,
gang green is dealing with a burgeoning
scandal over the treatment of Inez
Saints, uh, for Azteca of
Mexico. This girl is a 10.
She's fucking smoking gorgeous.
You've got to see the way she's dressed.
Okay.
And Fuck You lady. Fuck you. Look at the
way she's dressed. She's one of those,
you know what's funny about the broads
out there is this is the kind of girl,
all right, the kind of woman that kind
of fucking who were, who, if you know,
if any of these women, you know,
well listen to his podcast,
they're walking down the street with
their husband and this girl comes walking
by, they immediately, they take fucking,
you know when the eyes become like little
slits, is he looking at them? You know,
and then they're looking at their
husband and they're going to get mad you
because this other bitch goes to the gym.
You know,
like somehow it's your fucking fault
and they fucking looking at you because
they can't just come out and say, oh
my God, that girl is fucking gorgeous.
I'm so jealous of her. They, they
can't, they can't own that emotion.
So then they look at you and they're just
waiting for you to glance in that part
and that woman's direction so
they can blame you. That does.
Fuck another girl is eating right and,
and fucking doing herself up. Right?
It's going to become your fucking fault.
I used to do a bit about that.
Next time you, you know it.
Here's one for you guys on a burn,
a joke right here that I never fucking
record it. So who gives a shit?
Next time you're walking down the
street with your girlfriend, right?
And this fucking unbelievably smoking
shit comes walking up the street, right?
And what do you got? And she
immediately just looks at you like,
go ahead and look at her.
So I can take out my fucking hatred of
this better looking girl and make it your
fucking fault, right? This is what you do.
Rather than trying to look away
and having blood come out of your,
out of your eyes,
you try not to look at this fucking
hot piece of it's coming up the street.
What you do is you fucking point right
at her and whatever she's wearing,
you tell your girl that she'd look
right in that you point right.
And it'd be like, you know what? You
look great in a dress like that, right?
And then immediately just
a p, you know it, it makes
Samran security go. Oh my God.
Really? Do you think I could
get away with wearing something?
They totally used to girls feeling good.
You're staring at the girl's ass.
You're talking about the cut of
the dress. You, it's bullshit.
You're checking around without
disrespecting your woman. See right there.
Bill Burke bringing couples together.
All right, let's continue on here. Um,
so this woman, 32 years old, 32 years old,
still in smoking fucking shape,
a former miss universe
contestant complained.
She was bombarded with cat calls
and boarish antics at the jets,
New Jersey training facility to the extent
she wanted to end to end quotes said
cover my ears. Um, dying oven, barest.
This woman,
right?
Former Miss Universe contestant who
would walk on stage with a fucking string
bikini and high heels with a hoo ha
hanging out talking about how to save
Greenland or whatever is
embarrassed because she walked
around. I mean, give me a,
you know what I mean?
This is why women stink.
It's like,
what are you doing there to begin with?
It's a bunch of guys playing football.
It's like,
and then we're cool enough
to let you win there.
And then everybody has to fucking adjust
their behavior because your there wake,
excuse me, excuse me.
There's a lady present.
You know what I mean? And you'll
wonder why you get called a cunt.
That's why. Right fucking there.
It's just fucking unbelievable.
I would never walk into a god damn baby
shower be, oh, excuse me. Excuse me.
There's a guy present.
Can we put fucking game on Ovia I wasn't.
I'd be standing in the corner gone. Oh
Gee Gee, when is this Shit gonna be over?
But I wouldn't at any point try to cock
block what anybody was fucking talking
about.
Go ahead and talk about sex in the city.
Talk about your favorite shoes or
whatever the fuck it is you do.
I wouldn't be covering my
ears dying of embarrassment.
If you all started talking about
my package, I'd be flattered.
MMM.
This is some of the more and more ignorant
shit that I've said on this podcast.
But I think there's a point behind this.
I'll, let's continue with the article.
MMM,
good. Hell is she said, I'm dying of
embarrassment. Saints tweeted in Spanish,
um,
Goodell immediately ordered
an investigation into the
troubling in air quotes,
allegations, which were addressed
in a team meeting last night. Uh,
this meeting is now called to order,
uh,
last night when that smoking hot chick
with the tight clothes came in and
everybody said, God Damn, look
at that fucking ass. Yeah,
you're not allowed to do that anymore.
Uh,
she excuse to coach. Uh,
yeah. Yes sir. Yeah, we'll,
you're talking about that
girl who came in or a Teddy's,
we're hanging out of her shirt.
Yeah. That one. Yeah. That one.
We a disrespected her.
See, this is, this is the deal.
All right. They come down,
they want the fucking attention. You
know what? Wait, what? What is she,
what is she doing in the fucking
locker room to begin with?
You know what? She even in the locker
room, did I even, they even say that,
I can't remember. Didn't you see any given
Sunday? You don't remember that movie?
You're gonna stand there and there's
gonna be some black dude with a dick down
to the floor. I mean,
why are you going in?
I wouldn't go in there if I went in there,
they'd start giving me cat calls like I
was at fresh fish guy in the beginning
of shot,
Shawshank redemption,
and I'd be dying of embarrassment too,
but I'd fucking take it. It'd be like, ah,
well what the fuck did you
think was going to happen?
You're a fucking pansy and you
come in and do an NFL locker room.
They're all going to give you shit
and say you're a pussy, right? I mean,
what kind of a fucking
world are we living in now?
When a gorgeous woman wearing tight,
ridiculous clothes,
it's going to walk into a fucking at a
football practice and she's going to get
upset that she got unwanted attention.
Well,
why don't you come there and dress like
they did in the 18 hundreds with one of
the big hoop skirts so they
can't see you fucking thighs.
This chick is fucking ridiculous.
Look,
look at the New York Daily News and look
at the little inset picture that they
have of her. I'm sure they did it for
a fucking reason. It's ridiculous.
Look at that fucking ass. Look at
it. That's the first thing I think.
Look at that fucking ass. Jesus
Christ. And then she's holding a mic.
Looks like a dick in her hand while she
bobbing her head up and down and she
asked the questions.
This is like entrapment.
Okay.
Anyways, let's fucking
continue. Um, but, but proper,
we've had contact with the team multiple
times and are moving very aggressively
to establish the facts.
The NFL spokesman, Greg,
I Hilo said jets owner woody Johnson
woke up from his coma and said,
oh, wait, that guy no off.
That guy's actually young, uh,
called saints to hear or side
of the story, uh, said that,
that the team will take any appropriate
steps necessary to maintain a respectful
environment for the media.
Basically,
this girl is now going to become a
fucking millionaire off of this lawsuit
because she walked to an NFL practice
with her Miss Universe body with tight
fucking clothes on. And
somebody said, God Damn,
look at that fucking ass right there.
Hey mark.
What the fuck would you do with dad?
I fucking bed over flubbing table.
Okay,
and then fucking rex. Ryan. I can't even
see him. I fucking my fucking stomach.
So big. Huh? Was that a good one? Players.
Do you guys like me? I talk just like you.
I can't wait for them
to fucking lose tonight.
[inaudible]
all right,
let's get on to stuff that I want to
bitch about this week. All
right? I know a lot of you guys,
you probably think on some level
then. I hate women. All right?
And I gotta be honest with you.
You fucking right.
I don't like hate him individually,
but as a group,
they fucking annoying me because
they're always complaining, bitch,
moaning and all this fucking crap. Unlike
me who just always brings to sunshine.
I, this is the thing, whatever it comes
down to, male, female relationships.
What I've noticed on television is
that if someone's going to be the dose,
it's always the guy. If somebody
is at fault, it's always the guy.
If somebody's going to pay,
it's always the guy except for the
occasional Britney spears. All right. Who,
if I ever see a binder, a fucking
beer for growth, that bum ass husband,
right?
Backup dancers sitting around the house
getting fat sitting in sweatpants that
she paid for.
You know she ever went over there
and slap the shit out of him,
smashed him on his head with one of her
book dazzled high heels and I was on
that jury. I would say not
guilty. I would say not guilty.
I would say she's a fucking hero that
she hasn't done it yet. Um, here's,
here's a story for you.
These are the stories.
I'm just going to put this out here cause
I'm really hoping that this is going
to eat.
It inspires somebody to start some sort
of [inaudible] adulation or whatever the
fuck you need to do to turn things
around. Because I really, in this country,
there's a major problem.
Women are organized and guys are not
when it comes to this relationship shit.
All right. Oh, you go right ahead and roll
your eyes. Ladies. I don't give a fuck.
This isn't for you.
All right?
Here's a nice story is I'm gonna read one
of these every fucking week to fucking
people realize what is going on. All
right? What is not, not what is going on.
What is also going on is
every fucking three minutes.
I got to watch the story about some poor
woman who got the living shit kicked
out of her by some asshole guy,
right?
And you watch enough of those stories
and you start thinking, oh my God,
women are always the victim.
It's not.
So here's a nice story for you.
A little story called,
who knew I was not the father?
Do I even need to read it to you?
You know where this is going.
This happens all the fucking time.
But they don't talk about it.
You know,
it's not considered a
major fucking problem.
It's because guys are not organized
and we have to start bitch moaning and
complaining the way women do.
All right?
Just mentally try and imagine what
it's like to, to have a period.
And that's the mindset you need to get
in to, to make change in this country.
That's what I think. That's what I think
is needed. All right. Okay. Here we are,
boys and girls gather round. Who
Knew I was not the father. Take one.
It was July in 2007 when Mike and Mike
l s the Pennsylvania courts to declare
that he was no longer the father
of his daughter for four years.
Mike had known that the girl he had
rocked to sleep and dance with across the
living room floor was not as they say his,
the revelation from a DNA test was
devastating and prompted him to leave his
wife.
Uh,
but he had not renounced their child
cause he's a good shit cause he realizes
that the kid,
you know,
it's not the kids' fault that
her mom is a whore. You know,
sky's a stand up guy.
But he had not renounced their child.
He continued to feel that in
all the ways that mattered,
she was still his daughter
and he faithfully paid her
child support with guys a
seat. If there's a god, this guy
is going straight to heaven. Okay.
He could've been bitter.
He could've walked away.
He didn't stood in right.
So it was only when he learned that his
ex wife was about to marry the man who
she said actually was the
girl's biological father,
that Mike flipped supporting another's
man's child suddenly became unbearable.
Can you believe this woman?
Okay,
why don't they show that? Why don't they,
it's showing all these stories of guys,
bt women. What about a woman? Why don't
they show what women do? Shit like this.
Okay.
You know,
not only did she cheat on her husband.
Yeah,
she fucked a dude raw.
Not only did she fuck the dude raw,
she led a busted in them that only
did she have a fucking kid with them.
She didn't say shit to her husband.
So then make this fucking guy,
he has to find out. He sitting there,
you know, looking out, we looked in,
his kid doesn't look anything like
him and she doesn't say shifts.
So one day goes to Walgreens,
gifts will DNA tests does a little swab.
You Swab of her and then him sends
it off to you gotta be shitting me.
Labs in fucking Colorado comes back,
finds out it's not as kid.
He's absolutely fucking devastating.
His God,
their marriages over and
he's still a standup guy,
so now there's fucking whore goes back
with the guy that actually knocked her up.
Now they're living together.
Okay.
Wouldn't you think despite
the fact that she's a whore,
that maybe she wouldn't be a cunt to,
you know,
it's unbelievable.
Why not at that point,
just have the fucking real dad pay and
if for some reason the courts are making
this guy go through the motions of
writing the check, just take the check,
cashed it and give it back to the guy.
Why can't you do that?
You know why?
Because they can never have enough that
you know how guys can never have enough
pussy.
Women can never have enough stuff.
You ever noticed that even if
they have a one night stand,
they still got to get a tee shirt. You
know, they always got to get something.
I don't know if I've said that before
in this podcast, but it's fucking true.
They always got to have stuff,
you know?
And he still got this free fucking money
coming in. This bitch has got to be,
she's pimping these guys.
She's got two guys,
two guys working for God damn genius.
Also a con,
but she's a genius of
a cunt. Okay? I mean,
how dumb is that guy who actually knocked
her up? How dumb is he to marry her?
Who the fuck marry somebody who was
who? Who Marries, who makes somebody,
their wife who was already somebody
else's wife and fucked around with you?
You saw what she did. You think
she's not going to get tired of you?
You think she's not going
to go somewhere else?
Get some more dick and a little more,
you know,
foreign spackle between the fucking gams.
Unbelievable Sago.
That's Jen.
That's not misogynistic that I'm
only reason reading these stories.
What I'm doing is I'm trying to balance
out the bullshit that you see it on TV,
the bullshit vibe that only
guys cheat guys are dogs,
guys, guys, guys do all the fucking
bullshit. It's okay. We are equal,
okay?
We are equal.
We are capable of doing wonderful things
like this guy who did the right thing
by this little girl. And we're also
capable of doing horrific things. Alright?
Slapping the Shit Outta fucker.
Women's sticking their heads in the glove
box and try and see if he can get it
all the way closed. You know, we
also do shit like that. And ladies,
right?
They can be absolute angels and they
can be a steaming pile of conflict.
This woman. So there you go. That's
my little fair and balanced reporting
for this week. Go Fuck. I've
done an, I've done two hours,
two and a half hours of comedy
tonight. My new special, uh,
I'm taping this Saturday night at
the Lincoln Theater in Washington DC.
And let me tell you something, brother.
I'm fucking bringing it on this one.
All right.
I am on a mission to outdo my
last two fucking specials. Okay?
And I don't care if you conch,
don't think I did it.
I think I'm going to deal with
[inaudible].