Okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
February 11th, 2013. Um,
how are you? How's it going?
How's your week going so far?
Uh, you know what, I just
looked across my Roman,
I saw an object that reminded me of
one of my many failures this week.
I was in a rush to leave my house and,
uh,
I was taking my truck cause I was
finally going to get the brakes done.
I bought a kit to switch my fucking,
um,
I got drum brakes on my old truck.
And as much as I wanted to keep
the truck as original as possible,
just the way people text and drive
out here and there's so many people,
I just know that if I ever hit somebody
with the front end of that beautiful
truck that you know, I'm never going to
be able to replace the parts. So I'm like,
I gotta do this shit. All right.
So, uh, Christopher Titus,
very talented. Christopher Titus,
uh, he's into all of that shit.
So he tells me go out and go buy a kit,
will drive it over to my place and
we'll fucking slap this thing on.
It's going to take no more than
four hours. Bing, Bang, boom,
everything's fucking done. Right. So I'm
all excited. I bought this kit by the way,
in July of last year and it's
just been sitting in my office.
I've been using it like just, you know,
putting my legs up on it because I'm,
because life goes by that fast.
When you're as old as I am next weekend,
next week, next week. Next
thing you know, you've,
you fucking had the thing
for like six months.
So finally we set a date where like,
all right, let's fucking, let's do,
it was at Wednesday we were going to do
it. And uh, you know, I'm fucking nervous.
I don't know what I'm doing. So anyways,
I got to move the Prius out of the way.
So I move that out of the fucking way.
And I got the hazard lights on, you know,
because it's the day where the cuts
come around and they give people parking
tickets. So I bring the truck up, right.
It got to fucking choke off of
[inaudible] bring it up the fucking thing.
Right.
And in my haste,
okay,
bring in the fucking car back.
I left the hazard lights on.
So after we were done with the job,
I came home and my fucking,
the fucking car was dead and I'm like,
no big deal.
I know how to jumpstart this
fucking hybrid. I know how to do it.
I watched the AAA guy do it and I went
out and I bought one of those self
contained battery pack fucking things.
Opened the hood.
Cute little hood dead. It is. I
opened the little battery pack,
I took the little red thing
off and I can't fucking
figure out how to clip it on.
I tried to clip it on the bolt rather
than that metal tab and it didn't matter
anyways because my thing wasn't fucking
charged and I had to call AAA to have my
car jumped.
Do you realize the level of,
of like how emasculating that is.
Have somebody come over,
you know, have somebody teach you how to
your brakes. Okay. That's understandable.
All right. That's, that's
some next level shit, right?
It's fucking jumper cables out
was the one word. It's the worst.
When the guy showed up, I should have
come out of the house and address, um,
just defeated fucking man. But I,
I bit the bullet, I was like, yeah,
I can't figure out how to do it.
And he explained it.
My thing didn't work anyways and I can't
find the cord to charge the fucking
thing. So they're there, it
sits there. It sits. Actually,
I just kind of slammed that
whole thing together. Reality is,
is it took us two and a half days to
get the fucking brakes on because uh,
the back plates that you stick
the rotors on, once mark left,
the other one was mark.
Right. And we put them on,
we know the difference between left
and right, and Titus kept going,
is it me or does it look like it's kind
of like talking in like it's been what
the, you know, and I'm looking at it like
I know what's going on. Oh, you know,
it looks pretty good to me. Right.
You know, put the fucking things on.
It's rubbing. If you turn too
far to the left or the right,
you know the calipers are
going to hit the springs.
The fucking break lines weren't
long enough. The whole God damn kit.
So finally we get these people on the
phone. I'm not gonna say who they were,
but when I would finally get him on
the phone and they like, oh yeah,
we had a batch of their ma went out
and all they weren't labeled right.
I got to tell you is of the Titus and
one of the most eloquent fucking ass rip
eggs you've ever seen in your life.
Never raised his voice, never cursed.
I think you said one f bomb. But it was
a throwaway cause he was like, you know,
I've been, I'm fucking here for
three days. Like one of those things.
Not saying you're a fucking asshole,
but other than that never cursed.
And he just basically went
right down the line like a,
so you knew these were labeled wrong
and you didn't call anybody these,
this is a safety issue.
And the guy at first would not admit any
wrongdoing to the point was hilarious.
He wouldn't have been any wrongdoing at
one point. I swear to God, he goes, well,
did you look at the picture?
Oh, in defense of them,
the picture was right,
but the picture was like the size of
maybe three postage stamps and it was in
black and white. And it was very confusing
because you couldn't quite see it,
but you kind of could.
But it was written clear as day left and
right. So what are you going to go with?
What I can barely see or
what I can clearly read.
That's what we went with and uh Oh my God.
And then we finally got that out of
them and then we fucking switch to them.
And then it worked like a dream.
But the great thing was,
was trying to figure it out.
We put them on and take,
took them off like I think
at least three times.
So I kinda got three like,
um,
okay.
It's almost like I did three,
three brake jobs.
I got like that level of experience
and I got to tell you, it was,
it was the fucking coolest thing ever
to finally do something like that to see
how it all goes together.
It was absolutely a fascinating and um,
I dunno,
tidy since the shit because he would not,
he could have just slapped it on and
be like, Hey, go take a team mechanic.
I don't what the fuck's going on?
He was determined to get this
thing on correctly. And he did.
And when he found out it was messed up,
he went to bat for me any so eloquently
reading these guys that they actually
gave me a credit on the kit.
So it didn't cost me a fucking dime.
How great is that? And then we said, oh,
you guys are all right now we're going to
send him some DVDs and it's all a wash.
So I finally, that was was three, two
and a half days of that fucking shit.
And then I finally do auto
zone like fucking nine times.
And every time I came into auto zone I
was a little more tired and a little more
dirty.
Nothing.
I was thinking how enjoyable
it would have been,
had the whole thing gone together. I want,
probably want to learn nearly as much,
but just,
uh,
you know,
like when you watch those youtube videos,
like Eric the car guy and
he's just fucking, he's just,
this goes here and this goes here,
you take that off,
put this on and put this
thing back on and it just,
it just goes so fucking smoothly.
And uh,
that was not the case on this thing. But
when we finally got it all together, um,
it was tremendous. And
I'm, I'm, I'm sick now,
but this how much of a
sentimental fool I am, I'm,
I'm keeping the old drum brakes and I
bought the tools to be able to put it back
together just cause I don't want to
leave it. I want to learn how to do it.
And then I also don't want to just leave
all the springs and shit laying around
in the garage, you know, kicking
them around and shit. You know,
how long can you leave that shit around
before something fucking happens and
then you lose it forever. So there you
go. How'd you like death? That was my, uh,
fixing the break story. So I
now have, I now have a, uh,
a disc brakes and I put one of the road
is on with the caliper and all of that.
And a, I was beyond, uh, beyond
site, although it does have a friend.
It does help to have a friend
who's basically a master
fucking mechanic who has
all the God damn tools,
uh, who was getting home.
I should have been over there
with a fucking nurse's outfit on.
I was just handing them shit,
but whatever. I get dirty.
MMM.
So anyways,
I,
I have no idea what is going on
in the world right now because,
uh,
for some reason I've decided to do like
10 do it yourself fucking projects and
uh, I'm painting my living room,
so I n I don't know. It's a,
it's a motherfucker. It's a
pain in the ass. It's easy,
but it's a pain in the ass
and a to tape everything up.
And I haven't watched TV for like the
last two days, so I know it in Boston.
Uh, that blizzard with the fuck are
they calling it Nokia? Nardi. Yeah.
What the hell was it here?
Nameable Nimoy Nimmo.
Blizzard Nimo I guess they're
gonna name a snow storms now.
Okay.
You know,
I don't even need to get into that.
Enough Comedians have made fun of
how much they overhyped these things.
This looks a little say was actually a
decent amount of snow, but in the end,
even if you have like, you know, fucking
okay.
Let's say there's three feet of snow.
Okay.
Yeah. I mean, what is, what is that up to?
Yeah.
Let's say two feet of snow.
Two feet of snow.
Is that even up to your knees
if you're an average size adult?
Yeah.
Like what is going to eat?
You can go 30 days.
I think I've said this
before in the podcast.
You can go 30 fucking days without food.
Maybe more than that.
The big thing is water.
Alright. Snow right there.
The Nice fucking handful of cold water
sticking your mouth and just relax.
Let it melt. He couldn't be
fine. You're not going to die.
Some guy on youtube made this hilarious
video of just screaming, I have to get a,
I have to get bread and milk I think is,
it's already got 2 million hits.
It's the funniest bucket that why
do you have to get bread and milk?
I don't know. Am I, I guess if
I was old I would be nervous,
but only if, if like, you know,
if the heat went out then that's
the only way I would be nervous.
But other than that, it's just fucking
snow. You're going to get the day off.
He can go sledding.
Build a snowman.
Yeah.
Just put on a fucking scarf. You
pussies. It's easy for me to say, right.
I'm out here and fucking Los Angeles. I
gotta tell you though, you know, it's,
it's been a while since I've been in
snow and I saw some of the pictures. My,
my buddy sent me this go and look
at what the fuck I'm dealing with.
And that actually looked awesome to
me. You know, Snow's fun to visit,
but you don't want to live in it when
it first comes down, it's beautiful.
And then once it starts being
dirty and all that fucking Shit,
you just get tired.
There's less parking spots.
It'd be buddy down in
southeast shoveling out there.
Kaz Putting a fucking trash barrel there.
Some Yuppie doesn't know the rules.
Pulls in his little fucking Puccio
and he never sees it again. Um,
at least that's how I
heard it works there. Uh,
this is the Monday morning podcast.
What am I going to do here? Well,
you know what else I miss today? I
didn't realize the broads. I know that,
that that game against Tampa Bay got
canceled and I didn't realize that they
played a, the Buffalo Sabres,
which has become a big rivalry.
And I know a lot of you
guys don't like hockey,
especially the Douche who had to write
me on Twitter to let me know that he
tried to watch hockey. Hockey didn't
enjoy it. It literally wrote Jaan
fucking cunt. You know, I
just said, you know, if you,
it's a great sport, watch Bruins
Montreal. If you want to try to get it,
do I really need your fucking like do you
think the Nhl get well maybe they give
a fuck. Maybe they want
your money, you know? Right.
Then why are you writing me
like I'm the commissioner
anyways.
Okay.
Why do I read them? I don't know why
I re I should just not read them. Um,
so anyways,
people hate fucking the Sabres.
They hate Lou Cheech because he ran over
their goalie last year in a hurt the
guy, granted it was a Douche move,
but you know, he was frustrated.
He had a breakout,
he couldn't settle down the puck and
old fucking old big eyes came out of the
net,
came out a little too far.
You know when he ran them over your right.
Your right to be mad at him.
But can you please stop asking why
Luci Cheech won't fight. John Scott,
why do you get John Scott
is like six, eight, two 70.
He's a fucking goon.
He can barely skate.
Why?
Why would you have an all star fight?
That guy risk getting hurt
and then sit in the box.
That's why he's not fighting them.
There's no way ownership is going
to let that guy fight. All right.
And all Lou chichis is a fucking million
dollar piece of meat to the ownership,
you know what I mean?
So they're not going to have him go
out there and go fight that big fucking
Sasquatch.
He shouldn't even go out there and skate.
So she just walk out there
with like work boots on.
I don't know. He probably can
play. They don't allow him to,
but I hate when people say that shit.
They pick like the best guy in
your team and were like, yeah,
he's too much of a pussy to fight
our toothless moron. Yeah, that,
that's a good switch off.
That's a good trade off.
Let's have one of our best guys sit down
for five minutes and all you lose is
some fucking God damn
gorilla. I get it. Buffalo.
You're upset.
Yeah.
Okay. You want to see Lou Cheech get
pounded. I understand how you're probably,
logic is well,
fucking what about saucer eyes there
he wasn't exactly a tough target.
Um, there maybe deserves it. I Dunno.
I feel bad for people in Buffalo.
You know what I mean? That's just,
that's, I been there as a sports fan.
Fortunately, I, they let me up off the
mat over the last 10 years. You know,
I'm rooting for you guys. You know,
I know what people say to you.
I know exactly what the fight I dealt
with that Bucky Dent 1918 all at fucking
horse shit.
The fucking curse with the Canadians
back when they dominated us 25 fucking
years ago, whatever the hell it
was. Unless you're Dan Shaughnessy,
every time we lose to him, he starts,
the Kurds is back, noodle headed cunt.
Um, I know what you're going through.
I know. People say, why'd right?
They say bread hall. They
say a white, he plays sports.
Why don't you just stick
to make an appetizers?
You already came up with buffalo wings.
There's,
is there something else you guys can come
up with that we can enjoy eating while
we watch our teams win championships?
I realized they say holy Cunty Shit too.
And it eats away at you after
awhile. It's awful. You know,
I,
I don't,
I don't have any animosity towards any
fans who go through shit like that.
Haven't gone through it myself. I only
wish it on, uh, you know, I wish it on.
I don't need to get into
that shit anymore. Um,
yeah. Take a Colby stop passing the
ball. You guys are losing again. Huh?
Did you figure it out?
Laker fans or to years,
you've just figured out a new way to
compliment Koby Bryant. Unbelievable.
Do you know like last week out here,
uh,
Colby for like three games
in a row actually pass the
ball for the first time in
his career, he actually was passing
the ball on a regular basis.
And I know a lot of people are gonna say,
cause they wrote to me and who's good
foot Selgian careers schist Muggsy Bogues
has over 6,000 in like three less seasons.
Okay.
The motherfuckers not passing the ball.
Everybody who plays with
them is not lying. They're
not making up shit. Alright,
guide finally passes the
ball in place the team game.
Fucking the Lakers night and day.
All of a sudden they're this,
this does this team that's winning.
And the Laker fans think, oh,
oh, that was the problem. Colby
was the fucking problem. No,
they immediately dropped to
their knees in bloom again.
It's a new facet to with gay.
They started calling them Magic
Bryant. Kobe Johnson. I just,
I've never seen,
I just don't understand.
I'm not saying the guy
individually. Once again,
this is the Peyton manning thing all
over again. Individually phenomenal.
It's not even, it's not even paint, man.
He say, I can't even bring him up. Ah,
Christ, I'm rambling. Let's do, uh,
can you tell I got a zillion
fucking things in my mind. This,
this podcast is more fucking retarded
than usual. All right. Anyways,
plowing ahead here. Let's,
uh, what's today the 11th.
Oh my God.
Valentine's Day is only three days away.
What are you going to do? How many guys
out there are actually sitting around?
And you haven't, you haven't,
uh, you haven't stepped up yet.
You don't know what you're going to do.
You want it.
You want to step in the right direction.
Pro flowers.com all right.
And press her friends.
Her friends are going to ask you.
So where did you get her for
Valentine's Day? What did she get her?
And you'd be like a big bouquet
of flowers or a big bouquet.
However the hell you say it.
Impress you.
A woman and her friends is probably even
more important to impress their friends.
Send her flowers from
proflowers. Yeah, get it.
The best guy with the biggest damn vase.
Shut all her friends up and she'll
be happy for a couple of days, right?
A one doesn't.
Romantic rainbow roses and a free glass
vase from my friends@proflowers.com for
just 1999, 20 bucks, 20 bucks.
You're already getting kisses.
And for my listeners, double the
roses for just nine 99 more. Uh,
you just need my code bur
bur when you order, um,
what did the hell is this?
Please use this time to tell your
listeners about your personal experience.
How did the flowers look? How did they
smell? How did your recipients, oh, okay,
I got this. I guess I was supposed to
read that before. Uh, you know what?
Last year they said some to my mom
and she loved him to call me up,
left me a great message and I saved it
for six months. That's how it she was.
That's how wonderful the messages,
the message she was that she left.
Do you understand what I'm saying here?
People,
you can't go run and only cost you 20
bucks is the only way to get this amazing
Valentine's Day deal.
You call one 800 pro flowers and mentioned
bur bur or go to the pro flowers.com
or go to proflowers.com click on the
click on the microphone in the top right
hand corner and type
in Berbee you are are.
That's Plouffe proflowers.com click
on the microphone and type in Burnaby.
You are ordered today and um,
and get on with your wonderful day.
Hey ladies,
you know what's to stop you this year
from getting your, your guy? Oh man,
you should do that.
Get them four dozen roses.
Just embarrassed the hell out of him.
Sent it down to the job site. Uh,
proflowers.com do it today.
All right, the next one here.
Let's get through this year. What did we
get? What do we got? Um, oh, here we go.
stamps.com everybody. If you never
want to go to the post office again,
but you want to be able to do everything
that you can do within the post office,
all you have to do is just
sign up@stamps.com stamps.com
everything you would do
with the post office,
you can do right from your desk by in
print us postage for any letter or package
using your own computer and printer
stamps.com we'll send you a digital scale,
calculates the exact amount of posts
did you need for any class of male.
Then just hand your mail to the mailman,
drop it in the mailbox,
or even schedule a free package pickup
using stamps.com you'll never have to
deal with bad weather again to
send out letters and packages.
I use stamps.com to send out
all my DVDs to my road gigs.
I've never had a problem. I weigh it.
I get the figure that prints it out.
I slap it on, I go to the GIG and the
magically they're there right now.
Use My last name. Burpee. You
are our for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a $110 bonus offer
includes the digital scale and up to $55
in free postage. Wait, go
to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
and to
burp
you
are
are all righty.
Moving on.
Yeah, so I missed the gay. Yeah,
I miss the game today and I saw Campbell
jumped that guy in the savers. He get,
he, he uh, he didn't come
out too well in that one.
I love the guy in the state was
like looking at the ref like,
I don't want to fight. Oh
right. What does your day, um,
all right now put the sports talk.
Okay,
I need to appease the ladies
and the nerds out there. Oh,
here's one for,
um,
this weekend I actually took a night off
from standup comedy and I went out to a
Indio, California, I can't
remember the name of the Casino.
I saw Don Rickles. They had
to do it, man. I was like,
I always see these guys underrated.
Going to a casino and seeing a legend.
He was amazing.
And Tony Orlando tie a yellow ribbon.
He destroyed in front of them. I didn't
realize how many hits that guy had.
You know, I went with Bart neck and
we will, and I was just going like,
I think this guy's going to
open with tie a yellow ribbon.
He's going to close
with it and he's gonna,
he's gonna play it again in the middle.
And he came right out of the gate,
tie a yellow ribbon. And in my world,
I'm like, this guy's Outta hit.
He's out of hits and all of a sudden he
goes to the next, I'm like, wait a minute,
I know this song not three
times on the ceiling,
and if you want me twice or not pipe,
right?
Everybody go nuts. Then he had another
hit after that. I'm like, God damn,
this guy's got a lot of hits.
Then he got do a drum battle,
this drummer,
and I'd have to give the nod to Tony
and then Rickles comes out.
It was just amazing just seeing an icon,
you know, Tuxedo, the whole old school
thing, guy opened up for Sinatra,
underrated. Go into, go into a casino
to see a legend. This is what I realize.
This is a very blanket statement,
but I'm sort of the king of this.
Legends play casinos,
hacks, go to cruise ships.
Is that bad? I'm just saying, you know,
they give you a certain amount of
time to make it in this business.
And if you don't, they just, they
just put you out to see, you know,
Eh, that's not 100% true. There's
some, there's some good guys doing. Uh,
but you know what? I'm fucking
talking about. I told you this story.
I did a cruise ship one time.
I worked with like a juggler and a,
and the guy hosting it, I swear to
God, was like a real life guy. Smiley.
That was that story told you why?
Well,
they told me it was going to be
a young crowd cause I was like,
I don't think my ex can work on a cruise
ship. This is like 10 11 years ago.
I like not, I don't know. It's this young,
these young with a young hip cruise
liner thing, right. So I show up,
it's a bunch of old people in the guy.
Smiley guy goes out there.
This is how old they were.
He went out and he opens with the
f you're happy and you know it,
clap your hands. And they did it. And
at that point I was like, oh my God,
I am going to fucking eat my balls.
And I did.
It wasn't easy because we
were rolling over the waves.
It was kind of tricky to get
that second ball in my mouth.
But I did seven minutes into my set,
fucking munched on both.
Captain wrote a letter to the agency.
Oh God,
why didn't I ever get a copy of that?
Said I was offensive to
all races,
the handicapped.
I forget what else he said.
I don't know.
Nothing I said was as was as offensive
as the fucking food they were serving on
that goddamn boat. Oh my God. You never
saw so many fat fucks in your life.
I swear to God, if one of those
cruise ships ever goes down, you know,
has there ever been like an obese shark?
The whales too.
You know what fat people must be for
sharks just because they don't, you know,
we're not part of their diet. We just sort
of accidentally like we gotta be like,
remember those big pink snowballs,
those mushrooms there,
mushrooms in the middle and then they had,
I don't know what the fuck was good.
I never had the balls to eat.
One only reason why is because it was
marshmallow always thought marshmallow was
disgusting. They remember fluff
peanut butter and fluff and other,
that toxic horse shit.
I actually grew up right at the tail end
of just feeding kids absolute poison.
Like now they feed poison
but it's sort of disguised.
You have no idea cause they'll write
oh packed with protein or you know,
nutritious shit. You know,
there's somehow they'll put,
put like those words in there.
They try and camouflage.
But back then it was just straight up
like, you know, it was just poison.
Fluffer nutter. The fuck is
that? I Dunno. It's bunches.
White Shit with bunch of sugar and you
mix it up with peanut butter. I let,
um, right. What am I talking about? Oh,
we're talking about fat people going
overboard and he fat listeners.
You're going on a cruise and just
think like, wow, if this goes,
oh well wait a minute,
would you float more if you're fat.
The big thing is you'd have to relax.
But the problem is,
is like, you know, if you're
wearing like a fat person, like a,
like wet suit, you know, you
just covering yourself all up.
When you laying on your back in the ocean,
you know the water that's been absorbed
in your bathing suit is going to be
coming down in your face. Sort of be
like waterboarding yourself, you know.
So maybe you've got a
rollover and you stomach. Nah,
but then the roles in your neck of the
kind of holding your face in the water,
it's so rough deal.
Um,
is there ever been a fat navy
seal? I don't, I don't think
there has. All Right, oh,
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. People I,
this is why I do these Monday
morning when the brain is fresh.
I'm just attacking fucking people who
can't defend themselves or stop eating.
Um, all right, here's something for you.
It's just choppy is health.
I got to recommend something
as somebody recommended to me,
told me to go see that Dave
Grohl documentary on sound city.
You can actually go to his website. I
wish I had that up there. Just look,
update growth.
Sound city,
you can download it for 12 bucks
and it's worth every goddamn penny.
It's about this studio sound city
where basically I would say maybe 40%.
It seemed of every fucking awesome album
you've ever downloaded or ever wanted
to get over the last 40 years was made,
um,
in this studio. And, uh,
Dave Grohl actually bought the soundboard
when it was going out of business.
He bought the soundboard. So that kind
of starts it off. And when you watch it,
this isn't really a spoiler alert the
whole time they're interviewing him.
He's sitting in this old school
van and I was sitting there.
It's going to Zana one
of those old Ford Vans.
Okay.
The original, like the, the, uh, equal
liners that you say it, the early sixties,
I, he'd help like pedophiles
ruined vans. You know what I mean?
I don't know if it was pedophiles or
date rapists, but like vans in the,
in the 60s, if you look at
them, they're not that bad.
They're actually kind of adorable. I'll,
I'll bring a picture up there like,
you know, the Ford Econoline, it
looked like a big, big fucking eyes.
Looked like it needed some sleep,
you know,
and they was so tiny and he
could just see it. You, you,
you couldn't do anything
and people could just see,
you could see almost right through
the fucking thing. Um, in the 70s,
they became creepy. That's
when they started, you know,
putting carpet on the floors
and the ceiling of them.
And they had these crazy sort of
acid murals on the side of them.
And guys with Harry chess and mustaches
started driving him around and just saw
him somewhere. It just became
the big, just mobile, you know?
And this Skaggs liked him.
I wish I was around when vans were cool,
you know? Well actually
I was, when I was a kid,
I used to think custom vans with a shit.
I used to think,
why don't my parents have a custom van?
Remember that when you wanted
your parents to be cool,
why can't he get a corvette? Oh, I dunno,
cause you're this fucking six kids
with the hell. Am I going to stick you?
That's when you know your dad's fucking
around on your mom comes home with a two
seater. Fuck the family I'm
going out tonight. All right,
Bill, how do you tell a girl
she sucks in bed? Uh, the fish.
Uh,
hey bill,
how do you tell a girl she sucks in bed
without hurting her feelings or making
her embarrassed?
Is it okay to give pointers in the
bedroom or would you may over it make that
make me look like a Dick helped
me out, Bill. Go Fuck Yourself.
Um, all right. The first half, there's
no way to tell a girl she sucks in bed.
There's no way for a woman and tell a
guy he sucks in bed without hurting the
failings. Alright, let's
be politically correct.
There's no way for a guy to tell another
guy if they live in an alternative
lifestyle, 2013 date, no
one wants to hear that.
Um, well, this is what I would do. I eat.
You can't just make somebody good at bed.
The potential has to be there.
There has to be a certain God
given talent. You know what I mean?
I mean, some women, they, they
reach for your package, like to,
they're grabbing something out of
the cupboard. You know what I mean?
There's just no,
yeah,
it's, you know, what's funny about women
being bad in bed is there's not a lot of,
um,
there's not a lot of stories.
I think guys not knowing
what they're doing is,
is pretty well documented
and guilty as charged.
Guilty as charged, you
know, but um, that it's,
it's definitely a two way street.
What I would do is if you
feel she has potential,
rather than give her
pointers, like, hey listen,
you're doing a great job in there.
He's a couple things like make
some halftime adjustments.
Maybe you could do that, like stop
halfway through fucking, you know,
have her run into the bathroom and as you
run into somebody interviews you. Yeah.
Well, you know, the first
half hour is pretty good.
There's definitely some
things we could do better.
I know my balls are kind of lonely and uh,
you know,
she's got to know she doesn't
have a good read them.
We're going to try to work on our
rhythm and the second half. Right? Yeah.
Go Fuck Yourself. You
know, runs back in. Um,
I would suggest rather than cake,
definitely don't tell us she sucks.
Do not give pointers. I would,
uh, the keyword here is guiding,
guiding, and, um, informative, moaning.
Okay.
I would say would be the,
uh,
the most user friendly
way to protect this girl's feelings.
It is, that's what you have to do.
Um, I need more information.
Do you feel she's aware?
How did she suck in bed? Like I said, she
grabbed me a dick. Like she's, you know,
reaching into a mailbox to see
what the fuck's in there or
is she just shy? You gotta help me
out here. I don't, I don't know.
Um, you know, that,
that's what I would do.
I would, I would guide her and by guide
her, I don't mean pushing her head down,
it guiding,
no forcing,
none of that type of stuff. And, uh,
and then where you gotta be Simon
Cowl is, um, don't give her any, um,
sympathetic mode once she starts
picking up that the moments, you know,
you know, don't give her any sympathy
once, if it ain't doin it for you.
Don't give her a AH,
yeah, no, don't do that.
Just dead silence. Okay. She has
to know she, it's not working.
I don't know what to tell you dude.
I know I told this story before.
I hooked up with this girl one time and
we were having sex doggy style and you
know, when I come forward you're
supposed to back in, you know,
like we're clapping, uh, with crutches.
Is that a,
was that a fucking,
does that one of those dances with wolves
names clapping with crutches? Sorry.
Hacky joke.
Um,
okay.
Yeah, no, what she was doing when I went
back, she went back, when I went forward,
she went forward. So I was
inner, but there was no friction.
So I was starting to have a performance
problem before I ever so gently put one
hand on her hip and the other
on the back of her neck.
And just sort of stopped her.
Okay.
Went back and then pulled her, but
it still didn't work. It was like,
not only does she not know how to do it,
she was I think almost as tall as I was,
you know, so doggy style, you know, they
got to have the kind of like, you know,
you can get a little too high there,
you know, without getting too graphic.
So I was already dealing
with that, you know? Um,
I don't know. Beautiful
girl though. All right. Um,
okay.
Unexpected pregnancy. Oh,
Jesus. He's a rough this week.
Unexpected pregnancy bill. Absolutely
love the podcast and the stand up.
You like a skinny Louis C K or conversy
Louis C K is like a fat bill burr.
I really wish I didn't read
that. Uh, um, anyway, not sure.
Now I get dragged into it. Uh, and
I'm not exactly skinny anymore.
I've been having, I've been enjoying
the high life lately. Mila. Um,
anyway, to business. I'm a
24 year old guy from Sydney,
Australia who's run up
against a big problem.
Last November I lost a well paying job
due to an anxiety disorder I've developed
over the years.
I sought out treatment,
been through therapy, had all sorts
of diets and breathing exercises.
And although recently it's been much
more manageable. It's unfortunate.
Unfortunately it wasn't enough to
hold onto my high pressure job.
You know what dude? Yeah, it
was probably the job. Granted,
I have no medical background whatsoever,
but I really don't, you know,
when you have to like eat a calm,
quiet and start going,
just so you can fucking go to work.
Hello.
Okay.
Oh Nia, how are you? Sorry. Just so
the door opened. Uh, the lovely Nia.
Everybody. Oh, you're busy. Okay. Um,
what was it that was when you know
that I was here. Oh, okay. All righty.
Well, I'll see ya feel
me along this week. Okay.
Um,
yeah dude,
when you have to fucking do shit
like that just to go to work,
it's probably the job. And considering
you developed it over the years,
let me guess, was it as you got this
fucking high pressure job? I don't know.
So anyways, um, uh,
currently I'm looking for
a more low key job anyways,
days after I'm let go,
I get a call from a friend I had
had drunken unprotected sex with.
The only reason why I went back to our
house was at our house was within walking
distance from the pub. We share a
bed in nature, takes its course.
Oh my God.
It was a core of it was of course
a risk and like any idiot mail,
I just assumed nothing would happen.
Turns out I'm going to be a dad.
Come August after a mere
one sexual indiscretion.
I've known this woman for over three
years. She successful, smart, witty,
and we get on really well.
I'll be getting on really well.
Uh, she is sorry. There was a
big space in a new paragraph.
I'm not that dumb people. Please,
please will still believe in me. Um,
she's been up up until now childless.
And you can understand her reasonings
for wanting to keep the spawn.
She expects me to play an active role
in the parenting game. And to be honest,
that's something I am wholeheartedly
prepared to do. That's so fucked up.
They like make the decision.
I mean cause it is their body.
They have to go through the procedure,
but it's just really, you're really just,
uh, you're just a fucking Tj's hose.
That's really all we are a,
we were both really irresponsible and we
should both have to pick up the pieces
and work shit out. Here's the problem.
She wants me to move in with her.
Fuck that.
Okay.
Before I read any more the fuck that.
Anyways,
in fact she's demanded
I moved in with her.
A double fuck that she's making demands.
Go Fuck Yourself.
All right. I wish it did that
earlier. I wouldn't have been as um,
I can't help thinking that
this arrangement would
descend very quickly into
mutual resentment and unhappiness
and would eventually be a detrimental
environment for the kid apps.
A fucking lutely.
I live with friends in the past and if a
dirty kitchen cook can cause irritation,
I don't know how shitting drooling
a shitting, drooling screaming baby,
we'll fly under the radar.
I want to move somewhere close by so
I can share their parenting duties.
But I don't see how moving
in is a better solution.
She is also asking for financial
support to the tune of half,
which the Shit I've spelled out
above surely makes this impossible.
Okay.
Um,
she's tit deep in an already blossomed
career and I'm doing my best to stay away
from the Dole or as
Americans say, welfare. Uh,
so I'm asking advice on two things.
How do I re
how do I relay my moving in doubts to a
hormonal pregnant woman without hurting
her feelings or making her feel
like she has to go, go at it alone.
And how can I spell it out to her that
I won't be able to be there for the baby
financially in the way she
wants Jesus Christ. Dude,
what else and how do you fucking
jumped to the moon? Uh, by the way,
when she told me about the pregnancy
in old Jesus arrived fully formed in my
mouth, go fuck yourself count. Um,
you just have to have an adult
conversation with her. Just be like,
look, who's kitten? Whoa. We're
not in love with one another.
You're not my soulmate.
I'm not your soulmate.
But we're both adults and we did this,
so we have to take responsibility. Okay.
Um,
I would still like to meet my
soulmate and I imagine you were too.
And we're not going to be
able to do that if we're,
if we're basically pretending
to be a couple, which we're not,
we're not. Okay. Uh, just look
at the baby like we both, we,
it's like a timeshare condo.
Sorry.
Um, no. Just to tell you, you,
you, you're not gonna move in.
I'm not moving in with you. I'm going
to support you 100% with the baby. 100%,
but I'm not moving in. And when
she says why, I just be like, oh,
cause I'm not in love with you.
Okay,
we're not,
we're not getting married.
We screwed up and now we're
doing the right thing.
But um, yeah, I'm not moving
in. And what's she going to
do? Grab you by the throat.
Make you move in. No. Fuck this. And the
fact that she's making these demands,
she wants half of your money.
Well, this is the deal, dude.
You knocked a girl up and
now you got to fucking,
you got a kid coming so you got
to go make some money. All right.
And you do have to support the kid.
Um,
this is one of these fucked up things.
If she's got a great career,
why does she need half of your salary?
You know what I mean?
If you had a great career,
she wouldn't even fucking work.
Why don't you say this? All right.
How about this? Why don't I be Mr Mom.
I'll stay home with the kid and you go
out and work and you support me. I'll,
I'll wear a fucking apron.
Have added Lady,
go put on your Nancy Reagan power suit
and fucking have added. Yeah, Dude,
look what, what, what do you,
I know you got the double whammy
here. I, this is, I wouldn't,
I wouldn't do a double header here,
although the conversation
might go in that direction,
but I would definitely not tell her that
I'm, um, I'm moving in with her. Does,
there's no fucking way. There's no
way that that's happening. All right?
There's no way that that's happening.
Um, cause I'm not in love with you.
Okay. And let her ham, let her hall, let
her cry, let her scream, but a throw shit.
Let her do whatever the fuck she wants to
do. Yeah, you're not moving in with her,
sir. All right. Don't do it.
Yeah.
No, go to bed with the price
on your head. No, don't do it.
I'm sorry Beretta. Don't
fucking do it. All right.
And then as far as like a,
you know,
supporting your kid,
you got to do it.
You got to give her the money. You
can't have that, this kid. Okay.
Isn't an unbelievably unf unfortunate
situation and you have to make the best of
it.
And you guys have to be friends.
And that's another reason
for not moving in. You know,
w what are you gonna sleep in the
same bed? Like you're married.
Like you love each. I mean,
you can't fucking do it, so,
okay.
Um, I dunno, but as far
as the money thing, yeah.
You got to go out and start making some
money and if you have to sleep on a
Fuckin futon or whatever, believe me,
that's going to be better than having,
you know, some 18 year
old kids someday who, uh,
had a shit childhood because of you.
And then you got to deal with that and
then try and put the pieces together when
you're on your fucking death bed. You
don't want to do that either. But uh,
as far as moving in,
fuck that move close by and uh,
that's it. It's not up
for discussion. Okay.
And she can make all the fucking demand.
She wants to demands fucking dope.
You made a,
she made a mistake to, to fuck. She'd make
it demands out of you four. Furthermore,
why the fuck you? Why you? Why
you worry about it. All right.
She can't force you to move in. So fuck
her. All right with a condom next time,
sir.
All right.
Legal zoom.com everybody legal zoom.com.
Are you waiting for the perfect
time to start your dream business?
It's now legal zoom, the official
sponsor of the national starch.
Your business month. Once
you to get started, right,
you got to protect yourself for everybody.
So whether you're setting up an LLC,
an s Corp,
a sole proprietorship or a nonprofit
legal zoom takes care of you from start to
finish.
Um,
are award winning service was developed
by the best legal minds in the country.
And every business gets
personalized attention.
That's why over 90% of
legal zoom customers would
recommend the service to their
family.
You'll be in good company.
Over two dozen companies on the inc 500
lists were started through legal zoom.
These guys got to credit Sierra
what? Uh, it's national start.
Your Business wants to start your
business right now@legalzoom.com. Uh,
legal zoom is not a law form and provide
self help services at your specific
direction. So if you have questions,
ask them and they will answer them. Um,
but there's so much more now.
Every Loc and incorporation package
includes easy to use business accounting
software, uh, $269 value
for absolutely free.
Be sure to enter burpee. You are,
are in the referral box at checkout.
Start Your Business.
Protect your family and safeguard
your assets@legalzoom.com today.
Um, is that it? Is that it for the,
I think that's it for the ad stuff.
Here's something I saw.
I was trying to get something to
talk about on the podcast here.
Um, so I looked up to drudge
report cause I always here,
this is like something that people look
at and they were talking about newt,
Newt Gingrich's ex wife unloads
on camera network debates,
the ethics of airing what she said about
her former husband before the South
Carolina primary.
Okay.
And you guys know like when I talk about
hockey and you have no idea what I'm
talking about. This, this is my version
of South Carolina primary for what?
What is Newt Gingrich running for?
Mayor of South Carolina or senator?
Is that what it'd be?
I don't pay attention to the
shift. Um, so anyways, it gets,
his is Marlene Gingrich has said she
could end her ex husband's career with a
single interview.
Oh Hell hath no fury.
Just take the fucking alimony. What
did he, oh Denny Denny do something.
Wasn't she sick in the hospital?
And he kind of tagged somebody else.
Why did he think he could get away
with it? With a giant head of his? Um,
anyways, earlier this week, she
sat before ABC News Cameras.
She spoke to ABC News reporter Brian
Ross for two hours in her explosive
revelations are set to rock the trial.
What trial?
I don't fucking know. It's just another
ex wife. Just going. Absolutely. Why?
Why would you do that?
Don't you biting the hand that feeds
as much as you hate this guy and he was
probably a piece of shit to you. I mean,
you really going to affect his ability.
If he doesn't win that political office,
how can he pay for your Mercedes
with all that fucking hush money?
All the bribe money he's going
to get. You know how cow can,
how are you going to afford to get your
hair and nails did every fucking two
weeks,
you know,
if he doesn't have a job where he gets
to look the other way as people pour shit
in the water supply.
Okay.
For God's Sakes, woman had, have
you, have you thought this through?
I don't fucking know. All right,
what am I doing here? Is that,
is that all the advertising?
I got to make sure I didn't miss any of
the fucking advertise and they always
end up flipping out at me. Oh, you know,
he's supposed to read it and you didn't
read it. You just go through the,
couldn't you read it earlier?
I think that was it. All right.
That was it for the other than the
Amazon stuff. And I say that every week.
You know what? Where am I in the podcast
right now? 46 fucking minutes in.
Look at me wheezing across the
fucking finish line this week.
You know what? I actually had a
great week. Really built. Well,
it hasn't translated into a great podcast.
You unfunny cons, right? I know, I know.
It's been a little lack luster.
Little Fuck and lack luster.
Um, dear billion, I know
this is last minute. Oh,
I didn't even tell you guys
why I had a great week.
I went out and I did a bunch of stand up
in this bill was like four things that
I've been working on meticulously
crafting in front of tourists down at the
comedy store.
And uh,
I suddenly I figured out a through
line where it all connected. Like,
give me that shit. When people
say, you know, you don't
know how to write a script,
just start writing a bunch of themes,
just write little vignettes and then
somehow they all stick together,
which you never fucking works. Um, that's
like you're trying to build a house,
just start hammering shit.
Um,
but it actually worked out with the
standup thing. I have a nice through line.
I have a new chunk of shit
that I've strung together,
like some cheesy thing with a bunch of
beads and some native person that was
supplanted through genocide is now
sitting on the fucking curb out.
Now what does it Honolulu is that
when I saw them, um, supplanted,
is that a word?
Relocated Valentine's Day advice.
Billy by deer is billion.
I know this is last minute.
I had a question about Valentine's Day.
I am a single guy in my
mid twenties rejoice,
okay,
dude,
I'm going to tell you right now,
if you're a single guy in
your mid twenties and you
live in America and you're
living on your own,
please
drop to your knees and thank whatever
God you pray to every day because you're
never going to be freer in your life.
I know you'll probably get student
loans and blah, blah, blah.
This stress and all that
bullshit. Fuck that. Okay?
Did never going to be freer in your life.
Go get three years supplies of condoms,
okay,
and bang away my friend. Maybe you
don't need to do it for three years.
Maybe you're one of those
guys for only three weeks,
but you need to get it out of
your system. All right? He says,
I never really had a girlfriend
for whatever reason. Oh,
Jesus Christ. All right,
we'll go on the whole other other way.
Truth be told,
my friends could name numerous
reasons why I don't have a girlfriend,
but that's an entirely different issue.
Well,
Jesus Christ as a fucking can of worms.
They could.
You don't seem defensive or argumentative.
So I don't know if it's an anger
issue that look well, I'm so,
I'm so sick of trying to be fucking
Hannibal Lecter here to try to guess what
your shoes look like with w with the
way you're right, you know. All right.
I'm just going to read the rest
of this shit. Uh, as of right now,
I am currently sleeping with three
girls off. Oh, so you're fucking,
you're good knocking it out. I thought
you'd like never had a girlfriend like,
and you'd never bagged
anybody. All right. My fault.
All right.
Do go fuck yourself.
You're a guy in your mid twenties and
you fucking three girls right now and I'm
on this. You need advice? Uh,
keep doing what you're doing
anyways, depending on what day of the
week it is and how much I've drank. Okay.
That depends on how many
girls he's banging. Ah, I've
never lied to any of the,
any of any of them about where
our relationship is going.
And although they never met each other,
each of them has an idea that I'm seeing
other girls. It's kind of a don't ask,
don't tell policy. Uh, yeah dude and
I, you got to come with that. You know,
you can open with that. You know,
what are you doing? I'm dating,
I'm playing the field.
Find people you date right now.
A couple of people kind of see
it just having a good time. Well,
I don't do stuff like that.
Well there's the door sweetheart.
Okay.
Then they'll respect like that.
The honesty of that. Some won't.
Some will actually have
self esteem and walked out,
but a lot of them they'll hang
around eventually the tire,
their net gets weak and they'll
fall right in your fucking Dick. Um,
birthdays and Christmas are always a
piece of cake because all that requires a
quick text or a phone call or at
the very most drinks at the bar.
But Valentine's Day is tricky.
Our dates consist of bar
hopping and drunk sex.
So flowers and a nice dinner would
completely send the wrong message. Dude,
you selfish con.
Are you asking me how to keep banging
these three chicks while getting through
Valentine's Day?
Why don't you just look at the Valentine's
Day like that's your pussy getting
all star break.
Just take three days off the day
before the day after and the day of.
Okay.
Just say a,
what are you doing for Valentine's Day?
Um,
uh,
going to be a Jesus. Where are
you going to be? I don't know.
I don't have a good one for that
one. All right. You know what?
I just put myself in your shoes and I
understand your problem now. He said,
I got to do a little bit of trouble.
Last year,
one of the girls texted me and said,
you know,
every girl likes flowers
on Valentine's Day.
Okay.
He said, I knew my
response couldn't be. Yeah,
but if I get you flowers then I have
to get flowers for all the other girls.
So I just pushed out and
responded. Yeah. Well, oh dude,
you shouldn't respond to it at all.
Yeah.
You know, every girl likes to get flowers
on Valentine's Day. Isn't that funny?
And that has nothing to do with most
likely her having any sort of feelings
towards you.
It's just the bitch next to her and
the other cubicle probably got some,
you know why the girl on their fucking,
whatever the fuck you want to call it.
Some guy broke my balls this
week is fucking hilarious.
He was trashing me say come off as a
pompous ass because I always talk about
anybody who doesn't do comedy
works in a cubicle, you know,
and for some reason he decided to take
that seriously and tell me that he
actually works at the UN and
travels all around the world.
If that's actually true, sir. How? Why
don't you just get on with doing that?
You work at the UN and you
travel all over the world.
Why would you give a fuck
what some absolute jackass is?
Say It on a fucking podcast. How
insecure are you? Your insecurities?
Probably a great thing because that's
probably the thing that drove you to be at
the UN where you travel
all around the world.
You know what sir? Good
for you. That's awesome.
I hope working at the UN and travel
rolling all around the world
fills you up some point where it fills
you up high enough where you don't have
to respond to a silly joke
on some dumb ass podcast.
Um,
I travel all around the world.
Um, you know what? That's
actually a great fucking job.
Do you feel like you get anything done?
You know,
do you sit there wearing that head piece
next to that guy who was wearing the
water buffalo hat?
I'd bet there'd be about doing that shit.
And you're sitting there trying to talk
to him about how you can sell your Ritz
crackers to their country.
Is that what you're doing when you're
traveling all around the world?
I travel all around the world.
I can just see you on the plane
with your fucking dress socks on.
You have a dash. Oh,
just sitting there. Well,
what movies am I going to watch on this
flight as I travel all around the world?
Um, anyways. You know
something sir, you had you,
you had the James Bond job and then
you fucking, you played yourself.
I don't know why you did that.
Why would you fucking,
that's like me responding to people
on Twitter. Why would I do it?
I should pretend like I have
better things to do. Um, anyways,
I want to keep seeing all these
girls back to this guy, but this,
but at the same time, I don't want
any broken hearts on Valentine's Day.
Yeah.
Oh, to do you know what I did? I don't,
I'm just, what is your problem here?
Okay,
dude. Yeah. You like a Gemini. It's
like you're this fucking lady killer.
Then also you kind of like, you
know, you don't want to hurt anybody.
Should I get her some jam jams?
Yeah.
I can't even,
I went and talked to the fucking UN guy.
What the hell was going on here again?
Okay.
Valentine's Day got a little
trouble last year. Well, listen,
you're anticipating trouble. Didn't you
learn anything from last year? You know,
every girl likes flowers
on Valentine's Day.
Yeah.
Um, what, what would I write back?
I know what my response would be.
The second I read that if it was just
some girl I was banging and then they
wrote that I would get this
awful feeling in my stomach.
Yeah.
And I would, I would read it and
as I got that awful feeling, I go
and make that noise.
Yeah.
You know that thing like when you're
just banging a girl and then all of a
sudden she just fucking
makes that comment.
Okay.
You know, you think she's on
the same page as you. When did,
she just makes that comment,
you know,
I was thinking about you today and you
just feel that feeling in your stomach.
Oh yeah.
Well don't
fucking worst. Ah, you
gotta be one and done,
but one had done is scary.
Okay.
You just gotta be honest. I don't know if
some girls, what would I say? You know,
every girl likes flowers
on Valentine's Day.
Um, what would I text back? Yeah. You
know, that's what I heard. You know what?
I don't, you know what? I
shouldn't give you shit.
I don't have a good response to that.
Well,
maybe some day you'll meet a
guy who wants to give you some,
you want to get drunk and fuck. Um, yeah,
I got nothing and you can't ignore it.
You know what I would've done?
I would have ignored the texts
than I would've called her.
But a good three hours later, three,
four hours, three hours later,
that's a good one. You call
her, you ignore that text.
Then he called and she goes,
hell, ah. And you're like, Hey, what's
going on? What are you doing tonight?
I got no plans. Valentine's
Day. What are you doing?
And he just started with
that. And then she, well,
when he went again, and she'll be seen,
if you're gonna take it and some romantic,
you know,
direction and you don't,
you just keep it in the fuck buddy.
So I figured we'd go down to why meet
hammers, whatever the fuck he call,
we go down to, uh, take it the face.
I have a couple pitchers of
beer and see what happens.
Yeah,
Dude, you know what? You're, you're,
it seems to me you're not
just fucking these girls.
You're actually having like these
mini relationships with them.
You don't.
The the key to have an a fuck buddy is,
is the time between fucking him and I
don't give a shit how much a woman says
that she can handle it. Most of
them can't. Most of them can't.
If you fucking come on over there and you,
and it just,
eventually they're going to get feelings.
They're more,
I don't know if they're more mature
or if it's a defect. It's just,
I just respect the fact that
that's how they're wired. So you,
if you have a fuck buddy, okay, let's,
let's just do the math. Okay, now,
now February is a very short month here.
So let's just say right out of the gate,
you fuck her on February 2nd
okay.
All right.
You shouldn't come around again till at
least the 17th and progress you fuck and
you leave f and l,
you fuck them and then you leave.
You don't bang her on the second.
You Bang it on the second and then you
bang her on the seventh year in a fucking
relationship in their world.
You know,
unless you literally this second
you have an orgasm as you're coming,
you're scooping up your clothes
and you walk out like half naked,
then you just bizarre is another
good way to keep them at bay.
And why don't I just read
the rest as to see what it,
what is questioned is here he says,
I want to keep seeing all these girls,
but at the same time
I don't want to break.
I don't want any broken hearts
on Valentine's Day. Yeah,
you want to keep fucking all of
them now do what you have to have.
You have to have a road evolving door.
You have to have a stable of women if
you're going to live this life or you have
to give into fucking rubbing one out,
all right?
But you can't be a relationship guy
with three different women cause you are
going to end up hurting them.
So what you have to constantly be doing,
you gotta be like a college.
All right?
Every year you lose some top prospects,
but you're out there recruiting. Okay?
So you, so you maintain, but it's
never ending. It's fucking exhausting.
But if that's the game you want to play,
that's what you have to do.
So that girl who says,
you know,
every girl likes flowers on Valentine's
Day right there, you put on waivers,
okay, for a fucking piece
of ass to be named later,
you guys got to get rid of her,
okay?
And you got to look,
go back and analyze what the fuck you
did wrong that she felt it was okay for
her to text you cause you fucked up.
That right there shows that you fucked up,
that she felt that she could send that to
you if you think you just fuck buddies.
All right? So anyways,
he continues. He says,
I know that likert or not,
this shit is important to women.
If I take one girl out on playing
favorites and setting a bad precedent,
plus if she does that, check in Shit
on Facebook, I'm completely fucked.
Yeah, dude, you're doing dirt bag shit.
If you're a single guy and something
could happen that fucks you on Facebook,
you're leaving these girls on anyways.
He says,
if I take none of them out or do nothing,
I have three irritable ladies on my hand.
Dude,
are you gonna marry any of
them? No. Well then let them go.
Why don't you have the balls to do that?
You know,
when a team halfway through the season
just realized, do we? When in the shit,
just pull a fucking Marlin's.
Just get rid of everybody
and then you have fan bases
your Dick and they're gonna.
He's gonna be pissed for awhile.
Um,
but then you build it back up again.
Build it back up again. You know, I dunno.
Look through it. If you want to
be in a fucking relationship,
you know there's other ways about
going about it than doing this,
but you're trying to have your cake
and eat it too. Did you get you,
you got three women right now,
your bang in three different women.
Where's your confidence?
You know what you're doing.
All right.
Dump to keep one at bay
and then get two more.
Then dump the other one to get
the other one. Just see them.
You don't even dump them. You just
phase them out, phase them out.
But the new recruits that you get in,
you gotta be straight up honest with them.
You know, unless you actually feel
fails, you've, you feel are no feelings,
you know, don't keep coming back fucking
him unless you know, you get that 15 day,
okay,
you fuck I'm on the second.
You fuck them on the 17th.
Okay,
then you're into March and
then bang her on like the 11th.
Okay.
All right. And even then, they
can't catch feelings doing that.
But before you know it,
you know,
okay,
that's like 14, 15 days out of
the year taken up. You, well,
you got to bank somebody.
This is such, this is,
this is really should be eye opening to
women that I'm actually saying this is
really a, this is really awful.
Not, I'm speaking this out loud. Um,
he says,
in a perfect world,
I'll take all of them out at once and
have the force and I've been chasing after
my entire life,
but we don't always get what we want.
Any advice from the lovely Nia
would be much appreciated as well.
Love the podcasts. Go
Fuck Yourself. Uh, yeah.
She probably wouldn't have been
his, uh, understanding as I was,
even though I gave you a
lot of shit. Um, anyways,
that's the podcast for
this week or a buddy. Um,
and I don't, I don't have any, I'm
fucking tapped out. Tapped out.
It's been fucking three
days under a truck.
Okay.
Not really doing anything. Just watching
Titus do the whole fucking thing.
Um, anyways, uh, thanks to
Christopher Titus for, uh,
helped me with the brakes on my truck.
Thanks everybody who's been a
continuing to download my special,
which is a tremendous and a,
if you want to help out somebody,
uh, or just check out something great,
uh, please check out a sound city.
The new Dave Grohl, um, documentary.
I cannot recommend it highly enough.
Uh,
it's 12 bucks off his website
and money well spent and a,
when that fucker comes out on DVD,
I'm going to buy it.
I like having the gold behind my money.
I don't like downloading
shit and then just,
you know,
then it's just on this thing
and then this thing dies and
then that thing fucking crashes.
And then I don't have it anymore. You
know what I mean? I don't like that shit.
All right, I'm rambling. Go
fuck yourselves. I'll talk
to you next week and, uh, oh,
I know why. There's nothing to
talk about. Football's over.
It's fucking over. It's fucking over, man.