Hey,
what's going on is bill burr and it's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
May 27th, 2013 I don't like
the way I just said. Um,
Monday. Um, you have to catch
yourself. Sounded like a Douche.
They're happy.
Memorial Day.
Happy Memorial Day.
A Beautiful Tab to thank
the troops and stuck.
Give stuff your mother fucking
face with Shit. All right.
Isn't that what you're doing?
Let's all have a moment of silence for
everyone who made a sacrifice for this
country. Alright, right.
Let's go stuff our faces,
right? Isn't that what it,
isn't that what every fucking
holiday is? Flag Day. Today is a day.
Okay.
Joe, Roman by, I remember,
I remember all the flags set
up wave though about those
contract Godrej projects
and allies. Stuff our faces, faces, faces.
Let's get drunk and have a fight with
a mother's mother's mother's mother's.
You know,
isn't that what it is?
How many people are actually going to
go to a fucking parade today from the
halls up Ooma to the shores of Tripoli?
Huh?
Who can sing beyond that fucking two
lines other than a goddamn ex marine or a
current marine, one or the other.
Is that what they do? And when you,
when you joined the marines,
by the way,
do you have to sing that song at
some drill sergeant is in your face.
Hey you,
you fucking screaming.
Oh Shit. They're single
arc. One of them. Of course.
Right.
I commend anybody who's in the military
service simply for the ability to get
through bootcamp and having somebody
screaming in your face and just pushing
down every ounce of your being to not
like just punch that guy right in the
fucking face. This is thing like,
I've thought about that Shit, right?
Like let's say thanks,
get really fucked up and all of a sudden
they want to draft soon to be 45 year
old balding red heads like myself.
And I've actually thought
about for some reason
I think I think about it whenever I do
pull ups because whenever I do pull ups
or climbing the rope,
I always think you think I could make it
through fucking maybe three obstacles.
Okay.
Three obstacles in one of those bootcamp.
Thanks.
I could get up the fucking rope.
I probably couldn't do the
required amount of pullups,
but I wonder if I could just get
out of the drill sergeant. You know,
I'll still take care of Claire.
I haven't pressed,
where's your upper body strike you all
right. Get the fuck out my face. Right.
Can I at least get one of those?
But my thing is if someone screaming
in my ear like that, like I got,
I got tonight is what our tetanus,
however the fuck you say.
I have it one of my years.
So if the guy screaming in my ears,
I'd have to be like, yeah, skills me. Uh,
I guess I'm not trying
to not be Maureen light,
but I just wanna let you know when I
played a lot of drums and my ears are very
sensitive. If you could just, uh, you
don't even continue with the insults.
I'm not trying to tell
you how to do your job,
but if you could just somehow
bring the volume down, you know,
and then immediately I'm pile because
everybody else has to start doing pushups.
Is this quiet enough for you?
Private bar.
Okay.
Look at the rest of your platoon
sitting here doing pushups.
Cause you don't want me to yell too loud.
Just exactly.
How quiet do you think warriors,
you redheaded freckled fucking faggot.
Right?
There's no way that they have a city.
It's always the homophobic shit is
not what they come at you with. Huh?
I bet you're sucking Dick.
Right.
You know what?
I actually shouldn't say any
of this because I have no
idea what they say to you
other than what I've watched in movies,
you know.
So anyways,
Happy Memorial Day,
a beautiful time to thank the troops and
stuff he fucking face with some shit.
Um,
that should be the official memorial day.
I think the only people who truly
appreciate it are people who have actually
served and know people who have served
know
that would be my really built.
He really think that the people who are
closest to it appreciate it the most.
What other groundbreaking things are you
going to say in this podcast? Oh, I know.
I know. I'm a moron. All right.
Can you just let me have my moment?
Can you well,
all right then.
MMM,
I'm in New York City right now.
I'm in my old up Budnick loneliest shit.
I Dunno how he used to
do this as a single man
at all.
Although I have to tell you it's a,
you guys know the comedian,
not Ted Alexandro if you don't,
you showed he's one of the
best fucking comics out there.
He used to have this great joke.
I'll just do the gist of it cause
I don't want to fucking burn Joe.
He used to just say that basically
it was essentially that, you know,
being single, it's sucked at
night cause you will lonely.
But it was great for the rest of the day.
I can't say I'm feeling that,
but I do have to.
I have to concur with that joke that at
nighttime when you fucking go home by
yourself,
that's when it gets to you.
I think it was when you wake up in
the morning, you have errands to run,
you got to, I'm going to go to the gym.
You know, there's hope. That's what it is.
This hope that you're going
to find somebody, you know,
when at night all that hope
is gone and it's just you,
a pint of ice cream and a slice of pizza,
you know,
solely crying as you crying
softly as you're chewing,
getting down to the crust.
Um, actually, you know, I, I've, um,
I've made a rule that this time
when I go through in New York,
I'm not having any pizza and
I'm not having any ice cream.
And I know what you thinking,
Bill, you're in New York City.
You have to have the pizza. Okay,
well, I'm going to tell you what,
I've had enough New York pizza
to last me a fucking lifetime.
First of all,
90% of New York pizza sucks a giant
pizza cock because it doesn't make any
sense.
Um,
it doesn't make sense simply because
there's so many people living off the
fucking reputation that
New York has great pizza.
You know,
that's the problem.
New York does have great pizza,
but there's no laws prohibiting anybody
from opening a pizza shop saying the
best pizza in New York City,
you know,
it's fucking horrific.
Maybe if I do danger fields or
go over to that Sutton pizza,
they're over on first avenue.
I always liked have pizza and a nice
fucking zip over there and I zipped to the
sauce there. Nice Little Tang near
Nice little, what the fuck was that?
Their in their uh,
in their pizza slices,
you know,
I don't know.
Pizza is always that shit.
You're like stumbling home after a couple,
two, three fucking whiskeys. Right.
And then you fucking,
uh, I dunno what I mean,
what the Hell I'm saying
you got to realize I have
to get a fucking appointment
book cause I just realized how much
shit I just planned for tomorrow.
You know
I'm going to get a steak fucking dinner
with Joey roses and Keith Robinson.
Somebody over at the stand comedy club,
the head chef over there is going to
teach me how to make the fucking pizza pie
over there.
MMM.
Cause I got the big green egg and I
can heat that fucker up to 700 degrees.
Do you guys even know what I'm talking
about? Just realize that I bought this,
this big green egg,
this barbecue where in a smoker and they
give you this book showing you all the
wonderful shit that you can make on it.
And all I've made on it is burgers,
hot dog and fucking chicken.
So I want to take it to the next level.
I want to be able to make a pizza.
But you gotta know how to
make your own fucking dope.
You know,
which I don't know how to do.
So I'm going to have this person show me
how to do it because I'm a fucking seat,
right? I'm always trying
something new. Oh, what's that?
What's that bill up to the
to fucking today. Anyways,
how about those Bruins? Huh?
Hey are we go bro? And we go.
That's how it used to be.
That's the chant that used to get going
back in the days in the old Boston guy.
Now they go, let's go, Bro wins and I'm
telling you, that's the ranger champ.
Who is, here we go, Bro. Ones. Here we
go. And let's go. Rangers. All right,
well you know where the range,
is it going now out to the
fucking golf course because yes,
the Bruins and one short week
went to the fucking Mecca,
Madison Square Garden and in five games
it was actually a five game sweep.
Who's kidding? Who? You know, not to
take anything away from the Rangers,
but I've got it all right.
When the whole rally on your side gets
going, cause our goalie fell down.
I want,
have you ever a goalie?
He just falls down like some kid playing
peewee hockey and then he tried to go
out. There was a Rut in the
ice. You fell down. Took.
It's okay. It happens to the best
of us. Go down to a public, Rick,
you see it all the time.
My favorite thing in a public rink is
watching that guy who where it takes like
12 seconds for him to fall.
[inaudible] I've ever,
oh right.
The fucking six going backwards.
Six going forward. Right.
And then the fucking Bam,
and it's usually the back hits first and
then the fucking whiplash and then the
head makes that nice hollow coconut
pook right off the fucking ice.
That unmistakable sound of somebody
squash hitting a sheet of ice.
That's a fuck as an incredible sound.
You know what?
And I don't think that
that can be reproduced by
Hollywood unless you actually
had somebody slammed the head on it.
That's incredible.
Not even with one of those Casio keyboards
that has access to over a thousand
sound effects.
They never have to even notice that they
never have the sound effect of a head
hitting the asphalt or a,
or a sheet of ice.
So there's one few nerds. What does
it somebody out there, you know,
when are you Photoshop concept? They're
trying to get me up the perfect that,
that perfect sound effect and sent it to
me and I'll have my first sound effect
on the podcast. You know, and I'll
turn this into a wacky morning show.
And every time I say something
dumb, I go, oh, what was I thinking?
And then I'll click the button and then
you'll hear it and then your laugh.
Okay?
Then you'll be in the parking lot at your
job holding onto the steering wheel 10
and two just staring at that front door
that you don't want to walk through.
It's having those last
few moments to yourself
thinking about all the decisions
you've made over the last 12 years.
Why did I break up with her?
Why did they major in this?
Why did they buy this car?
Okay,
why can't I feel feelings anymore?
Is Your eyes well up with tears?
Just
look up at the heavens.
Wonder if there's some old
guy up there that gives a fuck
you Christ softly.
And then for some unexplained reason,
you look over to the left
and this is your boss stare at you.
But this weird look on his face.
Like
is that my crying in his fucking car?
Yeah.
She quickly tried to play it off.
Like you sneeze,
you take a big deep breath and you
push all those fucking feelings down.
You like it and you get out of
the car. Hey Paul, they boss.
Are you doing and I allergies.
Allergies. All right. Yo.
See in there you have can't wait.
I'm sorry.
Anyways,
so the Bruins are now
going to go play the,
the, the most confusing
franchise in, uh, in,
in um, in Nhl law, in the NHL.
I don't know how to feel
about the fucking penguins.
I totally respect him and I'm fucking
blown away by their ability to somehow
always get the guy that's the
next guy. I mean, it's insane.
I liked in the last 20 years,
25 years,
I would actually put
them beyond the Yankees.
Yeah. Wait a minute. Or I would, I would
know. I would compare him to the Yankees.
MMM.
When the, when, when
the Yankees, you know,
got a babe Ruth and Lou Gehrig.
Then Joe Dimaggio,
Mickey Mantle.
I would actually that this is the
closest thing you've seen where they,
the penguins,
Mario Lemieux.
Jaromir Jaga um,
Sidney Crosby,
it fucking Gino market. I don't want to
say [inaudible] [inaudible] and Denny,
I don't know how to fucking say
these hockey names nowadays.
I used to be shocks all these French
fucking names. So that was easy, right?
Michelle Goulay oh, shoots. He scores.
MMM.
Fucking for absolute snipers.
I mean,
unbelievable fucking top
notch goddamn players.
It's incredible, right? They have that.
And then on the other side, right.
And then whenever they get
hit, they're like, you know,
Mario [inaudible], you know,
if people don't stop cheating,
I'm not gonna play anymore.
Alright. Yoga was always like, oh,
he's got a mullet and he
just loves those Kit Kats.
Yeah.
Late some all the time. So people flew us.
Why? You know, he scored all those goals.
Well, I'll tell you, I wish I knew that
when I'd Floyd. All right. Sidney Crosby,
big pouty lips. Fucking cub
scout dead. He is, you know.
Yeah.
But say hate about that guy.
Other than the fact that you know,
he doesn't do anything wrong in life.
Okay.
Help an old people cross the street.
Even with the skates on
runs out of the arena,
is that an old person
trying to cross the street?
Just a fucking Wheaties cereal
box cover look and son of a bitch.
Why is he a son of a bitch?
Because you know he's better than you
head and shoulders.
The best fucking guy in the league.
Then he got milk guy who could be
a fucking cunt and be like, Hey,
what about me?
He doesn't give a shit.
He just plays his Goddamn game
and his tremendous, all right,
it's a great fucking hockey town.
They had one of the great last arenas,
that Mellon arena, Carnegie Mellon,
Heinz, whatever the fuck they called
it, Goddamn Pittsburgh people.
They got three names for everything.
See the Heinz Carnegie,
Carnegie Mellon or just melon?
I guess that's four,
but was really just Carnegie Mellon. Just
all fucking remix like p. He's in there.
By the way,
the more years that goes by,
that biggie has been dead and,
and his legend just keeps growing and
growing with the fact that nobody's ever
matched that guy's ability with humor,
storytelling,
and being able to paint a fucking picture.
Forget about his charisma.
His last time you saw a guy even remotely
with the fucking charisma, that guy.
All right.
As the years go by and you keep going
back frustrated with the new shit,
and you just keep going back to that,
that mumbling fucking shit that
puffy does on every fucking track,
it's,
it's like it's kicked somebody out there.
Send me some fucking biggie tracks,
will you?
You removed Tahfeeth going,
that's right.
Uh Huh.
Okay. And the fucking pack round,
whatever the fuck he says. Oh,
just repeats every guide that the last
word of every line that big, he says,
it's like we heard it.
Was it an enough for you to be
in there with the fucking faders,
pushing those up and down? I've got
to listen to your mumbling jackass.
I tell you one of the worst fucking rap
songs ever was when he and that other
mumbling jacket, Mace
County who've had those,
that how he heard the guy to do.
You know what?
Tell me which one to use fucking
rapping because I can't tell the it,
why am I this upset? Anyways,
let's, let's, let's dial it down,
but style down, let's get back
to the fucking, to the SBA. Okay,
I'm agreeing with him.
Um,
oh fuck.
So that's one side of the penguins.
And then on the other side of
the penguins and, and you know,
Crosby bitch moaning and complaining,
Mario Lemieux bitch moaning and
complaining about the thuggery,
the cheating and all that fucking shit.
And then like right in their
own goddamn locker room,
they have had
the exact same thing where you had the
Ruth Dimaggio and Mickey Mantle of Lou
Gehrig. They've had that of the
fucking biggest God damn need breakers,
cheat and sons of bitches ever.
You know,
I have this love hate with the penguins.
I love him because I respect the franchise
and I hate them because not because
they have these cheat and constant
fucking just go out there and try and end
people's careers. It's the fact
that they then have the balls.
Okay to bitch.
You hope those are kind of walking.
The yard loaders are going
to deploy them in order.
You know why we're even in this week.
He wanted to get fucking Matt Cook in
35 years of watching people play hockey.
I've never seen a guy check somebody in
the boards and accidentally completely
sever the guy's fucking Achilles tendon.
How does that happen?
I don't know.
They say it was a fucking accident and I,
if it was anybody else
I would've believed it.
You know what the sad thing about Mac
cookies is a guy can actually play.
He's a fucking great player and
he's definitely toned down his shit.
But I mean I can't have a,
forgive the guy cause he ended Savardi
career guys on a follow through of a
fucking shot could not be more vulnerable.
And you come by 30 miles an hour and
hit him with that plastic shoulder blade
would pad,
which is like hitting somebody crossed
the job with a fucking wrench and you end
his God damn career.
Unbelievable.
I'm fucking so this is going to be a,
okay,
this is going to be a brutal series.
MMM.
The only fucking weak part I
can see on the penguins is the,
they have shaky goaltending
yeah.
You know, but just their
offensive power. I just, I am,
I dunno,
my heart says Bruins,
but if I was putting money on it,
I mean I would say penguins. It's six,
nine, it was a lot of bronze finish.
Go let your flag waving flags
and Shane do you what? You,
you fucking get no weird. Now that
you live in out fucking la. Good.
Now I just watch enough hockey and I've
seen what the fuck they're capable of.
Like Sidney Crosby is
literally unstoppable.
Okay.
You don't fucking stoppable. And if they
just had one guy like that, you know,
like the capitals and Ovechkin
is nowhere near a Crosby.
Although he had a great year.
MMM.
Now I'm going to have those
guys fucking wine into me
total.
MMM.
If he just fucking had him. But the
fact that you have all those other guys,
you know, Malkin and all
those guys, it's good.
It's going to be fucking,
I dunno how he, I,
you know what I'm calling it right now.
We were going to play the trap.
We're going to try and play that boring
ass fucking hockey and it's going to
kill me. I'm going to have to
watch because it's my team.
But I want before anybody sends me the
emails, no, I don't enjoy watching it.
Even if we win a game, I
don't like it because, uh, I
really enjoyed watching the,
uh,
penguins senators series,
even though that one last game was
that seven goal game was a fucking,
was a blowout. Um, oh, by the way,
once again,
you know,
a lot of people explain to me why there
was such hatred towards a maple leaf
fans, Toronto in general
and all that type of thing.
And everybody was saying that basically
that that's the biggest city in Canada
and that's where like all the media is so,
because all the media is there,
it's like everybody in Toronto then
thinks the whole fucking country of the
whole world revolves around them. I'm
not saying it's true, I'm an outsider,
but that's what they say.
But it reminded me kindness kind of like,
like New Yorkers,
you know what I mean?
Okay.
Like they just think everything
begins at fucking ends,
you know,
with like mad.
And the only reason I Madison
Square Garden is this Mecca
is because it's in the
middle of the biggest fucking city
with all this media here, you know?
And a lot of New Yorkers, they really
confused that it's a mecca. Yeah.
That's just a gathering place.
Okay.
People come and play hoop there because
that's where they can make the most
amount of fucking money and get
the most amount of media exposure.
But that has nothing to do
with the Knicks are how good.
Okay.
Oh the, the, the legendary.
The Knicks are not legendary.
They're not all right
with spike Lee sitting court side.
You're fucking low rent. Jack Nicholson.
Oh, woody Allen with his
awful hat. Jesus Christ,
you know,
at least La,
they have the decency to
get their faces laminated.
If you're going to be the
celebrity sitting on the side,
just fucking with you anyway.
So the next route,
the rangers are out cause of
the Boston Bruins. And uh,
once again, the garden is silent
and it's ready for the circus.
The Mecca [inaudible].
That's their fucking,
that's what happens every goddamn
yet you realize the rangers have one,
one Stanley Cup and the less 73
fucking years you understand that.
Do you realize that in like the fucking
60 something years that the NBA has been
around the uh, New York Knicks?
If one, only two titles,
two titles. Last one. That one was in
1973 Oh, let's do the math on that one.
That was 40 fucking years ago.
That's a verse he kills me.
The guard was rocking last night.
He's always telling me how loud the is.
I'm fucking believable. Rarely. Okay.
Louder than the fucking piece
of shit. TDF, Xyz Garden,
whatever the fuck they call the Boston
Garden. No, when the boys came back down,
fucking three goals and a game.
Seven. Was it louder than that Paul?
Versey I'm asking you. Um, all right.
You're listening to the Monday morning
podcast here. Everybody. Geez Louise.
You know what?
I think it's time to tell you guys about
some wonderful products that you might
not have been aware of. All
right. Here's one for you.
The Dollar Shave Club,
getting a good shave can
be a real pain in the ace.
I'm searching through 50 brands,
matching new blades to old handles,
bullshit features where your razor
doubles as a flashlight at vibrator.
Toothpick, 20 bucks for new
razors. That really is a rip off,
by the way. The new razor blades I
love. They haven't behind a case,
you know,
like they're giving you gold coins.
It's like maybe if you didn't
charge 80 bucks for each one,
you wouldn't have to fucking
lock 'em up. Um, but anyways,
I go to dollar shave club.com to get high
quality razors delivered to your door
for just a couple of bucks
a month. They've made it
simple, high quality razors,
100% guaranteed sent on schedule. So you
never have to think about it ever again.
Every month you get a new pack and every
week you change your blade and it costs
a fraction of what you'd pay at retail.
Plus you don't have to stand in line.
Um, I want you to try it. Give it
a shot. Let me know what you think.
Go to dollar shave club.com.
Forward Slash burpee you are are,
you'll get a free sample of Dr Carver's.
Easy shave butter,
which is awesome with a, your
first shipment. Also make the PR.
It also makes the perfect father's day
gift gift. Come on bill, hang in there.
Dollar Shave Club, something he can
actually use a support the show,
go to dollar shave club.com.
Forward Slash burr or click on the
dollar Shave Club banner on the
podcastPage@bill.com.
Alright,
Hula plus everybody you've tried
streaming hit shows on your PC,
on hulu.com.
Now it's time to start your free trial
of exclusive content in your living room
and on your mobile devices.
On Hula plus with Hula Plus,
you get total control to watch
thousands of shows whenever you want.
Wherever you want. Use Hulu plus
on connected TVs, gang console's,
Blu ray players, Roku. Is
that what you said? Apple TV,
PC or watch from anywhere
on your smartphone or tablet
on demand at all times.
Even on a plane. Can I do
this on a plane? Um, anyways.
And with Hulu plus you
can binge on full seasons,
your favorite current shows and eve or
even full series runs of classic TV shows.
It's endless. Actually. You could do this
on a plane because now you can get Wifi.
God Damn it. This is unbelievable.
We're in the future here. Everybody.
They've got community, modern family,
southpark, SNL, Monday night, raw,
the man show Jimmy Kimmel,
family guy and more.
Feel free to check it
out in your own time,
who the plus is only seven 99 per month,
but right now they're offering an extended
free trial of Hulu plus that is only
available to podcast listeners. Take
control of your TV watching experience.
Go to the podcast page at [inaudible]
Dot Com click the Hulu plus banner for
extent for an extended free trial
or go to Hulu plus.com/bill again,
the Hulu plus banner on the podcast page
at [inaudible] dot com or go to Hulu
plus.com/bill and we got one more for Ya.
He voice everybody.
He voices.
The reason you're gonna make more
money in 2013 when your customers call,
you'll have your own toll free number,
professional greeting,
dial by name directory,
and more. You'll sound,
you'll sound like a fortune 500
company and blow away your competitors.
Eve voice let you give out one number
that rings wherever you are. The beach,
the bar. Does it matter? You'll
sound like you're at the office.
You got to go to he voice and
use the Promo Code Bill. Um,
he voice takes all your voicemails,
transcribes them,
and sends them to you instantly as a text
mail so you can check your voicemails
before the meeting ends
and not even look rude.
He voices only 10 bucks a month right now.
Listeners to my podcasts,
get a free trial of the voice for 30 days.
So check it out.
Stop what you're doing.
Hit pause,
set up your ear free trial and
see what I'm talking about.
It's a great way to support my podcasts
and an easy way to make more money this
year. I hope you guys all do it. Go to
[inaudible] Dot Com Promo Code Bill.
That's easy.
voice.com Promo Code Bill,
or just go to the podcast
page bill bird.com and click
on the voice banner right
now. All right, there you go. See that?
Helping you shave better,
helping you watch TV better,
helping you get your fucking business go.
And you know,
I'm hoping you leave me behind
some day. I'll be reading an ad for
your company there. Hey, let's keep,
let's keep talking with the sports
here. All right. Who's kidding? Who?
I don't watch that much NBA hoop.
I don't, I really, I like it.
I know I shit on it a lot.
But uh,
I got to tell you that Dwayne
Wade flying fucking elbow.
All right. Now it did look like he
was trying to leap over the guy,
but at the last second there
was no fucking reason to
do what he did was like a
wrestling move.
And I know it's debatable,
but what killed me was Reggie Miller
and the other commentator or Steve Carr
immediately
the first reviewing of it just go.
Yeah, that wasn't intentional at
all. That's that, you know, it's,
it's part of the natural bodily
movement when you leap into the air,
like one of your elbows just sticks out
like that to give somebody a forearm
shiver.
He fucking gave the guy
an impromptu flying elbow.
That's what I think had he
leapt in the air, you know,
cause they were kind of crossing
over each other in a weird way.
He jumped over the guy and was
like, oh, there's his head man. Boy,
I ain't going to fucking
write their friend out. He
liked the game. One of those,
the guy collapses in a fucking heat.
Although I heard he's known for flopping,
but it just killed me. That just
automatically deny him. Holy Shit.
Look at that elbow. Oh wait, that's one
of the superstars of the league. You know?
I don't think that there was anything,
there was no malicious
act. Just, it's ridiculous.
If that happened at Dwayne Wade
and he went down, I swear to God,
both of them, would it be like,
see now that, that right there,
that's the kind of thing that just does
not belong in this game at this level
or, or at any level for that
matter. You know? I mean,
there's kids at home watching this game.
I mean,
that's just a little look at that.
Let's watch this again. I mean, oh,
that's just disgraceful. That's
just, I mean it just premeditated.
I'll tell you the legs got to
take a look at this at all.
I would be really surprised if that
gentleman was plaguing a next, uh,
the next contest. Fucking
superstar does it. Ah, you know,
he didn't mean anything by that,
you know, he's kind of a, I mean,
he was in the area, had flap
his wings like a bird, you know,
he doesn't have any feathers,
so he's got to tuck his, his,
his hands back towards his torso. It's
very normal, very normal right there.
Um, that's it. That's all I
know about hoop this week.
Other than him pulling for the paces, who
else is playing? WHO's out in the West?
I love,
you know what I love,
I love the spurs and their white
guy basketball that they play.
I absolutely love. They are
fundamentally sound. Pick and roll.
Fucking kiss it off the glass.
I can't jump either game that
they played this tremendous,
there's not a lot of white guys
out there doing it, but when I,
when I watched the spurs play,
that's,
it looks like five white guys
playing pickup at the y and it,
and it's effective. I don't know how
they do it. So who are they playing?
They're playing the grizzlies.
MMM.
I don't give a shit. I'm just so
elated that the Lakers aren't in it.
So fucking a lady absolutely love it.
And I hope Dwight Howard stays with
the Lakers the same way I've enjoyed.
MMM.
What's his face? Alex Rodriquez
steak with the New York Yankees.
Alex Rodriguez is my most favorite
Yankee of all fucking time,
you know,
is they try to shame him out of town and
he's just like, ah, you know, I, you know,
you want me to sit down at a playoff game?
I don't give a fuck.
I'm not leaving that contract. Go fuck
yourselves. I'm staying. I love it.
I absolutely love it. Um, actually,
what's your really disturbing
a youtube video last night?
I'm trying to think of
how the hell I got there.
I was watching animals and I was watching
these two little fucking weird things.
They can't see that.
Well their heartbeat when they're
nervous can go up to like 1300 beats per
minute.
You know,
like somebody trying to win
one of those fastest hands,
single stroke roll drunk contest.
They fucking,
they can beat them with their heart.
They can't see that well
and uh, I dunno, they basically
they have to live meal to meal,
their heartbeats so fucking fast that
if they miss a meal they could actually
die.
The sleuth of sloths.
I don't know what the fuck this thing was,
but all I know they don't
see that well and they,
two of them don't see each other too.
They literally run into each other.
I got to find this fucking video
and they just had this,
does this sickest
fight I've ever seen in my life.
Like they had to slow it down.
Look, when they were showing it,
they go and this is not sped up footage.
This is how fast these guys,
it was like watching two flyweights
times like, you know, to the fifth power.
So I'm watching that shit, which leads
to more shit. And then I see like these,
these,
these bloodhounds getting fed,
doing all that shit. Next thing
and you know, you just give me,
just keep looking to the right and it's
more, you know, eagles killing snakes,
snakes,
killing fucking this a mancuss
killing a fucking a black Mamba.
And then next thing you know I'm watching
these rednecks going bear hunting.
All right.
And it got all these dogs in these
metal cages and they could stick their
fucking heads out and it's hilarious.
They stick their heads out and the go
right and all the Peta people
are of course like there's
thing I want to get out
of this cage.
They're really excited cause they want
to go fucking hunting is what I'm what
I'm thinking they do it.
So I might think in a hunt,
these bears with dogs,
what the fuck is this?
I made a bear could just swap one of them,
kill them.
But what it is is they have so many
of them and basically the dogs go,
they chased the bear,
the bear goes up a tree.
And then like 10 rednecks walk up to
the tree and then one of them decides,
all right,
I'll fucking shoot it.
And they shoot it and it
falls out of the fucking tree.
It's just the worst thing I've ever seen
in my life just as far as like, listen,
go and bear hunting takes
unbelievable fucking balls.
If it's you and a buddy,
you know?
Yeah.
And you're in bear country and you
could stumble upon a grizzly bear that's
she's walking with their cubs.
And then she immediately comes over
and tries to rip your fucking face off.
And even though you got a gun, that still
takes an unbelievable amount of balls.
But I gotta tell you this hunting
black bear with like fucking 10 dogs,
five dogs, and they chase it up a
tree and then you show a watch here.
So I'm going to shoot that thing that's
the size of my garage. Fucking nailed it,
man. It was, it was fucking disgusting.
It was really disgusting.
Okay.
I respect it on one level because you
have an ability to live off the land.
The dollar crashes you like, well, we
didn't have anything in the stock market.
Fuck it, let's go bear hunting. You know,
because those people really are
the ones who are going to survive.
So I have such a tremendous respect for
anybody who hunts and has the ability
okay.
To go out and,
and
yeah,
basically go get some food.
Unlike me, he's a total pussy,
just goes down to the
fucking grocery store.
They're kind of get a pound of the
Omega three quarters of a pound off the
Turkey. Do you have to smoke?
Let me get the smoked Turkey.
Some of heartache cheese with that. I'd
like that. Right. That's me hunting.
And I get frustrated when I
can't find the cereal aisle.
So I'm basically one of the guys who
when the shit hits the fan, you know,
and I'm in a city and I just get fucking
hurt into some goddamned FEMA camp.
I'm done. Vantage Bay, I'm
done right? Those red rednecks,
we'll just fucking back slowly
back off of their property.
Like that dude who tuck his package
between his legs in that movie with that
chick who was in the
fucking pinball movie,
right silence of the lambs and it just
slowly fucking back out into the woods
and you'll never see them again.
They're going to be able to live off
the land and fucking ride it out and
they'll create a new clan,
you know,
and they'll be the ones that eventually
topple over the bankers after they
exterminate everybody and they take
all the land and they'll laugh at those
rednecks, you know, and just
call him a pesky problem.
Okay.
Not Try to hunt him down with
drones from their fucking,
Phyllis knows fucking rednecks.
They're going to be out there
covered in mud like Rambo,
a little bit of deer urine
behind the neck, you know,
and eventually begging to come
back like fucking Attila the hun
and all empires fall and it's going to
be those mother fucking rednecks who do
it tremendous respect from.
Okay.
Now having said all of that,
Jason,
a fucking bear up a tree with a
bunch of God damn dogs. It does.
Did she just see the bear up there?
Like things just appear like, dude,
are you fucking kidding
me? You know, it's, it's,
it's not like it, but it's not totally
upset. It's like, all right, I'm up tree.
I don't really know what those things are.
They're very loud as a lot of them,
but they don't seem to be able
to climb up the tree. So a,
eventually they'll get tired, they'll get
thirsty, they'll leave, I'll climb down,
you know, crack open a keystone and
have a pot full of honey and I'll just,
you know, that'll be my day. And
then all of a sudden these fucking,
you know,
do you have to got all bore these
fucking guys just come walking up and I'm
telling you,
they're literally standing like maybe
20 yards from the tree and this giant
furry beanbag is right up there and
they've just shoot it in the neck and then
it just falls. And they always,
they don't need edit out.
It fallen out of the fucking tree.
Uh, it's just, it was just a, uh,
I dunno. Any red necks out here
listening to this while you can defend.
Okay.
I Dunno, that just seems like the, uh,
the tiddly winks of fucking a hunting,
you know,
checkers, not chess. You know what I mean?
To quote Denzel and one of his movies
where he screams at the fucking white guy
from the suburbs doesn't quite, you
know, it was in over his head. Right.
Teaching them the slang. Um,
all right. So like I mentioned,
I'm here in New York City and, uh, had a
great time last night. I went down to, uh,
the comedy cellar and did
like three shows down there.
And it reminded me of the old days when
I used to do all the shows here in New
York and fucking jumping calves and
sit back and forth between the clubs.
You'd have a new joke and you get
to try it three times a one night.
He just can't, uh, you can't
put a price tag on that.
And I ran into Ari Shaffir who was
living in La. He's now in New York City.
Um,
and he's working his way into the club.
Told me last night and he's going to start
being leaving a veil so you can check
out Ari Shaffir hopefully
on some upcoming shows. And,
uh,
I'm psyched for him.
It's like to watch and grow by leaps
and bounds by getting all that, uh,
that extra stage time. So it's been
a, a wonderful thing out here. Oh,
I know what you know, I forgot to
bring up, um, the Toronto mayor.
Can you guys give me some
more information on that guy?
They're trying to say that he was smoking
crack and he goes, uh, he goes up,
there's a video of him smoking crack.
He said it doesn't exist.
Then he called the media a
bunch of maggots, so vent.
So immediately I'm loving this guy.
He's talking all this shit,
but then I kind of read up on him.
He's got a lot of sketchy
shit in the background.
I always wonder what you people
in Toronto think about the guy.
All right in neighboring cities. Do you
think he is a piece of shit? Do you think?
Uh, the media is a bunch of magazine
of fucking dope. Let me know. Anyway,
so here we go, Bill. As a
penguins fan, I have to ask,
do you endorse the Bruins pa
announcer going woo after goals?
If so, what is wrong with
you? Um, I have to admit,
I hated it when I first heard it.
I hated it,
absolutely fucking hated it.
And uh,
but I've come to an acceptance but
that the Bruins aren't mine anymore.
I'm an old man now and uh,
it's onto the younger generation
and this is how they're doing it.
And uh, I got to admit now
when I watched the games,
it's the playoffs and they score. I'm so
fucking excited that when the guy goes,
Woo,
I fucking do it too.
And I feel like fucking ric
flair and it's, and it's,
you can call me a Douche all day long and
you'd be a hundred percent right. It's,
I can't even defend it.
And if it wasn't my team, I would
be trashing the shit out of it too.
I really would. All right.
Well let me ask you this.
You guys have off Samuel Sing Alf,
Sammy scene.
I'll Samuelson in your ring of honor.
Okay,
let me ask you what's worse. All right.
And I know what you're going to say.
You're going to say the woo cause you
don't give a fuck. You don't give a fuck.
Cause he's not fucking blowing
out the needs of Sidney Crosby.
But I can guarantee you cried
like a fucking bitch would.
Crosby was out for a year and a half
because that guy gave him a concussion.
Right? And when Mario Lemieux was
bitching about the fucking islanders,
probably like, yeah, that's like
Mario. That's exactly right. You know.
So here I am trashing something
that my own fucking team does.
Why don't you grow up and have
the ability to do the same if not,
go fuck yourself. Okay. A few
weeks ago I asked, you know when,
when you go to a casino,
you know once the deal
with the fucking covert,
like why they have the
ugliest carpets planet.
My theory's always been a
casino was so goddamn big.
The amount of money that you will save
by buying the ugliest fucking carpet on
the cheap.
MMM.
You know, that's why you do
it. When you political, I
mean, how many square feet is,
is like, you know, the Mirage,
how many square feet is the fucking
Bellagio and all that. I mean, I mean,
it has to be,
I have no idea.
I have no fucking idea. A million
square feet. I have no fight. I mean,
how many trucks have to pull
up with that Goddamn carpeting?
So that's why I thought that it was the,
it was always ugly carpeting.
So here's some theories
that people have said to me.
MMM.
Hey, bill, wanted to let you
know in response to your five,
your May 20th podcast from having
worked in the casino industry.
I've heard the reason the carpets in the
casino are so vomit inducing Lee ugly
is so people will avoid looking at them
and look up at all the slot machines,
restaurant signage,
merchandise and whatnot.
It's a psychological manipulation to
focus your attention where they want it.
This also usually a confusing
pattern to the carpet,
uh, to the pattern. A weight.
She was also a usually a confusing
pattern to the carpet design and overall
structural layout too,
to the place to make you subconsciously
wander around and put your money into
something rather than having any
clue where an exit might be or how,
how much time has passed.
Um,
I agree with that. So I
would, I would agree with the
second half, the first half.
I don't know. How long would
you stare at carpet? You know,
like God, look at the fiber, look out,
look how beautiful that carpet is.
Um,
I would actually think at this
point if he had a beautiful carpet,
like a nice fucking electric
blue, you know, but, and
people feel like, oh my God,
something exciting is going to
happen here. You know, maybe a piece,
something peaceful they could be,
can be a little more relaxed when he
fucking walked in there and he can look
around at the horse,
I don't know.
But as far as like having a confusing
pattern and a weird structural layout,
I mean if you've ever been,
if you've never been lost in a casino,
you've never been in a casino,
which you ended up having to do
is you've got to pick like a,
you got to start memorizing
where the restaurants are.
Like there's where the sports book is,
so I know the elevators to the right,
but if you start cutting through slots
and you're like fucking oh another Jack
Nicholson,
reference him in the shining in the end.
Why under her as you're going
through all those hedges, you're not
like,
I'm surprised you don't see somebody
sitting on the ground like dead with an ax
in the head and not frozen.
But you know if frozen like those people
you pass when you're trying to get to
the top of that mountain there,
Mount Everest right over there in the
Himalayas. Is it in the Himalayas?
I have no idea.
Here's another theory.
Somebody has this strange pattern and
the carpeting on casino floors is so if
you drop a chip,
you don't hear it hit the floor and the
crazy colors hide the chips if you're
looking for them. Um, I
don't buy that one either.
That just seems like a fucking long
way to go to try and make some money.
You're already playing a game where
the odds is so in favor of the casino,
they don't need to be crawling around
the floor afterwards. Vacuuming up chips.
I wouldn't go with that.
Somebody else said that the reason that
they have it is because it's easy to
clean up puke stains. I don't
know what it is, but please,
please bring me more theories
to that because I find it
fascinating. There has I,
out of everything that I, that
was just, I just read there.
I believe it's a confusing pattern and
it adds to the confusion of trying to get
the fuck out of there and then you
just, next thing you know, you're,
you're playing a game. I, that one
seems to make the most sense to me.
All right. Um, here's the next one here.
Where the fuck am I here?
All right, dear bill,
both Fagens I have recently discovered
my lifelong friend is in fact an asshole.
First let me give you some backstory.
I put friends with this kid
since car seats and baby teeth.
So last year when I'm looking
to move into a new place,
I naturally turned to him. Oh, that's,
that's not a good thing to do. Live it.
And you know,
one of the quickest ways to end a
lifelong friendship is to go and live with
somebody. Just think of all
the people who've fallen in
love. You're my soul mate.
They get married and within five years,
you know,
one of them goes mysteriously missing.
You know,
by the way,
that's a bad thing to do.
If you're going to kill
your wife or your husband,
you should really go practice on some
homeless people and prostitutes first,
you know, get you get your murderer
in game up to par. You know,
to really try and get away with a
murder with your first murder when you,
you have everything to gain
with that person being gone.
It's no wonder everybody gets caught.
You know,
you gotta you gotta suck it up.
You got to push your ego down
and go to the miners first.
Get some at bats down there at the foot.
The fucking,
the fucking Newark bears. They a couple
of pokes, you know, get out there,
shake the rust off. I'm sorry. Anyways,
took us last year. I decide to move
into a new place. I naturally, uh,
so when I'm looking to do that,
I naturally turned to him.
He was living on his own with his cousin,
was happy to move in with me.
Now since I have known him so long,
I know his tendency to be a slob.
I discussed with this,
with him before we moved in and let
them know I could only tolerate so much.
Uncleanliness he responded
back in, kind in. Agreed.
Now flash forward to after I move in,
I wake up in the middle of the night
to snoring that can wake the dead.
I do what any normal person would do
and go out and ask them to do something.
Since it was keeping me up.
The kicker is he wasn't even in his room.
He's laying on the floor
in the living room.
So I wake him up and asked him if he
could either a stop snoring or B go to his
room.
This elicits no response from the beast.
He attempts confrontation and finally
relinquished his to his room. Yeah,
this guy's a, he's, he sleeps
pretty hard. Um, he goes,
this has happened on and
off now for the past year.
Usually he just gives me the finger now.
Just gives me the figure.
Now when I wake them up for snoring,
clearly I get the impression that he
only cares about himself and gives two
shits about anybody else.
There's other things like him
not cleaning up after himself,
not caring for his pet and some smoking
habits that are less than appealing.
I'm willing to compromise though,
but he just makes no effort.
He refuses to address any of it.
He always says he thinks of me as family,
but I don't imagine anybody treating
their family. This actually,
that's exactly how you treat family
cause you know they're not going to leave
you. I'm so, he goes, so now,
so now I'm moving out and I haven't
told him this is the reason.
So what do I what? So bill, what do I do?
Do I tell him he's an asshole
and tell them to kick rocks.
So just forget about it and let bygones
be bygones. You just forget about it too.
All right? Because this guy was your
best friend until you live with them.
Just like,
okay,
just feel bad for his future wife and
this is the deal. One of these days,
you know,
he'll bring up,
you guys live in together and you'll just
laugh about it and just be like, dude,
I left because I swear to
God I was fantasizing about
going out into the living
room and chopping your fucking head off,
you know,
or just fucking stuffing a chloroform
rag in your God damn mouth it all and you
can just laugh about it. But to a right
now with how upset you are at him,
it's going to affect your
friendship. Um, you know,
if you'd done being friends with the guy,
I would bring it up now,
but if you're not, then I would just, uh,
I would use that story to get laid.
That's what I would do because
it will be a funny story.
And as you're telling the funny story,
the woman's going to be listening
and being like, Oh my God,
this guy's consider it.
He picks up after itself.
I have this unbelievable urge to
suck his dick. Now what is that?
Why do I do that guys? That's
how I would use it. All right?
And then whenever he brings
it up, just laugh about it.
That's like a, I live with,
uh,
Bobby Robert Kelly,
one of my best friends
in the whole wide world.
We almost killed each other
when we lived together,
but Opodo Polo [inaudible]
I left with them and he was a
fucking slob and I was the fucking,
I want, I mean, I'm not even that neat.
That's the thing. I'm not even that neat.
Like I don't make the fucking bed every
day. You know, I always have three,
four days of clothes, but I get to
that 0.34 days and then I pick up,
I'm pretty good about doing the
dishes, but he, he was just like,
I'd come back from the road and there
would be like dishwater like six days old
or something and they'd be like noodles
from like the Chinese food floating in
there.
It was like,
okay,
ah,
we didn't have any rubber gloves and I'd
have to stick my hand reached for that
plug. Oh, it was fucking nasty.
We lived in such a shit hole.
I got to talk to them about
that someday if he remembers.
We had this fucking kitchen.
The counter top was,
this was plastic.
I don't,
I don't know what it was like this hard
plastic and it was yellow and it was
dirty. It was, it was so fucking gross.
Like couldn't even cook in there
and had this fucking stove.
I swear to God that features,
you could rock it back and
forth two or three times.
It would literally come down like an
old shack. It was such a piece of shit.
And then the guy who actually
his name was on the lease,
used to keep his smelly hockey
stuff out there in the kitchen.
It was the most disgusting fucking thing.
And then there was three guys
living there and like assholes.
We had like a bathroom
basket out in the kitchen,
not a big like kitchen size of
bathroom one. So it was always,
always overflowing with whatever
the fucking eight. It was fucking,
it was nasty bug. That really just took
me back to a bad period in my life.
Although it's funny now.
It's funny,
yesterday I was over with Bobby and
his lovely wife eat some dinner.
She cooked a fucking tremendous meal and
we started laughing about the old days
living together. Right. And I'm
still friends with them, you know?
And you know what I did?
I addressed what a slob he was while we
were living together and we went like
six months without even speaking
to each other after we moved out.
And you know what? You don't want
to go through that type of shit.
But we were both young and immature.
Maybe that's where you're at.
Maybe you got to go through it. I don't
fucking know. Anyway, success story.
A Billy red face.
I'll keep this short,
but you gave me spot on advice a few
months ago about my cheating ex wipes.
So I sincerely thank you.
Well, you're welcome sir.
And if anybody's listening to this know
that I'm a fucking moron because every
once in a while like, you know,
he played darts long enough,
you're going to hit a bullseye.
Alright.
But you guys listened to me and my advice
at your own fucking risk. All right.
So anyways, he goes,
I couldn't be happier.
My real question is how long were you
single before you met Nia and would you
care to share any of your
bad dating stories? Um,
thanks and fuck. Syd The kid and the
pussy. Penguins Bruins and six. Alright.
Bruins fans. Um, how long was I single?
I was single for quite a while.
Uh, I don't remember. So
fucking long ago. I don't know,
a couple of years. Couple
of years. But I was not,
I was never good at being single,
doing that whole fucking playboy thing,
you know,
talking girls into bed and all that types.
I always felt like shit afterwards unless
the girl was like fucking smoking hot
and then you had like cute bleed. She
slept with me man. You know, kind of vibe.
I never a
okay.
I Dunno, you know, it is. By the time I
figured out how to talk a woman in bed.
By then I was like in my early thirties
and it was always something that,
you know, he fucking talking
to somebody like, you know,
2123 and they're just fresh
out of college. I literally,
it was like the pussy verges of watching
those rednecks hunting bear with dogs.
You know, I just didn't feel the, uh,
the sense of accomplishment after awhile,
you know, I'm a big softy. What
can I tell anyways? The man,
great system. Everybody father's
day, it's right around the corner.
Everybody all right.
And whose dad doesn't like to grill,
you know,
everybody's dad likes to go out there.
Even the people who don't like to grill.
There's just something about being a
guy cooking some raw meat over an open
flame.
I don't know what it is.
You actually in your and your head,
you feel like you hunted that thing
down like you shot that cow. You know
that saber tooth cow you just give you,
I don't know what it does.
It's in your DNA. So this father's
Day, thank the man. Great.
What is the man great us?
Well, I'm going to tell you,
put your eyebrows down because
here comes the information.
They are 100% made in America.
Cast iron grilling greats that are
revolutionizing the way people grill heavy
duty grilling greats.
Deliver exactly what you need to
achieve that perfect steak house flavor.
This is making me hungry right
now. Chicken, steak or veggies.
We'll never have tasted so good. No
more flare ups. No more dry meat.
Guaranteed named one of the 2012 best
grilling accessories by men's health
magazine. Man Grades are the perfect
gift for dad this father's Day.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter the
coupon code burpee you are are for their
1999 father's day special.
Or Click the man great banner on the uh,
on the show website,
20 bucks.
You're going to hook up your dad
for the whole summer. And basically,
if you don't understand what they are,
you know when you buy a grill,
they come with those anorexic, you
know, like those aluminum grill racks.
You know, you're trying to mark up
you stake. It doesn't look good,
but then when you go to a steak house,
they got those nice thick ones.
You know what I mean? That's what those
are. It's basically, it's like a hot rod.
You're upgrading the quality
and it's 100% made in America.
100% cast iron, 100% steakhouse,
quality grilling, and your backyard.
All right,
so remember each Monday morning podcast
order also comes with a heavy duty
grilling brush. The 20 bucks
people. Again, that's the man.
Great Grill enhancement system. Order
today, man, great.com magic man,
great.com and enter the
coupon code burpee. You are
are at checkout. All right.
All right. Last advertising of the weak,
weak, weak, weak, weak, legal zoom.
Everybody.
Okay?
America was built by
innovators and dreamers.
People like Edison, Henry
Ford, and then they write,
feel free to add your own example of
an innovator slash dreamer because last
week I, I laughed when I
read Steve Jobs, a Edison,
Henry Ford and Joe Derosa.
Joe's a dreamer.
He likes dreaming because
dreaming can make him mine. Um,
but it's the vendors and entrepreneurs
and entrepreneurs all around us,
people like you that made America
such a great country. That's right.
This month,
legal zoom celebrates innovators by help.
What they've really saying there was
at some point, Edison and Henry Ford,
but just like you go into a football
game with that plastic cap with the beer
cups in the strati of mouth, you
know, and then one day they will like,
I got to get my s together and next thing
you know you've got lights in a car.
All right,
so what are you doing?
What great idea you sitting
on the need to protect it.
You don't want some corporation
to steal it from you.
Go to legal zoom.com this month.
Legal Zoom celebrates innovators by
helping them launch their dreams.
Apply for a patent to secure
your, uh, your invention.
How awesome is that applying for a patent,
uh,
register your trademark to
protect your product services.
Incorporate or form an LLC and
launch your business dream.
Just call or visit legal zoom.com and
they'll take care of you from start to
finish. They've already helped a million
businesses get started the right way.
Okay? So if you got that great idea, okay,
the first step towards your dream is going
to legalzoom.com and making sure that
you're, you're incorporated
so nobody can sue you. And,
and the next one is you got to get a
patent so nobody can steal your ideal.
All right?
Then you're off to the races and I help
all you guys make a zillion dollars.
And it all starts with legal zoom.com.
All right,
let's get back to the questions here. Uh,
I really do want that for all you guys.
You know, if you're happy in a cubicle,
I know I break your balls about that,
but if you're happy you don't give a fuck,
then you know, happiness. I'd like to,
I'd like to like for you to
achieve happiness. Um, so anyways,
off to join the army, but up
[inaudible] at all. All right.
This is a good memorial day email. Hey
Bill, thanks for all the funny, well,
you're welcome.
He said,
I've come to a point in life
where decisions have to be made.
For the past seven years I've been working
within an industry that has thrown me
so many curve balls and fuck yous
that it just doesn't seem normal.
The brief roundup of what I've been
through, shit, canned three ones, three,
three weeks after buying a house.
Oh my God.
You know, I've never had to
deal with stress that level.
I can't imagine that one.
Number two business close
two weeks before my wedding.
Oh my God. So not only,
you're not making money,
you now have to be even more involved in
the wedding planning because you don't
have the, I gotta go to work.
Excuse. All right. Number three,
numerous dead end jobs and
what not leading up to today.
Although I have had the pleasure of
listening to the wise words of birth.
I don't know about that dude.
You're listening to a more on that
you can relate to you. You said, uh,
I have decided enough is enough.
I'm off to join the army.
Going to do a trade,
throwing away eight years within the
tech industry to become a chef. Um,
so be a chef in the army.
Did he go,
you just hang back and peel potatoes?
That's what I know. You're not even yet.
You fucking make that shitty army
food tastes unbelievable. You know,
and then you got it. Then you don't,
then you get fans within the army.
Then you come out, don't blow all your
money on hookers and all of that bullshit.
Save all your fucking money.
Be a chef in the goddamn army.
And, and then when you get out,
you know,
start your own restaurant.
Okay,
I'd experiment with food and find
out what the average American likes.
You know,
you have an a in total like
demographic right there,
running the gamut. You've got people
from all 50 states, all right.
And some of them know how to cook.
Maybe the southern guy can teach you how
to make some of that fucking barbecue.
You know,
somebody out in buffalo could show you
how to make some wings that are juicy on
the inside. Crunchy on the outside
is a tremendous opportunity.
You can go see the fucking world, eh? Uh,
I know it was other people in the army
see the fucking world over the middle of
this fucking shit. All I know, I'm sorry,
I'm trying to put a positive spin on
this. Yeah, it is. It is what you,
it's what you're, what you
put into it here. So he goes,
there's a lot of hard work ahead.
Yeah. That guy yelling in your ear.
What kind of chef do you know can
go through an obstacle course?
I hope you're going to do some
pushups buddy. And he goes,
it'll be well worth it in the end.
If all goes to plan,
I'll be away from home and
the wife for eight months,
nobody said I'd get a holiday to a lol.
Anyways,
just wanted to say thanks and
I'll be sure to listen always,
even when I'm living on some base,
far away from my friends and family.
All right dude.
Well good luck for your man.
Do you feel like that's
the right way to go?
I hope you come back to being
a chef though, man. You know,
if that's actually in your heart.
MMM.
You know,
it's funny,
that story just reminded me of something
and I was laying down and then I just
sat up and now I can't even
fucking remember the fuck.
I gotta go back and reread some
of this shit. I'm a chef. Uh,
hard work will be worth it. Ah, fuck.
What happened in my brain? Huh? What
happened to it? Everybody. All right.
We're almost done. Oh, I know
what it was. Getting into shape.
I gotta show you this youtube video,
by the way.
I love youtube more than
anything on the fucking planet.
It's one of the things that I always
go to, but this whole thing where they,
they're not letting you say, I don't
want to use my real name. You know?
I don't want to use my real name.
I don't know cause I write country shit
just because I don't want people knowing
who the fuck I am.
You know?
I don't even really leave
that many comments on youtube,
but you know what it is.
I just don't like how they're not
giving me the option to say no.
So you keep hitting the refresh button
and you know it's getting to the point,
you know? Well, you know what I would
do if I had any sort of computer savvy,
I would just start a total rip off
youtube where you can remain anonymous and
you just have the exact same fucking
videos. And anyways, I don't know how I,
I've tried to find this youtube video.
We're going to have it up there.
This guy has this fucking plank position,
five minute fucking workout
that I'm going to start doing.
You know the plank position where you
basically, it's like you're in the pushup,
pushup position, but you're,
you're, you're on your forearms.
So he, he does each one of these
positions for 15 seconds. All right?
This is basically the workout as
far as I can remember it. All right,
so you're doing the original
plank position. You're on
your forums. 15 seconds,
alright,
next 15 seconds.
You just have your left arm
pointed straight ahead like
you doing sieg Heil Heil
Hitler,
right?
You do that and then after
15 seconds you put that down.
Now the right hand Heil Hitler. All
right? This is by no means pro Nazi.
I'm just trying to give you a visual
here or you can just watch the fucking
video. All right? Then the next 15
seconds, she left leg straight out,
put that down. Then your
right leg straight out, right.
And then, then you go, uh,
left leg, right hand, right arm.
That's like a balance of thing.
And then the opposite of that.
Then you go to your cell.
It's fucking insane.
Like the longest I've ever been able to
do a plank position when I was in really
good shape was like two minutes.
So I'm on the ship,
I'm on this shit. All
right. To do it with me,
I'm going to want to put a link up to
the podcast page to the youtube video and
hopefully you don't have to go through
that rigor Moreau of having to leave your
real name if you do,
just hit the refresh button.
But I found lately if he hit
the refresh button too much,
it just keeps going back to it and then
you just have to shut it off and then
just click on youtube again.
It's a pain in the ass.
I don't know why they're doing
it, if anybody knows why. MMM.
I mean,
one of it I pointed the Chi kind of would
be great if people who write all that
racist shit actually had to leave their
real names. Maybe they wouldn't. Um,
but what does that really solve? There's
still going to be racist, you know,
they just know not to say it out loud
so they won't lose their jobs. Right.
Isn't that right? I don't
fucking know. Anyways, uh,
that's a podcast for
this week. Everybody, uh,
I still had a couple of good ones to
read here. Gay reminding you would get,
what else do you got to deal
with some Memorial Day, right?
Let's read a couple more horses. I hate
bill. Thanks for your relationship.
Uh, think of your relationship with
your dog. This is what you can,
you can have with the horse,
but it's more, oh yeah.
Cause I said if I ever had a horse, I'd
love to have a horse that I never wrote.
I hate that whole breaking the horse.
He goes,
dogs are kind of like
happy go lucky buddies.
They have a lightness
horse are like noble dogs.
They are a little smarter and can
be even more emotional than a dog.
So they uh, so they can be even
more loyal than a dog. They,
they have to be one over,
oh, you left out the beat.
They have to be one over with respect.
And once you do this,
they consider it a pleasure
to have you ride them.
It's a two way thing that's hard to
describe. Watched the movie black beauty,
the one with Alan Cummings as
the voice and go fuck yourself.
Um, all right. I, I don't know that they
would you ever find it a pleasure to
have 150 to 200 pounds on your back?
Magic.
If you had a backpack that way we'll
just say 180 pounds and I don't think,
was it on your back?
It was fucking slap in your ass telling
you to go faster and which way to go.
Would you enjoy that? I Dunno.
More horse stuff. I wanna know.
I want to know because I love horses,
but I just can't,
I could never break one that
would kill me. That really would,
that would hurt my fucking hat.
A underrated uncle billion.
This could be the
underrated of the century.
Keeping your Dick and check flipping
the script on the lace and refusing your
woman's sex.
I just told my girl no sex until she
goes and applies for 10 jobs today.
And the look on her face was priceless.
Like she just had no
clue what just happened.
Look like a little kid that had just
been just sad. It's teddy bear stolen.
Love the podcast and go fuck yourself.
You redheaded bastard. Ah, yeah.
Now that's a great one. That's a great
one. I'm like, you're fucking with that.
That's, you know, what you have in your
Dick and check is like you're a woman, um,
fucking bench pressing more than
you. That's basically it. I mean,
the core thing a guy has over a
woman as a, he's physically stronger.
Okay. Core thing a woman has is she does
that were run by our Dixwell. I mean,
they're all so smarter.
I think they're just there.
I do think women are smarter in, in a lot
of areas just because they have to be,
it's a nature thing. You know,
we're stronger. So we don't, we,
I think we just didn't use our brains as
much back when you could fucking drag a
woman around by her hair and beat her
with a branch. I shut the fuck up.
You know,
you didn't have to grow as a human being.
They had to sit there and be like,
how do I get that big,
dumb Oaf to do exactly
what I want them to do?
I can't grab him by the fucking throat.
How can I make him do it and actually
make him feel like it's his decision,
you know? Anyways, whatever. That's a
podcast for this week. Go fuck yourselves.
Um,
I'm torn with the teen idols sensation.
We're going to be at the count Basie
theater this Wednesday, you know,
one o'clock jump count bass.
He fucking theater out in Red Bank,
New Jersey. And then we're going down
to some fucking theater in Baltimore.
I don't have the names of these on
Friday. And then Saturday, I don't know.
I'm in some place in a, no, Thursday,
I'm in Baltimore.
Friday I'm in Pennsylvania and this
Saturday I wind it up with two shows down
there. And what do you call
in fucking Atlantic city.
And a tickets had been selling
unbelievable the best I've
ever sold in my career.
And I want to thank all you guys.
It means the world to me that you guys
are coming out to my shows and I get to
continue live in my dream here. Right? So
thank you for that. That's the podcast.
Like I said, go fuck yourselves.
Have a great memorial day,
and I'll talk to you next week.