Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
September 16th, 2013. I hope
this doesn't sound weird.
I don't know what happened.
I think my dog laid down on my mix.
It sounded weird. Sounded weird to
me, man. It's freaking me out. Me.
And, um, how was your weekend?
Why do I ask questions
that you can't answer?
Like I'm talking to a listener on the
phone. I'm not, I'm not doing that.
I'm laying here by myself as
always excited to be back home.
Um,
for those of you who have lives,
for those of you who just happened to,
I dunno,
end up on this podcast.
Welcome.
I do one of these every single week and a,
I have a website,
they bill bird.com and a,
if you like what you hear here and
you want to hear my fucking a standup
specials,
they have a hard copy version
and a $5 downloadable version.
Whatever the hell you want to do,
it's right there for your taking.
All right there.
Whored myself out early.
People showing a lot of
leg early in the podcast.
Um, I don't know where to
begin with this weekend.
Okay.
[inaudible] let's start at the beginning.
First of all,
just when I think Paul
Versey is a smart man.
Just when I think like,
no, no. You know what?
This guy isn't like,
I don't little,
I don't know what the word is.
Do you know?
I bet you guys have a lot
of people like this. I,
I know a number of guys in this business
who have these unbelievable like
perceptive powers. Like they see somebody,
they can read them and, and they,
they can figure out situations,
but you know,
you give them a simple math problem
and you just see the look on their face
and you the whole time you're friends
with them, you wrestle. You'll,
is this guy a smart guy?
Yeah.
Or is he a moron who just guesses
really well? Now fucking with you,
I obviously think Paul's a smart guy,
but you know, we all have our moments.
Paul Versey had a moment, uh, but
right before we went to Texas,
and this is the deal,
we're doing El Paso on a Thursday night.
We're doing San Antonio Friday night
and then Saturday we'll go into the,
uh,
the Alabama and Texas a and m game and
then we're going to get back and we're
going to watch the Mayweather fight.
That was basically the weekend.
That was the plan. That's
what was on the books. Okay.
El Paso is a makeup date on the Billy
red state tour and we added San Antonio.
Okay. So one step back, two steps
forward. That was the game plan.
So me and Virginia ridiculously excited
cause we're going to this fucking game
and we're going to drive from El Paso
to, to San Antonio. And in Texas is like,
you're driving that all
my God, good luck. That's,
you're not gonna see anything.
There's nothing.
It's going to be like driving on the
surface of the moon and all this shit.
This is what they tell us.
So I don't know what somebody told Versie,
but evidently he's watched a couple,
two or three things on these Mexican
drug cartels and he was freaking the fuck
out. Like he's going. Yeah, dude,
I don't know about this. Uh,
this El Paso, you know, they
got like these drug lords
down there and blah, blah,
blah, blah. And I don't know
if, wait, are we talking about
Paul? He goes, yeah man, I,
I just wish we had a gun or something.
He kept saying how he wanted to
bring a gun and I was like, Paul,
we're not going across the border.
I'm not saying it's not a dangerous city.
I'm not saying that it's not right
next to a really dangerous city.
And I'm not saying that something
fucked up might not happen, but you,
you're freaking out and I need you to
relax. And he just kept going. I'll do,
we should take the tire iron
and have that under the car.
I mean under the front seat of the car.
Like before when we liked,
this is a guy who lives and
works in New York City at night.
All right? This is a classic, classic
fucking New Yorkers. I'm telling you,
they are no different than somebody who
grew up in the middle of nowhere and
lives on a farm. They're the exact
same way. All they know is their world.
He's so used to the danger that's familiar
in New York City that he doesn't even
see it anymore and he watches one on one
or two of these fucking hardcopies 60
minute things on, uh, you know,
people get in their faces,
peeled back and getting tortured and
kidnapped and all that shit down there in
Mexico and all of a
sudden he's freaking out,
freaking out about Mexicans as he's
driving by the Puerto Rican day parade.
You see what I'm saying?
Worried that he's going to get robbed
when Wall Street is right down the
fucking, I dunno, right around
the corner from where he lives.
Those people have their fingers
in your fucking account already.
You're worried about some
hypothetical shit. All right.
Where you live as third and short El Paso,
that's a fucking Hail Mary when it
comes to something actually happening.
So I'm kept going, Paul, will you
fucking relax? It's going to be fine.
It's going to be great.
It's going to be a part of the country
you haven't gone to and we just kept bad.
No, dude, I'm just saying I'm not
an idiot. I know I'm from nude.
It just kept escalating and at one park
point I'm yelling at him on the phone
and I went and I screamed
the words drug cartel,
trying to reason with them and then I
just stopped and you can ask him this.
I just said, listen, I just said drug
cartel. I'm done with this conversation.
I'll see you in El Paso
so I fucking hang up.
So I get to the fucking airport.
I fly out and I'm ridiculously
excited to go to El Paso,
Texas and then fucking do this
drive down to San Antonio, Texas.
All right. That was the game. And
to let you know a left turns coming.
How about a little foreshadowing?
Here's a fucking letter in
email I got from some somebody,
I don't know where they live either in
New Mexico. I don't know what Orin, Texas,
this is what it says that my heart
is like, I can't wait to go here.
Can't wait to make up this date. I'll
probably do an hour and a half on stage.
This is going to be fucking awesome.
That was my intention.
This is the email I get Monday
morning. Thanks for nothing, Bill.
I'm done with you.
I twice you've ditched El Paso
and yesterday he means like, uh,
the day of the Gig,
he goes,
I wasn't notified until 4:12 PM the show
was at eight o'clock after a five hour
drive to El Paso, basically that
the show was canceled. He goes,
apparently you think nothing of El Paso.
So right now you got to
be sitting at your desk.
You gotta be sitting in your shop.
You got to be sitting at your cubicle,
maybe sitting,
sending a bus stop.
Maybe you're waiting for that
fucking plane to take off.
And there's some [inaudible] telling you
you have to power down your device and
you don't feel like doing it because you
want to know what happens in El Paso.
All right? So this is what
happens. I fucking, uh,
I landed in El Paso and overseas already
there and he's meeting me at the term
and El Paso's a great fucking airport.
It's one of those ones where there's no,
am I in terminal a terminal B?
The whole fucking thing is in one area.
It's like a mom and pop airport. Get
in, get out the securities grades.
Fucking awesome. I love it. All right,
so I land there and I get off the
plane and there's Versie alright.
Dressed like he's going to go
clean somebody's fucking pool.
Yeah,
he's got these fucking basketball shorts
that are hanging down below his knee.
Right. He didn't have on flip
flop. He had on black socks,
black sneakers and I think white shorts,
Mesh shorts that hung down below. He was
a fucking, and he said he was already,
it was already a shit show and he's got
his tee shirt on and he's sitting there
with a backpack,
like a book bag,
like he's going to class or something
and then like some assorted duffle bag,
like he's going to go to the gym in
1977 this is how the man travels.
Okay.
And he's standing there
with like this excited,
relieved and nervous look on his face.
He's at the airport and he's
fucking nervous about being
in El Paso because he's
convinced that he's going to get
kidnapped by some drug cartel.
Dragged back to Mexico
and held for ransom.
And evidently Obama's going to
get on TV and be like, you know,
we got to get this, this citizen back.
He's done so much for this country.
You know, this, this is what
he's fucking concerned about.
And immediately he starts going
like, yeah, dude, dude, you know, I,
I was just over there. You see that
they are selling a bunch of skulls.
They sounded like all these skeletons
and all these skulls in the, uh,
the gift shop and it sent Mexican holiday.
You know that the day of the dead,
I don't know when it is,
but they celebrate the dead.
It's a little weird, but whatever
Santa Claus isn't, you know,
some fat fuck coming down you
goddamn chimney to give you toys.
And if you're a cunt,
he puts some sort of fossil fuel.
Okay?
I love that. If you're
bad, you get coal. Well,
you still giving me a way to
heat the house. You dumb cunt.
Why don't you just hit leave?
Nothing.
Just why don't you just leave a terse
letter in my stock and you have a think
about that. Um, it's not Santa Claus.
It's Billy Gibbons. Grandfather.
A lot of people don't know that,
but let's continue. Speaking of Texas. So
I'm already laughing and I'm just like,
Paul, come on man. It's
the day of the dead.
And I actually went up and I bought the
magnet knee is actually into that shit.
So I was like, all right, let me, uh,
let me grab one of these fucking
magnet things here. And um,
so I'm just laughing at them.
So now we drive over and it's,
it's like already starting to rain.
Okay.
Which in my, in our worlds is no big
deal. It wasn't even that bad or rain.
It was kind of bad, but not that
bad. Right. So we're driving around,
I'm fucking all excited just checking out
the landscape, the different buildings.
And it's a really cool city where, you
know, they have some corporate shit,
but for the most part the Starbucks is
and those kinds of things. I don't know,
the skyscrapers aren't
really fucking with El Paso.
Like everything's kind of
like get, you know, like, uh,
no more than like a five story building.
There's a few, but generally speaking,
you drive down the street.
It looks like one giant main
street is all these places, right?
The lady at the Hertz Rental
car tells us where to get, uh,
some good Mexican food. We go there, I
forget the name of this shit that we had,
but it was on fucking believable.
It was great.
And of course we walk into the place
and it's some mom and pop kind of place
that the locals go to. We walk
in, everybody turns to look first.
He immediately thinks he's going
to get kidnapped. He goes, dude,
you just see that everybody's,
everybody's looking at us.
It's like Paul that happens in
a dive bar where you're from,
where you fucking relax,
you're going to get us fucking punched
in the face with that fucking look on
your face. Alright, Jesus Christ.
So we sit down,
we have an amazing fucking meal first
starting to relax a little bit, right?
And I'm sitting there and I haven't this,
this might, this little FedEx envelope.
I have the four tickets to l pass up
to El Paso to the, uh, the Aggie game.
And I got the four cigars were going to
smoke. All right. And, uh, you know, for,
for the, for people going into the game
and I just keep holding onto that thing,
like, yeah, might as well had
it handcuffed to my wrist.
I was so paranoid that I was
going to lose the tickets,
crushed the cigars and just fuck
up the whole weekend. So, um,
we eat, it's awesome. And we drive down
the main street and versus you just going,
yeah, I do that. I don't, I don't
like this, I don't like this. Right.
And he said she's all fucking
nervous and we get to the hotel,
it's a fucking hotel. They check
us in, everything's all good.
We get up to the rums and,
uh,
I called the venue by tee
shirts for the red state towards
shown up. Everything's looking
like it's going to go good.
Then it starts raining a little
bit more. But once again, you know,
actually when we would go in there too,
there was some streets that were blocked
off because of flooding. And I'm like,
ah, you know, it's kind
of a desert out here,
so I guess they don't handle the rain
too well, but I wasn't thinking anything.
And then all of a sudden my agent called
up along with the promoter and they
said,
listen,
the first thing they sent me was that
it had the venue, it got switched,
which should've been the first red flag.
They said the venue I supposed to perform
it lost power and they were having a
little bit of flooding or something
like that. And I was like, you know,
I'm looking at my hotel
window like really?
I had no idea I that doesn't seem
right. So then they fucking, they said,
change of venue. It said, please
wait, let me confirm that.
And I said,
all right.
So I sat there and all I'm thinking is
people are driving into the fucking show.
I don't want to start the show and have
half of them go to the wrong theater.
The other half girl, the right
to you. So I say fuck it.
And I tweeted out and I say,
a, the venue has been changed.
It's now over here, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Um,
about a half hour after that,
my agent and the fucking promoter
call up and they say, listen,
um,
you know,
we're now having problems
at the other theater.
Like there might be a power outage and
because of the flooding and roads and all
this type of shit,
people like maybe half the
crowd is going to show up.
So I was like, all right, wait a minute
now if only half the crowd shows up,
does that other half get
refunds? And they said, no.
So what do you want to do?
Do you want to do the show or
do you want to reschedule it?
So at that point I'm going to fuck
over half the people. So I said, no,
let's reschedule it. I'll fly back out
here. It's only, you know, a couple,
two, three hour flight. I'll
do it again. And uh, you know,
I'll figure something out. You know,
let's rescheduled as soon as we can.
So I went on Twitter,
I deleted that one,
and then I sent the thing and I knew that
there was going to be people like this
guy who's fucking pissed.
Um,
all of that shit happened
between two and four o'clock.
So my apologies to the person
who's done with me, but, uh,
you know,
and I said on Twitter to
quote breaking bad and uh,
Hule slash Lavelle Crawford
who's a fucking, a phenomenal
comedian and actor, uh,
was an act of God. There was nothing I
could do was I supposed to do, you know.
Um, so I, uh,
I apologize that it didn't
happen and then, you know,
me and [inaudible] went out and got
absolutely fucking hammered and spend as
much money as we could in El Paso
killing our livers and brain cells.
I actually,
we went to a bar and we uh,
I ran to a couple people that was supposed
to come out to the show and they kind
of explained to me that because
it doesn't rain out there a lot,
that the grounds really dry and it can
absorb it and then you just kind of flows
down right over the top of it.
I have no idea because that looked like
a above average rain storm to me and um,
so whatever. So I am going to reschedule
it. Surf you are done with me. Uh,
I understand,
but I was not my fault and the first time
I guess it was my fault cause I chose
an acting gig in a movie. But um,
what the, what am I supposed to do?
I have to do that. That'd be
like, sir, you are going to
go to my, my fucking show.
And all of a sudden the chick you always
wanted to bang says, Hey, you know what?
You can hit it but only tonight.
What are you going to say?
You're going to come and see my
dump. Freckled redhead, you're not.
So there you go. All right.
So that's just the beginning.
People of my Texas trip,
my tech,
my trip to the great state of fucking
Texas. Um, all right, let me, uh,
it's not one of these things out here.
People will advertise and for the
weak dollar shave club, everybody,
there's so many things in the
world that irritate me. Um,
reigning in hell in El Paso, Texas
that causes the shows to get canceled.
This guy walking around telling
everybody wherever the hell he lives,
then I'm a piece of shit and
that I don't care about El Paso.
I care about a party.
Um,
when you fly out of a smaller city,
so they stick you on a smaller plane.
So instead of taking 50 minutes and now
it takes the same fucking three hours,
so you might as well just flown out
of Dallas. That also irritates me. Um,
when so many things can irritate you,
why add razors to the list?
It's time to stop milking
your razor blades. Everybody.
I know with brand name razors,
you're used to paying outrageous prices
and exhausting those razors until they
start to look like rusty soda
cans. Um, it's time to move on.
Dollar Shave Club delivers amazing
quality blades to your door for just a few
bucks a month. Never think about it
again. They send a pack every, oops,
they sent a pack every month for the
love of God. Can we fix this copy?
I trip up over that every damn week.
They send a pack every month so you
can change your blades every week.
So it's a four pack.
Giving a new blade every week.
I love these guys and you flight
your face will love them too.
I don't love their copy though.
They've also got a new pop up new
product called one wipe Charlies people.
You have to watch this video.
It's hilarious.
It's a buttwipe for men and it's classy.
Check out the video for that and
sign up for your razors today.
It's basically the poor man's per
day. What it is is it's a, it's a,
it's a baby wipe one wipe Charlie baby.
Go to Charlie.
Charlie got a dollar to dollar shave
club.com forward slash bur bur.
That's dollar shave club.com.
Forward slash bur bur or go to the,
go to bill [inaudible] dot com and
click the dollar shave club banner.
Okay. Hulu plus. I'm sure
you've tried hulu.com everybody,
but I want to talk to you
about Hulu Plus Hulu plus.
What lets you watch thousands
of hit shows anytime,
anywhere streaming on your TV or
go with your smart phone or tablet.
Why start in a lot? Well, why
stand in a line or ride on a train?
Just stare at your feet. You could be
watching your favorite shows on Hulu.
Plus Hulu plus is a great way to binge
watch your favorite TV shows. Um,
it has tons of episodes
from great comedies like SNL
community, modern family,
South Buck, family guy, and
thousands of other shows.
It's only 799 a month.
That's seven 99 for all the
shows and movies you can watch.
Catch up on current shows, binge on
old favorites or catch a great movie.
You can do it all on Hulu plus right now.
You could try Hulu plus for
a couple of weeks free on me.
When you go to the podcast
page at [inaudible] Dot
Com and click the Hulu plus
or go to Hulu plus.com/bill please
make sure you use Hulu, Hulu,
Hulu plus.com/bill so you can get
an extended free trial. And so that,
so they know that we sent you. All right.
That's it. Hulu plus.com/bill. Okay.
All right,
let's continue on.
So unfortunately for the second
time the El Paso Gig did not happen.
Um,
I don't know why.
I have no idea why it didn't seem
like it was raining that bad.
I definitely saw a lot of
emergency vehicles. There
was definitely a lot of, uh,
you know,
flashing official lights.
I know I had to make like three d toward
turns because the road's kept getting
blocked off. But, uh, I don't know.
I'm determined to make this show happen.
Maybe the third time
will be a fucking chair.
Um, all right. So anyways,
so me and [inaudible] go
out and we watched the, uh,
the Patriots jets game and he's cracking
up because I have the entire patriots'
offense and defense and jets offense
and defense written down on two cheat
sheets,
flipping them over and that type of stuff.
So I know what the hell is going on
because I'm obsessed with watching the
offensive line this year,
you know,
and I'm also enjoying watching Brady
playing with the level of talent that he
has at the wide receiver
position and watching him, uh,
getting frustrated and trying to
get those guys on the same page.
And I already saw a huge
improvement between, uh,
the first week and the second week,
especially from a, that Tompkins kid.
The first week he had a brutal week,
I think maybe you have one cat,
she bumped into another receiver on like
a pig play down by the end zone. And uh,
I know I thought he was a 100%
better and I know it was a sloppy,
ugly game, but I liked to, shit,
I like watching a team rebuilt.
Like I said, it's a very, it's
very healthy for the fan base.
It's kind of like a forest fire where it's
necessary. It's kind of a horror show.
You don't want to see it, but
it's necessary, you know, and uh,
when a team has to rebuild,
what it does is, uh, it Kinda,
it burns off a lot of the bandwagon. Um,
I actually got into with a buddy of mine,
he was sitting at saying that
Bellacheck is overrated. And, uh,
what has he done since 2004 when
last time we won? It's like, I dunno,
went to two more Superbowls.
Okay.
Four grand total of seven
Superbowls that he's, he's been to,
is that right? Three. Five, seven.
Yeah. And he's won five out of seven.
You know what I mean? Hey, find
out what the fuck you problem is.
And we went through a soup bowl two years
ago. That's like some New York, Philly,
Boston shit where it's like,
they get this so fucking,
I don't know what,
so quick to pull the trigger and be like,
fuck this. I'm Outta here. You know?
I mean, a lot of shit happened.
We lost Welker to free agency.
We didn't want to pay him, but we've
always done that. That's been our model.
We let ty Lago,
lawyer Malloy all the way back.
We let all those guys go when we felt
they wanted too much money and that it was
going to affect, uh, the overall
level of what we wanted to do.
Bella check is always, you know,
traded his way out of the first round.
He's running to get a second round guy.
We could have had Dez Bryant. He goes,
I don't want to get that fucking guy.
You know,
he doesn't like that flash type shit.
He just doesn't,
and it's when you want too much money,
let you go.
He's been doing that
forever and it's worked.
So I'm not questioning the guy and uh,
I'm going to enjoy watching
them try and, uh, you know,
win some games this year and the
very what looks to be very weak,
AFC east.
Um,
I'm going to say some really obvious
shit this week about football. Uh,
I watched the Broncos giants
yesterday tape that game.
And a Broncos are obviously
the team to beat. Um,
I didn't know they had
holiday to being an Lsu fan.
I was trying to keep an eye on
him when he went to the Texans.
He just was so exciting to
watch when he played for Lsu.
I didn't get to see him too much.
Um,
I know he took back a word kickoff
and upon a playoff game last year,
but now the Broncos have,
and we took one back.
So now that special teams are a threat,
they got a great defense or offensive line
is ridiculous. They got that dude, uh,
the hell's his name there. Uh, no,
Sean Moreno and Peyton looks
better than he ever did.
So obviously that's the team to beat.
Uh,
okay.
You know, the usual powerhouse
teams, the Patriot Steelers in them,
they're not looking too good.
Somebody for the love of God.
Figure out the fucking San Diego
chargers for me, Jesus Christ,
those fucking guys,
what they're doing to their fan base.
If I hadn't been down to a game
and had such an awful time,
I would actually feel bad.
I actually still do.
I feel bad for most of the people because
I'm sure most of the people were cool.
It's just a cut sitting behind me.
Um,
okay.
But anyways, but I gotta tell
you, even after the Broncos
handle their business with the,
uh, the giants, I have to tell you,
watch and Seattle on the 40 niners was,
it was what,
it was a whole other level
of a professional football.
And,
um,
and even though Seattle really manhandled,
not manhandled,
but really handled the 40 niners,
um,
I've just watched enough football
to realize it's only September.
And that doesn't mean shit. It's
definitely a good thing you won the game.
But that by no means basically says,
well, you'll definitely beat them again,
and then you'll beat them
again if you have to win.
If you've got to play in January, it's
probably going to go back and forth. But,
uh, I guess, Hey, that
dude, Richard Sherman,
not only is a fucking phenomenal player,
but he, that guy's fucking hilarious. Um,
somehow I missed last year when he
would yelled at Brady. I miss that.
You know what it is? I don't watch
pregame and postgame analysis.
I just can't sit there and watch about
people talking about people getting it
done and not getting it done and what
people have to do that day. It's like,
I dunno, I, that shit drives me well,
you know, you know what I really like.
I like when they cut to that guy who knows
the rules and can break down what the
fuck just happened.
I liked that stuff.
And I like listening to the
former players tell stories,
but like analysis of what just
happened or what's going on.
So I usually just shut the thing off.
MMM.
And so what our eyes,
I saw the Brady thing and then I
watched that thing where he came at skip
Bayless. We see set, I'm
better at you in life.
It said I'm the top whatever in my field
and I would not put you in that level
and broadcasting.
And I just thought it was hilarious
and um,
I dunno, I thought he could
have hit him even harder.
You know what he should have said if
some point Richard Sherman should've said
to skip Bayless when skip
was disagreeing with the,
with, with, you know, Sherman,
that he was one of the,
I guess top guys in the League,
whatever the hell the argument was,
what he should've said to him was he
should have said, yeah, what do I know?
What do I know? I just play for a
real professional football team.
I don't play in a fantasy football team.
I just do this for a living.
I play football for a living. You
Watch it? Yeah. Why? Why would I know?
Why would I know better than you
please you, you sit there with the,
a brand new knees and shoulders that
have never been fucked up in your brain
that's never been concussed cause you
never played a context sport you bad bit
and play in Jackass with your fucking game
show host hair. Why don't you tell me?
Why don't you tell me who the best
fucking quarterbacks are in the league?
I if he, if he went that way. Oh,
I already loved what he did. So,
mmm.
I'm looking forward to
that. A, he was funny,
he went up be pat his old coach on the
ass after he beat him. I think that's,
I think that's really,
especially
if it gets the job done,
but if you are gonna run your mouth,
you better hang out on the field if
they loose. Which, but like I said,
I don't know much about him,
but a Seattle looks fucking,
they look amazing and uh,
I,
I was laughing my ass off when I
saw Pete Carroll doin though. Woo.
He's got more of an edge to him now.
He used to just look like he was Robert
Young on father knows best to bring out
a fucking reference from 60 years ago.
He used to look wholesome.
I don't know what happened to him at USC.
I know some dirt went down,
you know. And uh, do you
guys see the cover of this?
Why don't Fall Pete Carroll?
Did you guys see the cover of
our sports illustrated this week?
Talking about all this stuff that happened
at Osu and all the filth and the sex
and the scandals and the boosters
and all that type of shit. Um,
I think at this point sports illustrated
has done a cover story about probably
half the football programs.
They write that article every
fucking year and a half,
two years about some sort of scandal
about either football, basketball,
whatever sport that's going on.
And they act like it's shocking.
Um, here's the deal. Okay.
If it wasn't for these football
and basketball programs
and the money that they
generate, most people's fucking
campuses would look like El Paso,
Texas, a fucker with the El
Paso. But you know what I mean?
They'd look like
there would be nothing there.
The sports programs build
all the dormitories,
the eye and that article,
I read the pack 12 sine of $3 billion
TV contract and these kids are going out
there,
you know,
doing lifetime damage to their bodies
for no fucking money for no money.
Um, I know a lot of people
go, well you mean no money.
You give free education to joke the foot.
Say they had time to fucking go to school.
Okay,
let's just say they had time to do,
let's just say that the schools also
only drafted people who could actually,
you know,
uh,
only sign people could actually
handle the school work load.
You know what I mean?
They didn't get somebody
who flunked everything in
fucking high school and found
a fucking loophole and then stuck
them in the basket weaving class.
Let's say they actually fucking tried
to educate them. You don't have time
with that. I Dunno. I don't think you do.
Anyways, I'm going to skip Bayless. He,
I never fucking play. And then
secondly, if you get hurt,
they'd take away your fucking scholarships
and then not trying to educate you.
And even if they do fucking educate you,
the amount of fucking money generated
versus what it costs to stick you in a
fucking dorm is a joke.
It's a fucking joke. So
I don't
know what the solution is.
I Dunno if you pay him,
but I understand why those boosters come
around and give the money. I get it.
It's fucking ridiculous.
Look,
if I go to some fucking strip mall and I
give a great show and I sell a bunch of
tickets,
like I get compensated,
you know what I mean?
I, I don't, and these guys play
in front of an entire stadium,
entire fucking stadium sold out nationally
televised fucking games and they
don't get any, they get like a
$15 like stipend, $15. I mean,
I guess you could feed you and two other
teammates if you went to Mcdonald's.
I don't know what, but anyways, I'm just
saying it's a filthy fucking business.
So,
uh,
I don't need sports illustrated to expose
what you already know what's going on.
I mean, Jesus Christ, it's the same
story they've been doing forever.
And then they get some hot girls there
and they fucking bang the recruits so
they feel like, wow, I'm going to be a
rock star here. Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
They're doing what they're
supposed to be doing,
that trying to make money and that's how
the game's played. All right. So anyways,
uh,
so the El Paso Gig gets rained out and uh,
I was anticipating way more emails
like that. So, uh, people of El Paso,
you're very understanding and
the person who's pissed at me,
I get why you mad at me. Uh,
but I, I can't handle it at the,
the weather or the typography is not,
is beyond my control.
All right? So I'm going to
reschedule it and uh, you know,
if you don't show up,
I understand why.
Okay.
I, you know, go fuck yourself at fucking
rain and they cancel it. I did, you know,
Geez, I'm done apologizing. All right. Um,
so next day we wake up in the morning
and a, we're going to go drive to,
uh, from El Paso, San Antonio, Texas.
And everybody is telling us that, you
know, like they said that there's,
you know,
there's nothing out there.
It's going to be like driving
and they'd like laughing at me.
Then I'm going to do it cause
it's like a seven hour drive,
eight hour drive or whatever.
And I got to tell you was one of most
beautiful drives I've ever gone on in my
life verse.
He's freaking out.
Like he was worried that between El Paso
and San Antonio Somehow we were going
to get abducted driving the
speed limit 80 miles an hour.
So I'm doing like 87 88 and got the
cruise control set. We're fucking flying.
I don't know what he thinks somebody
is going to jump off, you know,
down a highway.
I don't know what he thought was going
to happen and if you saw what was on
either side of us,
anybody who comes
at us is going to be like
hallucinating from lack of of water.
It looked like a spaghetti western out
there. It was absolutely fucking gorgeous.
You ride a motorcycle,
that would be a great one to go.
I would definitely wait till it
wasn't so fucking hot out. Um,
I'm telling you Plat, we saw
a fucking, everything we saw,
we saw vultures on the side of the road.
The real ones.
The ones,
what the hell boy heads that
fucking all red head and,
and the fucking those black feathers
just picking apart this carcass was
fucking, I was unbelievable.
Absolutely gorgeous.
It made you want to ride a horse. It was
one of the great drives I've ever had.
Um,
so underrated El Paso,
Texas and then driving to San Antonio,
Texas.
It was a fucking great time.
Um,
and people saying that there's,
I guess nothing out there to see
basically means you can't go to a subway
sandwich. There's no
mall, there's no outlet.
There's no movie theater. That classic
shit. Well, when I go out there,
I can't see what I can already see here.
Therefore they got nothing
out there for me to say.
I shouldn't have done that in a southern
accent because they appreciate the
outdoors. Those southerners, hell half
of them live in the outdoors, don't they?
It is a stereotype. Sorry. Um,
okay.
Silversea it now [inaudible] is
enjoying ease and joy and Nah,
he's starting to enjoy Texas about,
look at this Paul.
Every fucking twist and turn
every going up and down the hill.
Look at this valley. Look at that.
Look at that plateau, look at that.
I don't look at those rocks. Legit
shit. We're not going to see. Um,
yeah.
And meanwhile our buddy
who's going to the game,
he'd already arrived in San Antonio and
he thought we were driving. So he's like,
dude, I'm already at the
hotel bar. Where are you guys?
So rather than text and back,
we made them this fucking, uh,
this video that we actually, we did
with two. We did it with two i-phones.
We use the music on my iPhone.
I ran it through the radio and then verse,
he filmed it and we did it. And uh, I
think it was two texts. The first take,
the music was too loud.
And then the second take is the
one that we actually used. And uh,
he fucking laughed his balls off.
It's basic.
It's a video from us to our buddy who's
sitting in San Antonio letting them know
that we're driving and we're on our way.
So definitely check that out.
That'll be up on the, um, the
podcast page. Bill [inaudible]
dot com check it out.
Now. What am I saying?
It's going to be up.
It'll be up by the time are listening
to this, hopefully. Um, so anyways,
we're driving and as far
as finding places to stop,
it's definitely slim
pickings. So we ended up, uh,
we stopped at
this Mcdonald's.
We had to get gas and we just
stopped at a fucking Mcdonald's.
There was nothing else out to any
port in a storm. So we go in there,
we walk in and Mcdonald's is something
you do, I love about Mcdonald's. You know,
you shouldn't be nay.
So you always avoid it.
But when you finally give in
that you're going to eat it,
this is certain level of excitement
or you just like, fuck it.
If I'm going to eat it, I'm strong
with down. So I went in there,
I had been in there and I can't remember
the last time, and they got something,
they got a triple cheeseburger
and it's like, absolutely,
I'll take one of those fuckers as perfect.
I'll take one of those,
give me a large fry and a,
then I got a water.
That was my way of trying
to be halfway healthy.
Forsee orders like a fucking smoothie.
I love it.
It Mcdonald's go to is a fucking smoothie,
right?
It's probably ground up like squirrel
tail with some, I don't even know.
I don't know what, um, so he orders that.
So we're standing in line
and we're waiting to get
our food and all of a sudden
Versie just creeps up on me,
gets right in my ear,
and he just goes, dude, don't turn around.
I don't look.
But there is a guy right behind me sitting
down in a red shirt with the mustache
who is trying to fucking stare me down.
He just,
no joke,
dude.
He just gave me one of the most hardcore
fucking stare down it looks I've ever
seen in my life. All right, so now
he's got me fucking nervous. I'm like,
what the fuck's he talking about?
So I kind of do the pretending to stretch
and I glance over and I look over at
the guy and he has like some
sort of brain damage. Okay.
He's sitting there, you know
that full metal jacket. Look you,
your head's kind of down.
So you're looking through the horizon
of your eyebrows with your mouth hanging
open. That's what he's doing.
There's barely any brain activity.
I don't know if he had some sort
of, uh, a head trauma or whatever,
and then I kind of scan around them and
there's like seven other adults with the
same look on their face.
And then I look in this two reasonable,
not reasonable to regular
looking at adults.
Whatever adjective I use is
going to be offensive. Um,
two adults with all their faculties,
obviously they brought these people
here in a van to fucking Mcdonald's.
And I look at Paul, Mike
Duke, the guy's fucking idiot.
It's got special needs.
You should've seen the guy though.
He looked like fucking a,
you know,
Jack Nicholson in one flew over the
cuckoo's nest. When he fakes it,
he got the lobotomy. That's what
the fuck this guy look like. And
so finally verse,
he just starts laughing and he
realizes that he's being an idiot.
And now he's so into Texas.
We're driving for the rest
of said to San Antonio,
he's looking for a place
to buy a cowboy hat.
And a couple of cap guns cause he wants
to make another fucking youtube video of
him standing on the side of the road
of this, of this highway on a rock,
you know,
doing some shit about how he loves Texas.
And this is the same fucking guy who
like two hours earlier wanted to have a
tire under one under the seat and some
sort of fucking pistol to shoot whoever
the fuck was going to kidnap
us. So I don't know, long
story short then we've got,
we have got to San Antonio, we did the,
we did that Gig. Had a great time. And uh,
I think I'm going to run out of time here
because I've got to read your letters.
We ended up going to
the, uh, the next day we,
we go to the ag you game and
we were coming up from Houston.
We drove over to Houston. So we basically
drove across the state of Texas, uh,
on the 10 from El Paso all the
way to Houston and then a Houston.
We fucking drove to a Walmart to
meet this booze bus to drive us up.
Now they had to booze buses and
eight in the morning and one at 1130.
Everybody jumped on the eight
in the morning cause they
wanted to get fucked up.
We showed at the 1131,
it was like us,
this older couple and then a
group of four people in the back,
the whole bus to ourselves.
And they are Alabama fans and they were
all cool as hell. And it was awesome man.
They had all these beers and then they
had like this, uh, you know, some brisket,
beans and all this shit
that they made for you.
It was fucking great with Chow and
the food was slamming beers. Um,
we've got the cigars, we got the
tickets were ready to go drive up there.
There's no fucking traffic because
everybody's already there partying and we
pull into college station,
we see the stadium,
we see everybody up there with
the fucking, uh, Aggie colors on.
I never noticed how much,
how much rent,
a brighter red Alabama's
colors are then the ag is.
And until you saw the two fans, you
know, Stan it together and was just,
it was fucking awesome. We had a
great time going into the game,
right as we got,
and we got an adjust right up to the
flyover and Manzell was starting to drive
down the field and do it.
I gotta tell you when they scored
those first two touchdowns,
the stadium was going fucking crazy.
Aggies go up 14 to nothing.
Okay.
And uh, you know, cause we were
thinking Alabama was going to win.
I didn't think they were going
to cover it, but I was like,
I think they're going to win.
And uh,
he goes up 14 and nothing and they was
shutting them down on defense and then I
don't, it was one of the loudest
stadiums. I fucking bed and,
and then all of a sudden,
oh by the way,
that whole fucking thing with the Seahawks
fans trying to set the record to be
the loudest crowd is one of the gay
is things I think I've ever seen in my
fucking life. You know, what
are you guys doing? You know,
you know what that shit,
somebody tweeted me that and I said,
well you know when you've never won a
championship you got to hang your hat on
something.
What is the purpose of that Seattle
fans and you might win one this year,
but as of right now, what, what are you
guys doing? What is, what is the, the the,
do you guys have a team song?
If it is, I, I, if I, if it is,
I have to guess it's going to,
it's basically this,
we are the loudest by friends,
eh?
Okay.
Till we lose Doo Doo,
Doo Doo.
Who we are the loud it is.
Oh louder.
Loud.
Cause the architect designed the
building to make a sound louder.
You're a bunch of cheaters up there.
You're not louder than anybody else,
you know louder than those Aggie Fan.
They had some rooftop orchestra
fucking pit to keep it all
contained. Bade sound loud
to this is the thing people,
I went to a game there, I heard I'll
fucking unbelievably loud it was,
but I looked at the fans and
you weren't yelling any louder.
There was no guy like,
like fucking punching himself.
Like how you could yell louder
than any other human beings.
You're, you're, we're basically created,
we call came out of the same fucking mud
puddle. You can't yell louder, you know,
more passionate or nothing. You just
got that little rooftop thing there.
Hold it in.
You know why?
Because for all these years you've
needed that extra help. All right?
But enough, just when a fucking
championship, when a Goddamn Chan,
which might happen this year,
I hope it does because when it does,
you won't waste your time on stupid
pointless things like trying to be the
loudest, you think you're louder
than Kansas City chief fence.
Those fans allowed. Okay. And
they've had nothing to chairs about.
Tear of off for fucking years.
So anyways, so we go in there,
the fucking Aggie game.
It was ridiculously loud.
All natural to no ped snow
architect trying to help him out.
Just fucking completely natural Christ.
They didn't even have half a fucking
third. A third of the stadium was missing,
you know, one of the end zones, they
just had these little bleachers.
You could see the dorm rooms, the
traffic going by, you look far enough,
he could probably see a cow taken
a shit out in the field. Um,
so anyways, they go up 14 to nothing.
And then here comes fucking Bama.
14, seven, 14, 1421,
14, Alabama, 28,
14 Alabama than halftime.
And I gotta tell you they took the fucking
air out of that stadium. All right.
Fucking Aggies. Did they get the ball
back? I think Alabama had at first,
I don't remember. I was
pretty hammered. Uh,
but all I know is that they
stopped them or whatever,
but then the Aggie start fucking drive
and then they throw a fucking pick and
the guy takes it back. 35, 14,
five unanswered touchdowns. And, uh,
one of my buddies that I'm,
I'm with WHO's in the pro
semipro football hall of fame.
All right. Which is a fucking
accomplishment, more than
skip Bayless of it. Did.
Why am I attacking skip? I just think
it's funny to make fun of that guy.
I don't give a shit about him either
way. Um, he was just talking about, uh,
Alabama's offensive line that just
saying like the blown them off the ball.
I don't give a fuck who you, what weapons
you have. If you went in that war,
you're going to win the fucking game.
And he was saying how uh,
what's his face was going to run
the score because they uh, they uh,
they lost last year or they beat,
they got beat last year. And uh,
so I'm sitting there, I, I can't believe
once again, I get unbelievably depressed.
I just want to see Alabama fucking
loses is the second year in the role.
But then all of a sudden here
come the Aggies, 35, 21. Okay.
The kind of back in it and then it
was dead. Fucking Alabama scores. 42,
21, people start thinking it's over.
But then the Aggie score again, 42,
28.
Then they finally got that number four
in Alabama to fucking do something wrong
all day. He fumbles the
ball, they get the ball,
they throw it to that number 13
kid. Fuck, I should know his name.
The guy had like 290 something
yards receiving at Goddammit,
I'm the worst.
I really should know his name and I
should say at the name of every fucking
offensive lineman on Alabama,
they were fucking unreal. Anyways,
they're on like their own
six or five yard line. He,
Johnny football throws
the thing like 50 yards,
13 catches it's stiff arms
to dude covering them and
runs the rest of the way of
fucking like 96 yard touchdown.
And now all of a sudden it's 42 35.
It's like,
what the fuck?
Here come the Goddamn Aggies.
And then right when you think
they're going to tie it up,
just Mike going overtime.
Fucking Alabama scores 49 49 35 and then
fucking Aggies come back 49 42 and then
that was it. And it was fucking
over that. Why me? Tell me,
what is that seven 76 13 touchdowns,
13 touchdowns.
The Aggies had over 600 yards in
offense and still lost the game.
Um, I dunno, it was an, it was an
unbelievable, unbelievable game.
Um, [inaudible] self at some point
you got to go to college station,
go take taken an Aggie game.
We didn't have time to hang out the Dixie
chicken and all those places that look
cool as hell. Um, cause we had to
catch the fucking bus going back.
And uh, all right, as great
as the bus was going back,
it was an absolute shit show. I mean,
coming up, it was great going back,
it was an absolute fucking shit show.
First of all, we get back to the thing,
you know where we're supposed to meet
and everybody's breaking open brews.
And at this point I'm done with drinking,
you know,
cause I'm gonna fucking fall asleep
and I want to watch this fight and I'm
sitting there and then this,
this,
this lady comes up to me and she
starts talking to my buddy and he said
something really nice about is she asked
him a question and he said something
really nice about his wife like
ours or she just said, hey,
what do you think about all these ag
girls out here? And he goes, ah, you know,
I'm married, I love my wife, I don't
really look above blah, blah, blah.
And then she goes, good
answer. Like all of a sudden,
like he has to fucking get her fucking
approval and immediately I'm just like,
can't
cunt.
You know when you're going to whisper
it. Right? What a Dick. Good answer.
Okay,
so you give me another thing
too was nobody's talking to you.
Just come fucking walking up, right? So
she says to me, what are you doing here?
I said, Oh, you know, I've just hanging
out with my friends who had came out.
She goes, I was, is she? She
goes, is this your little,
is this your little guy's weekend out?
Right?
And I'm just like looking at, and I
just looked, I was like, no, no, no,
it isn't.
Okay,
Doug, who are you? Get the
fuck Outta here. You know?
Then she went over and she started
throwing a football and she could throw a
football. So that I think that I
shouldn't have whispered, can just cut.
She's not a right. She could
throw a football. This,
there's gotta be something that's all
right with her. Right. So anyways,
so this guy on the way up on the bus,
like 30 year old guy from Alabama was
a cool guy, funny guy and all that.
Now he's completely loaded and is one of
the biggest jerk offs you're ever gonna
meet and your fucking
life in Amelie's like
you hang here college day, should you,
hey here you go. Hey come on you are. Hey
cause it was two buses, the early one
in the next one left for another four us
the chain here called station.
We you are hanging here in college station
and I'm like no I'm on the early bus
and all I'm thinking is thank God this
fucking jackass is not on the early bus
cause I don't know what happened to him
cause he was a great guy and the way up
shut the shit with them almost for like
the whole fucking write up.
We were all taught his group and our
group was totally cool but I don't know
this fucking guy,
one of those guys add alcohol.
He becomes a completely different person.
So now we got to go meet
this booze bus back.
There's a bunch of people I
know it's going to be packed.
And who comes walking up this
fucking Shit Bird, right?
Well, you know, no one else is.
Dang it has the word taking the bus.
We get on the bus,
I sit down verse,
he sits next to me in this fucking jerk
off and his buddy, his buddy was cool.
They sit right across from us cause sort
of diagonal. So immediately what I do,
because it's pitch black out,
it's Sun's gone down.
I just closed my eyes and I act
like I'm sleeping. Cause I'm like,
I'm not making contact with
that fucking shit show. Right?
And are the buddy sitting right in
front of us and uh, this fucking guy,
I'm telling you,
the whole ride back would not shut up.
And he's just yelling,
hey, hey, 12th man, I ain't he shear.
You guys were quiet as hell.
I, no couple of touchdowns.
Then he just starts
saying I'd suck a Dick.
Okay.
I Dunno why. I Dunno what spawned
it. He just kept going, right?
Say I suck a Dick.
I would suck a Dick Right
now if I could fuck.
And he would name somebody famous.
Who's playing that king?
Would you fuck Kathy
Bates if you could fuck.
I tell you I would suck a dick now I'm
not talking about a hermaphrodite ain't
doing no licky licky sticky,
sticky. Just wouldn't,
I know this sounds funny,
but it wasn't.
It was like old people. A couple rows
up and at one point this girl got up,
this lady gets up to go to
the bathroom and he does this.
Whoa, Whoa, hey, you know,
like this. And all of a sudden I
felt like I was like in the accused,
like he was making her uncomfortable
in like a fucking sexual way.
It was really fucking bad.
So,
okay.
I Dunno, I don't, I don't even
fucking remember. Then file infers.
He keeps going like I'm going to
say something and we keep saying,
I just keep going. Forsee the guy
is a jerk off. Okay, you got a wife,
you've got kids, you got a
house. Okay. When a lose the
fight, you're going to lose.
All right? Just this in our life
for another fucking half hour,
just ignore him and [inaudible]. I
Dunno why, I dunno. Started gate verse.
He finally just said to the guy,
cause he kept butting into
our conversations and I
would just go, hey listen,
I'm talking to my friend, you know, I
don't want to talk to you or whatever.
And then he just goes, hey, you know,
Bass Bass versus bursary basic
just told them to shut up.
Said you being a drunk asshole. Nobody
wants to talk to you. All right,
just shut the fuck up.
And all I'm thinking is I have my sneakers
off and I five to fucking pull these
guys apart.
I got to run in my socks on a bus
that, that verse, he couldn't
have handled. This guy's
guy was just a drunk idiot.
But anyways, uh, and then the
guy turns around and faces front,
like he's been scolded and
he shut up and I'm like,
thank God. And we found out
afterwards, people around us were like,
thank God you said that Shit.
But then I don't know what happened.
Then he just started back up again.
And one of my other friends
started talking to the guy
and then he started going
again, you know, I'd suck a dick. Hey,
would you fuck blah, blah, blah,
blah. He was a fucking moron.
Tell you what I need. I need a
loose horn, some Mexican food.
These are direct quotes
and I'm telling you there's these two,
all this cute old couple,
like two seats in front of them.
It was,
it was an absolute fucking shit show,
and by the time we get off the bus,
it's like, I don't even want to, I
don't even want to go to the fight.
I'm so over people at this point. But
in, and of course we get back late.
We can't find where we, where we were
staying at the Sheraton or whatever.
We finally get back to the Sheridan.
We go up, don't even shower,
just put on some remotely
respectable fucking clothes.
And we run downstairs to catch the shuttle
where we're going to go see the fight
is like 11 miles away in the shuttle
will only go in a five mile radius.
So He'd go, fuck our, I call a cab,
call a cab. The guy calls a cab,
never calls comes, he calls another cab.
It never fucking comes. And at that point,
I'm looking over at the bar, the
hotel bar, and they're serving food.
And I just say, it's four of us. I
say one of the guys that go, look,
I go, I'm done man. I'm just going to get
a case of d and go to bed. Just fuck it.
So version and the other dude, uh,
looking at like, what the fuck? Come on.
We gotta make this happen.
And then the other guy,
I just don't name names in the podcast,
the hall of famous friends. It's like,
yeah, dude, that's what I'm doing.
So we go saddle up to the bar
and it was fucking hilarious.
We're sitting at the bar now we're done.
Our Day's done,
which is going to get something to eat,
maybe get a drink and we're going to
go upstairs and go to fucking sleep.
But if we,
if we look to the right,
we see the TV with the highlights and the
score is, but if you look to the left,
we can see into the lobby and I
see [inaudible] and my other buddy,
and they are still in the anxiety
of trying to get to the fight.
So I say to the dude, I'm
sitting at the bar with, I go,
you know what's funny that over there,
and I was pointing Diversey in the
lobby is going to become way more
entertaining than this shit on the TV.
And about five minutes and sure enough,
four as he starts flipping out,
I swear to God,
he must've said Sheridan
like 58 fucking times.
He just kept calling like,
well, we're at a Sheridan.
How can you not get a cap? And it,
and it shed is a Sheridan. This is,
this is a shower.
I don't understand this.
How do you not get a Cabinet Sheridan?
Right.
And then he walks over to the bar and
he's leaning in between me and the other
dude just go and ask. I
just don't understand where
we're at. A Sheraton right?
He's drunk.
So that's sitting there and they walked
back and forth like 58 times trying to
get the guy at the front desk
to get a cab. That'll show up,
but for some reason they're not showing
up. It's a fine. And then I'm like, Paul,
just just fuck it to wrap. Sit down and
get some food. He goes, no, fuck that.
Fuck that. This is one of the best fights
of the year and I'm going to miss it.
I want to see it live.
I want to see like I just never been at
a shower where you couldn't get a cab.
So now the cab doesn't show up. 20
fucking minutes later, whatever.
We got a couple of drinks in front of us
and my fucking burger shows up with the
French fries. I got a coke.
The other guy's got an,
I don't know whether he had a salad with
some chicken Assam Shit and fuzzy at
this point. He's like, invading my space.
He's literally becoming like that
jerk off on the bus. I'd suck a dick.
Except he's going where to Sharon?
How do you not get a cabinet at Sheridan?
And he's fucking leaning
on the bar and all that.
My food finally comes in before the
plate even hits the fucking bar.
He goes, Hey, can I get
one of those French fries?
And I looked at him and I was so fed up
with people. I looked at him, I said,
you know what? No, no you
can't. And then the lady goes,
the kitchen closes in five minutes. I go,
Paul, just order a cheeseburger. He goes,
no,
I'm going to this fight.
And then he sits down on the other side
of the guy who just looks at me. He goes,
you know what? That was fucked
up. That was fucked. What
you just did there, right?
Because if I buy it some French fries,
you want to have to ask me.
I in mind grabbing like two huge
handfuls. I go here, I'd go here,
take this, take this, and I'm like,
fuzzy. You would lean an I for,
I don't lean over people's food.
How to fucking,
you're not getting a cabinet at Sheridan.
So finally I look at them and I just go,
you guys realize you have a rental car
sitting out there in the parking lot.
I don't know if you're too drunk to drive,
but if you're not drunk enough to
drive the fight as it start enough,
just go jump in the car and drive down
the fucking street. So they go fine.
That's the plan. So the other
guy goes up to look for the keys.
He's up there for like 20 minutes and
I'm polishing off the Burger in Versie is
telling me that he,
you know what a piece of shit friend I am.
And at one point I go,
Paul,
I didn't look you like an athlete who
doesn't know when to end his career.
It's over. We're not going to see the
fight. It's fucking over. You know?
So then he tries to order a fucking
cheeseburger and by then the kitchen's
closed.
Then they find another place that's
within five miles that they can see the
fight. So they run up to the front desk
and they go, Oh, the guy drives a shuttle.
Just went home and fuzzy
is fucking losing his mind.
And uh,
that guy upstairs could not find his keys
to the rental car though it was a shit
show.
It was one of the most,
it was almost as entertaining as the game
watching those two guys trying to get
to the fight. And uh, they
finally find that, oh,
the guy I was sitting with had to
go up and find the fucking keys.
He finds the keys
and then they decide they're going to
jump in the rental car to go watch the
last half of the fight. And they like you
share you to want to go. And I'm like,
dude, I am paying for this and I'm going
to go upstairs and I'm fucking going to
sleep. And uh, and that's
exactly what I do. I go upstairs,
me and the other dude,
we go upstairs and we're just laughing
our asses off and those two fucking guys
jumping a car to go find this fight in
like a Dave and busters or whatever.
So whatever,
they went to some ESPN zone place and
they go there and they don't have the
fight.
So the whole thing was a fucking wash.
I'm laying in bed,
right just about ready to fall asleep.
Just laughing my ass off and just
think what a great game it was.
What a wonderful drive. It wasn't all
that stuff. Right. What a great weekend.
And all of a sudden my phone buzzes and
I get this picture and the underneath
it,
it says pussies and I fucking look at
the picture and it's a picture of Paul
Versey with a Mug of beer. You can't
even see his face. He's sucking it down.
And I laughed and I just texted him back,
don't get arrested cause
I'm gonna have to get out,
basically fucking bail you out.
And then he fell asleep.
I fall and like three hours later.
Okay.
I think I started dreaming
about chainsaws out of nowhere.
And then I fucking wake up
and vs in the bed next to me,
he's in the other twin there and he is
fucking snoring at an Olympic level.
So I'm waiting on forsee frozen anything.
Okay.
Yeah.
Like, like that. And
I'm just like, firstly,
I'm fucking kicking the bed and
he's with ha ha ha. And I'm like,
dude, don't just snoring.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
All right.
And then two seconds later,
like immediately would fall back
to sleep and sound like, I dunno,
like someone was choking
a fucking wart hog. So,
okay,
I'm sitting over there,
I'm making like a pillow sandwich with
my fucking head trying to block them out.
And uh, he swears that he
heard me yell, motherfucker.
I don't remember saying that,
but I kept falling asleep and then
waking back up to this fucking jackass.
I Emilia,
have sympathy for every housewife out
there if your husband snores like that.
Right?
So I fucking,
I went into my bag and I got earplugs
out that I wear on the plane or whatever.
Jan, those things in there. And then, you
know, there's like four pillars to a bed,
had two on one side, two on the
other. And I, you know, it's, in fact,
it was possible to put
myself in a headlock.
I would have to try and block
my ears and uh, I was hilarious.
Woke up the next day when
I woke up in the morning,
he was already gone and get an
early flight. And at that point,
of course we were laughing about
the French fry. He's still pissed.
He's still pissed on some level is
questioning my level of loyalty to him.
Um, and I don't give a shit. All
right? That's the deal. I would never,
if you're listening to this,
Paul,
I would never hover over your fucking
food and I would never ask you for any of
your fucking food before you've had a
chance to get byte number one. Okay?
There's this, there's etiquette. There's
etiquette. You don't show up to picture,
all right? You don't sit on
somebody else's motorcycle.
Y'all play somebody else's drums without
asking them. There's all kinds of stuff.
All right? You don't tell some you
don't. You don't criticize about waste.
So many parents that are on kid.
You don't do that. And for the,
and you don't fucking
take somebody French fry.
You fucking do that before the
plate even hits. How dare you?
How dare you Paul Versey you
weren't raised right. All right.
I fucking stand by that in any way with
a piece of shit out there that defends
him. You know what? Go eat with versa.
You're not welcomed at my table.
All right, here we go. I haven't gotten
to the fucking, let me got into the uh,
the letters for this week. Well,
that's what happens. You go to Texas,
you're going to have the biggest
podcast there. Um, he voice everybody.
If you're an entrepreneur
and a customer calls,
do you want to seem like you're
in a high rise window view,
fancy pants office or do you want them to,
you're sitting in you're
there and your underwear.
Um,
with the voice you can create the
appearance of an entire building. Sales,
customer support, tech support, you name
it. The person on the other end the line,
they're not going to
know what you're doing.
Give your customers the royal treatment
with he voice eve voice will forward
business calls to your home, mobile or
any number you choose. Wherever you are.
Eve Voice, we'll find you don't have
time to make a call. Don't, oh, sorry.
Don't have time to take a call. It's
routed to your voicemail, no worries,
and you can read it at your
convenience as an email.
He voice not only gives you
an edge over your competitors,
it takes away the edge the big
companies have over you right now,
and that is huge, ladies and
gentlemen, and right now you can try.
He voice for free for 30 days.
How do you do it?
Go to [inaudible] dot com or just click
go to the podcast page at [inaudible]
dot com and click on the voice banner.
I hope you'd do it.
Good luck starting your own
business. All right, legal zoom.
A lot of pride comes along with
starting your dream business,
but think about the stress you'll feel
if you don't take the right steps to
legally protect your business and
personal assets from the beginning.
That's why I recommend legal
zoom.com during the past 12 years,
over a million business owners have
trusted legal zoom to help start their
businesses.
Legal Zoom will save you a lot of time
and a pile of money on startup costs.
Plus they'll provide solutions to
help you run a successful business.
Legal Zoom can provide self help services
at your specific specific direction or
connect you with an attorney, but
they are not illegal offer. Uh,
just go to legalzoom.com today to see
what's right for you. Form an LLC,
get a Dba,
incorporate or form a nonprofit
all starting at just $99 a month.
You can't beat that.
Plus you'll save even more when you went
to burn the referral box at checkout.
Please don't forget to do that. That's
legalzoom.com. Promo Code [inaudible] B U,
r. R one more time, legal
zoom.com. Promo Code. [inaudible].
All right, they have it.
So that was it. Those are my, uh, my, uh,
my Texas stories.
This has been the Texas diaries.
Everybody and a is bombed a as,
I can't say,
bumped now knowing that that
means ass rate than England. Um,
as sodomized as I felt
as disappointed as I was that we
didn't get to do the show in El Paso,
the upside is I get to go to that
wonderful part of the country again.
And I think what I'm gonna do this time
is I'm going to do the show and I'm
actually going to do a road trip,
but the other way I might
drive out to a Albuquerque,
New Mexico where they, uh, they shot
the unbelievable show breaking bad.
I got to do a few episodes of that and,
but they also shot one of
my favorite movies of all
time, no country for old men.
And I want to drive around and look at
some of those shooting locations like the
motel with a shoot brought or they killed
Josh Brolin and all of that type of
stuff. Um, I am converted.
I the southwest,
all of that stuff is some of the most
beautiful scenery you can ever see right
up through Colorado, Wyoming, Montana,
all those places they fucking make fun of
man. I'm telling you, they unbelievable.
Um, and my apologies to that
guy. I'm going to try and
get his email from my, uh,
the guy who helps me with my podcast.
I get to try to smooth shit over with
him cause I feel bad about that. Um,
all right, here we go. Let's read some
stuff. All right. Character assassination.
Hello billion.
I'm a freshman in the university over
in England and everything is good in the
world apart from one small annoyance.
I have just gotten in from a night out
on the time I had just got in from a
night on the town and
it's 7:00 AM I experienced
something that I feel I need to
ask you about and I had loved the advice
you give and I love the advice you give,
so feel and so feel you're the
best person to ask. All right,
granted you're hammered. You're writing
this at seven in the morning. Okay. Um,
I've been at the university for five days
and everyone is getting on really well.
I have been the guy that cracks the jokes
and make sure everyone is included and
make sure everyone comes
out to drink every night.
This evening I'm a new guy,
moved into my flat and immediately
the group dynamic changed.
He seemed to be very sure of himself
and it felt as though he believed he was
better than us.
He constantly made remarks about the lack
of girls in the group and at a general
air of complacency. Uh,
to put a long story short,
he tried to humiliate
me in front of everyone.
He made me feel little by making
a big deal out of a remark.
I made sarcastically. I said that I
had a cousin who is quite attractive.
I was clearly joking, but he made it his
mission to say it was incest you with.
And because I'm from Wales,
he suggested that I have sexual
intercourse with sheep. Oh,
you guys are the ones who get that out
there. I'm a well known Welsh stereotype,
but is potentially true. He wrote
with a Little Smiley wink face. Um,
I sensed that the entire room knew I
was joking and found it strange that he
made such a big deal out of it.
But due to is highly confident,
almost cocky personality. They were
scared to argue with with, well,
you got to nip that in the
butt. Yeah, you got it.
You got to step to that guy immediately
be like, dude, it's just a joke.
Why do you keep talking about it?
Do you secretly want to fuck his sheep?
So you're trying to put it on me cause
you dick gets a little hard as you
talking about it. You fucking
Weirdo. Just so you've got it.
You got to come at that guy.
You know,
you don't have to do like dough.
You shade it again.
I'll fucking Yaki teeth down your fucking
throat. You don't have to go there yet.
You don't have to. All right.
Anyways, let's, let's, let's,
let's move on here. Uh,
they sense the entire room,
but Blahblahblahblahblah I
explained myself for several
minutes and he continued
to make a big deal out of nothing and
I feel most of the room agreed with me.
Yeah. You, you were giving
them like to a guy like that,
that's a sign of weakness. A few to
keep explaining where he goes. Nah,
I take you want to fuck a sheet? No,
no. It was a Joe. No, I was just,
I thought I died it at, I said, you are
right. Spider. He become a spider here.
You can't do that.
Um,
I felt like the best course of action was
to punch him as hard as I could in the
face. Ah, all right. I
like that. Good move.
I resisted the urge to punch him and have
removed myself from the situation and
as I have a feeling that the best way to
deal with shitty peoples to avoid them
while depends on wolf.
Avoiding him means not hanging out
with the friends that you're making.
You have to address it now.
You don't need to punch him in the face.
So I'm just joking.
Uh,
the problem was that most of the room
came with me as they felt I was in the
right, thus isolating him
on his first night. This is
not what I wanted to happen,
dude. You got to stop being a people
pleaser. He's been a continent.
Needs to sit there and think about it.
Um,
he said this is not what I want it to
happen as the first night in universities,
the hardest.
And I didn't want to be the cause of
his lonesomeness even though it was
somewhat self inflicted, somewhat in
self-inflating was totally self inflicted.
Sir He go, this made him dislike me more
and as we left to go out drinking in the
nightclubs, he came up to me and locked
me in the eyes and said, I hate you. Yeah,
this guy is just an insecure can't
he goes,
I did not handle it as I was not set out
to make enemies and he seemed to want
to hate me.
Yup.
I just say, all right, well
cool. All right, well we
got, we got that over quick.
Enjoy your time at the university.
We don't have to be friends.
Have a nice evening. Yeah. He goes,
I feel like I've tried to be nice,
but he has beef with me. Don't be nice
to this guy. Fuck this guy. He goes,
my question for you is,
would you have left the room when the
guy tried to humiliate you or would
punching him be the best option?
All right.
At this age I wouldn't have left the room
and I would have given him shit and I
wouldn't have punched him in the face.
At your age.
I probably would have let them
roll all over me, bully me,
and then would have for some reason become
friends with them and let them treat
me like shit for the next
five years in my fucking life.
That's what I would've
done at your edge. So, um,
pet space at work,
you shouldn't avoid this guy.
He shouldn't take any shift from this guy.
This guy has got a lot of issues.
He probably has a bad father or home
situation and he's basically in the
beginnings of going out into the world
and taking out his childhood and other
people. So the only way he can do that
to you is if you allow him to, uh,
you don't need to be friends
with someone like that.
But what you do need to do is
you need to draw a line in.
That guy has to respect the fact that
he can't get out of line with you.
All right? So if it comes up
and says, I hate you, just
be like, hey, you know, well,
you know, it's not going to do about that.
Have a nice evening. And he said, yeah,
I really fucking hate you. And just be
like, listen, dude, do you have a problem?
Is there something, you know,
if you're going to do something,
do what the fuck you feel you need to do
or get the fuck out of my face and just
leave it at that because he's not going
to throw a punch and it comes up and
says, I hate you. It sounds
like a fucking seventh grader.
And it sounds like you have it in you
to punch somebody in the face. Uh,
so you know, and if, and if you already
know that about yourself, you don't
have to prove it again. So don't, don't
go with violence, man. That's just,
that's stupid advice just when it comes
up and says, hey, you just be like, yeah,
all right. It's not an I could
do about it. It's unfortunate.
I wish it wouldn't happen,
you know? I mean, I don't,
I don't know what he
wants out of you, but, uh,
the biggest thing that
I've gotten from this,
cause I can't tell you what to do because
I'd have to know a lot more about the
situation as to how to handle that guy.
But the biggest thing I got out of this
is your need to try and make things
better and be a people pleaser with
someone who doesn't deserve that.
You sound like a really nice guy.
All right?
And you know what happens to nice guys?
They attract assholes because
people who don't tolerate assholes,
they can't get in there.
So some of the biggest countries in the
world hang out with some of the nicest
fucking people in the world who don't
know how to stick up for themselves in
certain situations.
So this is what I've told a couple people
in my life may make somebody earned.
How nice a person you are.
Don't just be giving it away and
just being nice to everybody. Uh,
this guy hasn't earned it, so fuck
him. All right. Fuck that guy.
Don't take any shit from him. And,
uh, but don't, don't let them,
don't allow that guy to make you mad.
Yeah.
And then you throw a punch and
then you've got issues at school.
Cause this guy's a cunt. He had
a bad dad. Fuck that. Fuck that.
If it comes up and says he hates you
again, just be like, dude, I got it.
You already said that.
I understand you don't like me.
So get out of my face and
get on with not liking me.
All right. If you really didn't like
me, you wouldn't be coming up to me.
So why don't you prove to me how much
you don't like to me. Don't listen.
When I say everything I say will,
it always escalates into a fucking
rolling around on the floor kind of thing.
I hope something in there
helped you. Um, all right,
Hiroshima and documentary to checkout.
Dear Billy von Reddington
bill, I ain't, I'm American
good living in Hiroshima teaching English.
It's a great gig where I get to meet a
lot of the locals and teach them how to
pronounce things the way we do.
My Dad was in the army,
so I grew up learning a
lot about American history,
especially military history since
it was such a big part of our lives.
Being in a military family
and all, I'm a huge fan, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
He writes and I am happy to hear that
you are getting into world war history in
a big way.
Uh,
the last few weeks in the man podcasts
have almost been weird as you are
discovering a lot of the same things
I did about our past and about how the
modern world came to be when I was a kid.
World War II aviation,
especially in this Pacific had a profound
effect on me and the book fly boys was
the first time I ever read about,
uh,
about shit going down in the Philippines
and how we got all these oversee
territories in Puerto Rico
and Guam and all of that.
Before that I was just bought into
believing that we were the good guys and
everyone else was to blame for
everything wrong in the world. Also,
I have to agree with the last person who
wrote in that the Dan Carlin podcast,
ghost of the oss front. I got to listen to
that. Asked front, O, s, t, F, R, O, n, t,
everybody, Carlin spelt the same
as George Carlin, c a. R. L. I, N,
ghosts of the OSS to front
O. S. T. F. R. O. N. T.
All one word from the hardcore
history was life changing.
The fucking Russians lost between 20
and 40 million people and many of those
were civilians. We lost a half
million in the whole war. Uh,
there is a saying that World War II was
one with Berlin, British intelligence,
American steel and
Russian blood. Wow, man.
Jesus Christ. That's a sacrifice and a
half, huh? Understatement of the year.
I got to listen to that.
This could not be more true,
you saying about that expression after
the war when we went to rebuilding
western Europe and the Russians basically
occupied everything to make sure this
shit never happened again.
MMM.
Oh, me read that sentence in
a better way. After the war,
we went to rebuilding western Europe
and the Russians basically occupied
everything to make sure that this
should never happen again. All right,
now the cold,
now the Cold War from the Russian side
makes total sense to me and I think it
will to UFT listened to
the podcast and also,
I know you mentioned that you hate
ancient shit before cowboys and Indians,
but you have to check out the podcast
also from Dan Carlin called death throes
of the Roman republic.
I'll do it. I'll listen.
If someone's going to tell me about it,
I can listen to anything
but to sit down and read it.
My brain doesn't work like that. It just
goes, why don't we go get a beer man?
Why are we reading all this
heavy stuff? Man. Ancient Rome,
you see used to be a democracy before the
Roman empire and it faced a lot of the
same problems. Jesus Christ rail. We
actually learning things here. My God.
All right, stay with me people. I
got a little more to read here. Um,
ancient Rome used to be a democracy
before it became a Roman empire,
and it faces a lot of the same problems
we face today before it ultimately
became an empire rather than a democracy.
Oh Jesus, that sounds familiar.
You see, there were two groups in
ancient Rome that basically ran shit.
The public caneys.
I hope I said that right.
Who were rich and conservative.
And the popularity is the populist who
sought power through gaining the support
of the poor. Oh my God. So basically
this is their Fox News and CNN,
and ultimately it was this struggle that
led to the imperial Rome. Check it out.
Uh, last one here. You need
to check out fog of war.
It's a documentary free on youtube
that won the Oscar back in 2004.
I think it's about
Robert S. Dot. Mcnamara,
who was most famous for being secretary
of defense during the Cuban missile
crisis in Vietnam. Before all that, he
was a statistician and World War II.
He was one of the guys who crunched
the numbers to see how much destruction
could be caused by daylight
bombing in Germany.
And later in Japan and this documentary,
he points out that by fire
pump firebombing Japan,
we killed more civilians in Tokyo in
one night than we did in the bombing of
Hiroshima.
And that's also amazing when you read
the that fly boys book is you just
realized that
okay.
You know, cause I always learned
that we were trying to our dominance,
that's why we ended up dropping
the bombs that we didn't need to.
But like when you see how their people
were taught that we were devils had
tails, had green blood and we
were going to eat them if we won.
And when we approached the civilians
they would throw their babies off cliffs
and jump off to that.
I mean we were going to have to
lose way more people. I don't know.
There's an argument for
both sides. It's, it's nuts.
It's crazy and it's nuts that there's
actually rules and war and that it's
somehow legal. Um, anyways,
the bomb looms still to this day and
the town of Hiroshima and there is an
overwhelming belief that it should not
have been used no matter what. Yeah,
of course. Absolutely. You think
that they would think that, you know,
and over here we were like,
well, you know, you're going
to lose a lot of guys. Um,
but here they seem to to miss
a few things. First of all,
a land invasion would have resulted in
a million more Japanese dead since they
would not surrender and were told that
the Americans would eat them and their
families. Yeah, we read
the same book. Second,
if we had blockaded the island rather
than invade or drop the, the a bond,
millions would have starved to death.
Last of all,
and most often overlooked is if
the allies had invaded Japan,
then Russia would have invaded too.
And just like in Europe,
we would've given a large part
of Japan to Russia to rule over.
So northern Japan could have been like
North Korea if we had dropped the bombs.
I'm not a hippie and I'm not writing from
some idea that America is evil and our
enemies did nothing wrong.
But it is amazing to see how much was
going on from all sides, good in bed.
And it gives a richer,
fuller version of what actually was
going on all of the world at the time.
Exactly. That's why I loved reading that
book. I like, you know, that's why got,
I like listening to people
trash the Patriots. How,
what is your viewpoint of this?
How do you look at it? You know,
you got to listen to some of that.
Right. Anyways, love the podcast.
Come to Hiroshima to the bomb museums
sometimes for a pretty sobering history.
Keep Up. Oh, I'll definitely
do that someday. Keep it up.
And most of all go fuck yourself.
All right.
It's probably the most intelligent
thing has ever been uttered. Of course,
it was written by somebody else.
All right.
I'm plowing through all of this
people. We got a couple more to go. Um,
Henry Kissinger, dear
Billy Westwinds, uh, oh,
Billy West, the great a voiceover guy. One
of the voices of Ren and Stimpy. I mean,
he might have done
both, right. Steepy ETF.
You don't deserve to live. I'm
sorry. Terrible impression. Um,
do you know how Evil Kissinger
is? The man is a war criminal. Uh,
he carpet bombed Cambodia, oversaw the
coup in Chile that practically destroyed,
destroyed their great nation,
jacked off to the dropping of agent
orange all over Vietnam. Okay.
This is very slanderous,
sir. He's pure evil.
He's a Zionist who believes
in ethnic cleansing,
cleansing and has gone on record promoting
policy that promote d population,
not the, hey everyone.
Hey, everyone's cool.
What not the hey everyone cool it on
the fucking deep population. More like,
let's get guys to fight those guys.
Both sides will have
civilians die and go hungry.
I think you've left out some
words in that. Um, he goes,
I'm Jewish. I love juice.
The good ones. I love all
people no matter their religion.
I've been to Israel and believe it
is a beautiful and moving place,
but the state of Israel is pure
evil, not the people, the government.
My father worked for a company that did
business with the Israeli government.
That's all I can say about his business,
but I can say that he was
privy to some insane things.
The types of things that
make you lose sleep.
The main objective in almost all policy
he saw was to create money and wealth
for a few families,
for the few families that run Israel.
True Judaism and love for the religion
is almost obsolete when you get high
enough in power.
Yeah,
that's kind of true everywhere kind
of all goes out the window. Um,
when she gets to that
eyes wide shut level, uh,
they heads of the state used Judaism as
a way of silencing anyone who questions
their actions where we
use support the troops,
call someone to antisemites and see
how quickly they shut up a college.
You and anti Zionist and it's
the same thing. They shut
up. US Jews have suffered,
but so have lots of people who can't
be quantified into that group. Anyways.
Fuck Kissinger. All right, well I guess
I have some reading up on to do on that.
Uh, that's one man's opinion,
but I mean it just, it doesn't,
it all just what you start reading about
it all just seems to be the same story
over and over again because we really
are all the same. And I think that like,
you know,
once you go beyond a certain level power,
I think there's maybe a handful of people
in the world that can handle it and
the rest of us start to feel
like we're godlike. And uh,
we start summoning people to
come in and give us blow jobs
and drinking wine out
of some JAKKS bladder,
whatever the file over the fuck they did
that. That's disgusting. Um, all right,
last but not least,
I probably shouldn't fucker.
Uh, hey there could QB,
the freckle faced kid. Hey,
how cool was it last week where
they gave my character a first name?
I don't want to ruin anything,
but I was sitting there on
pins and needles watching
that stuff. And by the way,
if you're up to date, I'm not going to
ruin anything on breaking bad, but, uh,
I'm asking this people outside the
United States because I don't know of any
United States show that has ever
been better than breaking bad. Um,
my stomach has been an absolute Nazi
watching the show and each week it just
keeps getting ratcheted higher and higher.
Like last night's episode was like one
of the most disturbing things I've ever
seen. And if you live in another
country, okay. And you know,
have a show. If you've watched
all of breaking bad and you know,
have a show that you think is
on par or dare I say better,
I want to know what it is and I
don't care if there's no subtitles,
I will sit down and just
view it because what they've done with
the second half of this fifth season,
I've,
I've never seen anything like it in my
40 years of sitting in front of the idiot
box. I could actually say
it's not an idiot box anymore.
When this something like that on TV,
it's just unbelievable.
And if you're late to the party,
by all means,
when all five seasons come out,
you,
you owe it to yourself to download them
by him and don't blow through them.
Okay. It's a fine wine.
Open a bottle at night,
sit there with your
friends and discuss it. Um,
it's incredible.
I mean,
a lot of the stuff that we're talking
about as far as people handling power,
you know, it's, it's unreal. It's
unfucking believable. Anyways, last one.
Here we go. I want a lot of people
have asked me about the Saul, uh,
you know, Saul Goodman spinoff. Um,
I know as much as you guys know,
I just heard it. I heard it. It's
not, it's going to be a prequel.
So if it's a Prequel,
I would feel that that's years before,
I dunno if he gets to Albuquerque and
people have been asking if I'm going to be
on it. I have no idea. I
hope so. I have no idea.
But whether I am or whether I'm not,
I'm watching every episode.
Um, anyway, it was a prequel.
Shouldn't I come in at
like the very last one?
And then we all moved to Albuquerque.
See that right there.
That's why I don't write
ups. Terrible idea. Sorry.
Anyways, I probably shouldn't.
Fucker is the last one here. Hey,
there could be the freckle face. I need
some help. So there's this crazy broad,
it might job who's I'm,
who I'm 99% sure I could
fuck if I asked directly.
Uh,
now I feel free to,
now I feel free to think this because
she isn't exactly top shelf trim,
but she certainly worth trying
a shot if it's free. Um,
I got to tell you, do this. That's one
of the biggest lies in the universe.
It's never free.
There's never been a free,
there's never been a free
piece ever did the history.
It all comes with a
price all and all does.
Especially when you're trying to bank
somebody you're working with right there.
You're shitting where you're eating and
you take that could go very bad very
quickly. Uh, he goes,
I've worked with her for about two years
and for awhile she was putting on what
seemed to be a pretty strong press,
excessive hanging out at my desk,
finding random ways to mess with me,
laughing at anything I do, you
know, office flirty, bullshit. Well,
maybe she likes you.
She might actually like you see,
this is the way guy looks at.
She was the suck my Dick, right?
So she's going to be sitting
there thinking you're
making love and you're like,
ah, good cum in your mouth. Right. And
then you treat her like I'm telling you,
that's how shit starts.
So anyways,
then I launched a
passive attempt to smash,
told her we should get drinks.
Oh no dude.
Just the way you talk about women in the,
which is hilarious coming from me,
but the way and totally hypocritical,
the way you talk about women like this,
this is not going to end well.
I told her we should get drinks.
We went out to catch a movie after work
but didn't make a major move because of
fear of her having a story to tell the
office about rejecting me. Very smart.
Nothing happened and
things cooled way off.
Uh,
long story short,
since then she's exhibited
advanced signs of female dementia.
Well, before I go any further, I'm
going to guess that because you,
you didn't make a move.
She thought that, oh,
he went out to see what kind of a person
I am and was expecting maybe a follow
up date and when it didn't happen, that's
sending her the signal that you didn't,
you didn't like something about her.
So maybe now that's why she's distant.
I don't know.
He said the worst one being an incident
where she invited me to hang out with
her and I taught her how to rip a bond.
Yeah,
it's all right.
This one is a wholly different direction.
Totally different direction.
She got unreasonably high and wound
up locking herself in the bathroom,
calling her mom.
Just say how she invited me over God
high and was worried I was going to take
advantage of her. Her mom was about to
call the cops, but she did stop her.
For what it's worth,
I'm six five 200 pound black guy
and she's a small Asian girl.
So I really saw Ben into that
storyline. Oh Jesus Christ. Absolutely.
So we are now back to normal with her
being a 200 proof bottle of crazy and me
wondering if the crazy too good pussy
positive correlation holds true.
That's fucking hilarious.
If I figure she can't get any crazier in,
if I just ask directly,
we can eliminate the chance of
confusion and calls to the police.
Am I totally insane for still
wanting to fuck this girl?
Thanks and go fuck yourself
bitch. Um, all right.
I hope there's women listening to this
cause right now because you
don't have a dick. You probably,
and this is why you think guys are so
dumb and I want you the same way this guy
was talking about World War
II from the other perspective.
You got to look at having a Dick from the
other perspective with, I swear to God,
empathy and I'm going to pause
while you roll your eyes ladies.
But this is how powerful
having a Dick is.
This is how much it runs your life.
Like the amount of shit.
Yeah,
that just got shot across the
bow of this guy's Dick. Okay.
And he's still thinking like,
I think I can make it.
What if I just said, hey, you
want to fuck and we just fucked.
I could somehow get this urge out of me
and then I could then go back to work.
You know what's funny,
sir,
is the fact that if you fuck this girl
and if it is as good as you think it's
going to be like you're
going to be able to go back,
you know to work and where
you're never going to bang again.
You already know that this girl
is fucking nuts. All right?
I'm removed from the situation.
I haven't seen her so I don't
have any desire for you.
I could tell you 100 fucking
percent do not repeat.
Do not. Fuck this girl.
Stand down, sir. Abort.
What other of the other military
rub one out before you go to work.
Okay,
go out.
You know what?
Go out and find some other crazy fucking
woman that you don't have to see at
work.
Okay,
that's it.
That's it. All right. Do not do it. Yay.
You're not totally insane for fucking
this woman. If he didn't have a Dick,
you would be,
but you do have a dick.
So I understand cause God knows I've
made neverending mistakes with my Dick.
Trust me. All right. And by the
time you figure out your Dick,
women don't want to fuck anymore anyways,
so it's pointless.
So I'm trying to fucking fast
40th to where the hell I'm at.
Hour and 30 minute podcasts. It might be
one of the longest ones ever. All right,
that's the podcast this
week. Everybody. Um,
before I do the little wrap up here,
I want to just let you guys know
where I'm going to be this week. Uh,
hang on a second. Hang on,
hang on. Hang on, Bill.
Ah, you can't, I can't even type
with two hands. Forget about one,
one finger. Uh, all right. Official
website. Being a beggar. Barnwell.
I know I'm going to be able to
be in West Virginia, Pittsburgh,
and Toronto this weekend.
Uh, this week I should say.
So let's see if I can get the
uh, all right. On September 18th,
the fuck Outta here.
I got to fly out to him Wednesday.
No,
at Jesus Christ. I really have.
No, I have no fucking life.
All right.
Evidently on September 18th I'm going
to be a Keith Alby theater provided
there's no rain.
Whatever the fuck could happen,
what could happen provided nobody's
still blows up near the fucking venue and
lights it on fire. I'll be at the Keith
Alby theater on the 18th. On the 19th.
I'm doing west. Spread your near West
Virginia University in Morgantown,
West Virginia.
On the 20th,
I'm doing Hines hall for the
Performing Arts in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania,
Heinz Hall.
And then on the 21st I'm doing Queen
Elizabeth Theater, Toronto, Ontario.
Uh, that is it. In the
following week, September 28th,
I'm doing the Chicago theater for
two shows. First one is sold out.
The second one is almost
there for the love of God.
Get your ass down to the show. All
right. And with that, let's do the,
let's do the old wrap up here, the
old wrap up. Where the hell is it? Uh,
now that the show is over,
don't forget to sign up for your free
trial of Hulu Plus Hulu plus let you binge
on thousands of hit shows
anytime, anywhere on your TV,
PC, smartphone, or tablet.
Support this podcast and get an extended
free trial on Hulu plus when you go to
the podcast page at [inaudible] Dot Com
and click the Hulu plus Ben Banner or go
to Hulu plus.com/bill that's
Hulu plus.com/built. That's
the podcast this week.
Thank you everybody for listening.
I apologize.
Everybody in El Paso was an act of God.
There was nothing I could do about it.
I'm definitely coming back.
We're going to get that
makeup date as soon as we can.
I don't give a shit if I have to come
there 50 times. I'm doing a show there.
All right. That's the podcast. Go fuck
yourselves. We'll talk to you next week.