Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
July 23rd, 2012 here's my
little sesame street moment. Ah,
today's show is brought to you by audible.
Please visit audible podcast.com/bill
for your free audio book download.
You liked that?
Wasn't that just like sesame street?
Today's show is brought to you by the
letter l and the number five and they'd be
playing that harmonica. Remember that?
The outro music. How the fuck did,
I used to know how that
went. Bat Bat, bat that.
That's mash. I don't fucking know. Um,
well you should probably ask yourself
at this point, what is audible.com?
It's basically, it's for people who liked
to read books but don't like to read.
You know, you have, it gets sticky
or I going from left to right,
left to right or your eyes. If you're
not wearing a patch, you know, people,
do you want to read a book but
like don't want to read it.
I'm going to be nice if it,
you know,
if you had someone who could just
read it for you, go to audible,
podcast.com/bill and you
could die any book you want.
I'm a big urban Welsh fan. The acid
house. I liked that one. You know,
you could read that one if
you wanted or not really.
And then you go to a party
and say you read it. You know,
it's kind of like fake credentials
except in like a book sense.
Audible podcast.com/bill for
your free audio book download.
C'Mon.
When you drive into work,
just have him read all the classics to
you and then you'll actually seem like
you're well read and you're not.
It's perfect.
You don't need to read a map anymore.
He does have that broad in your car
going may go left and seven seconds.
Right now you can just have
some guy reading the book.
Once upon a time in a galaxy far,
far away. They live these people.
You fucking nerd. Um, all right,
this is the Monday morning podcasts for
you people. This is was a brutal, brutal,
brutal. Not Funny, fucking
weak in the world, you know,
as opposed to what Phil, all the happy
go lucky w you know, weeks in the world.
You know what I'm talking about?
Very tragic, tragic fucking week.
And today I woke,
I woke up to more tragedy or the
ending of a tragedy via Paul Versey,
Vir, z. I few people trying to find
them on Twitter. Versie v, I, R. Z.
I don't, I call it what I say. Um,
he called me up and he texted me, he goes,
dude, you wash and you watching this,
they're cleaning house
epic cleaning house.
And I thought he was talking about
the red sox. You know what I mean?
Which by the way,
I'm in Boston right now and
I don't understand why the
fuck everybody's so down
on the red sox. If 48 and 48 they 583
and a half games out of second place.
Who gives a fuck? You know,
the ebb and flow of life.
They want to world series. Now they're
going through a low point, you know,
why are you acting like in your own life?
You make the playoffs every,
you hold up the championship, you know,
and they asked you, you know, hey,
what's it a, you know, what's
it like to be a championship?
What do you got to say about finally
winning the championship and then you go,
it's about that time.
Yeah.
That might've been the worst.
Just winning a championship quote ever.
Lebron James J was broad King James,
you follow the,
I had to bow diab die. Well, why
didn't you just go, you know,
I just want to thank my teammates and the
feds are being supportive of, you know,
it's just, it's an unbelievable I
words you can't put it into words.
It's something like that. So
it's about that died, you know,
I dunno.
His stupid fucking agent's probably
going to try to trademark that and just
start having him say that. And
every stupid commercial, you know,
advertising toasters, toast
pops up. It's about Dab, Dab,
cut Lebron. You know, when you're
saying it's about damn time,
it seems like you're saying that the
toaster takes too long to toast the bread,
you know? Okay. No, I'm not saying
that he has it. I wasn't aware,
I couldn't talk to him. I'm sorry. Who and
who are you? White guy in a suit. Okay.
All right. Okay. Well we'll
fix it in the Edney. Oh, Gigi.
She um, yeah, it was just a
brutal fucking brutal fucking day.
Brutal fucking week.
Not a lot of funny shit.
Where the fuck is my phone buzzing
right now? Hang on a second.
Fuck that phone.
Fuck that phone in his ass. You
know what? Speaking of just brutal,
you know I had one of the worst
nightmares I've had in forever last night.
All right.
I'm laying in a hotel room here and
right now you should be asking yourself,
bill,
it's Monday.
You usually home or you're flying
back from some God forsaken place.
Why are you on the road? Why are you
in Boston? You want vacation? Do it.
What are you doing?
You taking a booze cruise?
MMM.
I am a actually buy books, some
acting work to be honest with you. Um,
I'm shooting a pilot out here.
They are redoing the kid shows zoom from
back in the day they're going to do a
reboot. And, uh, I
booked the Gig. You know,
I'd like to think it was
because of my acting ability,
but I think it was because I remembered
the jingle from way back in the day.
Right? Zoom z double o m box
three five Oh Boston mass.
Oh two one three four.
Set it to zoom.
And I pointed right at the cast director,
right casting director.
She had a zoom on zoom. I took it
out, right? Like a fucking gun.
And they were just like, wow, this kid's
got the fire. We've got to hire him.
Get him in a striped shirt. Anybody
used to watch that? So zoom,
I think it was a very like local Boston
show where it was just these burnout
fucking kids.
Okay.
You ever seen a kid like five years old
and he already looks like he's got a
coke problem.
That's what like zoom was
and they're doing a reboot.
They're rebooting it up. You know,
I had an idea to do a
prequel to my, my, my,
I have three standup specials. I've got
one more coming out in October. Right.
So I got a three, you know,
so that would be my star wars,
empire strikes back and
fucking return of the Jedi.
So now I should do like a prequel.
Okay, I should fucking grow my hair out.
What's left of it and get like a fucking
red wig to put on top of like a Gabe
Kaplan Afro and just go out there
and do like topical humor from like,
I don't know, 1982,
you know, go out there.
Well doing some bad Ronald Reagan
impression and I figured, you know what,
that'd be funny for about 20 seconds.
Then what do you do for the other
fucking 59 minutes, 40 seconds.
And then there it goes that day. You
know what? I should just do a trailer,
a prequel. Ah, Jesus, who
gives a fuck. Um, anyways,
anyway,
uh, it's just, just been a brutal week.
So I turned on the TV to see
what verse he's talking about,
what he was talking about.
And it's um,
no, wait, let me get back to the red sox
here before I get into that shit. Ah,
I'm all right with the red sox sucking.
I actually liked them more now
that they're not doing well.
You know, I know this is, this is when,
this is, when you see who the real fans
are and who aren't it people won't do it.
You Know Those Guys Bandwagon Bandwagon.
You bought your first hat after game
seven of 2004 I'll maybe game five,
you know, if fucking break with your
green monster tickets. You can't
sit down in the bleachers like the rest
of us. No, it's fucking awful blue seats
right by. You should go to games,
right? There'd be nobody fucking there.
Just baseball fans before ESPN ruined
it and just so inundated the phone.
Maybe it's, we just like out fucked
our stadiums. I don't know what it is.
There's so many goddamn people now.
I remember back in the day,
you'd go to a game,
you know,
just having a good fucking time and
they'd always be some guy and he'd have,
there'd be an empty seat on either side
of him. And that's how we get that,
you know, you know, let's
go shocks then going,
he would just slam both chairs down.
You know, the cause it fold up shares,
right? That Jesus built. Can
you paint a better picture here?
If you lose an us and he'd be slamming
both of them down and everybody be
hammered and you know,
there'd be maybe five people there who
had like some sort of like Red Sox,
Actual Jersey on. Other
than that, you had a hat.
You just fucking,
Jesus it counting down some out there.
I'm near the water near the water.
Fucking coast Gad.
Um,
yeah, like you, you, you'd have
a red sox hat. That was it.
And he had the piece of
shit, one the one size, all,
you didn't have like the same one
that Clemens was wearing and you know,
and now you go to the God damn games.
It's like people did their fucking
wearing the whole damn thing.
Everybody's walking around, they look like
managers. You don't like bull pit lake.
There's like, they should
be in the bullpen. So I like
it. I liked that they suck.
I liked that. The trailing off. I
like that. I'm starting to see, uh,
some empty seats. It's
bringing me back. You know,
if they could just stop singing that
fucking song during the seventh inning
stretch and if they could just get
rid of that stupid fucking mascot.
All right. I understand. While you're
doing it for a marketing reason,
I totally get that to try to get kids
hooked into the gate. Why don't you,
you know, you know, I got into the game,
I went to the game and I enjoyed
fucking watching the game. That's it.
I went there and I was sold
the second I walked in there.
I didn't need some big fucking muppet
coming up to me in some creepy way. And,
but it's like, you know, you cut its
tongue out so it can't talk to me.
I fucking hate that about mascots.
I hate how they won't talk to you.
What do you go? Hey, what's up man? And
then they do that real fucking hyper nod.
It's like, I know there's
a guy in there. You idiot.
There's no fucking kids around. You
can't give me, hey man, what's going on?
It's fucking hot as fuck in here. All
right ma'am. Oh, here comes from kids.
I've got to shut up. You
know, can't do that. I mean,
how much are they really paying
you a game? All right. So anyways,
Versie was talking about a,
he was talking about Penn state, like
all those sanctions against Penn state.
Dude, it's fucking
brutal. Like I, I don't,
I don't think that the
punishment is in the right area.
I don't get it.
Why are you punishing
the players in the fans?
You're acting like they look the why
did the winds don't count from 2000 from
1998 to 2011 why don't those games count?
He won those fucking games.
You know what I mean?
That would be like if,
if fucking, I don't know
if Mark Sanchez gets arrested for
drinking and driving, right? Does his,
you know,
if they beat the dolphins the week before,
does it not count what the fuck is
drinking and drive and have to do with
whether, you know, you beat the dolphins
or not? I don't, I don't get that. Like,
so now all these players that played for
Penn state who now sit around probably
get together every couple
of years for union. Amen.
At that time we played Clemson,
you know,
sitting there with a cigar and scarred
up knees and they want to tell a war
story. Oh yeah. That
doesn't count anymore. Why?
Because somebody fuck the
kid. I didn't, you didn't,
nobody played the game.
Did nobody did. Yeah.
Can I at it happened during the game and
they played the game around the crime.
I mean, it's a fucking
horrible crime, but I,
I think what they're trying
to do is just a race,
Joe fraternals name off
of any all time a list.
They don't want his name up there.
You know what I mean? And, um,
I dunno, I just don't
think it's, it's, uh,
I don't think that that's right.
I think that those victories should count.
Yeah,
he fucking won those games.
That doesn't make any sense of what
the fuck is going out there on outside.
You know what,
I'll write out the winter,
they've got a couple of coast guard and
thinks and has probably some fucking
idiots went out on a god
damn dinghy every year.
Some stupid fucking kids do that.
Right.
And they had the stupid a memorial
little Stevie sure. Rip By and
uh, Mike, uh, mark and which,
you know, they was going to do that
shit and just have some sort of like a,
whenever there's a tragedy you got to
have some sort of like metaphor, you know,
water is, uh, it's the liquid of life.
It, where did a Stevie, she rep Mike
Berkowitz went out of their diggy. Uh,
they realized that that uh,
life nectar could also be a,
I really talked myself in a corner here,
have an I how they fucking drought and uh,
we found the raft
that would be the worst doing that.
Um, I don't know dude. It's
just been a brutal fucking week.
I feel bad for Penn state players.
I feel bad for their fans cause I feel
like they getting punished too and they
didn't do a fucking thing.
Okay.
It's a great fucking football
program and it's fucking,
I can't even wrap my head around that.
Joe Paterno was involved in that.
I mean this is the biggest sports mind
fucks since Oj Simpson, you gotta stand.
Oj To me was,
you know,
was the juice 2000 yards
in a 14 game season.
Um, those hertz rental car
commercials, Monday night football,
I even watched this bad movies like when
he played that astronaut and it didn't
make it to the moon and then
they tried to kill him, you know,
and the two white astronauts coast,
they killed Oj cause that's
how it always worked back then.
If you watched any def jam comedy,
they'll let you know the black I always
died and those movies right through the
naked gun and then out of nowhere he's
on trial for a fucking double murder and
he's got to look on his face like, yes, I
did this shit. How do I get out of this?
Um, this is the biggest, I think,
mindful as far as like who you thought
somebody was and then what the fuck they
were involved in. It's just brutal
and there's nothing funny about it.
So let's move on.
Let's move on.
Um, all right, let's
continue with this sports.
Okay.
Uh, as of right now, Dwight
Howard isn't a Laker,
but if Dwight Howard goes to the Lakers,
you know,
in Colby wins his sixth championship,
I am not going to engage in that argument
that he's now equaled Michael Jordan.
Anybody who comes up to me, I am,
as you say, comes out of your mouth.
I'm going to kick you right in the balls.
All right.
Look, you know, this is the
steroid era in baseball.
There has to be the pylon era. You
got to put that in there. Okay.
Michael Jordan won six championships with
Bill Cartwright and Luc Longley as his
fucking centers.
How long do you think Colby Bryant
would tolerate that before he demanded a
trade. Okay. This guy
won three championships,
was Shaquille.
He got Shaquille O'Neal and Phil Jackson.
He got them brought to his team
and I know what you think of. Well,
Michael Jordan had Phil Jackson.
Phil Jackson was nobody.
He became a legend coach
and Michael Jordan. Okay.
And I'm not taking anything away from
this guy, but when the Bulls got him,
it wasn't like, oh, they got Phil Jackson.
This guy knows how to win. He was nobody.
He was an ex nick who want it
and 73 as a player. That was it.
He came in with is, hey man,
fucking Afro and mustache.
That was it. Okay. And
Chicago was rebuilding. Oh,
they had Scottie Pippin. He came
from this system. All right.
They signed Dennis Rodman.
One fucking guy.
Okay.
They won with fucking Bill Cartwright,
Luke Longly,
Bj Armstrong,
that Mormon with the blonde hair.
Okay.
Before Jordan came along,
it was considered impossible to win
without a fucking big name center.
You had to get a big name
center. You had to, okay,
the guy totally changed the fucking game.
And I'm so sick of these
fucking bean counters who go,
well, he has six gib chips,
ed, he has five. Therefore, if he gets one
world championship, it is the same thing.
It's like all these people who watched,
uh,
whoever the fuck it was break Dan Marino's
passing record and they don't even
look at the fact of all
the passing rules changes.
I mean, they say that hitting a curve
balls. The toughest thing in sports,
I think at this point covering a
receiver is because you've basically
essentially made it a legal past five
yards down the fucking field are out.
Jesus, he's on a soapbox. He's
on his soapbox. All right,
so now if Dwight Howard goes to
the fucking Lakers, it's just like,
I don't get,
I tweeted about this,
like the amount of shit that the Miami
Heat got for having a pylon championship.
Coby Brian has been part of a pile
on fucking team from about 1999 on,
that's all I'm saying. Okay. And
I don't want you to take a, well,
Boston did it in 2008 yes they did.
That was a pylon championship team.
I don't look at that team like,
that's like the 86 Celtics or the 84 team.
I don't, okay. I wasn't
a fan of what went ha,
what happened there either,
you know,
but doing it once versus doing it every
year for 15 fucking years. You mean?
You know you're making a pile on
team and like the NBA in and blocks
of fucking trade. You know when even
they're sitting there going like,
all right guys, this is getting a little
fucking ridiculous. Don't you think?
You know what I mean? Ah, I'll get a
ton of shit for that too. All right,
let's just, let's just get
it. Let's just read Christ.
I'm all over the Goddamn map here. Let's
just read something. Advice here. Advice.
Uh, 37 and at the end of
the love road, Jesus Christ,
I thought we were going to pull out
of the fucking dirt here. Hey Bill,
I'm 37 years old and I've never had sex
with a woman I've been in love with. Oh,
I thought you said he never had sex. I
was just gonna be like, all right dude.
Well that's a wrap. A dream is over. Or
just go out and get yourself a hooker.
All right?
And like the thickest fucking condom ever.
Um, anyways, I'm 37 years old and
I've never had sex with a woman.
Don't you hate on these fucking Max when
just some application just keeps, what?
Why is it just keep bouncing up and down?
I see you.
It's like the fucking nerd in the back
of the class who? I know the answer.
I know the answer. Um, I'm 37
years old and I've never had,
I've never had sex with a woman I've
been in love with or liked strongly.
I've fallen in love with many beautiful
young women over my long run by my
deduction is that I become a total social
retard with those chemicals when those
chemicals are coursing
through me by chase a girl,
if I chase a girl, she's turned off
when I'm indifferent. I do. All right.
Okay.
That's good. That basically means
you're coming on too strong dude.
It's like a burner turned down
the Gasol though. Do you know,
are you showing up with like fucking
flowers and candy with your hair parted
down the middle the first fucking day?
Yeah. You're going to freak her out.
Um, anyways. One, I'm indifferent. I do.
All right.
I've kicked a number of women out of
my bed and life after they've made the
smallest infraction.
One girl had the greatest sense of
humor and had a perfect athletic body.
I threw,
I threw her out one night because she
was eating chicken wings in my bed.
Okay.
Only because I didn't have that.
Um,
only because I didn't have that emotion
that made me want to chase her down or
keeper. Otherwise, I think she was great.
You broke up with a girl because
he was eating chicken wings in bed.
How was your lock? The door test? Um,
yeah,
of course.
Now I get that love feeling less and
less frequently as I get older and my
failure to grow mature with the woman
over the years has given me an Anthony
Kumi, a complex, I only
want young fit chicks.
But now after years of living with a
void in my social life and being daily
devoted to girls of the Internet,
I finally fell for another real girl,
a young professional personal trainer
who joined my beach volleyball team.
I'll fuck you with your
hot ass. Ah, Jesus.
Look at this fucking guy. He probably
looks like a fucking James Bond.
The other chicken, our team tried
to convince that this new girl
was interested in me. Oh yeah. All
these chicks trying to help you out.
What is she was blowing you? Uh, the new
girl was showing signs of flirtation,
but when I made a move, she
fell silent. I am an old man.
My question to you is,
since hand guns are illegal and very hard
to find outside of the urban areas of
my country,
of Canada,
should I get a sling shot and shoot myself
over and over in the head with acorns
until I'm dead?
Or at least until I am particularly,
I am less particular about what
kind of vagina falls onto my cock.
MMM.
Yeah. Dude, you got, you got, you got
to make a pick here. You 37 years old,
you're drafting in the later rounds.
She's still trying to pick up a blue chip.
It ain't there. I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you.
You can take a risk on one,
but you know, I think, uh,
okay.
Yeah,
I think you've got to look at the douchey
qualities that yourself and realize
that they're putting up with you on
whatever the fuck it is that you do.
You know?
Um, you're only 37 years old.
Fortunately that's still young.
Back in the day, you
know, Ben Franklins Day,
you'd look like you were 106 and it
would be over and you'd have fucking
tuberculosis, you know, wheezing
that you never fucking found love.
So you're fine.
You're playing volleyball.
You just sound like an in shape guy
who keeps banging all these hotties.
But woe is me. Can't
find love. You know what?
Go Fuck yourself and your awesome life,
Huh?
You can't find love and you're
all fucking, you just, Oh,
I just keep fucking one personal 22
year old personal trainer after another.
This is a problem. Look, if you
want to find love, I, I would, uh,
I would stay single until you found it.
You know,
I think you like women just
being infatuated with you
and playing with your hair
and telling you how
amazing you are as you can.
No,
no.
And then he keeps saying, yeah,
look at you. You're not that old.
You still have four abs. Right.
I think you like all of that.
I think you'll like that
fucking attention. I saw a
guy like that this weekend,
right?
So hanging out with the lovely Nia,
we went to this Mexican
restaurant and this guy shows up,
right dress like Arnold Schwarzenegger.
And when he lost a little bit of weight
and he was promoting terminator two on
our [inaudible] Hall and he came
out in that Leather Ensemble, uh,
that's how the guy was dressed.
Any comes in with this?
Absolutely fucking smoking.
Okay.
I don't know.
Brazilian are meaning out of Iranian.
I don't know what the fuck she was fucking
smoking hot chick with like this lime
green.
I don't even know what I gotta know
what the fuck she was wearing it like,
you know, showed like her fucking
flat stomach, her fucking round ass.
Yeah,
I was checking.
I think it's one of those girls you
can check out right in front of your
girlfriend and she doesn't give a shit.
You know, she's like checking her out too,
like at the end, but pitches
hot. Um, so the bartender cards,
the guy was,
she loves because
he thinks it means that he thinks
that he's fucking 21 you know,
the guy looked like he was 50 and he
just goes, he's like my friend, he goes,
how we'll do that guy.
Yet he has this big cheesy date rapes
smile with his awful fucking beard.
And he's just like, how old do you
think I am? Right. And the guy goes,
I don't know, 35 right.
And the Nia goes like,
fucking like, you know, like goes,
makes us gesture of like way higher way.
I fucking burst out laughing,
but I don't think the guy saw,
because he was so full of them that he
actually didn't realize that this kid was
just working for his tip. It's
like, dude, you look like you're 50.
And he goes and he's like, I am 48.
You seem like one of those guys,
like you're out there
hooking up with them.
So I would say stop being
such as self involved,
douchebag and realize that
you have faults yourself.
Get over yourself.
All right.
You're actually starting to cause your
cause just starting to slip into those.
Uh, I'm not getting, you know, you're in
your David Hasselhoff ears. Who's kidding?
Who.
Okay.
But you know, if you're going to be in
those years and you haven't found love,
you're doing it the best way ever.
Banging personal trainers
and a volleyball players. Um,
in any ways. That's, that's the
picture that you painted yourself.
You could be a tub of shit cause you are
playing volleyball in Canada. I mean,
I don't know how many weeks a
year you can do that up there.
I can't tell if this is like the picture
that you painted is who you really are
or if you're in even bigger psycho
and you actually don't look like that,
but that's how you picture
yourself. Um, yeah. I, I would,
my advice would be get over
yourself and realize that, um,
you know,
I know. Yeah, I'm talking myself into
circles. I have no fucking idea. Oh,
do you know I ruined a
woman's Day at the mall.
I just remembered that
this woman in a wheelchair.
Okay.
I ruined a woman,
an old woman in a wheelchair his day at
the mall and it's been killing me for
like the last two days is what happened.
Me and Nia,
we were leaving the mall, the mall. Okay.
And we wait for the elevator opened.
The elevator opens and all you
see is this beautiful babies.
This the first thing you see when the
doors open is this baby laying in a,
in a stroller looking up big blue eyes.
One of those Gerber looking babies, right.
And me and Ian both go ah, second we see.
But like how are you doing? You know,
talking like baby talk to
it and saying the mother,
how good looking the kid is
and all that type of shit.
And with Gugu Gaga and
about the fucking baby.
And she gets off the doors
open when the door is open,
the first thing we see is this old lady
in a wheelchair being pushed by some
lady and you know they back up and the
woman with the baby gets off the elevator
and then the woman starts pushing the
old lady in to the elevator and she's go,
is this going up? Is it going
up? I'm going, it's going down.
And it's one of those things that's like
tension because the doors are starting
to close. So even though I
keep saying it's going down,
the ladies not hearing me cause all
she's focusing on is the door she says is
going up, is it going up? It's gone
down, it's going to. And I finally got,
it's going down like I yelled over the
fucking old lady's head so the old lady
looks up, she just goes, okay, thank you.
And I totally knew in that
moment that she was just like,
you were talking to her
like I wasn't even here.
You didn't even can
acknowledge that I was here.
And I realized that in that moment,
and I don't know why I think it
was cause I was talking to a baby,
I was still ice and she was
like fragile to my brain.
Went back to talking to the baby
and I just looked at her and I went,
as the doors were closing, I was soon,
okay, bye bye. I said it just like that.
And I waved to her like she was a baby.
I don't know why I did it.
And then the door closed
and I immediately,
I immediately looked down at
the floor and shame and Nia,
it was one of the hardest
I ever heard her laugh.
She just turned around and face the back
of the elevator and was laughing to the
point she couldn't even like get the
words out to ask me why. I just did that.
She kept just going like,
like she just kept getting out the why
part and I just kept going. I don't know.
I don't know why. Just did that. I stuck
my hand out right in her face. You know,
you wave to a baby. I did
that. I went, okay, bye bye.
Towards closed.
And I know she was probably thinking
either I was mocking her or that I felt
that she wasn't mentally there
anymore and I knew that she was,
and I just feel like shit.
And um,
the reality is is I could've written the
elevator back up and tried to explain
myself, but I didn't, I just
walked in shamed in my Prius.
Um, yeah, it was just
a fucking weird week.
The whole fucking week was just weird.
I have one of the worst nightmares I've
ever had in my life last night I was
laying in bed.
It's one of those dreams where like
this something trying to get me,
but it's like,
yeah,
it's like sort of envy. It's like
a force. He's trying to get me,
I know it's going to get me and I
can't fight it or get away from it.
And I'm just like,
even like the dream,
I'm like laying in bed and I can't
fucking move. And then in the end,
all of a sudden this fucking woman
appears like, just kinda like,
like a ghost, but it looks
like a person. Right. And, uh,
I have my hands clasped
together and she's like,
she had like fucking, uh, like
reddish hair, but like, you know,
the uncle and hot chicks
dye their hair red.
They're not real red heads like that.
Like almost like a fucking,
I dunno, like a page boy kind of
haircut. She's like a rocket ship.
She had tattoos and like this tank top
on Nice titties and I'm sitting there and
I had my hands class and she clasp hands
around my hands and she looked me right
in the eye and goes,
you're going to kill yourself one day.
And then she just disappeared
and it fucking freaked me out.
Obviously.
She goes,
you're going to kill yourself one
day with this look on her face.
Like either she knew or she definitely
knew and that she had killed herself and
I was going to join her wherever
the fuck she isn't in the afterlife.
And uh,
I was so fucking scared.
It actually woke me up and I wouldn't
open my eyes because I also be afraid that
she was going to be standing there
waiting to class my fucking hands again.
How freaky Zen.
Now let me ask you this because you know,
I think about killing myself, but I do
it in a very mainstream fucking way.
Like, you know, okay, bye. Bye. When the
doors close, I wanted to kill myself.
I wanted the elevated a land on me,
but I don't really want to kill myself.
So what the fuck does that dream mean?
Anybody wants to do?
Um,
okay.
And I don't believe in go see them.
I think the reason why I had that dream
was because last night I turned out all
the lights and I, and I got a
little freaked out because, uh,
my room right is right near the water
and it was this really
weird reflection and uh,
I had some weird shadows and stuff.
So what I always do when I get freaked
out like that is this is the stupidest
thing ever is I give the finger
to the shadow. That's what I do.
It's something I learned when I was
a kid because if it is a monster,
it's not going to put up with that.
Right?
It's immediately going to come
over and do something to me.
So if I give it the finger and it doesn't
do anything that when I was a kid it
just let me know that it wasn't a monster
or that it was a fucking pussy and it
wasn't, it didn't have it in it, you know,
it didn't have that killer
instinct and it was just going to,
it was just good to just stay over there
in the corner, which I was fine with.
You know, you can spend the night,
just don't come over here and kill me.
That was basically it. So I did that. I
still do it to this day and I, I do it.
It kinda has a joke and it makes me laugh
for some reason I was thinking about
that chicken,
the ring,
just what their fucking hair popping up
and doing something to me have you do
that? You just mind fuck yourself.
And I was like, all right,
I have 10 seconds to get into the bed
or that chick from the ring is going to
appear and fucking kill
me, you know? So I got my
self in this anxious state,
I think before I went to sleep.
And then I ended up having this goddamn
nightmare and she fucking class both my
hands and goes,
you can you kind of kill yourself one day.
And I just sat there laying, they'd
go, I'm not going to kill myself.
Okay.
Don't open your eyes. That freak
you out. Well, what gives a fuck?
It's been a weird fucking week, you
know, that awful tragedy out there.
And uh, Colorado, you know,
was driving him in my truck.
All I have is fucking a am radio and um,
and so all I could eat,
you know,
and that's all they were talking about
on talk radio. And I'm one of those guys.
Once I see it, it's
fucking horrific. I know.
I don't want to hear about it anymore.
I don't want to know the kid's name and
know what his face looks like just in
case he's trying to get
famous. I just, you know,
yeah,
it's just fucking awful. Right. But
all I could listen to on the radio,
that's all they were talking about.
And these fucking people calling
in every God there. One of them.
It's just saying the same fucking
thing over and over again. It's like,
who doesn't know that it's terrible?
Who doesn't know that it's not a tragedy?
Who isn't going to send prayers
out to the fucking family?
Why do they got to keep calling up?
It's fucking guy calling up yet I believe,
and I have the,
I believe in a hell and
uh, this guy, he's a,
he's deed all. If I, if I
was running deck, z would
definitely shot that. We got it.
Okay.
The fuck you calling up for?
I Dunno. It just fucking,
it became annoying after awhile.
And,
and then the talk show hosts
just wanting to keep it going.
Okay.
It was like no other way to say it was a
tragedy and he just kept piling on is a,
it's bad for families.
It's bad for,
it's bad for the nation and the dead
and the freedoms that we, uh, we,
we give people at level,
but the lab, but the public,
well then the NRA always
has to immediately pylon
after somebody uses a gun.
Like this doesn't mean the
gun dated gun didn't do it,
person did it just just letting you know,
just in case you thought in an inanimate
object could somehow do shit on its own,
you know?
Okay.
And then they always come
up with the brilliant,
what if everybody had it was allowed
to have a gun then that wouldn't have
happened. Yeah. I think that that
guy would have killed less people,
but I think a lot more other people
would have got killed getting shot in the
back of the fucking head is people
tried to shoot that person. Right.
I'm not against guns by the
way, but like, you know, look,
everybody can have a driver's license.
How many people really are good at
driving? You know what I mean? Hi,
people are good at sports. I don't
feel have good hand eye coordination.
Do you want these fucking people with
guns and all of a sudden somebody starts
squeezing off some rounds and those
motherfuckers are between you and the guy
shooting at you and you're
not organized at all.
Yeah.
You know when,
when like 10 cops going in store my house,
they know where the fuck
they're at for a reason.
So they don't shoot
each other in the back.
If you got a bunch of people in a goddamn
movie with fucking glocks and somebody
comes in and start shooting, I
mean, it's going to be a fucking,
it's gonna be even worse.
Okay?
I think what they should do is,
okay,
there's gotta be two, two, two
levels. You have to pass to get a gun.
Okay? Aside from not being a psycho,
you should, when you get a gun,
you should then have to become
a fucking marksman. All right?
And if you're not a marksman, then it
affects the caliber of gun that you get.
This actually makes a lot of sense. All
right? It's like taking the driver's test.
You can't go there blind as a bat and
they just give you a fucking goddamn car.
Like they'll go fuck yourself,
go down a Pearle vision
and get your game together.
They should do the same thing with
guns. Okay, I want to get a gun license.
So God bless America. You can have
one go over there, the gun range,
and now go shoot at that
silhouette over there. Right?
Yeah.
You know,
if you only hit it once she get a BB gun
or maybe one of those little toy guns
that that shoots the plastic things.
So you could still put somebody's
eye out though with it, you know?
But if you actually go down there
when you're, you're a fucking
goddamn maniac, right. Psycho fucking,
you know, just everything's a headshot
or center mass. Then you get the glock.
Right.
Does that make sense?
Can you just have a safe word?
Yeah.
Just something the guy yells,
when would shit like that and everybody
hits the fucking deck and this guy gets
up and just puts too right in the fucking
psychos head and it's over as oppose
to just letting everybody
just start fucking shooting.
Okay.
Would that make sense?
Oh,
if everybody just thought the way I did
the world would be a just as fucked up.
All right.
Anyways,
but what kind of people
have to fucking call up?
Yeah.
During a tragedy and you just have to
call up and you just have to reiterate
that it was a fucking tragedy.
Okay?
You have to call up and say that, I
think this guy's going to hell. Like who?
Who doesn't think that
you know,
fucking idiots
watching this fucking
politicians stammering.
Okay.
Through, so you know, family is the
love to put, we asked. We got it.
It's fucking horrible.
Just get on with punishing this guy.
Go hang that guy by his fucking toes.
They won't,
they're going to go through some big
nine fucking year of trial with this guy.
Okay.
And then did they try to like,
they try to blame guns or they tried
to blame the fucking movie and she's a
white tee. He's out of his fuck. I can
guarantee before you waste all this money
doing all of these studies, this guy,
he's out of his fucking mind. Who, who,
who the fuck would go in and do something
like that and that now I'm doing and
see what, see what I'm doing right now.
I'm doing what these collars are doing.
All right, let's plow ahead here.
How the fuck is it? 38 minutes in.
This is the tragic Monday morning butcher
gonna talk about tragedies one after
another and I'll try to somehow find
something mildly amusing and all of this
shit. All right. Um,
advertisement number two,
game fly.com. Everybody gamefly
offers over 8,000 video games.
You get the sense, the disks in the
mail to you and you can send it back.
You're done playing the games.
Do you like video games?
Want to be nice to have 8,000 of them.
There's no late fees,
no hassles with access to all the new
releases works for your playstation,
Nintendo, Xbox, and now your PC.
For Xbox listeners only,
you get a free 15 day to
try to dis trial 2195 value.
If you go to my website,
a podcast page and click the gamefly
banner or go to www.game fly.com/burr.
Um,
what does that for listeners?
For my listeners only.
Okay. For my listeners
only you get it. All right.
I thought it said for Xbox players only,
I was like, why did they do that? No,
it was for my listeners only www.game
fly.com/birth all right. And the, uh,
what do we got here? The last
one here? Um, number tree,
amazon.com. You guys
know the deal. All right.
If you go on amazon.com just stopped
by my podcast page first click on the
Amazon banner. You don't have
to do anything after that.
If you buy something, uh,
they kick a percentage back to me.
It doesn't cost anything extra to you.
And then I kick a 10% to the
wounded warriors project. Uh,
I've actually just been kind of kicking
10% of what I'm making on the podcast to
it. And it's been great even though
now I'm on some fucking, you know,
junk email list, I think, you know, the
second you give any money to anything,
then all of a sudden they're just like,
next thing you know, you're getting
shit in the mail about penguins.
Do you care about this to anybody?
Um,
all right, so plowing ahead, plowing
ahead. Next. Uh, advice buddies x.
What's up Billy boy,
I need a little unlicensed,
unlicensed advice that you've
been doling out. I liked it.
This guy said that this is my unlicensed
advice that you should not listen to
because, uh, I do not have a
degree in anything. All right?
I am about,
okay,
two shades below Dr Dr Phil.
That's how bad I am at this.
Okay.
That wasn't pumping me up.
That was dragging him down. Uh,
my friend recently broke up with a girl.
He's been dating for awhile and wouldn't,
and when you know it,
this girl is the tips.
I've been friendly with this guy
for almost a year in his girls,
was always with us when we
hung out a Jesus. All right.
I can tell you right now,
just go ahead and Banger and say
goodbye to your friendship. Um,
from the moment I met her,
I've liked her and wanted to bang her.
Oh wait,
but you just want a fucker.
Uh, dude, this is dirty. This is dirty.
The kind of girl I imagine
when I think of a girl,
I would want to have a relationship with.
Go Fuck Yourself.
You said you wanted a banger first or
you like some sadistic guy who just wants
to uh,
fuck this girl and fucker better than
your friend so you can just be behind it
going, yeah, you lay dead bitch. Yeah.
You liked it. You one of those guys.
He's trying to paint a good picture
here, but I'm not buying it. Classy.
Attractive. Funny. The whole
Shebang. Dude. Right off the bat,
the first thing you said was you
wanted to bang banger. I Dunno.
You're trying to be funny.
I'll give you the benefit of the doubt.
Let's plow ahead. Uh, I've even developed
feelings, feelings, question mark.
I know that's gay. Fuck you. Uh, for
her axial guys, we just can't, we just,
we're not allowed. I actually liked this
girl actually feel like I could spend,
like, I can't even say that
without having that. Ah, oh my God.
Fucking tone in my voice. Um,
let me see if I can just say it.
How I say I really liked
this girl. I think I could
spend my life with her. Okay.
That just sounded like a bad read. There's
no way to say it without feeling like.
I just feel like I just
really connect with her.
Ah, go fuck yourself. Ah. I've even
developed feelings for her quickly.
I liked hanging out with her
whenever she tagged along.
I never flirted with her
or anything like that,
but I did rubber muff under the table.
Come on, dude. You leave in some shit out.
He didn't say that last part, but come
on, but we did get along pretty well.
I would and still do.
Think about her all the time.
Some real grade school crush type shit.
Now they've broken up and she's single
and ready presumably to do some revenge
banging. Yeah, dude, you're a
piece of shit, but God bless
you. She was hot enough.
I probably do it. No, I wouldn't.
My younger days I would.
I wouldn't. Maybe I would. I don't know.
I'm not going to judge you anyways.
See where I'm going with this.
Yeah.
I saw where you were going with it from
the second I started reading it. Anyway,
unlike most guys, I don't want
to just bang this broad. I want,
I want to be with her,
do the whole boyfriend thing,
but I know doing so would break one
of the most important rules of male
friendship. Never fuck
your friends girl. However,
the power of pussy has be thinking that's
crazy and that the best and that's the
best thing for me to do.
However,
the power of pussy has me thinking that's
crazy and that the best thing for me
to do is wait four to six months until
things settled down and see if she feels
the same way that I do.
I'm not sure if she will,
but I'm willing to try
and find out despite the
ramifications. What do I do, Bill?
Should I go after this awesome,
awesome girl risking my friendship
or do I go bros before hoes?
Forget her and wait for the next four.
Do Juror a or am I just bat shit crazy?
Um,
AH, Jesus dude. Like I
can't figure you out.
You sitting here talking like you Gugu
Gaga and then you're also just saying
like, you just kind of
want a banger. All right,
this is what I'm going to tell you.
Okay.
Rather than just telling you what I'm
going to tell you that this is what I'm
going to tell you before telling you
that thus eating up more time in this
horrific podcast.
This is the sad thing about getting older.
Okay.
When your friends get
older and they get married
and they have kids, you barely
see him anymore. It sucks. Okay.
And if they have some,
if they married some fucking Douche
bag who you know the in the and,
and they, and they just gave their
balls away in the relationship.
He had never gonna see him again.
But if they actually have a cool life who
lets them go out and hang out with the
Fellas, you still only going to
see each other once in a while.
You got to raise kids.
So in the long run,
if you feel like this girl might be
the one you got to do what you can't,
you're gonna regret it
for the rest of your life.
But if this is just some sadistic
shit where it was, she was,
you just wanted to bang her cause she
was around, you know, and you saw like,
it's just like,
dude,
I gotta tell you if you bang that
girl and afterwards you're not feeling
anything dude.
It's like now
she's got something on you and if she's
a psycho and if they had a bad breakup,
you can better fucking believe.
Like that's like that's chicks
ways of getting back at guys.
Like they'll go out and
fuck their friends. Um,
I mean just, I mean you weren't just
like Hell hath no fury as they say,
like a woman's scorn. And if
it's a bad breakup, like women,
they want to throw all your shit out
in the front lawn, light it on fire.
Okay. And that's not enough to
fucking go after you material things.
Okay.
That's what they want to do.
They want to leave you with and then
we'll go on and go bang all your fucking
friends and then let you know about it.
So then you lose all your friends,
you lose your entire wardrobe.
You standing there like a flood victim
just tearing up as it starts to rain,
as you stand on the fucking front porch
at some dilapidated fucking three family
house, that's how they want to
leave you. They're fucking nuts,
some of them. Okay. So
you know the deal, dude, you're stepping
in Shit, you're looking at a field,
you know,
it's a minefield and you want to walk
across in any ways because there's a woman
at the other side of it,
which this is a classic Shakespearian
tale about ready to unfold.
So, and I can say that having never
read Shakespeare, I tried to read it.
It's more complicated than the Bible.
Um,
I, you know, I don't know,
Dude. I don't you, you have to.
You got to figure out where the fuck
you're at with this shit. All right.
Do you really like this girl?
Do you really think she's the one or
was she just around long enough that you
just were thinking about them and you,
you know,
looking at a Tan fucking thighs are a
fucking titties or a God damn mouth to
something and just like, I'd be
one or would it be like, you know,
and you just sat there doing
that the whole fucking time.
There always is that excitement that all
your guy friends have when you break up
with a hot girl. Cause they're all like,
Oh God, I always wanted to fuck that girl.
A Jesus Christ.
All right.
And you guys have that conversation with
each other and that's how you fucking
talk a bunch of pirates. You
sit day. Do you hear, uh,
Mike and Joanne broke up? Can you
believe that? Yeah, it's fucking crazy.
And then you guys sit there
and then there's that half
second pause and you both
just start laughing because you
don't like do it. We can't, we can't.
Oh Geez. I would love
to. I would love to. Uh,
I won't say anything you don't fuck is
anything. It's just, it's fucking brutal.
It's brutal.
And then the guys all insecure because
this is the bottom line is if, you know,
that's why you don't
bring your girl around,
you don't bring your girl on it because
you do it enough. You're good guy.
Friends are gonna want to fuck her,
you know,
and then she kind of gets to know them.
And then did you already do that stupid
fucking phone call when you call? Hey,
you know, just calling up just to
say, I'm sorry you guys broke up.
I thought you guys look great together.
Blah blah, blah, blah, blah. Right.
Try to catch her in that week
fucking moment. Did you do that,
your Predator? Ah, we all have, um,
that is a shitstorm sir. There's
no, uh, there's no way out of that.
Um,
and there's no way you're going to wait
six to eight months because if the girl
hot enough in six to eight months,
she's already going to have somebody else.
And if you come back around again,
it's going to be like her going backwards.
So there, see what I did? I just lit a
candle under your ass to go fucking do it.
Oh, it gives a shit. Let me know
how it works out. Uh, advice.
Friend's girlfriend is a bitch.
Haven't I already given
an advice over this thing?
I've given this advice
a Zillion fucking times.
I'm a high school senior and in
three weeks with me in three weeks,
me and my friends are going backpacking
through Australia for a month and a half.
We've been planning this trip since middle
school and I have saved for the past
five years because I am paying
for my share of the trip myself.
We're both psych to graduate from
high school and for this trip, dude,
I hope you have the most,
the only way I would backpack through
Australia is if they made thigh high
hooker fucking snake boots.
Okay.
They got like some of the
deadliest snakes on the planet.
Okay.
They've got that Tai pan where
the fuck it is. They got the uh,
nothing got black Mambas out there.
Those ones you get bit like in the
second it get registered that the pain of
getting bit,
you like collapsed.
Okay.
Yeah. Fuck all that. All right
dude. We'll have fun with that.
This sounds like one of those trips
where somebody ends up dying and then
somebody goes on trial for
possibly murdering the other
person and then they get
off and then the,
but there's always that wonderment of
what really happened whenever Americans go
to Australia,
somebody dies.
Remember that guy who was on the honeymoon
and went scuba diving and his wife
got eaten by a shark?
Yeah,
yeah, I remember that one or something
weird. Or they went deep sea.
A fucking snorkeling.
Okay.
I would say right now, if you're a
fucking woman and a, if you're a lady,
um, and you're on it,
you're going on a honeymoon.
If it involves fucking scuba diving,
so any sort of going out to the ocean,
that's it. It's over. Call off the
wedding. All right. Call it off.
Nothing good comes from that.
He's either going to get drunk and fall
overboard or he's going to shut the air
valve off.
Yeah.
Don't go on a cruise.
You know? And if you do,
you do not go up on deck unless there's
plenty of witnesses around. Fuck that.
Moonlight kissing. Fuck all that. That's
when you go off the back of the boat.
She was just, she wanted to
reach down and touch the water.
I don't know what happened. No
body, no nothing. Ah, fuck that.
Hey billion. I'm a high
schools. All right. So anyways,
they're going to Australia.
My friend and I have known each other
since we were three and our families are
very close.
He's like,
he's like a brother to me and we've
often confided in each other and ask each
other for relationship
advice. Whoever. Lee recently,
my friend had started dating this
girl who has put a huge rift in our
relationship. Congratulations.
He's met his first psycho.
You guys are really high school age.
I don't think this is going
to be that big a deal.
The girl my friend is
dating is a total whore.
She's ignorant and jealous and generally
has an unattractive personality.
They've only been dating for two months,
but she feels like she owns him.
She found out that my friend and I were
going on this trip and has been rude to
me ever since. Yeah, she's
insecure. She's young. Um,
and she's fucking a lot of
guys. It stayed, it started
with just snipping remarks,
elevated over time, blah, blah, blah.
But this is just going
to be the usual shit.
The other night we were all at a party.
She got hammered. She came up to me,
started shoving me and told me that my
ghetto pussy wasn't going to seduce her
boyfriend.
What his comment probably had something
to do with the fact that I'm black and
her boyfriend is white
though I was seeing red.
I tried not to sucker punch that bitch
in the face. He had dude, dude, don't,
don't ever do that.
Uh,
I've boxed and kickbox for the past three
years and I'm pretty sure I could have
stopped the yard all over. Yeah, Dude.
What the fuck? Where did that come from?
I think the fact that you're a guy, you
could pretty much beat up most women's,
so, which is why you
don't do it. You know,
it's like running up the
score and a college game. Uh,
I told her to calm down.
I have never done anything with
my friend and have no desire.
Intentions of anything
happened in Aussie land.
She kept yelling and screaming
and making a scene eventually. Oh,
so she's basically calling you gay in
front of all your friends at a party and
you're at a high school level. Yeah.
That's kind of a, that's a situation.
Eventually I just gave up trying to
reason with the drunk broad and I left
naturally.
I told my friend what she said.
He agreed it was absolutely unacceptable
and had a talk with her that turned
into a fight.
My friends girl gave him an ultimatum,
me or her and for forbade
him from going to Australia.
This is absolutely hilarious to me,
which it should be. Since they're fight,
my friend hasn't called or texted me.
What should
I do? You know what? Fuck him. Fuck him.
Let him learn the lesson.
You know what you do?
You go down there with your
fucking American accent. All right,
and you're going to get more fucking
pussy than you could ever shake a God damn
sticker, a walking stick act. All right.
To keep it in, in a hiking sense here.
All right, fuck him. And then
you come back and just, you know,
let him be with that whore. Wash
your fucking hands of it, okay?
You Go. I invested a lot of time,
effort, and money into this trip.
I'm not going to have the beginning of
my senior year destroyed by some skank
phase control freak,
lush, which you shouldn't,
but I also don't want to hurt my friend
and have and have them be miserable when
we're going to be stuck living, sleeping,
traveling together for six weeks. Hey,
fuck them. This is the
deal. Fuck him. Fuck him.
Okay? He wants to be with that
horror. Let them be with that whore.
Get on with your fucking life. He wants
to go with you to Australia. Let them,
if he doesn't, if he wants to stay back
there with that psycho, let them let,
he has to learn this lesson the same way.
You got to let a toddler fucking slam
his head off the God damn coffee table.
Different, understand gravity or at least
putting his little fat baby arms out.
You know,
you gotta,
you gotta let this dude fall right
on his fucking face. All right,
let's hope he's wearing a condom,
but he's old enough to know how
people get pregnant. So you know,
give me a fucking break.
Fuck this shit. All right.
That's it. Fuck him. Wash
your hands of it. It's over.
All right. You go out, you enjoy your
senior year, you go to Australia,
he comes, he doesn't, you don't give
a fuck. All right, that's on him.
He wants to sit there and invest all his
life and some stupid drunk skank phase
control freak, lush as
you call her. Let them,
what the fuck do you care? Okay.
She fucking embarrassed you.
I mean you, you don't do that.
You don't do that. I mean,
one time I was dating this fucking girl
and she was so fucking rude to one of my
friends and that night I was like,
I was beside myself and I was asking
her how she could do something like that
and she's just like, she was just
like, I'm sorry I didn't like him.
And I know it was the first time.
I was just like,
is that the most arrogant fucking thing
ever? And I'm not going to lie to you.
It took me like another,
like a week or two,
but I, from that second on I just
fucking pulled back and I was just like,
you know what?
Go Fuck yourself because you know
that's the life you're gonna have.
You're gonna have no, you're going to,
all your friends are going to be gone.
So fucker. All right. Did I say it
enough time? Yeah. Fuck her. Um, dilemma.
Um, all right. Number one
at their physical peak,
would you rather box Laila
Ali or will Smith Will Smith?
There's no winning with Laila Ali
either lose to a check or beat one up.
That was easy. I'll fight. Will Smith
worse I can do is lose to an actor.
But he used to rap, but he was
mainstream rap. Right? But,
but what was the ones that he had?
What the fuck was that?
I know people who started
about that summertime when I,
I don't remember how that one went.
I was too busy listening to metal
with the fuck did he have back then?
Parents just don't wonder.
Don't understand.
That's when like mainstream white
people were finally discovering rap.
That's what we did. We parents just
don't understand. Can't touch this
the worst of the worst, but go
fuck yourself. African Americans.
All right. I bet the first white music
you listened to was, it was, it was awful,
uh, with your hall and
Oates. Um, anyways, uh, if,
if you were a parent of a boy and a girl,
would you rather see your
son on to catch a predator?
Jesus being national
exposed as a pedophile or be
driving down the street and
see your daughter out on the corner of
whoring yourself out as a prostitute,
a prostitute.
Prostitute.
Yeah. Prostitute. There's nothing
worse than fucking a kid, you know,
I don't think it should change the
outcome of who won a football game. Uh,
but that's just me. A overrated,
underrated, underrated. A scabies.
He's underrated.
A great reason to launder.
I don't even know what
the fuck that means.
I don't know what scabies it would
launder. What money you're clothes.
I don't even what you're saying
there. Number two, pointing out,
did I even pronounce that correctly?
Um,
to pointing out details about a steamy
sex story that make it uncomfortable and
unsexy. Jesus Christ. What's, what
the fuck is this creek for example,
hey baby,
remember the other day when I bet you
over the dining room chair and we raw dog
did and you finished me off on your
knees between the cat food dishes in the
litter box.
Your girlfriend expression will change
from sexy to four horrified in zero to
60. Um, if you're the woman
who's dating that guy,
please break up with that
fucking reptilian psycho. Um,
is that the podcast for this
week? Oh, we're coming up on it.
We are coming up on it. Oh,
you know what? I forgot.
I forgot to do the classic
stamps.com read. Hey everybody.
Oh wait, what am I thinking? I got
to do this other one. Legal Zoom.
I forgot about this one. This is a new
advertiser. I think it'd be pissed.
58 minutes into the podcast is only way
you could read a little earlier. Um,
58 minutes in. All right.
Legal Zoom, everybody. Uh,
you probably heard about legal zoom.com
and I probably seen it out there aren't
a bunch of youtube videos,
but now I'm telling you about them.
So you gotta check 'em out. These
guys are great. All right. Um,
cause I've actually half the shift that
they do here and I paid a fucking lawyer
to do it. It cost me a zillion
dollars. Uh, all right.
If you basically,
are you sitting in a cubicle right now
that you wondering why you're making
somebody else's dream come true
while you're working towards that?
When you actually have an idea
for a business, you know well,
and you sitting there going,
well,
I'd love to get myself incorporate
it to start my business,
but it's going to cost a fortune.
well@legalzoom.com if you've been waiting
for the perfect time to start your
dream business, um, right
now's the time to do it.
You can incorporate your business or form
an llc@legalzoom.com starting at just
99 bucks.
It costs me like 1500,
something like that. 700 1500, I
can't remember. It was a lot of money.
They'll do it for 99 bucks.
And if you have a family, um,
and you need to make sure
that they're protected,
legal zoom also will help you a make out
your last will and testament for just
69 bucks. That's something
that I have to do. All right.
I have to make up my
last will and testament,
which is really a scary
thing for me to do. You know,
cause you're actually dealing
with your own mortality.
And considering I just had a dream like
I did last night, it freaks me out,
but I got to tell you if I'm going to
do it, I'm doing it for 69 bucks. Um,
in the past 12 years, over 2 million
Americans have used legal zoom for Llcs,
wills, trust, trademarks, and
more. This is basically, look,
if you're trying to start a business
or if you need a will to protect your
assets, this is the place to go.
Uh, you're going to save hundreds,
even thousands of dollars versus
going the traditional route.
And I know what you think of.
Well, what if I get bogged
down? What have, what have,
I can't figure it out. They even have
an attorney to help you if you need, uh,
if you need help.
Basically they have attorneys that you
can call in that type of stuff. All right.
Mandatory close. Sorry. It was
supposed to ride the worst.
There's the mandatory,
close everybody to this ad starting
Your Business and protect your family
today@legalzoom.com.
You can also get a special discount
from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter bur bur are in
the referral box and check out, uh,
at checkout for more savings.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm and self
help services are provided at your
direction. All right? So
that's the deal there. It is.
You want to start your business.
You want to be incorporated.
That is the cheapest, most
efficient way to do it. Uh,
I wish they were around back
when I got incorporated.
Could have saved myself hundreds
of dollars. So they got legal zoom.
What else? Is there anything
else I wanted to talk about? Um,
I don't think there was stamps.com
stamps.com you got that one down by now,
Huh?
If you don't want to go to the post
office anymore and you want to be able to
weigh packages and print your own legal
stamps off your computer and printer and
your own damn apartment
at any hour of the day,
go to stamps.com click on the
microphone in the corner and a,
you get $105 bonus offer free shipping
and all that type is our free stamps.
You're all over it. Look at me just
saving your money. Yeah, I got you.
A way to start your own damn business.
Make your last will and testament bringing
the post office into your apartment,
8,000 video games in there and
help out the wounded warriors.
What more do you need?
What more do we need, bill?
We'd like one more funny fucking story
from you to end the podcast. All right,
let's see what it got.
It wasn't enough that I said bye
bye to somebody in a wheelchair.
Jesus Christ. If I went to
church, how many fucking
hail? Mary's a said, you know,
stuff that I should go to confession and
just tell that story just to see what
the guy says.
You know,
cause I think they just make that stuff
up to off this boy hail Marys back there
drinking out of a chalice.
Who did that first?
Those rappers in Atlanta or priests?
Well I guess hip hop's only been around
since. What did I just say? Hip Hop,
I think I did since when?
When did that actually come about?
Was it in the early seventies is that
what it was number one run DMC actually
said that. Walk this
way was the first rap.
Remember that? Why did
they say that? You know,
did they run out of leather
jacket? Uh, Shell toes?
I was that was that fun running
low when they actually said that,
that wasn't the first Rep.
Why would they say that?
Did black people get mad at them when
they said that shit? No one gives a fuck.
You know what people,
I don't think I have anything left.
I was actually hoping that the red sox
were going to be in town tonight cause I
wanted to wear to head down there.
Um, even though I'm not drinking,
I really want to drink. I ain't gonna
lie to you people I really want to drink.
I do. I haven't drank in a couple of
weeks dry and myself out. You know,
I get through the uh, the kid show
that I'm going to be doing here.
You gotta be known at this point that
I'm not doing a fucking kid show is I'm
sitting here talking about pedophiles
saying bye bye to somebody in a wheelchair
and saying that Joe Paterno
is winds should still count
in case you detective work.
He was still questioning whether or not
I'm actually going to be hosting some
sort of revamp of a kid
show. It ain't happening. Uh,
actually get another acting gig.
I'm doing all right.
I'm doing all right on the old, the old
acting gigs. Thanks. This is what it is,
is perfect. It's the exact fucking
reason why I moved out to La.
I just wanted to start getting
some parts in some shit. You know,
that's all I wanted to do. I don't
need to be as, I just want to,
I just want to be in a, just let me
shoot a gun, gets shot to something.
You know, I told you guys my acting,
these are, these are my acting goals.
I want to do that scene where you run
down the alley and you're getting chased
by cop and he get to the chain link fence
and you get like three fucking crawls
up at and they drag you back down. I want
to do that. I want to get interrogated,
I want to get shot.
I'm going to get blown away.
I want to get killed by a monster
at some point.
I want to be getting eaten or something.
Just be gone. That's all I want to do.
All right.
I don't want to do gorillas in the mist.
What the fuck are they
counting down out there?
I think these are like coast guard people
learning how to be coast guard people
outside this way. Hang on.
What am I doing? Hang on,
hang on, hang on, hang on it. Yeah.
I think it's some sort of coast guard
training thing out there. 10, nine a,
you know, he's no one your boss in
Boston when they get down to four,
six, five, four
actually heard somebody say,
but is day I got breakfast she wants
him to is with that. Uh, no, I don't.
Trying to cut down on the
carbs. All right, that's the
podcast for this week. Um,
go fuck yourselves. Don't take any shit.
And uh, you know, I obviously wasn't,
you know that. Who gives a fuck? I'm
not gonna sit there and even try.
What am I doing? I just said it
wasn't an apologize for anything.
Fucking Penn State's wins should count.
Alright.
Those fucking players played the Goddamn
Games. They blew out their knees.
They risk fucking injury. They
won the Goddamn Games. All right?
Just cause some old fuck was doing some
shit that he should be burned in the
street for. You shouldn't punish
those fucking kids. I, Oh,
Penn state sells out all
their fucking games, you know,
learn from Smu. All right,
everybody just walk the fuck away.
You show up in force.
That'd be the greatest fucking thing.
You know how how unbelievable.
If you want to somehow turn this fucking
thing around Penn state fans is if
every game over the next
four years sells out,
even if you lose every fucking game,
okay,
there's no other program out there.
Could ever question your loyalty.
That would be the greatest
example of a fan support.
Unlike these, some of these
fucking red sox fans out here,
48 and 48 the fucking walking away,
you know?
See, that's the deal with most vans.
They're not real fence. You know,
you're like a marriage in sickness
and in health, good times and bad.
It doesn't work that way.
The fans fans basically say,
I love you until you suck
and then I'm walking away.
I'm going to leave you when you need me
most just like that Kenny Rogers song
phone with children
cropping and they'll feel
bad.
We want 48 games the last 48 games
and now you're leaving.
You can't, you know what?
Get the fuck up. God bless John
Lester. I know he doesn't want to lose.
I love and Pedroia when we're fucking
down like that and he's fucking powder him
on the leg trying to get him psyched up.
I love that shit.
I love that as much as watching a wind.
All right.
And if you're walking away now you're a
cunt and is Tom Cruise said in fucking
taps takeoff that baret right.
Poor Tom Cruise is fucking lady left them.
I think everybody like comes down on
Scientology. You know what I mean?
What's the fucking problem with it? Until
they have like a uh, uh, inquisition.
I really don't think there anywhere
as bad as my fucking religion.
You know what I mean?
We had like 58 Sandusky's running
around doing that shit. Did they, did,
was the Catholic church not
allowed to go to a bowl game?
Did they take away some of
Jesus's miracles? They didn't.
Those fucking games count down
screaming in a hotel room.
Those fucking games count. Those kids
won those games, those games count.
I did stand up for the Penn state Nittany
lions when they came out and they did
the, when they were playing
USC and the Rose Bowl,
I did stand up for them
and they were fucking,
it was like performing for the troops.
Pine tight. Everybody listening.
I know you have a great set.
Nobody heckled me. They were great.
Great Bunch of guys. You're going to
punish them. Go Fuck Yourself. All right.
This is what I say.
If you take away Penn state's victories,
then you have to take
away Jesus's miracles.
Jesus miracles didn't count if
Penn state's victories don't count.
That's what I'm saying. That's
my statement. I'm sticking to it.
Go fuck yourselves.
We'll talk to you next week.