Okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's built burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
August 13th, 2012. How the hell are you?
How's it going? August
13th. Can you believe it?
Only three more weeks of this summer.
Right?
But thanks to global warming,
you can still get a Tan right through
the second week of October. You know,
enjoy it. Folks. This is the golden
age of global warming. You know,
this is before polar bear swims up
to your fucking apartment, you know?
Okay.
All those fires in the middle
of the country, who cares?
Those are flyover states, right?
That's just our food supply.
Um, I've always thought it was funny
the way people make fun of those states,
you know,
because they don't have what?
A water slide and a giant
fucking skyscraper. All of
a sudden they don't count.
Yeah. All they're doing
is fucking, you know,
providing nourishment for
everyone in the state. I'm sorry,
everyone in the nation,
all they're doing is growing enough
food to feed the world, but we don't.
Right.
And I think that's a good thing.
I think a good thing that
we don't feed the world.
Okay?
There's too many fucking people, and
that's why the polar ice caps are melting.
It has nothing to do with v eight engines.
Okay? There's too many goddamn people.
So when I'm going to do eventually in
25 years when I get famous enough is I'm
going to put together my own collection
of musicians and we're going to do,
we aren't the world.
All right?
Yeah,
we are the world.
You're not a responsibility.
I'm sorry you don't have an apple tree,
so go fuck yourself.
There's too many people taking shits every
day and it's fucking up the world for
me and you all right?
We got more shit.
That's how it worked out. All
right. You get the idea. You know,
I wonder who that would actually return
that fucking phone call no fucking
maniac from was in that movie heat. I bet
he would. The guy was doing porns now.
Oh God. I mean that guy. Just once,
I want to have an orgasm like that and
be fucking gone. Oh, Jesus. Like he was
like, somebody kicked you
in the nuts. Um, anyways,
you wouldn't believe this right now.
The way this is going in where I'm
saying don't save the world. Okay,
let them go. That's how I would
run for office. Excuse me. Um,
non senator prayer.
I was wondering what you thought
about the problem in Croatia.
Rwanda damned. Uh, yeah. I don't
really know. I don't give a shit.
I mean, I think it's
terrible, but uh, you know,
you know, the more people
die, the more fresh air for
us. That's how we look at it.
You know, as long as it isn't anybody,
uh, with, with our flag on their shoulder,
I think that that would be okay.
That's appalling.
That's a realistic outlook lady.
Okay.
You want to be on the ship
that's sailing towards surviving.
I suggest you change your attitude.
Next question.
You over there with the striped tie?
No.
The other guy with the striped tie
and the receding hair. Yes. Yo,
I'm not answering that. Go Fuck Yourself.
It's a figure of speech. Jesus Christ.
Um,
I actually have a giant announcement.
Giant. A big for me. Okay.
Yeah,
I have a big announcement for
me. All right. I'm pregnant. Um,
I just found out and I'm really
excited for myself. No, I, I um,
I had been telling you guys
that I recorded a standup
special and the wonderful
district of Columbia back in March and
ever since then you guys have been asking
me, hey pill, when is that
special coming out? Well,
on this week's podcast I will be
announcing when my special comes out,
but not right now for some stupid reason.
I'm going to wait until the end.
Just like one of those dumb
shows on TV, you know, we're,
all you need is one piece
of fucking information.
They just try to drag it out so they can
get in eight minutes of advertising and
so we can have a yacht right now.
I'm fucking with you.
I'm going to do it right out of the gate.
That's how I do it cause
I'm not playing the gay man.
Um, okay. My new special isn't titled You.
People are all the same and it will
premiere exclusively on Netflix.
It's the only place you're going to be
able to see it is Netflix. Why do you ask?
Because I love those guys.
They show my entire special,
it's unedited itch.
It captures the exact level of ignorance
that I wanted to put out there.
I love those guys. So it's going to be
premiering exclusively on next flicks. Um,
this Thursday,
August 16th at 6:00 AM Pacific Time.
So for all you grumpy people out there,
that's 9:00 AM Pacific time. All right.
It will be available to all Netflix
members in the United States, Canada,
Ireland and the United Kingdom.
Well,
isn't Ireland part of the UK?
Okay.
Hey Nia, isn't Ireland part of the UK
or at least Northern Ireland is right.
I just lost everyone in fucking
it didn't and he is making a face.
We went over there,
we learned this,
we went on the double decker bus tour
and they told us what the lady and the
king owned right number
that the United Kingdom,
as far as my understanding
is, is England, Wales,
Scotland and a in Northern Ireland.
I don't know.
That's what it is.
It's Northern Ireland.
My apologies to everybody keeping it real
and southern Ireland as opposed to all
those sellouts in Northern Ireland who
are just fine with that bigger douche
telling you what to do.
Is that what you're telling me?
How many beer glasses am I going
to get thrown at my fucking head?
If I ever go back,
if I go up to Belfast anyways,
I'm just fucking with you guys over
there. All right, hang on a second.
What'd you say
Eastern and,
and I'm talking about the United States.
Okay.
Oh 9:00 AM eastern. Oh, did
I say for Pacific twice?
I'm sorry. Well, either way.
I was just talking about the United
States with those times. You know, why?
Cause we are the world.
So I'm really excited that it's also
going to be in Canada, Ireland and the UK.
Um, because uh, I go to those places
and when I go to those places,
only three people show up. So, uh,
maybe this will be able to, uh,
as the dollar collapses,
I'll be able to, uh,
go to places where there's other currency
and I'll get to start this journey all
over again. Nia. Remember when you
met me and I was still on a futon.
That's actually true. It is true. Okay,
so my new special you
people are all the same.
It's going to premier exclusively on
Netflix this Thursday, August 16th,
6:00 AM Pacific,
9:00 AM eastern and a,
what's the difference?
What's the difference between here and uh,
was it five hours to England?
Uh, you guys figure it out,
your fucking metric system.
You know,
what is somebody, somebody actually
summed up soccer for me. Finally.
How the hell did he describe it?
Oh,
was saying why Americans don't
like soccer. This guy said to me,
he goes, we already have this game
over here. We call it hockey. You know,
except it's way faster.
This hitting you guys fighting.
It's phenomenal.
And it's funny that he said that because
whenever I watch soccer, the, the,
the stuff that appeals to me is that it
is like hockey with the off sites and
that type of shit.
But I don't get it.
Why the defenseman just gets to stop
and then all of a sudden I'm off sites,
you know,
keep running. You do. You know
what I'm trying to do? Like that's,
that's your defense. You don't even have
to knock me on my ass. She just stopped.
It's just a terrible game.
You know we have arms.
People use them.
What would you watch a sport if all you
used was your arms and you didn't use
legs and everyone was just standing
there and maybe sitting on the ground or
maybe just one of those craftmatic beds,
like just throwing balls to one another.
Oh my God. Did I just described
murder ball? No, I didn't.
They roll around in their chairs. All
right. This is the money promoting podcast
for August 13th I got one more day on
my project here. I'm doing here, man.
I, I let the cat out of the bag, Nia,
and I told them that I was going to be a,
I'm working on the pilot for the
reboot of that kid shows zoom.
Remember that show?
Do you remember that show used to go.
Okay.
Did you try that song again? Zoom.
Muslims. Come on. Zoom, zoom,
zoom, zoom. We're gonna
Zuma. Zuma is Omasum. That's,
that's what was the song in the
70s. Come on, give it a try.
We're going to show you just why
we're going to teach you to fly high.
It was a drug reference. That whole
thing was take drugs. Come on,
give it a try. We're,
can I show you just why?
Why I don't want to do LSD.
Come on. Give it a try. I Dunno,
but come on, we're going to show
you why. Just take the shit.
We're gonna teach you to fly high and
everybody had the same stripe shirts on.
We're doing a reboot of
that without the drugs. Um,
all right.
So anyways,
I'm staying here in the north end of
Boston and I got to tell you something.
The Italian nose, make the best
fucking food out there. Bar none.
Go fuck yourselves.
I don't want to hear it.
If you're into Thai food or
you like Scottish fucking, uh,
what a Scottish people eat
Nini? What the fuck? What is it?
Haggis yeah, what was it
that's, that's like what?
That's like Shetland sheepdog balls with
the, some bangers in the mash there.
Um, by the way, when I talk
about, uh, Great Britain,
I should state that like a Scotland is
less than thrilled to be part of it.
That was the vibe I got.
Yeah.
When I was over there.
This is really just my ignorant travel
channel show this time, isn't it? Um,
so anyways, we didn't stay in
here in the north end and a,
all that mainly doing is eating
Italian food. I'm having a great time,
but as of last night I was finally fucking
sick of it when I had some Gnocchi,
which is basically potatoes with
wallpaper paste in a little bit of a,
was it pesto that they put on there? You
know, I ended up something fucking Irish,
but um, I never used to come over
to the north end. You leave in Nia.
Okay, bye bye. It's like I said to that
old lady in the wheelchair by, by, by,
by um,
what a sport.
I actually woke her up and kicked her
out of the hotel room so I could do this,
you know. Hey, if you want to come
back later, I have another microphone.
If you want to do the final
fucking 10 minutes, I know.
Are Dying to know what's
going on in your life.
Yeah.
I thought you going to
slam the door on me.
That would have a great
a nod to Jim Norton. Um,
anyway, so we've been
hanging out here. Uh,
I got fucking octopus
coming out my fucking e's.
Yeah,
no, I've eaten way too much Italian food.
I'll even know why I love it. I'm done.
Okay.
I've had fucking total lady.
I've had fettuccine Ed fucking
Spaghetti weedy. I've had everything.
I had a red [inaudible].
Um, that went right.
Fucking threw me.
Okay.
I wish it would be great if there was a
website that had a picture of a bunch of
people's different faces when they
ate something that, that, that,
that moment when they realize it's going
right through them and they realize
that they're in a public place,
it's going to get ugly and they're doing
the math on how far away the nearest
private toilet that they know is versus
how bad that feeling is in your gut.
Uh, let's just say wrapped it up pretty
damn quick with the person I was with.
Um,
anyways,
and then he had some
big festival down here,
some sort of religious thing
where they had a picture of him,
they had like Mary and
everyone was putting dollars
on or I don't know what the
hell that one is. I felt like I
was in some sort of Scorsese movie.
Um, and then they were playing this
Frank Sinatra music, which is just a,
it's just the best music ever.
It just makes you feel like you're
a fucking millionaire. You know,
they started playing this summer when,
you know,
the summer when it came blowing
in from a cross does see.
Right.
And of course it sounded amazing and if
for some stupid fucking reason they just
write as I'm hearing the
beginning of that song, you know,
that fucking little keyboard starts
playing and then the little fucking hits
with the horns and you're already swaying
as you're walking down the street and
I'm walking towards it,
right? Just mesmerized.
And all of a sudden this fucking
attitude voice starts singing with it.
And I realized that doing Sinatra like
Karaoke and it was some little girl going
up there and she was so fucking
flat and off I couldn't get.
And I like,
it was like frank singing like this summer
when Kay blow it in and she's on top
of that.
Okay.
Worth their fucking eight
year old high pitched voice.
I can't even do it.
My voice is shot.
And I was like immediately turned in the
other direction and I was trying to get
out away from it. But the way the north
end is set up with all the streets,
diagonal and all the
buildings close together,
it was just echoing down all the streets
and I couldn't fucking get away with it.
So addie go up fucking causeway street.
Okay.
Right.
Press the that goes over the fucking
Chiles town that you saw in the movie,
the town. And I walked up two,
uh, I walked up to the garden,
Boston Garden and I looked at
the Bobby or statue and uh,
I got to admit from the side,
it looks like Bobby your,
but when you look at the face,
it looks like that bit.
I used to do where remember the old man
face bit for my last special Dulia we'll
do you,
that's what it looked like.
I don't know what it is
about those fucking statues.
They can get everything to look
like the guy except for the face.
You know the Magic Johnson
Statute doesn't look like him.
The Bobby, your statute doesn't look like
him. The Michael Jordan statute. Just,
it doesn't look like him. Even with
the tongue sticking out. It's a,
I don't know what it is. They, they can't
make the face. They can't get the face.
Right. Really bill is, is, is this, is
this the level of fucking, you know,
Shit that you think is interesting to
us out. Go fuck yourselves. All right,
let's do a little bit of a,
let's get to a dilemma here.
Now, wait, wait. I got some other
stuff to talk about first. Um,
before I forget the, I took her,
we actually took a water taxi.
Um, you know, I wanted to surprise Nia.
We're going on the water taxi and
women are so fucking intuitive.
One of the hardest things to
ever do is to surprise a woman.
The second you start thinking,
God, I hope she doesn't notice.
I got, I hope she doesn't
fucking ask me x, Y, and Z.
It's like they sense it.
They were like fucking dogs.
They just pick it up and they'd be like,
what's wrong with what's going on?
Nothing. Why are you yelling at
me? What's going on? Freaking.
I was going to fucking surprise you.
What? This fucking boat ride. Well,
you don't have to. Yeah, they run real.
Like I don't understand why
every interrogator on the
first 48 isn't a fucking
woman. Their ability that,
that's one of those things that
nature gave him because nature new,
right nature knew that
fuck and Eddie nature.
He knew that,
um,
that guys could just beat the shit out
of women and there were no laws in place.
You know, back in the day can just,
whatever you want it to do. You know,
if she gave you a rough time, you just
balled up your big fucking caveman fist,
Harry knuckles and all and you fucking
cracked her right in the fucking nose
and it bled all over her woolly
mammoth to piece that she was wearing.
And that was the end of the
discussion. So, you know,
they had to adapt.
So fucking mother nature gave
him this fucking, I swear to God,
I can't get away with shit.
It isn't possible to
surprise Nia. I just, it's,
I can't fuck it. It, it drives me nuts.
I don't understand why there's not more
women in, in the world series of poker.
All right bill. We get it. They
can pick up what you're doing.
That's what I'm saying.
So I was sitting there trying,
I fucking finally just stopped and I said,
will you stop fucking up the surprise.
And then she just laughed.
You know, probably cause it made
her feel more secure. Right.
Well good. That's good to know that I
can tell when he's fucking acting weird.
So if he ever did try to be deceitful,
I would be able to pick up on it.
You know what I mean? Fucking
maniacs. So when he was,
so I take her on this water taxi,
right?
I bring her over to sue
one of these little fancy
fucking food food stores where
they, you know, they go walking
in where they had the lady Gaga,
where in the fuck in, uh, who's,
who's another one of the horse that they
all think is just amazing fashion sense.
Did you see the meat dress? Oh
my God. Not the meat dressed.
They obviously don't like that, but
they'd like that fucking veil in the face.
Shit, don't they? Don't they all,
isn't it fair to just lump them all
into one category and then just say
something ignorant? I think it is. I
think that's totally fair. So anyways,
we're riding over on the water taxi and
it's a fucking tremendous, you know,
the guy drive and it's an ex
fucking fishing boat captain.
So He's loving life. You
know, he's got this great job.
He doesn't have any crew
that he has to deal with.
He doesn't have to go out of the harbor,
you know,
he just gets to cruise around on this
little boat. So he's in a great mood.
You know, he's making Nia laugh and he's
breaking my balls way had taken her,
I'll make sure he gets you
something expensive, blah,
blah, blah and all that shit.
We having a great fucking time. So
as we're going over there, right,
all I'm doing is, uh, and by the way, if
I ever had a boat, that's all it would do.
I would just go around the harbor.
There's no way I would ever go out to sea.
I am unbelief.
I'm terrified.
Did you see that fucking video of that
guy just sitting in the ocean and that
hammerhead shark just circling around
them? They, before they fished him out.
You know what I don't get,
I don't get why I can't just
be in the ocean treading water.
Like why that just immediately make
sharks go, oh, what the fuck is that?
I'm not bleeding.
I'm swimming just like a fish.
Why are you so God damn
fucking interested in me?
Why are you fucking 20
miles away? Gone? Oh,
I sense a pair of Alabaster
fucking legs in the water.
I think I'm gonna go over here and take
a bite out of them, see how they taste,
and then spin back around again.
And if I liked the way taste,
I'm going to come back and kill it.
I just don't understand that.
I could see if you were dead,
you know?
And then you know, they're like
the garbage disposals of the ocean.
They come by and they fucking eat you.
But if I'm totally fine,
what is their fucking problem?
It's plenty of fish in the sea,
right? Why you got to come at me?
What am I doing? I'm treading water.
I know I don't belong here. I, it's just,
they're fucking annoying. Another
thing and another thing, oh shit.
I'm on a fucking Roman. A little fucking
rant here. Um, which I'm not, by the way,
I hate everything is
defined as a fucking rant.
Okay.
You know, he had, he,
everything's a fucking rent.
Everything's awkward
or it's a fucking rant.
It isn't a rant is to me is absolutely,
you've completely lost your shit.
You're screaming.
There's fucking Goddamn foam
at the corner of your mouth.
That's a fucking rant.
Yeah.
Going on some little clever little
fucking 45 second run is not a rant.
All right. Yo, dumb cunts on the Internet.
Can we clear that up and can we also clear
up that the comic does not heckle the
crowd? I know I've brought
this up, but it's becoming,
people keep saying that I loved when
you heckled the crowd. No, I'm on stage.
Okay.
When you're giving the performance,
you can't heckle the crowd.
Okay?
Heckled. A heckler is someone
who disrupts a performance.
If you're the guy on stage,
am I disrupting the crowds performance?
You're not given one.
Sorry.
Um,
yeah.
It's fucking shark week on
the discovery channel and a,
I don't know if anybody who works at
Discovery Channel listens to this podcast.
All right? But you guys are so
fucking irresponsible over there.
Okay? You do all this bullshit
when you talk about sharks,
about how fucking horribly
they're misunderstood, you know?
Okay.
And the beauty of,
of the species and all this type of stuff.
But you always sell it with that
jaws vibe, you know what I mean?
It's like, it's literally,
it's like fish fucking racism.
Okay.
Like the way that they show sharks on
the discovery channel is the way they
showed black people in the
news when I was growing up,
they did everything but
play the jaws music, um,
back in the day and this still
doing it to sharks. All right?
And I want to know where all the African
Americans, when it comes to this shit,
you know,
why don't,
why don't you have fucking reach out and
have a little bit of fucking empathy?
You can't see, you can't
see the parallel, uh, the,
the fucking cross pollinization
whenever the fuck he call it.
I don't what I'm saying.
All I'm saying is I fucking hate the
way they do that where they sit there
and they, they, uh, they make it,
they make the shark out to be like,
yeah,
it's beyond instinct what it's doing.
Like it's sitting there
rubbing its fins together,
thinking about fucking sinners
there stuff to do. Okay,
it's hungry.
Just get something to eat. You're a
dumb fuck. You're in the ocean, right?
I still don't get why.
If I'm just fucking treading water,
why do you have to come over and take
a bite out of my leg? Leave me low.
I fucking hate it. And I gotta
tell you something. When I was,
I was sitting there waiting
for that water taxi,
just looking into that
fucking black water, you know,
you can't see,
you can't even see below the surface.
I said to Nicole,
you couldn't pay me $1 million to
jump in that fucking water right now.
Right there. And immediately jumped,
jump right back out. I wouldn't do it.
And she goes, you know,
you're an asshole. She goes,
I'm going to go to fucking jump in it
just to show you how ridiculous should be.
She goes, there's no shark in there.
And I was like, you know what?
Or maybe there is,
did you see that fucking those people
fishing off their back porch that caught
that fish and all of a sudden
a shark came out of nowhere.
The F I, I just, I fucking hate the ocean.
So anyways,
so what,
we're on this fucking boat and we're
going by all these God damn ma,
all these giant fucking yachts,
like $50 million boats
parked out in the harbor.
And I just really
realized like that whole,
like the level of wealth
that is out there,
a $50 million boat, a boat, a hobby,
something you just got sitting in the
fucking Harvard that maybe you're going to
take out once or twice in a month was
$50 million. Give me a fucking break.
I mean,
if I had,
if I had a $50 million boat,
there's no fucking way I
wouldn't be selling drugs.
I would just do it because
it would be so God damn easy.
I would just get a brick of fucking
cocaine and I would just fucking put it on
my boat and I would just drive up the
Goddamn coast and I drop it off to
somebody.
I get some money and then I would make
a payment on the boat and now wait and I
got to clean the money that Jesus
say, I get caught. All right,
strike that.
I will be the guy driving.
I wouldn't drive the boat because I'm
afraid of the ocean. You know what?
Fuck yachts. Okay, let's get a little
fucking advertising here for the week.
Um, what do we got here? Where is it?
What did I do with it?
All right, here we go.
Advertisement number one. Um, all right.
Mandatory intro. Why do
I always do that? Um,
okay.
Hey,
you've probably heard about legal zoom.com
but now I'm telling you about them,
so you got to check them out. These
guys are great. Um, all right.
If you've been wanting,
if I'm waiting for the perfect time to
start your dream business, it's right now.
Incorporate Your Business or form an
llc@legalzoom.com starting at just 99
bucks. I paid 1500. I paid 1500.
You can do it for 99 bucks. And
if you have a family, guess what?
You need to make sure they're protected.
You can protect your family and assets
with legal zoom with a legal zoom will
for just $69.
Look at this setting your whole life up.
You're still under 200 bucks
here in the past 12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used
legal zoom for Llcs, wills, trusts,
trademarks.
Come up with an invention.
You don't want somebody to steal
it or when they do steal it,
you want to be able to sue
them and then come, you know,
settle out of court and then you get a
yacht and then you're doing your thing.
You can even trademarks and more,
they've save hundreds,
even thousands of dollars versus
going to a traditional lawyer.
Legal zooms online process guides you
step by step and you get total customers
more support. It couldn't be much
easier if they even have attorneys,
an attorney to help you if you need
to get through their legal plants. Um,
Start Your Business and protect
your family today@legalzoom.com.
You also get a special discount
from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter burpee.
You are,
are in the referral box at
checkout for more savings.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm and self
help services are provided at your,
uh, your direction. There you go. All
right. That was painless wasn't it?
Um, you don't actually have
to get a will done and I have,
I have been putting that off because
I'm superstitious when it comes to that.
I feel like if I start to write a will,
that means I'm saying to the universe
like, all right, tapping out,
I've had enough. But, um, I'm actually,
I got inspired to do it.
Okay.
Uh,
this past week a,
a one of my relatives passed
away unfortunately, and um,
he had to go to the funeral,
but this person had it all worked
out right down to their outro song
and I underrated picking
the music for your funeral.
As Morbid as that is, you got to
realize we're all going to go someday.
And uh, this funeral
was, was fucking awesome.
It was,
it was a celebration of a life and
there was way more laughing than crying.
And I think a lot of that
had to do with the music.
Fucking outro, music, wheeling
out of the Church, uh,
when the saints go marching in was this
person's favorite song. And it was,
it was, it was the shit. And I really
got inspired. I was sitting there going,
what the hell would I, what?
What's, it seems like, you know,
old people's like that
their music is appropriate.
It's such great music that it's
appropriate for any situation.
And I'm really trying to think like,
of the music that I listened to,
you know, all that heavy metal and
fuck and Zeppelin and ac DC. I mean,
I can't have any ACDC
plane as I'm wheeled out.
Half of that's about the devil and going
to hell. I don't to put that out there.
You didn't have those three things from
ghost come up or you remember that shit
and drag me down. Um, but I,
I'm telling you underrated. So I want
to know from you guys. All right,
when you kick the bucket, tell me about
how you're going to do your funeral.
How would you like it to be done?
And,
uh,
yeah. Outro music and all that type
of shit. What are you gonna do?
Are you going to be going in the box?
You're going to get cremated.
This is fucked up,
huh?
You got to make these decisions
and if you need to make a well,
go to legal zoom.com Bam. There you
go. In and out right there. All right.
What else happened this week
in the world of sports? Uh,
Dwight Howard went to the
Lakers and absolute shocker,
absolute shocker that yet another guy
who couldn't win a championship somewhere
else is now going to go pile on
with the Lakers. It's ridiculous.
It's,
they have literally become the New York
Yankees of the NBA every fucking year
they do this and I want Koby Bryant
to start getting some shit for this.
If you're going to give fucking
Lebron James Shit for pilot,
for leaving Cleveland and pile on
piling on in Miami than God dammit.
Coby has had people fucking coming to
him for his entire Goddamn career 15
fucking years in a row and they got the
nerve to sit there and compare this guy
to Jordan.
Look at the fucking teams.
This guy he's been on and go back and
look at those Chicago Bulls teams and I
want to, I want you to start telling
me Dennis Rodman is the only fucking
like free agent that I can really
remember that they signed. All right,
and he was,
it was one fucking guy.
Coby gets two, three guys every
year. Oh, it's ridiculous.
It's absolutely ridiculous.
I'm telling you as a crabby old man,
these are not your father's championships.
These are not championship teams.
These,
there's no difference between these
championship teams and that rich kid whose
first car is like a fucking Goddamn
Maserati because his dad is rich.
All right.
You know,
it's so fucked up about these teams
and I include the 2008 Celtics in this.
That was a, that was a bought
and paid for championship.
I know they put the work in. I know all
of that, but it's not the fucking same.
This is the funny thing about these pile
on teams is I remember as a kid when
you'd be out outside at recess and
they'd say, we'd start picking teams.
If they got too lopsided, kids
would be, oh wait a minute,
that's not fair.
They would,
people flip out and they'd break up the
teams and you balance it out where I was
from there, it was called mk teams. I
don't even know where that came from.
The TCIS schmuck teams, these teams
are smug, which meant it was bullshit.
You had Shaq and Kobe and
all these fucking guys are
one team was going to be a
goddamn bloodbath. All right. And even
it's like second and third graders,
we understood how fucking pointless it
was to then go out and play the game.
If you had all the most talented
people on one fucking team, right?
So we broke it up and we would,
we would have it evened out and we'd
have a great game during fucking recess.
Now,
if we can understand that,
why can't full grown adults understand
that in these leaks and professional
leagues, why can't they understand that?
All right? But if that's the way it is,
I accept it.
I accept these pile on championships,
but I want them to be called that.
All right.
The same way they had the dead
ball and then the live ball era,
these fucking Laker championships, Celtics
championships, Miami championships,
these are not the same
as the ones in the 80s,
right through the fucking Chicago Bulls.
I would even say the Spurs,
you know the David Robinson,
uh, Tim Duncan ones like,
I don't want to hear it.
Don't fucking be talking about don't
bring up Larry and magic and all these
other guys with the guys at today.
It's different. Okay. Because
just imagine back in the day of bird
magic just piled on and got on the same
fucking team.
Like why is that enjoyable?
I gotta be honest with you. That first
Dream Team, I didn't even watch it.
I didn't want to watch fucking Larry Bird,
magic Johnson,
a key Malaysia one,
Charles Barkley go play Rwanda.
You know what I mean? What am I
going to do next? What and then what?
Watch me go play a game of wiffle
ball with some fucking second graders.
Like I don't understand what,
where, what is the thrill in that?
And if you're in one of those cities and
you're getting all these guys and you
fucking sites and you don't give a shit,
um,
that's cause you don't understand.
You don't eat,
you don't even understand sports you and
you're the same kind of person that I
bet I bet cannot be swayed in an argument.
Even if somebody makes
a good fucking point.
Cause all you want to do is be right.
You just want to win like that.
Fox News kind of,
uh,
like debating style where it's all good.
If you agree with me and
if you don't agree with me,
I'm just going to yell at you and cut
out your mic and that's going to be the
fucking debate. Um, it sucks. Okay.
So now I'm down to two sports,
no football and hockey
because you can't do that.
And either one of those sports
because they have a hard cap.
I know people say in baseball they have
a hard cap yet will they have a loophole
that you can drive a $200 million
team through call the luxury tax.
You can just basically pay it off
and you can go out and buy everybody
on the fucking planet. So I dunno.
Yeah,
I dunno. I got to find some
different sports to take place of,
of Hoop and fucking baseball cause I'm
done with both of those sports until they,
they, they just fucking, you know, help.
I don't know. It's just fucking stupid.
You know what it is about those teams?
Why I don't respect them?
Because it takes more money than brains.
Cells to put those fucking teams together.
Back in the day you need a brain cells.
You had to like break down.
People get to see stuff before other
people saw it. Now you just go, hey,
we need a center. Who's the best guy
available? What's he being offered?
Offer him 10 million more. Next
problem. I could fucking do that.
Bite a bottomless pit of cash.
That's fucking, it's depressing.
It's depressing.
So,
okay.
I Dunno, but I still don't
think the Lakers have the
coach. I know God damn well.
Colby Bryant doesn't fucking respect them.
You know when you're doing great in the
game and the coach goes to high five you
and you completely ignore him.
I would say that that's a complete
lack of respect. What do you think?
Am I crazy to think that?
Am I crazy?
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo
Doo. All right, he voice everybody.
Here we go is another way to start up.
If you're going to start up your business,
I'm slowly getting advertising here.
That subtly is going to get you
out of your cubicle. All right.
He voice your mobile phone at work.
Uh,
one of the great he voice features
is call recording. It's easy to use.
All you have to do is press star two
to start a stop recordings during any
incoming or outgoing call. Um,
basically what he voice is,
is you have these, what do they call
them? Viral, viral, uh, phone numbers.
You could basically with your cell
phone get, you know, like three,
four other phone numbers and it just
will ring to your own damn phone.
No one has to know what
your real phone number is.
It's a great way to be at
work and actually have a
private business going on so
you can just,
you know,
rather than having to save up your
trinkets that you cubicle job.
Okay,
you don't want to have to start from
square one to start your new business.
You can be,
you can actually be sitting in your
cubicle taking business calls for your own
business without those bosses
known about it. It's phenomenal.
Um, anyways, the file
is then saved as an MP,
uh,
on a wave file and you can store it on
your computer to refer back to later at a
later date if need be. Um, all
right. Call recording from eve.
Voice is perfect for doctors,
lawyers, real estate agents,
hiring managers or any
professional discussing contracts.
If it's even great,
if you just don't have a pen handy or
you're in the car driving and can't write
something down.
Other eve voice features include call
forwarding music on hold voicemail to text
toll free numbers and 1-800-NUMBERS
for free. Six months trial.
Go to ww.
Okay.
Dot e voice.com/bill burr or go to the
banner on my podcast page at [inaudible]
dot com. Um, yeah, it's phenomenal.
If you can make you have conference
calls with up to 90 people,
it's just a great,
and they actually have like professional
voice actors that will, uh, you know,
give you some little, a fancy
outgoing message, you know,
so it actually sounds like you have an
office when you don't. It's phenomenal.
He voice everybody. Go check it out.
All right, back to the podcast. Um,
okay.
All right. What do we got here? Let's
get it. Let's get on with dilemmas here.
The lemme ish. Okay. Hey Bill,
would you rather have as many gold
medals as Michael Phelps or as many super
bowl rings? Is Joe Montana? Uh,
or do I get to be Joe Montana?
Seeing that and that's that,
that little odd dilemma.
I don't know if I'm Joe Montana,
if I'm going to have as
many rings as Joe Montana,
I want to be Joe Montana or Jerry Rice.
I want to be somebody that they remember.
I don't want to be the
fucking left tackle, you know,
per protecting the blindside or whatever
the fuck's going on there. Right.
I don't wanna be that guy.
I want to be suddenly that
somebody remembers Ronnie
Lott or be Michael Phelps.
MMM.
That's a good one because you know what
sucks about being Michael Phelps is like,
he's kind of done at 24.
You know,
he's gonna come back at 28
and not quite be as fast.
Those sports where you just
finished at 24 like tennis.
Um,
I dunno
Michael Phelps,
but football's such a man's sport,
but you can't walk when you're 40.
Although I saw Joe Montana in a,
in a, in a restaurant and
you still look great. Uh,
fuck debt. I'd rather win super bowls.
I'd rather win super bowls. There you go.
All right,
dear is billion.
I am friends with a lot of people
who have a lot of delusional hobbies
throughout the last couple of years. I've
had to attend their shitty band shows,
the shows for this shitty bands to make
that a little more clearer or go to
their place.
I've even been asked to donate money for
the cost of making a CD and solicited
to donate to a buddy short
film so he can make it. Well,
it sounds like you have a lot
of motivated friends here.
What do you [inaudible] are you
the Heda? Maybe he's right. Let's,
let's read the rest of this before
I judge them. I repeat a short film.
Well,
I made a short film with the Teen Idols
Sensation Joe to Rosa and Robert Kelly
who's on a new fucking TV show called
the Bronx crew or something like that on
Fx. Like no joke. He's like the lead.
Um,
and a god Damn TV show Bob,
Huh? Yeah. Great. It is to see that form.
I've watched that man
for 20 years on stand up.
They would stand up doing plays and all
that type of shit and he hung in there
and he kept swinging and he put his
fucking head down a bang. Look at that.
It's fucking phenomenal. Anyways, all
all of this wouldn't be so bad. Yeah.
We made a short film of gotten
to the Tribeca film festival.
You know Joe to Rosa is now on his
way to having a little burgeoning,
like a directing career. All
right. Don't knock a short film,
so are you have no idea where
this could go. Anyways, he goes,
all of this wouldn't be so bad if all
of their stupid hobby hobbies didn't
always end up costing me at least 40
bucks from donations to cover charges at
the Gig they're playing,
etc. The most recent one is a friend's
Improv class showcase where I get to
watch a bunch of amateurs put on a show
with a two drink minimum and ticket
costs. Exactly what I want
to do with my free time. Now,
my question is,
can I just start a blanket policy of
not going to any more of these and not
donating without coming
off like a complete Dick.
I want to make the Improv
show my last event.
Then never support the hobbies of my
untalented friends that constantly pissed
my money away.
To put it bluntly,
my friends events aren't exactly the
same as you going to support Dane Cook in
the producers. He probably had
the decency to comp your ticket.
Yeah.
And any help is greatly appreciated.
We'll do it.
But you have to understand is that Dane
didn't start off doing starring in the
producers at the Hollywood bowl.
We did open mikes and shitty restaurants
and we had to learn how to do stand up.
Look, if you're always having to go to
these things, I understand that, but um,
you know,
you know something, I wouldn't want you
to come to my show if I was starting out.
You just seem really like
annoyed by the whole thing.
You're going to have a negative vibe
and I just would feel like I would be on
stage as I'm trying to
learn how to do standup.
And I would look out at you and you would
have like your eyebrows up like, Gee,
you know,
like think he'd done yet.
Rarely you thought that was funny. You
know, you wouldn't even be smiling.
You just be staring at me like, was that
the last one? Can I go now? Can I leave?
Um, so it sounds to me like
you need a hobby. All right?
You need more of a social life and a
then you wouldn't have time to go to all
your friends.
MMM.
I Dunno. Plays and all this. I find it
weird that you don't do any of this shit.
You know that you have people
making short films, you know,
people in bands and you know,
people in Improv classes.
You kind of spanning the
performance, uh, rainbow there yet.
Do you perform?
Do you want to perform?
Why aren't you a performer?
If you hang out with all these performers,
I don't understand what's
going on with you, sir.
Did you go to some high school for the
gifted and the time you realize that you
weren't gifted,
it was too late and you just stayed there.
So now you're going to school with all
these future Fiona apples and all that
type of shit,
and you're going to watch them play an
acoustic set at the corner of some subway
franchise and you've had it. I don't know
what it is served, but you know what?
Be Your own God. Damn
man. Just say, listen,
I don't fucking want to go to
any a shit anymore. All right?
I don't have the money or the time.
I would rather see the completed,
call me when you make it
and give me a free ticket.
And then you can be the guy when
they do the, uh, the early days,
you'll be that guy.
You know,
you'll be one of those documentaries
where nobody from the band.
That's always like a major red flag
when they're doing a documentary on a
person,
like an actor or a band or an athlete,
and that person,
the person,
the subject isn't in the documentary
and neither are any of the person's
immediate friends. And then they always
go to a guy like this guy, like, Yay,
I used to fuck in a,
he's to see him go on in front of
fucking two people up, put the,
you'll end up being that guy, you
know. Well, this is the thing, surf.
Any of those people make it,
you better not be that Douche who said,
I always believed in you because you
don't believe in these people on any
fucking level. So, uh,
I would start, I would just fucking
make sure you had other plants.
That's the easiest way to,
if you want to be nice and not hurt
their feelings or you could just fucking
come right out with it and just be like,
listen, I've seen you improv before.
Um,
I'm going to wait six months in late.
Maybe you'll get much better at it and
it'll be entertaining for me. Okay,
I'm going to go to a bar
and go hit on a girl.
That's how I want to Improv because I
don't know what I'm going to say either.
Okay. I'll throw it a subject. Me fucking
that girl over there. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'm out about that. All
right, next one bill.
Should I have kids?
How the fuck he supposed to know
if you should have kids or not?
Neither my wife nor I have strong feelings
either way and we are getting to that
age where it stops making sense. So we
need to make a decision and live with it.
Um, yeah. If you're not
feeling it, don't do it.
This plenty of fucking kids is plenty
kids to go out and adopt. You know?
If you realize later that, oh,
maybe I wanted a kid. Well what age?
What am I kid Ben? If I had
one, probably about eight. Yeah,
let me get an eight year old.
Let me get it out and let me get to
eight year olds in a fucking seven and
throwing the 11 here we go. Then you
have a fucking big Brady bunch family.
There's plenty of kids out there
that need to be adopted and uh,
there's too many fucking people on the
planet and we're running out of natural
resources. And, uh,
my belief is that the population problem
is going to be handled like a fucking
term paper.
You know,
the same way we handled y two
k at the last fucking second.
And when you do shit at
the last fucking second,
it's going to be a rash
fucking quick decisions,
which means there's going to be some
sort of final solution going on.
I really believe that we are
rapidly headed towards that.
You know, if they don't, I mean,
we have 7 billion people on the planet
and there's no politician going, hey,
you know,
why don't you just fucking
not have kids for a minute?
Or if you're not really feeling it or
we'll give you some money not to have kids
is fucking insane.
I Dunno.
We'll run it on a chicken
and fucking soup. Uh,
that didn't even make sense.
Alright, cheating. Hey Bill.
Okay.
Um, word on the street is,
you're the male version of Oprah,
so hear me out. You know what? That's
actually insulting to Oprah. All right.
Um,
I've got this lady I'm fooling around
with now and then she has a boyfriend but
doesn't seem to mind hooking up
with me when I asked her to. Yeah.
That chick's of fucking
nightmare, dude. I am.
Before we even go [inaudible] you're not
going to have a relationship with her.
Yeah.
If she cheats on so much,
she'll end up cheating on you and every
time you fuck her or you're risking one
of these times at boyfriend's going to
find out and he might show up with a tire
iron and a, you know,
remodel your face. Anyways,
when we met,
she never wants to go further than second
base saying that would be cheating.
Um,
last night I went to her house
to pick her up for a party. Dude,
there's not another woman out there
that you could pick up for a party.
What are you doing, dude? Do
you want to be that guide?
You want to be the guy who fucking plays
with the tits is some fucking broad
that has a boyfriend
come on.
Ah,
there's nothing makes a guy
weaker than a fucking easy pussy.
Easy Pussy.
His brought down more goddamn men,
the layup piece of ass.
Um,
because we're lazy anyways, before we
made it. And when I say we're lazy,
I mean human beings in general.
All right ladies,
before you fucking pat yourself on the
back and make your tits Schick. Um,
uh, last night I went to her house
to pick her up for a party. Uh,
before we made it in the, in the
car, I had her up against my car.
We were making out like war.
World War Two ended.
I then suggested suggestively
opened the door to the back seat,
but instead of entering,
she asked me if I loved her or
if I just wanted sex. Yeah. Dude,
this girl is crazy. I neither confirmed
nor denied either of those questions.
Yeah, that's stupid. That's a
great lie. That's great. All right.
This is just straight across the,
this is a linear story begins with deceit,
goes into the seat and it's
going to end with it. Um,
I just went back to kissing her.
Okay.
After she got drunk at the party.
Oh Jesus.
That and you're sitting there
like a fucking wolf waiting
for it to get hammered.
Uh,
we talked again and she said she was
willing to dump her boyfriend and have sex
with me if I just told her that I love her
and want to be with her.
Yeah.
I actually don't,
but I really want to bang this chick.
I was thinking about just saying I love
her and then dumping her after we banked.
But I guess that would be kind of a dick
move. Yeah, it would be, but I got it.
We got it. Everybody's got to take
responsibility for their actions.
This fucking woman is setting herself
up for this shit. My Morris comp,
my moral compass has no needle
needle bill. Help me out.
Greetings from Belgium.
Okay.
Uh,
I hope you were able to read that fluently
as you always still look at this guy
fucking sarcastic in a second language.
Um,
yeah. Listen, uh, you know,
do you really want to be this guy that's,
if you believe in Karma,
that's a really bad thing to do.
All right.
You're being lazy. Okay? This
girl's obviously damaged.
There's something wrong with her.
And um,
if you do what you're thinking of doing,
just so you can bang her,
you're really going to devastate her.
And Is it worth devastating?
Another human being just to get just
the f two FEC it Banger is one for you.
This is classic.
All right?
This is not my advice.
This is standard advice,
okay?
Here's the deal.
Why don't you rub one out to her
and afterwards immediately think,
do I really think about what you're doing
and the way you're going to be getting
this girl and ask yourself if you
really want to do it all right,
okay.
And then act accordingly. And
if you still want to do it, um,
please don't ever get
a job in a corporation
because you will move up that ladder in
20 seconds. Oh my God, he's a sociopath.
He has no feelings. He doesn't care about
people. Let's give them a corner office.
MMM, okay. X Porn Star or something.
X Porn is all it says.
Dear Bill,
I'm a 22 year old lady seeking some
valuable male insight and perspective.
I've been dating my boyfriend for
over a year now and everything's been
incredible. Well, congratulations.
I have no feeling that this is going
to go in a different direction.
Anyways, we felt like soulmates
and didn't like to be a part.
However, all of a sudden it became very
distant towards me. I tried to ignore it,
justifying it with some personal issue
he was dealing with. Little did I know.
Those personal issues also
involved me and his ex, o g.
G feeling a horribly familiar sense,
feeling a horribly familiar sense.
Infidelity,
Deja Vu.
I think you skipped a word in there.
I did something awful I could
kick myself in the face for,
I looked through his laptop.
I know it's a really disbelief
despicably Dick thing to do,
but I needed some strand of truth.
Even if it would break my heart.
I got to tell you something.
If he was being a good guy
and you did that, you know,
that's a piece of shit thing to do
and the fact that he was giving you the,
I'm cheating on you vibe and you still
felt like a piece of shit by going
through his emails. The, you're a good
person, you're being too hard on yourself.
Um, what he's supposed to
be, you know that person,
a good fellows whose content to be a jerk.
What am I supposed to say that
my boyfriend cheats on me. See,
I switched it up for you.
Anyways,
I read an email he wrote to
his ex girlfriend expressing
his lament about being
with the wrong person. Well, there
you go. It's over game set and match.
It went up and went on about how amazing
she was and how any other girl me would
only ever be second best.
This prompted me to look
through his photos and I
found some recently opened but
only nude pictures of her.
This hit me really hard
because unlike regular porn,
nude pictures of xs holds something
sentimental value I don't appreciate or
think it's appropriate. Well that's
about as lightly as you can put it.
Um,
yeah,
you should definitely not appreciate
that he actually knows that woman and
banged her.
Uh,
putting myself in this conundrum.
I couldn't bring this sensitive topic up
without admitting I invaded his private
invading his privacy.
Although my hunch was right.
I know I was wrong and looking
through his personal shit,
but is it wrong of him to still
masturbate to naked pictures of his ex?
Even after he reassured
me he had deleted them?
How would I go about talking to him about
this? Or is this situation better left?
Undiscussed now that we are
on better or closer terms,
I appreciate any piece of advice
or opinion greatly. So, uh,
go fuck yourself. Question Mark. Uh,
I,
you know,
I wa I can't even fucking answer this.
What he gave you the vibe. Like he
was fucking around on you and he is,
he is fucking around on you. And that
whole thing about that. Your, your,
your second best.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Fucked that. Break up with
the guy. All right. You know,
what's your biggest problem is,
sweetheart, is you are a sweetheart.
And this guy is at the
very least a confused,
uh, fight. He's a fucking dirt bag. He's
not being honest with you, okay? Now,
this is the thing about if
you're a sweetheart and life,
male or female,
uh,
pieces of Shit gravitate towards you.
They need a sweetheart in their life to
put up with their piece of shit behavior.
So what you have to learn to do that.
If you are a sweetheart via big
hearted person, you have to be guarded,
all right?
And you have to make somebody's earned
the fact that you're a sweetheart,
you just don't give it away.
Yeah.
All right? Cause when you just given
it away and you fucking Nice Day,
how are you? I just met you. Will you
help me move? Okay? That's a nice,
you gonna get,
you're gonna get taken advantage of.
So this guy has taken advantage of you.
Fuck this guy. Break up with them, okay?
Okay.
If he wasn't such a fucking
shifty piece of shit,
you wouldn't have to
done that piece of shit.
Then he basically gave you grounds for
a warrant to go search through his shit.
All right. And you were right. Okay.
Although you didn't get a warrant,
you kind of did it like the rogue cop who
now is the throw his badge on the desk
yet still go out and solve the fucking
crime, like all those 80 cop buddy movies.
But you are right. You
deserve better. Fuck this guy.
All right.
Yeah,
you should break up with them even
though it's going to hurt. Um, all right.
So you know what? I think that that's
going to be the podcast for this week.
A little under an hour. I know that's
shorter than what you're used to, but, um,
I gotta I gotta upload this and sent
it to my guy to give to you guys that
you're now listening to.
And by the way, I was on,
did you guys check out breaking bad?
I was on breaking bad last week.
I'll last night and everything. I
didn't get a chance to watch it. Um,
but uh, it's always weird watching
yourself anyways, but I love that show.
So I have to, uh, I'm
actually two episodes behind,
but, uh, I peeked at my Twitter and I got
nothing but positive things. Thank God.
Thank God. So I appreciate everybody's
saying that cause you know,
this is acting stuff is new to me.
All right?
So all the compliments you gave me really
makes up for the fact that you break
my balls about my podcast every week.
So thank you to anybody
who wrote something nice on
Twitter that really made me
feel good and uh,
and go fuck yourself to all the people
who are now going to write mean shit
because it's funny, which it is,
but I don't care. Are the, the,
the honest reviews already came in. So
have at it, have a good time trashing me.
I don't give a fuck. Um, that's the
podcast for this week, by the way.
I want to be down
Nantucket Wednesday night.
I have a show Wednesday
night, uh, down in Nantucket.
There's still tickets left.
It's going to be a great show
where I basically perform to a,
like fishermen in the fucking Illuminati.
He's going to be a really
interesting mix of people and uh,
I'm really excited to go down there.
Beautiful,
beautiful island off the
coast of Massachusetts.
And what else do you guys want to hear
some of my other upcoming dates before I
bring this mercifully to
an end? Uh, what do I got?
Oh Jesus. Bill, why don't you have things
ready? Why don't you have things ready?
Um,
I'm going to be at the Orlando Improv
beginning on September 7th and then on the
eighth and on the ninth.
I've never been there before
and I got Carolines on Broadway,
New York City rescheduled that
from the one that I moved in July.
It's going to be September 20th,
21st 22nd and 23rd.
Um, and that's it. Other than a,
what do we got here? Oh Jesus.
Hang in there for a second.
I got one other thing that I want
to tell you about and that would be,
oh, here it is. Here it is. The
real quick amazon.com people.
If you want to support this podcast
and the wounded warriors project,
just go on to the podcast page on
billboard.com. Click on the banner ad,
the Amazon banner ad and then
go to Amazon and buy something.
You don't have to do anything else when
she gets to Amazon. If you buy something,
Amazon kicks me a little bit of money
and I throw 10% to the wounded warrior
project and game fly.com.
Um,
anyways,
uh,
thanks for clicking the game flight
banners for your free to two desk two week
free trial over 40 people
did that last month.
So thank you very much for that and
hopefully you, you enjoyed the service,
you enjoyed your 8,000 games that
you could try for two free weeks.
If you want to be part of
those people who are doing it,
having a great time playing video games
instead of paying attention to their
significant others. Um, you
want a free two week trial.
You can go to game fly.com/burr or the
banner ad on my podcast page for your
free trial free trial and enjoy all the,
all the video games you can play.
That's it. You guys have a
great week. Go fuck yourselves.
Don't take any shit and
I'll talk to you next week.