Hey,
what's going on?
Is Bill Burns time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
July 11th, 2016 what's going on now? Why?
Yeah,
I'm recording this 6:01 PM on Sunday.
July 10th.
Still fucking light as hell out even
though it's getting Jackie by the day.
Um, I'm in a great mood. Uh,
I think my Sciatica is Phi Psi.
I think it finally went away. Um, like 90,
95% of it went away.
Uh,
that Mizzou said I was seeing who
was fucking amazing winter again.
She beat the shit out of me.
Um,
and show me this stretch from my
leg. Brie. I just lay on the floor.
I put my leg up against the door jam and
it's been working fucking wonders for
me. Um, and I really feel like I'm
going to see her again next week.
I just keep doing that stretch.
Do all these other stretches.
She was telling me all of
this shit. I, you know,
I need to strengthen my obliques cause
it's putting stress on my lower back,
the whole fucking thing.
My back feels amazing.
And what's so great is my back
has been fucked up for 30 years.
You know, I did a podcast this
week, not trying to drop any names,
but stone cold Steve Austin,
the stone cold.
And that's the bottom line.
Cause stone cold said. So I
did his podcast. He's like,
well we talked for like
two and a half hours. Um,
he's going to turn it into I think
a part one and a part two. And um,
I was talking to him on that podcast,
how the first time I threw out my back,
the two times, three times in my
childhood, I throw out my back.
Two of the times where's was
doing wrestling moves, right?
One was the figure four leg lock,
which I've told you before,
that's the first time I threw up
my lower back. Right. And then, uh,
try to imitate a Gary Valentine. His
kid was trying to show me how to do it.
He did it and everybody went
nuts and he wouldn't fuck it,
let me out of it because all the fourth
graders started flipping out like it was
the WWF.
Right.
And then when I was like in seventh or
eighth grade or maybe the beginning of
high school, I, uh, I tried to pick
my little brother up over my head,
like Tony Atlas, his finish
and move. And I swear to God,
like three quarters of the way up
my spine, it felt like it folded.
And I just had it kind of dropped.
My brother dropped them
down on the fucking ground.
Fortunately there was wall to wall carpet
in cause it was leftover from the 70s
there. Um, but anyways, uh,
yeah,
so my back has been fucked and then I
was playing just pickup football and I
fucked up my lower back.
And for the last 30 years,
if I ever fell asleep laying
on my stomach, like a,
I woke up in unbelievable pain and had
to literally like just slide down the
side of the bed,
get on my back and just start doing
stretches for a half an hour to get it
undone. And uh, that has gone away.
And the cyanic things going away. And I
guess I had no fucking idea. I thought,
you know, like I stretch,
you know what I mean?
I get a massage and wants to be couple
of years. I thought I was all right.
But I guess all the way down the rights,
I probably shouldn't do this.
If I lose my health insurance,
they'll just have to just splice
together all my podcasts to get all my
preexisting conditions.
Um,
that muscle that runs down your entire
right side of that whole thing was
spasming.
And then like half of it on the left side,
the muscles in my fucking
left thigh and left calf dude,
she fucking slammed her elbow into the
back of my fucking leg and was bringing
it up. It literally felt like my
leg was going to fucking explode.
Um, but, uh, but it's, it's actually,
it's been way better in like today.
I just, I dunno, it just kinda felt so
everything kind of like freed up and, uh,
I'm just gonna keep going to these people
and I'm going to try to get my back is,
I had no idea how fucked up it was. I'm
site and all these people going to do it.
You know, you gotta go get an
just go to a doctor, you know,
these chiropractors that there's these
[inaudible] or that just go to a doctor,
get a cortisone shot and fucking get an
operation. And I was like, fuck that.
The last place she ever want to get an
operation on as your fucking back. Um,
as far as I've seen, like you remember
when they were operating on Bobby,
yours knees and they just was scooping
shit out. Next thing you know,
he was like bone to bone at like
27 years old. Um, I feel like,
you know, as far as they've come
with knee surgery, back surgery,
they're still in those Bobby your
years and I just don't want to risk it.
I would never do that.
So I'm happy that I was able to do it
in a noninvasive way and it's literally
affected my mood and like a positive way.
So I'm so psyched about that. But, um,
as I mentioned before,
um,
Stone Cold Steve Austin's podcast, he's
got a podcast, and I could not believe,
I don't want to ruin anything
that we talked to her,
but I could not believe
the similarities of, uh,
wrestling to stand up as far
as listening to the crowd.
You know,
not getting them all the
way to high before you're
going to get off and building
up your time. Like that's a big
thing when you're, you're like a,
a comedian starting out,
like you're doing 10 minutes sets and
then one night somebody tells you to do 15
and x extra five minutes.
Doesn't sound like a lot,
but that's like you coming up
with another 50% more of your act.
You know, there's a math workout.
All right? In that, I mean,
the five minutes is a lot of fucking time.
And he was the same thing he would do.
He would wrestle for like
eight fucking minutes.
And then one day he moves up and they
go, all right, give us 20 minutes.
He's thinking, what the fuck am I going
to? Am I going to do this for 20 minutes?
Um, but of course, you know, we don't
get the shit kicked out of us, but, um,
I will definitely a retweet when
that thing is going to be on.
I had a great time with him and he in the,
in the best way possible.
He is exactly like when you see him,
he's just completely no
bullshit and all that. And uh,
he wants to learn how to fly a helicopter.
So we talked about that.
We just went on and on and on
and fucking on it. We just,
it was just fucking awesome.
A great guy and uh,
definitely was beyond cool that
I got to meet that guy. So I'll,
I'll definitely tweet that when
that shit is coming out. So anyways,
let's get on with my, uh, my
sports weekend here. I, um,
I had a crazy weekend.
I Saturday night say,
uh, I went, um,
by watch the UFC first of all and um,
you know, I'm not going to blame
the UFC for that one. You know,
they kept hyping UFC 200 and that was
supposed to be fucking unbelievable and
all their great susposed to come back.
And then what happened? You know,
God and my grandmother,
they had that big issue where he fucking
loses and then he doesn't want to do
some sort of Promo. I don't pay attention
to the soap opera, the shit, right?
Ronda Rousey's still not fighting and you
know that they felt that those two are
going to be on that card. So
they're above, both are on the car.
And then some guy named Joe something
or rather tested positive for some shit.
So you know,
there was scrambling for
bodies and I'm fucking is,
oh my God. Am I going to say his name
is an Anderson Silva? Is that his name?
How can you fucking watch somebody so
many fucking times? It just, I just know,
I never know the names. I just
fucking sit down and I'm like, oh,
that's the guy who
crawls in like a spider.
He's going to kick the
fuck out of this guy. Um,
he, uh, you know,
he was supposed to be sitting in the
crowd and neck three and three days later
he's in the octagon. It was like
the whole Vinnie test of Verde Shit.
We're back in the day, you know,
Vinny tested where he's like,
he was sitting on his couch watching
the game or he's like in the backyard,
you know,
putting together a fucking horseshoe
pit or some stuff and all of a sudden he
sees under send a plane for
the jets. Yeah. Anderson Silva,
he had to come in and um,
yeah,
fight Daniel Cormier,
Cormier and I, you know,
as much as a fucking douchey UFC
fans were born, um, you know,
cause they wanted to stand up against him.
Anderson Silva,
it's like what the greatest of all time
and had nothing to fucking lose in this
guy earned this title shot that got
taken away from him or whatever the fuck
this big fucking payday.
And if he loses to this guy,
then all of a sudden Anderson's coming
back and he's the next contender in this
guy's ass. The fuck out. Right.
So he did what he had to do.
We just kept taking on the ground.
He stayed on top of them.
You could hear him and his after he won
going, hey listen, I did what I had to do.
You know, you could tell he felt
bad. He wanted to put on a show,
but the guy fucking prepared for months
and months for this other fucking guy
saw the fight of the night
for me obviously I think
in everybody else was the,
uh, was the um, mission to Tate. Uh,
Amanda Nunez. I'm saying all these
fucking names, right? And uh,
Jesus Christ. I mean that, I mean, that's
of course what everybody wants to see.
It's like when people watch racing,
you know,
as much as they want to see wheel
the wheel, they want to see.
So see somebody go careening into the
fucking wall. We want to see a car,
you know, hit a wall at 200 miles an hour.
That's what the fuck they want to see.
And fight fans want to see somebody
get knocked the fuck out. Right.
I'll get the shit kicked out of him.
So I feel like the one thing
that other than the first fight,
whether it was at six foot seven guy,
lot of dad bods for UFC,
you know,
200,
did I say 50 earlier on a fuckup talking
about a lot of dad bods that was like
the dad bod fight card.
Um, granted all of them,
I obviously could kick the fuck out
of a hundred normal people at a time,
but that first fight there
was like dead six foot six,
six foot seven dude,
which is hilarious to me.
You're six foot seven and you gotta
learn mixed martial arts. It's like,
it's not enough. You can step on the
average person like a fucking man.
You're now going to add,
add this whole other level of
fucking craziness, you know?
Um, that first guy, Jesus
Christ, that first guy,
whatever the fuck his name is,
that guy looked like he was in the Bourne
identity and he was like the head bad
guy that you had to beat.
He just came fucking walking
in. He gave that tall dude,
the old right there, Fred,
and he was fucking done. Um,
and the only two guys who were in shape
with those, those, I don't fucking,
I mean I don't know anybody's fucking
name. I have no fucking idea. You know,
this is my deal. I ordered it. I tech any
was anybody else go to tech store. Right.
And you accidentally ordered
it in Spanish. Like the way
the text thing came out,
it says order UFC and then it says,
uh,
no sports event.
And then right after
event was the number one,
and then after done the next
line it said UFC 200 number two,
and then the next line said
Espaniol or something like that.
So you didn't read that,
you just saw events and
then you immediately went
to the second line and you
supposed to press one for English
two was for UFC 200 in espanol.
And I fucked the whole thing
up. So I hadn't, you know,
I had to talk to the fucking
lady to get it, you know,
the whole fucking thing taken off.
But I'll let a lot of dad bods a lot of
fucking dad bods until you got to the
women they came in,
they were like w and other than that
featherweight fight that I can't fucking
remember.
Um,
but I just hate when fucking when it goes
to the ground, everybody fucking boots.
You know what I mean?
It's like this kid,
you have a little respect for
the person who's on their back,
taken forearms to their fucking head.
You Boeing,
because they're not standing up.
I Dunno.
People start chanting,
stand them up,
stand them or whatever the
fuck they was saying. Um,
I dunno.
To me it's a lot scarier to have somebody
on top of you and you can't fucking
move and they're just raining down on
you and they're putting a glove over your
fucking nose and mouth
and you can't breathe.
Like I'd be on the guy fucking kitten.
All claustrophobic.
I would tap out so fucking fast.
Do you remember that?
We remember that UFC fight with that guy
just backed up the whole fucking time.
The whole fight. He just fucking
backed up. That would be me.
And then you'd get me on the ground.
I'd be like, Woo Ellie, just tap out.
I would have to, I, I would say I have
to leave the country after the fight,
but UFC is worldwide. I would have to
like move to mainland China, you know,
not Hong Kong to try to somehow,
and even then somebody gets
some sort of bootleg shit,
whoever is the son of that dude who sat
and stood in front of the tank, you know,
he'd have the fucking balls to get the
UFC feed and then he fights, you know,
walking around with my fucking okay God
damn Whitehead just walking around in
fucking China. They spot me in a
second. Hey, you're that fucking guy.
And had screaming bitch from
UFC fucking whatever. Right.
So I don't know.
I think those fucking people that go
to the UFC got you got a lot of fucking
balls bu in a professional fighter.
Every time I watched the UFC it,
I always,
I always had some point,
probably about 15 times during the night
have to say these are like some of the
toughest people on the fucking planet.
Just like the,
I can't imagine the mental place you
have to go to when you're walking down
there. No one you're going
to fight somebody, especially
as the fucking underdog,
right?
That it's just been training for three
months with like some of the best people
in the world. And their skill is
how to beat the fuck out of you.
Like they broke down your
style and they're just going
to figure out how to beat
the fuck out of you.
It's like nauseated.
How do you even get your raisin brand
down there that morning? I mean,
these people, they're on a
whole other level. So, um,
congratulations to amend Amanda Nunez,
the first female Brazilian
UFC champion and, uh,
you know, I, I was loving me just
to take, you know, always class act.
He's fucking gorgeous. You know, it was
hard watching her get busted up like that,
that fucking, that upper cut
that was perfectly timed. Ugh,
Jesus Christ. Um, but anyways,
so I did that and then a buddy
of mine texted me and he said,
why don't you come down
to the fucking troubadour?
There's some band playing down there.
And I hope I get the name of this band
right. Cause I went down and saw a band,
I think they were called Earth
lists. Yeah. Earth lists.
Okay. And I'm still processing
what the fuck I saw.
I went down there, I watched like three
seconds of a youtube clip and I'm like,
I gotta get out of the fucking house.
Right.
So I went down and that my
buddy started drinking waters.
It was really good that night. Right. And
this band comes out, power trio, right?
To guy in a strat, there's a fucking
bass player and a drummer and that's it.
And the guitar was starts playing
immediately. You're like, wow,
this guy can fucking play.
And then the drum start coming in and
then the base and then they just went into
this epic fucking like,
just imagine if you were
playing an arena show, right?
And you just,
you're in,
you're bringing home the
greatest arena rock show ever.
Like where your energy would be in
the final minute before you said,
right. Bragen row. Right.
They basically started there and
stayed there for a half a fucking hour.
We're as far as I could tell once there
was like four or five songs that we're
all one giant song dude. It
was, it was fucking exhausting.
Just watching it and I
remember about 12 minutes in
when they were ended.
One part of it that you don't like
the cliched endings to things.
They would like add 15 minutes
each at see it was fucking unreal.
I just looked at the guy I was with and
we just started laughing like this is
fucking nuts. 20 minutes in I got
to go up to the bar and get a drink.
The fucking band is poor and sweat.
They look like they're in a fucking sauna
and they're still going and the guy on
the guitar is fucking shred and
out of nowhere you're like, wait,
what the fuck song is that? What does
that feel like? A couple of bars,
they played that fucking
part of dazed and confused,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo
Doo Doo Doo Doo and the fucking guitar
player, the drama that we're all doing
and then he like, hey, that's daisy,
daisy and fuse.
It goes right by it.
Then they were into something else and
then finally after a fucking half hour it
ends right.
It's fucking,
it's and people are like,
people are exhausted from
just watching it and uh,
I couldn't hear what he said cause I had
my own earplugs in because I'm an old
man.
I eat psychedelic something
was the name of the song,
psychedelic infinity,
psychedelic fucking a scrabble.
I have no fucking idea what he said.
And then they went into another song
that was like five minutes long and then
they closed with communication breakdown,
I guess it was like three,
four bands and they just played it like
a quick like hour 45 minutes set and it
was over and it was a,
I like,
it took me till like halfway through
today to like process what the fuck I saw.
I don't know how you would ever
put together something like that,
the complexity of the whole thing.
But it was definitely worth it.
And I heard all of their shows
are different every time,
but I was completely blown away by him.
The band is called Earth lists.
If you get a chance to see them.
Um, I guess, uh, here is Wikipedia.
They're on a San Diego,
California, Isaiah Mitchell.
Is there a,
is there a guitarist?
I hope I sailed the names correctly.
God knows, I always fuck it up. Uh,
Mike [inaudible], e g, I n t o n
was the bass player and then Mario,
Mario,
I'm never going to try with the last name.
Rubella Kaba who I guess is also
some fucking psycho skateboarder,
uh, meet up the band and they were,
they were absolutely fucking amazing.
MMM.
If you get a chance,
he had definitely, uh,
definitely check them out formally
a professional skateboarder.
So, you know what I instantly love about
that guy. He's never had a real job.
And I mean that with all respect.
When I first started doing comedy,
I used to work with the guy who used
to have his first job. Was he a,
he was a professional roller skater.
He was about 10,
15 years older than me. So
like he was like 18, early
seventies Assam Shit. Right.
And that's when like,
you know,
the rollerskating and that type of
shit was at its height and there was
magazines about it and I didn't believe
him until he told me how he fucked up
his elbow, what the maneuver, and he
knew the name and all of that shit.
And then he played drums in a band.
Yeah.
And then he became a standup comic and
I was thinking like, dude, yeah, you,
he's like, yeah man. He goes, I never
had a real fucking job. I that I,
that stuck with me.
I think about that every once in a while,
just like you want in life.
Like I don't care if you never made
any fucking like real money doing that.
As long as you, you can pay your
rent and you can eat, you know,
you're not fucking homeless. If those
were the three jobs you had in life,
I swear to God,
if there's an afterlife and God's looking
at your resumes and like, all right,
professional roller, skater,
professional drummer,
professional comedians, nothing
else. Lee was fucking guy. All right,
it's gone up, buddy. I'm looking forward
to popping in this VHS tape of your life.
See what's going on
here. Right. Um, anyway,
so let's do a little bit of
advertising here for the week.
MMM.
All right. Let's see if some reeds
here. A Indo Chino Indochino.
I. N. D. O. C. H. I. N. O. I have
no idea to say that. Indochino for,
that's what I'm saying.
It talk about how a manmade,
how about a made to measure suit field
fits and feels compared to a generic off
the rack suit.
You want me to talk about that?
Why don't you fucking write something
for me to say Indochino is reinventing
men's fashion. Well, I would
imagine if it's off the rack,
you got to be the exact same
fucking size. Is that suit? If not,
it's going to be tugging a polling
or everybody's going to be laughing,
looking at your ankles as opposed
to a suit that fits. I mean, yeah,
I would think that people would know
the difference, you know, I mean,
off the rack you got,
you gotta be,
you gotta be the same build as a mannequin
and nobody has that bill passed the
been like 18 years old. Unless you're
a fucking underwear models. All right?
Cause you out and get a
couple of cheeseburgers there
and then it's fucking over.
Your whole torso starts sinking down
to your bull big. All right. Indochina,
his reign as reinventing men's fashion
in a made to measure suit is the best
suit for you. It's the best suit
you will ever own. So suit up,
get a one of a kind a made to measure
suit. Customize the details you want.
You pick your lining, lapels,
personal monogram, and more.
14 unique measurements. Go into
making a suit that fits you perfectly.
You can't go wrong with the well
crafted 100% Merino wool suit.
Well, what if it's hot out? I can
think of, you could go wrong there. Uh,
also checkout, they're made to measure
dress shirts and men's accessories.
I Bet Merinos like not like the itchy
wool, right? Moneyback guarantee. Today,
my listeners get any premium
suit for just 399 bucks.
That's up to 50% off at Indochino,
indochino.com when entering burr at
checkout plus the shipping is free.
There's no reason not to try your
first custom made suit with a deal.
This good and as suit classic from
their premium collection will look good.
Feel good and last.
That's Indochino indochino.com promo
code birth for any premium suit for just
399 bucks and free shipping.
Indochino your look your way through
custom fit suit for 400 bucks. Man.
You can't go wrong there. You
know, and if you do go wrong,
it's your fault because you're picking
out all the materials, right? All right.
Dollar Shave club,
everybody. Um, all right.
We really appreciate you
listening to the show and, uh,
I wanted to do something
to thank you guys.
Evidently this is what dollar shave club
does a saying that I wanted you guys to
do. So, uh, they're going to
give new members this month,
the executive razor for free
just by buying a tube of
Dr Covey's easy shape. But,
um, they are super excited
to do this for you. Um,
now let me remind you why millions of
others have joined the dollar shave club
revolution.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers amazing
razors right to your door for a third of
the price of what the greedy
razor corporations charge.
That means when you go
to dollar Shave Club,
you can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
Get a first class shave when you use the
executive blade and that's without even
hurting your wallet. Uh, when
you use the executive, uh,
well I got the hiccups the fuck.
Okay.
When you use the executive
with Dr Carver's,
easy shave Dr Carver's shave butter.
That's what it's really supposed to be.
The played gently glides across
for the smoothest shave ever.
Shea butter isn't your
average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula with
high quality natural ingredients leaving
your skin unbelievably soft and smooth.
Now a great now's a great time
to join dollar shave club.
New members who buy a
tube of shave butter,
get a free month of the
executive razor for free.
Take advantage of this
special offer today.
It's available by going to dollar
shave club.com/bird that's dollar shave
club.com/burr. All right, frame bridge to
more people. Just hang in there with me.
All right, two more. Two more stuttering.
Rumbling, bumbling, stumbling.
Fucking reads here. Frame
Bitch. Frame Bridge.
You got an empty walls
and you got something special you want
to frame but she never do it because it
takes too long. It's a pain in the
ass and it cost too much money.
So what does it do? It sits over in the
corner. Then your dog walks on it, right?
Or You bump into it. Dust
gets on it. Just reps.
You know you're never going to do it.
You're like,
why the fuck didn't I frame it cause
it's a pain in the ass. All right.
Remember when cameras
weren't a part of your phone?
The way we take pictures has changed, but
the way we frame them has it until now.
All right. Frame, bridge.com is the easy,
new way to frame things you love from the
treasure trove of photos on your phone.
To posters and at work frame bridge
makes it easy and affordable.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com and pick
out the frame you want or let their
designers help you choose. You can
preview your item in any frame style.
They'll uh, send you a prepaid
package to ship your items safely.
Or You simply upload
a picture under frame,
bridge site or APP Jesus
Christ can't get an easier,
you can even upload a picture
directly from Instagram.
You know, if you take the ultimate
photo you sent it right to those fucks,
they stay in their,
frame it for you.
The expert team at fridge where they
fuck spill, I don't know, frame bridge.
We'll custom frame your items in a day,
in days,
not weeks or months and deliver your
finished piece to your door directly.
Ready to hang in style
called frame bridge.
The genius site that makes custom phrasing
and framing easy frame bridge offers
a happiness guarantee.
Their team gives each item personal
care and attention because meeting your
expectation is as is as
important as meeting their own.
Instead of the hundreds you pay
at a framing store, their prices
start@thirtyninebucksandallshippingisfreeandrightnowifyougotoframebridge.com
and
use the Promo Code [inaudible],
you'll save an additional 15% off
your first order. Okay, one more.
Okay.
stamps.com everybody
trips to the post office,
it probably becomes sec second
nature to you. They same.
They seem easy because you've
been institutionalized, okay?
Cause you've been doing your mailing
and shipping that way for so long your
whole life.
You don't mind smelling some Old Lady's
wig in front of you as you worked some
kind of put together a priority box,
right? But think about all of that hassle,
man. Dropping what you're
doing, driving, they're finding
partying, parking, waiting,
all of that bullshit.
There's a much better way to do it.
stamps.com stamps.com is the easy and
convenient way to get your postage right
from your desk by in print official
us postage using your own computer and
printer with stamps.com
there's no guesswork.
They make it easy to get the
exact postage for any letter.
And he package any class of
mail the instant you need it.
No expensive postage meters to lease
and no more trips to the post office.
You have to try it. I use stamps.com
whenever I send out my posters,
I'm a moron if I could figure
it out. So can you, don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before you do else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinperthatstamps.com
enter
ber.
Ah, righty. Um,
all right.
You know what I missed today?
I thought I fucking tape that I missed
a fucking British Grand Prix. But uh,
I ended up watching most
of it on a youtube. Some
French dude put it up or like
lady,
um,
yeah,
and I watched most of it and uh,
congratulations to a Louie,
the uh, Lewis Hamilton and
fucking, what's his face?
The Tom Cruise of Formula One.
Nico Rosberg get panelized again.
Fucking penalize them again. They
fucked, they don't like the guy.
Evidently he got too much
information from his pit crew.
Some was going on with
his fucking gearbox.
See every couldn't go from six to seven.
He had to go to six to eight.
He was saying that, you
know, it caused a dangerous
assumption. Shit. Yeah. He's guy.
Every fucking, every race, every race,
there's some sort of fucking deal.
And he's getting penalized.
He came in second but they
bumped up down to fucking third,
which is huge because now we only leads
Lewis Hamilton by fucking three. Yeah.
Points. I, I'm, I'm actually
taping it tomorrow I'm going
to watch the whole race,
but it was kind of fun
to watch it and French.
MMM.
Picking out words.
I Dunno.
I got to get like a tutor assumption
maybe then I'll actually start to get a
little better with that ship.
But um,
so now let me tell you, I think I
got the standings here somewhere.
Where the fuck is it? I got lyrics to Mac
Davis, baby baby, don't get hooked on me.
I started this podcast a couple of times.
I can't remember if I sang that yet.
Baby Baby.
But don't kid hooked on me cause
I'll just use you and sits you free.
I'm all right.
Nico Rosberg has 168 points.
Lewis Hamilton has one 67.
They fucked him out of three points today.
You know, he would have been up to
one 71. Okay. Guys. I don't know.
He's just constantly getting into,
he's just constantly, I don't know,
putting himself in a situation,
I don't know how many fucking
times can one man have problems.
This is the third race of this year,
right?
Slammed into fucking his
teammate at the Spanish.
You slammed into his teammate at
the fucking Austrian one, right?
I think this is, then he got
penalized. Two different, fuck,
this guy's having a hell of a fucking
year. I didn't see the press conference,
but he had the had
fucking tears in his eyes.
It was looking like the kill even
Cavaliers fucking coach there. Um,
anyway,
so I've been getting my back
taken care of and uh,
the fucking gym out in the garage
has been a Goddamn game changer.
We finally got an elliptical out there,
so that's it.
If I can just stop eating like a lunatic,
I think I can be under one 80 by
the end of this writing season.
Speaking of which, we're a recording, uh,
we're doing the table read for episode
nine tomorrow. The record on Wednesday,
it's fucking great.
And then we're on 10 and then the
writer's room as far as going there,
every single day is done. But, uh,
we're now looking at the animatics
and I got to tell you guys,
episode one,
there's a scene in there that we have
been trying to get right for like weeks.
So we've all seen it like fucking 20 times
each and they finally animated if the
way we want it to. We finally, we
were able to basically see you.
It's all about conveying
your idea to them, you know,
and they finally understood what we were
trying to say and we watched it and we
fucking died. I cannot wait
for you guys to see this shit.
And uh, oh man. If we get a laugh
like that each fucking show,
that's what we got to go for.
If we can fucking make you
laugh the way it made us laugh,
where a bunch of jaded assholes so we
can get you laughing like that. Um,
I think we can, uh, I dunno.
I think we can keep making some more
of these very excited about it. And uh,
very excited to get out of
the fucking writer's room.
Now I back's feeling great and uh,
I've been hitting the fucking gym,
had um,
told you guys want a bottle
that fucking wheat. You know,
I put up to 25 once in my life.
I weighed about 165 pounds when I
did it and I put it up one time.
I always wanted to do it. I was always
just too fucking little to do it. Uh,
just my frame. I was never like a
Starkey fucking guy. Like naturally.
I mean anybody eats fucking
pizza and drinks beer,
you're going to look for little husky.
But I'm just saying like naturally, um,
I was just more of a middle weight and
I did at one time for the fucking gym
rats.
You know that if you put up to 25 you get,
you got the two 45 plates on both sides.
So that was like a big fucking deal.
Right? So, uh, today I'm
inching my way back, right?
I put up one 75 twice.
I could have done it three times.
If I had somebody there sparked me, they
could have helped me on the fourth one,
which would have been huge
because that's how you build up.
But I've been going really
sick slowly up from, you know,
one 35 just going like 10 pounds at
a time rather than back in the day.
I'd go up 20, it's just been too much.
And what I do is I wait, you know,
like gone from one 35 to one 45 and then
up to one 55 and I just make sure I can
do before I tried one 75 I make
sure 20 pounds below it, I can,
I can do it like seven,
eight times.
And they did one 65 four
times in one 75 two times.
So I felt pretty good about that,
which means I could,
I could probably bench my
way at this point. I could,
I could put up one 85 just makes me feel
good. But, uh, and I got the atomic holds.
I can now fucking do a
little Ninja Warrior Shit.
I can go from one side of
my garage to the other.
It's a bad deal for 48 fucking years old.
Pegboards coming along.
I can do like too thick to,
uh,
take it out like twice on both sides
before I then fall down to the fucking
ground. But I'm, I'm telling you, if I
wasn't so busy doing this fucking show,
I could actually get in great shape.
I cannot recommend those
atomic holds enough.
They are fucking incredible.
And they have all these different kinds.
And just to the grip strength that you
get, the core strength that you get,
it's fucking amazing. It's,
this is the free advertising.
Atomic holds a t, O, m I k. Um,
and they have a website and they
get all these different things.
If you watch that Ninja Warrior Shit,
American Ninja Warrior, which is on, um,
it's on Mondays and Nia has always gone.
They should do a celebrity,
one of those fucking things.
You should go try to go on and do
one of those and it's just like,
you know that there's
no fucking way I could,
I would fuck up that first jump at thing.
But you know something,
no matter how great,
let's say I was fucking 30 years younger,
right in the prime of my life,
18 if I fucking trade,
no matter how much I trained.
Okay.
Which I don't think I ever had enough.
I just don't have the gift to get
into that kind of shape. But the,
let's just say I could at 18,
there's no fucking way ever I could
ever make it up that last wall to me,
that's the most,
you know,
out of all the crazy shit that
they come up with, you know,
is hard as it is.
Most of it is just being able to
fucking hang on that shit there.
Forget about it.
I would fuck it.
I would do about three steps up and
we'll do the most embarrassing faceplant
like I would do a face plant,
but like it would be like I was running
into a wall. I do like one, two,
three steps and I would slip and I would
slam my fucking button nose right into
the fucking wall.
And then that would be the end of me.
And it would become a meme.
It would become all of this shit.
I would never fucking live
it down. But, um, but I,
the inspiration for my gym was all the
shit that I did in the 80s, you know,
when it was all about just doing
your upper body and fuck your legs,
walk around the chicken legs,
it was that shit.
Little bit of Yoga. And then,
uh, American Ninja Warrior,
just looking at all that shit and just
going on youtube and watching people who
are training for it and these crazy
fucking things that they build in their
backyards. Um, you know,
just the strength that they have.
I mean,
I'll never have to be actually do B if
I ever do a muscle up. First of all,
my head's going to go through the
fucking ceiling. Uh, but I, I just,
I just don't have it my age. I
just, you just, there's just,
you get to a certain point, you
know, nature's just like, yeah,
we're beginning the dying process.
Okay.
At this point you should have had a
couple of kids and they should be handling
the hunting for the tribe and a,
you need to just sit around a fire telling
stories about what you used to do. So,
um,
I am excited though that I am,
I'm able to do a once 75 two
this is like such an 80 shit.
Only old people get this stuff because
I'm basically 10 pounds away from being
able to have the 40 fives and then the
20 fives that was all like a big deal.
Like you know when people would be doing
pyramids ten eight, six, four, two, right.
It was always like the
fucking guys would come in.
They put the 45 played on for 10
then they put the 25 add that right.
One 85 they do eight reps of that.
Then the 35 two oh five and then
the 25 to 25 and then they do,
and then everybody would fucking pretend
they weren't looking when anybody went
above two 25 if they threw one
like 25 pound plates again,
10 of five pound plates. Nobody gave
a fuck. But if you do the 20 fives on,
now you're up to 75 right?
If anybody put the three plates on,
that's right when the bar starts to bend,
right?
I remember is at the gym one time and I
saw this guy curl to 25 it was fucking
unbelievable. This guy was the
most dense human being I ever saw.
And he would like bring it up and just go,
ha
ha.
It's just like,
what the fuck?
And I wanted to laugh.
I know I've told you guys all those
stories that we tell that guy,
when I used to go to New York sports
club and when I was living on the upper
east side, New York, uh,
near Spanish Harlem, I just
take the fucking train down.
There was one in the 70s I used
to work out there. And, uh,
this guy came in one day and he had
to speak in a fucking bay, but bay,
but don't get hooked on me.
He had the fucking Mac Davis haircut.
He had a fucking Bandanna on not
doing some fucking a I heart.
I heart Huckabees that Royal Tena Bonds,
hipster horse shit. He wasn't doing that.
He was like, he was one of these guys
that just dress like how you dressed.
Like he stopped looking at fashion
at like fucking 18. He came in,
he had fucking like the glasses slash
shades all in one with a headband,
the curly fucking hair, like a tank
top. He had Larry Bird shorts on,
his socks pulled up. He looked like
Ken Patera. That's what he looked like.
And he would fucking work out dude.
And he would, when he would do a rep,
he'd go,
yeah,
yeah.
So you'd be in the gym and you just hear
this guy over in the corner and he was
a fucking monster.
He didn't want to laugh.
We just hear this guy
in the corner unquote.
Yeah,
yeah.
He would bring it down and go, and
then when you push it up with, yeah.
And then when he get to the last set,
when he was pushing himself, he'd go,
right.
I remember one time
he was sitting there, it was me and
some other dude and all I've tried,
I don't even know the other guy,
but I can feel him laughing and all
I'm trying to do is not look at him.
And finally when he did that, she, ah,
I fucking looked over at the other guy
and he was curling any, it's, you know,
he brought the curling bar down.
He was just holding it and he had his
eyes close with his back to the Ken Patera
Guy, so he couldn't see him and he was
just silently like crying, laughing.
And I'm you dude, I, I don't, I
think I was doing cardio Asub Shit,
I almost fell off the fucking treadmill
lunatic right out of Boogie nights.
So, um, anyways, I sh, I mean, you know,
at some point I'm going to
post a picture of the gym.
I don't like giving up pictures of my
house, but it is just a fucking garage.
MMM.
So anyways, I, I, I'm, I'm totally
off the fucking rails here. Where,
what else did I want to talk about?
We talked about the Grand Prix.
We talked Steven Adler, we
talk Amanda Nunez, stone cold.
Uh, it too. We're only a month away
from preseason football. Always.
Another thing I saw this weekend.
Do you guys ever watched
that live at Darrel's house?
Darrel Hall of Daryl Hall and Oates.
He had Joe Walsh on.
What a fucking, every time I
see that guy play, it's like,
why do I always forget what
an unbelievable fucking
guitarist and singer that
guy is. He came in and
absolutely just fucking ripped.
If you get a chance to watch that
one, I think they're up online. Um,
so I'm like VH one and then like this
headbangers ball think came on and a Nia
somehow got into it.
She is promised me at some
point she's going to sing. Um,
oh, what the fuck is that?
Saw that Queens rake song.
I don't believe in love.
She's been singing that,
that in teenage Frankenstein,
she just got into it. She,
she loved it and thought it was
silly all at the same fucking time.
So maybe on Thursday she's
a little tired today,
so I'll have her come on and sing some
of that shit for you. But at this point,
let's get to some of the questions here.
MMM.
I guess, well maybe before I
do that, just I have to say,
I do have to see something with all the,
just the shit that went on in the
over the past fucking week, you know,
with those two guys getting killed and
then the five cops get murdered. It just,
I actually believe it or not,
I think something positive is going to
come out of this. I'm really hoping,
I just feel like,
I think everybody at this point,
no matter what side you're on, if
there's one to one side, two sides of it,
whatever the fuck three sides,
whatever the fuck it is at this point,
I think everybody can kind of agree
that whatever the fuck it is we're doing
isn't working. And I'm, I'm really, I
don't know. I don't know what it is,
is horrific is all of
that stuff was to watch.
I feel like at this point
that you know,
everything on both sides was undeniable,
that it was wrong and it
shouldn't have happened.
And I think I just,
I dunno,
I was fucking devastating as it was.
I just feel like,
I just feel like that was a bottoming out.
I'm really hoping anyways and that it's
going to turn around. I'm hoping, uh,
cause I dunno man,
that's this
as just one of the fucking
worst, all of that shit.
The worst shit I've ever seen in my life.
Somebody just go on for that license.
He just, I just kept replaying that, just
wishing the guy said, listen, my license,
can you want to reach for it?
Can I get out of the car with my hands up?
And you just reach in and get it.
Just sold. That doesn't have to have,
is a fucking kid in the car. It's just
the whole thing was brutal, you know?
And then the cops,
Dallas is just down there.
They're just trying to handle the crowd,
make sure nobody gets hurt.
And then just, you know, all of them, you
know, I didn't, it was so fucking brutal.
I didn't even look into the backgrounds
of them, but you know, you know,
people were married,
had kids and the dad isn't coming home
and she said the whole fucking thing is
horrible and because it is so horrible,
I,
I'm really holding out that something
positive is going to come out of that
cause.
Uh,
okay.
I Dunno.
Cause what else can you think if you
can't get something positive out of that,
that's just too fucking devastating
to even think about. All right,
so let's get to the,
uh,
the questions here for this week.
All right, sweet. Hi Mr. Byrd.
I don't know if it's the correct way to
address someone you don't know in the U
S. Dot. It's fine. It's fine.
I like the call me Mr. Byrd.
I'm old enough to be a minister here, uh,
in Sweden. I would just call you bill,
by the way. I don't want to
Piss you off anyway. I was,
I was wondering if you're
coming to Sweden again.
I quote discovered you on Youtube a year
ago and I watched you every night while
I put my son to sleep.
Oh, that's great. He said,
and I love laying in bed holding
my mouth so I won't wake my son up.
I would love to see you live.
Greetings from Sweden a PSRF
if my spelling mistakes,
spelling sucks. Sorry
Dude. You're fucking,
your English is great compared to my shit,
unless you just looked
it all up and typed it.
I'm definitely coming back.
I just got to figure out when,
uh, my life has changed a little bit
now that I'm doing this show. But, uh,
I think what I'm going to do,
I have this European run that I'm going
to do and then I think I'm going to do
another one possibly march,
April of next year. Uh,
but I'm also taping a special, I got to
make sure when I go over there though,
I'm, I'm, I'm bringing
the fucking, you know,
I don't want come over
there with some halfass act.
I'm not flying over the other side of
the world to give you guys a okay show,
but I'm definitely going to come back.
I'd like to go back there and um,
well ideally I could go over there right
before my special comes out and knock
that out deck deck. That is
ideally, that's what I could do.
But I'm definitely gonna come back and
maybe do a little bit of eastern Europe.
Some of the countries that I
haven't been to. Uh, we shall see,
but I'm definitely going to come back
like I've done the Sweden, Norway,
Finland run two times already.
And uh,
I think I've been to Sweden three times,
so because one time,
but I think I just did sweet.
Then the next time was Sweden. Uh,
no way in Finland, but I'll definitely
going to get back. But thank you so much.
That's a really fucking,
that's a thrill.
That's someone that far away is
watching stuff. Laughing at my
stuff. Thank you very much.
Okay, here we go. Uh, Bill,
I fucked up and could use a
hand. All right. Let's see.
Why did you fuck up? Hey, you
all biscuit big and bitch.
Uh, I fucked this one up and could
use some of your broadcasted advice.
I'm 26 year old guy living and working
in the great white North Toronto to be
exact and I love your podcast and
all that shit. Thank you. Anyways,
few months ago I started seeing this
really sweet girl. She's pretty,
she's thoughtful and she's as low
maintenance as a 1991 Honda civic.
Okay. It sounds like the
beginning of a horror movie,
everything's like fucking perfect.
Right? And he literally says,
perfect explanation point.
She deserves to be treated right.
Okay.
About a month ago I was eating at a
restaurant with a buddy when this smoking
hot redhead comes up to me
out of the blue and says, hey,
you're cute. Take my number.
Let's go out sometime.
I should have said no.
I have a girlfriend right then and there,
but the excitement of having a babe throw
herself at me was too much for me to
pass up apps. A fucking Lulea
was, that's like a fucking movie.
We're not wired to pass that moment up.
I'm not saying you go and do it,
but Jesus,
uh,
he said I didn't have the damn strength
to keep it in my pants. Later that night,
after a few wobbly pops,
I texted her looking to meet up.
We did and we did the deed.
I felt like a piece of shit. Ah, yes.
We've all been there as men. We've all
been there and a lot of ladies too,
which never gets any press because it's
considered sexist to suggest that, um,
here's where it's getting
interesting and slightly complicated.
Not even 48 hours later,
I'm hanging out with my girlfriend when
she gets a call from one of her friends
saying, I have some bad
news to tell you. Oh boy.
I overheard the conversation coming
from my girlfriend's phone and knowing
exactly what the bad news was.
I snatched the phone from
her and proceeded to spill
my guts and told her the
whole story. Well, there you
go. At least you're Amanda.
Evidently the friend dead
called was roommates with
the red head and the redhead
through social media and hunted me down
and showed my picture to her roommates
too. You can't, you can't get away
with anything anymore. Look at this.
The friend goes on to tell the redhead
that I have a girlfriend. Oh Dude,
this is what this is like.
You're going to end up with nothing here.
My girlfriend obviously was super upset,
but being the sweetheart she is and after
many many's, I'm so sorry. It's from me.
She agreed to let me make,
try to make it up to her.
MMM.
Kind of cheaters do this shit.
I didn't even last 48 hours.
Cut to two weeks later myself in three
of my buddies since kindergarten or on a
mountaineering expedition in Peru.
Okay.
Do what do you Jason Bourne,
what's going on here?
Hot chicks throwing themselves at you
and now you're in fucking Peru. Uh,
a trip we planned since February and I
get this panic stricken email from my
girlfriend saying she parentheses the
redhead had broken into my apartment and
trash the place.
See attached photos.
Okay.
Do what the fuck women are fucking crazy.
Let's just say, let's just say this. Okay.
Like how was she hurt?
She came walking up to you
through her fucking clam at you.
You fucking took it.
Who?
You're not in a relationship
with her like voices.
Lily crackers had a really shit,
you don't have to fucking relationship
with her dude. You need a cross. The cute,
this fucking woman. This has to stop
this whole fucking thing that would,
women get upset.
They can destroy property.
Let a guy go out and fucking trash some
woman's car after she fucks around on
him. He'll end up in jail and
have to pay for the fucking car.
Everything was smashed.
My TV, one of my guitar,
she cut up my bedsheets and the dubé.
She even went so far as to throw all my
towels in the bathtub and ran the water.
How do I know it was the red head?
The dumb bitch left a note next to TV.
St cheaters never win or some bullshit
like that. Give me a fucking break.
She even bragged about the whole
ordeal to her affirmation roommate.
Classic Guy.
He just writes sheesh.
My borough friend called my girlfriend
called the cops and a problem.
I returned from Peru. I set up a
restraining order against the redhead.
You should fucking chart.
You should, you should sewer.
Here's the problem.
All this drama has led to my girlfriend
reconsidering her willingness to give me
a second chance. Dude, his surreal thing.
Anytime some fucking smoking hot girl
just comes up and throws it at you.
You know,
it's a headcase.
Uh,
go with a fake name. Um, I,
I feel real bad about the whole situation
and want to make it work between us,
but there's this little
voice in my head says,
let her break up with you and start fresh.
I'm pretty confused.
I was going to say that. Just
start over again, dude. You're 26.
What are you going to, you know, you got a
dick. This is going to happen. All right?
So he goes,
I fucked up initially,
but forgiveness then got fucked with in
the forgiveness was retracted. Anyways,
I hope your site,
your sage advice is half as good
as those fucking pies you make.
Thanks a lot and go fuck yourself.
Yeah, Dude. You know what you gotta do?
You gotta walk and you got to
have this crazy redheaded a bitch.
Pay For your shit.
All right.
Jesus Christ. She takes no responsibility
in that. Just walking around,
throwing a fucking pussy and everybody,
I mean,
what the fuck he thinks going to happen,
you know,
is a guy you could walk around throwing
your Dick at fucking people for,
for years and not get,
this is why there's the double
standard. You know, if a guy does it,
he's a stud because he has to convince
people just the way we're set,
it was just, it's the
way we're set up. Okay.
Women are no better than guys.
It's what it is,
is the way they're set up anatomically
is they're letting someone enter their
body. That is a major decision.
Sticking your Dick in something. It's,
you know, it's funny. It's like, you know,
it's like putting Sera back
in the cabinet. I mean,
you don't even fucking think
about, um, I probably, you know,
that was probably ignorance
in there. I, yeah, I would
just say like, you know what?
You're right.
I fucked up.
That's a really big pet peeve of mine
that fucking women get to do shit like
that. They teach us, get to
walk around, destroy your Shit,
just fucked up your TV and all that dude.
Then you just in your whole thing is just
like sheesh. Like we're like, we like,
we're just conditioned to be like,
all right, well that's what they do.
They ruin your stuff, dude. You are 100%
the wrong. You shouldn't have done it.
It definitely did a piece of shit thing,
you know?
But that doesn't give somebody the
right to go to break into your fucking
apartment that's breaking and
entering and destroying property.
She should be in jail.
MMM.
This is what you do. I would break up
with her and uh, I would, I would, yeah,
I would try to take legal action against
the red head and at some point I'd s
you know, you want to send her a
note, but don't do it. Just say, yeah.
Breaking and entering, you know,
fucking felons never wind either.
Whatever the fuck that is.
MMM.
Yeah, Dude. Whatever you
know it happened. And uh,
you know, you know what I would do
with your 26. Stay single for a while.
Stay single for a while, go
to the gym, get back in shape,
figured out what the fuck you want to do.
Do you want to fuck a bunch of women or
do you want to meet the one? You know,
I, but I, I think at this point,
dude, you got enough fucking drama.
I can't believe she gets to do that.
Like first of all,
she got laid the redhead, she
got fucking late. You know,
she had a great fucking time and she
gets to bust up somebody's place,
like a fucking rock star and then walk
out of there and feel like she's a
fucking hero.
This is why I don't give a shit that
they make less an hour than I do.
Because when you add up all
the fucking parks, I mean,
it's a pretty good goddamn
deal. Being a woman, you know,
you get all your emotions
out all the fucking time.
You get to break up people's Shit
and you get to live longer than men.
I don't know what the fucking problem is.
You're going to complain about
an extra 79 cents. Alright. Um,
ex wife wants me to adopt ex's son.
Hey there.
Bill Burlington coat factory. I usually
laugh at some of the poor schmucks.
Who right into your, into you asking
the advice today. I'm that schmuck.
I won't go into every little about this
and hope she can give me some advice.
A few years ago I married
my soon to be ex wife. Dude,
I was so fucking thinking about that
woman ruining your apartment and how they
can just get away with that. Let me,
let me, I wasn't even paying attention.
I mean it's again, I am today. I'm the
smock. Okay. I won't go to every detail.
All right.
A few years ago I married my soon to be
ex wife along with the marriage came or
two year old son.
His biological father is a deadbeat who
didn't hold down a job and avoids child
support. He has never had any
contact with the sun. Wow. All right.
So I did the most manly thing that one
can do besides going to community college.
I put on my big boy pants and
I took her son in is my own.
He Calls me Dad and whatnot.
We bonded.
I really care for the kid the first few
years of marriage, my wife for great,
which ended up leading us to
having our very own daughter.
And then my wife turned into a
whore. Oh God. What happened? Uh,
so we're going through the divorce
and I still pick both kids up,
even though I'm legally
responsible for one.
I carry her and her son on
my insurance to this day.
Maybe against my better judgment,
but I'd like to give her some time to get
our shit together until I drop her off,
drop her off of it. Complete dropper out
of it. I think been sick completely. Well,
the finalization of the
divorce papers is in August.
The soon to be ex mother in law keeps
insisting that I legally adopt her
grandson. No, don't do
that. Now here's the thing.
I send a very gracious amount
in support payments biweekly.
MMM.
We choose to not go through the court
system because my ex sees that I'm a good
father and still take responsibility
of her son. Keep it like that.
I flat out said, no, I'm not
legally adopting him yet.
Your fucking mother in law does not want
you to legally adopt him because she
thinks you're a good father.
Okay.
She's looking at you like an ATM
machine like a lot of women do with men,
which once again,
you can't fucking say that despite
the 10 million fucking examples of it,
it's considered sexist.
All right? One wrong move.
And now the court system has me by
the balls for support for two legal,
uh, children. What, what happened?
Yeah. Yes. It flat out. Yeah.
He said and flat out. No,
because one wrong move.
And now the court system has me legally
by the balls for the sport of two
children. Yeah. There's no
fucking reason for you to do that.
They don't hold anything over you.
They have no negotiating, nothing. Uh,
the mother in law is in sit unless they
try to keep your daughter from you.
The mother-in-law's insisting
that if I don't legally adopt him,
I'm a scumbag who doesn't
deserve to see him.
And he was gone so far in so many
words to say, I won't be seeing him.
She's even getting my ex on
board with this. Like I said,
I really care for the kid.
He's a good kid who will never had a
father figure until I came into his life
six years ago. What's my play here?
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself. Uh,
what you're seeing with
these two fucking lunatics,
um,
generation fucking psychos here,
uh, is the tip of the fucking
iceberg with these people. Okay?
They don't give a shit about you.
They're looking at you like an ATM machine
and they're already fucking with you.
They don't,
they don't have that kid's
best interest in mind.
They think they do. They don't. They
using him as a fucking negotiating tool.
All right. I'm surprised
they haven't said, well,
we'll fucking go for full custody with
your daughter and try to fuck with it.
That'll probably be there next fucking
move. And it's the thing with them,
okay with them.
It's the more you're in their lives,
the worst it's going to get.
Do not legally bound yourself to them
whatsoever. And this is what I would do.
Do not get emotional at all. Do
not get into a fuck you. Fuck you.
Fight with the mother in law. Do
Fight with your soon to be ex wife.
You have leverage in that your ex wife,
as much as she's, you know, going to
divorce you here still cares about you.
You guys still had a child together
and
you just have to just talk to
her logically and just say,
I'm not comfortable doing that.
Um,
but I'm going to continue to make payments
and support and all that and help you
out with your son and obviously
our daughter. All right. Um,
and this pressure that you're,
your mother-in-law is putting on,
this is only going to make
both of our lives miserable.
So what you do is you, you, you
divide and conquer there. Just say,
I have no problem with you
and the way that we get along.
I don't think your in
mother-in-law understands.
And that's why she's applying this
pressure. But that pressure is,
it's going to be bad for us and
it's going to be bad for our kids.
Let's just continue going on like this.
I love you son,
and you know I'm going to continue to
support him. That's as far as it goes.
All right. And I totally
comfortable with supporting them.
I'm giving you my word, but I'm not,
you know, I'm not doing the legal thing.
I'm not doing it. And you
just, that's it. That's it.
And if they want to keep coming at you,
I'm telling you right now,
if you do think that, if, when
you legally adopt that kid,
do you honestly fucking think that that's
going to be the end of the demands?
What the fuck is the mother-in-law
involved in this shit for anyways?
Right there. That's a nightmare.
That's a fucking nightmare situation.
And so many married women
have that fucking debt,
ridiculously close relationship with
their mom. You know what I mean?
And it it to the point that it hurts
the fucking relationship and God forbid
it's as if a guy you keep bringing your
mom to the fucking relationship with
your wife. That's dead. That's a
fucking rap. It's a fucking rap.
But once again,
guys
put up with that shit.
We put up with that shit.
We put up with them coming in
and busting up our shit. Dude,
you hold all of the fucking cards
here. That's it. They don't have,
they don't have, they
don't have a dime. They,
they're not even in the fucking game.
You hold all the fucking cards.
Do not do this.
You don't have to do this.
Just stay calm and keep reassuring your,
your soon to be ex wife that you know
you're doing what's best for the kids and
what's best for you and what's best
for the both of you guys and just keep
saying,
ah,
this pressure that's your mother in
law is putting on us is unnecessarily
unnecessary. It's, it's,
it's just we're good.
Okay. I'm still like, if I
was going to be vindictive,
it would've happened by now. I'm still
picking both of them up. All right.
There's no way I'm going to let anything
happen to your son and there's no way
I'm letting anything happened to
our daughter. That's it. That's it.
So tell your fucking
mother to shut the fuck.
I can't do that part. Don't do that part.
All right, Harry girlfriend. No, Jesus.
Here we go. Harry
girlfriend. Dear red herring
on a 25 year old guy of moderately
good looks in mid level intelligence.
Uh, this is both the, if that
means you're actually a smart guy,
people walk around thinking
this smarter fucking dopes. Uh,
this is both helped and hurt my game.
I've had girlfriend,
nobody who's like mildly intelligent,
like thinks that that takes like a
level of intelligence to understand that
there's a lot of people way
smarter than you. You know,
people would just get like that fucking
medium brain. Like they walk around,
they think that the shit, you know
what I mean? They walk around,
they make bold fucking statements
and people list too, right?
Like Donald Trump, that guy's,
he's got a mid level brain.
He's too stupid to realize
what a fucking dope he is.
And then people just listen to him.
He's still,
you become the Pied Piper of fucking
morons. And next thing you know,
you're there. Uh Oh God,
what a fucking decision.
That fucking idiot or that Goddam
lunatic. Anyways, here we go. Ah,
this is how, um, mid level intelligent,
I've had girlfriends in the past,
but most were just objects of
lust instead of true connections.
I met a new girl through a dating
APP. Not Proud of that. Why?
I wish that thing existed back in the day.
It's like the fucking draft.
All of a sudden you're fucking Bill
Bella checking your Dick there. Uh,
and things are great. She's
beautiful, smart, and actually
gets my sense of humor.
That's why dating apps are great.
You can cut through a lot of bullshit
as far as I've heard or meet a serial
killer. After a while of casual dating,
we started to become more serious.
She is a Brazilian descent and
has some body here. Nothing crazy.
Just arms and lower back type shit.
Here's my question.
Is there a subtle way I can tell her to
lose the for or should I just stop being
a cunt and be happy? Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Um,
all right.
How do you do this?
Best case scenario is
you're a little furry too.
And then would you do is say,
Hey, I'm going to go fucking
get some of the fucking let her
know hair taken off my back.
You want to do a two for one? That's
not gonna work. Don't say that.
Um,
oh Jesus Christ.
She has someone on her lower
back and where else? Oh,
on her arm.
So she just her arms.
Uh,
you know what I'm going to fucking to act
like on. Who wants to be a millionaire?
I'm going to fucking phone up.
Not even phone a friend.
I'm going to fucking Google this.
How to tell your girlfriend
she is too hairy.
How to get out of a hairy situation.
Five ways to get a girl
to shave downtown. Oh Gosh. Can
I say the worst? I, you know,
I actually thought you know what
that was on the Bro. bible.com.
Hey Bro,
how'd he tell a girl she
has a bit of facial hair?
My girlfriend has a lot of hair on
her ass. How do I approach this? Okay,
here we go.
This is on reddit.
Uh,
you don't read.
It's not going to have the fucking answer.
I'm going to go with this one.
The student room.
How do I tell my girlfriend she's too
Harry l this is another fucking shit, Ron.
I'm dating a girl. Okay.
We know what the deal is.
How dare you dislike something that comes
naturally. Oh God. These fucking broads.
I swear to God.
Hashtag yes all women stop and posing
your fucking patriarchal standards on this
poor girl. If you have nothing good
to say, don't say anything at all.
It's her body. Uh, gimme a fuck.
And it what women do the second getting
a fucking relationship with them.
They're constantly trying to change you.
If you don't like it,
don't be with her. Don't make her feel
insecure. If Jesus is all a Harry chicks,
a chime in in, how would you like if
she told you to shave your sweaty,
hairy balls?
I would say absolutely sweetheart.
Why would I want to have hairy sweaty
balls in your face if it's turned you off?
The game plan here is to get in the mood.
By all means. What do you want me to do?
A, you could maybe remove your own Man
Lady Garden that would create natural
opportunity to discuss your lady friends,
luxury and growth.
That was kind of my suggestion.
Okay.
Uh,
just tell her seriously,
why do you let people create
stupid threats? Ah, Jesus.
Uh, yeah, I don't, I don't,
yeah, this is a hard one.
Yeah, that's a really fucking difficult
one. Cause you're talking about something,
it's just weird thing that they can help,
but they can also fix very
easily. Although, yeah,
it's Kinda hurts too. Right?
According to the 40 year old virgin.
MMM.
Why don't you learn how to do it?
Did she sleep on her stomach? Right.
And then just when she's asleep, he just
put it on her and then you just go home
and then you as she sits up to scream,
you just fake asleep.
He goes, what the fuck was that man?
I Dunno. I think you had a bad dream.
And she's like, my back's killing me.
Oh, well you sleeping on your front.
Maybe you were putting pressure on your
spine then, you know, I don't know.
And then when she wakes up the
next fucking morning, you know,
she goes back to sleep. She wakes up the
next morning. Maybe she doesn't notice,
but then he got to do it every time.
Yeah.
I just gotta I guess you could just
got to tell like, come on ladies, you,
there's gotta be
mmm.
It's gotta be something that we do. Right.
They, you know what it is about women,
they can sit down, they could sit
down and just tell you. And as a guy,
he just have to take it. You just have to
fucking tell you this. It's constantly,
I think that does that why we
died before them. It's just,
it's just a one way fucking street.
Ah, dude. I don't know how to, I don't,
I don't know what to tell you, man.
That's a tough one. Listen, I love you.
I'm crazy about, yeah, I think
you're really attractive. Um,
I was just, it will, there's one thing,
you don't have bad breath. Yeah, yeah.
You're gorgeous and all
that. It's, it's just,
it is any way you could just take down
a little bit of the lower back for,
I mean, you know, it's fun.
She's Brazilian, you know,
they came up with the Brazilian wax.
It's like,
can you do the Brazilian
wax to your fucking back?
Why don't you get her to get her,
get her a tramp stamp. Right.
So we'll have to shave it anyways and
then you'll be like, ah, you know,
you gotta keep it shaved this so
people can always see it to that to
get her an anchor tattoo on both forearms,
like,
or drag couple of dragons like bond Scott,
I don't know what to tell you to do that.
And I'll tell you, that's a rough one,
you know? Um, I'll try to remember that
one for Thursday when Nissan. All right.
Hey Bill, is there any type of Gig
you wouldn't do? Would you pref? Yeah,
of course there was.
Would you perform for the queen of
England and all our stiff cohorts?
Now, how about a room full of
priests, a priest at the Vatican?
Absolutely not.
Not all this shit I've said about them.
And then I'm in their country.
That's a sovereign state Vatican City.
Bonus question.
What is the exact dollar amount it
would take you to do a cruise ship?
Well, I already, I did one a long time
ago. No, I, there's no dollar amount.
I,
uh,
I don't have a lot of,
okay.
And that really into stuff. I'm
into no debt. So I've kept my,
I've lived within my means and I have
enough t shirts and shit and I can eat.
And uh, you know, so no, I,
I can make enough money on land.
I don't need to do that.
Um, there is no amount.
There really isn't. Uh,
as of today, July 11th, 2016, what?
The 10th one I'm doing it. Who knows?
In the future, I dunno when
I'm like 60, I imagine.
Then you could talk me on a boat
if you gave me, like bill will get,
you could do one more fucking Gig. We're
going to give you a fucking, you know,
something's zillion dollars to do this
gig and then you got to walk away from
stand up. I might be so fucking
tired at that point that I do it,
but as of right now, 48 years old, a,
there's no dollar amount that can
get me on a fucking cruise ship.
MMM.
You know,
what could a a benefit if there was
some sort of benefit or some shit and it
actually seemed legit. I'm a sucker for
a fucking benefit, but like, you know,
I don't care.
I don't need to go on a fucking boat.
I don't want to go on a boat and just
be on this fucking thing with the crowd
the entire time. And uh, you know,
if you're happy and you know it,
clap your hands. I bet on
it. They fucking brutal.
I worked with guy doing that
and there was a juggler and a,
you couldn't fucking say anything.
You just had to sit there and act like
the cruise was the greatest fucking thing
you ever had been a part of.
It just went against everything
about being a comedian, you know,
we're contrarians. Um, all right,
so that's the podcast. Uh, people,
if you want to write in and in,
anybody have a hairy girlfriend out there
and you had to say something or, or,
or even better women have you
there had to be something.
Yeah, Guy, maybe he had a giant fucking
something on the side of his fucking,
I don't know what his head or some shit,
you know?
Okay.
It was wardee moly or some shit.
You had to say something had halitosis.
I Dunno.
I think if a woman had a smelly vagina,
I think it'd be easier to tell her that.
Then she had a hairy back.
Uh,
how do you, how do you do, how
did you just listen? You know,
I think you're beautiful. You know,
I think you're gorgeous and you know,
you turn me on and everything, but
I, I just, you know what's so funny?
It's just how guys, you know, just
our shit is not validated. You know,
like if a woman didn't,
you know, was turned off by
something God for fucking bit.
I mean, if you still climbed on top
of her with your hairy back, I mean,
I think you'd be charged with some
sort of like, you know, I dunno,
pubic raper bad pube break or some shit
cops would show up and putting in some
sort of choke hold and drag
it out of the fucking house.
And God knows if you ever
see anybody again. Um,
yeah. You know what, you
me, I got to think about
that one. Um, all right, well, that's
a podcast. The Monday morning podcasts.
Go fuck yourselves.
Enjoy your next couple of days.
I'll check in on you on Thursday and
maybe I'll have Nia helped me answer that
question. All right. Uh,
let's it go. Fuck yourself.