Hey, what's going on is bill burn? It's
some Monday morning podcast from Monday,
July 6th,
2015 how fucking
what's going on? How was your
weekend? Did you have a good time?
Did your blow off your fucking fingers?
Um,
did you enjoy the 4th of
July? You know, first of all,
before right out of the gate,
right out of the gate,
I want to thank everybody that did some
dumb shit with fireworks and it had the
presence of mind to fucking
make a youtube video out of it,
you know?
So guys like make it just sit down.
I was laughing my ass off last night.
I went to bed and I was watching people
shooting bottle rockets out of their ass,
having a Roman candle fights,
seen somebody take one to the face.
Do you know some guy in
Maine lit something off on
top of his fucking head and
he died instantly.
They will like he lit off,
they said some a mortar or
something fucking insane.
What could,
what kind of,
you know what kind of a fucking
asshole would do something like that?
He must've had it. There's
no way. Everybody knows,
once you get up to anything like a pack
of firecrackers on your head, you like,
that's, that's funny. You're going to
fucking kill your ear drums and you know,
but you're going to survive.
But what,
what do you put an [inaudible]
in his mouth or something?
Well, I don't know, Bill.
You fucking brought it
up. All right, relax.
Let's just look at main guy dies.
Fireworks.
Okay.
All right. Man. Shoots off fireworks
from top of his head dies instantly.
A 22 year old man was drinking
and celebrating the 4th of July.
Happy Birthday to America.
Don't put it on my head.
I'll fucking lie again.
Happy Birthday.
Wow.
Okay,
Michael. Oh my God. So many cool. Um,
that's how I went down.
22 year old man who was drinking
and celebrating the 4th of July.
I tried to launch a firework from Trump,
is his head, killed him instantly.
Authority said,
okay.
30 said,
you gotta be an authority to say that
somebody is fucking dead after the light.
Something off on their head.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Claire. Claire the way.
Click yes. Yes, he is dead. Well,
we kind of knew that he has Brian's all
over the sidewalk. Watch your mouth.
Watch your mouth woman.
It's one of my favorite quotes
in sports over the last fucking,
I don't know how many months, six
months. Watch your mouth woman.
When that woman called,
uh,
ask the Braun what it was like to be a
punk ass bitch and then that guy's going
to watch your mouth.
Woman wants your mouth woman and you know,
you would think that the
broads would've had such,
which have fucking difficulty
with it. Like, you know,
I realized that she said something
derogatory towards him through excuse,
go change your Bra Lady.
All right.
I love that they didn't say anything
because even they knew even they knew that
I guide. Yeah. That bitch was out of line
up just talking shit today.
Um,
they won't say what kind of
firework it was. All right.
Apparently he thought that was a great
idea that have just when you died in a
stupid fucking way,
when somebody starts it off when
they start your yield eulogy off with
apparently. Yeah. Apparently this guy,
Todd sticking his head in the
garbage disposal was a, you know,
going to give him a good buzz. I
mean, I'm sorry to bring it up Claire,
but you know, how did they
even get it in there? Um,
his friends said they thought
okay.
They thought they dissuaded him from
doing it. The next thing they knew,
he ignited the firework and
he was killed instantly.
What the fuck did he shoot off?
Yeah,
there was no rushing him to the hospital.
There was no Devon left when I got there.
She said 25 year old Cody.
Jesus Christ.
The names of this
generation. Huh? Devin Cody
jeep wrangler. Uh, Devin was the kind
of person who would do something stupid.
Absolutely.
He was the kind of person who would
pretend to do something stupid to make
people laugh. Well, he wasn't faking it.
MMM.
All right,
so first fireworks fatality,
since they legalized
fireworks January 1st, 2012,
while he just fucked it up for
the whole state, it's bad enough.
Everyone's on heroin now you're
going to give them fireworks. I mean,
what next does isis get
their own juice store?
Come on,
people.
Over 80% of bottle rockets are shot out
of people's anuses in this state alone.
This needs to stop.
Woo.
That's going on in main
street right now in Maine.
Okay.
Hi. Do you know me? Of course you don't.
I'm your regular housewife here in Maine.
My son is on heroin.
My other son shot a
Roman candle up his ass.
I'm sorry to be graphic.
He was trying to shoot it out of his ass.
But apparently his excitement.
Okay.
Who was getting who? I mean,
in order to light the wick,
you gotta be able to see it.
So I don't know how these things
were done when we were kids. We just,
we let them and we ran away. We hid
under a desk. That's what we did.
Devin was a great person.
Um, and in New Jersey,
a 52 year old man blew off a large
piece of his leg below the knee.
When he set off a tennis ball size
in Montana,
Montana, Montana, a 32 year old man
was killed. That is billings home.
In a fireworks accident
involving a mortar tube.
Okay.
All right. At least there was some sort
of mortar round. I mean mortar around.
I mean,
first of all,
when you start lighting off shit where
your neighbor starts screaming and
comment, you know what? What do
you think is going to happen?
Okay,
so look up a mortar tube here,
everybody.
I'm learning about fireworks through
the death of my fellow Americans. Um,
I spelt motor.
All right.
Firework, mortar tubes. How
about some images? Let me see.
What the fuck these things look like.
Is there some sort of,
all right. All I see is army guys. Yeah,
that's not good. You know when, when
the shit you're shooting off. Oh,
there we go.
Okay,
well there's one that looks like a little
barber shop thing. What a fucking dope.
He shot that off his head.
You know what probably happened,
I would guess is that there was some sort
of discharge from the bottom end of it
and he concussive force,
but it seems like there was no
Deviney fucking blew his head off.
Know Jesus. Want to where to start.
I had such a wonderful weekend. Um,
I didn't mean this one. I was talking
about funny shit I was just talking about,
you know, people, they haven't
Roman candle fights. Come
on, we all did that shit,
right?
That's,
that is the evolution of
all weaponry and all right.
Anything that has an explosive
device, anything that, that, uh,
it's explosive device. Anything that,
that fucking blow shit up. You just,
you start or do you anything
that you can shoot at a target?
It always starts simple.
Let's light it off. You know,
let's, let's point it in
that direction at the trees,
right?
And then what? Then you move up to
a, let's torture some insects. Uh,
let's shoot a bird.
And eventually,
because you know,
the way human beings are that we always
try to top one another and we get bored,
which is the reason why we went from
walking to the horse to the car.
I'm really in deep right now.
I know.
I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about.
Eventually you're going to move to the,
the, the ultimate prey, the human being.
You know,
something that can think the same way.
You do something that may have done
better in math than you did. You know,
that's the challenge. This
person passed Algebra. I did not.
We're both trying to kill one another is,
you know,
first outside, inside, last,
going to come into play here
when we're out in the woods
are opposite angles being congruent?
Is that going to be the death me or
do I just have that extra something?
Do I want it a little bit more? Am I
able to block out the fifth commandment?
Do I have such a strong
religious background that I
can hear God's voice in my
head telling me that I'm
right telling me to deliver?
Okay,
that animal, so he met a man anymore.
It's a fucking animal. Deliver that animal
in the express lane to its maker.
Right?
Do I have that? I mean, it's inevitable.
That's personally why I
don't fuck with fireworks.
I don't fuck with fireworks because I
know that I am scatterbrained and I get
bored easily and I have 10,000 fucking
hobbies and eventually lighting it off on
the driveway is not going to be
enough for me. Okay. I have neighbors.
I have neighbors that I get along with.
Maybe I'm bored with the fact that I get
along with them. Maybe I want to stop.
Maybe some days you just wake up and
you just want to start some shit and you
just happen to have some
fireworks that don't just blow up.
They go way up in the air
and you want to shoot
somebody. Right. Okay.
Anyways,
uh,
my condolences to anybody who knows
somebody that died and I don't have any
condolences for the people that die
because you're fucking dead and you are
either dead or I think you were in a
better place because someone who's dumb
enough to blow themselves up on the
July 4th weekend with their own goddamn
explosives,
I don't think ever had the brains to
really hurt another human being knowingly.
I never knowingly, Lloyd knowingly
hurt another fucking human being.
I mean, honestly, if
you're that fucking stupid,
obviously could go out and you
could hurt somebody, but you know,
do you really have the mental
capacity to understand, you know,
your actions.
Okay.
It's gotta be one of the dumbest
fucking things you could ever do.
Yeah.
Take something of that level.
You know what it is.
I really think it's the fucking, while
they don't, there's no video of it.
I was thinking this is the
youtube generation where you know,
everybody's basically on TV is that
fucking skinny blood disease to cont who
painted the soup cans and everybody
flipped out over Andy Warhol,
one of the most overrated,
overrated fucking artists of all
time. All right. I almost said,
I'm sorry, but I'm not
sorry. I'm not sorry.
That fucking jerk off drugging up people
and banging them in the ass and then
fucking drawing a soup can. I mean, if
that's, if that's an artist in your world,
then you know what? There's a lot
of artists in prison right now.
They're fucking tasty. Jacquez, you
know, he was the original hipster,
you know,
didn't have the balls to fucking
strike out and do something new.
He just sort of mocked it just by the way,
did anybody see the last two
episodes of the comedians?
Ah,
did anybody with Josh
Gad and Billy Crystal,
I fucking love that show.
And uh,
this is a mini spoiler alert.
Basically Josh gets caught talking shit
about Billy crystal in his act and uh,
then they still have to do what
they gotta do promos to do.
The upcoming is through the fight
that they fucking have is great.
And,
um,
Billy Crystal's character and makes fun
of Joshua's like fucking hipster friends
and such a fucking
just beautiful way,
eloquent way,
and just really sums up that whole when
your creativity is just mocking whatever
exists,
it's such a pussy place to create from
because at some point that's what I
always do whenever I watched somebody,
like even one more time watching
somebody that went on on TV
and they just mark the artist's stand up,
you know,
which on on a certain level was funny,
was basically doing all the,
I don't know what is, what is the
word in the industry, the tropes,
the Hacky fucking, you know,
setups and all that type of shit.
Did all of that. But you know, after
a couple minutes it's like, okay,
I get it.
There's some tried and trued fucking
paths that you could walk down and as a
comedian, all right, if you
so adept at seeing that shit,
why don't you show all of us the new road?
And that's what those hipster cons
never do. They never, they don't cut,
they don't carve out any new ground.
They just stomping all over shit that's
already been done, making fun of it.
So I actually, you know, it's weird to
me it's because there's so much of that.
Okay.
During this period of time, you know,
like whenever, in 20 years from now,
when this generations of directors makes
their fast times at Ridgemont high,
they're fucking dazed and confused.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
No,
actually fast times at Ridgemont high
took place in the 80 so that was actually
very current. But I'm
just saying how, you know,
when the nineties to
seventies became the strategy,
can you made fun of all the clothes and
the fucking hairstyles and all that in
the two thousands and people made fun of
the 80s and now people kind of mocking
the 90s what are you going to mock now?
People mocking the decades before.
Like that's what people did in this.
There's gotta be something. I know what
that did. I see. What will they do?
They'll do a DJ music and being
too hard on this generation.
They got their own stuff.
They get math.
Every generation has to have their
own drug. By the way, you know?
Okay.
And heroin, a little bit old.
Something old, something new.
Something borrowed. Something blue. Right?
So what he did a, they get the math.
That's the new thing, right?
The old things. Heroin,
something borrowed. They're mocking
all this shit and something blew.
That's when they fucking Odie and they
don't have any oxygen in their blood
anymore. Jesus Christ. Bill,
what are you doing poetry over here?
Um,
I'll tell you right now,
that was a solid 15 minutes and
15 seconds of absolute horse shit.
And you know what?
You sat there and listened to it.
That's what you're doing today.
Two days after the fucking birthday of
America when we kicked England's ass.
Jesus Christ.
Fucking England.
Isn't it amazing that that
little ass fucking island,
that there was full of so many fucking
evil white people that they could
actually actually kind of took over
the world for a while? We're actually,
there was way less people.
It wasn't there. You know,
most of the places they went
to, you know, they weren't,
uh, they weren't as advanced, right?
This is where a white guy gets in
trouble for saying some racist shit.
You know what I mean?
I'm not trying to say that you know,
your boats weren't as good as
their boats. I wasn't there. Okay.
And in a lot of ways,
cultures that were considered primitive,
if we continued to live that way.
I want to ask you,
do you think that the planet
would be in the, the, the, the,
the polluted state that it is?
I don't think it would be,
but I'll tell you this right now.
I would already be dead.
I would already be dead,
you know, which for me,
selfishly, I'm glad we continued to
advance and pollute the fucking world,
you know?
But that's just a selfish fucking move.
I should, I should have said like, you
know what? I wish it stayed the same.
And I died of a ruptured appendix when
I was 12 years old under a stack of
blankets, sweating in a fucking
log cabin, log cabin, too advanced,
too many trees in a hot may not have
the skins of the animals that ate
throughout my life, my life. I
was going say my lives, my life.
I was actually trying to think the,
I was watching something the other day
and uh,
I've been doing this weird thing where
I fucking start to nod off watching TV
and then I wake back up, back up again,
and then I start thinking like that.
I just watched that or
did I just dream that?
And then I always do
the math and I was like,
that is way too fucked up
to have been on television.
I must have just been dreaming.
And then I never have the presence
of mind to fucking write it down.
You know what I mean?
I'll tell you,
it'd be fucking insane as
we could actually make a
movie that made people feel
like they were dreaming. Right.
But you knew you were dreaming,
but you couldn't wake up. Am I
describing a coma right now? Am I awake?
Can you guys hear me?
Hear me, hear me? Um,
okay. Closest thing to that would be, I
guess we'd be movies like Jacob's ladder.
Jacob's fought Gandel.
That movie was fucked. That movie's still
great. I watched that the other day.
Very underrated movie starring a,
the guy from shark,
Tim Robbins,
the guy he used to be married
to Susan Surandon. Oh, crush.
Two names in a row there.
I saw Susan Surandon
recently in a movie with a,
I want to say Melissa McCarthy.
I don't even, I don't remember.
All I know is she was fucking
hilarious. Oh, it was Melissa McCarthy.
She was fucking hilarious.
Fucking hilarious. Um,
it has what's Melissa has always.
So anyways,
speaking of lady luck,
be a lady two night.
Okay,
you won the ladies World Cup.
Okay
baby.
You stuck dead ball and the mother
fucking goal and you won the World Cup for
the first third fucking time though.
Fucking man.
Have any even wanted one.
It isn't fair.
It is not right.
Why do all leave the ladies with the
fucking World Cup while all the guys got
their soccer balls on ice? Sorry. Um,
the ladies World Cups.
I actually fucking really got into it.
And by really getting into it,
I kept forgetting it was on,
but whenever I saw it I kept going,
you know what? I'm going to watch this.
I saw Japan versus Australia.
I Japan obviously one that one,
cause they played the lady to the file,
you know the fucking women had.
Um,
okay.
The women had what? Three goals in the
first four goals and like the first,
I don't know how many minutes,
like five minutes or something like that.
I missed it. Of course I was out. Uh,
what was I do? I was playing drums.
You know what I mean? I was doing that
shit and then he fucking came back.
This is what I do.
I look like a fucking eight year old.
I should have died when I was 12.
What am I doing here?
I'm walking around like a big kid,
you know, I to have a bio shit,
have a fucking pacifier. The way I
live my fucking life. It was, he goes,
Weirdo guys, you know, they can't
let go. They fucking childhood.
Remember on Opie and Anthony one time
we were watching these things and they
fucking walking around in diapers and
then mothers treats him like a big baby.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
That's the one good thing.
If Hitler lived the one good thing,
if Hitler lives,
people who want to be adult babies
would would have been exterminated.
That's the only good thing. That would
be the only time Hitler got it right.
You know what I mean?
That you'd take out child molesters and
all we know beyond a shadow of a doubt
that guilty.
You got the guy dead to rights lane
in a fucking play pen playing with the
mobile mobile. One of those fucking
things that hang over. You had shell,
Exxon, what do you call those?
Fucking thinks immobile. A Menorah
Menashe. What the fuck is it
called? You know what it is?
The things that hang over and the kids
look at it cause they haven't like a
fucking acid trip. Dude. That would be
the ultimate drug. Don't worry ladies,
I'm going to get back to the
women went in the soccer.
I got a lot to say about that. Or football
as they call it, around the world.
That would be the ultimate fucking drug
is if you could take something that
erased temporary temporarily erased
everything you've ever learned in life
and you could go back to being a baby
again. Like the first time it opens its
eyes and you're just staring at a chair.
Like what in the fuck is that? Is
that my mother? Is that edible?
I mean,
you know what I mean?
Like cause I heard when baby's
first opened their eyes,
it is, it's like an acid trip. When
they're taken in all the colors,
light in every, they don't know what
the fuck. They didn't want that fucking,
they don't want their own hands
are sit there staring at the hand.
Can you imagine,
can you imagine the wonderment of that?
That's why, that's why babies need
diapers. Cause there's, there's,
they're on such a trip that you,
if you could fucking do,
then you looked at every no, you
shit yourself. Cause you don't even,
you don't even want a toilet is,
yeah,
he'd never been teased for
shitting yourself. You'd
never even smelled the shit.
You have no fucking idea
what it smells like.
You just have to shit and your shit.
Okay?
You know what tie do it nice.
You fucking end zone.
You just bury in threes like Steph curry,
except we hit all of them where he only
missed two out of a hundred but you bury
all of them because you don't know that
it's fucking practically impossible.
Tell you right now, if I was running
a basketball team, might sign a baby.
You know, get him up on his feet.
Just get them up and his feet. Okay?
Keep feeding this kid. All right. This
is the new triangle offense. Okay?
We got the fucking baby
right at the point.
We're going to keep fit and keep
working it around to him. All right.
[inaudible] kid, kid over
here. Hey. Yeah. Oh yeah.
You just keep launching it.
Everybody under the fucking me.
You just keep fucking throwing up,
right?
Be like when the nuggets decided not to
play defense and they thought that they
were going to have the first 200 point
game. What am I talking about now?
Fuck you. I got an hour to fill here. I
don't have any fucking advertising copies,
so this is just going to be
me just running my fucking
Yap for as long as I can.
Um, all right, so back to the
ladies. The ladies of women's soccer,
the soccer playing human beings
that have the, the, the lady bits.
All right. Um, so they scored four goals.
Of course I missed all the fucking goals.
The only goal and was 41 the only goal
I saw was when Japan all of a sudden cut
it to four to two when I was like,
oh fuck,
is this like Nhl hockey were
no lead is safe anymore.
And then the ladies came right back
down and gave Japan the old right there.
Fred, they gave me all right
there. Fred Bam. Shut the fuck up.
Go home.
Go home crying because you
just lost all right now.
Okay,
let's look at, yeah, I actually,
the sound into motor sports nerd.
I am even a sport that now don't even
admittedly do not even watch or don't
watch it nearly as much as I should
because it is a beautiful sport.
Especially the way that women play it.
I actually prefer women's
soccer to men's soccer.
Why you say over there?
Jolly Old England,
Ireland, a WEF, fucking
Argentina, Brazil, Germany,
all this fucking soccer giants.
Football.
I'll tell you why I preferred because
the women don't dive every three seconds
crying like a bunch of babies.
Okay?
Like when the women go down,
like they fucking, you know,
they got tripped up and then they,
they look at the ref like,
what the fuck you going to call that?
I thought the women play down.
They play a better game. They just play
a better fucking game. I'm sure the men,
right? This is a little faster,
fucking blah, blah, blah, blah.
But all the God damn fucking whining and
crying and men's soccer gonna tell you
right now, men's football players,
you gotta be ashamed of yourself.
And that goes for you too.
They're fucking Rooney or whatever you
fucking name is there. And Man United.
All right,
look in like fucking,
I don't want to fucking what?
Champs Sport,
whatever the fucking characters name is.
Sorry.
All right, let's just fucking
plow ahead here. Yeah. The women,
don't fucking cry be two seconds,
but I will tell you this.
What is fucking funny is when they lost
Japan's goalie just started crying.
I mean the defense sucks.
The defense had a total fucking meltdown.
I don't know what the Lady's coach saw,
but whatever it was,
they exploited it fucking three
times in the first five minutes.
And the only bad goal was when they
actually shot one from center ice.
And uh, the goalie looked like me playing
right field when I was in fourth grade.
Like, oh, it's going to drop
in for a single room. Come
on, come on. Maybe all shit.
It's over my head.
Remember that when you totally
misjudged it. Second it hits the bat,
you start running in towards the
first baseman and then, I don't know,
and I'll tell within three steps you
do that fucking just immediate stop.
And then all of a sudden your head's back
at a 45 degree angle is that ball just
keeps going up over your head.
That's what she did.
And what's funny is she leaped up in
the air with the one hand to try to stop
it,
and when it went over ahead head,
she just fucking landed on our entire
backside and you could already see her
just going fuck.
And in the end of the game,
I guess she felt that she caused her
team the victory, which she didn't.
It was absolutely horrific defense.
She just burst out crying,
which is one of the beautiful things
about being a woman. You know,
when you look at a baby,
all right boy or girl,
you know they want something,
you know that's yours,
something of value when you take it away
so you can't have that and they want it,
they immediately,
or you can just start fucking crying.
They're upset, they don't like
what's happened and they immediately,
they just cry it out.
When we can do that,
women can do that and you feel bad
for if a man cries another man,
the only thing you can do is just laugh
in their face and tease them until they
stopped doing it because it makes you
so fucking uncomfortable as a man.
The only time it's acceptable is when
your friend blows his head off with a
mortar round. Whenever the
fuck he did at a, at a, uh,
you know, and a 4th of
July party. And even then,
okay,
even then,
you know,
you got to shake it off within a
couple of Miller high life there.
Okay.
You know. All right, cliff. He's dead.
Okay. It's not going to bring them back.
We still got all these beers.
What is the difference?
If we'd say it now or in the morning,
he's going to be just as dead in the
morning. We're running out of ice.
We got to finish these sinks. And you're
like, you're right. You're right. Sorry.
Why would he do that? Sorry. Um,
cheeky.
That's the thing about women.
They can just fucking cry and we're not
allowed to and it's that combination
that they are allowed to cry out their
pain and we have to hold onto it.
And the fact that they then turn around
and Nag the fucking shit out of us,
that they actually take
10 years off our lives.
Do you realize that if women
died 10 years before men did,
can you imagine how much they
be complaining about that?
How much they would be blaming us for
it? You know, when we say that we die,
you know men die 10 years earlier. They
just blame us. Well, you know, you don't,
you hold onto your emotions.
You don't go to the doctor.
Yeah. And what about the
current factor? Uh Huh.
Anything there? Can
you, if I'm sweaty, got,
if you turn the fucking tables
and women died average of 10 years
before men did. All right. What color,
what pansy colored uniform with the
NFL players have to wear for an entire
fucking month as they raised awareness,
how much would they be blaming us?
How many movies would Meryl
Streep Win an Oscar for?
Playing the woman that was strong enough
to die at the same time as the guy in
her life?
I don't know.
You know what's funny about guys
in the beauty of guys is we still,
we don't even give a shit.
We die 10 years sooner than you
do and we don't even give a fuck.
It's the beauty of this
simplistic man brain.
Okay.
Um, anyway, so let's plow ahead here. Uh,
so women's World Cup soccer has been
around since 1991 and as of yesterday,
the United States of America,
we've won the most,
we've won three once.
Germany has one too.
I'm spice.
Norway has one,
one the death metal capitol of the world.
And Japan has one,
one Japan actually when the last one.
So we different the champions.
Alright.
Um, men's World Cup soccer,
there's only been so wait, wait,
women's World Cup soccer,
there's only been five, six,
seven times it's been played.
All right.
This is why I'm finally
gaining respect for this.
I always get had respect for the
championship because the entire world does
compete, but not only does the whole world
compete, they do it every four years.
So it's really,
it really fucking mean something here.
And all these people around the
world who are going like, yeah, Bill,
you'd dumb fucking Yank it. Yeah, it
means something. Well, you know what?
Maybe if you guys want a bunch of fucking
girls flopping all over the fucking
place and you could actually
pick it up with your hands.
The fuck did,
I don't understand a sport where you
have four fucking limbs and you only
allowed to use two of them. Yeah.
Jesus Christ. It's like, it's like,
it's like you're mocking the
handicap the entire time.
I'm watching the fucking
game. Anyways. Sorry.
So this is only been 20 men's world cups.
All right.
Brazil is one the most at five.
Italy and Germany. You have both one four
and I got to give the nod to Germany.
As much as I love Italians,
the way they dress their food,
they're flashy fucking jewelry.
I'm all about it.
I love Italians and I am fucking German.
I got to give the nod to Germans because
they won their first three with half of
fucking country. They won their
first one. Let's let me look this up.
Let me make sure that I have this
correct. Um, they won their first one,
I think in 1954.
I mean,
that's literally like,
what is that like about nine Yeoman?
Less than a decade.
Yeah.
They formed their first one in 1954 world
war two ended in 45 46 something like
that.
1944 maybe we'll say 45 what the fuck?
Within nine years of trying to take on
the entire world and losing Dresden and
bombs all over the fucking place.
They,
they won a world cup with half
their country, West Germany.
You know what I mean? I'm sure
East Germany was actually in it to
who's getting know Jeremy is just, I mean
that is just a roid factory over there.
1974 they want it.
Okay.
They are, they were on, they were on.
They were doing so many
steroids by 1974 dad,
a lot of people don't know this,
that West Germany team
was actually 80% a women.
A lot of people don't know that. East
Germany, east German women, you know,
they were so write it up. They didn't
have to sneak out of the country.
They just stare down the people in the
guard tower and they were just like, Amen.
I don't want any problem,
bro. All you, all, you,
you want me to open that gate for
you? Okay. Um, 1990 they want it.
All right, let's get back to what the
fuck I was talking about here. Uh,
what the hell did it go?
Oh, there we go. Alright.
Uruguay as one to Argentina.
Hand at God.
One, two, and then England,
France and Spain have all one one.
And that is it.
It's only been one 20 times
and one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight countries.
Only eight countries have one.
So now I feel better that the u s a
men's have never won a fucking world cup.
You know, most people given a shit. It's
like, well how many did you fucking win?
You'd never want it either.
And I love that.
I now know who's won it and who hasn't.
So I've ever walked into
a soccer sports bar.
I know who I can talk shit to
and who I can't to. What are you?
Huh? You from Brazil. Oh, Chile. Oh, go
fuck yourself. You ever won? Shit either.
What's your big butchy big feather
in your cap that she care? Um,
which makes the women winning three,
all the more impressive,
but you got to give it up to Germany.
Germany is the only country that has
won both the men and the worlds in,
in the women's and they've won for men's
and they've won two women and they were
only off by one and bolts.
You got to respect to Jesus Christ.
When is Bryant Gumbel real sports going
to be doing a what's in the water,
what's in the water over
there and fucking Germany.
He know why they're not going to do it.
Cause we have a base over there.
We already know what's in the water.
A van of fucking steroids.
I got to tell you, it's amazing, you know,
to watch Germany channel all their hatred
for other races and nationalities and
and put it into something more productive
like sports and look at the success
that they've had.
You know what I mean?
Bad Burning Passion
to incinerate people that aren't,
that don't look like them.
The fact that we've been sitting on their
fucking chest for the last 60 years,
they've had to to,
to focus that energy in different areas.
And they are dominating the world,
game of soccer, football, whatever,
and look at the cars that they make.
It's incredible.
If you've noticed all the fascist
countries make the greatest cars, Germany,
fuck in Italy.
Who else? Finland. They
don't make good cars.
They make good phones for a minute.
But look at them. Angry birds.
They made those angry birds.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
All of a sudden they couldn't
exterminate the people.
They didn't want to exterminate near
country. What did they do? They said,
all right, what, uh, what are we
going to do with all this? Hey,
what do I have to make some phones?
Sorry. Can't do a fucking Finland accent.
Actually,
I give fin when a pass for
being down with the h bomb in a,
in a World War II. I, uh, you know,
what were they supposed to
do? You know what I mean?
This ship was like, all right,
where we are geographically,
you look to the right,
you got Adolph Hitler with beads of sweat.
There's bdis in his fucking eyebrows.
[inaudible] or are you against us? Right?
And on the other side, they got, uh,
eastern Europe's Tom Selleck,
the one and only Joseph Stalin or Yosef,
if you're a history buff,
okay.
Staring you down.
Right?
This motherfucker would sacrifice 100,000
Russians every day just so we can have
fresh pineapple juice. I mean, this
guy was a fucking maniac. They will,
they will between
too.
They were stuck between two of the
biggest psychos in the history of,
of in modern history. All right? So
they had to go with self preservation.
All right.
Hitler's style and equally out of
their fucking minds. All right,
so that's a wash and what's
the next thing? All right,
let's go with technology.
German cars. What do we got?
What do we got going on here?
They got their Mercedes Benz,
they got the Duesenberg.
Did they make the Duesenberg?
I don't know what the fuck they had. They
had fucking, I'm they, you know, they got,
they got,
they got a,
they make an eight track tapes over
here fucking 50 years before the gout.
40 years, 30 years before the fucking be,
Geez, what are we supposed to do here?
They got real real machines. You go
over to Russia, what do they get?
They got vodka.
They got a God damn fucking made with
a lawnmower engine spitting
out blue smoke. And they,
you know, they got, you know,
they've got those checks with the
fucking lousy to watch. You know,
by the way, Russian women
have really come around, Huh?
Jesus Christ to fucking gorgeous.
Now back in the day during the Cold War,
maybe those are the only
women that they showed us.
They all had those fucking Popeye, the
sailor man. Boop, boop, fucking forearms.
You know what I mean? From throwing
calves over some fucking hill.
They weren't supposed to run over. So
whatever. So Finland goes, you know what?
Fuck it. We'll go on with
the h bomb, you know, but
we'll have it up.
Boom.
They went with him by
flashlight gas chambers.
They fucking went with this maniac.
What were they supposed to do?
They fucking pick the wrong guy.
And you know what's funny was Russia
actually attack Finland in Finland,
kicked their fucking ass with no help
from the Germans as far as what I
overheard and bars and Finland,
and this is the funny thing,
but they went down with the ship
with the h bomb over there. Right.
They went down with that guy who fucking
pussied out and killed himself in the
end.
This fucking broad.
Rather than going out like Saddam
Hussein talking shit is they put the rope
around your neck.
Yeah.
Even people heckling you was still,
he's still add them on their heels. Huh?
For me that's like a,
like when you know,
when people bring up comics getting
fucking heckled and that type of shit and
people like to watch it, the ultimate
one, like if I was a dictator,
I would be looking at how sit down
was saying when I'll be like this
motherfucker here, right there. Right. And
everybody La, what about Hitler? You know,
we killed all those people. Like that's
probably be respected with fucking,
you know, dictators like that's
how many HBO specials you had.
Like how many fucking people
you killed. They, but you know,
all evil people are going like, ah, man,
like his fucking amazing numbers
that he had. It's like, yeah,
but he went out like a bitch.
You know,
he went out like a bitch just like
Gaddafi went out like a bitch pleading for
his fucking life. So now I'm going
to say, walked right up going, yeah,
go fuck yourself. Fuck you. I'm going
to come back. I want a hot chill. Right?
He fucking stare at them all down.
He didn't give a fuck standing there,
stepped onto that thing. No one at any
second, they could pull the fucking lover.
He wasn't even shaken.
Okay?
He was staring them all down. Go Fuck.
He wasn't even nervous to meet his maker.
It's one of the sickest things
I've ever seen in my life. Um,
what am I talking about?
So they fucking, they beat,
they beat the Goddamn Russians, but
because they, they picked the wrong guy.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
That's like when you were in
the wrong division in baseball,
you have like back in the day,
you know,
you'd have a better or I want a pill in
that year when the patriots 11 and five,
but they didn't make the fucking playoffs.
That's what,
that's what fucking Finland did.
And they actually had to give up
even though they beat the Russians.
They didn't have that.
They still had to give him some land.
How fucked up is that? Oh, war. All right.
I hope some of that was even just remotely
historically accurate. I have no idea.
As long as it's entertaining.
Did it entertain you? All
right. So anyways, I had,
I had an amazing weekend. I
had an amazing weekend. Um,
I uh,
you know,
it had some family came in and
for the first time ever I, uh,
I gave a helicopter ride
to some family members.
I went up with the fucking uh,
instructor though, cause I'm on a moron.
But we did this great flight.
We flew out of Long Beach,
we ran around the palace Verdes peninsula.
It's great man.
You fly right over the Queen Mary.
And then you go around the peninsula
and then as you go around the peninsula,
that's when you start realizing how
many goddamn things are in the ocean,
even though we fucking fished him out.
And we started going along the beach
and I thought they were dolphins and my
instructors going, no, those were
actually baby great, great white sharks.
They just haven't reached
the predatory stage yet.
And I swear to God there
was like five of them. Um,
and there was one and there's all these
people frolicking in the fucking water.
And there was this one jackass who
had swam beyond where they were.
Um, they were perpendicular to him,
but he was further out into the ocean.
They were closer to the beach.
I hope I'm explaining this correctly.
And he was swimming out to like a bully
like that naked chick in the beginning
of jaws. Um, yeah, I
said it a million times.
You're out of your fucking mind.
If you swim in the ocean,
if you don't believe me,
take a helicopter ride,
have him fly a hundred feet
off the fucking ocean. I
know you're thinking bill,
once Jesus Christ.
And went the how fucking nuts and they
have a 2100 hour fucking overhaul.
It's a brand new helicopter every
2100 hours, go fuck yourself.
What I'm doing is infinitely
more safe. All right. Um,
and then we uh,
made a right turn at the Ferris
wheel on Santa Monica Piers.
We flew over Santa Monica over Beverly
hills right over fucking Aaron de Aaron
Spelling Mansion,
which is the most ridiculous house
ever built that I can think of.
Do you know that house was so big?
I saw a thing one time they did
it on the Aaron Spelling House.
They actually have a room in there
just for wrapping gifts to have a gift
wrapping room. You know
what I mean? To me,
I always thought that the people who do
American horror story like that would be
a great place to do one of those things.
People that are that level fucking
rich and then somehow the kid,
the children and the poor people that put
together all the things that they wrap
in there somehow come and haunt him.
I have no idea,
but feel free to send that
to the producers over there
so they can fucking laugh
you out of the Goddamn Room.
Um,
and who doesn't like watching
a fucking rich person
get haunted and die a horrific
death? I mean, it's just fun. I mean,
that's a fucking home run right there.
American horror story.
You know, you don't have to give me
any money. All I ask is if you use it,
just give the Monday morning podcast
the fucking shout out. That's all.
That's all.
Just have somebody tells somebody else
to go fuck themselves and have them
wearing an orange wig and I'll be happy
right there. That'll be enough for me.
Um, all right. Plowing ahead here. Uh,
in the playboy mansion is right to
the left of it. Then we flew up, um,
to the Hollywood sign
over the observatory,
did a lap around dodger stadium
and then my favorite part ever,
we flew up route to bang the
left up and over the hill.
And where is it at?
Eight at grand daddy of them all flew
over the fucking rose bowl and then went
right back. Took right down,
back down to a long beach. Um,
it was fucking awesome man,
but flew in what's called an
our 44 Robinson 44 some day.
You know what I mean? Some day
I want to get one of those. Um,
when I get a little more,
uh,
confident and I also have the kind of
money to blow on a fucking helicopter.
I imagine I don't have to drug my
wife on some level. There's a lot of,
there's a lot of,
you know,
variables as a man to buying a helicopter.
Like the amount of fucking money and and
hand is, they sit on Seinfeld,
the amount of hand that you,
you got to have hand in a relationship
that you'd have to have to fucking
justify buying a helicopter when you
really have nowhere to go in the thing.
So anyways,
don't get a used one on fucking
craigslist. Damn. Things are awesome.
Um, all right. So guess what?
Last night was my last cigar and my list.
I'm taking a booze break. Old Billy
clean cakes is back in the house.
I got a nice round white
belly from, uh, you know,
grilling,
drinking.
I had a great fucking weekend
and I mad my own grill man,
my own Grill Aza. Man Does. Even if you
don't know how to do it, even if you're,
you,
you risk giving the people at your party
eat Kolai it doesn't make a difference.
You are a man and you fucking
human your own goddamn grill.
Um, I, I kept it simple.
I've just made burgers and hot dogs and
what's fucking amazing is we got this
butcher,
um,
in the next neighborhood over
from us and they make their own.
Okay,
you can order homemade
hamburger buns and hot dog buns.
They made us like the hot dog buns.
They came in like a,
it looked like ribs except
they will hot dog buns.
And you had to cut them to separate them
and then cut them again to make them,
you know, to them. So you put
the hot dog in. It was fuck,
I felt like it was like the 1920s
assumption, you know what I mean?
Everything was homemade and boy,
oh boy, was it refreshing. Um,
so anyways, uh, let's get to, let's
get to some of the questions here,
um, for this week. Yes. So I am,
I am announcing it on the
fucking podcast because uh,
that I am not drinking or smoking or
anything like that, so I will stick.
So you guys will hold me to it so,
and I don't have to hang my head in shame
next week and tell you that I fucked
up. All right, so, oh, here
we go. I finally got my
advertising here for this week.
It was a little bit late.
Um, all right, here we go.
Dollar Shave club,
everybody,
some of you out there who still
have not joined dollar shave club.
What's the issue? People, what
is you, what are you waiting for?
These guys are great. You know, you've
heard me talking about them for years now.
Do I got to break it down for you again?
Obviously I do. Their razors are amazing.
It's more convenient and cost a
fraction of the price. All right,
here's how the club works.
You go to dollar shave club.com and
pick one of their three great razors.
The six blade executive for the
Werewolf Mediterranean in you,
the four blade forex and
the two blade humble twin.
However, Harry, you are right.
If you like Brad Mash and you can grow
a beard in between periods back in the
day, you'd get the six later, right?
Cause the Danoe Chara Eastern
European guy, right? Four blades.
And if you're like me, oh
Billy German cakes, right.
You can just need the two blades
on. Everything is smooth. Yeah.
Um,
you get your first box in about a week
and includes a free handle in a sleeve of
blade cartridges. It's high quality
stuff. People, it's got that weight to it.
You know like your member when
it's standing up. Oh Jesus.
Like the expensive ones
you've used before.
The humble twin has to stainless
steel blades and an alloys strip.
That's all you need.
You've never gotten a shave like
this or at least not for this price.
After that first box,
they mail you a sleeve or replacement
blades every month or every other you and
you never have to worry about it again.
That's it. If you haven't joined yet,
you're missing out. Simple as that. I
don't know what else we have to do here.
Try Dollar Shave club.com/birth that's
dollar shave club.com/bar mirror.
All right. Oh Jesus. Here we
go. Boop, boop, boop. Me undies,
me undies. No more sweaty balls,
boo. Doo Doo, Doo me undies,
me undies. Uh, drinking them. Fucking bud.
Talls you can take a piss
while you're wearing them.
Grabbing another one with your
friend's Piss Yourself Fang.
It taints stays dry with some
fucking me undies. Oh yeah.
They even make them for the ladies.
No Way. No swearing. He clams.
Just get these fucking things are right.
90%.
That's the percent of your life that
you're in your underwear and underwear.
It gets old fast. You know they're
feeling of putting on old saggy underwear.
You need to know the feeling of great
fitting underwear that is two times softer
than Compton, Compton, cotton.
You need to know about me undies,
me, undies, me, undies.
Dot Com me undies has the most comfortable
underwear you will ever try on and
it's insane how good they make you feel.
They fit perfectly.
They don't ride up on you and
they literally pull moisture
away from your skin so you can stay
cool. They're great. I, I don't,
I'm not wearing a pair right now, but I
got them and they send them right to you.
New Underwear, what? A country. But
they also make you look great. Oh,
not the way I look right now. I look
like a hot dog that's been overcooked.
That's little right before,
right before it fucking splits.
That's what I look like right now. Go to
[inaudible] dot com and check out this,
the photography. You fucking
Weirdos. And for the ladies,
check out this smoking hot boy shorts.
I was filling a pervert saying this and
ladies check out those smoking hot boy
shorts. But you have to
try them on for yourselves.
Who's one of those fourth
for the fucking runaways.
Should fucking send those to
bus stations around the country.
And this quality would typically
retail for two times the uh,
the price according to me undies.
No retail middlemen means
more savings for you here.
We will make it easy here at
the Monday morning podcast.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com slash
burr and get 20% off your first order and
low flat rate.
International shipping save even more.
When you buy a pack of them,
they guarantee you're going to be happy
and with and with them you're guaranteed
you're going to be happy with them
or your first pair is free. Oh,
I'm not happy with this underwear.
All right, here's some more.
It doesn't make sense but I have more
stuff so I'm happy once you feel me undies
on your body, you're never going back
in me. Undies isn't just for you,
isn't just for you guys.
They just launched their all of me.
Why not take all of me mean we knew that
Dan clam should only get wet when your
excited,
the lady's soccer team won the fucking
World Cup and all they had clams were dry
because of me on ds weight.
They launched their all of me on these
women's collection of four piece line of
undies designed specifically for
the female body and all its complex.
Gorgeous has hell glory. I hate that
fucking line because it says it's complex.
Like you don't know where the fucking
come button is and also glorious is hell.
It just made, it just makes me feel
weird every time I say. Okay. Yeah,
it's a little more difficult.
Okay.
The Women Women's fucking privates.
It's like,
have you ever owned a van and you've
got to change the fucking oil. Yeah.
It's like you got to go inside the van.
That's the thing where the guy,
you just get underneath it,
lick them balls is a sweetheart.
Um, but to get that 20% off,
you have to go to [inaudible] dot
com slash bird that's me undies,
m e undies.com/bar.
All right?
And lastly, but certainly not
leastly. Oh actually it doesn't.
We've got two more here.
Sorry guys,
I just got the heads now
we're just going to vote.
Is going to have to Paul through this
shit trunk club. Everybody. Hey fellas,
you might hate shopping, but you
still want to look good. Right?
Okay.
Right? Uh, what if you
could snap your fingers,
hey and have a trunk full of clothes
that fit perfectly and make you look
amazing.
You're going to love what
you get delivered to you
from Trunk club@trunkclub.com
slash burr. You answer a few simple
questions about your look. Oh,
you know, it's like, I don't want to be
too forward, but I do like being noticed.
Your style in size and then they assign
a real person who helps you to style.
You've a real person.
They assign a real person.
I just thought of Aaron Paul at the
end of fucking breaking bad when he's
chained around the neck having to,
having to make meth.
Who is this person that
gets assigned to me?
Bring me some clothes.
Slave boy.
They aim either they email you a list of
clothes, they recommend sending you a,
you approve at no cost to you.
They ship ship a trunk full of fresh new
clothes to your door. You try them on,
you keep what you want. You send back
what you don't want in their prepaid box.
That's it.
A better wardrobe than you could ever
pick out for yourself in minutes did I
mentioned the services free your
stylist, the shopping, the box,
even the shipping all 100% free. When you
go to trunk club.com/bar it's not free.
Your role in the price with the other
bullshit. Stop talking down to us here.
Only pay for the clothes you keep. No
ongoing subscriptions, no hidden charges,
no malls, just great. Closed,
handpicked for your style. All right,
you should use this shit.
Yup.
If you don't have to fucking
shop, why would you? Uh,
you're going to thank me on this
and right now it's completely free.
So go get started@trunkclub.com
slash bar today.
That's trunk club.com/ [inaudible] all
right? And last year we go legal, zoom,
everyone. You know, there's a lot of
great reasons. While a great reasons.
Smart business people trust
legal zoom first. Dallas.
For starters, if you want to incorporate
form an LLC or a nonprofit, file,
a patent or trademark,
get a DBA in more legal zoom provides
to help you need over the past decades,
decade more than a
million business owners,
just like you have
started with legal zoom.
But did you know that legal zoom is also
your first stop when you need advice
from an attorney. Legal
Zooms, not a law firm,
so they built a network of independent
attorneys in most states to provide legal
advice and other useful services
to help you run your business.
So whether you need a
contract reviewed or advice,
or whether you should incorporate or form
an LLC, whatever your legal question,
start with legal zoom and as always,
stay provide complete transparency
with upfront pricing, customer views,
and 100% customer satisfaction guarantee.
Make this match choice for
your business@legalzoom.com
today and don't forget to
enter Burr at checkout to save even more.
Again,
that's Burr at checkout for more savings.
Legal Zoom,
Promo Code burr legal help
is here. Well, there you go,
everybody. That's the end of
the advertising. All right.
Let me get to the fucking reads this
week. This is becoming a long podcast. Uh,
Jesus Christ. Bill, can you learn how
to fucking use a computer? All right,
here we go. What do we got here?
I'm coming up on an hour. All right.
Uh, quote, retard. Bill as a mom of three,
count them three mentally challenged kids.
And what?
You have my permission to use the word
whenever you want to describe idiots that
you show. I don't want permission.
I don't want to use the word.
I don't want to hurt people.
Okay?
But I reserve the right to every once in
a while if I flip out and I dropped the
fucking word in a moment of anger cause
I'm standing there in front of a fucking
drunk who won't shut up, I still
expect you to give me shit about it.
But just accept my apology and know that
I don't have anything against mentally
challenged people. I just was pissed
at this person and I made a mistake.
That's all I'm asking. I'm not
asking for a license to use the word.
I don't want to use it. Jesus. Alright.
Orzo response to mentioning
Orzo last week or the last week.
Uh, red bill gives you wings.
Hey, there's a new one.
Uh, tell that woman a yours to
get back in the goddamn kitchen.
Orzo is a pasta shape shaped like rice.
Not a grain.
Christ alive,
but seriously love near her appearances
of the best part of the podcast. Well,
fuck you. I like to think I
bring something to the table.
Um, oh, that's great. I'll have to
let her know that Orzo is a pasta.
Pasta shape is pasta. Oh, Jesus Christ.
Or as though his pasta shape like rice.
Dude,
I really have a fucking learning
disability, man. I can't read words.
I can read them. I just can't put
them through. I said, it's a, I said,
Orzo is pasta shaped rice.
I don't even,
what the fuck I said Orzo
is pasta shaped like rice.
You know what?
Anybody who listens to this podcast
has gotta be at least as dumb as I am.
Let me fucking look this up.
Maybe they're right or zo
orzo up. Wikipedia says it's
apostasy gig. You got it.
You got to think it's true.
Orzo.
It's Italian for Bali from the Latin.
Also.
Risoni is a form of shortcut pasta shape,
like a large grain of rice or as
oh can be served alone as a soup,
a coup Trumbull as part of a salad
or Pilaf or Geo Vestey or Bacon,
a castle role, which she invests the,
I want to go to Italy. I want to go,
I want to go to Florence, uh, cheese.
It's look at what the Italians are the
best man. What the, oh, that's Greek.
My apologies. I want to go to Greece. I
don't want go to Greece right now. Hey,
I didn't, I didn't even see
how the fuck did they vote.
They vote to fucking let
them. They're there. God Damn.
Banks just fail.
That's what they should do.
They should just let
everything fail and then,
then everybody's money isn't worth shit.
And then you know something,
those bankers got to come out in public
and then you fucking stab them in the
gut. Like that dude at the
beginning of Scarface, right?
Leading gap lay band, gap, uh,
Greece. Vote. Let's see what,
come on, man. Come on Greece.
You know,
they didn't mark is
resilient after no vote.
Uh, and we always plus
the out. We always pussy.
Everybody always ends up pussy
and out. You know, something.
Only fucking Iceland has had the balls
to stand up to their fucking bankers.
And you know what? I hope I'm
wrong about that. And if I am,
please tell me who else has. All right,
no idea where to start. Dear Mr Burr,
I'm a 16 year old high school,
junior from a rural town in Mississippi
just to good old bar they ever made in
no hall getting the conferred or red flag,
birthday cake every fuck and see x months
because his parents are too dumb to
know what a year is.
You're not even 16, Buddy.
You're really fucking a sorry.
That was totally stereotypical and
I shouldn't have done that. Um,
now that I'm nearing my final year of
high school and will soon be having to
decide where to go to college,
I realized I have no idea what
I want to do with my life.
The only two things I have interest
in his writing and standup comedy,
unless those are two phenomenal things
you can make a hell of a living.
I flunked everything in high school.
Uh,
but here's a few places from where I live,
but there's a few places from where I
live where I could do something like an
open mic and Jesus Christ. But you know
some that should inspire you right here,
right here.
How awful.
I am at reading out loud yet I've been
able to do something in this business.
You know what I mean?
I'm able to make a living and,
and I can put frosted mini wheats
on the table for my family of one.
I'm the only two things I am
interested in is running standpoint,
but there's few places from where I live
where I could do something like an open
mic or get honest opinions on my
comedic writing. I'm writing to ask,
in your opinion,
would be a great town for starting,
for starting convenient to start.
Uh,
also if you think someone can
juggle college in a standup,
do you think someone can juggle
a stand up in a car, a college,
in a standup career?
I would truly be grateful for your
advice and also go fuck yourself.
I'm all right.
Any place is a good place to start.
Just start. If there's an open mic,
I would drive
as long as I had to drive to go to it.
Um, let's see. You're in
Mississippi. All right. What do I,
what do I know about down there?
I mean,
the closest thing that I
know of from Mississippi,
Atlanta and Nashville, uh, Texas.
Houston was always a great comedy town.
I don't know what the open mic
scene is like. If anybody, anybody,
any comedians out there
starting out and even buddy,
anything going on in Alabama,
what's going on in Mississippi,
right in give this kid some fucking
advice. Uh, tweet me about it.
I'll retweet it.
That's the easiest way to do it because
we might not see your emails because we
get a bunch of them. So just tweet
me about it. And, uh, you know,
at Bill Burr on Twitter and if you got
some good advice, I will retweet it.
Um, can you juggle college
and a standup career? Yeah,
absolutely. Absolutely. Um,
you can do whatever you want to do in
life, dude. You can do whatever you want.
That's the one fucking thing.
Everybody, you know, you know,
cause people want to make it,
they try to look at what is working
for the most people and then they,
they get locked into that.
I,
that's the biggest advice I can give
you is do not get locked in to what
everybody else is doing. Get locked into
what's going on in your fucking chest,
whatever that thing saying like do
this unless they say and to shoot your
neighbors. Don't do that. But if it's,
you're doing something that's not going
to hurt somebody, like writing jokes,
telling them, writing a script. Yeah, you
can do whatever the fuck you want to do.
And the fact that you're 16 and you're
already are listening to yourself,
you're way ahead of the game. So, um,
and you have the intelligence to
understand that, you know, hey,
I need some help and you reached
out for it. Keep doing that,
my friend and I hope to see out there.
Give it a shot, you know. But I would,
I would, I'd write five minutes is shit
tonight and then sign up for an open mic
somewhere and within the
week I would start do it.
And that's unbelievable balls to be able
to do that as 16 it took me almost a 24
to get the balls to do it. So my
hat is off to you sir. Or ma'am,
I don't know who you are. All right, here
we go. Girlfriend has prejudice parents,
a Billy Billy dingleberry. I am a
white man who was dating a black woman.
She is the greatest thing that has ever
happened to me and there's no doubt in
my mind that I want to spend
my life with her. Well,
congratulations until now.
Don't done.
We'd been dating for 10 months then I
finally met her parents this past weekend.
When I got there,
seemed shocked by my skin color,
almost like my girl hadn't even
hinted to them that I was white. Well,
that's probably what happened
if they are fucking racist. Um,
the whole dinner was very awkward.
I wasn't being looked at in the eye
and I was left out of most of the
conversation.
Then they make a movie about this Ashton
Kutcher in the late great Bernie Mac.
I even tried talking to her dad about
music since we are both musicians,
but he just kept giving me short answers.
Like he didn't give a fuck
after the whole thing was over.
My girlfriend said that they
didn't like that I was white. Uh,
she said that they wanted her to have
strong black babies and not to dilute the
bloodline
also.
Uh,
they sprouted a bunch of other shit about
how much trouble will run into as an
interracial couple. It has been four days
and we still haven't talked about it,
nor is she told her parents off
for being prejudice assholes.
I truly believe this is the only
situation where a white person can fully
understand what a black person go. I
don't know about that. Dewayne you get,
you get, you get a little
sprinkling of it. Uh,
a black guy with the microphone on the
street corner can call me cracker all he
wants and I won't lose a wink of
sleep over. But when you told, uh,
the person you love is wrong and invalid,
that's like a kick in the balls anyways.
How should I go about addressing this?
I'm assuming you didn't run to this
problem with Nia. No, I didn't make,
maybe she could weigh in on this as well
anyway. Thanks and go fuck yourself.
Uh, Jesus. Um, I would
say if you love her,
I would stay with her.
If, if you questioning it,
I pull the rip cord cause that's
just going to be a fucking nightmare.
That'll end up being a nightmare.
You know what I mean?
You gonna be going to be in a relationship
where you're waiting for the other
person's parents to die.
Sitting there going like one down
today. You know, that's just the
fucked up. You know, you really,
when you're going to get
married is you have to, uh,
okay.
I Dunno. I mean, who are the fuck am
I to say I waited so God damn long.
So I'm not an authority.
But you know, if you,
if you're with somebody that's fun,
you know,
and they come from a good family and
their family supportive of you guys.
I mean that's so much of the battle
actually, you know, something,
this past week when I was in
Vegas, somebody came up to
me, said, hey bill, I want,
let me, I got to ask you a
question. Who makes you laugh?
And without even thinking,
I said my wife and it made me feel really
good like that. It's quite, you know,
my wife saw hot shit. She makes
me laugh, we have a good time. Um,
and uh,
so I don't know,
she might not be bringing it up because
she's embarrassed about it or whatnot.
Um, I have no idea. But uh,
okay.
I mean that's going to be a hell of a
fucking situation if that's how they're
going to view their grandkids.
I mean, that's kind of a,
that that's a major fucking
situation where I would at least
want to see where her head is at.
And then you throw out certain
scenarios about the future.
So how are we going to handle this?
And Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Um,
you know what?
I'm sorry you're going through that dude,
but you definitely need to have some
fucking conversations. I would think.
I would definitely think
some conversations that were
in the order. All Right,
Collin Farrel movies.
He, Billy Redskin, uh,
Colin Farrell has done a couple of great
movies since phone booth. You should, uh,
you should like, namely in Bruges, Bruges.
I don't know how to say it.
And seven psychopaths with the
always excellent Sam Rockwell.
Oh, Jesus Christ. I got to
c seven s seven psychos.
Seventh Psychopath. I got to see that. Um,
you could give, you could
give them a look. All right.
Coming to California next
year from Ireland on holiday.
Hope to see you in action.
All right, well, I hope you
make it out to a show. Oh,
right. Said, I got hit with
a wave of fucking tired.
All right, that's the podcast
for this week. As always,
if you'd like to donate to the podcast,
anytime you go on amazon.com,
you thinking you're going
to buy something lays. Um,
if you'd like to donate to the podcast,
it doesn't cost you any money.
Just go to the bill bird.com.
Click on the podcast page,
and then you just click on
the, uh, the link, the Avatar,
or whatever the fuck
you call it to Amazon.
And it doesn't cost you any extra money.
It's just,
I get credit for driving traffic to
this site. They kicked me a little doe,
Ray fucking me,
and I try to give a 10% of it to a fucking
charity that hopefully is on the up
and up right now. I do the
St Jude thing, Saint Jude,
please don't fuck me.
Oh, uh, take them money.
Give it to the right people.
I'm sorry. All right.
That's the podcast for this
week. Go fuck yourselves. And A,
I'll be checking in on you on
Thursday. All right. See Ya.